[Music]
oh hello again my friends
fancy seeing you here
welcome to the next episode of the
podcast
[Music]
the cannabis podcast for buddy
enthusiasts
on this episode we're joined by our
alaskan friend the one and only ak bean
brains
[Music]
talking all things genetics new school
old school and everything else
this episode as always was brought to
you by the one and only seeds here now
your only seed bank that offers a
guarantee both on satisfaction and
germination there's no reason to shop
elsewhere they've got all the best hit
them up
likewise 420 australia and organic
gardening solutions your two number ones
in australia holding down the fort
everything from apparel to grow needs
get it there first
[Music]
and a quick shout out to our
regenerative farming friends at
dragonfly earth medicine
[Music]
let's get into it
alrighty so a big thank you and welcome
to our first guest from the final
frontier an extremely nice guy i've had
the pleasure of hanging out with a few
times now aka beanbrains thanks so much
for taking the time to join us today
well
thanks for having me on it's uh good to
finally do this like you said after
we've met a couple times
we should have already been uh you know
fishing or something but the interviews
uh
passed due so i'm glad to be here
it's great to have you on my friend so
first question for today what are you
currently smoking on
funny thing is it's the same thing that
uh you know i had a lot of at the uh
emerald cup do you remember what we were
smoking that uh
platinum huckleberry cookie do you
happen to remember that i do fondly
oh good because but uh yeah i happen to
have
a little bit of that and i
i'm just picking that as a really good
favorite
it's really good smoke
i love dynasty so um
his smoke just stands out
hell yeah i can definitely agree with
you on that one let's loop back to that
one a bit later because the first thing
i wanted to ask you is what was your
first experience with cannabis
that's funny too they're uh
you know i was a bad kid so
about fifth grade
when uh you know all the kids are
starting to score cigarettes and stuff a
friend of mine's dad had a little
uh wasn't convenience store it was like
a country store and he lifted uh
like cartons of the worst thing in the
world was i think camels or whatever it
was was horrible strong tobacco and we'd
get it together after school and you
know smoke a couple but it turned me
green
and they uh
they tended to keep smoking and i found
out that um
you know pot at the time was like real
weedy and it's
around i think it's probably
right about 80
a little bit earlier than 80 78 but uh
you know my mom had a friend
and uh he'd give me
ounces or not at the you know they
called it lids at the time it was five
to ten bucks a lid i'd have him uh
he'd get me to roll and clean it up and
roll like you know 35 40 uh
doobies out of uh out of a lid you give
me a one or two
so i smoked that it was just such swaggy
weed i never ever really got high
and um i thought i was getting high just
like a real poor
butt every time but
i guess i was around 12 years old and i
babysit for a friend
my mom's friends and i don't want to be
stereotypical but they were bikers and
they had some bud they knew that i'd
already smoked and they said it would be
cool to try it they gave me a bud
and it was chocolate thai for all i can
tell from everything i've ever seen
later in my life it was real chocolate
thai it was all uh basically right off
the thai stick and uh i pulled the seeds
out of it and i smoked it but it stuff
that hit me
and i was like euphorically high for
four or five hours shouldn't have been
babysitting their kids because it was
like super potent so then i realized
that uh
what part really was
yeah wow and has that always left that
as kind of having a little fond spot in
your heart do you want to ever go back
to that
uh it really does because the uh it's a
rarity though chocolate thai
and that certain uh flavor that was on
that it was a leathery tobacco-y uh
chocolaty flavor and
if i could have just had or had the
knowledge or any kind of sense to keep
those seeds man it's insane how many uh
you know pounds of seeds have gone down
the
into the waste because at the time all
the import was just seed bud and we
never thought we would want the
genetics
yeah definitely and i mean just as a
little random side question do you think
it's true that there ever was tai coming
in that had like been altered with opium
or anything like that you always hear
the whispers
this uh
i don't know that economically would be
viable uh for them to do that but i do
believe it had to have happened because
there was uh
it was talked about for sure
i do believe there was opium
uh dusted uh
it said opium dipped he knows what they
call it but it was it was basically uh
a very potent
psychoactive uh product so uh
i never really got my hands on it but i
know people that they swear that it was
uh certainly the real deal and it came
in
yeah definitely i've heard an anecdotal
story from a friend who
said that one of the only times he'd
ever greened out was from
uh some like you know some thai stick
and and to me that it always gave a
little bit of credence to the idea
because a lot of people when they first
have opioids they vomit
yeah certainly uh
it it'll take over your whole uh system
so you're not ready to
be hit by a truck and that's what hits
you
yeah so with all that being said have
you ever looked at some of the kind of
notable thai hybrids and thought oh i
want to get into that like for example
maybe haze given it was like 50 tie at
the end
you know it's always been
a big challenge up here
for um outdoor growing
is really a challenge up here so our
summers are harsh and short so
if you're going to do light depth in
greenhouse you uh you have to have a
program for it it's just devoted to it
for colombians or ties so uh
it's not an impossible thing but most
that's one of the things i've put off
the most i've hardly ever grown a very
very little haze due to that it's hard
to
it's hard to grow it up here
but i have i've always
been super fond of that and want to
relive it and i've i've smoked like
bodies uh you know really good 16-week
tie
at emerald
and uh
it's got a really similar high
but it wasn't that exact same thing that
i'd smoked before so yeah i'd always
like to relive that
yeah certainly i think i know the tie
you were talking about it was that that
pearl tie with like the alternating
calyxes
yeah it was it was kind of yellowish and
uh brown uh not yellowish but um
amberish i should say
and uh brown
and it was just hamstrings tied onto it
onto a uh
bamboo splint is what it was so
they they tore it off for me and
actually gave it to me and i broke it up
but it it it had
qualities and tastes that just
i don't know that will ever be refound
so
yeah i'm chasing that rabbit for sure
yeah it definitely sounds very
interesting let's take it back though
let's start off at that point where you
tried the tie from that point onwards
what made you or were the factors that
led to you then deciding to grow
yourself and how long did it take before
you did do that
it took me a little while about three
years before i uh realized that you
could grow at that point there wasn't a
ton of information
i probably accidentally sprouted a seed
and
went from there but
at the time
after 75
the uh here in alaska the there was a
supreme court decision
with the state of alaska supreme court
and it was called the raven
uh decision and it legalized uh personal
use cannabis here so there was a lot of
ornamental kind of like shrubbery
seeds being thrown out and you could see
people growing uh leaf
type of plants they never flower because
they're summers about 21 22 hours and
sunlight just blaring and then it'll
like shut off to nothing and freeze so
the plants will just start to sex and
maybe three weeks in the flower they'll
just freeze out it'll be solid winter
from then so
the
uh
i was always thinking about growing and
it took me about three years before i
realized it was just something easy to
do
yeah okay and so a lot of people outside
the states may not be aware that alaska
legalized or decriminalized
growing very early on compared to say
california and commonly i get it here
told in the context of yeah they were
almost trying to invite people up there
you know get the population boosted was
that the reason behind it and did it
work
you know it was kind of like opened up
to be a free
free state and um
just uh it wasn't like a move that a lot
of people would have took took this took
up i don't think
but uh
it was viewed as more of a freedom type
of a state and uh what it what the what
happened with the supreme court ruling
is it said that
the right to privacy was stronger than
the fact that marijuana was illegal so
you could have four ounces in your house
and up to 16 plants so
it was just like
so common and when you're having the
mindset of it being legal they did have
illegalities on it which was
transportation and selling of it but you
could gift it
you could never transport it so you know
they'd get you on that uh which was
really silly but
it was so commonplace to just grow
that uh
nobody there was a paranoia for sure
because there was apparent there was
federal uh rules that came into play
after 24 plants you'd be into like
federal felony land and
you just didn't want to go there
yeah most certainly so what was your
first setup like back then when you
first started
well outdoor sun
and uh
i knew about light depth at the time so
you try to just get it in
in september and start covering it up
for
three weeks advanced before the weather
really turns on you and uh
and i wasn't
we had crappy lights and and uh
certainly halides had just come out but
i didn't have a penny for them so
i used the eight foot uh high output
fluorescent lights which is pretty
common grow light back then
and uh super inefficient and
you'd get real stretchy plants and
besides the genetics were you know i
tried to grow colombian inside and end
up being 12 feet tall
sideways and
i realized real quickly that
we had to have something better going on
than that so it i learned very quickly
so what type of genetics did you look to
that would be more well suited to the
environment
well there was plenty of uh
you know by mid 80s there was plenty of
indica that was going around so
up here especially there's always been a
ton of local indicas that were never
named and
if you were going to grow indoor in a
light depth you would get something like
the northern lights
northern lights number one was super
common from about 80
to 85 and uh
there was others that weren't named but
they were just about the same three foot
to four foot tall maximum
bushy christmas tree shaped
solids really solid could support
themselves you know they'd support
their their bud which was heavy
and it'd always be mold resistant and
tended to be
just pretty good straight up easy to
grow indoors so that's that's what we
kind of
aim for pretty quickly
and this this might be a silly question
to some people but i've always wondered
you know given the name northern lights
do you think that there was some sort of
breeding effort put into the actual
northern lights up around the alaska
canadian area or do you think it was
purely just a marketing name
it had to have been a uh a marketing
name either i think it was developed in
the northwest in the seattle area much
more so than it was ever past british
columbia
so i don't think it was up here it only
it only made its way up here
but uh
by the time i saw it it was a mainstay
so
the the name stuck and uh
really really uh probably one of the
best things that ever happened to the
cannabis and that we've come across so
far
yeah most certainly so
let's fast forward a little bit when did
you decide to have a whack at breeding
yourself and what was the first thing
you ever made was it an accident or was
it purposeful
the first time i ever tried to breed now
would probably been um
i've been about 8 18 or 19. i just
thought uh
thought it was a way to advance
any uh any way to get genetics because
there just wasn't seed stock available
so
i would take
whatever uh so-and-so's
feve from from usually it was like
trailer park genetics and
i would cross it over to whatever other
one might have you know uh red petioles
uh stem and uh i would just start making
crosses just by cool looks and smells
right off the bat that was kind of like
my goal
try to breed the best of the best of
whatever we could find and
give it a test run that next batch
and what was the consumer market like at
the time like did you do it because you
knew that it would be unique people
would want to try it or there wasn't
that much push from consumers to say
develop new things
you know up here uh
there was no market such like that um
everybody grew their own smoke or you
would bomb it off with somebody that
that happened to have plenty excess of
smoke
uh so it was it was pretty clandestine
gardens but everybody knew each other
and they knew where there was a supply
of bud around and
we uh
they're really i don't even remember
even selling any bud until like the late
80s you know it was it was pretty unique
where we were just growing it
okay so the scene sounds like it was
kind of focused around the grower what
were the things people were most
interested in was it like as a grower
were people just interested in the
biggest yielding or was it more a
quality focus
yeah it was definitely uh
i'd say a lot of it had to have been
with yield because nobody uh [ __ ] there
was a lot of still a lot of people not
having uh nice big grown rooms there was
a lot of basements that were dug out you
know when they're growing under the
rafters and
you might get a five-foot ceiling out of
that so people were growing
good stocky ass plants and try to get
good yield but
i don't think that we ever
never
ever gave up but had just quality i
don't think nobody ever looked any other
direction but quality
it sounds like the dream almost
well it's kind of crazy it's crazy
because people did focus their own goals
for their own purposes
and uh
everybody basically wanted to make
themselves happy so
before all the competitive uh brand
naming and uh
so-and-so's bud is better than so and so
it was like a cooperative thing and
people were really just trying to
extend the good feeling of the 70s kind
of
yeah okay and so were there any breeders
at that time who you were kind of
looking up to or you were inspired by or
was it still a bit too early for that
uh still a little bit early for that
there was no advertised breeders and
that
the very first that i had ever heard of
was
navel schoenlocker over in
amsterdam in 88
it opened up you know a whole new world
when i realized that there was genetics
that could be
just picked up from a collector
yeah and so this is a question i i love
to ask people where do you hold neville
in the hierarchy of breeders throughout
history is he numero uno for you
you know that's uh
i'd say uh yes because when we were
first involved with them my
partner who's one of the best guys in
the world uh and i don't deal with him
and haven't for 30 years or better he uh
he would hand write letters to
neville and uh
he would it would be you know it might
be a two three month process to get a
return reply but he was steering us and
telling us and
he's like like such a great mentor and
uh
so in that aspect he didn't just collect
and breed but he wanted to spread the
knowledge so i would say he is
yeah most certainly i love that little
bit of aussie pride in that question but
um
so something i wanted to touch on
quickly was when i spoke to him in
person you mentioned this idea of like
up in alaska you guys were very isolated
and you kind of were okay with that in a
way would you mind expanding a little
more on that
we were
you know isolated in quite a bit of ways
to where
we didn't get imports
and when they did make it up here
i would say it'd be a 10-year
hiatus and it might have made itself all
the way around the world before it
actually hit to alaska or
the local region and outlawing you know
towns so
it was um
it was well proven by the time it got
here or it would have just faded out and
uh
when you think about our uh our
isolation it it made us a lot better
growers because there would be like
there's still things that were developed
up here
uh multiple named things that are just
like legends and still up here and um
the same old heads have got them and
still don't generally put it out or even
care to
and
it's amazing that the mentality is is
still nearly the same for 30 and 40
years the people have
kind of kept the mains the same mindset
so it's it's a unique thing
certainly and so
do you think that's still the case does
the
the hype strains make it up there or is
there still that time lag
no now as uh
like you and i are
you know different sides of the world
it's uh
technology is just here
you know i had a couple years ago taken
uh
live cuts
to
emerald
and was actually stopped
by the tsa there are flagged i should
say and then our airport police wanted
to interview me and
it got down to where they when they
wanted to know how much flour i had and
how much concentrate and then they
wanted to know the weight of all the 100
seed packs i carried and i i had come up
with the right answers
you know he asked me where my medical
growth permit was and i told him
it was supposed to stay in the groin
you're not supposed to copy it or it's
fine it's in invalid
everything just was the right answer and
i was under the weight limit for caring
and then he just says okay well what
about the live
cannabis plants and i said well as far
as i'm concerned the law says you can
carry six plants and the tsa
says whatever the state legal limit is
is what you can carry so
he you know he ran me for priors i had
no priors and he's like
okay well if this is all the medication
you need then we'll have a you know have
a good trip and you just like let us
straight go on our way so at that point
and just like you can go to emerald if
you're brave enough to buy uh
you know clones that are available down
there
you can just straight pick up any strain
and bring it back hype strain or
maybe heirloom or
and then
clone shipping
is
not a
big thing now it tends to be that
anybody that
has access to good genetics
you can just get it shipped straight to
you
and
now uh the door is wide open for
genetics up here every day i think
there's
20 new strains coming up here
it's interesting you mention that
because i'm not sure if it was you i was
talking to about this or someone else
but they said
there was a little bit of finickiness
with the clone shipping compared to say
other states in that say you sent it on
the friday and it was going to sit
somewhere over the weekend not only is
that you know not ideal for the clone
but given if it was winter time it could
potentially kill the clone is that a bit
of an overstated fact or is that very
much the reality of the situation
it's pretty common that um you could run
into small glitches i've had
you know half dozen or more uh packages
that would maybe hit during the
california
two or three years in a row man they
were hit with the fires then they were
hit with drought and flood and
they'd shut down county roads and
certain
outlying
towns they might not get a three-day
priority package you could generally
send a clone three days safely in a
clone porter or a clone chipper and
they'll make it but on the seventh day
they don't like to be in the dark that
long and i've had i've had them just one
after the other going to
even
like bob hemphill and the nature farm
and they'd get them and they'd be just
seven days they'd be yellow as hell and
droopy and ready just to die and no way
you're gonna
not gonna talk them back into life and
then in the summertime i think it's
better to ship in the cool season truly
we don't have bad luck in the cool in
the summertime it tends to sweat the
plants a lot more so if you're going to
send them dry tech just snips or fresh
cut tips you know
the dry tech
it works to a certain degree but if they
start to sweat it'll just cook the
foliage and it'll be wilted lettuce or
worse every time
yes certainly i guess it brings its own
challenges
you mentioned a minute ago that some
really old school really awesome strains
were developed up in alaska and they're
still being held by the locals up there
brings us to the question that everyone
knew was coming what's the story behind
alaskan thunder [ __ ] or matanuska
[ __ ]
yeah we know we know that was coming but
uh
there's a lot of stories behind it
so
the experience that i've had with it
was the
1970s and the mid 70s
quite a few uh northern california
emerald triangle uh people whether they
were coming back from vietnam at that
exact point or getting
at the end of the war about 1774
they didn't want to go into that
conflict so some of them went to canada
and some of them ditched out and came up
here and it's a it's a i'm not going to
say there's a bunch of draft dodgers
that just
that filled our state but there was a
lot of people that were you know
patriotic minded but didn't want to go
and uh
fight for some political cause that had
no no wind to it so they they uprooted
and they came up here and what they
brought was um
some bud that was you know it could have
been
originally burmese or crosses of their
import bud that they were growing down
in trinity and and humbled but
it didn't work up here so
within i'd say four or five years there
was no more that tall
structural uh
equatorial i'd say
lowland type of uh
flower upping there was they would
basically outcross it to
the best fastest shortest most
controllable grow plant there is so
a lot of the sativa genetics went out
with it by
1980. there was there was hardly any of
it to be found
interesting and so what's the plant like
itself is it is it more of a stocky one
as you just implied and what's the kind
of the flavor and the highlight
ours stands as uh we have a very old
cutting that
uh i started my job currently right now
in 87 and my foreman at the time
is where i got this and he had it at the
time growing in a quonset head so
it puts it at over 33 34 years old
and
the
plant as it stands these guys never cut
it was a cutting and it's amazing
they had it been taken bottom cuts for
decades on the plant and uh it started
getting a lot of generational
drift and uh
getting really sluggish and uh
woodier and woodier and they didn't have
any common sense to like regenerate that
plant in the sun or
you know try to advance the
upper growth and take cuts and get
better healthier cuts so
about
a long time they grew it like that and
it
you know it's an indica and it once it
are not an indica it grows like like an
affy type of a plant and
it'll get real thick solid base that
could go to two and three inches even
indoor gets this monster base on
it supports great
great amount of bud
it's uh you know super crystally
and it smells like
sweet wine and sweet chocolate it's kind
of a crazy combination because it's like
sangria wine and uh hershey's chocolate
bars with the terps are on it and it
tastes like that too
so um it's a real unique plant but i've
delving into it now by uh
making
bat crosses of itself and i dug into it
and we're finding that the uh
the sativa hybrids are still in there
just it laid dormant in there nobody
really wanted to deal with it now
there's a point to where
i've sent it to uh
you know a couple of guys to play with
like
uh deadpan head and two-tone willy and
they came out with a lot more
hybrid types not as much as the standing
happy that she is so
and i have to i've come up with really
really cool hybrids that and i've even
pulled pure skunk out of it i've
collected a male that's just the
heaviest pure skunk so
um
it's it's crazy to think what could
really be dug up out of the matt newsday
so i guess kind of the last question on
this one is do you think that it was
kind of developed in like a communal
sense kind of in the way that like skunk
was initially developed and if you had
to take a guess what do you think are
some of the genetics in there i mean you
mentioned the burmese and the affy
i would just equate it to being
a pure
trinity county and humboldt we the
flavors are right there real real close
when i used to [ __ ] let's see 1980 you
know humboldt
we would just get bud called humboldt
and uh
it was just a really
killer sweet affy is basically what it
was and you'd get some uh
interesting terps every which way but it
wasn't super skunky or anything it was
just like great great flower like the
like the best cushions that you can get
now
and i think that's uh half of the
genetics and then
there there has to be some uh
thai in there and
burmese because the
what what's coming out of it now is uh
is pretty uniquely
different than the way she stands
yeah okay well if we jump to another
kind of old australian that i know
you've got in the collection tell us a
little bit about your cat piss i wasn't
aware that you actually had that one but
i am aware that they tend to there's a
lot of them basically your cat piss
probably isn't the same as someone
else's so would you mind giving us a bit
of backstory on your one
yeah the uh
cat piss just came our way from imported
puna bud that came shrink wrap from
probably the very first seal of meal in
the world uh right around
85 we were getting just uh some import
bud from hawaii
of all things
and uh
it was some of the best flower that
we've ever smoked too real comparable to
i would say the uh
the what we would call humboldt it was
just a fantastic uh
indica though it was a kush so um
but
it had the craziest terps to it so
we just bred it to northern lights and
for years we had it
and it is still a super unique type of a
plant it's uh
it for whatever reason grows much more
sativa she'll have a very long middle
finger that's about
one third longer or two up to twice as
long as
all the others in the pattern and
it'll grow into this crazy
sativa looking bush
and i've got it in a probably
f2 f3 and then bxes and bx23
and 4 but i recently you know outcrossed
it
to a really ranked
uh catfist that came from california el
jefe gardens he has a
haze that was total cat piss uh indica
haze that uh
is just about it'll make your eyes water
when you're dealing with it when you're
uh
in the flower form
so it's it's really pungent ammoniated
ours is slightly sweeter
but super ammoniated so we couldn't help
but you know put it together and
i think there needs to be a lot more of
the old-fashioned uh
combinations of that terpene being
brought back our hawaiian did have real
unique thin
leafs the leaf isn't thick like it like
a indica leaf it's much thinner uh
and uh
it's a lighter green by far than most
any indica but uh the bud that we did
get for certain was a
really good indica and that's what they
called it too was hawaiian indica so
i've always just called it the hawaiian
indica but uh
as i'm getting to do a lot more digging
into it i'm coming up with a lot more
sativa hybrids
yeah okay very interesting quick shout
out to el jefe great guy one thing i
wanted to ask you though was that you
know this this idea of having these
clones for a while is pretty common
within your collection how do you keep
these clones for so long you know it
seems so common for people to just lose
clones over the years and you've got
like 30 plus year old clones
you have to uh farm
you keep you keep about five
plants with your trusted group
and hopefully uh everybody can cover
each other's bases
because certainly we've all we've all
had situations where we've lost our
mothers
and
my biggest advantage to saving genetics
was not necessarily
keeping a clone alive the whole time i
have a lot of old old old cuttings but
i've got a lot of old old old seeds we
would produce it in the late 80s and
early 90s and i would just preserve it
and
i can go back on it you know at any
point in time
and generally have a
very high success rate just to reproduce
what we were dealing with 30 30 plus
years ago
yeah okay so on the topic of 30 plus
years ago let's talk about that epic old
school northern lights freezer beans i
know you've got a few different freezer
beans but fill me on this one because i
believe your one was different to the
one coastal worked with
it is different um and it's the same too
what mine is is uh
just the standby
typical northern lights one that was
going around
and it was uh just fantastic in every
way i don't think that i still think if
it came out today it would just beat the
[ __ ] out of cookies everybody would just
go wow
such a complex uh
old school hide to it and then the
flavors and
the look and bag of peel covers anything
that the cookies and all of the thousand
cookies crosses are so
uh i had the 85 cut and then in 89 we
purchased the uh skunk
i mean sorry the nl1 from
from scentsy and it was one of our four
picks that year in 89
and it's a three times
inbred
so where his was uh
you know back crossed
to be extremely fast 45 days super stout
super resistant to uh molds and uh it's
almost a bulletproof type of a plant
and uh i crossed a male to my female
cutting and we just had seeds of it so
at the you know i'd grow out the seeds
for sure but i crossed i put them up to
f2 and f3 and then i'd frozen a ton of
it
and uh what i think that coastal
cague's
nl1 is the same thing
i'm thinking it's the exact same 85 cut
that i had but uh
different phenotype his has a lot of the
terpenoline and spray paint phenos
but it still has the same uh
everything on it is identical the resin
the look the structure
um
it's uh it's a real unique type of plant
that
it's so strong and dominant that the
single stemmed
capabilities
can override everything that i've bred
it to i don't think that i've ever seen
anything ever be able to override the
nl1 genetics
yeah wow it says something for dominance
and line breeding right so
a question related to this i want to ask
is when you were doing these early seed
increases or back crosses f2s et cetera
did you do kind of more open pollination
types of things or were you just
selecting one male kind of how more
modern genetics is done
we've always opened pollinated if we can
i mean if there's only one male you know
if you end up with one male
and you're going to reproduce anything
you're going to use that male so i've
been at that point but every time that i
can open it up
i won't open it up and use the weak
genetics there might be a couple real
shitty males that just maybe they might
not even be genetically inferior it
might have been that they were lagging
because they cracked later or they got
more shade or
but i generally take like the top five
to seven uh males every single time
i'm also looking for you know a lot of
high quality lots of different qualities
in the veils but
opening up a
population is a lot better to me than
just to isolating it with one superman
yeah of course of course and so do you
remember the types of things you were
selecting for back then and can you
contrast that for us in terms of what
are the traits you like to select for in
your mail nowadays
there's a big difference
the uh
we were
pretty idiot idiotic i should say on our
selections on our
in the 89 90 years because
i didn't realize the dominance in
the hemp flower everything that we're
basically dealing with if you're going
back you know 10 000 years it's going to
come down from
a fiber
wild
strain of of
flour and
i realized and learned a whole lot in
the first couple years because we would
pick a super male it's what we call a
super male the male that wants to
dominate over everything it'll just be
a foot taller it'll be about a week
faster and in some cases
twice as tall and three weeks faster
than other males and
we would think that male would just be
the tits and we would grab it and breed
it and
i realized after
three generations four generations of
doing that we had actually degraded the
flower to becoming so dominant and
that's you'd get long internals
uh
stretch
uh so it just basically was just
reverting back to hemp and in the fourth
generation of picking a super male like
that it basically
i think you can turn a plant's genetics
faster than anybody thinks you can and
send seven generations you can make a
plant just just be whatever you want it
to be that's that's really what we've
come up with
yeah yeah it's commonly held view that
you know if humans were to disappear off
the planet and we left cannabis to do
its own thing we'd we'd get back to him
pretty quickly so i guess that backs
that idea
yeah and on the contrast view i uh
i'm i've got a lot more insight on what
uh
you know what is what each train is
going to be a lot a lot of difference in
their
values and
i i realize that
you want to get
certain males for certain things and i
do everything a whole different way now
so
it's always just every day seems to be a
you know a new chapter and a learning
experience which is one of the things i
really love about it
yeah sounds very humbling like a lot of
breeders say so let's get a little bit
specific what type of uh attributes or
kind of um tests if you want to call it
that do you do on your mails are you
like a stem rub guy are you more of like
looking at the root zone what things
help you identify a quality male
i know most people are really really big
on stem rub
um
my opinion on stem rub is that it's
valuable but it uh it changes and you
you might find uh day-to-day changes in
males so you can't go by stem rubs so i
would just go on structure
the health of the plant
stem rub
i will generally
breed
a plant and grow it completely out and
instead of maybe reverse a male with
floral or some other hormonal
spray to test to see what type of
female type of traits it will throw like
the uh what pheno it can possibly throw
for terps and and the amount of crystal
and
structure that's one way to check but i
just like to grow a male out and
generally they get
sixth to tenth week they're going to go
fully ripe on you and uh
show you exactly what's available in the
mail so i probably have five different
real big criterias that
they all go go into play but definitely
like to see the final product finish
down
yeah we've heard this sentiment echoed
by a few different breeders and i think
we've only really had two 707 seed bank
and uh
gosh the name is escaping me of the
other breeder who used the florell and
reversed the mail like what you said my
always my question i love to ask in
relation to that is do you find that the
terpene profile you get off that reverse
mail is quite accurate and indicative of
what it will pass on
you know that's a good one right there
because you're inducing it so um
you can change you can change uh
vegetables and fruit so much with any
amount of
hormones so
it's really not a super fair test is why
i don't use the uh the floral i mean
just think how much you can change
ripening of any fruit or vegetable with
ethylene and
gibberellic acids and
that's right on the same line so it's
better i think it's better to go on to a
natural test than to rely on a hormonal
change that you created
yeah okay and so on the polar end of the
spectrum
what do you feel is the role of labs
within breeding do you like to utilize
any of their services or do you still
kind of like to use first principles
well i was uh
i'm a big advocate of analytical testing
i mean i
i think it's it's very very
um
important uh it's also
a lot of times not uh financially viable
so
as uh since we are like crazy addicted
to uh
producing new strains and wanting to
test them out at 80 to 150 dollars per
test which is real cheap compared to
what i hear there's there's very high
testing rates at other places ours is
is relatively inexpensive but when
you're doing 10
10 terpene tests or 10
uh potency and kinematoid profiles
that's 1500 out of your pocket just to
get an answer so
it only makes sense so much but um
i would if i had unlimited amount of
money i would probably put a lot of
stock into it
yeah okay and so maybe a bit of a
redundant question but have you ever
utilized the whole um like you know
finding out the sex of seedlings when
they're still just got their little
petioles or do you just think like nah
just go old school they'll show
themselves soon enough
that's funny because we talk about that
quite a few people are starting to
utilize the uh
the different testing services i know
philos has it and farmer uh
farmer john i think is one of them or
farmer freeman and
i have never done that i i prefer to
just grow the mail because i i consider
that there's some uh genetic potential
it might only be five percent or
something but i still want to kind of
like
roll the dice and see what's there
i do uh
i have done about 80
analytical tests though on different
plants so
i'm like i said i'm a big i'm a big
supporter of it i'm just not uh
financially capable of constantly
testing everything
but when i do narrow something down and
i have to know we we test it
yeah yeah good good sentiment definitely
so when you are testing out some seeds
you've made how many seeds you like to
pop to get a good idea of what's going
on within the line
i like what i like and what i can do are
way different i like to do 300 at like a
minimum and then i get a pretty fair
answer
um
at a minimum 10
and that doesn't give you a whole lot of
answers unless your genetics are like
super inbred or
if they're so focused and you know
exactly what they are
you can
get a lot
you can get a lot out of uh smaller
batches
yeah definitely so
this is a bit of a devil's advocate
question but let's just say you had a
strain that you were liking the results
in terms of what you were finding inside
of it but you rather consistently found
that you get a hernia every say three
packs so you know one really definitive
herme every 30 seats
does that like rule it out for you or do
you still think that there's potential
you just maybe warn people that that is
a possibility like how do you feel about
that one
that is a good question because i think
that super worthy genetics would be um
you know i don't think that that's going
to be a problem one in 30 if you are
if the people that are getting the
genetics from you are wanting it because
it's such a good plant they are going to
deal with it and
you know a bunch of people that don't
really know what they're doing and
grow kind of improperly or stress their
gardens too much and might have high
occurrences of hermes i would i would
just talk to them ahead of time and uh
which is near impossible if they're
buying it out of a seed bank but if you
tell them ahead of time what's going on
that's really not a bad number but if
the genetics are just mediocre and
you're getting that it's totally
unacceptable it should be standout
genetics or
the answer is no
well that brings us to an interesting
question how do you feel about strains
that have a little bit of controversy
surrounding them
you know i'm not super familiar
because i'm not a uh
i'm not the type of guy that follows any
drama and uh
for a lot of time i've dealt only with
certain genetics so i wouldn't uh
necessarily study or know a lot of
people's
creations or what they're famous for or
what they hurt somebody else's butt over
or
uh you know i just don't keep up with it
and i get told this by a couple of very
knowledgeable young people that are like
strain fiends and they they just know
everything so
i uh
i have no problem probably using
somebody's genetics like that but i
would want to go back to the person that
they
double crossed and uh
i'd be straight with them first because
i'm not the guy that goes out um
i'll go out of this world with my name
you know that's basically i'm not going
to go around being talked bad about so
i have no problem working certain lines
but uh i would avoid it if it's just too
much controversy i don't see the value
in it
yeah most certainly i mean kind of the
most high profile incidence of that is
res dog are you familiar with that case
and would you use res dogs genetics if
you had something you liked
that is a real good question there too i
am
i'm getting old enough to quit being so
spiteful but i was for my whole life the
type that would cut off my nose to spite
my face so i'm gonna avoid a lot of
situations and not uh
not go to that point but i knew all
about what happened with res dog
and then
so that gives me a kind of a low opinion
of the whole thing and somebody had sent
me a pack of his uh
aj sauer diesel
v3 so i grow this [ __ ] out two of them
are basically like uh
they're not poly
poly polyplopiloid but they oh they were
like horrible violet taxi and uh
one was a herme and then the other two
like sucked [ __ ] so
res dog can kiss my ass
sorry my doctor you might have to edit
that
if you're happy with it i'm happy with
it that just kind of came out i told you
that might come out something like that
but uh
you know like i gotta pee i gotta hold
people
you know
for their standards and if your genetics
suck and you're a piece of crap then you
know that's that's just it
certainly know that a lot of people um
have done good with this his uh work
yeah well i mean it's a great little
segue onto camdog you know kemdog is a
focal part of the show and indeed modern
cannabis history where does kem dog sit
in the grand scheme of things to you and
do you have any plans to try to work
with it going forward
that might be the best question that you
ask me because uh
i'm i am uh
i recently
met
say
you know lucky
dog uh skunk va and i've known i've
known uh duke for a while and uh
[ __ ] duke send me some uh kim cross
maybe a couple years ago when i grew it
and i you know i didn't think too much
of it i had never been experienced with
kim period at all
and this is going to be a little bit
harsh and
i might get people to hate me because
they're followers of the people but in
in the high time san bernardino cup in
i wanted to get a handle on what cam was
and the cat that i'm
running around with his uh his ig handle
is
uh 907 or falcon or 907 and this kid has
a
you know 150 000 to two hundred thousand
dollars worth of genetics that he's
collected and
he intends to maybe start up or
uh using it someday i don't know what
the hell he's doing with it now but he's
collected it and you know it's been a
fortune to collect it so he knows every
single person
in and the back stories that's who i go
to for information and
he's carrying me around
and i go i want to smoke some i didn't
know what gorilla glue was or had a
whole list of stuff i didn't have no
idea what was so
he went over to jj at uh top dog i do
believe and uh introduces and we were
all talking and jj like had a pre-roll
or something maybe he rolled i can't
really remember because i'd smoke like
20 joints but
we start smoking and it's my little
partner ak rizzo and uh
and falconer and and uh
jj and we're smoking up and man the
third or fourth hit around the
big ass seed pops out of that [ __ ] and
it blows up like a grenade and uh which
you don't normally see a lot of usually
you'll see them like fume out like a
little volcano but that [ __ ] popped and
it's like oh that shit's arch and i
nobody you know really wanted to smoke
it and it's like oh no we're good to go
i'll roll another one out of my stash i
go no no we're good you know we rolled
on and it's such a poor example of what
my first my first chem dog was like oh
so that's that that's not really uh
you know real happy feeling
and uh
then and emerald that same year
i was over there talking with uh he goes
by montana roy now you know uh cody and
uh yeah over at dukes and uh duke
disappeared maybe to get a smoke or
something and uh he he goes man you
you check out this cam dog
or yeah chem dog i think it was but uh
he gives us a bunch of his flowers he
gave us like
you know the he had killer flowers that
that year he had the like
dominion skunk and the granny skunk and
uh the local h and i think the dominion
or the uh capital g and
he had such stinky ass bud pole cat and
uh he gave us some of that cam and i
just sat right there and rolled it up
and uh
second or third hit
of that [ __ ] going around i realized
what cam was it's like oh they hit me
between the eyes and i was like okay it
overrode
probably 15
other times that smoked and i realized
that you know cam's pretty serious
pretty serious but so it's a good thing
to judge by it's got rankedness to it
it's got bag appeal
it's it's a good standard to uh compare
a lot of things to but i'm i'm so
inexperienced with it first time ever
that i was able
to get my hands on it and do something
with it was like you know uh this year
emerald uh
skunk va gave me a nice handful of the
crossroads kim and we were smoking the
[ __ ] out of it and it's really great but
so um
i like it a lot but i'm not going to go
down that road
what could i do with kim
that hasn't been done and then there's
people that are specializing in it so
there's no sense in
i wouldn't say competing with them
because i don't i don't necessarily
compete with people i'd make something
equal or as good and then you know share
it with them
but
i'd say that there's a lot of people
specializing in kim and i don't need to
go down that road at all
and that's a really kind of mature
mindset to have and definitely a huge
shout out to cody and skunk ba i love
all the skunk fam crew i'm just out of
curiosity do you remember which cam you
tried was it the 91 or maybe the d
it was chem d that's what it was
i'll tell you what um there was a couple
people standing there on that third
round when the when the joint came back
and uh
they backed out and didn't take a fourth
drag off of it because the [ __ ] was
starting to affect them heavily so
that's a good that's a real good uh
standard to go by that's what i think
yeah certainly and i mean it's probably
a bit of a no-brainer but if anyone
including yourself ever gets the chance
to try some 91 from skunk va do not pass
up that opportunity
oh i would put it in my library and uh
i'm i think i've been offered
you know he was he's always been really
a great guy i don't know him super well
but he's always been super generous and
offered me things but i never took them
up on it but i would keep it in my
library and uh
i guess that finest uh
cut that was going around the chem
what was it um candy at the emerald this
year
i know a couple people that grab that so
i might uh
i might snatch that up even though it's
not the 91
yeah i mean heck the d is uh really
comparable to the 91 in many ways i
always thought of it as though it's not
quite as potent like maybe if the chem
91 is kind of like a hundred out of a
hundred impotency the chem d is like
somewhere between 90 to 95 but the taste
and the yield are much better so
commercially it kind of makes a bit more
sense
yeah well i know uh
mr bob grabbed up one of them he said
his was doing real good and um
he was going to prove it out but i had
heard from second-hand sources that uh
peabud mike
confirmed that that was the real uh
candy so
i don't think you can go wrong
yeah it's hard given there's so many
different chemds at least three i know
of and um it's there's there's varying
voices vouching for each but i mean heck
if peabod mike is vouching for one that
that definitely stands for something
well i'm i heard it second hand so i
can't say but you know i was real lucky
to to be in the middle of the
conversation with uh skunk va tommy and
or you know duke and a couple of the
other guys that were actually at emerald
and uh a.k.a rizzo and i happened to
just pop in at that moment and uh
duke grabs up skunk va and tells him to
come over because they're gonna settle
this thing right now on provenance on uh
who had what on this
chem d so
it's like oh i need to hear this
inducible i don't know this is kind of
private conversation so we instantly
just sucked up like flies on the wall
and listen to it and at that point it's
so valuable to get you know five of
people that are like
you know the holders of it and then all
you hear is well i got it in 91. you
gave it to him in 93. it came from him
okay you're right it did that's the
exact source i'm wrong and then [ __ ]
just gets squared out right then and
there and
the provenance is like so well set on it
that
that's one of the best things about that
right there
i'm really i really really get lucky to
get a hang with guys like that
yeah most certainly i um i've been
really grateful to have had a few
conversations like that i remember the
first time i was at emerald cup
um just out of nowhere not so dog kind
of tapped me on the shoulder and
introduced himself and it was like oh
awesome he's able to reveal a few things
to me which was very interesting because
he's tied into more things than you
might know of
you know it's funny with uh
with him that um i've got friends that
had used him as good good friend and
librarian and holder of keepers trains
and
he is he is the further i
see his got his hands all over and you
know
i've got a really good friend that uh
knows him but that's who held
el hafiz
uh
that hayes cat piss
and el jefe did not have it and during
the fire
lost everything so uh
they thought it was gone forever but not
so dog held it and uh
sativa seed stash uh leaf he was able to
go snatch that that thing up get the
cutting up so now oh happy's got his uh
cat piss either coming back home or has
it back and
it's it's so valuable to have somebody
like not so dog holding
you know might be years later but when
it comes into play
it's it's an incredible value to
everybody involved
yeah most certainly and so him and bob
hemphill i think in my mind are the two
really notable librarian figures so to
speak
if we just jump over to bob for a minute
um i noticed on your instagram feed
you've got some mtf cross nl1 and i
think you mentioned in the comments it
was given to you by bob was that the
case or was it like you did he make it
and give it to you or did you make it
and do something with it how does that
all tie together
no on that
that's my mtf in my nl1 i uh
i have given bob my mtf
and uh
he could certainly have my nl1 or close
to the standing what i have right now to
it with no problem but
that's just something that i made up i
had to use nl1 to uh
i had to do something to
get seeds for matanuska [ __ ] and
there's really
probably no better choice so that's what
i used
yeah okay so i mean on that same kind of
train of thought your feed it's
essentially like a gold mine in terms of
all the different genetics on there and
the next thing which popped up to kind
of sprink my ears up was the northern
lights haze hybrids i think they were tk
northern lights haze hybrids
what's the backstory behind that and
what do you want to kind of do with
those
i'm glad you're that observant i know if
i knew what you know at your age like
you're an incredible you know human
being especially for your age i i uh i
value you a lot so
just you have insight beyond a lot of
others
and that being said uh
that's that's a real real real special
thing right there that the t channel 5
hayes
we've been able to work with it for a
long time
my original waco in the 80s
we never knew what it was it's a local
plant
but it has to be
nl5 haste and we never knew it looks
looks every single thing about it like
the cover photo of the
8990 scentsy catalogs and
we didn't buy it from novell because uh
it looks so ratty on the cover photo
funnier than [ __ ] that we would pass on
something due to looks but uh
i've been able to get
nl5
haze from uh
i think uh mean gene grew
some in 98 from uh a
friend of his in england so
might have been his first breeding or
first
it could have been his first breeding i
know it was his first nl kind of cross
so uh
he did a seed increase and he gave me
some of that seed and then when i grew
on i
i thought they were pretty cool they're
super nl5 dominant but i just recently
crossed that tkno5 haze male
to that nl5 haze to
kind of do a back cross on it and
go that route but uh
as it stands tkno5 haze is
and this is going to go on record but
this is the
uh
the finest
and best and strongest cannabis that i
have come across
in two decades
wow that's a big claim
yeah i hate to i hate to uh
go around and keep repeating myself but
i have told
all my local old heads
my partners and and
all my uh testers all are on board and
100 don't they
they're not taking anything for granted
on the deal but uh
i've sent it out to a bunch of people
that are
they need to be amazed
and if you did
get sent the tkno5 haze i don't care if
it was the nl dominant or the tk haze
dominant or a cross of it i wouldn't
sleep on it because it
oh man going out on the limb here but i
do believe it's all of what kim ever was
and uh it tastes better
yeah well that's exciting just quickly i
just want to say thanks so much for
those kind words i really appreciate
that um but i guess does it go without
saying that this is the next type of
line you're looking to work more or has
already been done
you know what's been done but i just
don't see where this bottleneck that's
created with 1000 cookie strains is
going to go from here it's not going
anywhere it's uh
it's going to revert back to
uh
a lot of heirloom and
i say even a lot of land race genetics
are going to get re-added back for a lot
of different reasons
might not be uncontrollable hard to grow
wild strains but there's going to be a
lot more need to uh
to try to you know break the bottleneck
and
it has been done ten ways to sunday for
sure nl5 haze but if you consider it
like this uh
one of the one of the most knowledgeable
and uh
trustworthy and uh
old heads that are out there be ed
rosenthal you know he he had a good
opinion of uh nl5 hayes being the most
potent uh
smoke that he'd ever come across and it
was like his favor you know and then if
you go on facts like
dynasty relic seeds has uh
he has a yeah it has a 27
19 year old cut of the cough and i'm i'm
imagining it it's the fort collins cough
or the you know it was it was named the
cough but it was uh
i think in uh
probably uh
produced right out of fort collins but
i've heard it called the texas cough and
other things too but it is the same
thing and
it's an outstanding
nl5 hay so i was able to send pollen
of my tkn05 haze to
relic and he got a breeding done and
being the gentleman that he is he sent
me one over half of all of the seeds
which just you know totally amazes me i
probably uh
i could probably shout out to him uh
as being one of the uh
more heartfelt uh people that i've come
across in the industry so uh
uh he's he's a really good guy but we
created a monster right there that uh
it's something else so uh that's
something in the works
but
the tkno5 haze i'm going to work it 10
ways to sunday right now and
it's going to be
the next thing if you if you got a high
if you have a high tolerance to most
profiles right now
this will take care of the problem
it's uh
you know it's a 20-second onset type of
a plant that hits you like a brick and
it's not that dizzy spacey uh high like
the
durban tie high flyer or tie or durbin
or any of the uh super heady
like flying your head on a kite string
type of thing this stuff hits you like
way different it's an anti
it's a diavasculator
very very very heavily as like a medical
diavascular so you get zero blood
pressure
in your brain so if you're smoking a big
head event hold it it could uh it could
floor you many many many people busted
their heads on coffee tables or
uh whatever hard object that's nearby
it's it's a dangerous animal you know
it's no joke i've told this to like a
bunch of people and they just like in
one ear and out the other because they
don't think such things exist but i
think that
in in navel's uh description of the nl5
he said experienced smokers were
you know having uh urination and
defecation and they lose bodily control
over smoking this [ __ ]
yeah um it's a fact this stuff does
medical uh
properties beyond any normal weed so uh
it is definitely something that i'm
gonna dig dig a 10 foot ditch
into
yeah i can 100 attest to
some of those claims certainly certainly
not the
the loss of bodily function but i mean
when i was at bodies place most recently
i was lucky enough to try some c5 haze
which is the neville's keeper cut of
northern lights haze and jesus i've
never been that high before it's truly
something special so i'm gonna have to
chase you up on your one because that's
that's truly interesting but
now is the time for us to shower our
buddy dr p and some love you know how
did you first get introduced to dynasty
genetics and what's your favorite strain
by them
wow that's
that's a good one uh
i
was
totally
disconnected from internet for 20 years
so
i was anti and uh
when i did realize
well let's see about 12 or 13 years ago
really i realized that there was so many
forums and that there was
on those forums there was like seed bank
information and once i started like i
had a dozen favorites and all of it was
i started to be getting addicted to it
and
uh it's it's something that happens to
everybody right but then uh
i i started to see
opinions on what was what and i did buy
some old
seed stock right then but the professor
priyan dynasty came along about
maybe three maybe about four years ago
but rocky mountain seed bank i just saw
that they had
a release of of
platinum huckleberry cookies and
i'd never seen cookies
i heard about it and i thought i would
never want to have nothing to do with it
because uh
people are saying it's a low yielding
super elite and uh you know i'd like to
let it go it's uh run its course i'd
like to you know ten years later i might
pick it up
so uh
but that one sounded real interesting
and uh
i i just got a pack of that from the
rocky mountain uh
seed bank i don't even
know that that's an existing seed bank
right now it was a little tiny uh
man and wife operation i think but they
treated me super right and
seeds made it
i grew them i got um
everything on it was awesome i got two
og
kb
dominant uh
versions a super male and a super female
the male like turned super black
tons of resin
uh probably the nicest uh ogb tape uh
i mean kb uh type of uh plant that i've
come across for a male
and then the females were just like
super good so for three or four years i
i just been in love with the
i don't even know how i might have
shouted him out one time and he hit me
back on a friday night and told me to
you know chill and have a good weekend
and
slowly we kind of talked and um
he no whatever boiled down to we became
friends and
he's a stand-up guy so
not enough can be said about him being a
good guy
yeah no i agree i've got so much love
for that guy i probably can't put it in
words but i guess uh kind of by virtue
of what you said the platinum huck is
your favorite strain from them
i i can't say that now um
you know uh his
the pineapple fields is outstanding
everything that he's made has got
something special going on uh the blue
magoo was uh really
nice i know that the um
huckleberry the um
the what is it i've got about a pack of
everything that he has he has sent me in
but the vanilla
cherry cookies is is off the hook
really a good keeper really good smoking
um
so i don't i don't think that i really
have a favorite of his i think that he
has proven all of his to be really well
there's not like no duds in it so each
one has a pretty good
uh thing going for even
you know everything he crosses is pretty
well thought out and done upright so
his males are outstanding and then his
females you know speak for themselves so
but i tend to smoke a lot of that i do
smoke a lot of the platinum uncle berry
cookies
of course of course just as a little
personal thing i've i've grown the plat
huckleberry cookies out before and i
loved it something i noticed was it it's
such a short stocky plant you know did
you have any tips to how to get around
that because i just i could never get it
to stretch at all you know that cookies
were so dominant
we have the opposite with one of ours
it's has to be caged it'll have 20
20 and 30 uh tentacle branches that want
to go it'll go off like nuts so i've
crossed it with things like lemon tree
and
central core with strong centers and
slower growing to
to just slow it down but we have one
that
it's og
kb
dominant it just grows
nice central
you can make it to be six and eight tops
easy enough and uh it's real easy to
grow and fast growing so now is that was
the version one the v3 now is a stockier
slower growing one at bush here
but he says that it dominates more
towards the oregon huckleberry so it's
faster in flower
and a little bit better flavor towards
the uh the huckleberry
but it's slow i have some four month
olds that are just stocky as hell
they're wanting to look like um
like little trees
so it's slower if you think yours was
slow i'm i don't know that it was the b3
it's
it's uh you can you can hang ornaments
on it when it's christmas time though
because it's that sturdy
oh yeah no i definitely definitely had
that nice strong branching for sure and
i should clarify i didn't mean that in a
particularly negative way i just was
kind of wondering if you had any tips or
tricks for it but on that same line of
topic i noticed you have a little sub
forum on matt riot's forums that's an
interesting one how do you strike up
your friendship with matt we love matt
on the show we're always interested to
hear how people met him
that is a good one too because i didn't
know who he was and uh
you know i think he uh oh i know how is
that i had uh you know i had offered a
little bit
on the instagram of the old seed catalog
collections and uh
he
you know being that he's got the history
and at least like i'd say 14 going back
15 years even working with navel and and
uh you know the whole backstory there um
it uh
he hit me up for them catalogs and it's
like wow old head i imagine this this
dude's 50 years old and old head and he
wasn't what i
you know when you when you meet him face
to face he's certainly not what what
your first impressions are but i asked
uh falconer my my buddy who's the uh
he's the go-to for information
who's this riot cat he says oh man that
guy man he got a lot of controversy man
he'll bring up but he
he's he's honest and he's straight and
you put you you put uh
he'll put a [ __ ] on blast
yeah oh yeah it's like
like okay i need to check one of these
live feeds out this cat has and um he
shouts me out big time on there for um
for the catalogs and
it went from there he sent me you know a
ton of seeds and a
bunch of packs of like reservoir uh
strawberry diesel
f3s or whatever the [ __ ] that bruce
banner came out of you know he sent me
packs and packs of it and it's like well
i thought maybe you'd want to sell it or
auction it off or something
and it's like oh
he is a good guy
he'll uh he'll stand up for the right
and um
and that's it if if your [ __ ] needs to
go on blast that's the guy to
talk to because he's knowledgeable and
and
he's a dick but man he's a dick in a
good way
yeah i love i love bodhi's analogy he
says he's like the pit bull and we need
the people to go off at people sometimes
yeah people that's the best analogy and
from a good guy too because you think
about it
bodhi is too nice of a guy and people
might
i'm not going to say that he's
non-confrontational he might know he
might be a seventh degree black belt
brawl i know and like
kill you in two seconds but
he i don't think that he's gonna go
busting somebody's balls because they
did him wrong and then you know matt
ain't gonna let that [ __ ] happen so
um he'll go out of his way
to you know make [ __ ] right and i i know
for sure there's another side of that
and a p a lot of people um
[Music]
take it or leave it i don't give a [ __ ]
what they think about me uh
so
i just kind of like to uh
stay straight with everybody but [ __ ]
matt's a good guy to go to for knowledge
and uh
he's way more into the uh
breeding knowledge for femmes and stuff
so if i have any kind of questions and
[ __ ] like that that i need to know i
would be right to him on that
yeah i definitely wanted to add we
definitely get matt back on the show for
a catch up he's always got some funny
anecdotes to say but just looking back
to a different post i saw on your
instagram i noticed that professor p had
sent you some kind of cbd stuff from new
relic lines and i noticed that you
mentioned you've got your own kind of
cbd thing going on would you mind
telling us a bit about your cbd project
yes it's uh
it's pretty uh
it's pretty ongoing and
you know getting to be widespread
because
basically
about march of
i was like
affected very badly by
something i didn't know what it was
we've done you know
literally
a thousand tests i thought i might be
dying from heavy metal poisoning from
painting cars for 30 years or i thought
i might just be dying from whatever i
was dying so um
we got it diagnosed after
tons of trying and it just turned out to
be a form of r a and it's called
polyarthritis so it's like
one of the worst forms of ra it just
hammers your joints so
i was about 80 percent disabled it was
it was
it was ugly i mean no putting on i
couldn't do my belt or put on socks or
[ __ ] that was it was bad
i'd rather just about uh
roll up in a ball and [ __ ] die
because of pain
and we ended up getting it into
remission i went to a
specialist and
first my doctor just put me on you know
opiates and [ __ ] uh
methotrexate
not methotrexate at that point just
gonna be steroids because he's like a
general practitioner yeah so uh
we got i went to the um rheumatologist
and he gets me straightened out off of
uh tell me to suffer it out swell up
like he'll come back in pain and then
he'll tell me what's up and we did go
straight for uh he tried two or three
different little concoctions and
nothing worked he instantly gets me on
an injection of methyltrexate and then a
diloxatine
which is like a uh
pain blocker but it's more
it's diagnosed for um
depression so
it just makes you happy about your
[ __ ] arthritis so it's um
it might be the better drug but yeah
methyltrexate puts i got that and i get
it in remission to where i could go back
to work and uh i worked through the
whole time but it was brutal you know it
was it was truly one of the harder
things i've done in my life
and
i realized that cbd could take that
swelling out like crazy so i was buying
and checking out different cbd flowers
and
we ended up trying ac dc and pennywise i
think that um
northstar
might been who was breeding it for a sub
cool but i tried a couple different ones
and it turned out that the stuff had an
actual medical effect to it and um my
wife has crohn's disease fierce and has
had ileostomy so if she has like a
terrible
flare up the stuff could work wonders
for um internal inflammation reduction
and uh
such a good thing cbd so i realized that
it's some road that we have to go down
and then i started collecting
a bunch of the best examples that i
could get so you know ac dc
i uh
got a decent 20 to one i got a i got a
couple from the nature farm uh his api
apathetic purple indica to 15 uh 3 to
15. everybody always says 15 to 1 and
you know they got it backwards so
um
i generally say it the way it's supposed
to be his is a 3 to 15 and
i got can of montana from uh
king jay out of uh
out of montana there uh his cannon
montana is a really nice one um
but we probably got 15 different ones so
willie g's lebanese
the thing can go um easy
one to twenty
and uh
you know monster uh lebanese plants that
can just be crazy uh have all the good
things of the wild uh lebanese
and uh i don't know if it'll adapt well
to the indoor gardens but uh that and
that charlotte's gift from relic that
you mentioned that charlotte's gift is
uh
you know charlotte's web and ringo's
gift i think he has it to an f3 when he
gave it to me so
i asked him if he minded that um you
know we use the males and you know he's
doesn't uh doesn't care and
again he's the best guy in the world but
that's going to be uh
one of the components so
my goal is to just make something that's
about 10 to 20. that'd be to me a one to
two uh
and then
i want it to be
something that makes me happy
which would be the main goal with most
people smoking flower right you
definitely want something pleasurable
yeah of course so what do you predict
will be the future of the cbd orientated
strains especially given there's this
sentiment within the community that the
kind of the patients who are really in
need of the cbd have kind of been left
behind now that legalization has come
and passed
that's a that's a real uh problem
because it has come to that uh
cbd flowers not something that uh people
you know i always think indoor growing
but down
down in a lot of areas it's legalizing
now that they're not relying on indoor
growing they're relying on um
light depth or greenhouse or outdoor
growing and
they won't blow
much or any of their time and genetics
or garden or or whatever it takes to
make a decent amount of medicine
so it's going to just boil down to
large industrial hemp type of operations
for people to get medications i'm not
thinking that it's the worst thing in
the world because it's come a long way
and the cbd
plants that uh i'm going to give another
shout out right now and this is a good
one to do it too it's a cloud cove farms
on instagram has a
full spectrum cbd that's available and
they have their own products it is uh
it's all
packaged
and for sale in individual doses and at
retail shops but they're also a company
that's willing to sell
at the wholesale level and then
fairly small doses you can buy
a 100 gram uh
that's probably the lowest um
price break that you get but 100 grams
of their full
spectrum distillate
is ten dollars a gram
and it's one of the best medicines i've
ever come across
it it actually has a fairly high amount
of thc in it where if you're not a
smoker you're going to be
much more
recreationally medicated than you're
wanting
and
it is just enough to make the cbd work
and it also has every other cannabinoid
in it and the terpenes so
their uh product is one of the best i've
ever come across they're not they're not
out to be
you know the corporate king and uh
they've expanded from one size operation
to the next without
killing the little guy
and leaving the opportunity open
and i do believe last year he planted
almost 100 acres it went from a small
deal but he still has his indoor
greenhouses over the winter and he's
showing 100 love 100 of the time so uh
as long as he can sustain that guys like
that are
that's where all of the uh
i think medical benefits are probably
going to end up it's not going to be
flour for the people but it's still
going to be a high quality full wide
spectrum
cannabinoid uh distillate he has isolate
also but you know isolate
doesn't work the same as distillate in
the full spectrum is better than
anything so
there's a lot of value to people like
that
yeah well you just banged out my next
question which was going to be what do
you think is the most medicinal of all
the uh the type of you know full
spectrum extract et cetera et cetera
that uh that thing contends with
anything because you can uh it's such a
good high quality product to say that
you're into extracts and you might do
dabs on a on a quartz dab rig or
something uh
it tastes really good and uh
it's a very quick onset medically when
you're doing a dab the the length of it
isn't going to last you as long but his
products are so good that it it tastes
great and
you near grab the wall it's it's very
potent so
i wouldn't say you could comfortably
uh most people wouldn't want to work and
and be doing a bunch of dabs of it it's
that potent on the white cannabinoid
you know full spectrum side of it so
it's the best medicine but it's also
it's a really good uh mixture to where
it really does work it's it's it's a
real i wouldn't say a perfect because
somebody in a lab is definitely going to
make something that could be
get right past the blood brain barrier
and uh
and be the top of the line through you
know through lab work and
engineering but for just a natural
product his is is
it's pretty top of the line i've never
met anybody that doesn't get on board
when they find out about it
yeah okay sounds like good advice so
if we just loop back to a
topic we were talking about before i
remember you were you're talking about
cookies you know where do you think
it'll go i noticed that you've been
working with this f3 durbin and my
thoughts are now that you've played with
the durban a bit do you are you more
convinced or less convinced that it's
actually a part of the cookie genetic
makeup
i'm
you know
i'm convinced that it's nothing to do
with it
um my durbin is not there durbin for
sure so um and there's plenty of uh
different durbins but
this is original sssc's durbin stock and
uh
i could breed it 10 ways to sunday and i
don't believe i'm getting cookies
so uh
i i think that maybe uh
cookies is probably just like
hindu kush and northern lights
and
that's probably really all it is
yeah certainly that hindu kush ideas
been thrown around a bit especially
given that you can get these kind of
real savory bakery shop type of things
out of hindu kush easily
that and my nl1
leaf pattern
in its extreme form is identical to
the most extreme og kbb leaf pattern
so if i can go back
to 1985
and have a leaf pattern with [ __ ] loads
of [ __ ] photographic evidence
and i can reproduce it right now on an
og kb
it tells me a lot
yeah most certainly most certainly i
mean i think inspector from csi has said
something along those lines about when
you do s1s of mendo perps you likewise
get that same phenotype and you know
mendo purposes sorry not mendo purple
urkel my apologies when you when you s1
purple urkel you get that ogkb pheno and
i don't think anyone would deny that uh
purple urkel's probably got some nail or
you know some pure afghanica in it right
i would say it has to i've never been uh
i could think of ten
strains straight up um that i didn't
have experience with because it never
made it up here during the uh
i'd say
85 to 2005 so
if it wasn't in my hands i didn't need
it i'm that kind of guy that doesn't
look for a greener pasture and
very happy with what i'm working with so
i never saw a purple oracle until i mean
the very first time i had anything to do
was 12 years ago with quirkle and that's
half
purple urkel and then since then i've
heard stories that have been you know
put out that it wasn't even half purple
oracle that it was
it was a
a lavender hybrid so uh
i had no experience with purple urkel
but recently i did and do have and
it's a really unique lamp the leafs one
mine want to point upwards all the time
it has a very uh nl uh
dominant leaf pattern even though it'll
go to like easily go to 11 fingered
leaves and i never got 11 fingered
leaves ever off of nl
and
but it's a super unique type of plant so
it's uh
it's coming down from that line uh
it's crossed to something though so uh
and it happens to be that mine is a f2
of uh the csi's purple oracle too so but
it it's a fantastic thing that he
preserved and has passed on too
it's um
it smells good in veg it's one of the
things like like i'll go back to i like
weed that it's pleasurable that's like
most of the reason that i make flour and
love flour because i love to be pleased
by good flour i love smoking so
i can't wait until uh
i have big piles of that purple oracle
flower
yeah yeah definitely the that end
feeling of consuming the flower is
definitely
definitely worth the effort but uh you
brought up an interesting point you know
as time goes by there's certainly been
at least in the past year or so a bit of
controversy surrounding tga
and our buddy sub cool but with that
being said you know i think most people
have a strain that they hold somewhat
near and dear that comes from tga like
for me personally i got a brilliant i
got two brilliant cuts of chernobyl that
i just adore i'll never never give them
up no matter how much controversy
surrounds the name do you have anything
like that that you know near and dear to
your heart from tga
you know i do i have a lot of love for
old tga because they uh
they put some really good combinations
together
i think that blood wreck was probably
the best thing that they made and things
down from blood wreck are off the hook i
was uh
i was completely blown away when i was
able to get a crazy train
original crazy train about um
it was about 11 years ago
and i think i got it from the
the hemp depot of all places because
that place is as shady as [ __ ] and uh
the uh what i got was good and um i fell
in love with tga because of that i also
had space jill at the time the actual
what they called space jill and that's
what they were selling it as and
it was exactly like their description
uh
it's a little bit too much of a biomass
for me but still
it was a great uh
producer so i crossed it to chocolate
this this is a long time back now um
going on
at least 11 years and uh
i crossed that to chocolate that space
jail and i call it tropolo that's a
fantastic
thing that i've made i just recently uh
passed that down to miss jill and uh
she didn't want it when she was with tga
and uh
you know they were doing their own thing
but um another really really impressive
uh
thing that tga they had a limited
release
of
locomotion it was called by heroes of
the farm
uh pat did a really good job making that
it's blue city diesel bret ii
time wreck
and i don't know how many packs went out
but um
i guess quite a bit
i was at subpool's house at uh
in 17 in the summer and uh he was open
in a box that came in from pat
and had 20 one ziploc bag had 20 000
locomotion seats in it but he also had
quite a few backups of a couple others
but the total uh at two dollars a seat
it was a
sixty thousand dollar uh check he had to
cut over to pass so i mean that's his
personal business i shouldn't be talking
about it but i know that
quite a bit of that locomotion seed was
produced and still is getting produced
but
they had it understated on their on
their uh profile
and i instantly told subcool that that
thing had to be changed to over the top
over the top uh terps and uh
i don't know if it's uh
all good coming from the blue city
diesel or if it's the mix with the time
wreck but uh
that's uh that's something that i can't
live without on a daily basis too i keep
it at all points in time since i've got
it and
i breathe
it quite a bit because it's one of my
only true purples i get uh i get insane
color from it
but the the flavor and the high it only
tested out it uh
i had a couple of them i tested
analytically one was 13.8 that's the one
i keep
but the terpenes were very high on it
and uh with the pro the profile of the
terpenes and that that cannabinoids the
way they are
it hits like a 25 of anything that just
has that that thc spike and
it's it's a pretty great thing so tj's
put in their time whether they've uh
you know whether they've kind of
gone and done different things than
they've done in the past and you follow
them or not there was a lot of good
value to it if you found an old package
of like oh five third dimension i would
certainly crack it so
there was a lot of good stuff
oh yeah some of that uh apollo work they
did was definitely of value but while
we're on the topic what are some of your
favorite old school seed companies
whether they be around anymore you know
it doesn't matter you know they might be
defunct they might be still operating
but what are some of the old ones you
loved
that's that's kind of weird for me
because for 20 years i didn't know that
they existed and when i did find out
about 12 years ago that the internet was
you know available i mean i was like
i could give a [ __ ] about the um the
internet i i basically want to uh
live my life and never have to ever go
on it
and now i'm uh
i utilize it for uh instagram and if i
had to order something off of amazon
it's it's pretty handy or uh you know
look up a strain review you can find out
some instant information other than that
i don't need it so when i did find out
there was companies available and i i
dipped into it a little bit
one of the first things i liked was uh
dna
because of their chocolate here i like
the idea of that pure sativa and it
turns out you know whether people
there's controversy behind that like
crazy too saying they stole their looked
lines and lied about what it was and
this and that and
makes me want to have to you know
discount them
and then now what they're doing
you know they've blown up so big now
that i can't follow somebody like that
or even um i can't give them any love i
still have a ton of chocolate i mean
thousands of seeds of it and then
projects of it that are i still keep
them cut for them 10 12 years
uh my crazy train i mean my skunk
cabbage is
you know tga and dna that's crazy train
and chocolate and it's the thing that i
i go to it's my go-to to get stoned when
other things wouldn't get me high
and um
so that question's hard for me um
i go back to seed companies that i love
it would only probably be ssfc and you
know
the seed bank
i didn't have no contact for a long time
after that and then modern guys i love
dominion
um he doesn't put anything out that
isn't worthy and i love uh
you know dynasty and i can think of
probably 20 you don't mean gene those
guys they just don't cut corners
and that's who i'd say i love as as uh
seed producers but uh
that's that's a hard question for me
yeah okay so i guess if i'm gonna play
devil's advocate here how do you feel
european genetics in general have
influenced the world stage and how do
you feel about them now in terms of
their overall state of affairs
well i think that through
the very first uh
wave of it
it was really good influence
for the whole entire world the best
influence that could be but within 10
years there was more
industry um infiltration from they've
taken proprietary
genetics back and forth stealing them
and backstabbing because everybody was
trying to
to get something in the only legal
market in the world so uh
through that they'd either misbred
lied
and you know it came about to water down
their genetics severely so uh the state
of european genetics was a gold mine
that could have been tapped and still
there are some holdouts of it
but i do believe that it's uh
it's not compared to uh
it's never been compared to alaskan
genetics there's no there's no possible
what it ever could because the morals
were just like completely different and
we were breeding for ourselves and
though they were supplying the world so
they didn't give a [ __ ] they were making
money and i think it weakened the world
state of cannabis fiercely over the last
decade especially for at least from
oh five i mean it was garbage you know
five euro trash i hate to say it and be
so harsh on the people because you know
there's some good breeders and they're
still putting in good work
and there are guys that are still doing
some pretty good out there i uh
i personally know them and um
or i know some companies that are
working like through
spain just because it's the only legal
outlet
and they're putting in a lot of love and
i could say that they
they're trying to clean up what europe
watered down and spread out
so
how do you feel about kind of some of
the european breeders most notably
strain hunters having gone into these
land race areas and traded european
genetics for the indigenous ones
oh i gotta say franco was uh on the
right path and um
i think they did a lot of uh
bad along with good they certainly
didn't hunt in the very good spots they
didn't do a real thorough uh
selection
and um
did not hunt in the right spot so
if they watered down stuff by bringing
in european stuff they
they probably didn't like
do so much detrimental
uh
you know alteration because they never
were in the right spots in my opinion
and um half of that team was all about
money the other one was all about you
know cannabis
yeah okay and and how do you feel
smoking cannabis in conjunction with
tobacco affects it do you feel it really
doesn't make too much of a difference or
do you feel like it does
kind of detract or add to things
that's a good question because um
it's so popular with people making uh
you know using tobacco wraps and i've i
think i've smoked three of them in my
life
um i don't go straight up for um tobacco
wraps and
i got a lot of respect for the people
that do i don't see a problem with it
makes my throat kind of harsh and tickle
a little bit and i am an i'm an
i'm an anti-tobacco advocate so
i'd say natural wholesome good
old-fashioned
heirloom indian tobacco that's a whole
different um thing and i know in
different parts of the world they
certainly do just straight up mixed
tobacco
and hash or tobacco and cannabis and
that's just their system and that's
their style but i wouldn't be able to
hang with those guys [ __ ] that should
make it i'd be greener in hell
and uh
tobacco just doesn't do me any good
yeah no i can i can relate on that one
i'm i'm fairly anti-tobacco myself but
something i do like to point out to try
to show that it's not a one-sided view
is like there's actual studies done
which show that when you mix tobacco
with cannabis it actually results in a
greater amount of thc being released and
essentially not combusted so it's
scientifically proven you get more high
from smoking with tobacco so i always
try to keep that in mind whenever i get
on my high horse
you know i don't uh i don't want to
discount anybody that does roll once i
could say i've been
floored by [ __ ] that bust out the
blunts you know one of them is uh
uh down at emerald uh tony he has um
oh man it's slipping my mind is extract
company uh he's hooked up with the uh
pharmacy factory a little bit but um
[ __ ] that cat
uh he'd roll up a blunt that the weed
was just super really good but it was
the right kind of blunt because
it wasn't super annoying to me and we
had super pleasurable time smoking it
but then i've smoked some bad
a couple of like i don't know if it was
what it is
the the wrap or whatever but man
not as pleasurable so
i certainly don't have nothing against
it i'd grow my own tobacco in a second
if i um just for the look of it it's a
cool looking plant and i know a lot of
i love plants so we are so limited on
[ __ ] i might even grow a big patch of
tobacco this summer right next to like a
batch of hops
haha yeah nice nice the old backwoods
they're um they're an interesting kind
of phenomena taking over but you touched
on the perfect point i wanted to go to
next
given you live in this rather remote
place and it's hard to grow things
outdoors what type of things do grow
well outdoors like i mean and in terms
of cannabis do you still see ruderalis
on the side of the road type of thing or
was that more of like a myth than a
reality
no i don't think there was ever wild uh
root or alice up here ever i
i came across plants in the 90s that we
don't know where the root oralist gene
came from because i had bought in the
you know 90 i bought uh the skunk one
and the uh
indica root or alice from uh scentsy
seed bank and we tried to grow it up
here it was like smoke you know it was
like at this first stages it was root or
alice skunk so you're gonna get
one or two that tasted with some decent
uh smells and rust for cardboard but
there was never a wild strain up here
we've uh we've been able to do a lot of
in environmental kind of studies by
pushing plants to the end of the year
and where i'm at at this exact latitude
we know
a mild winter we can get five weeks into
flower and
[ __ ] it's just that close to finishing
so if somebody was to tweak it
or say
use an auto not an autoflower because
i'm friends like crazy with mofastos and
i grow a lot of his autoflowers his uh
his stuff's a whole different thing and
it does work up here but they just get
done super quick and
[Music]
they're not like other places they they
just do their thing uh i want to have
something like
a semi
auto that would uh flower before the
light is telling it to maybe start
triggering at 16 hours instead of the
slowly 14 hour trigger
and then we'd have two weeks advance on
it and um because i think maybe the
iranian auto something like that it's a
pseudo auto and
i've got some blueberries like that too
so we're experimenting and who knows we
we might alter the course of uh
of the cannabis to meet our environment
here if we keep playing with it
yeah i mean it's it's interesting that
you bring up blueberry because i see
that you've worked with it you and gave
me a pack of seeds as a blueberry hybrid
and i'm interested what's your
impression of the strain and are you
kind of a dj short fan in general
you know i'm not an anti-dj short
but i have never
never grown his streams ever we've uh
i think what i gave you was a blueberry
nine pound hammer and we we proved that
pretty well in the uh a growing la that
was for avid which was um you know a
pretty big aeroponics company they were
on the stock exchange and they were
building up uh
for selling the idpo and um
crazy [ __ ] happened the cfo and the ceo
had like hostile
takeover [ __ ] happened to each other and
there was about 60 million dollars in
accounts that got froze up and i was
doing test growth for those guys and
that nine pound hammer blueberry not
hammer was in there doing
a lot of videos of it so it did
excellent and
everybody kind of loved it but the uh
i got off track to what the hell was the
question
he indeed into dj show it
oh dj short yeah we've uh we just always
been thick with blueberry up here and
nobody's ever said the word dj short man
the blueberry was so common up here in
1995 that everybody grew up on it and
they're sick as [ __ ] a blueberry you
can't get people to even like it up here
yeah okay very very interesting there so
it's interesting because a lot of people
will say that you know like maybe they
read an article from dj short in the
early years and maybe that helped them
with their breeding or whatever did you
ever read any articles be it from
various authors or were you just very
much kind of self-taught oh mostly
self-taught but i definitely uh read and
got told a lot
like my little partner ak rizzo
he's a stay-at-home dad so he can
you know find those articles and if it's
something that that is even
curious to me which seems to be
everything is he relays it straight to
me so
i get a lot of good information and i've
read and found and read as much as i
could and certainly do follow
i like the idea of
like dj shorts had regenerative
practices of um getting full summer
growth and i like the practices of his
kid and i think that you've got it
you've got it going on for his uh
thing that he's got there they're both
doing really well
one thing of our our blueberry is uh
mostly always been just sativa up here
so
a lot of other blueberries in the world
turn purple and are indica and we have
some mean mean mean blueberry sativa
like indoor
average easy one pound per plant
sativas that stack up finish good fast
and over the top blueberries
but it's just our common it's ak
blueberry there's like so many there's
fairbanks blueberry salsa blueberry
goose babe blueberry
um a couple others one called arctic
blue
the arctic blue and the dean's beans
blueberry are both the same they're
about a 25
plus year old
cutting
and
i i have i've run that arctic blue and
bred the [ __ ] out of it to
just preserve it because it's so old but
you know those type of plants with the
generational drift they want to be hard
as hell to root
uh hard to get to going into beds you
have to completely shave their legs and
give them like a
you know
10 times oversized potter to get them to
encourage the hormones to go into the
growth tip and start producing
vegetative and they want to stay in the
flower all the time if they shock from
anything over feeding not keeping the
bottoms cleaned or
small roots they just laid a straight up
autoflower
which is a good house plant because in
the middle of summer you can have the
most beautiful uh smell on blueberry
plant like in the kitchen window
a little breeze blowing in and just
blows blueberry smell all over they
really do nice as a
a pseudo auto
but that has something that's happened
to them from
you know just being old gals
yeah the idea of genetic drift or kind
of loss of vigor is is an interesting
topic and recently we've seen a lot of
people engaging in this meristem tissue
culturing which kind of is said to
rejuvenate clones is that something
you've heard about and maybe possibly
interested in yourself
have heard about it and i uh i approve
of the uh
regenerative uh
practices
i think that's gonna be uh
helpful
to a lot of people i don't have any
duding or slow uh
something that's not
they can't be rooted i have no problem
um
it's just basically if you have
something that's that old and
kind of a pain in the butt
make it grow faster to get the roots um
you know makes a looser cellular
formation stuff that real tight cellular
formation that almost turns to wood
there's a lot of ways around uh
making plants like that grow
and uh
i've been just curious just now if i can
like give light doses of gibberellic
acid and 30 to 50 parts per million to
plants like
the lemon tree you know it grows
you have to grow it under a 65k to get
it to stretch or it'll grow if you put
it under 4 000 it'll sit down on itself
and have 20 internodes at three feet
tall and
that thing will be four or five months
in veg and uh little tricks like 6 500 k
and maybe 30 to 50 parts per million of
some gibralic acid you can get internal
length to come up from a quarter inch to
you know one or two inches and then make
that thing move
that's kind of things that run through
my mind a whole lot nowadays
yeah okay and so this brings us to a
perfect little segue do you grow
organically or are you more of a
synthetic base grower
that's really a good one because i have
uh forever done crazy um
we've always had animals a lot of them
for for 20 25 years long time ago we had
way over 100 wild boar that i was buying
them from like the bronx zoo
you could get them from mike
the san diego wildlife conservation
would sell their extra piglets and they
had uh you know 36 chromosome wild boar
from uh black uh the black forest line
and
the bronx who had the zygote line which
was from sweden and
we had all of these uh
the like lima uh ohio would have wild
exotic auctions you could just straight
up by polish imports and we were picking
up all of these 36 chromosome wild boars
so
we would have regular animals too but we
had to have
something exotic so
we would
always have corn mash or corn oats and
barley generally uh soaked or molasses
coated we'll soak it in barrels for a
week before we feed it
and 20 years ago i realized that stuff
will grow imo on the top of it and
sometimes we tap a little bit of the
water off of it you can either brew it
and make like you know some really good
hooch or you could uh
give it to the animals and they get a
little bit buzzed off of it but i would
uh i never knew to put lactic acid into
it
and turn it to like a
acetic acid so i would
just lightly water the plants with it as
like a nutritional boost thinking that
the starches would definitely be good
for the plants and if you let it sit too
long you'd grow an imo on the top of it
that made me
you know for a long time i've been doing
that we'd always get uh
tons up to you know up to tons at a time
of food from connections for our animals
so if i would let certain things ferment
and i realized about the uh
like the korean natural farming
practices i didn't know that's what it
was called but we would
you know i'd seen the value of
fermenting things because i've i've
worked
for 30 plus years for a korean and
we eat a lot of kimchi i know what
fermentation does for you know it's very
good a lot of different things fermented
are good so
[Music]
we've always kind of ate natural diets
and tons of fermented stuff so i figured
the plants are going to benefit by it
and then i found out later the whole
time that we've just been doing you know
natural practices
of all these organic styles
i can't say i haven't bought a lot of
bottles of uh
of uh pre-made uh foods but the ones
that i did buy
i would say
35 years ago we used eco-grow
and uh
it it's not soluble so you'd have to mix
it for a damn hour before you could use
it and um
it kind of went away and i used
something called uh esu
which was energy sun university and uh
for about 10 years that product was
around and it changed its name
to nsr and it has since gone off the
market but if i ever had to go to a
bottled nutrient that's what i would go
to because it
never built salt up
never burnt the plants it had a uh you
know an indicator for ph in it so it was
real real easy to use but
i have
you know we'll take like
a lot of our fermented fruit for our
animals and i'll just straight up been
forever making ffj
so
in my garage i probably have
25 5 gallon buckets of ffj in multiple
forms and then maybe five gallons of
ffa the the fish amino acid
and
[Music]
i have got some barrels of uh
you know seaweed collected from the
ocean just straight up right off the
shoreline massive collections of uh
seaweed now i'll ferment that and then
put
lactic acid on it let it brew and then
i'll put an imo that i grow
and
you know let it inoculate
and then
go from there and i try to keep like
good live soil i mean all the time i'll
recycle my soil and refurbish it then
you know kick it to the side using em1
or any of my imo's
i would just uh refurbish it real good
let it sit in tubs
sometimes over the whole winter indoors
in the garage and
if i use it too much or don't want it
i'll put it into my outdoor gardens one
thing you asked earlier what does grow
up here barely anything grows up here so
berries i have a lots of berries black
currants
raspberries and
tons of curry just different uh bushes
and
apple trees and any of the stuff i grow
i put any of my old nutrient dirt that's
living right right into my uh gardens
and generally
it'll any leaf that hits it it'll just
eat it up the imo would just drop gobble
it up into a pure white uh you know my
cilia it's really some pretty nice live
soil yeah definitely so i mean
now that we know how you grow we've got
to ask the other end of the spectrum
what type of lighting technology do you
like to use and what do you think will
be the future of lighting technology
that's funny um i was thinking about
that you know the other day when i saw
the uh
high times about 15 years ago
advertising 6 000 watt plasma lights and
i think they're landing craft lights and
that was going to be the future way back
when
and
now i see a change about every year
there's an advancement in light
i use uh
four
1000 watt 500
watt emitters they're they're 1000 watt
uh double enders but they're 500 watt
you know cmh they call it i always call
them lec's
and um those are really nice does
the plants are just loving the the uh
like a 3000 r spectrum they're like
super pimp lights but i also like some
uh you know good out sally leds i use
quite a bit of leds i like um
i like california light works
uh they make really good product i've
had real good success i like uh
the spider lights
they're uh
you know the biofluorescence spider lice
uh
they're a little bit expensive it comes
up to being
about three dollars a watt so
they're kind of prohibitive
and now the price is finally coming
around and the quality is about
the same on multiple manufacturers
so they're coming down to about a
thousand dollars for those 600 and 650
watt units and
but i also big on uh
timber grow light
shout out to timber grow lights uh
you know his 480 sams are
very inexpensive he uses meanwhile
drivers uh
they cover really good they'll replace
uh the 480 sams will replace the 1000
and they really are a good light i i use
a bunch of his cobs also
you know hundred watty meter cob some 50
watt emitter columns because he'll sell
those uh kits just wire it yourself if
you buy like a clone cabinet or a
revenging cabinet or a breeding
you know i've i've got the craziest
grows because i'll have 100 projects
going on so
i've got re-vegetative state going on
and i've got multiple breeding you draw
them i'm all over
so
i like leds for that purpose you can't
just stick a i have quite a few uh 630
this the 315 watt leds too and those are
really nice
they uh
they are not something that i would uh
recommend you're better off i think with
the 315s and spreading them out every uh
two two feet two and a half feet
versus like the twin six thirties
i mean the twin 315s because you're just
concentrating too much light in a little
central focal point
so um i quit using those uh the 630s
yeah okay so i mean we've talked about
kind of genetic drift as well as
lighting so it's it's almost inevitable
we get to this topic but how do you feel
re-vegging affects a plant do you feel
like there's a lasting difference
thereafter re-veging a plant or it's
just essentially a very time and
efficient way of keeping a clone
there's a lot of opinion on that and it
it does have multiple answers um
i don't think that it hurts most strains
because some strains come from
equatorial
land race and you're going to see 11 to
14 hour
time periods that sumbitch will go into
uh
it'll veg it like 14 hours and flower at
11 and there's a fine line in between
there so uh
if you're going up more towards the 36
parallel and you're talking about
uh either highland or lowland indica
they do a different thing they they
never do revenge their their life cycles
over at the end of their life so they're
genetically programmed to pretty much
die
i don't think re-veging any plant
hurts it i i mean i've heard i've had
bunch of people that are older than me
try to educate me and tell me these
other things and what it will do
um
i utilize it quite a bit uh re-vegging a
plant i i found out males revenge much
faster than females
ivory veg a ton of plants i don't think
it hurts anything but i do believe that
each plant's genetics are where it
varies for if it if it is going to
change it or hurt it it's where it came
from yeah okay
and so you did mention earlier that um
putting plants outside is a way of
rejuvenating them are you ever able to
do that in alaska or it's it's still
rather limited the time frame
no we have four months of solid uh
summer we'll
our light gains about
five minutes and 50 seconds a day so
every 10 days you're looking at an hour
of gain you know so we have this massive
light swing
and it's 22 and 23 hours where i'm at is
that that's my time if you go any
further north it's straight up 24 hours
a light and the damn uv index is so high
in the middle of summer it's equivalent
of uh
oh [ __ ] there's people that come up here
from phoenix and san diego and it'll be
75 and they're telling us [ __ ] at 75
they're going it's at least 95 it's a
hundred and they're dying man
and it's just our sun it's the angle of
that thing and it's the uv index so you
have four months to where you can you
can definitely regenerate a plant and
you oh man you can make some crazy
bushes you won't be able to move the
thing and you won't have nothing don't
have a place big enough to flower
yeah well okay so is that something
you've done yourself or just thinking
about
no i will um if i had a mother that
i hammered the [ __ ] out of and uh you
know they're so poor at that point if
you were to put them into flower you
will get nothing on it even if you you
know were to seed it to do a little
last-ditch effort to save the genetics
you still really are in a bad shape so i
would take like a mother that's been
over
cut and then give it a full four months
and let it get to the five and six foot
point and that it'll be almost as fresh
as it was if it had never been beat to
[ __ ] so that's an advantage there i do i
do that every summer
yeah okay so something i noticed on the
alternative end of the spectrum to the
sun is i seen a post or two about you
germinating plants around the moon cycle
is that something you do frequently and
what type of effect do you think it has
you know i've been told
told by a lot of people that it's real
proper
and i've uh
i've even said it's come out of my mouth
that i don't practice that hippie [ __ ] i
mean it's crazy what i've said but i've
contradicted myself because i
i do believe that the pull of the uh
the ocean
it has a lot to do with everything in
nature so the magnetic fields that we
have no understanding of period look how
animals you know get around the whole
world it's it's due to that they have
knowledge wave past our knowledge and if
i'm dealing with old seeds that are 25
and 30 years old some of them never were
put up correctly at all
so um
you are uh praying to god and hoping
that the moon's pull will anything to
get you through on old genetics so i
practice that quite a bit and it's just
a good timing a lot of time you know you
stray fox is real aware of all the moon
cycles i am too because i'm you know i'm
into the uh
farmer's almanac and fishing i know what
every tide is because i have to know
where my tide book is i'm a i'm a freak
about getting into the water and i know
what the tide's doing at all points in
time so the moon cycle means a lot to me
i mean it's it's it's a real uh
important thing to know
yeah okay so before we jump into some
fishing stuff which we are going to get
to just got to quickly ask you are
notorious for having these you know 20
plus year old seeds that you're able to
get to germinate what are some of your
little tips and tricks for getting these
bad boys to hatch
you know what it all uh it just was a
matter of luck when i first started
putting up seeds we had no idea when we
were going to use them i imagined a year
or two years and
i used 35 millimeter film containers
which turned out to be air proof and
waterproof
i'd put a little bit of a
decanter which at the time um people
would say and put in rice or
a small wadded up piece of uh like a
paper towel so i just opted for a small
piece of paper towel
and i would generally even write the
genetics right on the paper towel so it
would be labeled inside maybe labeled on
the outside in
a black permanent marker but
one or two years i i never used them and
[Music]
you know i am not one for change uh
i've worked the same job since 87
i've had the same house the same i raise
american bulldogs and i've read them
since late 80s i've never changed
anything i like to just like keep it all
the same and
i have changed a little bit but it's
easy to get 30 year old genetics you
just put them in the freezer and 30
years goes by and
[Music]
it
tends to be if you don't thaw them out
you're going to retain all the
germination
properties i i might lose 10 percent
germination if i thaw them out but i
never have to thaw them out because when
i dig through them
for one thing i have a commercial
freezer and i can almost stand in the
son of a [ __ ] and key it's 20 below so
i can uh
you know i can get in there and pick
[ __ ] out without thawing at the middle
of summer but in the middle of winter we
got we have seven eight months to where
you can just straight up grab your
collection and start digging through it
it's frozen it never does fall out so
people that i've sent uh you know good
old seeds to
mean jeans and
just a bunch of them they just they're
like instantly going
how old did you say they were because i
had 100 it's better than what i just
produced
and it's like well they just happened to
all fall together they were healthy ass
good seeds
and
people didn't know the time frame on
frozen seeds most people assume 20 years
on marijuana seed and i've heard 30 is
the window but it's way way way longer
than 30 years because i have 100
germination at 30 years
so um it is a it's something right there
that needs to be explored
it's uh exciting too because you if you
think about it um the joe rom cuts
saliva 50 years well
here shortly 20 more years i'm going to
have 50 year old seeds that just have
never been cracked and still ready to go
yeah well that's that's the real
treasure trove there so i guess my final
kind of question about alaska in general
is overall would you consider it a good
environment to be growing indoors given
that it's got that really nice cold
temperatures or do you think it just
kind of comes with its own challenges
yeah we're a lot more advantageous we're
are lucky i should say um uh
because you're fighting heat and every
every uh
every place in america but here
it gets real hot in the interior here
it'll get to 90 and you're fighting heat
there but
i know people that grow in texas it's
it's a pig
the law enforcement's going to stand on
your head and treat it like you're a
meth head and the [ __ ] heat you're
going to fight there's just no way you
could be comfortable grow in a grow room
in texas and
if you were cool on it you're going to
run a fortune in moving air or
cool in the air so
we have really good ambient air
temperature
most of the time so uh we're able to run
a little bit hotter lights and just run
you know run a
air box
and
bring in a little bit of fresh cool air
which is generally our summer air might
be
60 degrees to where
you can swap out your summer here and
keep a grow room without any big deal
keep it at about 75
so
as an advantage to growing up here we
also never had the uh
i'd say until two years ago we never had
powder mildew in alaska
never ever ever never
so that was a nice thing we were
isolated but now you know with modern
day people trucking clones back and
forth from pm fest uh
it's it's uh
it's common that now we're all
infiltrated and
um now i imagine next will be the
dudding disease did you hear about uh
dark horse nursery just found a cure uh
a viral a viroid that is uh
the name of the bud the deading
is figured out it's a hops disease i
thought that it was and
they actually know how to eradicate it
now so there's tests for it and
people with all that dudding or
there's a couple other names that they
call it you know they're figuring that
out so
right about the time that [ __ ] hits here
we'll actually have a cure for it
yeah yeah i saw that post it's
interesting because i think what they
were trying to say was that it's some
you know specified way of doing
essentially a meristem culture which is
interesting because i mean having spoken
to a few people a few guys have got
dotted clones that they're still hanging
on to because they're so old like you
know the original calio and stuff like
that
just to just to sidestep that point for
one sec overall what do you think is the
most important factor in a grower out of
the three possibilities genetics
environment or the growers skill
environment
yeah
because uh
you know you can make shitty genetics
shine if your environment's perfect and
it doesn't take much skill to uh to grow
yeah definitely i would like to have
perfect genetics for sure because
you could have the best genetics but
what if you just stick it in the [ __ ]
whole environment and then everything's
gone
uh and you could still just like be an
um you know idiot and grow i think it's
a weed it's it's um
that's one of the advantages of growing
cannabis is that it's resilient and it
gives you hundreds of breaks
lets you like live a very complacent
life and you don't even realize how much
it's given you
yes certainly certainly
so
just to kind of loop back to your
breeding for a moment the topic of
feminized seeds has certainly come up
is that something you're looking to
explore more and which of the various
feminization methods would you want to
pursue out of like the colloidal silver
the sts or like the gibberellic acid
that's cool that you brought that up too
because in uh
in 88 we uh
i was growing tomatoes and
at the time we had waco
and uh we
i was growing the tomatoes and the
cannabis together
and i was trying to get the tomato
blossoms to set so
one
of the tomato sets is just a
um gibralic acid just straight up
hormone they sell as it's called um set
spray or something and
i spray that [ __ ] all over my tomato
plants no more blossoms hit the ground
the tomatoes stretched you know
three feet and the spray got onto a
couple of uh
jamaican plants of all things let's grow
them in a greenhouse [ __ ] jamaican
gets against brelic acid on it so the
thing goes to a vine and
i thought it was cool it changed the
leaf structure and turned the stems red
like like
zero uh
like a magnesium deficiency and uh
low phosphorus it was like
how wild so i started spraying it on
everything and my waco plants
uh reversed and we made a big batch of
seeds
and we grew out we thought it was the
coolest thing in the world because we
knew at that point in time you could
find a little bit of information i think
ed rosenthal had some [ __ ] about uh
feminized seeds and uh
nothing about chemically induced though
it was always about just natural uh
you know late season flowers when the
things trying to save its own life and
it generally come from equatorial
varieties which at the time that's what
a lot of our genetics were at over 50
percent 75 percent had thai or colombian
or
burmese or any of the equatorial even
africans
uh and those things
will always start that late season
banana to save their own life and
that's what i knew as to be female seeds
so
i saw these and figured it out we grew
them they were all females and
you know it didn't reverse it didn't
feminize as good it was not as good i
should say as the mother so
while it was all female we didn't see a
value in it and we never looked back
from 88 on
i never looked back period and then
you know five ten years about five years
ago that um feminized movement just
crazily took off and
i just watched and watched well man
these guys are [ __ ] up everything
because i know that um
unless everything's tracked you can't
generally breed to any of this stuff
past s1 you're screwed so uh
i realized that it was watering down
everything badly i didn't really want to
get into it i kind of followed people
doing it but um recently i did grab some
sts spray sprayed a durvan down and i
was gonna just do a derby female
reversal or make german feminized and
just
just for the shits and grins i guess but
it took five weeks for the uh
pollen to actually come out so i just
feminized a lemon tree and an orange
tree the 17 high times san bernardino uh
sativa winner was the orange tree and
nobody disputes the lemon tree as being
like over the top of lemon skunk with
that you know the [ __ ] sour diesel
back it's it's one of the best
and i just figured it'd be like cool
with the terps of the durbin mixed in
with those and
i did mess with it but you know i don't
put too much value in it the seeds are
sitting there i never thought about
crack and i'd give them to anybody or
something if somebody wanted to play
with it because i'm not
i'm not thinking it's helping the
the genetics
at all
yeah okay
so
touching on that topic how important is
it in your mind for a breeder to give
away seeds and i guess specifically when
they're kind of starting out do you feel
like that's a part of paying your jews
yeah that should be a
good way to build a um you know a
clientele and uh
you make a lot of friends out of it i'll
tell you that much and you get a lot
more love back than you would ever think
so it's a it's
a real good thing
as an extension of that idea what would
be your advice for someone who's just
starting out wants to kind of get a bit
more established in terms of a breeder
i would say do their homework and get
a line
or or or collect genetics that can be
advanced
and can go somewhere not just
another uh
another poly hybrid that is
multi-generational poly hybrid they're
they're actually at a point of a
bottleneck so tight right now with 10
years of that going on that
a new breeder should gear up and try to
select
something that is unique and different
if it can be done
and uh if not you're just jumping on the
bandwagon with everybody else you're
going to be left in the dust because
it's been done 10 000 times
and as kind of a final thought to wrap
this topic up what's your thoughts on
the exponential rise in breeders we see
collectively within the community
well i don't know everybody has the
right to breed so
if everybody had the same goals it would
be uh
it'd be a huge advantage but um
that's never going to happen so
we are humans and we are all like um
on our own path so i see it going
you know
between
corporate and maybe trademarking and
that the way it could go that direction
i'd rather see independent people doing
it and just everybody do it at that
point
yeah definitely
so what type of breeders would you like
to work with going forward
just the guys that i work with right now
librarians that um
they paid their dues and they were there
at the time uh
and uh they put in their
you know 100
to get us where we are right now
that's people that i value the most old
heads and people that saw the value
you know 50 years ago
and then all the people with heart
that's all i don't need to uh
i work for a living and you know i could
retire anytime i don't give a [ __ ] uh
about trying to make a bunch of money
because i've worked a steady day job you
know that old saying don't quit your day
job well
i'm [ __ ]
august of uh
august of this year's like 34
years working down there so uh
i've always had a different view than
everybody else people are growing and
selling their buds i've never sold my
buds i did i might sell a cover a light
bill but i grew for myself and only to
further my genetics and that was my only
my mindset for 30 and 35 years
so um i don't think the same way
everybody else thinks
but i'd go with anybody with heart mean
gene
dirt farmer um
dynasty
mafestos these are all people that are
like they got your back and uh
there's a shitload of them way too many
to mention i would i
would hurt i'd be a total ass if i
didn't just come up with 20 of them
right now
because they're all like i want to work
with every one of them because they're
just good people
yeah certainly it's always one of those
things we don't want to leave anyone out
but something i do want to greatly echo
the sentiment you just expressed is
especially in australia please guys have
a day job you know it don't make this
your full-time gig because
frankly you're going to have to
compromise things to make money instead
of following the passion and i think
that's where the best results come from
when you're pursuing passion and not
necessity-based things but to get back
on track
i wanted to quickly ask you what land
race is your favorite and do you have
any plans to work with it going forward
i would have to say tai because i said
it's just that one crazy ass good memory
and
i know the potential that's there and
i'm at a point where
i've been offered so many things and
i've passed up on opportunities i should
have took up
and i do have a shitload of um you know
good land race and uh
definitely need to dig into a bunch of
it but
i would say thai is what i would try
i've tried really cool things and might
dig i've got some 77 himalayan that's
single stocked sativa and it's uh one of
the few single stocks that i've been
able to come across except nl1
and it's a sativa too so that's one
thing that i think is pretty unique uh
and uh
i like to
i like those unique
uh genetics uh stray fox made up some uh
used black affy i think which which was
bodhis and um
uh iraqi indica and when i grew that out
it was all like 13 finger fan leafs with
single stock growth and super dominant
so those are the things that i want to
work with right there
yeah okay and generally speaking would
you consider yourself more of an indica
or a sativa guy
you know i'd probably say 50 50 because
i like knock down drag out um indicas
but they're not going to let you get
anything done you better have a
[ __ ] couch to nap on or a four shot
espresso waiting after you smoke some
mac you know because uh
you're not gonna be doing a whole lot
you smoke some chocolope or my uh
tropolope that that space jill and
chocolope some things like that
you'll be way ripping ass high and still
get everything done
and then maybe uh sing a little bit and
groove to the music a little more
i love it sounds right up my alley so
it's uh it's funny you mention that um
the mac you know it it's interesting
because max not only like the flavor of
the month but you know there's that kind
of story of we're not really a story but
there's the incidence of you you're not
only collecting like a really impressive
amount of pollen but you know you kind
of sent it out far and right far and
wide which in my opinion really quite
noble and our buddy organically enhanced
here in australia even he managed to
make some crosses with that pollen so i
guess my question is
what made you decide to share it because
you know it's such high demand and um
you know the explosive popularity of cap
is
you know just you can't even deny it at
the moment so what's your thoughts on
the mac and why do you decide to share
the pollen with people
that's super cool you brought that up
for a couple reasons i did that because
i had already been in contact with mac
i mean cap and uh
i wasn't gonna buy no i mean it's
i've never been in a rec store i'll kind
of go down this road i've never been in
a rec store up here or in any other
place and i i have bought seeds like i
did i bought you know the platinum
huckleberry
from uh a seed bank and then i bought i
might have bought a dozen packs of seeds
but i've been given maybe a thousand
packs of seeds from
the best breeders in the world and it's
the top of their line where it's the
best dash
and uh
that right there is like so heartfelt so
uh when i seen how cap was giving that
away and it already run for a year and a
half [ __ ] and talk about you're the mac
right i
i was kind of like a little bit spiteful
and i was like
uh
i got it given to me and i figured i'd
read with it and offer any extra so i i
ended up you know putting a shout out to
locals only and i ended up getting hit
up by everybody in the world i sent that
to
thailand india australia canada
um
i think nine uh eight or nine countries
i sent that to and then sent it to a
dozen places in america got like 20
grams of the of the pollen it was crazy
wanting to dump pollen
and i figured i was being a wise ass i
put a post up said
um end of the year with a mac or
something just giving it out and people
are going there always has to be that
one guy that has to ruin everything good
and i was like
you know if you ain't had your run with
mac at this point [ __ ]
i mean it's for free anybody can get it
for free um the main cut so
i thought because everybody was going
man i'll never ever get in line you have
to get on his list and you have to wait
and wait if you're lucky enough to ever
get it or get in mine at an event that
he might release something and they just
go i'll never ever see it in our
lifetime over here and i'd love to try
it
and i just like you know what
if you're not the guy that would help
out those people you're a dick i don't
care uh that [ __ ] i think i lost my ass
sending that out it's like 30 40 bucks a
pack to send international even if it's
pollen you know
but
whether i got love back or not i uh
i figured i helped them people out
unless it was like going to india and
getting bred to you know land race [ __ ]
but
they they promised me they're keeping it
for their own personal you know
collection because they can never get
their hands on the back
it's certainly one of those very sought
after ones with that being said though
you know we see things like the gmo
having run its course and the skittles
and even mac appears to be kind of
reaching the end of its life cycle
what's your prediction for the newest
flavor of the month and would you ever
try to kind of get ahead of the curb and
cash in on the correct prediction
you know i don't think i care to ever
chase a dollar i would
i'd rather go fishing and uh
i i think what the next biggest thing is
is going to be exotics flavors um
some of the spice island type of flavors
man if we could ever get a cinnamon girl
back or some of the polynesian flavors
there's some really good spicy nutmeg
flavors and
another one i would be nuts about and uh
passion fruits and hawaiian exotic
fruits
and i do believe there's going to be a
huge resurgence of blueberry i mean
orange is so
roadkill run over and burnt out some
people still dig the terp but uh you
know it was orange and then it was lemon
and uh i still really dig the lemon tree
something fierce i'm growing like lemon
ice pucker and it's like a quarter of
the good what uh
the lemon tree is and then i've heard
the lemon royale from swamp boys is like
off the hook good so i'm super tempted
to uh you know check that out but i
think i would love to get ahead of the
game in the curve and produce passion
fruit or any of the guava
something that's new and exotic not just
that um
flipping cookie you know what there's a
hundred cookie crosses and you taste the
cookie and every one of them and it's so
[ __ ] blah i mean i was turning people
on that never seen it before and they go
is that the same as that other one we
just tried i said well it's half the
same and then the next would be the same
answer it's half the same it's cause i
had like a whole jar after jar of
cookie crosses it's uh
that's nuts i want some flavors back cat
piss and uh
i've never had a ton of sours but i do
like some sours chris barnes who uh he's
the front man for uh six feet under do
you you you know who that is yeah i
definitely have heard of them yeah he's
a he's like an extremely cool cat i mean
he's extreme in the in his uh music
lifestyle and and persona and stuff but
he's the most humble and and uh
good guy in the world he grows his
killer uh blueberry headband he calls it
bhb
666 which is uh
beyond hillbound 666. i sent him my best
uh
nine percent uh tested at the lab skunk
cabbage pollen and he knocked his
666 up and made the 777 and i guess
that's also symbol for heaven and hell
which i don't follow any of that
mystical [ __ ] or know about it so much
but yeah me and chris barnes are friends
and now his blueberry headband
i love it it's a killer's power and
it's like 27 percent
it's uh got lots of color so i'd like to
get into some uh sours
and uh
mix turks too
i want to have a front of one flavor and
heavy back of another but i think all
weed should have equal alpha and beta
terpenes if you cannot produce this
quit growing weed
definitely that diversity within
terpenes is huge
you you said the golden words in the
midst of a description you said
orange has been
ran over it's the road kill gotta ask
about it do you have any experiences
with the roadkill skunk
um we didn't ever call it roadkill but
we had a shitload of scout because we
bought you know big skunk from uh from
sense he was half real skunk and whether
some were sweet phenos there was still
a quarter of a more skunk phenos and
then in 91 we bought the super skunk so
super skunk to me to this day is still
the
um
the only plant i think you can go back
to that has the old what people call
road kill skunk but true scum
i call it true spunk but yes i have old
genetics
that's crazy as [ __ ] how i might have
old genetics but
i've got original uh
you know uh
super
dank ass true skunks uh super skunk mail
so i'm gonna try to get together with
with people like
i think farmer joe 420 i think is on
instagram uh he has he has an 87
super skunk and he has males but you
know
i'm kind of known for my males so um
we're gonna
try to bring out more skunk but i got a
half a dozen skunks that are i've got a
big skunk that's true skunk we got the
super skunk that's true skunk i've got a
madness called bx that's true skunk i've
got an o'hawk and big skunk that's true
skunk
and they're all males which is amazing
because you can rub the male at any time
and get that true skunk hit i just have
my wife smell it and she either hits me
with
ooh
and she's she's like very put off by it
or she just says i don't know very
strong marijuana
at that point i hit it right on the head
at that point it's like thank you give
her a kiss and it's like rally off to my
happy point and do a dance
you know
i love scoring the [ __ ] that it'll turn
her nose
that's that's a great description so
while we're kind of on the skunk topic
tell us a little bit about your skunk
cabbage or cabbage however you want to
pronounce it yeah it's cabbage but
everybody in the world is going to call
it cabbage i it's a funny thing so i
just let him let him be you know
whatever you want to call it
um
it's just um
crazy training chocolate but
it's off the hook it puts what it's like
if you were to breed the 91 white and it
puts white on anything
this [ __ ] will put white on anything
but it uh it has really rotten uh skunky
terps plus because there's a plant
called skunk cabbage that's up here real
prevalent and it's the first thing that
grows in the summer and it produces its
own heat melts the snow bank around it
and then the bears come along and the
deer and the bear we have we have like
implanted deer that have made it up here
since uh
it's been 90 years or 80 years they've
been up here
but um first thing they can find to eat
is that skunk cabbage but it melts its
own way out of a snow bank from
producing its own fire so when we
you know kind of put that together the
fire
side of it and the rank-ness of it
people actually smell skunk cabbage and
have come back and told me is that how
you name that it's like that is half of
why i named it that yes i didn't know
that tom hill had a skunk cabbage so
just embarrassing for me to you know
call it that for years and then find out
i seem like bean hoarder or something
that has like all these tom hill things
and it's like oh skunk cabbage i'm an
idiot
but that's why i changed it with the
cube because it was out of crazy train
from the tga side of it and uh
i i've separated it that way
but
it's my go-to if i want to get stoned
you know if i'm smoking 15 this satin
the other all day long and
i can take three hits of that and it'll
over
ride
all 15 joints of the 15
but it's it's probably my uh
my cannabinoid system my endocannabinoid
system is probably
just geared up for that terp cross and i
did have the highest in-state terp test
ever about three or four years ago and
also
i was told in canada at the biggest lab
up there it's hit the third highest
terpene
uh
um
chirping numbers on the biggest lab up
there
but you know saying that doesn't make a
lot of sense because canada's five or
six or seven provinces and
[ __ ] one million labs so
yeah i was told by somebody it hit top
three out of the biggest lab up there
so
wow very impressive got some funk to it
uh and
i kind of just dig it it's something
that i probably won't ever go without
i've sent it to people like
a bunch of people i gave it to bodie and
uh um i think story and doc and somebody
give it to me and gene i know i gave it
to pharmacy factory and i give it to
ever i don't give i don't care if you
like their hate or whatever throw it
away grow it don't matter but it hits me
just right
yeah okay sounds like that one which is
hopefully vibing with more people than
just you with that being said what's
your favorite strain that often maybe
gets a bit of hate or just doesn't get
as much love
from other people
[ __ ] i don't know because the ones that
everybody uh
um you know you get you get slapped in
the face or a lot of a lot of memes and
[ __ ] about aj sour diesel and a lot of
memes and
you know backhands from uh
uh the blue dream and uh i've never
smoked any of the real [ __ ] so i have no
idea uh
what's good and people call
bad or give a bad rap too i uh
i kind of only smoke my own flower
yeah i've never been to that sorry i've
never been to that wreck thing and uh
you know they have like gummy bears up
here somebody smoked that with me it's a
31 local thing at the rec market and
somebody's growing it in their home deal
the guy that gave it to the wrecker
whatever and i just thought it was such
poor weed so
i don't know i'm a picky ass dick and i
like my own weed
no it sounds like a man after my own
heart i can certainly relate to that
so
how do you like to make your concentrate
a little bit of kefir on top of the bong
heater are you more of like a bho and
concentrates type of guy
you know near zero uh
concentrates i make a lot of
keef a shitload because well i might
like even on the tk nl5 this last run
that i seeded out 16
16 or 17 different strains and every bit
of it went to that pollen and
i had no flour at all so all i had was
uh you know keef after i have de-shocked
that i can separate the keep and then
only thing i do with it is just put it
on a rosin press
so um low low uh heat rosin at about uh
65 celsius which is i think 160 or
something on fahrenheit and
just press it and i have i have i don't
smoke a shitload of concentrates and
never ever really ever smoke bho i'll
smoke some eho and people up here kind
of tag me for that and people go i know
you i've heard you don't do no vho or
whatever what this is real good now come
and bring me a sample which is real cool
but i hardly ever would ever smoke
eho tends to be better but
i have about a half a pound of rosin at
all points in time just because i squish
all the keef it's very common to get
eight ounce jars of kefir two at a time
you know
and then what are you going to do with
that you either had to make eho bho or
some rosin and to me rosin's wide
spectrum and a little bit better way
better high i think
yeah definitely
so
in terms of where the market's heading
towards the end of last year we saw the
rise of the uh the very controversial
100.8 from big al
and how do you feel like this affects
the market do you feel like there's a
place within the market for the ultra
premium products and the the high-end
consumers or do you feel like the fact
that cannabis has this medicinal
component to it that we shouldn't allow
things to creep up like that
oh i see both sides of that uh that
thing there's people that want to feel
special and i actually have
you know liquid assets
my dumb bulldogs are gonna go off
um
but um i don't think it's certainly not
good for the normal guy i think it's
unfair for the uh
the grower because they're getting
hammered on the low end of it and then
it's like rubbing it in their face
you know if you can
get a hundred dollars for an eighth and
and you're paying 500 for a pound that's
not right
yeah it it puts an interesting spin on
like what does the grower get out
because i mean big out to his credit
used to be a grower but i believe for
the most part now he's actually more of
a kind of like a middleman
i think there's a you know there's a
situation for everything and because
we're so diverse as humans there's uh
there's people in the world who would
never consider they never consider um
you know
first world problems like that so
if you look at the whole scheme of
things
everybody has a right to do what they
want and if there's somebody that
there's an if there's a need build a
void
as much as i may have some personal
questions about the situation i just my
mind immediately always wanders to the
fact that you know there are people who
pay hundreds of thousand dollars for
cars and you know
people don't criticize that and so i
feel like there's got to be some
congruency and consistency within
within our thought process at least
yeah you will you won't see anybody
giving somebody grief over that car
they're going to give them 100
of congratulations that they made it to
that point right
and not not even be butt hurt over it or
jealous unless it's your hard work from
your brow sweat that uh got that car for
your boss
yeah that's that's maybe a whole nother
conversation in itself so
one last thing i wanted to bring up
before we jump onto some fishing stuff
because we're going to get there don't
worry after this one i noticed on your
feed you've got some dungeon vault
genetics i'm a big fan of eric and
dungeon vault genetics what are you most
looking looking forward to popping out
of those seeds and do you have any
experience with brandywine or more
specifically the pink champagne which is
the mother of it
another really good question you're
nailing it because i had not known him
too long i
i met him through the catalogs i sent
him catalogs
up
because i think his genetics stood stood
up for themselves so i didn't hear
anybody um
except maybe some controversy you know
everybody gonna whatever your background
is or somebody always butt hurt so i i
knew through falconer that um he had
some stand up [ __ ] and he straight up
sent me like
maybe a couple packs of a bunch of stuff
and i i
i know that the humble pie was gonna be
real good and i had no this is how
backwards and or are like so old school
i didn't know
that grandpa's breath was granddaddy
purple i had to listen to your interview
with him to find out the history of
dungeon vault genetic
and i'd already met him and talked to
him and um he's given me his genetics i
had no idea what it was because i don't
follow if there's something that i i am
not going to have a route go a planned
route you know to go down myself i can't
absorb that [ __ ] at this point in my
life a very little room left in my brain
for new information so i'm not going to
absorb all
knowledge i just kind of keep it within
a
right in my view and uh he's a good guy
and i think it's um
a really good thing that he's got going
on and keeping it straight i know a
couple of my testers have grown this
stuff out they brought me the smoke it's
really good
i did just recently send him
uh multiple tkno fives uh the f2 of the
tea candle five haze the uh
my best purple
to the tcano five haste because i want
him to experience you know another
100 percent view of purple
and then get his dick just knocked
straight into the dirt
because it's
it it's it's something else i'm not even
going to beat a
divorce kind of [ __ ] if you if you
[ __ ] buy it and trust me
you have it if you don't then it's a
story
yeah totally totally
so
getting to some of the more
light-hearted stuff i've been promising
for a minute let's talk about fishing
you know you do a lot of fishing i've
even seen a few the odd photos of maybe
hunting here and there how does cannabis
interact with these things do you like
to do them while sober or is it just
like the perfect time to get high for
you
i am a total
weed-aholic
so i
i can tell you the days that i didn't
get high
um
to tell you the truth in 1985
from monday the 1st to friday the 5th
i did not get high i i quit smoking pot
i was like a teenager fed up with it
and then my brother or my good good
friend's brother comes back from the
peace corps with him
on friday night he comes back thursday
night
and uh
gives him some thai bud from whatever
country he was in and [ __ ] calls me up
friday tells me he's got this tie but
it's like okay
i'm on my way over man i was right back
to smoke and i quit for five days and 85
and uh
there was another time i flew in and uh
we're moose hunting in in
in 98
and uh as i see the plane take off i'm
ready to roll our celebratory
joint and i'm digging around and there's
no [ __ ] weed i left you know a week's
worth of weed
and it's like holy [ __ ] man it's gonna
be a whole week going to be over here
and [ __ ] that'd be the two times in my
life i ain't smoking i i did get i did
get i can't say the two because i almost
died once i was like you know 106 and a
half fever
i had
something
it was a
staph infection on my epiglottis that's
a little flap in the back of your throat
right it uh it's 30
uh survivability rate if you get this so
i waited the last minute like i normally
would and i went in almost dead i'd
already passed out and i woke back up
alive so i went to the hospital
and they innovated me and put me on
anesthesia for like four days so
there was another four days i didn't
smoke weed but i have no choice
yeah wow and and what type of fishing
and hunting do you like to do most
you know i i like to hunt just about
everything but our opportunities are
limited we try to fill our freezer on
moose and deer so we hunt
i don't do a lot of bird hunting because
it's not as much opportunity up here if
i had a lot of upland game bird
i'd do that a lot more we only have like
a couple we have a grouse and a spruce
hen and
i'll do that too i love bird hunting but
we deer hunt moose hunt a little bit of
bird hunt but fishing we just get
whatever comes up
as soon as we can get it
i would have been
like i mentioned earlier i would be out
right now getting crab because uh
federal crabbing for subsistence
crabbing goes from october 15 to
march 31st so they let us just as soon
as the weather has freezing spraying
you're gonna die trying to get this
substance uh your
your subsistence crab
it's the weather just won't let you get
it but right now there's a little bit of
a break the last three weeks but a storm
came through just now and uh it's ten
foot in the ocean with snow
and and we'd be out right now because my
my partner went out last weekend and
caught a 15 pound king crab he got a
bunch of littler ones but he caught a 15
pound king crab
i mean that that is where you want to be
yeah wow that's really impressive and so
the other thing i noticed from your feed
is that you know you appear to have a
little bit of a sweet tooth so tell me
what's your favorite candy
hey i'm a
kind of a
dessert kind of guy in sweet tooth
i don't know but jelly uh good good
gummies uh from european countries tend
to be very good
they don't have a lot of um they have no
corn
syrup they don't have any preservatives
so all gummies from every country i've
ever had
minus like america or are pretty good
fresh gummies are a big thing you can go
from place to place and there's like you
know shops that are
specializing in it so
i've had
my friend jolly glass send me back you
know ton of stuff from spanibus and
i've had a couple of friends that hooked
me up like that so but i i i got a sweet
tooth you got that right we're only here
once so uh
you better take advantage of whatever
you're given
and so does that extend into edibles or
purely just a you know a sober
confectionary type of deal
edibles hit me like a uh ton of bricks
so um i'm big time into edibles because
i love good edibles but i generally
would make
like uh virgin coconut oil and
maybe one jar of virgin coconut oil a
big size jar and a half a pound of like
uh
xj13 pennywise is a nine to 12 percent
uh cbd
and i would take all that flour and put
it in uh you know hydrate it so you
don't get no chlorophyll after it's
dried i'd rehydrate it and then just
melt off all the keef and make some real
good can of coconut oil
and then uh
my other biggest thing is
are we berry pick in prince william's
town where i fish a lot there are
there's a
there's a lot of berries cloud berries
um
there's black currant there's another
type of a black currant and there's
blueberry and there's salmonberry so i
can and then in my yard generally i have
a lot of berry bushes
so i will pick about 50 pounds of wild
berry every year
and freeze it
and sometimes more than 50 pounds i
might get i might get
sometimes way more [ __ ] buckets and
buckets of it but i'll make uh natural
wild berry syrup and put my rosin from
all of the rosin that i make from kefir
and just make a wide spectrum of natural
wild berry syrup and i'm kind of famous
for it now
so
i i do like that as an edible but i
would promote
anybody that wants edible green goddess
delights is the best edible producer
that i've come across she's a friend of
mine and she makes gummies that wicked
cherry gummies wicked uh
green apple or wicked watermelon wicked
pineapple or they have uh
you know jolly ropes they won the the
mid uh the east the new england high
times cup last year with their blue
raspberry funk juice and they're famous
for their funk juice
and uh their products yesterday i had a
friend come by and said he doesn't get
high on edibles and man i instantly
broke out a 500 milligram bottle of the
funk juice and said try this tonight i
had to eat a 200 milligram jolly rogue
and then we split a package of the
wicked
wicked watermelon gummies and they taste
so good as a candy that
you're not going to stop eating them my
boss is 60s almost 70 year old korean
and a [ __ ] he'll start eating them and
then
could it taste like candy and then you
know be hammered shortly after
even though uh
they're only hundred milligram packages
uh
they're they're they're they've got it
down just right
i've probably never had a better edible
uh no question 100 milligrams would
definitely put my dick in the dirt so my
question though out of all the meat you
hunt or just everything in general
what's your favorite food
wow um i love halibut but i uh
there is really no favorite food because
we get all unlimited amount of spa
shrimp like every friday night and uh
that's a pretty pretty premium thing no
matter where you're at cold water shrimp
is probably one of the best things in
the world and uh
good fish but good moose meat or a goat
of a mountain goat
man that stuff is the mildest best
tasting
i mean they live on cliffs and you
wouldn't think that they'd be edible
because a
barnyard billy goat tastes like grass
and piss and it's harsh man
these things got a big ass nasty set of
balls on them and they're super mature
they're solid muscle but it's like far
contender mildest meat in the world
milder than veal
and uh [ __ ] that that stuff besides it's
impossible to get
so uh you put all that together i'd say
mountain goat doll sheep might be next
to
you got to climb five six thousand feet
and uh
they can see for miles man you're just
not gonna get one so when you do
one of the best flavored animals in the
world of anything i've ever had and
the uh accomplishment of it makes it
taste even twice that good
hell yeah goat curry is where it's at so
to move on to our next subject many
people and you've mentioned it a few
times probably familiar with you as
being the guy with the old school seed
magazine collections so how did this
collection initially begin i know that
bodhi's mentioned in the past he's
traded you some magazines and i'm
certainly grateful to have a few copies
from you but how did this all originate
it just started because we
were buying seeds from
the scentsy seed bank and sssc
i just had my original catalogs from 89
90 in 91
and 30 years later i didn't really look
at them and uh
when i finally did look at them i was
just going holy [ __ ] they're in perfect
shape and it was like reliving glory
days
really
hard and uh
oh my god every feeling you ever had
came back the the sending off your 60
bucks and waiting three months and
paranoia like crazy like
like we're all going to go to prison
over this damn package of seeds and
we're all pooling our money together you
know
for not one of us had enough money to
actually buy seeds back then it's
funnier than [ __ ] so
when i saved them and realized how how
cool it was uh i kind of just looked for
more and uh saw that bodhi had a bunch
of them his friend was a photographer
for the 85 catalog and he had a dozen
uncirculated uh
poppies he gives me a brand new
uncirculated coffee
and it's like
man that guy
i mean what can you say about him but um
he'll go out of his way to make you
happy and and
it's like the coolest guy and i i bummed
his collection
he's that good of a guy i just like
don't know don't know him at all i just
like i'd love to copy him if he could
trust me with him send them to me
and he went over to mexico that's when
he went down to mexico with strandoff
and his he sent his wife to the
post to send him to me after he left and
she sure enough she
i got him in the mail
i was able to copy him and i gave him
back to him at emerald in 17
and um you know thanked him a hundred
times i mean it's such a valuable
history uh
sitting in your hands and you can just
cater it's all categorized and you can
just look it up even the information
that's in there is still viable today
yeah definitely there's nothing i get
more of a kick out of than going back
and looking at some of the strains and
being like oh this is the exact stock
skelly came from
well their technical information on
growing was immense it was like
at least the ssscs
they have a mini book in there they get
more technical than i ever wanted to for
30 years
yeah definitely well you know huge shout
out to stephen olivia they're two
amazing people who everyone in the
community loves
so
next one i wanted to ask you about
what do you feel is the future for the
emerald cup can we expect to see you
there this december or are you
considering going elsewhere the general
sentiment last year was that things felt
a little different would you agree with
that
things felt a lot different from the
first emerald cup and they're a hundred
percent different than the original
emerald cup so it it said you know it's
evolved and um
i
and alaska in general we
had our very first time ever real event
which was a high times cup up here this
year and it was like
no public display of cannabis no smoking
of cannabis no nothing
and
it was so shitty and harsh that it was
like the biggest turn off in the world
so in my view
emerald was 100 success even though it
wasn't the same as it was in prior years
you know the feeling is still right
there and as long as people are still
able to relay their message which i did
see a lot of that you know we're right
there in that circle of love the whole
time
and
um
you still can
be right there with the people that
really mean something in this industry
and
and doing right for the community so in
that sense emerald was successful did
people make as much money no i don't
think so damn i know dungeon vault uh
his dad died that morning that saturday
morning and uh he held a
a booth there and ten thousand dollars
he didn't want to just piss it away or
he would have just walked away from the
whole thing but he said he covered his
bases and
said it was worth it so
you know there's an opinion right there
actually i feel a little bad eric if you
listen to this i had no idea man i spoke
to you that day and i feel bad for not
saying anything about it but yeah you
know you hit it on the head right i
remember
you were kind of out front um the booth
i was at there was an awesome little
crew there like it was you bob hemphill
skunk va duke just every name you could
think of just kind of congregate and
have little chats out the front it was
kind of surreal you just sit there and
to just be like this is this is it right
here this is the little circle you want
to be in
it it truly was i felt um
i felt honored to be able to stand there
with every one of those guys including
you so um to me
i think it's still about
community and uh everybody that was
there that that's the sentiment 100
they're not one of those guys that
didn't have each other's back
yeah definitely as well as having the
community's back which is the big part i
think which linked us all
that too it's um it's a different world
boy i mean
10 and 15 and 20 years every single plot
everything has gone by it's been just a
crazy world where as much as separation
as there is right now with uh you know
people trying to get greedy and stuff
there's just as much uh
ties being made and i think it made the
community a lot stronger and it's
amazing
definitely definitely so
getting towards our little quickfire
questions the last question or two
before those though i wanted to quickly
ask what's your feeling about the rise
of the vape pen i'm not sure if you've
seen the south park episode mocking it
it's pretty funny but
essentially how do you feel they affect
the community in the sense that they're
trying to bridge the gap between like
casual consumer and the general market
do you feel though they're having more
of a detrimental effect than a
beneficial effect overall
you know you're right it's it's a way to
bridge um you know complete different um
generations there's good things about
them and bad things about them it's
funny that they got names like you know
[ __ ] stick and douche flute and
the people that um it's a different
generation that tends to use them it's a
convenient type of thing i can't say i
haven't used them
uh my buddy falconer bought one of the
cookie pens which was uh i guess
refillable only locally so he had it
engraved with his name and just tossed
the sumbitch when it ran out but you
know it was a very good product i
thought and uh
i don't see it being a horrible thing
i'm so neutral about everything that um
there's good things in it and there's
bad things in it i don't like the heavy
metals cheap ass chinese
you know materials being made and uh
untested shitty products being put into
it that is where i have problems with
the whole thing
so how do you feel about the kind of the
introduction of the non-cannabis derived
terpenes to these concentrates or even
the reintroduction of them after they've
been separated out
i am a
big fan of cannabis terpenes i don't
care um if you put them back in do them
uh
you know as a aromatherapy or whatever
but i'm not a fan of vegetable and fruit
derived terps being added to anything
yeah
you know uh you can get real like
terpenes
for flavor and add it to your brewing
supply and it's a whole different thing
there's a hundreds of terpenes that are
just straight up natural 100 natural
terpenes just in liquid form ready to go
back into anything you're brewing
and um
it's 100 good thing but i don't view
marijuana being flavored we've recently
had uh
terpene tests at the lab that i'm you
know i go through and i'm friends with
the workers there uh they have eight
plus percent terpenes
being tested at that lab with you know
only a half a dozen terpenes being
tested and it's an impossibility
and it tells you these people are only
trying to cur they're doing whatever
they can to sell the wreck weed and uh
that's that's a very wrong thing
yeah certainly when you when you
initially said eight percent i was like
what
um but but yeah i guess that makes sense
right there they're trying to game the
system
yeah and if um you know it it kind of
boils down to where it's uh with people
smoking electronic uh
cigarettes the flavors have been um you
know so
pussified that
everybody's sucking on stuff though i
mean i'll walk through cloud of it it
actually smells good to me and they're
actually just getting their nicotine so
it makes it so much less offensive than
a cigarette
but um you know you still got to deal
with the
other things with it i don't i don't
think it's the smartest thing to breathe
glycol or glycerin or any of that [ __ ]
so uh
i'm like a natural flower guy my god you
can't really i don't know how old school
i am but it goes very straight back to i
want a damn joint
yeah definitely i i can't go past the
cheeky bong hit
yeah that too i i mean i love
right before you called like i scrubbed
my bong out with alcohol and filled it
with nice cold water and it's like oh
man
i was smoking that purple
um
wookie v2
and um you know it's really unique
purple profile is different than other
ones man there's nothing like that
flavor you're altering it with uh
five different forms of distillation and
then re
configuring it to your tastes that's
good for you but that's not good for me
yeah no i can agree with that sentiment
so
that brings us to our last few questions
which are kind of quick fire questions
so first one up what's your favorite
strain of all time it's one that nobody
knows about it's waco just a um
just a local stream
but everybody that ever knew of waco
will agrees
and what do you suspect is the genetics
behind that one
uh nl5hs
haha it pops its head up again so flip
side of the spectrum what's your least
favorite strain of all time
oh my god that's so easy
it's uh
dynafem purple power
[ __ ] a friend of mine he he just thought
it'd be smart to grow femmes about 15 10
15 years ago
and it was a clandestine grow basically
his wife didn't want him to grow he dug
out the dog got the basement under the
house and
he gets that [ __ ] and
man it was poor weed
it was dark purple or real pretty purple
lots of uh
violet and magenta and then a lot of
dark purple too but it was a no high
pig
and it tasted like shitty purple
yeah i think we've all had an experience
or two like that
so
what would be your desert island strains
you can take three with you what would
they be
um
purple hindu kush that i got from uh
the nature farm
it it's it's
it's really the one and uh i would say
tkno5 haze the one that we are just now
digging through
and for the other one it's gonna have to
be
that
my old
dream time
chocolate tie that
you know
truly had me going i would say the high
was so high that it could have been damn
opm dipped you know but i was still you
know 12 so
but uh there are no highs like that
anywhere in the world today except opium
yeah wow definitely definitely
definitely so
uh next question is if you could only
recommend one of your strains for
someone to grow out or let's say give
them a packet just so that it's there in
their hands which one pack would you be
given to people
right now i would go with the tk905
uh haze f2
but
until i
you know just rediscovered that i would
have said skunk cabbage i gave out
over 3 000 seeds of it hundreds of packs
of it and then sold hundreds of packs
and i've never had one person ever say
bad about it
so um
pretty damn good one
hell yeah sounds like a solid one so if
you could go back in time to any place
anywhere throughout history to
presumably collect some land race seeds
where would you be heading
you know this
tell me you tell me because you know the
answer
gonna get some tie
well it'll be there but i'm going to the
castle right to the cannabis castle
you look at the collection at that point
in time what was available to the layman
oh my god this like
a hundred years worth of work done
waiting for you
yeah definitely definitely go uh steel
neville's collection
yeah because you're gonna hit it on
every note
including the uh you know g13 in its
purest form and just like everything in
its purest form
yeah yeah yeah sounds like a plan i will
uh i will join you on that one yeah if
we can get a time machine um
we're going there first
i love it so
what are you most excited about that's
going to come from the community in the
near future as far as you can tell
i guess just the
overall
legislation that's being put in
for nationwide legalization i don't
think it's fair for people that live in
arkansas and
texas and um georgia and
the nebraska you know there's
anti-states that it's not fair at all
for medicinal users uh especially them
but and it's a super legitimate thing
they are they're
treating them as outcasts and heavy drug
users and won't give them an opportunity
to uh
you know get any relief from something
that's going to help them without you
know have adverse effects to anybody
it's going to be a good biomass producer
and help the earth as opposed to
you know destroying the earth so
the movement should spread
i don't like the idea of marlboro you
know producing packs of
marijuana cigarettes and then that's
going to be the mainstream thing would
be like you know concentrate pens and
i like it
my dream would be that
have both sides available like what we
do up here we're able to still have a
medical permit up here and i can grow
with my wife i can have 60 plants i can
have a six plant count plus a 24 plant
extended medical account and she can
also so if you could have a happy medium
in all the states of
you know say
i'd like to see 12 plants
because they're harsh now going down to
six and three and then completely
blocking in other places so
the the legalization movement is bound
to happen and the decriminalization and
the rescheduling
of cannabis
uh from schedule one
that is they're going to be the biggest
and best thing in the cannabis movement
it might you know help out corporate
way more than it'll help out the
mom-and-pop but um it'll give relief to
the people that couldn't get it
yeah certainly
certainly so final question for the
interview can we expect to ever see your
seeds available via some seed banks kind
of more commercially available
i'm not against
selling through seed banks but i am
still working a nine to five job even
though the earthquake had destroyed the
body shop and we're at a low point we
are you know fixing to go back online
and i don't really want to walk away
from what i've done for a very long time
and
i will probably
pick up a couple seed banks just because
i've been offered and
it just makes me have to work harder
though to make the commitment and keep
everything happy
so if i didn't uh
so it's either quit working quit fishing
and hunting
oh um
and i don't want to
i don't want to do either one of those
yet i like to work
crazy but yeah i would say yeah i'm
gonna
i'm not i'm not the kind of guy that's
gonna jump on everything either so uh
it's coming
coming to the future near you
hell yeah so with that being said did
you have any comments or shout outs you
wanted to make
to uh
you
um
all australians i think uh they're
probably the next best people
um
next to alaskans and uh
my partners of 35 years
for not ever having a problem with what
i've done and said and we've just always
been together and
my wife of 29 years it's probably the
only thing that
keeps me going
fantastic what a beautiful sentiment to
end it on so once again thank you so
much akb brains for not only being our
friend on the final frontier but also
taking the time to chat with us today
yes it was great i appreciate you man
[Applause]
[Music]
thanks again everyone for sticking
around to the end and a big thank you to
ak beanbrains for taking the time to
chat with us today
[Music]
hope you all enjoyed it i had fun
make sure to go fishing sometime soon
[Music]
and make sure to check out our amazing
sponsors seeds here now hit em up for
all your seed needs 420 australia for
that apparel
and organic gardening solutions for all
things organic gardening
[Music]
big shout out to our friends at
dragonfly earth medicine and to all our
patreon supporters you guys are the mvps
you're the lifeblood of the show
and i just want to be your friend
[Music]
i'll see you guys next time thanks for
hanging around
see you
[Music]