foreign
[Music]
welcome to the next episode of the
podcast you're joined as always by your
boy heavy days here from the upside down
Library bringing you all that inside
information but guess what we couldn't
do it without our amazing sponsors huge
shout out to CT now number one seed bank
in the game all the best breeders all
the best genetics and the latest drops
if you're not satisfied at the end of
your Harvest hit them up they'll sort
you out best in the industry CT now
thank you so much
but in order to be able to properly
evaluate the crop you got to make sure
you have a good harvest free of pests
and contamination and for that you need
to check out the good people at coppet
biological systems these guys have all
the latest and greatest predators and
Technology to ensure that your garden is
Happy thriving pathogen and pest free
you got spider mites check out the
spydex vital with proof of predation
technology built in they turn orange in
front of your eyes to show you that
they're killing bugs what more could you
want well you've got Alpha to check out
the acuparem another killer product both
of these specifically designed for
cannabis products gonna help you to have
the most successful Harvest to date
there's nothing better than knowing that
Garden is free of pathogens guys get on
it you won't regret it
likewise huge shout out to our friends
at promix you've known them and loved
them for years they make the most killer
mediums in the game already inoculated
with micros trichoderma mycorizer but
guess what now you can get their
Standalone pro-mix connects a
mycorrhizal product design to improve
the yields increase the resin increase
the weight turkeys flavonoids all of
it's going to the Moon
don't do your Gardener disservice by not
using a high quality mycorizer product
truly the best in the game guaranteed
score viability is going to improve your
crop no second thoughts about it produce
connect thank you so much get on board
guys it's gonna make a huge difference
finally shout out to our friends at
Charlie's cannabis you know I mean you
love them oklahoma-based better known
producing some of the most fire top
shelf commercially available cannabis
you've ever seen they've recently
started making their own missiles you
will not believe the quality of these
products Fino hunted from scratch using
new exciting genetics all in-house any
products you get from it uses the
material they've grown none of this pass
into a million hand stuff made from trim
from God knows who's grow everything
in-house high quality Charlie's cannabis
just remember guys Charlize the birds
finally a huge shout out to the patreon
gang you are the lifeblood of the show
you guys helped to ensure the episodes
continue to be made if you want early
access to content you want to hear
unheard interviews get access to
exclusive giveaways prizes Discord so
much more go check out the patreon
www.patreon.com
on this episode we're joined by the head
honcho behind AGC Co a man who's been in
the industry a very long time and has a
lot of wisdom to share we're incredibly
grateful to have Todd McCormick on the
show
here to talk all things history
Northern Lights skunk
Hayes
old school genetics
and so much more
hope you enjoy
let's get into it
alrighty gang we're back for another one
and today we are both excited and
grateful to have one of the true
cannabis historians of the scene on the
show a big welcome to the editor of the
emperor where's no clothes as well as
The Man Behind AGC code
Todd McCormick thank you so much for
joining us today
good afternoon thank you for having me
on
my friend first question we'd love to
ask our guests what are you smoking on
at the moment
that's funny this is actually a haze
combination I have a lot of uh the
original older genetics and I really
love original Haze and I've kind of
crossed it with everything I have and
this is one of those concoctions it's an
on Haze which is a an old Neville taste
that I used uh I crossed it against in
our original Haze male and I made
something called on Haze and then I took
that and I've crossed this with
something called a super glue which was
like an Afghan Northern Lights uh it's
really nice it I some ways I was trying
to recreate that old nl5 Haze that we
all used to love so much
uh lovely and like how do you feel this
one compares to the old nl5 Haze
um
it's different you know because every
phenotype tweet we pick are different
even if the plants are brothers and
sister seeds
um there you can still get a lot of
variation between them too you know you
can have one brother or one sister who's
kind of overweight another one that's
really skinny another super smart
another one that can't do math so it's
like that with plants and it's similar
the original Haze is really the smell
and the taste that defines Haze and
everything else is like Fruity or gassy
uh that leathery kind of Afghan uh
sticky skunky smell we call it in North
America
is very different from the terpenes that
you find in the that Colombian original
Haze mixture it's truly unique and I
love it so I I really like it however it
comes out because I I just favor the
scent and the flavor so much
yeah lovely lovely and do you find
incorporating some of those more modern
genetics brings a little something extra
to the table or it maybe just takes it a
little different place so to speak
uh well it's kind of the other way
around because original Haze is really
the first hybrid it was the first bread
in the Santa Cruz mountains over here
near where I live back in 1969. uh came
along around five six years before skunk
one which is what I would call the
second uh real hybrid that that was bred
and then became kind of famous
um
and later on when I first got exposed to
Haze it was in the early 90s I visited
the Cannabis Castle in 1994 with Jack
Herer I was standing next to Jack when
Ben dronkers
um
gave the Jack hero variety its name and
in christened it um and I was able to
smoke some of the northern lights and
the haze crosses that were at the castle
at that time I also lived in Amsterdam
for over a year after that and visited
numerous times after this but it it
really was different for me because I
had been growing for 10 years at that
time but I'd never experienced Haze
so it was just it was a wow and I had
never experienced cannabis that gave me
like a coffee a morning coffee effect
where I felt like invigorated and
talkative and engaged I usually a lot of
the varieties of cannabis are more like
you know you relax you nod out you you
know you're in your own little world
um but not so much with Haze and I was
really intrigued and it took me years I
I picked up seeds I grew in Northern
Lights Number Five by Hayes I grew the
Jack Herer seeds that
um they gave Jack at the time I wish I
still had them and when I lived in
Holland I was able to get a really nice
Northern Lights number five clone it was
technically the plant that won the 1996
Cannabis Cup as a dirt grown pot but it
has a hydroponically grown pop and it
was really dirt grown it was truly
exceptional and I loved it and then
years and years go by uh 2012 I was in
Amsterdam receiving the Cannabis culture
award along with Dr Lester
Richard Branson of all people and Skunk
Man Sam came to the event and I used the
opportunity to ask him and I'd known him
since 94. I I actually was very silly
and was like hey will you sell me the
original hay seeds that you sold Neville
and after he got finished laughing at me
um he told me that he'd consider it and
then he asked me what else I wanted and
I felt like a dummy and I thought I was
like you know I don't know what to say
he says I think you want all the seeds I
saved for myself and I don't sell to
anybody and I was like oh that's exactly
the seeds I was looking for and he said
bring over your best option come over
and uh we'll talk about it so I went
over there and it was really a wonderful
experience you know Skunk Man Sam is
credited with saving original Haze
um he he his home was next to the
gentleman who I only know is the the
letter G who was the surfer who first
bred Hayes and they were neighbors and
the guy down the street was uh his uh
two initials were RL he went on to make
the 1976 original Haze poster that
became really famous and um
and also uh the other neighbor they had
down the street was the guy that wrote
the Psychedelic encyclopedia so it was
quite quite the block over there back in
the day so like uh but he uh skunked
Mansion realized that the original Haze
was a unique cultivar and he he saved it
by not
um losing it most breeders cross what
they have with what they've got and they
make new varieties and they think
they're improving it but they get
further and further and further from
that original creation and it's not
always for the better unfortunately
um so what Sam did which was unique is
he kept it through IBL breeding which is
only allowing the males and females from
that particular variety to breed with
each other so that he could capture
those genetics and work with them as as
the generations passed
um he took selected plants and he
created varieties like skunk by Haze uh
By Thai uh he calls that one uh
um then he has a he has a whole shitload
of in all reality I feel like a Fool's
listing them all off but what he did is
he gave me the original Hayes seeds and
then he gave me all of his favorite
outcrosses with it like uh which was
really quite beautiful because think of
it like colors it's like getting a
primary color and then all his favorite
secondary colors and you can go home and
do art uh so I was really happy and um
when I realized this I realized that I
had brother and sister seeds of the
plants that Neville had and Neville had
two male Haze plants that he used to
breed with everything that's quite
famous he had his hay and Hayes c
um those two plants came originally
through Skunk Man Sam and
um the seeds that he gave me were
essentially brothers and sisters to
those males so when I got home I took a
cutting I had of uh Neville's Haze and
then back crossed it if you will to a
male original Haze plant because I
wanted uh to turn up the haze I wanted
more Haze you know uh so I liked it and
um what made Neville's Hayes unique to
original Haze is that touch of Northern
Lights which was a little bit of Afghan
that it had
um because the recipe for for Neville's
Hayes was Northern Lights Number Five by
Hayes uh Hey C I think crossed back to
Haze a which was his other or not
crossed back to but crossed out to his
other Haze and that was what he called
Neville taze and then he took that plant
later on across it with skunk one and
called that super silver haze
um but
that little bit of Northern Lights uh
really is something that I always just
loved and um at the time I didn't have
original Northern Lights I just had you
know things like OG Kush and super glue
which are very reminiscent um in in all
reality so
I you know what I was doing is trying to
kind of recreate what I had with with
some of these genetics because going
back to Skunk Man Sam is like going back
to to the original Source he's the guy
that initially sold the seeds to Neville
in the first place and um you know he's
he's really the genius behind skunk one
and quite a few other varieties even
hemp varieties such as vanilla just
really quite incredible yeah I mean the
the breadth of his work is is phenomenal
and I mean on a personal curiosity how
did your Haze back cross end up turning
out for you
I loved on Hayes I've used it quite a
bit um in 2019 I used the mail from that
variety that I created
um and I crossed it against most of
these
um like clone only cultivars floating
around California because when I was
working with it
um I was realizing that you know when
you do a breed uh when you're breeding
with cannabis a lot of times the female
is a more dominant uh on in The Prodigy
than the male so I was able to kind of
use my on Haze as almost like a neon
filter where you where there's there's
no real color neon but uh you because
when you take red blue green and you
want to make it neon it's still red blue
green and what I wanted to do with a lot
of these clone only cultivars such as
green crack and OG Kush and train wreck
and others is I wanted to retain that
red blue green but I wanted to add a
little bit of spiciness to it which was
on Haze and um
happy 420 from California and uh I
always stop at 420 and then later join
and take a little breath and it's like a
little moment of a meditation but
um but that's what I did in it and it
worked out really well and then
you know as twist of fate would have it
I you know after Neville passed away I
wrote an article called Legacy of a
legend and um because he most certainly
was a legend and
um I got this comment from a guy named
Greg and he alluded to like Northern
Lights living on through Neville's work
and I I knew Greg's name I knew that the
guy that supposedly brought Northern
Lights to Neville was named Craig and
that he was from Seattle and we've heard
the story and uh I couldn't imagine he
was commenting on my my post so I
messaged him and said hi and uh tried to
introduce myself and he just said you
know Todd I've been following you from
since the 90s you know like like I know
exactly who you are it says why I'm
following your Facebook page and we
started talking and and it was really
nice and uh he told me that uh he always
wanted to get original skunk one and he
always wanted original Haze but he
couldn't get him through Neville and
that unfortunately him and Neville had a
falling out I'd say about a year and a
half after they started doing business
you could say uh Neville kind of went
behind his back try to buy some of the
seeds from another party and that was
that was that and it's interesting
because I am a collector of books about
cannabis and I have all the old Neville
catalogs and there's actually a
paragraph and one of the pre-catalog
letters that he wrote saying bad news my
Northern Light supplier is cut off and
and I was just it just stunned me a
little to get it from Greg you know and
what had happened and why that happened
why you got cut off and it's just like
wow and um
at the time I I sent Greg over the
original Haze and skunk just to be
courteous you know he's a legend he
deserves it let him enjoy these genetics
uh for sure
um and then I bought a um maybe a year
plus later almost two uh we had been
staying in contact and none he called me
and said hey my uh my sister passed away
and I I said wow I'm really sorry Lisa
will thank you but not why I'm calling
um I wanted your address want to return
the favor my family found some of my old
Northern Light seeds and one of her
freezers and they're from the early 80s
from even before I met Neville and uh
I'm getting germination out of him and
I'd like to see what you get so I was
like blown away and uh send them my
address and he sent me Northern Lights
Number Two he sent me one lights number
five he sent me what is called purest
Indica which is the Afghan that he got
from this gentleman named um Murphy
Stevens and he Murphy Stevens wrote a
book called how to grow marijuana indoor
is under lights one of the best cannabis
cultivation books and I I literally have
every cannabis cultivation book in the
70s really quite incredible he explains
um like cloning he explained CO2 he
explains
some of the things that have become
Mainstay like taking mothers and and
doing Selections in in our work of today
but was kind of unheard of back then and
they were friends because of this under
indoor Sun Shop it was called uh and
they he'd go in there and buy equipment
and I guess uh Steve Murphy uh Murphy
Stevens was his pen name but his real
name was the other way around Steve
Murphy gave Greg some of these Afghan
seeds gave him four of them in the 70s
and that is what became uh the Northern
Lights lines and then uh so what he did
is he you know Greg f2d them you know
which would be to mix the brothers and
sister scenes together and made a whole
bunch of them and he called that purist
Indica because that was the one he got
from Murphy Stevens and then what he
started to do is cross outcross it to
other Afghans that he got from Oregon
California and then more tropical plants
and I asked him what the numbers
represented when he sent them to Neville
and he said the numbers were one through
like 11 or 12 were based on how close
they were to that purist Indica you know
one uh being like pierced Indica would
more be like zero because if you're
counting it would be like oh comes first
periodica first hybrid is number one
second hybrid is number two third fourth
and so on like number five he told me
was actually it crossed with what at the
time they thought was a Hawaiian but he
has always believed was a northern
Mexican variety and uh it was a little
more tropical so each of the plant
numbers became more tropical and truly
fascinating I mean from my perspective
uh as a historian and then just an
overall cannabis geek you know I started
growing in 1984 and I was reading High
Times back then like we all were and uh
and it I don't know it just like a
little boy's dream to now be in
communication with this guy and you know
he's in his 70s a retired Marine he's
you know just incredible and so I
started growing them out and I had these
old books and I have these old photos
and later on I'll send you some pictures
it's truly remarkable because
it looks exactly like the first page in
America Murphy Stevens book uh it just
blows blew my mind and um so it's been
really wild to now have these original
Northern Lights and now I'm starting to
play with those and the original Haze
and the original skunk and it's quite
the palette uh if you were thinking of
it like like art it's it's quite the
color palette to start with and I
actually have more of these original
colors than even was given to Neville at
the time because Neville never received
all of Skunk Man Sam's favorite
outcrosses with Hayes
um he never received a batch of original
hay seeds he only got a couple males so
he was unable to do what I did which was
reproduce as an F2 or an IBL original
Haze
um and basically unlock it and share the
genetics he had to actually use them as
hybrids which uh started appearing in
the the Holland seed bank catalog in
um prior to 88 to 85 six seven there's
not even the word Haze mentioned in any
of those catalogs
um and there's not even the hey the word
Haze isn't even mentioned in the super
long High Times article that was uh
published in March of 87
um because I came to the conclusion that
Neville just didn't have Haze at the
time and Greg told me that too and then
I've heard it from other people as well
but I think it's a real opportunity I
mean there's been a lot of
you know reading uh done in the past 30
years plus since the 80s and
unfortunately I don't think a lot of it
was for the best I think that a lot of
people were breeding for uh for for
yields and and and for quickness rather
than overall quality and terpenes and
unfortunately I think we
um somewhat lost our way with some of
these older varieties and now that I
have thick original skunk one and
original Haze and original Northern
Lights uh in various forms I am it's
like a time machine to me because I was
growing back in the 80s and now to have
to be able to grow these again it's just
truly quite remarkable
sorry that was so long-winded uh that
was incredible and I uh I already have
that feeling in the back of my neck I'm
like this is gonna be a good one I can
tell really yeah a myriad of different
Avenues we could choose to go in after
you gave me so many good little leads I
could pull on I guess something I wanted
to discuss is this topic of Neville
being a bit disliked it's an interesting
one because I've spoken to a lot of
people who know him and the most
consistent thing I hear is he was a bit
disliked that he was a complex man and
although undeniably he did some of the
best breeding we've ever seen he also
burnt a lot of bridges and I guess my
question is do you feel like in a case
like Neville he's sort of one of those
people where you've got to separate the
art from the artist and did you ever
have any personal interactions with him
that's a beautiful way to put it
um I did have interactions with Neville
he was always nice to me when I met him
um I played chess with him once uh we
smoked Haze um I enjoyed it I I you know
I grew up around drugs as a kid I was a
little biker kid and um my cousin Kathy
died from a heroin overdose way back in
the early 90s before I ever met Neville
and I grew up around people that
unfortunately uh did abuse alcohol and
were flirting with heroin and
um you know when when you grow up around
it as a little kid you kind of feel it
and you know I'm not I'm I I don't do
hard drugs I don't drink I smoke hash I
smoke grass uh kind of square in a way
um but you know other than cannabis we
didn't have what we get high on in
common and unfortunately
you know Neville you know what I what I
respect about Neville and I'd like to
say up front is when you read that
article back in 1987 he's not a victim
he's never been a victim of his own
circumstance he doesn't portray himself
as a victim he deals with his addiction
issues like an adult and you know he's
remorseful for him he's realistic about
trying to struggle to deal with it I
have nothing but empathy for someone
who's dealing with alcohol uh and and
drug addiction it's like it's like a
disease I get people say well it's a
it's a consensual disease you you smoke
the stuff you drink the stuff this is
your fault but chemically it gets a
little deeper than that and
unfortunately I believe that that
you know his substance abuse absolutely
compromised his personal relationships
with a lot of good people and
unfortunately when I was writing Legacy
of the legend I know a lot of people
that knew Neville that was in business
with Neville that like really close to
novel none of them wanted to say a damn
thing and uh and unfortunate you know
because you know it's is it so much
cheaper at the bridges or it was his
addictions that caused him to burn the
bridges I mean you you know but he did
burn Bridges I I've interviewed Skunk
Man Sam I've interviewed Greg uh and and
they told similar stories around the
same time about how Neville ripped them
off knocked off their seeds went behind
their back it killed their relationships
with them and um you know Greg and Sam
don't know each other so so they're not
there's they they didn't meet until
recently when I gave each other their
numbers and said hey you guys you know
they're both in your 70s you're both
Legends you should talk to each other uh
but up until now they never had
communication so it's interesting for me
a journalist to hear these unedited you
know versions of of events from the
people who who were really in in touch
and have the genetics now and and had
the genetics then and um you know
and then you know and as far as Neville
I and I don't mean to to bash uh you
know has a someone who grew up in the
80s he was a hero to me in all reality
like like a rock star Led Zeppelin there
was there was the Holland feed bank and
unfortunately though the more you get
into the history of it you know like
Neville only picked up a Mel Frank row
book in 1981. uh he was inspired by it
uh and he started the the Holland seed
bank 84. uh initially started selling
seeds he was collecting from Dutch
coffee shops that he hadn't grown and he
literally had a disclaimer saying I
can't vouch for these I didn't make them
I think he was selling for like 25 cents
each
um and His World changed when he met
Skunk Man Sam and got that whole catalog
of really worked California genetics um
California Orange skunk one Hindu Kush
Afghani one turban poison none of those
never never had anything to do with and
um and realistically at the time with
the drug war and everything you know a
lot of people weren't really stepping up
to say oh yeah that's me that I did that
and uh he he begot these genetics 1984
and kind of took credit for the work of
many people that came before him and I
don't believe now in today's cannabis
economy or or or community that if
somebody was growing wheat for two or
three or four years even let's give them
81 which I understand he wasn't growing
in 81 82 or 83. he did grow in 84
outside of his apartment before he got
the Cannabis Castle uh and it didn't
work out it was Outdoors it you know
that the winner came it was just a in
the backyard type of thing and it wasn't
until he moved into the castle that they
started growing indoors and he started
getting help from people that went to
the university
um so really he had no experience
breathing he was a heroin addict who was
trying to get off heroin got a loan from
the government started selling seeds
bought seeds that were really good and
started mixing them together and I don't
want to say I mean it's like these DJs
that take really good music from One
artist and really good music from
another artist and mash it together and
it sounds great on the dance floor but
they're not musicians man they can't
they they can't write Love Me Do they
they're not making these beats they
they're just taking somebody else's work
and jingling it together and and their
little rock stars on their own Merit but
on their own they're really not
musicians and and I and I hate to say
this but I don't see Neville as much of
a breeder
um because he was handed such fantastic
varieties and he crossed them together
mainly because he wasn't paying the
people for their seeds anymore so
unfortunately we saw things like skunk
number two and and him selling a
half-price seeds from and then literally
in the catalog it says you know there
was like a an unexpected pollination and
I'm selling these at half price and you
know if if Mr Jack Daniels went to a
Distillery and sold them his number
Seven whiskey recipe and then you know a
year or so The Distillery realized you
know what don't need Jack anymore we can
knock off this whiskey recipe and send
it out the door tell him to beat feet I
don't think it would be a good energy
and that's exactly what Neville did to
Greg it's exactly what he did this on
plant Sam so unfortunately yeah things
went the way they did and and then when
you get into the the Handover of the
Holland seed bank to Scentsy seeds it
was continued in all reality I mean you
know initially when Ben bought the
Holland seed bank he attempted to
trademark all of the super skunk skunk
one Haze names uh and sent cease and
desist letters to other seed companies
telling them you can't use my names
and uh Skunk Man Sam got a letter and
unfortunately for Ben he had already
registered these varieties with the
plant registry and technically was the
legal breeder of them in the EU and sent
Ben a letter saying no you don't have
the right you can use the name skunk one
on a lighter or on a t-shirt but as it
comes to cannabis I own that and if you
try to stop other people from using a
name that I came up with in the 70s I
will go into court and block you so Ben
lost the ability to uh basically
trademark and register these these names
that are now very much public domain you
know as as were the genetics in all
reality because Skunk Man Sam had been
selling seeds by the kilo long before he
met Neville
uh and um plenty of people had skunk one
seeds and or you know California Orange
and you know originally it was Mel Frank
who made Durban Poison and Afghan number
one so it was really a lot of other
people you know that that really were
the reason why the the Holland seed bank
had such great varieties in the first
place you know uh in a really in one of
his last interviews if not his last
interview Neville is in mishka's book
and uh he talks about how he was never
able to make anything worth anything
from Land race varieties of cannabis and
he gives credit to the Breeders who came
before him who took things like Afghan
you know Colombian gold and Acapulco
Gold and turned it into skunk one and
you know Colombian genetics and turned
it into Haze and in the first place and
I honestly don't know how spectacular
the Holland seed bank would have been if
he hadn't gotten those American genetics
from Sam and Greg and others through the
80s on reality if he was just left to
the Jamaican Colombians and Thai seeds
coming in through the coffee shops it
might have been a very different story
yeah very very intriguing and very
interesting to hear sort of a more
inside take on it all because I think
that was I wouldn't say a pet peeve but
something which I always felt uneasy
about was how yeah people always said oh
you know Neville's had a shady pass but
no one would ever say to me what so it's
good to hear like you know this is some
of what it boiled down to and I guess
the natural question which comes to mind
for me is in my mind I always thought a
lot of those raw bass genetics never
used to make the crosses came from like
one of those mythical land race trips he
did but are you sort of more of the
opinion that it was more given to him
for the most part
well Northern Lights was sent to him as
seeds one through eleven I believe one
through twelve and um and he made some
of them very famous the number five he
used the number six he used the number
two he used extensively
um Greg did send tell me that he never
sent Neville the purest Indica the the
zero if you will the original egg of
Northern Lights because he didn't want
Neville to have
something better than what he had he
sent Neville to hybrids
um so you know I think that growers in
some ways have been wise to the fact
that they're going to get burned head to
a degree and uh they've wanted to
protect their IP in various ways and
Simon Schmidt who's Dutch who knows uh
serious seeds he's a good friend of mine
absolute hero of mine really
um but when he first started serious
seeds he only started with three
varieties
um AK-47 chronic and Cali mist and they
were all f1s and he held the parent
plants to each of those three varieties
and he could make those seeds forever
and ever and ever and if somebody bought
those seeds and then crossed them
together or outcross them now you've got
something different and um and because
of that you would always go back for
that F1 Cali mist from serious seeds
because it was exactly what it was last
time you bought the seeds and that was a
way that he protected his intellectual
property if you will nobody could really
make an F1 of Cali Mist but Simon
um so you know as this is when you look
at it that way uh that was happening
even with Greg that's why Greg didn't
send him the original purist Indica
that's why Skunk Man Sam didn't give
that's why that's why Neville never got
original AC is because he didn't want
him to be able to have two of them and
and make seeds of them he he wanted to
kind of keep control of the variety a
little bit because
you know I get it uh and you know in all
reality Neville had to wait for the haze
he didn't get it or even offered to him
in 85 or 84 when he first bought the
seeds from from Sand but also there
wasn't much desire for them because here
there are these long flowering you know
not even great yielding comparatively
you know the the Dutch and indoor
Growers were looking for quick flowering
short plants that yielded that heavy
resin that made indoor growing practical
and Haze sure the hell didn't make
indoor growing practical it was quite
the opposite so not there wasn't really
a demand for them even when I was living
there in 1996 people I mean Cali missed
sure nl5a is sure but were people
growing original Haze no and very few
people were actually breeding with it
because not that many people actually
had you know an interest in dealing with
these long flowering finicky plants and
uh in 1996 I was living in Amsterdam and
I was working at positronics which is
owned by Bernard and the gentleman named
old Ed who originally taught uh Bernard
how to grow seedless cannabis in the 70s
was over there and um he and I worked
together for a year growing out various
varieties of ponzi's genetics and
unfortunately you know after 10 years of
you know politely I'll say haphazard
breeding or breeding that wasn't for
let's say overall potency or or flavor
or scent but instead quickness and yield
a lot of them didn't have that they
weren't that they were kind of watered
down or muddied up would be a polite way
to say it and uh what me and Ed were
trying to do was make selections and
then try to make some f1s that could
kind of bring back some hybrid figure in
uniformity and consistency to the seeds
that posi was selling and
you know I I part of what I wanted to do
when I started my seed company was jump
a way back and get seeds directly from
Skunk Man Sam and Skip Neville skip
Bernard skip the whole Dutch scene you
know
um because
nothing against I mean I got nothing but
love and respect for a lot of my my
friends in Holland but but realistically
the the purpose of what they were making
seeds for was not necessarily the
purpose of what the California people
who were breeding which was quality over
quantity and everything else then they
got out there and it was about you know
quantity quickness and quality kind of
went down and I think a lot of people
that were visiting the Netherlands
coffee shop scene through the 90s would
attest that the the Cannabis wasn't
getting better over the years it was
kind of getting more and more uh
homogeneous and uh and and lackluster
and just very similar to each other and
a lot of that was because of a lot of
inbreeding and uh
you know I hopefully what I'm doing now
is kind of taking it back to the heart
of it and going for the quality and
going for those terpenes and going for
that scent and that taste over the
potency even because like I I feel that
if you have a good joint like this one
is getting me totally stoned a hard time
getting through it but uh if you have a
good joint even if it's not that potent
you'll go back and roll a second or if
it's good hash you'll go back and and
pack another dab
um but if it's not that good it doesn't
matter how potent it is
you know it's like when you drink you
know you don't drink straight alcohol to
get drunk you kind of like the nuances
of the wine or the beer or whatever it
is you're drinking so I think that's the
same with cannabis and I think as as we
get back into that quality over quantity
and quickness we're gonna see a lot
better cannabis hitting the scene and
unfortunately because of like that quick
mat you know mindset all the varieties
that were 10 weeks and you know 10 to 16
weeks really don't get grown by people
anymore but they're still around and
think of it like a box of crayons that
have 16 crayons we're only playing with
the first 10 crayons there's crayons
number 11 12 13 14 15 and 16 there and
people aren't even doing art with them
yet and and that's in a sense why I'm
really excited to be bringing the
original Haze genetics back and and kind
of moving towards these equatorial
varieties that used to be shunned
because of bag of Peel and growth
characteristics but were really great I
mean once you started smoking it you'd
love it you know but would you get past
the bag appeal
to get your joint rolled up and a lot of
people don't they they they eat with
their eyes rather than with their taste
buds and I think that that's going to
change as we move towards concentrates
and extracts and people are doing dabs
and you're feeling the terpenes and
feeling the the Synergy of cannabinoids
if you will and I I think people will
start buying cannabis based on how it
makes them feel over how it looks
in a bag
yeah I I certainly hope so myself and
you know so many Avenues we could go off
onto with that one I guess the first
thing I wanted to quickly run by you was
you mentioned this idea of Growers
protecting their intellectual property
and I think that's still a relevant
discussion in today's market
specifically we hear some breeders not
many but some who are quite vocal about
even if you buy their seeds you still
need to ask them if you're going to
breed with it or something to that
effect whereas a good number of breeders
take the opposite point of view and
they're like man if you bought them
they're yours where do you stand on that
issue
some strange I stand on both sides of
the fence I completely I call it public
domain genetics nobody invented cannabis
I wouldn't have this wonderful joint of
haze if it wasn't for you know some guy
named G that was playing with it a year
before I was born so I'm grateful for
the you know soldiers of the Giants I
stand upon and I try to give credit
where credits do it at every corner of
this
um
but that said
um you know when somebody like Simon you
use serious seeds as an example uh wants
to put a company together and put out a
product like Cali Mr AK or chronic
um I think they should have a right to
be able to try to make something unique
and it and by doing it the way Simon did
it which was so intelligent it gives his
customers a reason to go back and get
those F1 seeds from him because they
know why they they have a reason to
um because they know it's authentic and
he's the only one that held the parents
um now the way it works in plant
breeding uh if you buy seeds and you
outcross with them the prodigies your
creation okay but uh you know to take
somebody's seeds and just mix them
together and end up and to like you know
do what so many did which is to F2 them
without permission is not so cool I I
had original haze from 2012 till 2019
and I was growing it and playing with it
and it wasn't until I started my seed
company that I called up Skunk Man Sam
and formally asked his permission to
make seeds of it and uh you know within
his good graces I did he even consulted
on how he recommended I reproduce those
original seeds that he gave me so that I
would get the best you know quality out
of The Prodigy and have the most
variability in selection and I
appreciated that and he he did too and
when I got the original Northern Light
seeds from Greg I again I asked his
permission and um and not only did he
give me his permission he gave me his
encouragement because his goal has been
to share the genetics with people and
you know to spread the medicine and uh
and it's beautiful I mean a lot of
people don't know Skunk Man Sam's goal
in 1970s was to create a true beating or
a relatively true breeding variety
because he was an acid-eating hippie and
he wanted his friends to be able to get
the seeds and to be able to mix them
together the brothers and sisters
together and to have the Prodigy come
out relatively close to the parents and
normally that doesn't happen like when
you mix quality related genetics
together you get like a dog's breakfast
you get you know a lot of variation the
haze has got a lot of variation in its
genetics it's not relatively true
breeding at all it's the opposite of
skunk one and when I asked man Sam you
know why how did you do that he said I
didn't nature did he said I just had to
cross together enough plants to find the
ones that when I crossed them together
they had the effect of being able to be
a relatively true breeding plant and I
was just like wow and it kind of went to
show how humble he was there's a great
article that we republi in our magazine
grow called Sun soil seeds in Seoul and
he wrote it for what was called blotter
magazine which was an LSD magazine that
was published by the gentleman who would
go on to publish the Psychedelic
encyclopedia and he wrote this really
long breakdown of how people can learn
how to breed and how we created things
like skunk one
um
and he was trying to share the
information I mean anybody who's done a
lot of acid would understand that kind
of like feeling the Oneness with uh all
of humanity and that was his goal his
goal was to turn skunk one into this
massive public domain genetic that would
only create good cannabis for the rest
of the world once they got the seeds and
that's why skunk one has been bred and
into everything because it adds this
consistency and uniform to practically
everything that you cross it with uh
it's Unique in the Cannabis Kingdom and
um
yeah that's in a way why it became so
famous
yeah truly one of the most famous
friends of all time and interesting to
hear the back story yeah that's that's
cool the way Sam's quite humble about it
I was interested to quickly loop back
for a moment and ask you you know you
spoke about the Holland seed bank and
positronics and serious seeds and one of
the seed banks besides the seed bank
itself the Holland seed bank um like
yourself you know a lot of reverence for
them I also really really looked up to
Super sativa seed Club where did you
rank them
um
you know
I believe that Carl got the inspiration
to create sssc out of what Neville was
doing with seed bank
um and uh Carl also went and purchased
seeds from uh Skunk Man Sam as well
everybody did really when Sam moved
there and started working we're not on
the green team they were providing seeds
to all of these you know the Flying
Dutchman and others that started up even
before Scentsy seeds with Scentsy seeds
it was the Scentsy seed Club it was
technically
SSC and not sssc which was a super city
of C club and um they were all doing
this uh to a degree and uh sscc was cool
I mean they got you know some of the
haze genetics and some of the skunk and
and some of the stuff that Sam had at
the time and they made some cool things
with it but I would say they probably
lost most of it like many of my friends
did over there by not being mindful like
Sam was and keeping it isolated from all
the other work he was out Crossing and
making sure that he created an IBL line
that was vast enough that you could go
back to the original genetics and they
didn't have the Afghan and they didn't
have Hindu Kush and they didn't have
Thai didn't have anything else it was
just that three-way Colombian and
unfortunately a lot of them lost it and
when I started up my seed company one of
the first orders I received was from
sssc so I you know they wanted the
original hazeback and uh unfortunately
their seeds got sent back to me because
I didn't have a photo sanitary
certificate and Amsterdam was being a
kind of rude that day I guess at Customs
but I'm sure I'll be able to get them
the seeds in the future
you know but I I think they played a
great role in this too you know um I
think these seed banks were the first
Heroes because they were the brave ones
that made them available to everybody
and we all benefited from it
um to a large degree you know
unfortunately Neville worked with some
you know shitty people and he was turned
in by the guy that was actually sending
his seeds for him
um from Michigan so the story in a short
way goes that um somebody called Neville
up back when Neville was answering the
phone and drummed up a friendship over
the phone with Neville from Michigan and
Neville invited him out to the castle
and this guy um Anthony Ray kogo went
out there numerous times and something
happened with the seed sender that
Neville had in America Neville would
send cans of seeds to the Americas and
then um in bulk and then somebody in
America would get addresses and
quantities of which variety to send to
these addresses and they would package
it up in America and send 10 in 2015
whatever seeds out at the time and
unfortunately
um
Anthony rayco was was jealous was angry
something at Neville and unfortunately
um he had been sending Neville seeds for
about 18 months and he got busted for
bringing from what I understand hashish
into a jail to one of his friends in
Michigan and got arrested for it Neville
on sent money to him to help him on the
bequest of his wife I've read this in
the court paperwork the interesting
story is a little bit is that after
Neville passed away uh right before he
passed away actually about two weeks I
was arguing with somebody on Instagram
that was claiming that sunk man Sam
turned in Neville and it wasn't true it
isn't true it there's no truth to it
whatsoever and uh the guy that I was
arguing with that was making this point
um fancied himself an attorney so he
went to a court website and
um downloaded Neville's paperwork he
downloaded the two indictments he
downloaded the statements from the
witnesses and the police
and uh contacted me and said hey you're
right Skunk Man Sam had nothing to do
with Neville getting busted it was this
guy named Ray Anthony cogo that used to
send his Siege and I said how can you be
so certain and he said I'll send you the
paperwork I paid 29.60 and and I
downloaded all the paperwork anybody can
and I was a little shocked so he sent
over the the court paperwork and I got
and I'll send it to you afterwards
actually you can it's quite intriguing
um but it was the whole statement of
Anthony rayco the statement was taken in
uh January of 1994 and um it starts in I
would say March or April May of 1989
when Anthony Ray Coco willfully went
into the DEA with all of these addresses
that he had saved even though Neville
told him to destroy the addresses after
he sent the seeds this SOB saved the
address is brawl the addresses to the
DEA and turned in Neville turned in all
these people at the same time and cut a
deal for himself
incredible and um
truly amazing because unfortunately
Neville was paying him to send the seeds
but they made a deal that Neville sold
him the recipe to his nutrients and this
guy came back and started selling Coco's
nutrients this is still for sale today
and brags about the fact that he got the
recipe from the Netherlands and and once
he had that recipe and his and he was
making the fertilizer he really didn't
need Neville anymore he didn't need to
work for Neville anymore so he turned
him in and he acted as a undercover
witness if you will 1989 90 91 92 93
because they didn't take his sworn
statement until January of 94. so poor
Neville didn't even know
who did it for the at first you know you
you take 1990 91 92 93. it was a it was
a mystery to Neville all the way up
until the case was dismissed in I think
O2 uh and only then was this paperwork
made public and then there was no
internet like this so you couldn't go to
pacer.net or got dot gov and download
the court file so so it took a long time
I think for Neville to truly find out
who was really behind turning in the
seed bank and what the real story was
but unfortunately it was this guy
Anthony rayco and um and that's
inevitably what took Neville down
it's so interesting you know what's the
saying I remember skunk VA said it uh
real life is always more interesting
Than Fiction or something like that but
it sort of holds true and the the
general question that comes to mind for
me after hearing that is we often see a
lot of people blaming a lot of stuff on
Dave Watson and I've had Ryan Lee um
Chimera who you're probably familiar
with I like Ryan a lot Ryan stayed at my
house before yeah there you go right and
and Ryan is adamant that you know the
same as you Sam's another never done any
of this [__] so my question is why
do you think he's the scapegoat for all
the bad stuff that happens
you know when I I don't think he is a
scapegoat for any of it I think Neville
I you know I I to put it in plain
English I think Neville's a [__]
[__] for starting the room as he
started about David Watson you know
calling somebody a de agent who's akin
to calling him a pedophile it was the
most horrible thing you could do it's
the biggest Trader in the world and um
and and and he knew it wasn't true he
knew he was lying he knew it he knew it
and he lied anyway and he did it to
bolster his own reputation and he and he
was bolstering the work his own work
based on the work of of company Sam
David Watson I mean there's no two shits
about it I mean David was the genius I
mean David still is a genius I mean you
know talk about stability he just
celebrated I think his 52nd wedding
anniversary the same woman I mean you go
back to David's history in 1970 him and
his girlfriend sold all their personal
possessions and and took a hippie trip
from London to Morocco to Germany and
hitchhiked all the way across to India
and through Afghanistan and push
mountains and and they lived in India
for a year David collected the genetics
he brought them back to Santa Cruz he
started his breeding three or four years
later he came up with skunk one and all
along the way he was collecting genetics
if it wasn't for him I wouldn't be
smoking Haze it would have been log lost
40 45 years ago
um you know he was really a savior of
the seed and on a level that no one else
really has ever reached I mean to me
David's one of my heroes I mean people
don't really know the depth of the
genius he was but uh more people are
starting to realize it and you know for
the longest time I respected his wishes
and didn't uh I I separated his hippie
identity from his professional identity
because his Skunk Man Sam was the acid
eating hippie you know that was trying
to make the world better getting him
good seats and then when he grew up
had a couple daughters you know became
kind of square and uh started following
the progress of Marinol which is a
synthetic version of of THC and saw
there being an opportunity to create a
generic version of THC he literally
country shopped realized he could start
a company in the Netherlands called
Florida farm and he could become the
very first private commercial
cannabinoid pharmaceutical company in
the world and he did it and you know
part of the anger that my Dutch friends
Ben Bernard Neville a few others have
had against him is that they didn't
understand how he got a license to grow
cannabis in the Netherlands and they
didn't know how to and the truth is they
could have all gotten licenses to start
a cannabinoid pharmaceutical company if
one they knew what they were freaking
doing or if they saw the market the
international market for medical
cannabinoids but they they weren't on
that trip you know I'm actually writing
an article called ants under the
skyscraper which is actually about the
formation of the Dutch seed companies
and I and I labeled it that because I
feel as if these guys were like the ants
under a skyscraper that cannot
comprehend the engineering or the
building that they live under they can't
comprehend the sophistication that's
happening on the penthouse floor they
they they just don't get it and those
guys didn't get medical cannabis for a
very long time they didn't know what
terpenes were
um you know look at the pollinator
nothing against Mila I think she's
incredible but she named her resin
extraction machine
male pollen because like lack of better
understanding should have been called
the resonator because realistically she
was tumbling female flowers and
extracting the resin heads from it she
wasn't tumbling male flowers and
extracting the pollen from it but that's
the kind of misunderstanding I saw when
I moved there you know and I you know
and I and I got where why there was a
mystery and unfortunately you know what
people don't understand they often
condemn and I think that a lot of these
people condemned it and when hoarder
Farm hit the scene and suddenly there
was this David Watson a lot of the
people that had met Skunk Man Sam under
his fake name Sam
um and his last name was his hippie acid
nickname Jingles just spelled backwards
which is really kind of funny so he's a
big dude he's over six foot tall and he
used to wear these gesture hats that had
bells on it when he would there'd be
these like legendary acid parties in the
60s before it was you know illegal and
and in the 70s still and and they were
heavy into psychedelics this is where
the Grateful Dead was born these are the
Santa Cruz mountains where Ken kisi was
and the Mary pranksters were this is
this is what was going on back then and
he used to wear a Jesters cap that fit
jingled and uh so his nickname was
jingles and when he moved over there it
was also Skunk Man Sam and when he moved
over there it just became Sam seldenidge
which was Jingles backwards and um and I
guess that I mean my friend who
publishes grow magazine when you meet
him he usually says his name's Guy it's
not it's Steve but he has a wife and a
kids and he's you know trying to create
a little bit of division between his
family and the and the BS and I get it
and it was no different back then and
then when people discovered that skunk
man Sam was David Watson they turned it
into a big conspiracy and it really
wasn't and you know unfortunately just
because of their own lack of imagination
they didn't start cannabinoid research
you know companies uh because they
didn't know anything about it and they
didn't see the market potential they
didn't have multi-million dollar
investors that wanted to invest into
what could become a multi-billion dollar
company in the future I mean I think
these guys were forward-looking and when
you look at the work they put out like
hashish hemp diseases and pests later
cannabis Evolution enough no botany uh
you know even the hemp Industries
Association that put out a peer-reviewed
journal printed on 100 hemp paper and
provided educational kits made out of
like hemp wax crayons and Plastics and
like you name it hemp seeds fabric all
of it paper and then sent it to
universities so that the academics at
the universities would get a better
understanding of cannabis like to to
call these people de agents is the most
ridiculous [__] you could ever call them
because it's like if you think the eea
is gonna let their [__] Rogue agents
write these incredible volumes of
cannabis history and practical at
utility you're crazy man I mean they're
they're spending billions of dollars to
go against cannabis and you think
they're going to plant these two guys in
the Netherlands so that they can pursue
cannabinoid research and then write
about it and then send this damn
information to the universities which is
only going to work to subvert the
propaganda that the DEA is putting out
in the first place so I take great
offense at the lies and the rumors that
were not only started by Neville that
were continued and circulated by Bent
ronkers by we're not Bruning and others
who knew that they were [__] lying
but were lying to benefit their own
reputation and I still think they should
be condemned for doing so because I
wouldn't want somebody calling me a d
agent after I self-surrendered and did a
five-year prison sentence rather than
cooperate I mean I mean it's the worst
thing you can say to somebody that has a
clear conscience you know what I mean
and now I'm glad that skunk man Sam has
outlived a lot of these people and that
the truth has come out and that his
reputation is being you know
for what it really is you know not based
on some heroin addicts fantasy of what
he wished it was but on the reality of
of of a lifelong's worth of work
basically protecting the seed sharing
the information and doing good for for
the world around him and and that's I I
feel really passionate about Skunk Man
Sam and David Watson he's one of the
nicest people I've ever known I've known
him since 1994 one of the most solid
people I've ever known you know I mean a
lot of us don't have relationships with
our loved ones that last 51 two years
and you know it really goes to show what
kind of a person he is everybody that I
know that knows him really loves him and
has respect and admiration for him and
you know I after known him for so long I
understand why he's never done a bad
thing he's never said a bad thing he's
never lied to me and to me that matters
yeah very impassionate and informative
answer there and I I would agree
everyone who I've spoken to who knows
him personally has echoed your sentiment
and I guess I've just got two final
little questions on Nell before we sort
of talk about some other stuff and I
guess I'm interested for the last few
years before Neville passed away because
he he did pass away a few years ago now
he was actually a little bit active on
the Mr Nice Guy forums and he was
causing a bit of waves over there with
some of the stuff he posted I was
wondering did you ever get around to
reading that and did you have any
thoughts on any of it because some of
the stuff he posted went very much
against the grain of what the stories
that were circulating sort of said do
you think maybe he was just a bit unwell
or do you think there was maybe some
truth to it all
unfortunately I think Neville was one of
the you know first cannabis uh people to
like reinvent the stories and put out
misinformation to benefit himself and
you know when he broke up with Aryan
very publicly you know for those that
read forums back then it wasn't a pretty
divorce uh he took his genetics and he
sold them to Scotty he didn't move to
Switzerland he didn't follow Scotty he
didn't go do breeding he said here you
go give me money and he helped Market
the genetics that Scotty was making in
Switzerland until the point where Scotty
got busted and unfortunately Scotty also
went to jail for five years I believe it
was quite a while
um and you know Neville was already out
of the picture at that point and I don't
know what of those genetics were saved
or lost because I wasn't there I um
Scotty is Shanti Baba by the way I mean
I knew Scotty as the guy that worked for
Aryan when I first went to uh Amsterdam
Aryan and Scotty where you know Scotty
was like his assistant if you will and
um and I like Scotty I've always thought
Scotty was really cool I I didn't know
him around the name change I I'm you
know I don't know where the Shanti Baba
came from but whatever and uh you know
and I think Scotty's a good brother man
he did a lot of experience and stuff uh
but he inherited the genetics that he
got from Neville and you know Neville
pulled the same thing with uh Aryan that
he pulled with Ben I mean when him and
Ben broke up he took his genetics he had
people that he knew that worked it since
since he destroyed the genetics and even
worse I mean I know firsthand that the
person that supposedly was supposed to
destroy the plants stole the plants and
then years later offered them back for
sale to Scentsy uh which is just
such double cross that's just like
but you saw a lot of it back then and uh
you know but he broke up with Ben and
you know talk [__] about Ben and then he
broke up with learning talk [__] about
Aryan uh you know and I don't know what
his relationship with Scotty was towards
the end but he was using the Forum as a
soapbox and unfortunately a lot of the
stuff that I've seen uh it doesn't go
with the stories Greg's told me the
stories Rob Clark's told me the stories
that skunk man Sam told me uh the story
that Ben's told me and Alan dronkers
I've spent time with all these people
um and you know Unfortunately they they
sing a similar song and they're not in
the same room together and unfortunately
it doesn't paint a very pretty picture
you know it paints a picture of people
that were disappointed in somebody that
they tried to like a lot you know but
somebody that was dealing with the
Demons of addiction and unfortunately
that was spilling into the rest of their
life so Neville was haunted in a polite
way and who knows what kind of a person
he would have been if you take the
heroin and the alcohol that way you know
could have been a whole different world
for him he could still be alive today
but it's not the not the Neville that he
was and you just got to accept people
for what they are and you know give
sympathy and pity where where it belongs
to me anybody who's a drug addict I feel
for them I unfortunately not one but I I
have nothing but empathy for people that
are struggling with addiction but it
doesn't give them a free pass to be able
to try to destroy the reputations of
good people
um especially when they know they're
lying you know especially when they know
with what they're saying is is not true
yeah in that form I kind of condemn one
yeah no I understand where you're coming
from and I think maybe the saddest part
about what you just said is that I think
you banged it on their head in that
Neville probably likely would still be
around if he didn't have those demons on
the other end of the spectrum the
question has to be asked would we have
had the same offerings from him and yeah
well it was the addiction that caused
him to start the seed company don't
forget it was a grant from the Dutch
government because he was dealing with
uh addiction maintenance and they were
trying to get them onto starting a
business and the Dutch government gave
them a loan to start the hall and seed
bank back in 1984 which is quite
astonishing you know only only in the
Netherlands could could this story be
what what the reality the reality is
always much Stranger Than conviction
yeah well to Loop it back I guess I sort
of wanted to ended the Neville
discussion on a more brighter note and
something which I've always suspected is
that the point you made about how he's
like a DJ you know he's sort of mixing
and mashing other people's work that
kind of resonated with me and what I
thought is if we're going to use those
terms to keep it simple I sort of get
the feeling they haven't really been as
many DJs on the same level as Neville
like as much as I agree with what you're
saying he didn't create the music so to
speak so it's he shouldn't be credited
with that but I also feel like he did a
pretty darn good job as a DJ would you
agree with that and do you think there
are any other people who are in that
same Echelon of mixing and matching and
creating really standout work
sure uh you know Kenny Kenny Morrow
trichrome technologies that poster
behind me over here I think Kenny uh
ultraviolet which was the what became
purple passion Granddaddy Purple
everything else uh was his work back in
the mid 90s he released that he's
released quite a few varieties over the
course of time
um Simon Schmidt I think is a phenomenal
breeder I mean he went to school for
plants he's he's his his company's been
around now I think 30 years almost uh 94
I think it started so he's coming close
to around his 30-year anniversary
um and you know there's Skunk Man Sam
who's really a God over devil I mean
Neville used to really kind of attack
Sam all the time but Neville never made
a skunk one never Neville never made any
of the varieties that Sam gave and sold
to him and that he built his business
upon and he always tried to steal the
credit from where the credit was due
which is something I don't do uh you
know but then again when you look at a
lot of these California varieties
um
you know sour diesel train wreck Green
Crack God bud you know I could go on and
on who made California Orange I don't
know but it was really good weed and uh
you know unfortunately through the drug
war we didn't get a lot of people who
had the courage that Neville really had
to stick his head above the water and
say yeah I did that and then and I and
I'll give him credit to this day I mean
I think we should you know I wanted to
emulate him I was when I met him he was
still a hero to me you know I his his
courage to do something that was you
know wrong uh was right you know he is
selling the seed to the community was a
good thing unfortunately operation green
Merchant came out of it and he got a lot
of people busted uh because of his poor
relationships or his poor picking of
relationships
um but you know you can't go back and
fix the people that screw you over I
sometimes wonder if that guy was a cop
the whole time and that that was a full
engagement because why else would he
have saved all those addresses if he
didn't plan on using those addresses at
a later time to his benefit so there was
clearly a back door that he was
leveraging
um at the time he was also growing and
doing his own thing so maybe he just
like if you did get popped he would just
turn over which he did but if you read
when you get it you'll see what I mean
when you read it he went willingly to
the DEA and turned in Neville and turned
in all of his customers so
you know there's there's two sides of
every sword I guess and uh unfortunately
uh a lot of people got sliced by it but
it created a new opportunity and look at
all the seed companies sssc uh the
Flying Dutchman Paradise seed Luke is
awesome you know he's a really good one
too Lucas maintained a long time since
these Stars a great variety
um you know there's other people like
you know the guy that made white widow
his name was igmar
um not much of a greeter but he made a
variety that a lot of people you know to
this day recognize you know uh so I
think there has been a lot of people
along the way I mean Greg is another one
the guys Murphy Stevens that really
started all this with this Afghan is
also very underrated to a large degree
we're all smoking uh Prodigy from from
what he started you know way back when I
asked gunkman Sam before what would have
been the most popular cannabis variety
had you not really skunk one and without
a hiccup he said oh Northern Lights you
know so Northern Lights was that
impactive and it was it was you know
those Afghans that Murphy Stevens Indica
was was floating around in the 70s and
80s long before Neville ever started a
seed company so how many of these other
varieties also have it we don't know you
know and uh you know the truth is is
that unless we really get good genetic
testing DNA testing and we get better
samples in we're not going to know the
relations of these plants and uh you
know I I once asked Ben dronkers I said
hey are you going to send your samples
in to get DNA tested he looked at me we
were sitting together getting high and
he said why so we can prove all these
genetics came from Rob and Dave
and I was like I get it I get it and he
and and I get it I get it if you've made
a living making millions of dollars
selling Jack Daniels whiskey in your
Distillery and you ain't never had to
pay Jack I don't think you wanna I don't
think you wanna who is the daddy test
you know because do you really wanted to
come back can say you're not the father
Ben actually it's him you know and you
know and I think that's what a lot of
them don't want to see happen and
unfortunately when you even look at
philos which is interesting on a lot of
levels I don't agree with what they did
with community and conception nurseries
and all that aside
um but when you when you look at what
they were doing uh and you look at them
using Goji Kush as like a backbone to
all these other varieties I think it's
misplaced if you take out OG Kush and
you put normal lights number two then it
would make sense because I remember life
before rogie cush it was it was Northern
Lights and because philos didn't have a
good Northern Light sample they didn't
have anything other than OG Kush forward
to go on and for those I mean OG kush's
1996 1997. it's not that old I mean
original Haze 69 skunk 176 a lot of you
know Northern Lights Northern Lights was
named Northern Lights when he said sent
the seeds to Neville up to that point he
was just keeping track of the crosses
being made by the people within the
circle that he was sharing The Afghani
seeds from Murphy Stevens with so he
Greg does not take credit for making uh
Northern Lights number five he said that
it was a herbie I think that worked at
the sunset shop the sun This indoor Sun
Shop that worked for Murphy Stevens made
it but because they were all sharing
genetics
Greg had some of those hybrid seeds and
um and initially when he sent it over
his Northern Lights he he spelled to
l-i-t-e-s like a light bulb like turn
the light on because it was all being
grown in the north under lights and uh
and you know because uh you know Lite is
more like illumination l-i-g-h-t it's
more like the weight of something so he
was going with Lites and Neville changed
it Neville jammed it to leghts Lig HCS
and called it known the lights but
um the little the little funnies in the
story have always intrigued me but these
genetics were floating around quite a
while before Neville took him and
broadcast them and realistically I don't
think Neville was so much a great DJ as
he had a great platform I mean he was
like the first due to the Visa with you
know two turntables and a microphone and
everybody's like whoa and that and you
know a lot of people have come since and
probably been better DJs but he was the
first one to to seed bank it turned on
print catalogs and then send Seas all
over the world so he deserves credit for
being one courageous person and
unfortunately he paid dearly for his
courage
yeah a brilliant answer there and I
might just take us back a little bit
because you just brought it up we'll
talk a little bit more about the
Northern Lights stuff and I guess one of
the questions I was wondering was as you
mentioned there were sort of different
tropical males being crossed to this
purest indica and yet that's generating
the different numbers one two three four
five up hold up it's not just a female
because they had the seeds of the peer
authentica so as they would grow out the
purest intricacies I have boys and girls
of purist Indica downstairs so I could
go either way so it wasn't just uh girls
being married to Tropical males it was
uh you know and uh when I interviewed
Greg he he's really humble too man he's
like Sam when I asked him you know what
the genetics were he's like well we'll
never really no will we and it's just a
beauty it's a beautiful honesty that I
really appreciate because one of the
things I don't like about the Cannabis
Community is how certain people are
about you know things they don't know
and even now everything I'm saying is
from my journalistic research some of
it's from my personal interactions but
you know most of it's from research and
me they're trying to gather stories from
different parties and and finding the
threat of Truth through it all it's
always been my goal I'm really not
biased to what the truth is I just would
like to know what it really is yeah
beautiful sentiment there I guess it did
make me wonder did Greg ever mention
anything about any of the other parents
being kept in a pure form or was it just
the purest indica and then they would
just cross it but never keep the other
things pure as well
well if you know the way I look at it is
this if you had groups of people like
you know you have one guy playing with
what was a Hawaiian maybe neither
Mexican and Crossing it with it and he
had his genetics and then there was the
guy that they referred to as the Indian
who lived out on an island he had his
genetics and he crossed it together so
what I see is like
uh
uh uh
a Pure Color a primary color and then
the colors shared and then some people
are mixing a little yellow some people
are mixing a little blue some are mixing
a little brown some have yellow and and
some have orange and they're all coming
out with something slightly different
and then they're sharing again and uh
that's how Greg kind of described it and
um
it makes sense to me as somebody that
has friends and Loosely shares genetics
and then Jets don't go you've got to
have these seeds back I made them from
your variety it's kind of like that and
you know Greg initially sent seeds to
Neville because he wanted a trade but
now but he wanted some of the varieties
Neville had
um he made a comment though he goes
Neville never sent me back anything
nearly as good as we said
you know and uh and and I get it I get
where he's coming from too you know
because if he's experiencing the f1s
from his friends who are first making
them he's going to get more robust
Prodigy because they're gonna have the
the hybridized effect of you know
consistency uniformity and bigger more
so than the plants that are being maybe
inbred and bred again or being bred with
genetics more closely related to one
another uh you know which I'm sure
Chimera talked about when he was on
because he's he's brilliant when it
comes to breeding
um but you know normally like humans
we're not trying to you know have sex
with our cousins because you know babies
don't come out so good and uh and it's
kind of similar with cannabis and
uh you know I I think this is also why a
lot of Neville's initial offerings were
so good because he was making these F1
hybrids with um distinctly different
genetics original Haze males and
Northern Lights females or skunk which
didn't have any Northern Lights in it
Skunk Man Sam never had Northern Lights
genetics he never he never got them he
never worked with them
um and on the other side of it Greg
never could get his Hands-On original
skunk and never got his hands on
original Haze until you know some
[__] kid like me comes along and
sends him to him in his retirement
sometime in like 20 2018 I think I sent
him those seeds you know so you know
it's it you never know how it's gonna
work out but you know Greg was in
Vietnam from 1965 and 1969 joined when
he was 17 because he was going to be
drafted and um started smoking cannabis
when he was in Vietnam
and uh brought back the habit or the
Hobby and started growing in 1969 as
soon as he got home and he was taking
Horticultural classes at the University
in Seattle and the University of
Washington and it's funny because he's
in his 70s now and he is still taking
university courses online and he shares
with me links constantly about you know
testing sugar content in your plants and
like how to avoid different diseases and
like light penetration and he's such an
avid learner and I absolutely adore it I
absolutely hope I have his uh Vigor for
Life uh when um his age I guess it's not
that long I'm [__] 50 now so I'm
gonna just keep up with the health food
but it's it's really cool and uh and he
just kept it up I mean I think he met
Murphy Stevens in around sometime in the
70s mid 70s after the book came out and
he said to me that he first got those
four seeds from her therapy Stevens in
1979 and it was one of the you know the
best Afghans that he had ever gotten up
to that point
um because a lot of the hippies
initially were breeding with more
tropical varieties that were coming in
Thai Vietnam Mexican Colombian these are
all semi-tropical it wasn't until the
hippies started coming back from the
hippie trail with the Afghan varieties
in the mid 70s that these uh skunky
stinky uh earthy uh tones were kind of
brought in and these fast flowering
heavy yielding broad leaflet varieties
where we're starting to get brought into
it original skunk one started as one of
these Afghans crossed with Colombian
gold and that was skunk and then he took
that plant and crossed it with
everything he had until he realized that
when he crossed it with Acapulco Gold
the dot combination of genetics when you
grew out the Prodigy and you spread The
Prodigy together would be consistent
uniform so he did that with all of the
different ones he had and through the
Muay once you realize oh this is the
right genetic lock in order to go with
what I'm doing uh really unique I mean a
lot of people won't spend the time well
you know he always if you ever could
talk to him he'll say you know he kills
plants more than he grows them
but I get it you know what I mean
because you can't get attached man if it
doesn't meet the standards poop out of
the garden it goes and that's what
really makes great cannabis and uh and I
think that a lot of the unfortunately uh
you know people that came along later
weren't really working on the scale that
he was working on you know tens of
thousands of plants at a time you know
uh 50 000 skunk seats or 50 000 original
acids in a single 50 000 square meter
Greenhouse going off at once and
creating you know more seeds of its own
varieties something a lot of us don't
get the opportunity to do so he was in a
position to kind of maintain his genetic
gene pool
on a level that few others were and when
he you know from my interviews with him
my conversations uh when he was doing
order form
there's no limit on seeds nobody cared
about the seeds you know there's no drug
content on the seeds and of course you
need to save the seeds because you need
to grow more plants so the one thing he
could do was really intense reading and
saving of genetics so he was in a really
unique position uh that unfortunately
small scale seed companies you know any
name any of them just weren't in a
position to do
yeah the position a few of us will
probably ever be able to find ourselves
in sadly I just wanted to bring you back
for a moment to the Steve Murphy's
Afghani the purest Indica did they ever
have a cutting they kept or they just
used the seeds every year and as a
follow-up what type of Afghani do you
think it is do you think it was just
like a a hash plant or like more akin to
Afghani number one
um Afghani number one I got Afghani
number one you know I sell Mel Frank's
seeds Mel Frank is 77 years old now
we've been friends for since 96 I met
him at positronics in Amsterdam one day
when he was walking through and he was
complimenting some plants and I was the
one that was growing the plants
um and we got to talking and it was just
a really good connection and we became
friends we were best friends to this day
and um the Afghan number one is okay uh
it's not
uh the Northern Lights purist Indica is
really exceptional and the The Afghani
number one
has in my opinion some more tropical
influence in it it's not pure Afghan
like the pierced Indica is and uh it's
it's okay
um it you know maybe I'm really sticky
too though because like you know like uh
you know when you have one thing and you
think it's great it's because sometimes
you don't have things to compare it to
and then when I had other things I when
I had an Afghan one initially I thought
it was great you know but then I got all
these Northern Lights plants and these
Afghans the purest Indica from Greg and
I thought whoa that's really incredible
so it changed my perspective of
afghaning number one
um
but you know I I'm gonna sound like a
jerk too but I don't really like driven
poison
um I sell the seeds because it's
authentic Urban Poison and it has a real
it's got a great bud structure it's
super fast it's got great resin a lot of
people smoke it love it so you know
Screw my opinion but it's it's not one
of my favorite varieties uh but you know
what I've been trying to do with the sea
company is really make these available
to people because I don't know the you
know
the cannabinoids that'll be fine or the
terpene combinations that will be found
and I think there's still a lot to be
found in these genetics and I think all
of the genetics are medically uh useful
it's just a matter of of identifying
them and uh and finding them into
medical utility and I think that's
starting to happen and I'm
you know there'll come a day I believe
when when people will go in and they'll
have their endocannabinoid system tested
and they'll be able to just look like
they look at your blood and they can
tell you what vitamins and minerals
you're deficient in and they'll be able
to you know pull off the shelf all of
these various
um single cannabinoids put them together
and maybe add some terpenes uh for uh
you know a bit of an uh
I hate to use the word entourage but
it's it's it's more of an ensemble
effect and uh and and the way they
synergistically work together will be
how we use it to battle once our
endocannabinoid system and um the more
we have these genetics available and the
more people can start to grow them and
test them and and discover them you know
the more we're going to have more colors
we're gonna have to pull from when we're
turning around and trying to you know
color in our life and make it make it
better you know because I you know
obviously I've had cancer a bunch of
times I'm pretty certain we're all gonna
die at the end of this wonderfully short
trip but it's about our quality of life
it's really about you know the time
you're present and being present and
treating you know time like it's a
present and really appreciating it and I
think cannabis plays this really key
fundamental role in our wellness and I
think this really becomes a conversation
about Wellness uh more than it's a
conversation about you know getting high
on a Friday night you know and feeling
good and I think more people are going
to start to understand that as they come
to understand they that they have an
endocannabinoid system and that it can
help balance them better than
Pharmaceuticals or better than heroin or
better than alcohol or better than
smoking cigarettes
um a lot of people I think are going to
turn to cannabis like you and I have
um and uh really help help their life
considerably
yeah here here hopefully hopefully the
medical sort of improvements lead to
exactly that it would be fantastic
something a little left of field but I
thought you might have a good
perspective on was often when we talk to
guests about the really old school
genetics they reference how they really
like them because there was no ceiling
you know weed these days it only gets
you so high and I guess I'd be
interested in hearing your thoughts on
the ceiling effect and what it is like
how does it occur is it just do it is it
just land races have no ceiling and we
hybridize things they get ceilings
what's your thoughts
I get what they're saying I mean I've
been sitting here for an hour and 32
minutes too and I've only managed to
smoke half a joint of this stuff and
it's a lot because with the haze you
feel it you know like you hit it and you
feel it and you can put it down for a
minute because you're like self
titration happens quickly when you're
smoking this and I I I get it I mostly I
feel like with the haze varieties that
this that you can keep getting higher
and higher and higher but I feel like
you end up doing what I'm doing which is
you hit it a little bit and go whoa whoa
I'm doing an interview I gotta keep my
[__] and you end up putting it down
um I find half joints of haze all over
my head hurts all the time and I think
that's because I get really hyped and I
put them down and then I get distracted
and I am so high I forget I leave the
joint there and um I don't do that as
much with uh more of the modern
varieties unfortunately if I go to the
store in California buy some pot I'm not
that impressed and uh I've been
fortunate enough to be a Cannabis Cup uh
judge for high times for the emblem cup
uh for the secret cup I've been a
photographer for them uh for chalice
I've been a judge uh so I've had some
exposure
um to cannabis unfortunately a lot of
the Cannabis floating around California
is quite homogeneous and it's very
similar there's not a lot of standouts
what they call Haze isn't really Haze
um I was judging concentrates and I sat
down next to the gentleman that owns um
I would I'll just say a gentleman that
was one of the bigger extraction
companies and um he always gives me what
a little jar with everybody smoking and
uh I gave him mine and I had made some
extract out of haze and he opened it and
he smelled it and he was like
what is this and I was like that's
original Haze
um and he was just like holy [__] and we
were sent with maybe a hundred plus
samples in front of us and I made the
comment and I said you know what's weird
after smoking all this stuff I feel like
I could put this Haze jar down and it
would stand out out of all of these and
he goes oh it's a it's absolutely unlike
everything else here and we had I think
119 samples in front of us that year and
it's just because
Growers didn't want to spend the extra
time I mean you take Northern California
into an example you know when you get
North or San Francisco it's not the most
hospitable place to grow cannabis your
ability of variety is limited uh by your
early Winters your early rain your heavy
humidity that Coastal fog it's a
challenge I mean I have hats off to
everybody in Northern California that
can turn out really high quality
cannabis and there are a lot of people
who do
um but they're not growing no three-way
Columbia Haze up there until December
with that weather and so they're limited
so because they're limited to their
environment we see the limit to their
genetics that they offer as well the
emerald cup is my favorite event in the
world and everybody should visit it but
when you go to the animal cup most of
all those varieties have always been
under 10 week varieties only last year
when I was there taking photos for Girl
magazine and they had all of the
varieties separated by their dominant
terpene it is the future man and and so
now now you've got orange competing with
orange and you've got gas competing with
gas and you've got sweet tropical with
sweet tropical and you've got you know
hazy you know train wreck type varieties
competing with hazy train wreck type
varieties and you're not trying to
compare you know California Orange to OG
Kush which are completely different and
um by breaking it down into your
dominant terpene category you're
starting to get a better understanding
of which like let's go back to Colors
which primary color group did that
variety happens to fall into because if
it's pinene or if it's terpineline or
Mercy dominant it's going to fall into
that group you know aligning dominant
terpene plant is going to smell lemony
period so group them together judge them
for what they are and I think that's
really neat unfortunately it wasn't very
much when it came to really hazy
varieties offered at the time because
again it's an organic Northern
California event and when they move down
to maybe you know
they're not really growing it in Santa
Barbara yet either but when you see
Growers starting to grow cannabis in
areas that are more warm and they can
leave plants in the ground until
November December you know uh when you
start getting south of Santa Cruz and
California you start to experience this
type of you know summer all the time
weather and there's really two
distinctly different weather patterns in
Northern California that split around
Pismo Beach North of of Santa Barbara
and Santa Barbara South you've got hot
sunny days you know all year long and
then north of Santa Barbara you start to
get more wintry as you get more North
and you know people are going to start
growing
you know these long flowering varieties
in places like Northern Santa Barbara
and Santa Barbara and L.A and and
further south and it's going to be
fantastic and I think you're going to
experience cannabis like we haven't
experienced in decades because a lot of
the Cannabis coming in in the 50s and
60s was coming in from tropical
semi-tropical places
um that changed when we started getting
stuff from Afghan and then the 70s when
the hippies and others started mixing
together hippies and the soldiers
started greeting together various
varieties of cannabis and coming out
with the hybrids that we the haze the
skunk the Hindu Kush the Calio The
Afghani one uh the Durban you know we
could go on and on about what became of
those land race varieties that those
guys originally got in the first place
and then morphed them into the varieties
that we know today and then those
primary varieties were crossed together
to make a lot of the wedding cakes and
the the Skittles and the runts and the
stuff that we are now referencing to
today okay because none of that stuff
was bred from brand new land race
crosses it was all bred from you know
the seeds they got on you know vacation
to you know Amsterdam or through a
friend who was already growing and you
know quality was just passed on passed
on because you know why go through all
that [__] and try to you know recreate
the work others have done successfully
when you can take skunk one seeds grow
them out and then take another variety
grow them out mix them together and
everybody claps at you because you know
you're a DJ and they didn't think of
mixing Together the Beatles White Album
in the Jay-Z Black Album until they
heard your gray album and then they're
like oh that's the [__] you know and
and um again not musicians but still
you know I think the best thing these
seed breeders today could do is give
credit where credits do the reason you
don't see me making up a lot of funny
names on my seed website is because I'm
just trying to give credit where credits
do I'm not trying to come in and pretend
like you know you know I'm not you know
Reinventing the wheel I mean I do make
varieties that are unique to me that are
unique to my company but usually those
in those cases I just call them what I
made it out of because I want to leave
breadcrumbs for the people who buy my
seeds so that they'll kind of know where
to go with their crosses because then it
gives them it's like a dog or pedigree
information and if they have the
pedigree information you know maybe they
can make a better cross after they get
my seeds and they cross them with
something they have and I encourage it I
think it's great where I think it's kind
of shady is when you know I sent I sent
a company seeds in February seven months
later they knocked off those seeds
claiming that now they finally have
skunk and then they they told a brand
new story about skunk one said Sam the
skunk man got out of jail in 1981 and
the these seeds came to France in like
1974 kilo and it's all [__] man like
Sam didn't even make skunk one in 1974.
it didn't come around till after that
and these people that come and they try
to reinvent the history to benefit
themselves I think that [__] and I think
that's shady and I think they should get
called out for it because I think that
you know the Cannabis Community deserves
an authentic and and and real history
and not a history that's been maligned
by marketing uh people you know that
we're trying to Market their seeds or
Market their company and trying to you
know you know basically steal the wind
out of the sales of others because
they're still doing it to this day
this is invariably uh one of the
discussion points I thought we were
going to have to touch on which
hopefully give people a bit more
background but yeah as you just alluded
to you know that there has been some
sort of ongoing what's the word they use
in the news there's been robust
conversations between yourself and
Aficionado around a skunk release I was
just wondering if you could give us a
little bit more of the back story on
that I mean simply put they contacted me
uh actually way back in July of 2020
asking me proceeds uh because they were
following what I was doing and I told
them they weren't going to be available
yet I told them they'd be available in
probably like seven eight months
February of 2021 they contacted me
saying hey can you know we saw them on
your website can we get some and
unfortunately or fortunately you know
it's weird I almost didn't sell them the
seeds because I I they have it bad they
have a reputation we'll just say of
doing this with other varieties and
other people and I I've had words with
Leo uh who's Aficionado here in
California in the past and um you know
it is what it is but they contacted me
through Frenchie cannoli and I just I
adore Frenchie he's since we met we were
friends like I got nothing but love for
him I think he was one of the most
authentic
people who had such a true passion and
for cannabis and I will miss him forever
and I I'm crushed that he's gone and I
you know I've absolutely got nothing but
love for Frenchie
for sure but they were looking for the
skunk genetics and they were very
upfront about that and they contacted me
and I you know this is why after he said
I was a liar I posted the conversation
up on Instagram because I'm not a liar
and I would never misinterpret the truth
and I'm just not it's not my thing and
uh I'm not afraid of the ramifications
of Truth so I don't have to lie so
anyone who has to lie can go for
themselves in my opinion so that's just
how I feel and uh so I got him the
genetics I sent him some seeds I sent
him roadkill I sent them skunk one I
even sent them extra C's I sent some for
Frenchie so he'd have some to grow in
his house
um and uh yeah and uh then
they get the seeds like February 26th
and then you know end of August end of
August they released that bam they got
skunk one seeds now they f2'd their 1974
seeds from a kilo and told this
elaborate story that was not such
[__] and people in the community I
think also recognized it as [__] and
started calling it out because I mean
skunk one of all the freaking varieties
to lie about why pick skunk one it's so
documented
um but he did and uh
and it was weird so I called them out on
it I mean I woke up that morning called
the mud on it it actually happened a
little earlier though because when I got
the rks it was from that guy Jaime in
Alaska who's another great guy he's an
old biker that's been growing forever in
a day and um people gave him nothing but
[__] for saying that he had roadkill
skunk and uh he sent it to me and
you know it is it it is it is really
what he says it is it's just it's not as
strong as people would would
uh want it to be and I said this to him
and I've been really upfront and honest
about this to a lot of people I said
it's there but you're gonna have to look
through plants to really find that one
that is going to blow you away and stink
out the car and you know be smelled down
the street but you know since this
conversation has started you know I
don't know how much you're into the
files so files are what I now believe
are the cause of the skunk acrid smell
in these plants humans can detect files
and parts per trillion and it makes it
hard for machines to even be able to
detect it in measurable amounts as well
so thiols are what I believe a lot of
these Afghan varieties that smelled like
urine and acrid dead flesh and and
skunks to Americans
um that's where a lot of this came from
because when you talk to Robert Clark
who is to me the foremost historian on
cannabis in the world
um a lot of the more tropical varieties
have sweeter sense and a lot of these
more you know lemony and citrusy and
Flowery tones we're getting are coming
from the Acapulco Gold the Colombians
the the Thais the Mexicans and such
um so these thiols are what I believe
initially when everybody started
breeding with the Afghans they all took
on this heavy scent but because the way
humans work is that this is something
that when we smell makes my our brain
think oh this is going bad avoid it we
slowly bred away from it and bred
towards the sense that we're more
appealing which were the fruity
flavorful tasty dessert type you know
when you walk go for a walk down the
street you do not stick your nose in a
pile of dog [__] you stick your nose in
a rose you you smell flowers and and I
think for cannabis cultivators
especially considering that that stench
of [__] would get them busted they just
all may be subconsciously be bred away
from the thiols and move towards the
more aromatic plants and
um I think that's what happened to
cannabis and I'm not even telling people
this but the purest Indica because I
don't want to see their heads explode
again really smells like [__] skunk I
grew up I'm in California they get dead
skunks on my street my dogs come home
skunks sometimes I've lived with skunk
since I was a little kid we have them in
New England
um funny enough though their only North
American animals there are no skunks in
Europe none of them and none of my this
is what weirded me out when guys like
Ben were like oh I called it skunk I was
like Ben you've never visited America
how have you I asked have you ever seen
a skunk outside of Pepe Le Pew
like you mean a person yeah do you even
have them at your zoos no I don't think
we do okay so how would you know what a
skunk smells like and if you spelled a
plant that smelled nasty like in the UK
they refer to it as cheese because if
you go to the UK and you smell that
canasty ass [__] that they probably can
eat and that nasty act that I didn't
call it cheese they wouldn't call it a
skunk because they don't have skunks in
England so they wouldn't call it
something they don't have in the
Netherlands either so it makes sense to
an American when you smell it it smells
like [__] smells like that skunk smells
like hacker and rancid nasty which also
contains thiols in the skunk spray so
the relationship to me makes sense and
these you know the skunk one seeds that
I currently have I have only been
reproduced twice since the 1980s Skunk
Man Sam gave them to Mel Frank in 1988
he put them in the refrigerator until
1996 and then reproduced them in 96 put
those reproductions in the refrigerator
and left him there until he took him out
in 2019 and gave him to me I started
growing them out and realized [__] these
things all still smell accurate they
don't smell sweet so I did a selection
of the most accurate plants filled my
Greenhouse reproduced the seeds
um they came out great people have been
loving them
um the people who don't grow them hate
on me and say I don't really have scum
and the people who do grow them love
them and say that they that skunk
doesn't even as much skunk smell sweeter
than these plants one guy said you know
so and I get it though because these
genetics are literally old they're
literally from the 80s they're literally
from way back when and then I got the
ones from Greg they're from what he says
from the earlier 80s
they still have these like files that
are present they still smell skunky to
me and I think that as we do more
selections the we are going to be able
to bring the funk back in much of these
Afghans if if we're looking for it if
we're breeding towards
flavor and taste and you know trying to
make dessert recipe type flavors we're
obviously going to move away from thials
but if but if if people consciously do
what I did which was throw out all the
sweet plants and breed together all the
stinky plants I think over time just
like we can manipulate uh terpene levels
and cannabinoid levels we could
manipulate thiol levels and raise them
in future generations of plants and kind
of Bring It Back bring it back bring it
back a little bit at a time so um
yeah it's been an interesting uh it's
been an interesting Journey because when
I first released Haze I had a lot of
people saying you don't really have Haze
and I was like [__] you and then I
really skunk one and oh you really don't
have skunk nobody has skunk
ah you know and it was like whatever and
fortunately now with Northern Lights
nobody's giving me a hard time you know
but Greg is a little more uh active on
social media and it's a little different
but
um yeah I had a lot of naysayers at
first and even skunk band Sam's been on
shows like Ashford said yeah Todd has my
seeds that's they're real and you know
and I don't know why it's so hard for a
lot of people to wanna that don't want
to believe that you know I mean it's a
little ridiculous I actually saw like a
disparaging comment by uh what's the guy
that got the uh he got the
Tom Hill Hayes or whatever you got the
positronic seeds in 1996 and he brought
him home he made some seeds and he named
the haze after himself
and I was living practically at posi I
had [__] keys in my own office of
Posse and I grew out those seeds and
unfortunately they weren't that great at
the time and and he bought them and
thinks they're awesome and I think
that's great but then I saw him on one
of the forums basically talking [__]
about he doesn't know what I have but
they can't be as good as what he had and
I'm thinking really I skipped over 10
years of Bernard's breeding and went
right back to Skunk Man Sam and got the
original hay seeds from him and you
think the ones that I got from Sam are
not as good as the ones you picked up
from positronics on a trip to High Times
I just blows my mind and I doubt
honestly that Tom picked up thousands of
original hay seeds at positronics at the
time because one we didn't sell them in
very big packages and two most of the
people there were not buying thousands
of seeds when they got there and I have
had thousands of original ACS to do my
selections through and I would tend to
believe it's like a lottery ticket the
more lottery tickets you have the more
of a chance you have to win you know if
you went home with even a hundred seeds
I I can't imagine how you would get
selections as good as somebody who went
through thousands of seats looking for
selection so it's it's it's what it is I
think a lot of people wanna I don't know
they get on a high horse and they really
feel like they deserve credit for things
that really they don't you know just
because you went and bought some seeds
at positronics man doesn't mean you're
doing anything just because you bought
some Caesar positronics and mixed them
together and then sold those seeds
doesn't mean you're doing anything and
like me I am trying to not influence the
haze genetics in a sense like like I am
out Crossing and making my own varieties
but that's not original Haze and and I'm
trying to not [__] it up by listening to
Skunk Man Sam and doing the breeding the
way that he recommends I do it because I
want other generations to get the
opportunity to go through these seeds as
pure as possible and to be able to find
their own selections and and and
hopefully you know become great DJs you
know that's kind of what I'm I'm kind of
feeling like I'm the bridge between the
older generation and then the younger
generation of newer breeders and I kind
of feel like I'm the anti-cannabis
Cannabis company because I'm really
trying to get the genetics into the
hands of of of the community before
these big corporates show up and try to
turn it into IP and once they get their
hands on a you know purple passion or a
[__] OG Kush they're never going to
release it they're not going to cut
clones and sell them at the shop so you
can grow the [__] that they're selling
never in a million years so I think this
genetic preservation is super important
and you know I I wish more people like
Tom would see that we're all you know
trying to benefit the community and and
it's not a [__] quarter mile race
it's not about you know who's got the
best of What It's Like These are plants
we're talking about and you know
they're all unique every single plant in
a sense is a unique fingerprint on the
planet and you don't know its benefits
or it's you know until you grow it out
and experience it and I wish more people
would be open-minded to that and I wish
more people would
you know kind of have that open-minded
approach to breeding and looking for the
best quality and and and looking for the
you know best medicine rather than you
know looking for an ego stroke
yeah look I can understand how
understandably frustrating it must have
been to have to deal with all the
questions about validity of stock and
whatnot I mean it's it's interesting and
coincidental you bring up Tom Hill
because I was I actually had a question
I was going to ask you about him so we
may as well do it right now on the
photos I've seen you post of uh the
purest Indica it looks obviously like
Northern Lights but it also kind of
reminded me a bit of deep chunk with the
way like that resin's so thick like you
can tell like this has got some serious
Afghan hash plant type Vibes to it have
you ever grown out any of Tom's lines
like specifically the Deep chunk I mean
it's not really his lines they're just
land races but um what's your thoughts I
don't think they are land races I mean
just because you bought some seeds from
positronics doesn't mean you're working
with land races and uh you know the the
thing is is these Afghan genetics are
dominant in a lot of this stuff I mean
Neville did a lot what normally it's
number two Northern Lights Number Two is
one of my favorites right now it's so OG
cushion crazy I asked Greg years ago if
he ever smoked OG Kush and he said to me
he said yeah yeah it's just nl2 he made
a joke he said Todd we used to grow the
nl5 and sell it and we used to grow the
nl2 and smoke it and I thought oh that's
hilarious man and uh you know and it's
because the nl2 was funky and heavy and
[__] you know dank as [__] but then
the nl5 was more of that tropical kind
of like kind of light High you know
better yielding and [__] like that so
quicker growing because it had a little
more of the more tropical equatorial
genetics in it and uh I got what he
meant you know and and you know a lot of
this stuff you know Neville was a
blessing man Neville spread the seeds
around and Neville got these genetics
into the hands of many people that then
was had an opportunity to breed with
them you know it Neville did it is was
it was a beautiful thing for the world
and uh and he should always be revered
for that because it put the genetics
into the hands of many people
um
and I I think it made a big difference
in the in the overall quality of
cannabis you know in all reality by
going through these selections and
getting you know these like Afghans and
different things you know out so that
you can mix it with your hazes and stuff
it was just an absolute you know
blessing to the world in the way you
know not having to go through you know
land race tie or land race Afghan or
land race anything you know to to start
at the bottom and try to work your way
back up sharing the genetics was like
starting on you know the top floor after
all these people had done selections and
breeding and and made seeds and like
every single time hopefully was an
improvement and and that's why I think
in a weird way that there was the first
wave of breeding was all about quality
the second wave of breeding was all
about quantity meaning either quantity
of seeds or uh the fastness and like the
the the the the
amount of cannabis you get and I'm sure
short amount of time because you know
people wanted that they wanted quick
they wanted heavy you know they really
didn't they didn't ask you for the
highest quality you know when you were
selling seeds and all and I mean
everybody was like what's the fastest
heaviest yield you got I was like okay
you want big bud those who wants to
smoke big bud I mean I used to work for
Simon at Serious Eats in the day clean
in the seeds and stuff and um you know
chronic was cool to grow but if there
was chronic AK and Cali saying in front
of me I smoked the Cali then I smoked
the AK and I'd probably give away a
little chronic but you know like that
would be the last of the pot to smoke
you know because it was the least
effective in my opinion but it was the
heaviest guilder we we offered I mean
big bud
big big bud wasn't the biggest winner of
any of the Cannabis cups I ever remember
you know but a lot of people went over
there trying to get big bud seeds
because they wanted heavy fast you know
the prohibition Market demanded it
you know if you could turn over six
crops a year in your house uh growing
you know an eight week or or you could
turn you know four crops or even worse
you know two crops a year growing
something that was four to six months
what were you going to do you know what
I mean at the pure economics drove the
conversation to where it was so you know
I
the funny thing is I got I always hope
to meet Tom Hill actually when I when I
was younger I you know I had reverence
for all these breeders that I heard of
you know I went to the Canvas Cup place
to enjoy meeting everybody it wasn't a
big you know
who's got the highest THC game it was
just about making friends uh so I was a
little bummed when I saw him talking
crap but and uh I'm sure he has good
genetics I'm sure he's done good
selections I'm sure he's put out some
good stuff you know if I had the
opportunity to smoke weed that he grew
I'd be happy about it I would love to
try some of Tom Hill's Hayes and stuff
especially because I've been able to get
original haze from Skunk Man Sam and
grow it and I've because I've had great
cuttings of the northern light of
Neville's Hayes and smoked and loved it
because I worked at pausing was growing
[__] Haze for the whole year of 1996
and and trying to go through different
varieties to figure out which ones I
like best uh I have a lot of experience
with it and I would love to see you know
his secondary color and what he's made
with it I think it would be cool you
know but I don't know personally I would
rather have the seeds that you know Sam
keeps for himself and doesn't sell to
anybody then the seeds you can buy at
positronics so
personal preference of course I think
I'm there with you don't worry and I
mean you touched on OG in that answer
and I guess I'd be interested to hear a
little more about your thoughts on OG in
general is it a strain you like like
would you ever grow it and smoke it or
do you feel like it's just superseded by
the NL
uh you'll laugh but when I got out of
prison in 2004 I didn't have any money
kind of in debt and everything and uh my
friends at guruji Kush gave me back
because I kind of had it before I went
to prison too uh they shared the Clone
with me prior to prison but I can't I
wasn't really talking about that and I
won't say you gave it to me but then
when I got out of prison again
um it was offered back to me again in
2004 and I when I got out of prison
started uh select strains which was a
little nursery and what is on the cover
but OG Kush and uh it was my number one
cutting Scentsy star super silver A's
Romney and purple I'm 39.
um and uh I sold the [__] out of them I
think I was the very first person to
sell OG Kush cuttings in La starting at
the end of uh 2004 November December
probably December 2004 was my first sale
of OG Kush cuttings and um
maybe a little later maybe January but
not much later after Christmas
um
around that time the guy that offered it
to me uh I inquired to my friend who
gave it to me and I went to him and said
hey may I sell cuttings of this because
again I just didn't want to be an
[__] and um he came back to me said
Todd the person who wanted you to have
it died and I don't think it matters you
could do whatever you want with it you
know and I was like
whoa bro and I didn't realize that and
then years and years later
um
Adam Dunn had a show that he was doing
uh and he was telling this he was
letting people tell this real [__]
story about the origin of OG Kush and
unfortunately he had this guy that was
someone I knew and that snitched on me
he was one of the government informants
in my case his name was Dave and uh I've
known Adam since 94 and we're friends
and uh Adam is from the East Coast we
both grew up a little bit in Rhode
Island we're both kind of smart asses
and um while the guy was talking Adam uh
joked with them that oh you should have
just went to the cops and told him that
you only grew it at one house and not
all these other houses and the dumb son
of a [__] said I did I went to the DEA
and told him I was only growing here in
Laurel Canyon and not to charge me with
all these other houses and I always knew
that he cooperated but I couldn't
believe that he told on himself on Adam
Dunn's show and after that happened I I
heard from all these people that were
like you got to listen to this and I was
just like sweet Jesus and um and then
when that happened Josh d uh who's now
pretty famous for for being the guy from
La that had it at that time he was still
underground about it uh he hadn't made
an Instagram for it or anything and he
contacted me
and he said uh
you know in a text message like how did
you get OG Kush and I wasn't going to
answer so I called him on video and uh
he answered and I said
you tell me if you if you think you know
me and you think you know how I got it
you tell me who I got it through and uh
the first name you mentioned he got it
right and I said whoa wait a minute was
there really somebody named Mad Dog and
he goes Todd that was my roommate and he
held up this picture of his friend who
passed away from pharmaceutical
complications and uh he didn't know D or
anything he had medical condition and um
I was just it was a really touching
moment and he said you know Todd he used
to cut out articles about you from the
newspaper because this was before the
internet and he used to like put them on
magnets on our refrigerator so when I
would come home from work I could read
the article about you uh you know
because we were both you know thought
what you were doing was cool and that's
how in the 90s he found out I had
friends and he got me a cutting through
friends
um but he but I didn't know who I didn't
know who it was he didn't give me the
nickname and then after I got out of
prison uh he the same dude went through
friends different friends this time and
and offered it back to me and I said I
would love it and um and then when I
went back to ask I found out he passed
away but then Josh kind of put it all
together for me
um and the the conversation I had with
Josh was really sincere like there was
no questioning
Josh's like the authenticity of what he
was saying I was in LA at the time you
know I I I know it I I was there you
know so
I knew more than I should you know and
uh and that's why I went to prison
because I wouldn't talk about it I
wouldn't cooperate just lock me up you
know and that's what they did
um but then when I got out of prison all
my friends were still there and I had
nothing but love so I got a lot of good
things given back to me like I had you
know all my friends were still there
when I came home so it was really warm
to come home to it and then I just uh so
I got OG Kush I love it I've always been
a fan of OG Kush it's been a go-to mine
for medicine for a long time I used it
in the net 2019 breeding against my on
Hayes
um it's done really well for me uh
people seem to really love it and
you know but now that I have known life
number two and I just did a greenhouse
run of middle life number two I can
absolutely see who the daddy mommy daddy
of of the OG Kush was and when I spoke
to the guy who who supposedly originally
made the seeds in Florida that the
cutting came from he told me that you
know in 89 we went to the Netherlands
and we bought Hindu Kush and Northern
Light seeds from Neville so that's all
it can be because when I talk to him I
said man I think it's Northern Lights
because I remembered
so my first experience with Northern
with with OG Kush was in 1997 when I
came back from Amsterdam when I smoked
it in January of 97 I was like oh this
is Northern Lights because I had just
come back from hanging out with Alan
dronkers and going to the castle in 96
and and being there smoking Northern
Lights varieties that they had stuff
that they agreed with stuff that you
know the stuff that they grow so so I
got to smoke a lot of different [__]
with Alan Helen's a real pothead Alan
loves to smoke loves his house he's he's
really into it you know so we used to
get high I've I've had the opportunity
of sleeping over at the castle and you
know getting high with Alan all night
long and smoking the stuff that was in
the basement so I I feel like I've I'm
very fortunate to have the experience
that I've had with you know the Cannabis
that I've been around so when I got here
and smoked it I just thought it was
Northern Lights and then when I asked
Greg about it he kind of reinforce that
yeah there's just Northern Lights and
now that I've grown it I definitely
think the parents were knowing the
lights so
you know that's why I think that in
philos uh
if if if in the six different types or
five different types that they list out
because they lift up like have uh wild
berry skunk and uh something like that
uh and uh one of them's OG Kush if that
was Northern Lights then it would make
sense for me because that would be
Northern Lights and skunk one and then
all the other things that came from it
but to put OG Kush up there with skunk
one when there's like 20 years you got
to go back to the 70s if you're really
gonna get under the varieties that we
have now and those don't go to OG Kush
they go back to this Steve Murphy purist
Indica
um and I don't know if you've have you
seen the book I'm talking about have you
seen the picture I mean yeah yeah yeah
yeah so yeah and and I think the
genetics don't lie when you look at the
photo and you look at the The 1975 photo
it's like freaking twins
yeah 100 yeah it looks it looks the same
I definitely agree with that I guess my
mind then asks the question
I'm not sure how familiar you are in
terms of growing out the different chem
dog varieties but the same sort of
question often lingers around chemdog do
you think there's an L in that yeah for
sure 100 I've often thought cam like
chem 91 they call it an OG Kush are
closely related without question I've
also grants grown stuff that came from
the hog farm uh the way to gravy
Northern California and uh it was very
uh non-lights as well to me Northern
Lights has been Northern Lights Number
Two is the is the mystery
between Afghan and
uh just because it was an Afghan when I
asked him what not only it's number two
was he said it was mixed with
um the Afghans that they got from uh
Oregon and California and when he said
and California it made me think okay
this makes more sense because if you
have zero mixed with like a California
or Oregon Afghan and then you take Z you
know number one because that becomes
number one and then you mix that with
the California uh Afghan or Oregon
Afghan you get NL number two you're
still pretty close to that purest indica
and as they were bumping up
um that's where you know in his in
Greg's opinion it was simply growth
characteristics the leaves became
narrower the plants became taller the
finishing times grew longer so he just
numbered them from closest to Murphy
Murphy's Afghan to the most tropical
ones that he had and when you think
about it it makes sense why none of the
numbers over five really became popular
to Neville because Neville once he got
those male hazes everything was with the
male hazes it's as if nothing he didn't
he he didn't have any other Haze plants
to use he says he had a female but
he says he killed it because it wasn't
that good so I don't I don't believe he
actually had it to be really honest with
you
um but it it doesn't matter at the end
of the conversation he stated many times
that he only had two males
um and
I I just think that that's why in a
sense you get just a limited amount of
secondary colors from what he could do
with that primary color because if that
those Haze males were his primaries it
would have a good signature on every
other color he mixed it with you know
you know just to use an analogy that
people that maybe don't breed can easily
understand
yeah no look I I agree with you I think
if you had a female he would have
definitely made f2s and hunted through
them and we would have heard about it
but interesting nonetheless Lou we've
been having so much fun we skipped over
the question we normally jump back to it
around like 15 minutes in but we ask
everyone what was your first experience
with cannabis
um
I was sick I was my mom was a hippie and
I was going through chemotherapy and
radiation and I have a big scar on the
side of my body from uh I had a tumor
between my left lung and my heart for
the first time I had it in soft tissue
only it was inside a bone marrow and it
would break my bone my spine is fused I
had three locations in my skull I had
two more in my right ear I had two
locations in my left hip I was in a
wheelchair for over six months when I
was a little kid and then after all that
I got it again in between my left lung
and my heart and my mom had read in Good
Housekeeping that cannabis was being
used for cancer patients and she
inquired with my pediatrician and he
felt like man you have nothing to lose
in so uh she being a hippie already had
weed and
when we drove home that day
um she had me slip down I was only nine
years old she had me slip down into like
the front seat of the car and she had
the air conditioning on and she gave me
a joint and she told me to like uh she
told me to sip it like it was a straw
and uh so I got down in the little thing
and I was I was sipping it like it was a
store and I started getting and feeling
pretty good and mind you I just went
through chemo I just not only went
through chemo that I went through
radiation therapy because I was getting
chemical therapy and then they were
sending me to radiation so it really
sucked and um when we got home that day
I uh I wanted spinach I was a big Popeye
fan and I wanted like a sauteed spinach
and butter and um my mom was high and
thought well what I do to my kid you
know and uh she called my pediatrician
and he said you know feed them you know
and uh tomorrow don't give them any and
see if it's different so the next day we
drove home and it sucked and I got home
and I was being sick I was up in my room
[__] crying and puking and having a
[__] moment and uh she came up with a
joint and said hey it's a bit like it's
a straw let's try this again and we sat
on the floor in my bedroom and I had a
Don McLean American Pie 45
and you'd have to flip the [__] song
over halfway through and me and my mom
sat there and she had a joint and I had
a joy and I was smoking it getting high
and I got so high and I was so into the
song and she hated it because you know
they sing now is a good day today's the
day I'm gonna die you know and it's my
mom like a nine-year-old with cancer
[__] rocking out to this you know
we're all Gonna Die song but um you know
it's an American Anthem and I loved it
so it was just really amusing and uh
that was kind of my first real
experience getting hot with my mom and I
think it saved my life man it turned me
into an avid student and uh
and I am grateful to this day you know
to her giving it to me
what a beautiful touching sort of story
thanks for sharing that with us how did
it progress from there did you start you
know as usual sort of smoking as a
teenager and when did you develop the
urge to First grow
um well uh in a twist of fate I uh I
started some good pot and I stopped
smoking part after the cancer for a
while but then when I was 12
um my my my steps I was a biker a big
six foot five Monster uh you know
tattoos down to the wrist and the
Harleys and everything and uh when I was
eight I got a motorcycle and when I was
12 I got another motorcycle and um I had
a helmet on and my spine is fused my
first five vertebrae a few solid so I'm
a 12 year old kid riding trails on a
motorcycle that was too big for me I
weighed like 70 pounds and they gave me
100 CC Suzuki ETS 100 and uh I was just
a terror and I my head would be bouncing
around and it started to hurt so I
wasn't seeing my doctor and I said hey
you got to give me something from my
neck he said no he said you're next
fused and it's not going to get better
and the only thing I could prescribe for
you is opiates and they'll become
physically or mentally addicted and
it'll ruin your life and I'm not going
to do it so you got to learn how to deal
with it and I was like that sucks and I
was 12 you know and um and I said [__]
what do I do he goes well you could try
smoking your mom's pot and I was just
like ha ha and he's like no I'm serious
because of my help and um and I was just
like it was 1982 and uh and probably
October and I was just like so I went to
my mom and was like hey Peter Peter
Smith was my pediatrician I said he told
me maybe I could smoke some pot and it
would help my neck feel better and she
was like really and I was like ask him
and she was so she did because she
believed me though and she gave me some
on the spot but we did have a
conversation about it when we went back
to the hospital because if I had lied it
would have been the end of me and uh so
when we got there and she said did you
tell him smoke pot and he's like yeah
how did it work out did you try it then
it was just like okay you weren't full
of [__] you know because like how many
doctors back then were brave enough but
he had been my pediatrician since I was
like two or three years old so he had
like had such a close relationship with
me and my family and my mom and dad were
bikers so they weren't exactly going to
go to the cops like you know they may
have been Outlaws but you could trust
them I know that sounds funny to say but
like they would there was like dignity
and within that so like uh so he was
cool with it and um I started getting
bags of weed from my mom and one day we
were we were and I was sworn to secrecy
unfortunately but uh I stopped with all
the big kids because all the kids who
had motorcycles were like [__] 17 18
uh 16 at least and I was just like the
odd man out and uh I walked up to the
man and they had a little bag of brown
pot and I never saw a brown pop before
in my life my mom never had Brown weed
and I was like why is it brown and they
were like because it comes that way and
I said does it grow that way and they
were like what do you know and I had
gotten a 20 back from my mom that day
and I had split it I'd rolled a couple
joints split it in half left half of it
at home took half of it with me in case
I wanted more weed and took the two
joints with me and uh so I went back and
grabbed a little half a bag of weed
which is now like a six dollar bag of
pot and uh and and a joint and I lit it
and I passed it around to all the big
kids and every one of them bro started
coughing their ass off and my one friend
was like is he's coughing he was like
well this is what it's supposed to feel
like it was just really hilarious and um
the kid John next to me was just like
where'd you get this pot and I was like
can't tell you and he was like will you
sell it to me and I was like yeah I was
like how much will you give me for it
and he was like if I gave you 20 would
you feel like I ripped you off I said no
I'll sell you that for twenty dollars
because I got more than twice that and
two joints for twenty dollars because it
was a 20 back because my mom was a
dealer so I just was like oh my gosh and
uh right when I did that my big friend
said can I get one too and I had the
other half at home and I was like yes
and uh so he only lived three houses
away from my grandma so I [__] like
it was that was it man from that day on
I became uh my neighborhood pot dealer
and uh I my poor mom dude I went back to
her that night after hitting her up for
a bag that day and said can I get
another bag of pot and she goes oh honey
you know I can't just keep giving you
bags of pot you know I was like
because now I had like 40 bucks I bought
gas which my my gas tank didn't even
hold a gallon and I swear gas was like
60 cents back then and um and like I
brought my friend to friendlies and I
treated and I think I spent four dollars
and uh we got Burgers and Fries and
sodas and it was like four dollars you
know it was 1982. so uh
so my mom looked at me and I was like
can I just buy it and and the look on
her face was sheer [__] horror you
know but she's like I guess so and uh
and I was like cool can I pick and then
she was like I put the 20 down and I
went to go get the bag and she was just
like she knew it was like this is not
good you know but uh I started selling
pot to my friends and uh it worked out
really well and by the time I was like
12 years old in six months I was
probably selling like 200 worth of weed
to my local friends you know because I
buy an ounce and I'd split it into four
bags and sell it from 40 each so I get
like 160 per ounce for like a quarter
ounce you know for 40 bucks and um
I never sold joints I would only give
them away because when people ask me for
joints I always felt bad that they
couldn't afford a bag of weed so I just
give them a giant give them a hug
because I felt like there was karma in
the world and I felt like if you were
giving away joints and somewhere
somebody was like lighting up a joint
that they couldn't help but to think
good thoughts of you
because like you just let them off the
joint for free you know and like I don't
know like I felt like if a lot of people
were thinking good thoughts of you that
your life would be a little bit better
but at the time my thought process was
with that but
um and then I went to sell a bag of weed
to my friend's older brother he was all
of like 19 at the time and when we got
to his house he had a Mel Frank grow
book and he had
um he had built he was a construction
worker so he built like this plywood
Closet in his living room where those
most normal people would have a
television and it was like four feet
maybe four and a half feet wide uh
because he had four foot lamps in it and
then he it was like maybe 18 that put 30
inches off the wall and it had doors and
when he opened it and I saw plants there
growing with the fluorescent light it
was like the color version of the you
know
um
that [__] um the emerald Brick Road
well the wizard of Vara is like well
they show color for the first time but
like my whole life changed that was I
was [__] floored man and uh I traded
him the 20 bag of weed for that Mel
Frank row book and I went home I cleaned
out my closet I already had seats I
found the pots the the clothing lines
that I used to hang the lights I found
the fluorescent light I found the timer
all it was all my grandma's my
grandmother had the light in the
basement the timer in the front window
she had the pots in the soil out in the
shed where she used to keep her pots in
her soil and her watering can and I
[__] dude at work it works so good
and I grew pot for like a year until my
grandma caught me and when she caught me
it was [__] cute as [__] because she
came up like I used to have my light
cycle eight to eight so when I was at
school it'd be dark and uh so she comes
up at like 7 59 and 55 seconds and the
lights glowing in the closet and she
goes to touch me and the timer clicked
off and she freaking and loses it saying
someone's in your closet someone's in
your closet and I'm like nobody's in
like closet and she was like show me so
she pushes me towards the closet and I
slide it open and I reach down and as
soon as I clicked the timer she heard
the sound of it she goes hey that's my
timer and then the lights flickered on
and she goes those are my fluorescent
lights and she looks down and I had like
these cool clay pots of hers and she's
like those are my pots that's my
watering can and I was like Graham the
only thing I had to go buy I was the was
the potting was the fertilizer and I've
been dying to tell you why all of your
house plants are dying it's because
you're not fertilizing them and she was
just like what and the plants were like
six feet high because I didn't know what
I was doing I was just raising the light
as they would grow and there she was
like four foot eleven she was Italian
and she like looks at this and she's
like they were bigger than her men and
they were in Bud and the leaves were
huge and she was like
do you bring these outside I said no she
goes they grow under these fluorescent
lights I was like yeah I was really
surprised myself and she was like
couldn't believe I did it you know like
she just couldn't and she couldn't she
like because they were clearly had been
there for a long time and um I left that
day with the deal that she wouldn't hurt
my plants while I was in school and then
I came home and I was like yo
what's up you know and uh she said I
think they need more room and I was like
oh so she let me put him downstairs she
had me lay down a pallet put my pots on
the pallet so they wouldn't be on the
concrete and then she let me use some of
her old drapes that had white vinyl on
the inside and I hung it to the exposed
wood and I hung a fan up top and I had
my fluorescent lights there and she
started watering the plants when she
would do the wash and then they finished
and I had my first Growers dispute ever
because like like one in the morning I'm
all stoned I like [__] cut the plants
down in the next morning I go down there
and my grandma's mad and she's in the
kitchen and I'm like what's the matter
she goes what did you do those plants I
said I harvested them she goes you
killed them I said well that's what you
do you kill them you know because where
are they now I said they're hanging
upstairs in my bedroom she goes she just
killed them and I said yeah and she goes
well what do you do now I said I plant
some more seeds she said and start all
over and I said yeah and she was like oh
God Todd I can't you should have left a
little [__] because I've been taking
care of him and I was like and I
realized at that moment how attached she
came to him and I felt so bad and uh it
was really cute and uh after that I I
did my first cutting in the kitchen with
my grandma uh we actually put it in a
napkin with a powder like formats I
still use it to this day number eight uh
it had been around since she was younger
and um I put in rooting powder put in
the napkin and we had it like in the
little like in a little she had sauces
for her tea and she would put a little
water in the saucer and left it right
there and the [__] Roots grew right
through the paper towel and and it was
neat and and that's when I started doing
cuttings way back way back in 1984 with
my grandma and uh it was really cool
honestly and uh I I other than going to
prison I've never stopped growing sets
wow what a fantastic like real organic
sort of story that's so cool you and
your grandma grew together I love it
yeah it's really funny she took my
Pringles can because I used to have
these uh they like chips that come in
America called Pringles and they they
come in a can they they're very much
like this thing so your chips are all
like perfectly formed and they don't get
crushed and uh it was really funny
because I had Pringles cans full of
seeds because when I get pot with seeds
I would take the seeds out and just sell
the weed to my friends because they
didn't want seeds and it didn't look
good in my bags so I collected all these
seeds and uh she she snatched one of my
Pringles cans and she had a garden
outside of her window where she'd have
roses grow up and then she'd prune all
the Roses so they all came just to the
height of her window so it would she had
opened her window it'd be all roses it
was really cool she was like really good
at gardening you know but you have to
realize she was born in 1911 and her big
like technological advancement when she
was a little girl was her house study
electricity
so just to put it in perspective and she
grew she grew her food in the backyard
and they they had to understand food
preservation and you know cultivation
was a part of human existence to her so
she's the one who taught me how to grow
a garden in our backyard and um and
she's really where all this came from
and I I will give her credit forever for
turning me on to this it was really cool
of her and but uh but she took my
Pringles can and uh turned the ground
and then sprinkled these cannabis seeds
like broadcast style all there and I'm
in the backyard selling my friend a bag
of weed it was dude you're gonna get
caught and I went
like I thought he meant selling in the
bag of weed and I was like that's what
are you talking about and he goes dude
all these plants and I looked down and
they were all like knee-high because as
they grew up my grandmother would take
her hedger and just sniff them like you
know with the hedger snip snip snip snip
snip so she had a little like it was
probably a hundred something little
plants but or more but it was like it
looked like a little Green Hedge you
know because she was just
like she did her roses and I was just I
went inside I was like Grandma what are
you doing and she's like don't you touch
those those are mine and I was like
Graham are you gonna get us in trouble I
was like you can't just be growing you
can't do this she's like why and I was
like Grandma is he legal she goes ah
plant and I was like
this is gonna be kind of hard to explain
I think you know because she just
couldn't wrap her head around the idea
that a plant was illegal like she was
like the drugs illegal but the plant
like what are you crazy and I was like
oh
and uh it was funny and she did cut them
down but she was pissy about it and um
it wasn't until I showed my mom and my
stepdad and and they all were like maybe
you gotta cut these plants down there
she was just like she she was hot she
was just a cool little lady but you know
it was pretty funny I got my first
traffic ticket when I was 12 years old
speeding I was doing 70 on the sidewalk
I got arrested they towed my motorcycle
and when they took me to the police
station they made me call my parents and
I lived with my grandma so I called my
grandma and uh she drove a 69 Pontiac
Firebird with like a uh souped-up 350 it
was hugger orange my my stepdad gave it
to her because he thought that his
mother-in-law Drive in a fast muscle car
would be cool so he gave her a fast
muscle car so I'm sitting in a police
station I'm 12. and and the cop hears
the car pull up
and he goes who'd you call I said call
my grandma and he opens the door and
there's this little little lady standing
in front of this [__] 60s muscle car
and he says is that your car and she
goes you got a problem with that and he
was like oh this is definitely your
grandson and he had to come in and he
says he was doing 70 on the sidewalk she
goes I don't think his motorcycle can go
that fast
he goes I had it on radar she's like I'd
have to see the radar
and I was just like I was there laughing
it was just like that was my grandpa you
know she was just she was just Nails you
know so it was adorable I I'm grateful
for her to this day you know and it's
funny because I started growing pot 1982
19 well it was 1983 technically the end
of 83 the beginning of 84 and um
and 13 years later I was living in a
Belair Mansion growing [__] 4 000
marijuana plants with [__] you know a
staff of six and I kind of think you
know how weird it is to go from living
on you know like welfare because I was a
pre-existing medical condition and we
were poor as dirt you know to like
living in one of the wealthiest
neighborhoods in the United States you
know growing thousands of cannabis
plants in your own home it's it I would
never have expected that my little
closet Garden could end up you know
to the places that it's brought me
yeah what a wild game it's been
so what'd you think guys I thought it
was great huge shout out to Todd for
taking the time to swing by and drop all
that knowledge on us I hope you're as
excited for part two as I am as usual we
want to give another quick shout out to
our fantastic sponsors CTN our best
seeds in the game you know them you love
them go check them out
coppered by logical systems your number
one choice for beneficial predators and
keeping any pests or pathogens at Bay
check out the appip RM despite X vital
both killer products
[Music]
likewise pro-mix connect your number one
mycorrhizal product from the good people
at promix you know them you love them
they've been around forever try their
mycorizer product I promise it's amazing
highest score count there is guaranteed
viability your plants are gonna just go
insane
and last but not least your bugs at
Charlie's cannabis check them out if
you're in Oklahoma there's no other
choice simply the highest quality
available exciting genetics new phenos
and new strains on the horizons always
check them out our good buddies better
known in-house produced Charlie's a bud
thank you so much Charlie's cannabis
finally a huge shout out to the patreon
gang you are the last Blood of the show
you guys helped to ensure the episodes
continue to be made if you want early
access to content you want to hear
unheard interviews get access to
exclusive giveaways prizes Discord so
much more go check out the patreon
www.patreon.com
[Music]
that's it friends thanks for joining me
again for this one guys making it to the
end I'll see you for the next one
[Music]
see you