foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
as always you're joined by your boy
heavy days here from the upside down
library and as usual we want to give a
big thank you to our sponsors we could
not make the episodes happen without you
a huge shout out to our friends at seeds
here now best seed bank in the states to
get your seeds from a guarantee on
satisfaction not just germination why
would you go with someone else before
they promise you is that the seeds will
crack these guys promise that you're
going to be happy as well check them out
guys number one in the industry they've
been supporting us for a long time the
hottest drops the latest Bringers check
them out please here now
likewise a huge shout out to our friends
at cope with biological systems with all
the best Predators preventative bugs and
feeds to keep the good army happy
healthy and keeping pests and pathogens
are bad
if you're battling spider mice check out
the spidex vital
or if you've got aphid problems check
out the ahip RM with proof of predation
technology built in you can see the bugs
working in front of your eyes they
change colors when they start eating bad
bugs what more could you want
huge chat at Copper biological systems
thank you so much for the support
[Music]
likewise shout out to our newest
sponsors simply souvenirs an incredible
seed bank based out of the UK stocking
only the highest quality breeders as
well as a range of smoking accessories
and a whole lot more if you're in the UK
or Europe check out Simply souvenirs
your One-Stop premium Boutique seed and
accessory store thank you so much guys
simply souvenirs we appreciate it
awesome and finally a huge shout out to
the patreon gang you know it we love you
lifeblood of the show truly could not
make episodes happen without you please
consider supporting the show on patreon
www.patreon.com
so for this one friends we've got a
special one we're joined by the one and
only soul of Soul fire to discuss all
the latest and greatest in his world
specifically focusing on his mind fire
drop which is happening right now today
[Music]
this episode is a special exclusive
synchronized for the drop and we want
you to hear more about what you can
expect from the killer crosses in the
mind players series
so without further ado
let's get into it
[Music]
alrighty friends we are back and a big
thank you and Welcome To The Man Behind
Some of the hottest drops you've seen
going around undoubtedly a legend in the
Pacific Northwest scene and just a great
guy in general big thank you and welcome
to Soul of Soul fire genetics thanks for
coming on the show again
hey thanks for having me back man it's
been a while
yes super Keen I was looking at it it's
almost been a year since we last chatted
so really yeah it's flown by hey yeah
that's it seems like that was a quick
year because
it doesn't seem like that long that long
to me as it seems like we were just we
were just talking about uh the Bahama
drop but I guess I guess it's kind of
flown by
well hey you you touched on it yourself
I guess for a man who's been as
productive and as busy as yourself
probably not hard to understand why the
time's flown by give me a little bit of
a rundown on what's been going on for
you in the past year how did the Bahama
Mama drop go in your opinion
uh I think it went amazing I mean for us
it was it brought in a lot of new a lot
of new Growers maybe to the soulfire
brand uh like the just the way that we
um you know revealed it and just like
unfolded it for people on Instagram like
doing our reveals showing the pictures
that we grew
um I just thought I brought maybe a lot
more people into the fold
um so yeah I guess last time that you
and I got together
um that was a year ago we talked about
that was the first drop of Bahama then
this year we did a uh the the second uh
volume of it which was much smaller like
we sold out pretty much instantly like
it was just gone you know
um and it was just as cool and you know
now we're on to other things but yeah I
to answer your question I think the
Bahama was big for the soul fire Soul
fire brand we keep seeing just crazy
heat that people are are finding in
there and yeah it's awesome
I would have to 100 agree with you that
drop in my opinion was one of if not the
biggest in the past couple years in fact
and a number of questions sort of
stemming from what you just answered so
then I guess the first place to start is
I noticed that the uh part two of the
Bahama Mama drop was a little more
limited I was curious to ask is there
any strains out of that drop that you
think will come to gain a bit more
notoriety even though maybe you didn't
get quite as many packs out as the first
drop
uh yeah so
I think I mean
I think like the weekend at Gary's I
think it was our first opener with like
a Gary strain uh or a great Gary cross
that and the gas nana I mean
some of the things that we just saw in
that which the gas Nano was
um was banana runs with with Gary Payton
and just some of the banana flavors that
we saw in there that weekend at Gary's
is is so just greasy and it's such a
good breeder that Gary
um I think those ones are gonna when
when people really dive into them I mean
I had to I did a remake so I don't know
a lot of people I guess it's the first
place you'll you'll hear it
um because I haven't told anybody this
but I did a remake of a lot of the
strains that we ran out of that people
fell in love with from the Bahama drops
so like Bahama Berry which is from
volume one
um we sold so many of those and people
just keep asking for it and there's so
many ones that they love of that same
thing with the weekend at Gary's so
um I remade some of those I also did
some bx's and
um
and yeah and then we remade the Bahama
S1 because that went out as a freebie
and for the first month of the Bahama
the first Bahama drop and you know I
think we gave up gave away like 30 000
of those
um so now we've remade the Bahama S1 as
a as a retail pack it'll just be priced
at our normal our normal pack price and
that'll that'll drop sometime after this
mindful maybe a month or so a month or
two so yeah
um but to answer the question I think
out of out of that second
um
the second release I think for me
weekend at Gary's is probably going to
be one that we see a lot of the
um
I don't know the lemon peel I mean the
lemon peel cross
the Bahama peel there I think the hash
lovers once they really get in there and
they start finding the the terp profiles
in there like when we were trimming up
all the the testers oh my God I was
trimming it with a couple hash guys and
you know they were just trying to walk
out the out the door with their all the
bags they trimmed they're like I'm
writing my name on this one I'm taking
this one home you know what I mean so
just there's just so much in that second
I wish I had more of I wish I would have
had more of them to share with people we
just didn't
yeah what a great answer and many of the
strains you mentioned were some of the
ones that I had sort of earmarked myself
and you know it's funny you mentioned
the Bahama berries I I popped a pack of
that myself because it caught my eye so
there you go you are so nice speaking to
the Testament of it uh the gas the gas
Nana man it's got some traction behind
it undoubtedly a lot of people I've
spoken to are really excited for it it's
an interesting pairing as well how would
you describe the flavors do you get the
banana coming through or is it more
dominated by the Gary
no the the banana comes through strong
so I was a little scared to do it like
you know I was like oh I don't know
exactly how this is gonna go I know
Gary's a great breeder and I know the
banana runs that I was using was very
candy banana very creamy Laffy Taffy
fake banana and I was like you know if I
can get
if I can get what I'm looking for out of
this which is like a a greasy gassy but
yet still fake banana smell then I'll be
happy and
I'm happy to say that like we
accomplished that so there's a there's
some green phinos in there and then
there's like some jet black phinos in
there as well so our selection of that
the one that we kept
which I didn't even find it so I so uh
our partners here in in Seattle uh no
mids they found the one that I actually
um I actually kept I found a bunch of
great ones like the ones I pictured and
showed were great but the one that he
found is just so intense with the banana
terp like that fake candy banana terp I
had to I had to keep his and it's yeah
so I guess the base best way I can
explain it is like a super
mechanic shop greasy smell which I
believe comes from the Gary and then
that fake banana so something completely
different than you'll see in a banana
runs but
very intense very intense Great Taste
too
sounds beautiful and while we're on the
topic of uh Gracie gas I noticed that
the Manda sold out very quickly from the
Bahama Mama series and not not
surprising do you think that you'll re
look to remake that one at all it seems
like it was extremely popular
uh maybe I don't think I'll remake it
but I may I may go through it and and
use it later
in another project but I don't have any
plans to remake it and it wasn't in our
in our remake schedule for um
for the ones that we just remade with
the with the Bahama so a short answer no
not looking to to uh remake that one but
possibly look through it hunt a bunch of
them and maybe find something to work
out of there
yeah beautiful stuff and would you say
that in general uh one of the sort of
strategies you use as a breeder is that
you do look to continue the breeding
forward each generation so like you say
you make the man do this cross and then
next one maybe you breed with that and
like keep working it forward or do you
sometimes just go back to the same thing
um I generally don't go back to the same
thing because I don't know we try to
keep it fresh we try to keep it unique
but if you've watched the pattern of
Soul fire I guess over the years you
know we've been out like six seven years
and a lot of our a lot of our lines come
from our original Black Banana line
right so
um a lot of them build on that
um so yeah I I would imagine to see some
offshoots if we sign if we find
something amazing but you know the the
Bahama that came from the original black
black banana line uh you know the the
Don Mega that came from our original
Black Banana Line This mind flare you
know it's it's a few steps from that
right because that was from the Yu jelly
but still you know originated from that
original work and I I think we just want
to see how far we can can push it and
how
how much we can improve it I guess if
that makes any sense
yeah definitely and I want to look back
to that but I got to quickly ask you
this question I've just been personally
curious about did you name the strain
Don Mega after your dog or is the dog
named after the strain oh no the dog is
named after this train yeah I love that
he's a cute dog I was like I would love
if this dog was called Don Mega it's
like such an imposing name on this cute
little dog yeah yeah so hopefully so
that's a he's a lilac fluffy Frenchie I
don't see any of them here in in Seattle
really
um I got him from my buddy who you know
he breeds in shout out to uh King County
kennels
um yeah I got him from him and dude he's
just the the most lovable cool I
actually have two so I have I have
another uh and I have a female a female
mural that I got from a friend as well
um I bought from a friend and I'm gonna
pair those two together so they're like
soulfire selected Frenchies I'm not
gonna have a bunch of Glitters it's not
my job it's not you know I'm not jumping
in the dog game that's not my not my
thing but
um I do find it super interesting like
that you should see the genetic profiles
that come with these dogs right like
they break it down to the allele
um so it's really cool to to see the
breeding that's going on with these dogs
so I'm gonna have one litter maybe two
litters of some soul fire pups and that
that'll be it for me rifle lose her mind
she already doesn't want to do it
the the male one you mentioned she's a
cutie when I saw the photos of her I was
like man I don't think I've seen a male
Frenchie before
yeah the murals are are super cool man I
mean she's got uh she's uh she's a
chocolate chocolate try try Merle Coco
try so yeah yeah she's got like cocoa
Paws and then like that cow that cow
print look and just a personality and
she's super small she's like 22 pounds
and he he's like 20 he's supposed to
finish out at about 25 pounds 25 pound
fluffy so I love it I guess that uh the
breeding you're gonna do is just just
regular release only not Femmes
no yeah yeah no it's not even regular
like you have to go and get these guys a
C-section artificial inseminated it's
like a whole process that oh yeah yeah I
really wouldn't want to do all the time
you know what I mean and like at least
the Breeders that I got my dogs from
they don't they're not like puppy mills
they don't keep their dogs in cages or
you know anything like that like they're
like family dogs and that's how our dogs
are because
you know anything less than that I I
wouldn't I wouldn't deal with it so yeah
um yeah no they're great I I love them I
didn't I didn't really know
that was gonna fall in such love with
them but yeah they got great
personalities
beautiful I love it I love it well let's
go back to a question that we normally
start the episodes off with what have
you been smoking on
uh so right now mostly a lot of a lot of
hash rosins so I'm smoking mostly the
[ __ ] mind melter I washed a bunch of
it when we did our when we did our test
for the for the Mind flare run and um so
that one I mean that's our first Don
Mega Femme well actually yeah yeah
that's the Megamind the uh the Megamind
is what we watched I didn't wash the
wine melter uh that's what I've been
smoking on I I've been using my puffco
just because I could travel around with
it you know I just gotta travel around
that [ __ ] thing when I'm on the run
and [ __ ] and then I I actually uh put
some in some little pens just for me in
the you know for the me and the homies I
just give them pass them out some pens
and and dude it blows man like
sometimes I forget you know when you put
when you have hat like good hash rosin
in a [ __ ] pen
um I was in the this is a horrible story
but I was in the uh grocery store the
other day and I was like I was in the
mid aisle I was looking at some [ __ ] and
then I just rip on this [ __ ] pen in
you know and I just blow it out I I
guess I forgot where the [ __ ] I was at
you know and
I look over in this like old lady is
looking at me like what the [ __ ] oh my
God what the [ __ ] are you doing and she
just got hit with this Cloud I was like
oh God but yeah yeah it's it's you know
the thing about those uh hash browns and
pens is they actually smell like pot
when you blow them out I guess is the
more the point of the story it really
smells like you just smoke some pot and
whereas a lot of these other like pens
and [ __ ] you get from the store smell
like I don't know not like weed you know
so I guess that's why I I enjoy those
but yeah that's what I've been smoking
uh just a little bit the hash that I
made I got some um Bahama Bahama Berry
flour from Nomads
um yeah I smoked a joint of that the
other day it was pretty tight
um so yeah I had a nice strawberry
stripe nice strawberry on the exhale
which is [ __ ] so I can't wait till
you grow yours and we'll see if you get
the if you get the strawberry on the
exhale you're gonna have to let me know
yeah look super Keen I'll keep you
filled in and uh Forever on listening uh
we're specifically gonna drop this
episode on the first when uh the new
mind flayer release comes out so why
don't we use this opportunity to sort of
dive into it and take a little quick
rundown of some of the strains in the
drop if that works for you sure unless
yeah let's get into it let's do it well
look we've already sort of spoken about
the mine melter a little bit what sort
of additional characteristics would you
mention about this one would you say
that it's specifically made for the
concentrate enthusiast
uh no I wouldn't go that far and I I
just I can't go that far because I
haven't washed a bunch of them right so
I watched the Megamind I watched the
Megamind and that's the don don Mega
with the Mind flare and I already kind
of knew that I was gonna wash just
because you know Don Mega watched so
well and you know I had a bunch of them
that we tested and I had this one that
was just monster big huge plant
um and it was ugly as [ __ ] so I'll just
be honest it was super ugly but I was
like oh man yeah I was feeling that I
was feeling the the nugs I was like I
think this thing's probably gonna wash
and you know I did the trick where you
you cut off a nug and put in a in a
glass or a jar of ice and water and
shook it up
maybe it'll look like a snow globe in
there you know and uh I called up the
homeboy and I was like man I sent him a
little video of it I said what do you
think you think the thing's going on
she's like oh yeah I think it is so you
know I I froze that one and washed it
and that's the [ __ ] that I was smoking
but um
I can't say that
that uh
you know the everything in there I
wouldn't make a claim like that until we
get some more feedback from other people
uh on that so but there's a lot of cool
stuff in there
a man of integrity I love that I think
uh some breeders would just happily say
that every strain washes very well
no I can't I can't I can't uh I can't
attest to that I I watched the the
Megamind it dumped for me it was like
really pretty pretty hash and I I try to
only keep the best and I still got you
know I don't keep like the full spec
like all the bags or anything and I I
felt like I got a really tight return
and I was happy with it so if you're
looking for a washer Dominic is always a
a good choice
um
to go with so Megamind other than that
you're on your own figure it out for
yourself
definitely and uh yeah Megamind my
apologies I had a brain fart there when
I said mine melter so the next one I'd
love to ask you about is the utter
Madness I think this one looks beautiful
based on the the photo you posted the
other day and the the parental lineage
is very appealing to a lot of people
especially those who are particularly
impressed by some of the photos of the
Bitties you put up in the Bahama Mama
drop what sort of plants can people
expect out of the utter Madness
super Frosty so this one I've seen it
now I grew it
um now we've seen growing with dragon
which is like a soul fire team member if
you're not familiar with them he's a
moderator in our Discord he's been he's
been you know growing our stuff for
years he has a YouTube channel a great
guy super helpful Dude too like he'll
answer any question you have just like I
will but I mean he's always there to
answer questions for for Growers so I
always send him we don't have testers at
soulfire
um not anybody can just test for us or
any of that so
but we have a few few different people
that have been with us for years that
are you know passionate about the brand
and just growing pot in general
um generally guys that grow in tents at
home right
um because that's I think my base is
mostly guys that grow at home and which
I'm very proud of
and he grew it and [ __ ] crushed it
um and then I saw no mid-seattle they I
was just down there looking at all their
ones and they're crazy so that structure
of the Bitties that people really loved
and that color that pink magenta that
Pop
um comes through and then
the Mind flare gives it to like
some more
stack even though it was already kind of
that Blockhead was already kind of
stacky and then the frost which I was
surprised on because the Bitties itself
um it wasn't the frostiest for me at
least that Blockhead cut the one that I
used in that cross it wasn't the
frostiest
um but these ones that come out from
this cross are insanely Frosty so it's a
good it's a good choice and it's kind of
got like a fruity
parfait like a fruit yogurt smell to it
it's cool it's definitely if you're into
colors you're into Frost
um and you're into something finishing
early like the the those pictures that
we the picture we put up from the
Bitties reveal dude that's day 48.
really
that's day 48.
I had no idea yeah so and I saw the
exact same thing when I grew up
and I saw the exact same thing that I
just saw down at no mid-seattle they're
at the scene they're at the same day as
um Dragon over in in Michigan and there
it's it looks to most guys they would
call that done I mean obviously dragon
and Nomads and myself were taking it to
63. for me as a rule of thumb I like to
take everything to 63.
um but these look damn near finished at
48.
so if you're looking for a fast strain
if you're looking for something to be
done quick uh utter Madness is probably
probably something you want to go for
for sure
that's brilliant and you you sort of
touched on a a general thread I wanted
to swing by you which was that at least
from my perspective it seems as though
there's some amount of conscious
decision making going into trying to
beef up the yields and I feel like as a
community we've sort of backed ourselves
into a corner with some of the hype
strains it feels like more and more it's
just accepted that you're going to get
smaller yields but I feel like your work
largely speaking has all of those exotic
characteristics but as you just
mentioned you're trying to pull the
flowering times down a bit and getting a
bit better structure and yield is this
something you did consciously think
about or am I just like wishful thinking
no you're right so you know when I
looked at the Bahama line
there was some
crosses in there that were extremely
heavy so like the Bahama Berry heavy uh
NFC could be very heavy creature Panic
heavy but some of the other ones were
not as heavy as I would like them still
Frosty's still beautiful still
everything you want to see in in an
exotic strain still have the turb still
taste amazing when you smoke it just all
the things you want but we're trying to
maybe make that stack better and so like
whereas the Bahama would be a lot more
flour very little leaves great for
trimming you know what I mean sometimes
you know there's just a little bit of
elongation in there that I was trying to
on this drop
trying to shorten trying to fill in that
stack and I feel like that's you know
what what mindful brings to the table is
an amazing stack and a faster faster
finish a faster ripening
um
and then like a chocolatey more
grease your terp to it and it looks like
uh in my opinion from what I've grown
and what I've seen Grown
um it it really brought some Frost to it
which I wasn't expecting I was expecting
a lot less frosts to be honest
um from the Mind from the Mind flow drop
but we got lucky and we got we got some
Frost out of it but it wasn't it wasn't
what I was breeding for with this with
this drop there you go happy accidents
are always welcome they happen yeah and
while we're on the topic give me a
little bit of a rundown about what it
was about the mine flyer when you first
saw it or whenever it happened that made
you decide this is the next uh pollen
donor to do what impressed you about it
oh it was the smoke on this one like
well the smoke and the interesting story
that that the Mind flow that we use from
this actually came from uh my my good
friend Vic from King County kennels who
who had grown and I gave him a box of uh
of beans way back in the day and he grew
that and he was like bro look at this
thing and I came over and looked at it
it has like all these crowns and and
fingers coming out of it and wild leaves
and just super and he was like and you
know it finishes super early and I was
like dude that's awesome let me let me
get that and I held on to it for a long
time and grew it a bunch of times the
homeboys grew it they grew it you know
they mono cropped it they're loving it
and I was like dude I love this [ __ ] so
you know shout out to Vic for for
turning me on to to that that plant and
I mean I think that happens a lot I
we have a tight group of friends type
group of Growers that we hang out we all
grow [ __ ] together you know and and if
they grow something of mine or or
anything they they were like oh dude
this is tight you should you know check
this out and then I grow it and so I
think you need that that community and
then to select from I'm lucky enough to
have it really so yeah beautiful stuff
and it as you said it's sort of a
testament to the work that can be done
when you uh have like a bunch of friends
helping out I was just thinking of that
saying what is it you know it takes a
village to raise a child it's almost a
bit like that to find the right pollen
donor yeah no for sure like soulfire
you know I I love coming on and doing um
podcasts and talking about the company
and and and being on Discord and talking
with people about you know the brand and
what we're doing but it's no by no means
me I mean there's a it's a big
it's a big thing to get it done it's a
big thing to get your seeds out it's a
big thing to select plants and it's it's
not just me at all it's a bunch of
people that make it happen and if they
weren't there or they weren't
um helping me out it would it just
wouldn't be it wouldn't be done so it's
no one-man band over here
that's it shout out to the whole team
shout out to the whole team as well as
your uh lovely lady I know she does a
lot of work behind the scenes as well
yeah she she does the most
undoubtedly so if we take a look at the
next mine player drop one of the really
caught my eye was the turn because I
don't believe I had seen you use the
rose cake before as a as a mother tell
us a little bit about the rose cake and
then how did the turn work out with it
yeah so
that one I will say so we got that from
Bellevue cannabis um they had it they
were growing it for a long time
um I just love the chirp on it I love
this the the creaminess of it the the
cakiness of it I was always a big fan of
like I don't know the cakeier strains
like the wedding cakes and things like
that way back when they were like the
cool thing you know and and
um just the look you know me I love pink
I love pink
pot I think that it's
I don't know I think it's underrepresent
you know under
represented
um out there in the strains and it just
it was unique it totally caught my eye
and I was like you know what let me grow
this a few times
I grew it a few times I probably sat on
it I don't know
months and months like you know I grew
it quite a few times before I really was
like you know what let's let's put this
in and then
you know then we had to grow it from
there again we had to grow the progeny
out and the progeny the smell is just
amazing you know the fruity cakey smell
is awesome so that's why I made it
lovely stuff and how do you think the
The Strain turnt ended up incorporating
you know the Mind Flair and the rose
cake
uh
uh I mean I think it's at least gonna
bring that the the time down not the the
rose cake was even a fast uh or a long
flower because it wasn't
um so I just think with the Mind flavor
we're always bring it we're bringing
these times down a little bit
um and then
you know the one I think it might be the
next one that we reveal actually it just
it has a lot of color it has
it has a lot to it it has a lot to it
and I think really the terp is what it
is
um I'm trying to select
for good smelling things that that
people are gonna like I mean we got to
get some different stuff out here you
know because there's just
you can only have gelato so many times I
love gelato gelato is amazing
um but we can only have so many variants
of that
um and we just gotta try to I maybe
that's why the Bahama was popular with
people because it was different like
there were some different there were
some different characteristics to it
um same thing with the Mind flare some
different characteristics and I think
that's kind of what the rose cake added
to this would be something different
yeah okay that's that's a great way to
sort of put it in just as a personal
thought I I feel like um
what you're saying is 100 correct right
like there can only be so many gelatos
but I also feel like you've done a good
job of uh helping to incorporate into
your work but also do it in a unique way
because if you look at like the why you
jelly and all the work that's come from
that I think there's a strong argument
to be made that like while there is
gelato in there it's really like not
just gelato or even gelato derivative
you've sort of turned it into your own
thing do you think that that'll be a
sort of method you use going forward in
terms of like yeah maybe there is
cookies in a cross but it's not like
your regular cookies
right and I think that's I think what
what you said is what
um I think every breeder should do every
seed maker should do is try to make
something your own you know like it's
anybody can take two two hype cuts and
put them together and be like oh this is
that you know what I mean but make
something your own
make it individual
and and unique and then and then
incorporate some of the flavors that are
already kind of out there and you'll see
that what you make is something new and
something all your own even though it
may have something that we've seen
before but you Incorporated your own
flavor with it so now it's it's all new
so
yeah don't just take two two cuts that
you you pick up at the farmer's market
slap them together and and think you did
something I think you gotta
kinda
you gotta make something first
so yeah certainly and that that's a
sentiment we hear echoed by many guests
I should have asked you earlier but I
think now's a good time before we keep
moving on when I pop those Bahama Berry
seeds in Minecraft if the Australian
federal police is listening oh geez when
I when I put those seeds they raced out
the gate and I thought beautiful healthy
seeds what I want to see and then it got
me wondering because I don't actually
ask this question enough on the show how
long do you think it takes for a seed to
become fully viable because in the past
I think I've said to someone as long as
you give like the seed like six weeks on
the plant it should probably you know be
pretty happy do you do you let it really
go because I've heard some people like
they just let the plant go to like 13
weeks you know because it's just like
more is better maybe I don't know where
do you stand on that one are we talking
about when we're harvesting seeds yeah
if you're just because a lot of our
listeners like to make their own seeds
how long do you think it takes
right it does not take that long so uh
we've had this debate as well
um when I'm making seeds I'll I pretty
much run the plant
um the same amount of time as if like we
were flowering the plant sometimes if
you let them go for too long
um those seeds will start to crack and
you'll start to they'll split open and
the seeds will still be viable uh but
they look weird like you'll see along
the edge there'll be like a little split
opening and I just don't know how long
those seeds will probably hold hold on
the Shelf uh as much when they have like
an actual air hole in there but yeah I
think to answer your question I you know
I'll bring the plants down about 63 hang
them and and let them just completely
completely dry I would imagine and this
is just anecdotal
um that those seeds are still ripening
while they're drying so they're still
probably going through like a you know
some sort of growth process of ripening
on the vine so you know I give them a
long dry
while they're hanging I wait mostly
because it's just
absolutely irritating to try to sort
seeds in any kind of stock that's still
wet or not 100 bone dry especially for
the way that that we do it our technique
by using the easy seed so
let them go to 63
hang them up
and then let them you know get a solid
solid drive maybe two weeks even and
then easy seat amount and then they
should go in your in your uh
refrigerator for a winterization for I
don't know a month to 45 days
yeah beautiful info there I love that
and you know what I had seen those
cracked seeds before and uh did wonder
what the situation with that was and I I
got a surprisingly really good
germination from them so I I yeah you
will I really was a bit confused because
I was sort of expecting them to not Germ
at all so thank you for that info yeah
so I wouldn't worry about that like
those ones that have the if they have a
little crack in it they're they're gen
they generally pop just fine I don't
know if they're gonna sit you know make
it like 10 15 years because sometimes we
pop seeds that are like 10 years old man
and have no problem as long as they keep
refrigerated not in your freezer but
refrigerated
um seeds will last a decade in my
experience but
um yeah people freak out man about
Caesar like oh these seeds are these
seeds are so pale or these seeds don't
have tiger stripes right these seeds are
dude seeds are like phinos right every
plant has a different different looking
seed
um Don Mega seeds are super pale
beautiful germination cookies and cream
seeds from from Mike Super pale
like white pill
pop amazing so seeds are different and
don't think oh this one doesn't have
tiger stripes it's that tiger stripe
[ __ ] just rubs right off it's just
outside coating
so that's just you know it's just it's
just seeds are different remember like
Gorilla Glue back in the day anything
that you cross the Gorilla Glue
absolutely itty bitty tiny seeds tiny
micro seeds yeah so some great info
there I love it and as uh you mentioned
earlier you know you you make a lot of
seeds you give away a lot of freebies
and so I'm imagining you must end up
with a lot of like I love giving away
freebies can we give away free how do we
give away freebie [ __ ] here oh let's do
it bro let's figure it out maybe we'll
do it through our Discord I was inspired
by your Discord shout out to your
Discord everyone go check out the
sulfide Discord this is probably a very
redundant statement you're probably
already on there because it's so good
but please go check it out if you
haven't but yeah bro let's do it I'd
love to yeah yeah I'm down we'll give
away we'll give away uh some [ __ ] uh
however you want to do it let's do it on
your Discord you know we'll send uh
we'll do a box uh one of these mine
flare boxes Give It Away on your Discord
it'd be awesome oh my God people
get get them stoked I'm gonna I'm gonna
have to be like 500 renamed entries in
that cross because this box is insane
and we'll talk about it soon I did just
want to quickly ask you before we move
on what do you think is the best thing
to do with all of the uh material that's
left over after you've shucked all the
seeds out because it sounds like you dry
it till it's really crispy so the seeds
come out easily what do you think is the
best thing to do with that spent
material so to speak
I just throw it away it's gross
um I just throw it away because there's
something there's some sort of you know
chemical change that happens when a
plant is actually pollinated versus it's
just left to flower and never you know
and never get that pollination so
um
yeah all that extra material I just I
just throw it right away I don't think
it would make anything very good it
smells great and it it looks pretty
decent but yeah no I don't keep it
I just and the way you know the way I do
it I do it in like a big pan
and like a like a barbecue pan or like a
baking pan type deal and then I I shuck
a plant off in there and then I'll just
you know with gloved hands just sit
there and break it up into the finest
material and then then you kind of like
pan for gold to get your seeds to go to
the bottom and then you just remove that
top layer and then I run it through the
easy seed and boom it just it just
cleans them up I it was absolutely hell
before that machine to be honest
with the volume you're doing I I can
only imagine the frustration before you
had that so yeah oh God it was a
nightmare glad to hear the easy seed has
made life easier for you we just
mentioned the um the Box you're doing
and I love I love the box it's a it's a
concept that's catching on among the
community I guess before we delve into
the specifics of the Mind player drop
I'd just like to quickly ask do you
think you'll look to do a box going
forward with most releases
yeah sometimes I can some it just
depends on how much stock we have
um you know there's a new phenomenon
coming on in America where
um hydro stores because of the farmer
Bill and because of seeds being you know
quote unquote legal now
um hydro stores are carrying
seeds so you can just walk into a shop
and buy seeds here and that's going to
change the landscape when it comes to
everything breeding
where you buy your seeds all that stuff
how it works breeders may need to scale
up who knows you know but this is
happening there's nothing we can do to
to you just might as well roll with it
because
um that's going to be the new way so
I think I like to do a box because I
feel like I can give people a lot more
um I try to generally try to keep it
kind of small as far as like uh how many
strains I put on a lineup
um it's it's by it's by design that we
only do six to eight because I think
it's ridiculous to think that somebody's
gonna go out and buy
you know 18 of your strains
and spend you know these guys will put a
a lineup of like 18 different strains
and they want 200 a pack for every
strain that's crazy I like to do six to
eight
100 bucks a pack that's the soul fire
standard right there and then in a box
you just get all kinds of freebies and
free [ __ ] and fun stuff and
you know it's affordable it's definitely
affordable so this box particularly we
um a lot most of the time we just let
Area 51 handle it because the logistics
of getting them out to people are a pain
in the ass and Area 51 is local so it's
easy for us and let them deal with the
headache but this time
um
I just went crazy pissed off the office
and just pissed off and just said you
know what let's make sure that every
bank that wants 10 of them can get them
you know
and so yeah every every verified bank
had an opportunity every verified vendor
had an opportunity to get 10 so you'll
be able to get them from from them if
they if they got in on it yeah beautiful
to hear because uh if if the listeners
haven't seen these books is very
generous and there's a lot of cool swag
in there particularly some of the the
seeds in there that I'm not sure you can
get elsewhere or at least not at the
moment no and you never and you never
will so yeah I put in it's one or the
other on on the hood candy freebies that
are in there and if you you'll get them
in the box and and that's it so if you
they won't be in part of the hood
Kenny's drop yeah love it and look uh
you know a lot of cool swag in there
especially the hood candies freebies you
mentioned and uh if people have been
paying close attention they might have
picked up some little clues that the
hood candies feminized uh lineup is in
the pipeline do you want to give us
maybe a little idea idea about what it
was about the hood candies that
stimulated you to look at it as the next
line to work forward
yeah I just loved I mean first the
community loved it they're always
they've been asking for forever I kind
of just hadn't done it because we had
all these other projects going
um and then you know I was just like all
right it's time you know let's let's do
this but we got to do it right you know
we got to have the right crosses in
there this one we're really going for
flavor you know this one we're really
going for smell I mean that's what
we're going for Terps on this one that's
what we bred for and and it's in testing
now so I really can't it it may you may
see it pop up in September you may not
it just really depends on how how it
goes so
nice and you just got my brain sort of
ticking there do you try to have a
certain amount of releases per year like
say two a year or is it really just like
up to the whims of how it works out
is really up to the whims of how it
works out I mean it could be none of
your if if everything just comes out meh
or it doesn't meet the criteria
um to stay relevant I believe you have
to you know keep it unique keep it fresh
has to be fire you know every time and
if it I'm kind of going for a soul fire
signature look like if it has that
signature look if you can look at my
pictures if you can look at things that
other people grow and say yeah that
soulfire right there I don't even need
you to tell me I don't need you to tell
me who who grew that or who bred that
because that's a soul fire strain and I
think that's what we're striving to
become something where you
you look at it and you know and the only
way to do that is through proper
selection and being able to say no or
being able to say this doesn't make it
into the line or this this whole line
doesn't make it out to the public
so yeah maybe you know you never know
sometimes things just don't don't make
it so even though we talk about it now
you see some freebies
in a box or you you there's some you
know Whispers of a of that line coming
if it doesn't make it through our
quality of
it won't be there that's great to hear a
good sort of uh quality assurance and I
guess to talk a little more General
about say how could I phrase this your
sort of trajectory as a breeder I
certainly have noticed that you're
you're doing things in this very
professional sort of way in the sense
that like often I don't even hear about
your work like a lot of breeders they'll
tell you hey I'm testing this out blah
blah blah your work it's professional in
that it you just hear about the drop
coming and the testing's already
happened and you you didn't even know
about it and I wonder is this something
you're intentionally doing moving
forward because it certainly feels like
it could be a paradigm shift where
that's how breeders start working where
it's like you don't really know what I'm
doing right now but you'll hear about it
in six months
right I mean I think that's how they
should be working if you're not growing
if you personally aren't making your
seeds and growing your seeds then you
shouldn't be dropping your seeds it's
that it's that simple so if you make
something you grow it and you feel like
it's awesome and it was awesome for you
then you can have confidence in giving
it to other people so uh yeah there's no
there's no like this is the upcoming
dropping it's happening for sure because
I want it to that's that's not how it
works it's not I can't will it to happen
it has to happen because it was quality
enough for it to happen
so I I think that's probably how a lot
of
breeders maybe I don't know I I don't I
only really
[ __ ] with like my mic and and the guys
in my circle so I don't know what the
other people do I don't really pay much
attention to them
um
so I would hope that's how they do it
yeah look I think it's going to be a
growing Trend I just I always love it
when a log on and I see a new upload
from you because it's usually a very
mouth-watering picture but if we just
jump back to the hood candies you know
we mentioned it's coming in the future
it's looking promising I guess with
everything we've said so far it might be
a bit of a no-brainer that people look
at the block monster and think hey this
is the one tell us a little bit about
the block monster that's coming out
oh and the mind player dropped yeah so
that that thing is it's just got this
chocolatey Z Terps you know and it's it
was again a fast fast Vision finisher
super Frosty uh really vigorous like
early on in the garden it just it was a
bully that's not a guy's name it was it
was growing just so fast it was like you
know bullying its neighbors around and I
was like man this thing is a monster in
here so um yeah it was it was a fun one
it was a really a fun one to work with I
think people are going to be really
happy with I think we're gonna see a ton
of great
a great uh finals that come out of that
yeah and I love it I love I love when
people get it and then the joy that they
get from growing it I mean that's a huge
part of this for me the the reward I get
from the happiness like the actual joy
that people get from growing our strains
I I talk to them every day every day
um I I if you posted on Instagram
you'd be don't be surprised if I pop up
and like it and and say something about
it because I if you're growing my gear
I'm I'm behind you 100 I'm you'll hear
from me that's great to hear I love that
so I did see on Instagram someone uh
posted up a cross called Californian
demon the LA Crush cake cross mine
player and it got me wonderings right
how many crosses do you make when you
initially do a lineup and if you had to
guess what percentage of them make it
through to the end stage of like getting
to Market
yeah so we make a lot uh we we make a
lot and we grow them all so I can't I
don't know a a percentage of it but you
know when we make a line it starts out
very big and then we go through there
and we look at
who who gets to stay which which crosses
are good enough and a lot of times a lot
of them are amazing but just didn't work
with this the design of this lineup it
just didn't work with the flow of it so
um you know I'll look at it I'll pick
out which one do I you know this one's
going to be a great Soul fire slap or
sometimes sometimes a soul fire slap
might not even be tested you know
soulfire slap is such a it's a it's a
community and that's what that that
California demon is the soulfire slap is
such a
a community engagement uh
a group thing you know a lot of times
those aren't human tests those just go
out as a soul fire slap you slap up a
sticker you you put it in Discord
um if it's awesome I'll post it on
Instagram if you get posted you get a
free pack of seeds that's how it works
and yeah that that California demon is
dope like we've seen uh a ton of those
that are heat
um
but yeah to answer your question we make
a ton and then we Whittle that down to
that six or eight that we think people
are really going to enjoy
beautiful stuff that I'm Keen to hear
some more about some of the ones that
you've tested with but I did want to
quickly mention it because you you spoke
about you know your home is with exotic
mic you don't really drift too far
outside of your immediate circle people
would probably be aware and if not you
definitely need to get on to it you've
been doing uh your own podcast with Mike
The Grow life with the Bros tell me a
little bit about that how's it been
going for you being on the other side of
the mic
dude I you know what you know how that
came about as I was just so inspired by
our first meeting because you're such a
good host you know what I mean I went
back to Mike and I was like man you know
I hate I never wanted to do these
[ __ ] podcast things because honestly
I don't like it to be ever about me
because it's not about me like I was
saying before soulfire is a team like
from the guy in his that grows at home
to you know Soul flower in the in the
office that that sends out everything to
all the workers in there to everybody
else like are so much more important
than me in this
um so I never wanted to be like front
for Face Forward front in front of the
whole thing
um but then you know I did your your uh
podcast and a lot of people really
enjoyed hearing about about you know the
story and all that stuff and I was like
man like we should do one but
we should just do a podcast in Discord
that's live where we can give away stuff
and interact with the uh interact with
the audience just right there
and really just [ __ ] because that's
what we do all the time anyway I mean
the guy calls me you know every morning
when he's out for his his jogging we
just [ __ ] about everything that's
going on from politics to pot to just
what's going on in our life and so
pretty much every morning we'll have a
two-hour chat about just [ __ ] so so we
wanted to put that in front of people in
kind of a funny way and interact with
people that uh
that enjoy that so yeah so hey you were
the you were the inspiration for that uh
man you're a way too kind I appreciate
that that's I'm just being real oh man
look I I've tuned in and listened to him
myself they're great and I love the the
live interaction component that is one
of the aspects of this show but what did
you think about Mike's rap verse in the
start of the show look I still want to
get uh Mike on the show so I'm not I'm
not going to comment on it
yeah I think it's great I love it when
breeders kick back and have fun with the
fans I remember a while ago Mike would
do those um Talent nights on his
Instagram they were always fun to watch
as well when he was like with the milk
and everything yeah and he'd just like
get two random people on the live and
just be like all right debate each other
or like just do something fun it was
always good oh dude I remember I
remember the uh like uh the talent shows
he had some dude there are some people
in there with some actual like real
talent they were doing some crazy things
yeah right I forgot about that that [ __ ]
was great yeah yeah I remember one time
this guy's just beatboxing and he was
great at it I'm gonna tell him he needs
to start a variety show or something I
mean the guy is hilarious uh I'll give
him that like me I'm more of a more
conservative I like a little bit more
reserved and then you know Mike is like
just so out there sometimes he's like
the class clown so together we're it's
it's kind of funny yeah man good times
for sure will everyone make sure to tune
in for the next one I believe you post
about them on your Instagram so just
keep an eye out for it that'll be a fun
one yeah next one will be I think the
29th so so by the time this year is
it'll have already passed but we do it
every other we try to do it every other
Wednesday
um yeah I mean maybe we should get you
on there as a guest that's just like
flipping the roll the roll reversal all
the way around just look I would not
turn that down so uh very appreciative
nice all right yeah let's do it that
sounds awesome so if we jump back to uh
the the strandless from the mime player
there's sort of only one that we haven't
touched on too heavily which is the soul
Sonic how do you feel the Gary paired
with the uh the Mind player oh I felt it
was great so I don't know man like that
for anybody who's doing any projects or
or working any lines I was a little um
I don't know I was a little resistant on
using the Gary uh at first I grew it and
I liked it and I thought it was good you
know it was really good I had a great
smell
um but something special happens when
you um when you breed with it it breeds
amazingly well so when we put it with
that and you can just see from the the
picture that I posted so we did like
again we um a pre
a pre exclusive with that Soul Sonic on
420 where you could get it just for I
think a few days
um
and just from the pictures of it like
the way the leaves are the I loved
growing it I had so many keepers of it
that yeah I I don't even know it was
hard to narrow down and that's I think
that's kind of what how you make it into
a line in our camp like you can you can
test something and be like ah you know I
got one keeper out of like a bunch or
you know whatever but if you have one
that it's like hard to find a keeper
because you have so many Keepers you're
just like ah I can't keep all of these
plants but I I should you know that's
how you that's how you make it into the
line and and that was definitely the
case with um with soul Sonic yeah I
loved it it's great so that Gary just
puts his gas
like a greasy gas on on pretty much
everything it it touches
that's that's great to hear and I
specifically wanted to ask you a few
people have said that Gary and even as
an extension cookies can sometimes be a
bit of a bully in crosses because it's
so dominant do you find that that's the
case or do you think it's just a matter
of pairing it with something that's
equally dominant so you get a bit of
both representation
I think you need I think it's
it's the pairing I I will say
that one that Gary is kind of a bully
like it definitely leaves its mark on
its cross right like it it has this
greasy residue that's on the
on the flowers that's and then that just
man when you smell it it's so amazing so
I I really like it I like the way that
it breeds but yeah it's a it's a bully
for sure I wouldn't say that all the
cookie strains are like that but that
one yes
but I think it's progeny or better than
it itself
and that's just my personal opinion the
things it makes are better than the
original
yeah beautiful stuff and while I've got
you here I want to ask you because I got
to admit I wasn't really particularly
familiar with the cake mix before you
sort of introduced it with the baby
cakes you got me wondering do you have
any strong feelings on Cherry Pie I feel
like it's sort of starting to make a
little bit of a comeback but I've also
never really heard you speak about it do
you have any strong thoughts on it
um I think it's awesome I've seen it
grown a ton I remember growing it back
in the day and it had some stability
issues if you had the right the real cut
of it right yeah so I had I definitely
had some stability issues
um but I think with how
you know the modern Gardener is a lot
more Savvy when it comes to you know
dealing with problems dealing with
intersex issues I mean now we've we've
grown we've all grown enough cookies
to know how to spot and and deal with it
it's it's a much more educated um
I guess landscape so I have the cut I I
also just recently reacquired the cherry
pie
um I need to grow it again to like
re-familiarize myself so yeah it is
making a small comeback though and I
think the the the flavor and the terp of
it when it's grown
the the right way
is amazing so
definitely it's definitely got some
unique sort of uh characteristics about
us that's cool to hear we may hear more
about it in the future I would love to
ask you I feel like uh gas has had a bit
of a Resurgence in the past few years as
like a general flavor type would you say
that you agree with that and do you
think it's still on the up and up or
we're sort of plateauing a bit
well I don't know I think uh I think one
of the cooler things about you know
cannabis and cannabis breeding is the
locales so like certain areas in the
country like certain flavors if you go
to La it's gas they love gas down there
you know you go to the Bay maybe it's
more z-term more cookies you know they
still like gas too it's just different
areas of the country like different
things I know like New York went on a
crazy tangent for like sour d it was
everything had to be sour d and
um so these things they come in waves
they come in in different regions uh
have different popularities so yeah I
think gas is always going to be popular
sometimes it's going to resurge and then
it'll die down and maybe like you know
like a z-term or a cookie turp will pop
up it's I mean that's just kind of what
makes it cool
yeah definitely why have you heard about
have you heard about some new gas that I
don't know about because I'm gonna need
to know
look I I was hoping it was going to be
coming from you to be honest what's hot
on the rear what's hot on the radar I
need to know what if you what have you
seen lately have you heard about
um I've seen hardcore ogs1 getting a lot
of traction recently there must be like
a specific S1 that people have found
that's really special really no I
haven't but I'll be investigating look I
know that you're uh your reach spreads
far and wide so hopefully next time we
chatter you got it in the stable or you
can give me an update at least that's
right you never know now I want to find
it sounds like it sounds like it might
be interesting that's cool yeah I mean
I'm always looking for I I'm I'm always
looking for what the what the other guys
are doing you know like um I'm uh
I'm just like all the other I'm just
like any other seed guy that I buy
everybody's seeds every other breeder
any breeder that that is out there that
uh looks interesting I've bought your
shed I have it and I'm popping it
currently I go through a lot of
different people's stuff looking for
unique
things and I think if if you know
anybody out there is thinking about
doing like making doing projects
breeding I think you should and I think
I think you should pop everybody you
know popping so far is cool and you're
gonna find some heat you're gonna find
some stuff you love but but pop
everybody's go pop mic stuff go pop
whoever pop other people's stuff find
find all that heat because that's how
we're gonna get the new stuff
you know like it's come it's become so
mundane
um
like where's the new flavors at
you know I'm I'm waiting
I'm waiting I love that that's great
where's the heat like you know I don't
know that's it man yeah for the longest
time I've said that I think the uh the
wheels of our community metaphorically
spin on people popping seeds
oh no it does 100 like if if you're sick
of seeing the same strains or you're
sick of there not being a new flavor
then start popping seeds if you're not
popping seeds you're part of the problem
you know what I mean like yeah you're
gonna find those somebody somebody has
it right now it could be Soul fire stock
it could be whatever but they have it in
their Garden right now something [ __ ]
amazing they're probably never gonna
post it on Instagram probably never
gonna tell their buddies about it they
probably don't even have a call of it
it's just gonna come and go
I I agree it uh it could be the the
raspberry Mama inside heavy dice tent
dropping soon yeah it could be you never
know it could be anything like like uh
I'm sure with all these new Growers
coming online and all the beans that are
getting popped there's some there's some
cool [ __ ] out there we just gotta we
just gotta be as you would say privy to
it that's it man you gotta have your
finger on the pulse I was interested in
asking I'm I'm particularly Keen to get
my hands on one of these boxes because I
noticed inside it is the Mind flare S1
and I'm not sure you can get that
anywhere else have you tested those at
all slash what am I yeah I cool what are
we expecting
uh I grew some just uh a nice it's a
it's really close to the original the
original mind flare that I that I grew
and and used for this so
um yeah those are in the box it's not
part of the drop you can only get it in
the box so there'll only be x amount of
them uh out there you know so
enjoy I like to do that I like to I like
to make things very limited because I
feel like that makes them you know
cooler like if you were in that moment
if you were there to
to get those things then you got them
and if you weren't then maybe you can't
and yeah yeah that's it you missed the
boat guys don't don't be left that's
right don't miss the boat yeah because
and we do that with a lot like our last
supper cross that was out in the in the
uh Bahama line guys are always asking us
about that like oh my God we got these
last supper freebies with like some
banana runs packs and these are the most
amazing things so Frosty the turps are
crazy where are they at where can we get
them you can't if you didn't get them if
you didn't get that freebie for that
thing it is gone and we're not remaking
it so uh we do that
for sure on purpose for sure so yeah be
there in the moment or be
wanting or maybe you could find it out
there you know like guys have [ __ ] so
you never know but while we're on the
topic I would love to hear because I
know sometimes this is a hard one
because you you tend to want to know a
bit more info before you give an answer
but if you could only recommend one of
the Mind player crosses just as that you
think is sort of a crowd pleaser what
would you recommend and as a follow-up
what is your personal favorite of the
drop
um yeah so if I
if I was a guy and I was looking at the
menu and I was just like you know what I
can only get one which one am I gonna
get which one I'm like I probably go
it's hard to say because they're all so
different and you know you have
different reasons for forgetting
something but if I was a guy looking for
something to wash and I was a hash guy
I'd go Megamind
um if I was a guy that is going for like
bag appeal
you really can't go wrong with any of
them but that's a hard question yeah
it's hard utter Madness is is an awesome
one
um
yeah if I just had 100 bucks and I had
to pick one I don't know I don't know
it's tough isn't it it's tough because
like like I like we were talking about
earlier when we designed this line
we put each one in here for a different
reason you know
so they all have a reason why they're
here
exactly well what's your personal
favorite
I I don't have a straight up personal
favorite because I can't I couldn't
choose like Soul Sonic over mind melter
be I just couldn't and I couldn't choose
like mind melter over Megamind so I I
don't know who would be my personal
favorite I suggest like a mind melter
maybe if you're if you're new uh to Soul
fire you won't go wrong you know if if I
was a if I if I've never heard of
soulfire before I had 100 bucks to spend
and this is going to be my my
intro
go mind melter strawberry mind melter
you're gonna kill the game
you'll fall in love
um
yeah there that's I guess that's what
I'll say that's a good recommendation I
was gonna say yeah I think like the
heavy yields and the Terps are going to
help so that's a good one and yeah just
to loop back quickly you mentioned a
little earlier that you you know you pop
a lot of other breeders stuff and you're
familiar with who's doing what I was
curious to ask are there any strains or
breeders that have caught your eye
recently
um
yeah I mean I like I definitely like
what like Bloom is doing
um uh with his terp profiles uh I I've
been popping a bunch of like older older
stuff so I was uh I popped some TGA
stuff oh Kayla what stuff yeah
uh like so just like a bunch of stuff
like some of his uh his this was a while
back but his um
his train his blood wreck crosses so
um I think that it was it was named his
uh uh what the [ __ ] was it I know
chernobyl's one
no I didn't pop Chernobyl I didn't find
any any keeper sadly but um it was like
a quirkle it was like a quirkle cross oh
yeah uh crazy train is the Crazy Train
yeah yeah so so Mike has this huge uh
thing full of seeds tons like dude from
all over the years I have a big Vault
but he has like a huge Vault and uh he
gave me a bunch of crazy train uh seeds
and I I popped those I didn't find what
I was looking for like turb wise so none
of them really made the cut but
um and that's the case with a lot of
different breeders like I'll pop a bunch
of stuff there'll be some heat there'll
be some tight stuff but it just has to
like make the cut so
um yeah that and yeah I'm always buying
I'm always buying seeds I have a buying
seed problem I I would imagine like
everybody else
yeah look I think I think we're all
addicts in that regard
um just out of uh like a a general sort
of curiosity slash follow-up I remember
in the last episode we chatted about uh
the flave being one of your memorable
ones oh yeah did you know that Miss Jill
is uh putting that out again like you
can get it again
yeah I wonder how I mean I wonder how
like close to what it what it was before
is yeah so do you know when that's
coming out because I'll definitely grab
some well I think it it might even be
out now but you nodded on the head the
I've got a question about that purely
because the original it was like Romulan
by a space queen
that's right and the ram the Romulan was
heavied man yeah and so like there's a
lot of like you know question marks
around Romulan these days but on top of
that they also listed as Peach Romulan
and not just Romulan and so I'm like oh
is that their way of subtly tipping
their hat that it's not the same
yeah maybe because that wasn't what the
original one was yeah yeah exactly but
um who knows did they put up any
pictures of it or anything because I can
tell from like the pictures how similar
it really is because it's the flavor
that we used was very unique like the
one that Mike selected
um it was very unique
yeah look I'm I'm trying to pull it up
on my phone now it's on Miss Jill's page
but it should be like kind of eggy and
like
big big bright green or yeah bright
hairs I'll have to send you a photo off
the upside I'm trying to pull it up but
I can't find her Instagram right now
when I'm under the crunch I always like
dude everybody always is getting deleted
so
yeah it's so terrible it's wow that's
part of the reason why we went to to
Discord you know
yeah right the constant persecution on
Instagram is horrible
yeah I wonder if anything's gonna
actually change because it's like you
can like you see paid advertisements for
cannabis but then also people getting
banned yeah no I don't think it's Gonna
Change it's not gonna change until it's
federally legal I mean yeah the rock can
the rock can take down a a bottle of
tequila and that's fine and nothing
against The Rock I love the rock
um but you know God forbid like you post
some pot then you could just be banned a
lot of it is the is the like the the
weight that they give
um the report
like so sometimes you'll get reported
for uh hate speech or or all this other
crap that has not you know that
around you know it's a it's not even
what it is but
um they'll pull your post down because
somebody said that you were you know
being abusive by posting pot it doesn't
even make any sense
yeah it's it's definitely it feels a bit
like the wild west doesn't it
yeah a little bit it's just over over
policed it's crazy because you know you
can watch somebody literally get
murdered on Instagram that's fine you
know that doesn't come down but a guy
posts a plant and it's oh you know he
loses his whole account that he's had
for years it just doesn't make sense to
me honestly yeah do you think that
Discord will become even more popular
than what it is now oh yeah oh yeah it's
gonna be huge I mean I told so I wish I
could take credit for like
a lot of cannabis guys moving to Discord
but I really can't like Lem here in in I
knew about Discord years ago just for my
kids playing like video games and me
playing video games with them it took
over
um
for like TeamSpeak so like we would use
TeamSpeak or Ventrilo back then and
um Discord came along and my kids were
like oh dad like you know Discord is
away and when I first used it I was like
this [ __ ] sucks like it's not that
intuitive there's so much different
things going on I wasn't into it at
first and then after a while and I was
able to figure out how to kind of use it
and how versatile versatile it is I was
like oh this is pretty cool you know and
then um there's a there's a breeder up
here in in Washington named lemon lemon
hoco uh lamb and he has a Discord a
cannabis Discord and it was you know
they got a lot of different stuff going
on in there they got all this stuff
going on and uh that's when I first saw
that idea and I was like okay and I set
up the soul fire Discord we didn't have
any barely any followers we basically
just sit and and chit chat in there with
like me and dragon and just a couple of
the the regular guys and
um you know I told Mike about it and at
first and and and then and then at that
point then like uh Masonic started his
own Discord and he started you know
getting his thing going and then uh I
was telling Michael I was like hey man
we you should do a Discord bro blah blah
he's like nah I hate Discord that [ __ ]
sucks just like how I was when I first
saw it you know and uh he's like nah
this [ __ ] [ __ ] sucks and then
um after a while after he just had had
enough of it with like Instagram he you
know he started doing his nft steps and
he's he set up a uh Instagram and
um then we her uh Discord rather and uh
yeah and he just kind of got used to it
I think that's what's gonna happen I
think a lot of guys who Maybe
aren't that tech savvy or it's not that
intuitive for them I think they're going
to they're going to come along because
um I mean really that's where the core
of the soulfire base is is in Discord
you want help you have problems with the
plant pop into Discord we got 7 000 guys
there ready to help you answer a
question you want daily giveaways we're
doing them every day at 4 20. you can
get uh you know we're giving away a pack
of beans you want to post your pictures
of what you've grown and what you've
grown and show off and show other people
what you're doing that's where you can
do it um just the community interaction
in there is amazing like
you couldn't ask for more it's like
forums it's like a modern day forums I
would say you know definitely I feel
like yeah it's it does have that um
longitudinal ability to track threads
and things like that which is definitely
something that people have been calling
for for a long time which is like really
great to see and as as your Discord
illustrates you can really get them
popping with a lot of different
functionalities and sort of various
different things happening at different
times there's a lot of reasons to be on
there
yeah no for sure and you know it takes a
lot of work too like I have I have an
entire staff of um moderators that are
in their 24-hour Summit different time
zones so that like you know we can just
keep it like uh a positive space that's
um about what we designed it for which
is growing pot and talking to other
people about growing pot and sharing
um Tech and sharing ideas you know like
we have a whole area just about getting
your setup right a whole area about you
know every different facet and you know
you really get to know these guys I mean
in Discord you have pretty much
24-hour access to the breeder who's
making your safes so you can talk to
them about you know whatever at any time
and I think that right there alone just
changes the game so there's a lot to it
if you set up a Discord just be ready
for the uh the bumps here and there but
there's just so so many different things
you can do it's it's awesome
yeah definitely huge functionality huge
functionality cool I was just gonna uh
mention that one thing we hadn't
actually spoken about yet a little bit
uh off the topic of the Discord is where
do you think like the flavor demands are
going in the future like what do you
think is going to be the next big
popular flavor to take the scene by
storm
well I think I think gas is like you
said making a comeback
um I think it's cycling cycling back uh
I don't know I'm waiting for like a new
flavor profile to pop up we were just
talking the other day about like
watermelon strains and how I've never
I've never tried a strain that they say
tastes like watermelon it actually does
I would love to if you have one out
there and you're like so fire there
really is a watermelon strain that
actually tastes like uh watermelon I
would love to try it I haven't not like
one that's like banana or like
strawberry or like orange or apple like
our our Apple uh our Apple Pucker strain
that was in the Bahama is amazingly like
apple it's crazy like apple I would love
to see that flavor profile uh take off I
I just saw I was at the homeboys house
the other day it was
growing his uh his pucker UPS and it was
crazy Apple
so yeah I don't know I'd like to see
like a flavor like that like a true
Apple come out
um
I don't know I don't know where we're
where we're going uh as far as flavors
yeah I I certainly can attest that I I
haven't really come across many true
Apple flavors so that's neat to hear the
Apple Pucker will have to get on to that
oh it's it's insane yeah in terms of the
watermelon I haven't likewise haven't
ever really come across it but I think
Bodhi says he's got a land race
African hash plant I think uh I can't
remember if the Ethiopian watermelon
hash plant is what he calls it but again
that that's getting a bit uh wild and
Untamed to be dealt with it
yeah I mean yeah he he had a lot of
great he has a lot of great flavor
profiles and honestly I haven't popped
any of his beans for a long time I think
the last thing I popped from him was
like uh what was it like in a Kai or
something maybe it was a long time ago
I'll have to I have to Circle back now
that you writing it down right now
that's great he's got some cool stuff in
there for sure
yeah we have to Circle back and give him
a give him a a little test pop there and
see what we can find
out of curiosity have you ever come
across like a real passion fruit
flavored strain
like a like a guava yeah well I have you
so this is actually another point that
I'm only just starting to learn
um a passion for it's like common where
you're at like the fruit passion fruit
here in Washington no okay yeah I mean
we it just rains all the time right so
we don't we don't get any of the cool
fruits that you have down there in
Australia no we don't give any of that
[ __ ] no because it's like I was talking
to someone the other day and they said
oh you know I've never had it and it
made me realize like yeah I guess I just
take it for granted that it's just such
a commonplace fruit down here that um
anyway it's like a it's like a a sour
tart not like super sour but like a
Tarter version of like sort of a mango
with some more floral influence in there
more like citrusy almost but beautiful
stuff but another flavor profile which I
feel you don't really come across very
much like in that same vein as the Apple
right I mean maybe I don't know maybe we
just haven't haven't I I
believe that this isn't it like the
flavor profiles that we have right now
that's there's no way that this is it we
just we haven't created them yet or they
haven't been discovered yet like
somebody's gonna discover them so I mean
you know back in the 70s when they were
growing pot I was pretty much just
skunky skunky pot there wasn't all these
strawberries and watermelons that are
you know and all these different flavors
they weren't there so there's more to
come I mean I don't know I talk to
people all the time and they just seem
so like down and downs about
where cannabis is in general
um
yeah and about like the flavors that are
around they they talk as if we're at
like the peak and it can never be better
and this is it
and I just don't think that that's the
case
you know I think I think we're we're
nowhere near the top I think we're we're
still creating I think there's so much
more stuff for like like new guys coming
on to like create there's there's so
many new breeders coming out there's
going to be cool stuff being made yeah
definitely I feel like there's so many
like because I think this plant is very
well capable of producing any smell
possible and so yeah where's all that
stuff we haven't smelt uh-huh it's
coming don't worry like whether it's uh
whether it's me making it or somebody
that has it right now in like some seeds
that they made and dude that's why I
always encourage people like hey if you
find something cool in a pack of seeds
you get from me please by all means
breed with it make something new make
something your own
um it you do not need to ask me I still
get these messages all the time like hey
is it okay if I yes is it okay wait yes
yes it is okay it's open source I want
you to breed with it I want you to make
your own things I want you to create
something new so I have something to
work with
so yeah that's great philosophy I love
that I uh I do want to ask I'm not the
gatekeeper of the [ __ ] at all
and if they if if you buy a pack of
seeds from soulfire you already know
like it's it's inherently yeah ingrained
that you have my blessing to go ahead
and and work that line create something
create something new yeah that's amazing
so I did want to ask the uh with the
Bahama Mama drop we we had the part two
um after you know the initial uh success
of the the part one of the Bahama Mama
is there any chance we're going to see a
similar thing with this more recent drop
uh there won't be a part two of the Mind
fire
yeah there won't there won't be a part
two
um of it I think we did the part two
because of what I said earlier where
I think it's unfair to put out so many
strains at one time
and put that stress on you know just the
common Gardener's pocket like oh here's
14 strains but you can only pick a
couple at the you know what I mean no
I'd much rather put out six and then six
to eight and then maybe in
six months later you get another six to
eight from that strain if we had that
many that should go into it
um so but with the Mind flare I think
this is we're just going to do this this
six and and and that'll be it there'll
be different freebies or maybe different
exclusives you'll see
um but there won't be a there won't be a
a part two and we we made enough stock
so that there's plenty of boxes that go
out and yeah that'll be it that's the
exciting stuff I'm Keen to here and I
guess it further just reinforces that
there's no better time than now guys
don't don't wait around this is it jump
in yeah I think I mean our our
pre-orders are insane so like once it
goes it's it's gone and and then um
we'll you know we'll be doing this uh
Hood candies testing and if Hood candies
makes it great we'll see that you know
in the in Winter and or end of fall
maybe winter of this year if it makes it
if it doesn't you know we'll see you
next year with something we're not we're
definitely not a company that's known
for like putting up putting out drops
back to back to back we don't do it
um
yeah you can count my drops on your hand
I believe yeah hey that's that's good to
hear I think that's most of what I
wanted to touch on was there anything we
haven't touched on that you wanted to do
uh no no I think I think uh I think we
we touch bases I mean we talked about
the Mind flare drop Discord Frenchies
passion fruit
we learned a lot we learned a lot I I
don't need to pop over to your uh your
Discord and do uh and do a gnarly
giveaway man uh look I would I'd be very
grateful I think that everyone have you
sent me uh have you sent me an invite to
your to your Discord yet no I'll do it
now look I'll be honest I'm actually a
little late to the party with Discord
and I'm still figuring all the ins and
outs of it but I'll send you one right
now okay
yeah send me one and uh I'll come in
there and I can uh I can try to give you
any little tips and pointers I know I'm
not the best at it I mean the best thing
you can do is have a have a kid have a
kid that knows what he's doing because
my son yeah he's great at it oh yeah
look I bet he's he's The Mastermind he's
the da Vinci of Discord he really is I
mean that's that's these kids these days
right so I I was uh I was blessed in
that aspect to have him as a as a
moderator there quickly you can repair
things and change things and make things
do you have a do you have a giveaway bot
set up yet no God you can get a bot for
that
yeah oh yeah dude that's how we do all
of our giveaways it's like it takes it
it totally does the randomness
randomization of it
um 100 so it's all automated wow it's
awesome it's awesome I'm gonna go down a
deep dive after we get off the phone
based on the sounds of this
oh yeah man there's so many different
Bots that you can use for so many
different things
um in Discord it's just what makes it
great you know ticket system like you
gotta have that
so that's one of the coolest things
about our Discord is that if you have a
problem if you have a customer service
problem you have
issue with what's going on in Discord
anything anything you want to talk to
staff about you just open up a ticket
say what it is it gives us a ticket
number and one of our staff members will
pop in there and and solve the problem
for you I mean that's just how it goes
so yeah I love it
yeah cool look I'm I'm keen and I'd love
to have you swing by our listeners would
be very grateful to get their hands on
any of your work and look I'm sure
they're already in your Discord as well
so the big overlap I'm sure
yeah yeah no yeah it'd be cool I'll pop
over there right when just send me the
invite when we get off this and I'll
I'll pop over there amazing well I think
with that being said that just about
brings us to the end of it for today
were there any shout outs or general
comments you'd like to make
uh no I think that I think that that
covers it man I I appreciate you having
me on the show I can't believe it's
already been a year since the last time
that I was here but uh I always uh I
always appreciate the the opportunity to
come on come on here and you know big
shout out to seats here now
um for always always being there they're
the first bank that ever picked up uh
old soulfire when we when we first
started so
um big shout out to them for that yeah
hugely the original sponsors of our show
and have been supporting us all these
years so huge shout out to seeds here
now but likewise a huge shout out to you
so far for coming on the show for giving
us some amazing genetics and for sharing
some of your knowledge and history with
us as always very appreciative
anytime anytime
thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
and there you have it gang a huge shout
out to Seoul of soulfire series for
coming on by sharing the knowledge some
info about the upcoming mind players
series as well as some info about the
future drops you can look forward to
including the wood candies which sounds
really promising to me
but I tell you what else sounds
promising
supporting our sponsors you support them
they support us
you keep getting episodes how good does
that sound go check out seats here now
for all the latest and greatest drops if
you're looking for Autoflower feminized
regular whatever you're after they got
it see it here now I guarantee on
satisfaction not just germination please
check him out James being as you heard
from the man himself solved simply a
gentleman Beyond others supporting both
ass and soulfire from day one please
check out CTN now however you're based
in the UK or the EU check out our good
buddies at simply souvenirs they have a
great range of breeders including Soul
fire but they've got a range of other
breeders too
as well as some lesser known Boutique
breeders who they think you should keep
your eye on check them out guys simply
souvenirs or on Instagram simply
souvenirs F2 they are lovely people
thank you so much for the support
likewise coppet biological systems these
guys have been fans of the show for a
long time and have helped us to make the
episodes please consider supporting them
they have some of the best predators in
the game keeping your garden Pest and
pathogen free if you've got aphids check
out the active car around if you've got
spider mites check out the spidex buy
tool I really don't need to say anymore
Guys these guys are industry standard
world renowned best in the game check
them out coppet biological systems thank
you so much for your support we
appreciate it
and last but not least the patreon gang
a huge shout out guys you know we love
you we could not make it happen without
you please check out the patreon if you
would like to help support the show to
ensure that future episodes happen all
the while you'll get early access to
newcoming episodes unheard exclusives to
the patreon only specials as well as a
range of giveaways we're doing monthly
genetic giveaways now check it out guys
some hot seeds from hot breeders get
them into your hot hands
and with that I think we're just about
done my friends thank you so much for
making it to the end with me as usual
your boy heavy day signing off from the
upside down Library
I'll see you