on behalf of the group and myself about
to say thank you for the audition thank
you and I hope we pass the audition
that's our present on behalf of the
after the group in myself I'd like to
say thank you and I hope we pass the
audition hello welcome to the next
episode of the podcast this episode was
brought to you by the Brothers Grimm 420
Australia and I knew a sponsors
organic gardening solutions and the
village shop on this episode we feature
mr. Sol of the Brothers Grimm this
episode is fairly laid-back and you'll
probably hear it
enjoy alrighty so big thank you and
welcome to mr. self coming on the show
thank you very good to be here so we're
just in the Brothers Grimm facility
right now in Colorado and if you can
hear any fans it's just the fans keeping
the plants happy behind us so if you
hear any fans they're fans we hope you
are as well so the first question I'd
like to ask everyone is let's go back to
the start the first time you ever smoked
weed what was it like that's a good
story actually I was at my uncle's well
I should say where my uncle lived with
my grandparents and I have an uncle who
my father being the oldest in the family
has a has a brother who's only five
years older than myself and so I always
admired him you know is the cool uncle
that being that bit older than myself
when I would visit my grandparents house
he would always have interesting things
in the drawers and all around in his
room and I'd always go in and explore
one day I found what was a 1/2 ounce of
Acapulco gold in his drawer and I picked
that up and he happened to be in the
room as I did it and
I said wow what is this easily I said is
this real marijuana and he's like yeah
that's Acapulco gold it's some of the
best in the world and I said he said
have you already smoked marijuana I said
my friends and I have been trying you
know then out in the woods and trying to
find like if there's any wild marijuana
growing then you know we tried to dry it
out and smoke it and I don't know how
crazy that is if everyone's had that but
growing up in the 70s you know I guess
mm-hmm we didn't have access to
information like you do today realize
our folly so at that moment I was then
taken away from all of that silliness
and my uncle rolled a real joint and
took me out in the backyard where he had
this a good old van that was a abandoned
back there we sat in the front seat and
smoked a joint when I went into a dream
as the Beatles said and everything you
know from the moment someone spoke you
know it was like this spell had been
cast where I'm guessing I'm gonna wake
up later and this didn't really happen
you know I was just dreaming at all you
know that was hmm
I just felt a an affinity to and a great
liking of that experience and sought it
out you know in years after hmm didn't
come as frequently as you know someone
might today where they say hey I really
like marijuana I'm gonna start smoking
it all the time and the availability is
there mm-hmm
it was more of over the next year or two
I'd have a few experiences where working
in a nightclub as a busboy or a waiter
or something and those circles there
were people who were dealing pounds of
marijuana and you know I was just 17 or
18 in high school and I could remember
them sort of implying what they were
doing and saying do you want some and
they gave me like a matchbox full of
this great weed and I remember enjoying
that to myself you know and having a
couple of joints of that you know and
then from there I started to you know
obviously meet people and have friends
in the school that were
into this culture and we started having
the availability of marijuana much more
frequently and it got better and better
at a rapid rate I was in high school I
was in tenth grade in 1975 and you would
buy an ounce of weed for $40 it was you
know $10 per quarter basically at that
time and then all of a sudden you know
like five or ten years later you know
all those prices sort of tripled and
went crazy and it was like three and
four hundred and five hundred dollars
for an ounce in the 90s and now things
have calmed back down from there
such but I know I'm going tangential on
you so yeah that was my first experience
getting high and experiencing what
marijuana was and I I've never had
another drug I liked LSD very much
obviously I don't know why that's
obvious sorry I take that back but I
have commented many times that my
photography is influenced by LSD and
comic books so that that could be out
there you know people know that yeah
anyway I definitely think it shows so
those two drugs if you will have always
been something that I felt we're very
natural and my body had an affinity to I
never liked barbiturates and speed and
these kinds of drugs they always felt
like an artificial thing whereas those
other other two that I mentioned are
either natural or synthesis synthetic
version of something that is natural
like suicide them and so yeah I guess
yeah what feels good for my body this is
what I go for rather than you know I
don't like to beat myself up with
alcohol and drink all night like some
people and not that anything's wrong
with that lifestyle if they liked it but
it's not for me because I was a sporty I
rode bicycles most of my life and and
did that sort of thing motocross bicycle
racing I appreciated being able to get
on the bike the next morning and not
feel like [ __ ] and be able to actually
go out there and punish the other guys
you know it's a big testosterone thing
you know
when you're all out on your bicycles and
racing each other to the town line or
who can get to the hill at the top
fastest and such so how long did it take
before you transition from just
enthusiasts to your home grow up I
always felt like oh groaning it would be
so difficult and I was a child of about
a ten and I remember planting some
pumpkin seeds and that they didn't come
up and I felt like oh growing the plants
very hard you know I had that mindset
for some reason but then mmm so
consequently never really tried all
through high school you know and I
didn't even understand the concept of
like photo size photo periods and
triggering the flowering response in the
plant in fact when I was in college at
the age of about 21 I did discover that
having picked up a book marijuana
horticulture by Jorge Cervantes and I
took that hmm read it you know like
cover to cover in a day and I was just
fascinated by the whole idea that so
that's how it works you mean you can
keep them from flowering and you can
make them flower just by changing the
amount of daylight that they receive I
mean that was just phenomenal for me to
just that concept was like so simple and
elegant and beautiful all at once and
gave me such power and you know control
over what I could do in my mind just
start my imagination started to go like
wow that means you know X Y Z and I went
from there and it was a pretty short
time within a year I had done some
closet grows and outdoor grows and near
the college had lots of questions
started finding that you know you could
order seeds online got super sativa seed
club going and ordered one or two of
their packs of seeds and in those days
you know you just send a letter back and
forth if you had questions there was no
email that was a 84 probably 286
somewhere in that period and when we
first started connecting and through
those even those mails the company's
owner guy named
que es wrote back to me
saying you know you asked some very
interesting questions you seem to be an
intelligent guy you seem to understand
what you're doing and we need people
like yourself over in the United States
to help us would you be willing to work
with us not knowing exactly what that
meant it was a little dig I said sure
let me know what you have in mind you
know here's my phone number and he
called me after got after he got that
letter mm-hmm
told me what it was is that they would
send me bulk quantities of each of the
strains of their seeds my job would be
to receive letters from them with the
addresses and quantities of each of the
seeds that are to be sent to each of
those addresses and I'd be their courier
you know inside the United States
domestic forwarding yeah distribute
their seeds to the individuals who had
purchased them from them they paid them
and they're then paying me in envelopes
of hundred-dollar bills that would come
weekly as well with the orders and they
would you know pay more for a larger
order you know for the processing of the
larger and a smaller order you don't
need to know all the details but anyway
that was my job for them for four years
basically while I went through the last
year of graduate school been working
probably the first two years of my job
out of college then I met a woman who
insisted that I give up all the
marijuana stuff so if we just backtrack
a little bit while you were growing out
the SSC stock what was your favorite of
all of this dr. grad because we've heard
from skunk PA he mentioned that the
beatrix choice was one of his favorites
that doesn't often get a mention I never
grew it I would probably agree I you
know I always sort of drooled over when
I saw the pictures that they posted of
it in their brochures and so on but I
never did for any I don't know what
reason I guess there were other things I
wanted to try first and never got around
to Patrick's choice but that and what's
that Williams wonder also is one I never
grew but for me the Derbent I was the
thing that I thought was like wow that
was the most impressive and most
personally pleasing to me and I crushed
it with spunk number one one
and then grew it outdoors seedlings not
not a female that I had picked out of a
group that I had already flowered
indoors and chosen like I would do today
but at that time I just said let me put
out like 30 50 seeds in this field that
I had chosen that I thought was secure
enough and safe enough and hidden enough
but still got a lot of sunlight mmm went
out there hacked up the field and got
poison ivy all over myself later I found
out that I'd gotten that and I would
happen to be going Amsterdam for a week
for a vacation right at that same time
just made it to a doctor in time before
leaving she gave me some steroids and it
cleared it up in like three days
but anyway back to the story I dug
although you know ground up and planted
all these seeds and they came up I went
out like you know two months later
called the male's and then two months
later I had all these big beautiful
finished purplish bugs and very sticky
impressive females that were ready like
at the end of October you know
relatively early for the cross so when I
reported back to cash that I had made
that cross it was like that's amazing
like we don't usually get that result we
really have a hard time getting them to
flower fast enough to finish outdoors in
a climate like Connecticut he said
that's you should hold on to those and I
didn't have any more or whatever and
then having met the woman who I
eventually married that she made me give
it all up and I had to send the seeds
all back to s s SC back in Amsterdam and
didn't keep the cash of them for myself
other than a couple odd packs that were
discovered by my wife and thrown out so
I had to start all over after our
divorce say take us to the day when you
went to sensi small and found those
seeds was that during one of those
answered in troops you just mentioned
nope what it was then was I had been in
Belgium having gotten divorced from my
first wife and spent two years in
Belgium I worked on contracts there as a
nuclear engineer for attractive L
company it's a civil engineering group
that does all of the
that type of work for the country that's
a national establishment whatever so
while I was there I had met a Belgian
girl we started living together and then
as my contract came to an end after two
years she proposed that if you're going
back to America because you have no work
permit here and can't continue to get a
job we could be married and you'd be
able to do that either stay here or go
back to America and I said okay hmm we
got married and I looked for work in
Europe I like Europe I would like to
have stayed but I did have that conflict
of being a divorced dad and my children
were like three and six years old or
something too perhaps even a little bit
less like two and five and that was you
know pulling at my heartstrings and so
in the end I didn't find suitable work
there I speak French now very well at
that time it was a little bit
rudimentary you know so I think that
probably in my interviews they felt like
as French isn't really strong enough you
might not be able to you know keep up
and and what for whatever reason it
didn't work so in the end the things
that always seem to have happened in my
life fall in place well and a
disappointment in one place it's always
like one door shutting while another
opens we had an opportunity to go to
Boston and we did that and then before
leaving I knew that when I got there I
would want to be able to grow my own
having gotten used to being able to get
on a train and go up to Amsterdam or
even just over the border in Breda I
often go there just to save myself the
trip of going all the way up to
Amsterdam but point being I would always
have available smoke and of very high
quality I wouldn't necessarily be able
to do that moving to bus and I had no
idea what the availability of good weed
would be and my Belgian wife was
something of a little bit you know
reclusive introverted type and so a
really appealed to her as well that oh
great you know you won't have to go out
on the street for your weed and I know
you'll be home all the time taking care
of your plants and so on what a great
hobby for my husband you know it's such
so she was a very supportive wife and
after about two years living in Boston I
was doing the cannabis cultivation
full-time in supporting myself sending
child support back to my ex-wife and
everything all from proceeds that I made
in the basement of that home you know
and that felt great doing that but at
the same time was very stressful in the
sense that if it had ever blown up but
those at the time you know late 90s you
could do 20 25 years for cultivation in
Boston and my wife would have had a
field day you know didn't alert the
media
you know my husband is a complete
scandal look at this man you know
raising our children and having them
every other weekend in this den of
inequity you know so there was that
aspect of it it was stressful and I
think I said to you once before that I
was also day-trading as most people were
during like 99 and just stuff leading up
into 2000 I turned a $5,000 starting
point with into about 55,000 and a year
and then lost about 25 of it as things
started to come down in March of 2000
and then I just decided don't let any
more go and save that we sold the house
right a little bit after 9/11 maybe
three four months later mmm and having
done that we had some cash in our
pockets and I had closed up everything
from what I was doing with the Brothers
Grimm operation in my basement and we
moved back to Belgium with fair chunk of
money in our pockets
and I thought I'd sit on my hands for a
little while and then maybe look for a
place in Belgium where I'd have
greenhouse facilities indoor facilities
and such and restart up the company yeah
you may remember chip to Nirvana from
what was that company London direct the
seeds direct UK I believe it was
whatever anyway a little dodgy kind of a
dodgy character you know that's his
reputation and I found it to be a little
bit so as well when I met him we spent a
day hanging out maybe the weekend we may
have seen each other the next day -
drove around a little bit visited some
people Shanti Baba was one of them
mmm-hmm what was that woman's the woman
who does the hash in Amsterdam
I always her name Mila Mila yeah and she
made the machine yeah yeah yeah the ice
I know the isolator is her invention
she's touted to be the inventor of that
anyway met her lovely time there where
was I
incident yeah why was I there yeah so I
I had come back as I say from Boston and
I was trying to establish something
that's why I was up there talking to
folks like Mila and gypsy Nirvana but
nothing seemed to click they never felt
comfortable that I'd be able to like get
the whole thing started again there and
again went to sitting on my hands mode
and enjoyed Belgium and played guitar
for four hours a day and rode a bicycle
two hours a day or was four hours a day
or whatever rode with the bicycle clubs
on the weekends and so on and just
really had a great time you know I
firmed up my glenwood skills very much
so in that time you know people just
assumed I spoke French and spoke French
full you know all the time so it was
pretty cool great experience for me and
then I came back to the United States at
a certain moment after two years in
Belgium because of the children I said
you know the kids are crying on the
phone you know daddy's basically
abandoned them and decided to go off and
live his selfish life in Europe you know
satisfying his dreams [ __ ] us and I
you know I just felt maybe they weren't
saying that you know obviously but felt
that way and I just felt very guilty and
I had been in this marriage more as
convenience as you know we were in love
in a certain sense but there was also a
limitation to that where when push came
to shove we were at a fork in our
existence where she couldn't return to
America because her parents were older
and failing and needed her my children
were young and developing and needing me
and so we had to sort of degree that I'm
going back to America you've got to stay
here we'll see what happens
we stayed married on paper for the next
seven years and then finally decided
well let's put it on paper that were
not married anymore still great friends
and will send each other birthday cards
and hello at Christmas and email and
what have you so that ended in an
amicable way and then during about the
next seven years in America I worked as
everything from sale selling home
improvements kitchen improve kitchen
remodeling bathroom remodeling got to be
very good visiting people's homes and
just doing little demos you know I love
to be since I was a little kid I've
always been the show-and-tell guy my
wife will always say to you people to
Rick he's like the show-and-tell guy you
know he'll want to trot out his latest
whatever it is you know having gathered
everyone in the living room you know
like and so that was how I was as a kid
and so when I went into sales I just
really enjoyed that whole razzle-dazzle
of you know getting the person
interested in having their kitchen done
and getting them excited about doing
closing the deal that was the way that
thing worked was you had to be in and
out of their home in three hours turn
and either they bought then or they
never would it was the one one call
close they called it got to be pretty
good at that they made me a manager and
put me in charge of you know the sales
team and so for about four or five years
I did that and then I was called back to
engineer and fellow called me up and
said I found your resume on monster.com
you're a nuclear engineer blah blah blah
we are here in Boston and we really need
a guy like you all right I'll come in an
interview got the job started working
for Arriva it's a French company mmm
finished with them after four years and
moved to New York City married a woman
that I knew from high school having
reconnected through Facebook and after
four years of living in New York City
with her working as eventually
professional photographer as a sideline
job I did also work as a nuclear
engineer but in sales for a company
called high torque and after four years
with them my job was basically phased
out they were changing their strategy on
how they do
their sales and such and it wasn't
working for me and them anymore but it
was again a door closing that seemed
like a disappointing moment at the time
and then a couple of months later I'm
finding myself being swept back into
cannabis cultivation and seed production
and reopening Brothers Grimm and being
very excited at the realization that you
know after all of Lading these years on
the sidelines and cheering along the
legalization that was happening in
various states finally the two-by-four
slapped me on the side of the head and
said hey by the way you know if you were
to move to one of those states you may
well to restart your business and do
what you really love to do as you're
living and so having started to you know
scratch the surface of reaching out to
my old partners and friends and of
course lie to this day has never
resurfaced I don't know what ever
happened to him hmm our working
relationship was always pristine and we
got along famously left everything on
good terms but he's either lost interest
in this business or been killed or is in
prison or who knows you know what
happens to people but anyway the
opportunity was to partner up with
someone who could be that other side of
Brothers Grimm Duke diamond and you know
I was connected to him through
sub-cooled and I took the chance on
coming out and meeting and found that he
was beyond my expectations
excellent mate for me to do this
business and we slowly put it together
from the very early beginnings of
starting seeds that would be used to
find the right males to cross to the
clones of genius and princess that I had
recovered from the people who had been
holding them and you can imagine you
know wanting to have rooms full of
plants and making seeds you know great
guns and looking at this little 4x4 area
you know lit by one lamp and like that's
everything my pockets are empty I have
everything right there in this little
4x4 area and that's got to throw and
cross
or and multiply and become everything
though you know here we are a year later
and it's a full-blown you know seed
growing operation with we're in the
black and operating you know and with a
future yeah and always planning to ramp
things up from where we are and it's
growing at a great rate that it doesn't
seem inordinately fast or slow yeah
organic just likely grow our plans so
while you were a nuclear engineer among
other things how did you feel about
having this secret the whole time did
you feel like you were the anomaly or
did you think that maybe there's another
a nuclear engineer who's you know a mr.
soll by nine that's a great question now
there's two answers to it really I think
I through that whole time felt like yeah
this is a secret not only from employers
but I also felt in dating you know that
was always sort of the delicate at that
time maybe it isn't so much today I'm
now 57 years old so imagine when I'm 30
or you know 25 and yeah I have that
education yeah I'm in that profession
and when I'm out needing lemon or
something dropping that I also happen to
enjoy smoking cannabis you know in my
free time on weekends and evenings I'm
almost a daily smoker it could chase
away potentially interesting women and I
guess I should have realized that yeah
you know the right girls are gonna
accept me for that and the hell with the
ones who don't you know but that was my
mindset at the time and then with the
employer it was also like jeez I can't
let my hair down and let them know that
would be something that maybe I'm
getting away with the fact that I'm
working for an employer who won't
randomly drug test me and I know I'm
safe there's no sense you know raising
you know an alarm to myself or calling
any attention to it so I had to keep
that quiet so yeah there's that and to
cap off that side of it I think that I
love this new expression I've come up
with where
the letters are the same number of
letters and everything fits in place you
know pops is the new gay we're the ones
coming out of the closet now you know so
I think that would make a great slogan
and this so I do that segues until your
other had the other half of your
question feel that there are so many
people yeah who were in the closet
didn't reveal as I didn't that they were
cannabis aficionados in the closet you
know and that's all coming out and there
are statistics right now that I just
read the other day that the fastest
growing cannabis consumption age group
is something like you know the baby
boomers you know or just my I'm a little
B little bit younger than baby boomer
age so they're saying like people of
fifty to sixty or something like that
seventy-five that's the biggest most
burgeoning group of pot smokers because
they're all coming out of the closet and
saying hey [ __ ] it man I've always
wanted a I've always enjoyed this I have
a lawyer who was a great friend of mine
who lives in Chicago who only revealed
to me like during this past year when he
found out what I did and I was being
open about it I had come out he reached
out to me and said oh my god you know
I've been a path smoker since the 60s I
loved really the good stuff I can see
from your pictures that you're posting
and so that you're amazing I didn't know
about your whole history you know that
we've been friends you know on and off
over the years but we lost touch for a
really long time and he's like so you're
mister soul it's amazing you know said
and in the end you know I send him some
samples and he smokes and when he's like
I can't use writing back to me I cannot
believe this amazing you make better
marijuana than I've ever smoked in my
life you know like oh you know the whole
thing like we are so it's wonderful to
have that sort of openness now I do feel
like you know coming it's like a
coming-out and
and it's a great feeling especially
being open about the company and I'm
proud of everything I've ever done with
Brothers Grimm and to have not done what
I just recently did oaktree open the
company and pull this back to the Future
thing I would have always felt like you
have to understand we'd go to cocktail
parties or be at friends homes and this
story would be trotted out by my wife or
some friend you know you know that you
know wreck Harry
famous in the cannabis world he used to
be this world famous breeder he created
the strain Cinderella 99 and you know
that's really alien but you know it was
making me feel like a has-been
I don't want to hear these stories and
I'm not doing it anymore it's like oh
yeah you know don't trot that old story
come on you know it's like I talked
about what I do now you know and I'm a
photographic artist I'm having
exhibitions in New York City and to do
that you know forget the pot thing but
then there was this excellent segue
between that last job and before I came
out here to Colorado which was that a
friend of my wife's having heard that
old story you know about me and he was
on vacation talking to a fellow who she
had met two couples you know on the
beach night let's have dinner or drinks
or whatever later on they started
talking about their lives the guy says I
work as the operations manager for tweed
she says what's tweet-tweet is a company
in Canada that is the sole producer of
all the medical marijuana that is
consumed in the entire country they are
the one official source that the
government says is at least that's what
I believe the arrangement is so he hears
through her little story about mr. Stoll
and who I am and she's friends with my
wife and he says I'd love to interview
the guy you know we would probably want
to employ him she says really I'll find
out if he's ok with you calling him so
she did and I said ok he calls me we
have a conversation he says we're gonna
get you tickets and fly you up here I
flew up I spent a day touring the
facility talking to the master grower
all of the other you know people yeah
yeah they have a master grower there in
the interview went really well everybody
liked each other and I felt like you
know the guy wants me and he told me he
wanted me for the job they were
considering some other people a woman
included who had come from an entirely
different background they were looking
for an operation of cultivation manager
that would be the boss of this fellow
who would be the master grower and he
told me about a month later that okay
management made a decision to go with
somebody who was more immediately
available even if they didn't have the
cannabis specific experience due to the
fact that our lawyers are saying it'd
take us a lot of time to immigrate you
into Canada and blah blah blah we
haven't even made you an offer you may
very well say you don't want to move to
Canada and I said yeah you know you're
doing the right thing it's cool I see
what's happening here he said but we are
really interested in another side idea
which would be to license the Brothers
Grimm name on products like if we were
to produce Cinderella 99 and we could
say that you know it's bonafide and
licensed by Brothers Grimm and I thought
that's brilliant sure let's talk about
that whenever you're comfortable he let
that sit on the back burner way too long
and after like four months went by and
then in touch once a month or so and
yeah yeah well right now we can't and
there are you know these nuts is okay
look I'm gonna have to let that whole
thing go I wrote him an email and said
look that's not gonna move forward I
feel and I am gonna relocate to Colorado
I'm gonna reopen the company Brothers
Grimm and I will not probably be
interested in that right away but down
the road we could talk about it what
have you but the seed that that put in
my mind of you know this was a
possibility I could return to being mr.
soll and running Brothers Grimm again
and just based on having been
interviewed by them and the little
lightbulb went on in my head and as the
one door was closing with the job with
high torque as an engineer there I saw
that well I either dig deep and try to
continue being a photographer in New
York City and
potential is not that great photography
and photographers are starting to go
into a very it's also ubiquitous just
like music you know pay for like $15
albums anymore you download music for
next to nothing same things happening
with images and photography and so many
people are taking so many wonderful
pictures with the technology that's
available and the information that's
available to become a better
photographer so much faster imagine if
you are learning photography now you're
able to immediately see the results of
every picture you take that's a huge
biofeedback mechanism that was absent in
the days of film when I was learning
photography in the 80s and I had to wait
until I went to a drug store and dropped
off a roll of film and got it several
days later to figure out what I did
wrong a week ago it's akin to you're a
musician if you had been forced to learn
how to play guitar by having ear plugs
in your ears and recording your lessons
while you played by sight and then later
had to listen back to them but not right
away that was only after you brought the
tape down and had it processed and got
it back a week later and then you could
figure out what the you're doing right
now that lack of immediate biofeedback
would slow down the learning process and
extend advice is such a great amount of
time that's what was happening to us as
you know burgeoning photographers of
those days now I've seen guys where
they've had two years experienced as a
photographer and they're taking
professional level amazing pictures
because they paid attention and tried to
educate themself with all of the
available videos on YouTube and
information from other sources that they
can just immediately learn how to create
a great image and kind of master the
technology of their own camera and light
and everything else so price of that is
all going down wow I went a long way off
on a tangent to explain why I didn't
decide to stay in New York and stay a
photographer well have you ever
considered like moving your passion over
to
photography yeah yeah yeah I mean that's
happening actually you know there was an
immediate need for me to be able to take
pictures and transmit what we're doing
visually on Instagram and other medium
you know social media and old and I
thought is a comment from you and not
Duke well no don't
he's amazing do you know most of his
pictures have been done with his cell
phone until very recently and I just
think you know I showed him like here
here's where the sliders are on
Instagram one day and then I never said
another word to him and immediately
started doing like really great pictures
and moving the you know controls around
but yeah I would never it's not a
competition mate this is how I look at
everything in life it's like we're all
colleagues and we're all unique and
we're all trying to do our own thing I
don't want to make comparison so you
know who Jack Kerouac is the writer at
American writer did on the road in his
book the car doctor Dharma bums there's
one character who says comparisons are
odious yeah that's true you know like
we're all doing our own thing so
everybody's got their own scene it's not
a competition they know so again with
the photography it did it did a parlay
right into an immediate it became an
immediate benefit to me to be able to do
that I looked at my Instagram feed today
and thought to myself yeah you know it
just dawns on me that's good that I've
been able to produce good images of what
we're doing and make nice artistic
sometimes and sometimes just very you
know this is what it is just so you can
see the reality of what it is so yeah I
have been able to play around with my
style of photography and adapting that
to taking pictures of cannabis rather
than
you know architecture and cityscapes
which is what I used to do so if we
title back in mm-hm I guess my question
would be if you knew that things would
go the way they have would you have
considered coming back sooner Oh totally
but remember even two years ago Colorado
had just started to have legalization
and I don't know if any other states
were quite so accessible in terms would
be a good enough place to live in terms
of creature comforts and where I would
want to be and also have the ability to
grow with basically you know an impunity
that I had never experienced before and
that could feel comfortable doing it
openly as we are so yeah I mean if all
the conditions had been right I would
have done it or earlier I had gotten a
mindset over the years that yeah you
know I don't think the numbers work and
so on but as I started to explore it and
legalization had been running for some
time then I did see that
oh okay other people are showing me how
this would work as a seed company and it
could be profitable whereas I had never
really considered the seed money being
enough to live on as it wasn't back in
the day when I was in doing this in my
basement in Boston the most of the money
I made was through a contact I had in
southern Massachusetts who would take
pounds of high-grade weed from me and I
was breeding for you know growing good
sinsemilla to send to this guy and make
my rent every month and pay the bills
whereas the seed money was an occasional
pop that came from Canada that was like
oh that's nice to have that extra a few
thousand dollars or whatever it happened
to be might have been as much as fifteen
at a time or so but I didn't think that
there was a way to make a living but as
I say you know it was shown to me no no
it works so yeah here we are and like I
said we were able to pay the bills every
month and
what we love so pretty happy with the
way things are going so when we think
back to the initial incarnation a lot of
growers and breeders alike think of it
as this golden area you know you had the
original Brothers Grimm people like
Tommy Hill and big high releasing
strains did you ever realize that you're
a part of a age that would be looked
back on with you know this kind of
reminiscent envy or did it just feel
like same old same old at the time this
is again you know with the experience of
my age and so on I've come across things
where I can answer that pretty simply
because everybody who's ever gone
through this can can relate to there's a
quote by I can't remember exactly who to
attribute it to but he said one never
knows when one is making history so it's
like while you're making history you're
just doing it you're not thinking you're
making history and then you look back
and you realize how I made history so
there's your answer I guess it's
universal it's not you yet it to me but
it fits I feel that that's a good
response for myself as well as being
sort of universal responsible awesome
so one of those things I always noticed
in also you know really kind of praised
the original release of Cindy was was
that when you did the original Cindy
there wasn't really many cubing projects
going on and I always wondered where did
you get the idea to do a cube it's it's
even today not many people think of it
as a breeding project a lot of nibbler
to F Long's yeah how did you find out
about what would be regarded as a fairly
advanced breeding idea nobody I know at
that time were had ever heard of or I
don't think anybody has ever claimed to
be have been doing a breeding project
that involved cubing or was cubing
anything at that time I think I was the
first person to actually actively take
that idea and run with it he just felt
that I read an article once in a High
Times Magazine that alluded to that
process and it seemed like nobody ever
talked about it or no one ever really
noticed it but it piqued my interest and
I said huh it may sound simplistic but
each time a male and female mate the
children get 50% of the mother and
father and and humans and mammals and
that live on a timeline that's
continuous whereas cannabis can be
brought back in time and forward in time
if you will by taking a clone from a
female plant that's being kept in a
vegetative state it's as though time is
being made to stand still there and then
you can take cuttings from that female
and do any kind of breeding and growing
with them that you like and then the
offspring of say a male of that
generation being bred back to the
original female if you think about it
it's already got 50% of that of his
mother's genes so if we take a boy from
the first generation he's already half
p-princess let's say from the cubing
process I did to make Cinderella 99 and
she's contributing again half of her pea
to the mix that becomes the the children
of that cross so having half of her
already he can contribute only 25% so
there he's contributed 25% she always
contributes 50% so each time you're
hitting 25% plus the 50% that
generations going to have 75% so then
half of 75% is like 37.5 so you get
round it you get a P 88 generation and
then if you do the P 88 generation
you're adding 44 and 50 so now you're at
94% P if you will sounds simplistic
there's probably some flaws to the whole
process right hmm however if you're
careful about the male selection each
time it's almost like you're doing a
little bit of guidance like f2 to f3 f4
and such when you're guiding those
generations you're also choosing which
plants to mate each generation so I had
in each generation of P 88 p94 in such
the males that would resemble princess
was my simplistic way of looking at okay
the more it resembles the female the
more this one is carrying that trait and
each time it did seem to make
improvements and bring the plant more
toward the princess however I did want
to choose four more larger branches
bigger colas sweeter flavors more
pleasing high rather than the
devastating knocked you down kind of
high from the original princess you've
been smoking a little bit of a bit
lately
yeah so when you started the cubing
process we know now that you use the
shiva skunk as the original email why
did you choose that and were you
considering any others no I
mmm I had two choices in my mind I could
choose a very similar plant and use a
brother and then more likelihood that
some family genes are already in the
male side and you wouldn't have to back
cross this far but then it would meet
Lee leave me a little more confused as
to how to choose where I'm getting away
from the male side the original male
side and getting more and more toward
just the princess qualities so I felt
the other option was to go with
something that was so obviously
different that every generation I'd be
able to sort of culluh way the
skunky side of it and go more toward the
princess phenotypes and see that the
females in each generation we're also
producing better and better quality with
the sweeter flavors the larger coal is
the larger branches and more structure
than princess had so princess turns out
to be more valuable plant as a breeding
female than she would be in terms of
just growing that for people consumers
to want to buy that bud so some people
would argue that genius is almost as
valuable as a plant as princess in terms
of the strains that they've gone to
create so if you ever considered doing a
similar cubing project with genius I
didn't have time I ran out of time back
in the day and now I can do so I might
there's your answer I mean it's likely
you know I think that having done the
green Avenger we really got sort of a
plant that was so much beefier and more
compact and easier to grow and he still
had the flavor and the mind the the
psychoactivity of genius so right right
there with green Avenger we sort of hit
on a nice what would be a seed form of
genius but with many improvements but if
you were to try to go and get somebody
the genius in seed form thing I kind of
questioned the value of it you know I
don't know I want to I think we've
improved it yeah yeah so who died that
valuable as a breeding female yeah
so have you got any rough ideas as to
what might have been the mail which
pollinated the jack arrow which to end
up creating the princess genius
I would like to say from everything that
I've seen now in the past year or so of
observing more plants of different
varieties that are available for me to
observe than I ever had before I've now
got a much better handle on where before
I said look it's whatever I don't know
like really I wouldn't like to even
throw out a guess because it's just
meaningless to guess isn't it you know
so today
having seen the structure of Jack Herer
sorry having seen the structure of a
Durbin pure Durbin and knowing that
super sativa seed club and sensi you
know they all worked with some Durbin
and it's likely they may have had some
Durbin pollen floating around in just a
few you know that like I said that bud
that I broke open and since he smile
which I have to return to that story by
the way was mostly but I mean it really
didn't have more than six seeds in it
and I mean it was a reasonable size bag
that you get from an Amsterdam coffee
shop and the reason I was there just to
finish that story was before leaving and
knowing that I would want to grow weed
in America when we got to Boston we went
to Amsterdam specifically to go buy a
bunch of seeds and I went in the sensi
shop right next to the right nearby the
hash Museum on that little canal there
and I bought a few packs of seeds and
one of them being the especially the
skunk yeah and a couple of others mm-hmm
and lo and behold after having bought
the seeds you know we want to get a cup
of coffee and go smoke the joint or
something that's how I ended up in the
sense he smiled just to finish the recap
that little missing did that did you
ever after having popped the seeds get
the urge to go back to senses
and try to now that was just such a
chance thing that you know find a
hundred dollar bill you know in a
parking lot you don't go back there
everyday walking the parking lot looking
for dollar bills but it was really was
just an off thing that hey great but I
did coincidentally I don't think I've
ever told anybody this story but when I
came back a few days after having gone
on that little sojourn and bought the
seeds I thought well the ones that came
out of that but just for the hell of it
I'll try to germinate a couple and grow
and see what they looked like before we
leave we had another week or so or a
month before we were going to leave
we had a balcony and a little you know
space there I could set a pot out and
two or three of those seeds popped up
and grew and I ended up having to call
them just before leaving and just like
you know yeah they seemed to be healthy
and they grew well who knows what they
could have been you know I don't know
well every good story has to have that
low moment you know for us to crawl out
of them become champions at the end okay
so that wasn't such a low moment at all
because I still did have you know four
to six seeds left that I brought to
America and when I ended up German
everything from the packets as well as
those freebie seeds that rolled out of
my weed in this coffee shop they turned
out to have been the stars you know
weirdly enough and you know I don't
recommend to people as you know today to
buy seeds that have a lot of variety and
you know be on Fino hunts you know
you're causing yourself a lot of
unnecessary work I feel that one should
just simply ask a few questions to
himself like what did what is it that I
would like in terms of what type of
plant if I were to have to write down
all the characteristics of what I'd like
might vary from person to person
wouldn't you agree but there is such a
strain out there are likely to line up
with what every what someone's wish list
would contain and wouldn't it be logical
to just buy a pack of those seeds and
grow them and have an get to the finish
line do you really want to buy you know
something that is a poly hybrid with
another poly hybrid saying oh boy those
are both great things well you
chicken cordon bleu and asparagus is a
lovely meal but I don't want to mix it
with a hot fudge sundae at the same time
they're both lovely things but putting
them together doesn't necessarily make a
great thing and many people who are
neophytes to this craft or this passion
or you know want to grow marijuana I
think they get caught up in the lore as
many beginners in any field do there's
an old saying a beginner never under
does anything you know that usually
you'll find that their errors come from
overdoing something over watering over
fertilizing over loving you know over
handling until they get to where they
learn to let things be you know and not
disturb them too much and know that less
is more sometimes so I just feel that
sometimes people get caught up in the
names like you know superstar [ __ ] and
and porn star imagine you know it's like
a [ __ ] porn movie the the you know
the guy with the 12-inch dick is gonna
[ __ ] the woman with the huge ass or
whatever I don't know but what they
think is gonna come out of these crosses
but having not at least asked yourself
what would I really like to have as an
ideal plant and is does it already exist
in can I buy a pack of seeds where I'll
reliably did a dozen of them instead of
maybe I'll get that special one out of
this I don't know you boys I may be from
a different generation or something some
of the younger folks seem to enjoy that
and take some pride in I'm on a phyno
hunt of some sort like they're on a
safari in Africa slashing away with a
machete somewhere writing home wants
some fun I don't know yeah now it's
interesting every one of them spoken to
is always said that they don't like FINA
hunting per se like it's just kind of
viewed as
that's me so is there any plans for any
feminist projects from Brothers Grimm
we're working on it because there's such
a demand I've always been against it but
again you know I come back into this
craft years later with many advancements
in the technology as well as an
understanding of soil that was
unprecedented at my time you know in the
90s and I think that knowing how to
properly make feminized seeds and not
doing it willy-nilly if we can prove to
ourselves it's a reliable method that we
can master that I don't produce
hermaphrodites that's something I've
never you know grown anything that's a
term afroditi deuced any seeds that
produce from Africa it's I'm really
proud of that and my fear has always
been if we tried to make feminized seeds
we may be making some percentage of
hermaphrodites and I want to avoid that
at all cost so if I get the chance I
sorry if I should prove to myself in and
over this next period of time that we're
working on that project I am convinced
that yes we can reliably produce
feminized seeds and people will not have
hermaphrodites still have great feminine
feminized seed or 10 feminine plants by
all means I'd love to do that yeah so
we're trying we're working on it would
you ever consider trying to get a Jack
Hera with a Devon and try to recreate
the original seeds you got in a certain
regard I don't think so you know that
cross isn't possible with what we have
in the house at the moment that we'd
have to demonstrate it with that in that
direction we have so many combinations
that you could sit back and you know
Monday Morning Quarterback about how
wouldn't that be cool if you did there's
so many combinations you have to
prioritize and select the ones that all
right these are what we're doing as a
company and moving forward and this is
just you know mm-hmm
maybe not an interesting thing
I don't even make those choices I'm
sorry yeah they could very well be a
great idea I just don't know if that's
on the horizon anytime soon no worries
yeah
so if we look at the average order even
the better Jack haircut we noticed that
it's not really as potent as say genius
sorry I say princess do you think that
princess was kind of just a one in a
million where that point you see got
really jacked up because I mean if we
think about dev and it's not a strain
it's typically known for its potency so
it it doesn't appear on papers though it
would Jack the potency up of a jack
herer and yet it did yeah
genetics is a lottery you know it's a
it's a statistics game and with every
strain that exists at the moment sort of
deriving from you know a few basic
starting points and then being more from
there when you combine in a Jack Herer
that probably has at least three to five
different lines that come into it from
various origins and then the Durbin
which is just a land race you're gonna
get less variation than two poly hybrids
but you're still going to have those odd
numbers that come up those odd lottery
numbers you know because each plant is
basically like a lottery number and if
you have this if you can envision a jug
of marbles you know that we're gonna put
in a hopper and spin them and you know
you can only take out six at a time and
that's your plan and you have only two
different colors in that hopper there
aren't going to be a lot of variations
among the plants and they're gonna be
pretty predictable but when you have 18
different color marbles in there and
you're taking out six at a time you may
very well have six of one color you may
have you know one or one is each of the
six a different color and another one
that has six where each of them is a
different color but not the same colors
as its neighbor you know so there's so
many ways those lottery numbers can come
out princess is just one
that the right combination to get those
qualities existed and the next-door
neighbor in the same bud
the genius seed grew into genius which
doesn't looked a lot like in many
regards princess except in certain ways
that you can see a family resemblance
maybe more in flowering than in veg yeah
so yeah it's it's that lottery number
business of the lack of predictability
when you have a lot of genes in play
like that
yep you just can't say well hey we got a
thought crossing durbin to the jack
herer would have boosted potency no I
bet if you looked at the averages that
didn't but you have those outs the
outliers and she's an outlier basically
yeah how's that so the Brothers Grimm
are now looking at working with various
members of the chem dog family the
cuttings what is it about the chem dogs
that are appealing to you and what type
of projects would you envision with them
I think because they are almost so
opposite from the types of strains that
I've always concentrated on and then
known for the more cerebral fruitier
flavored you know those up highs and the
Terps and so on that are more akin to
what people are smoking in dabs today I
guess the chem dog line especially 91 oh
excuse me
appeals to me in that it's a
counterpoint to the types of weed that I
normally smoke and it's such a nice
refreshing change and you know it's
almost unbeknownst to me that my
attitude my energy level and so on is
what it is when I'm smoking my usual
types of strains and I could actually
use a little bit of chill pill sometimes
and the ninety one chem dog will give me
that like deep earthy connect back to
earth kind of thing instead of being out
in space and it makes me feel a body hi
it's relaxing and can put me in a state
of relaxation and also has that
old-world like back in high school
people would sell brown Colombian weed
and the taste had that earthiness to it
and that Kevin dog has that earthy
flavor so there's a nostalgia to the
flavor there's a counterpoint
counter-reaction that sort of is a good
mate to the highs that I get from the
more sativa leaning cerebral pot that I
smoked most of the time and so do you
have any projects you'd be willing to
share that you might even just vaguely
envision doing with it yeah we're trying
to think about ways where that heavier
indica leaning you know there's you just
can't get much more into this than these
you know hash plants and 91 of the chem
dogs and those types of things that
bring that Tommy brings to the table do
diamond and he he and I always think
about like wow you know what if we did
this and you know recently we went the
other way we're not the indica side but
we used the hazy thunder l99 haze
supercilious super Silver Haze to get
princess and Paula make that Apollo haze
and the princesses from genius and
princess so the next logical step is to
sort of take a heavy indica side thing
and go the other way you know and take
princess and genius and see what would
happen I'd be excited to see and we have
seeds produced already from some of
those heavy and at this side of course
we have had to not take the female and
reverse it to get pollen we don't do
that or haven't done yet so if we were
to try to incorporate chem dog into say
Cinderella 99 we'd do something like
cross the chem dog to another suitable
male have a male from that generation
work back to the Cinderella 99 and
and see how those heavy indica
influences can combine with the
Cinderella 99 there are people I'll just
give you a little heads up - we didn't
do it ourselves but out on the west
coast there are some folks who grew out
Cinderella 99 crust - some very heavy
like og cush type and they said
Cinderella 99 was so dominant that he
would have thought that that indica
would be throwing his stuff in in that
next generation but they were mostly
Cinderella 90 not dominant so that's
interesting you know and I'd like to you
know see how that plays out for us as
well so kind of just on the topic of
feminized seeds would you ever consider
crossing princess - genius singers a lot
of people including myself consider
these two to be kind of you know the
Brothers Grimm holy grails but as I
mentioned to Tommy the other day he said
oh I don't think it would be too
different to a poet yeah yeah yeah we
kind of to tie them together in a nice
way Apollo 11 in particular was the goal
all along to do that sort of the
combination never having thought about
or wanting to you know engage in this
reversing the plans so yeah Apollo 11
has that princess structure with the
more vertically angled branches and
denser structure at the same time looks
a lot like genius and veg at the time
when the buds are fully formed they have
a lot of the shape of the princess and
at the same time our much frost year
have a lot of resin a lighter looking
than either genius or princess so I felt
like it really brought the two together
and the flavors and the high and
everything or it is kind of like best of
both worlds there yeah well I guess the
reason why I bring that up is because as
you just mentioning we
be Cinderella dominating that og cross
your friends had made it does feel
somewhat the same with the Apollo and I
guess we attribute that to the true
greening nature of Cindy's gonna tend to
be more dominant yeah
just like when we were using the example
of the land race yet across to a poly
hybrid you know she kind of comes from
that say do you think he's c99
stabilized enough that making
predictable contributions each time so
do you think if you did do a feminized
of princess ingenious it would come out
more different to Apollo seeing as there
isn't that dominating nature you know
like princess isn't as dominating as
seen you necessarily fun let's yeah it's
likely that you'd be you'd be seeing
more variety interesting
so you referenced earlier on that the
Brothers Grimm you do everything
organically what's your thoughts behind
this is it just simply I prefer Gaara
stall or do you really think it's you
know I am really a pragmatic guy I
wouldn't be doing this for any other
reason and I find it to be giving me the
best results with the least effort and
you know there's going back to earlier
conversation we mentioned you know
beginners getting kind of carried away
you know and always making mistakes on
the high side of overdoing things well
there's also what I call the gee whiz
factor and when you first come into
learning about cannabis cultivation you
kind of go gee whiz that's cool about a
lot of things that are beyond your
present skills and abilities and may not
actually be the better way of doing
things anyway but I know that setting up
an automated room with all hydroponics
and co2 and lights that you know are on
crazy cycles that you read about
somewhere and you know these are the
kinds of things that the early guys jump
into sometimes and what was the question
so they get carried away but they get
carried away
and I did too I guess in the beginning
and wanted to do hydroponics and night
so I have you dabbled in that and did it
even during the time when I was doing
Brothers Grimm in Boston I had sort of
pebble bed draining tables with rock
wool cubes lying on top of them and then
you have to stabilize the top of the
plants with screening or steaks or
however you can manage to do it I was
stretching strings across the room and
making kind of a grid to get them stand
inside of it so to cap off and answer
the question fully it's just the fact
that I find super easy seems so natural
maybe there's no gee whiz factor to it
but I get my hands right in the soil and
I mix it up you can ask Tommy he says
I'm the best soil mixer he's ever seen
in his life but every grain of soil is
like evenly mixed and evenly moist you
know and that's in that van and I'm
touching that with my bare hands and
getting that soil ready and when I
transplant something into that pot it
just takes off like a jet plane or
something and I love that every time I'd
never tire of seeing I
I think transplant is one of my favorite
things to do I love taking them from the
smaller pot and putting them in that big
final pot and watching how there's a
room behind you right there where I was
remarking to myself only 15 minutes ago
how this room just really really just
jumped right up out of the soil in a
very short time and it's they're just
growing like mad so I love that process
and working with the soil moving a few
pots around mixing soil it doesn't
bother me in the least I enjoy it and I
feel like we get great yields and great
productivity doesn't slow us down at all
yes there's some bother too you know
around hand-feeding soil plants with a
wand of whatever food we were giving
them that day which is all dragonfly
earth medicine mixed into water and pH
balanced and such yeah you know we have
mixed our own soil and we're also
feeding with those types of products and
to me it just seems really simple you
know we can do a lot of I feel I'm the
kind of I feel person my goodness so
touching back on something you mentioned
at the very start of the interview you
said you had the Acapulco gold and
recently some tests were done on some
samples they found and they found it
that it still was fairly high in THC do
you think I could attest to that yeah so
do you think that modern cannabis has
improved the levels of THC or more so
just refined characteristics about the
high because I think a lot of people and
I used to be guilty of this think that
you know all the Acapulco gold for
example was maybe not very good and it's
through hybridizing cannabis that we've
got it to the THC point it is now do you
feel that that's maybe not necessarily
the truth I think in those days in the
sixties and seventies those fields were
grown not by people who are really
consciously cultivating them the way we
are now and that there were standout
plants and you got certain batches you
know in those days from your local
dealer and he had gotten a pound that
happened to be better than usual or
something and so you got some
outstanding ones and you probably got
some mediocre ones but that's it's just
the variation I think in the in that but
certainly there had to have been very
high THC content and very potent plants
coming from that region during that time
and people having stood on that shoulder
and bred from there could absolutely
improve it and I feel that maybe the
advantages one has today are
that you have this variety available to
you very easily and there's been a lot
of experimentation and people have
created information and written and
spoken on all these subjects so that
today with the instant information of
the Internet you're well informed about
what the different types of marijuana
might do and which ones you might like
and how to get them and which ones taste
the way you want them to taste and you
know so many more refined menu I guess
you could say you know you can build
build your own what you like to smoke
based on the information that's out
there and a little bit of sampling but
in those days it was like whatever was
around that week or you know happened to
be circulating through your neighborhood
or your school that's what you got and
it's kind of hard to compare the apples
to oranges you know you know you just
look back on it and there's a nostalgia
to that every human being I think
suffers from you today have a lot of
resistance to you know you're building
up resistance people have high tolerance
tolerances to marijuana that we didn't
have in those days that it was a lot of
times periods of time would pass that
there was nothing around and then when
you did finally get some Wow you know
knock you on your ass and you'd be
talking about how great that weed was
and is it really psychological or was it
really
pharmaceutical you know in in origin you
know the feelings and sensations that
you had
I remember having not smoked marijuana
after marrying that woman who I told you
made me give it all up and I gotten a
project as an engineer working on a
project in Scotland and it was 1991 and
as part of my job I was required to just
make a quick trip out of the UK and fly
back in with my paperwork in order
because when they first called me and it
was an emergency and I had to get there
and they put me in as a tourist you know
so I took the opportunity to go to
Amsterdam you know and turn around it
well and go back to wherever ed and
birth and while there of course I went
in a coffee shop and the first thing I
ordered was spunk number one because at
that time 1991 that was something that
was like highly touted strain that
everyone should try and I had been
growing it at home and you know going in
a coffee shop in Amsterdam and actually
trying it there was something I really
wanted to do but my point is that having
not smoked for so long and my tolerance
being so low and having been living this
really straight life with my wife and
you know was like a huge freakout that
almost was akin to that first time I got
high with my uncle in his backyard and
came back in the house and felt like I
was in a dream you know and then my
grandmother came home and made us soup
and we were sitting at the table and I
couldn't stop giggling and my uncle is
like kicking me under the table stop
giggling your grandmother's gonna think
something's wrong you know and so when I
went into that coffee shop after having
not gotten high for so long I remember
that skunk number one just made me feel
like oh my god I'm seeing all these
incredible visual things around here
like if I had a camera right now that
would be such a cool shot you know that
the floor and the way it goes into the
jukebox over there that way and so on so
I mean there is some subjectivity and
some you have to pay attention to two
things the subjectivity of the set and
setting of the people who are smoking
the marijuana and judging how great it
is where they coming from before they
get there you know and then in that same
vein what was their tolerance you know
what are they used to smoking all the
time
that can totally change a review you
know I would do yeah I mean if I hadn't
smoked marijuana for a month
mm-hmm been out hiking in mountains
drinking from streams and you know
living off the land and having this pure
life or whatever and came back to you
know here and everybody say yeah welcome
back you know hey let's all smoke
something that first joint would be some
strategies yeah man stuff that I didn't
think was that strong before would
probably knock me on my ass so take
those things into consideration and also
you know kind of reminds me that
cannabis cup competitions and such are
oftentimes very subjective and might
I'll put a lot of stock in okay that
strain one this time who knows you that
may have been three or four other ones
that I would have preferred better you
know yeah so so if we kind of keep on
that topic of tolerance there's a bit of
a kind of a trend in the breeding
community to quote unquote breed for
concentrates you know breeding for
terpenes that will translate to
concentrates all of these type of
general ideas these Brothers Grimm
getting aboard that pipe train or no I
would like to say that we have something
already that maybe it isn't even
recognized or appreciated or people
aren't aware of it that Cinderella 99
itself it just completely dumps huge
amounts of resin off of the buds and if
I understand well how that whole process
works with extracts the more the
resident you know that comes off the bud
you the more what do they call yield of
concentrate that that particular strain
would be rated sa you know I think that
if someone did a good grow of Cinderella
then were to process it and do
extraction they may find that it's
hitting numbers for yield that are
unprecedented you know I just don't
think anybody's tried yet
you know we released the seeds in April
enough times passed that somebody should
have done but maybe nobody has or
anybody hasn't stuck their head up out
of the rabbit hole and told anybody
about it you know yeah but I would feel
I would like to say you know if there
are people who want to buy seeds and
grow a plant that will give you a high
yield of high quality you couldn't go
wrong buying the Cinderella 99 and just
saying you know this will give it an
amazing terpene profile it's gonna give
an amazing yield of resin and it's gonna
have a psycho activity that you know is
world famous for you know really being
enjoyable and the kind of thing that
like the ladies for some reason I have
many times women come up to me
Cinderella and I mean that is my
favorite strain I just love that this
tastes so good makes me feel so good and
so I'm pretty easy I I yeah exactly and
it's funny you say that because I was
just about to segue into
foria is this spray for a you know it's
a sexual lubricant actually with
cannabis infused in it and one of my
girlfriends told me that she read
somewhere that Cinderella 99 is used in
that formula because of the effort
easyacc qualities that they found in
testing other strains and it yeah so I
did not see that with my own eyes but
I'd like to believe it's true and yeah I
remember I was talking to Duke the other
day and in regards to the hash making
stuff and he said that uh Cindy is like
the neverending golf stuff but it just
just keeps giving you more resin every
before you handle it it's crazy
so you guys are looking to re-release
the Killer Queen slash you have yeah now
yeah so it's out there go get it can we
expect any other little special Reed
oxes from some of these old-school
popular strains to make it out there let
me think about something we were
probably kicking around recently let's
see there was something that crossed my
mind I forget what it was like the sugar
blossoms or something where yeah look
using the white widow c99 white widow
type of earth and would probably be the
recreation of the what we called sugar
blossoms back then we also have talked a
little bit about there was a plant we
called the Green Giant back in the day
and we're sort of working toward a
similar thing we probably won't call it
green giant but it's an improvement on
that idea that now having stood on the
shoulders of previous work I can see
that we can do even better and we'll do
some you know big yielding outdoor
strain that you know can still mature in
time for the northeasterners here in the
United States and such where in
Australia do you have sort of a dividing
line of where people can start to be
getting too far south where it's too
cold in the winters or something or has
not not happen in Australia at all I
know people in New Zealand and they
still are able to do outdoor crops so I
don't think there is a too far south so
to speak
around there's you know like I I
struggle like I kind of cringe to say
but there's an area in Australia called
there the Emerald triangle
you know akin to the one here and that's
kind of what I consider to be the sweet
spot of Australia we grow in the
outdoors and they get like three four
crops into the outdoor season it goes
for quite a long time I guess
so is it daylight sort of not varying so
much from twelve twelve yeah yeah very
close very close so I think we get about
14 hours max sorry 14 hours max eleven
and a half minimum so yeah we we get uhm
basically from speaking to my friend who
does a lot of outdoors he says so
they're at first outdoor crops things
are starting to flower right now and
they'll be harvested a little bit after
Christmas he said those crops don't turn
out the best because it's still really
hot it's summer you know it's like 100
degrees resin production is coming yeah
really laughs you know density and then
he said but the last two you get in
which as you're just getting towards
July they're really frosty nice colors
because you get in towards winter and
yeah I look forward to those our autumn
there's also some other so obviously you
have a bit of an intertwined past with
the SSS see yeah being the u.s.
distributor when you decided to do the
Durban Tyson in 99 did they kind of give
you you know a lot of approval as it
thank you for the help earlier or
we don't really in contact with lost
contact for some time at that point I
hadn't spoken to them for something like
eight years and they were upset with me
for giving up working for them you know
and it was sort of abrupt because of
having met that woman and yet married
and so on I was a young man and easily
swayed by you know the influence yeah
you know there was some urgency
I don't know sort of the primal pressure
to breed or something at that moment
myself so I took five years and made a
couple of kids and came back to making
plants again now thousands yeah so when
you did that when I they were still
releasing the original Devon time by
flower or did you hold and track down a
packet of it or Oh No yeah that was
actually a friend out in the North
Pacific Northwest who I traded a cutting
of princess to who gave me the Durban
tie and he was meant to keep that under
wraps and not spread it around and I
believe he has done and you know I think
it may have circulated to another fellow
but so from that friend who I traded the
princess clone to and he gave me Durban
tie as see and I grew out those seeds
and having done many years before I knew
what to look for and found a really nice
early maturing little group there and
got the mail that was similar to that
and read that to oh I'm sorry I used the
female and used the amount the male c99
that's right so then so I got the Durban
tie c99 I found a nice early maturing
female and went with the c99 male so do
you have any beliefs on the effects of
using males and females and the
differences in the cross so what I mean
by that is I from memory I'm quoting
this DJ short said that he always found
you wanted to have the most achiever of
the two parents being the female I think
you said you've got the best results
from that have you found something like
that way you know what maybe you prefer
to use Cindy as a male more than a
female or you know anything along those
lines well here's the thing that's funny
you asked that question and after all
this time it was that question that I
asked to super sativa seed club that
piqued their interest in me and made
them think that this guy actually is
thinking and has a good understanding of
what what's going on with reading and so
on because I asked them the question
when you make a cross like you know
Afghani scum gunk Afghani you know does
it matter the offspring whether the male
was the Afghan year the female was the
Afghani or vice versa the males stump or
the female skunk and so he said because
of that question I really want to talk
to you can I get your phone number it's
Destin and in my experience he never did
answer you know to my satisfaction and
anything but in my experience now after
all these years I've found that what you
want to do is that the offspring are
presumably female that you're interested
in if we can just like assume that let's
say you want to grow seeds that will
give you a great female in general you
want the mother to be the type that's
most like the offspring you're looking
for and the male will be less and less
of an influence because of the following
reason daughters are going to look more
like there are mothers in general and
their feminine qualities will come from
mother
more likely and the male contributes a
why crumbs x-chromosome and the female
contributes an X chromosome so each of
them is contributing something to make
up that female daughter and when a son
is created it has the Y chromosome from
the male and therefore you know has his
influence and being his sons you tend to
see sons looking like their dads and
such in human beings and mammals and so
on and also when you are trying to breed
a female you're looking for the female
traits to show you what the daughters
will have and it's obvious right I mean
because of the female the mother's a
female the daughters a female that
traits those female traits that you want
the daughters to have are going to be
expressed in the female hopefully and if
you're hoping to get some of the female
traits from the male side it's gonna be
a subtler influence but you know what
will end up happening you have yeah yeah
yeah yeah so where was I if you press
them right also how does one pick in the
phenotype of a male and judge what
female traits he'll be able to
contribute when he has no feminine
traits to exhibit now one of the
examples I use is imagine you wanted to
breed humans you know you uh you wanted
to have large breasted women okay and
it'd be obvious that yeah you would want
to start with take a woman who's large
breasted she'll probably have large
breasted daughters yeah now if you make
that link to potency in marijuana and
you say all right well we're gonna want
a female that has high potency right you
know and
potency comes from high resin production
and the female parts of the marijuana
plant so it's very obvious to be able to
pick a female that has the drug quality
that you want but in the male he doesn't
have any female parts to judge that from
so what do you do guys in the old days
would do the following they would try to
smoke the male's leaves and flowers and
try to find out which males had the
highest potency and figure that would be
the one that will give the female more
potency and bring that into the cross
well if you think about it that's
analogous to in our little example of
trying to breed for large breasted women
finding men with large breasts to breed
with your large breasted woman that
doesn't make sense does it
yeah because you're looking for a
feminine trait in a male yeah that's not
necessarily going to happen that the man
whose breasts are the largest SAR going
to be a trait that he transmits to his
daughters he might more likely have
large breasted sons so that's the [ __ ]
up thing about doing it that way so what
I found was that I would grow out a
generation of plants and I'd have the
females and males growing through their
vegetative states together and I'd group
the ones that were similar in their
structure you know given all of the
neutral gender traits stuff that's not
specific to a male or a female thickness
of the stalk density of Internode's
the thinness or longness of the leaves
and such and group them together and
whichever ones turned out to be females
and males from each group I'd say okay
the males from that group that had all
of those vegetative properties that were
similar to the females in that group be
it you know tall short whatever I have
found that they are the ones that will
then transmit the type of female
characteristics from the sisters
the next generation and if you do a
little bit of reverse engineering and
sort of time-traveling you can go back
to our experiment with humans and say
okay how do we know a man who has
already proven himself to create
daughters who have large breasts that
would be what one one way of finding a
man who is a good match for your bit
large breasted woman right because the
proofs in the pudding it's not in his
breasts that he just that he exhibits on
himself the real test of a breeding stud
of a guy who can make daughters who have
large breasts is a guy who makes
daughters with large breasts you've
proven it he's done it a few times right
so you know how you find guys like that
find large breasted women and get their
dad so you go back to the father of that
large breasted woman yeah that guy
already has been shown to make a large
breasted daughter he's a good
probability so you can do that if anyone
is ever smart enough to you know hold
the male back and see what happens in
future generations say oh look you know
that male would have been very generally
you know valuable but we called him
because you know we already pollinated
something that wants you know sometimes
people do that but we tend to hold on to
our males for a while and prove them out
before we whatever so with this in mind
is that almost does that the school of
thought or mursaleen itself to make you
want to use Cindy more as the male
because yeah if you really restrains you
could look out for example in
straightaway say our well Cindy was the
dad like I mean space Queens a great one
well you're talking feminized now and
when you feminized and reverse a female
clone I mean it's almost a certainty
that this will now was Holland that
pardon was space Queen feminized no I'm
not talking about it I'm just saying in
general yeah not using space Queen as
the example but if you take a clone
female clone and colloidal silver spray
the things to reverse it and make pollen
the characteristics that are going to be
carried in that pollen
is much much more likely to carry all of
the feminine characteristics of the
plant that it came from than a male who
came from that generation and may have
an entirely different lottery ticket as
we were using that analogy earlier and
wouldn't give so reliably all of the
characteristics that that female clone
would have done in its pollen that would
be my assumption going into this and
that's what you know scientifically
makes sense to me but again proofs in
the pudding yeah in the next year or so
as we go through the process of learning
how that works for us
I will like to think that that will ring
true eventually but that's my gut
feeling yeah so do you have any plans or
want to do any kind of CBD project to be
right it's so ubiquitous at the moment
that people ask for the CBD and ask if
we're doing anything and I mean I've
always just felt yeah you know I'm an
old-school guy I'm the stuck a stick in
the mud or whatever I'm in this for the
THC I'm all about you know smoking
marijuana for the pleasurable
recreational value of it I know that it
helps people you know on the medical
side and my partner's Dukes much more
into that side of it and good you know
there should be one part of this company
that wants to devote you know energy to
that but and I will certainly go along
with anything we come up with the he
wants to do but it's not a big concern
for me or a priority for me for some
reason I don't know I guess I need more
experience with it I did have one nice
experience where I had come from New
York to Colorado and had a dodgy knee
for a while and it had been sort of like
a tendinitis that wasn't just from
recently I mean I had been suffering for
a while somebody gave me some CBD pills
I think there were 30 milligrams of CBD
oil and took one or two of them right
away never came back
I've never still to this day had that
tendonitis ever come back so I feel like
the stuff is pretty miraculous
the way that it can work and I'd love to
have people also experience you know a
really good result like that like I did
yeah
and so I'd love to get my hands on some
more there's one fellow who I did get
that from that I'd kind of like to see
again and I'll put the word out to
assume that come see me with more of
those CBD pills man my wife is asking
about him now
yeah so so do you feel that the true
medet world when i say truth obviously
subjective do you feel that you know the
largest amount of conditions are treated
by not simply CBD but a mixture of maybe
THC and CBD yeah I've always maintained
that it's the cannabinoid profile itself
and the ratios of the different
cannabinoids that go into any one plant
that give it all of its myriad qualities
of different high flavors and so on and
the high you're getting is influenced by
that you know almost like a chord being
played on an instrument that it's you
know first third fifth you know maybe
it's got a minor seventh thrown into it
and these kinds of things and they're
all subtle things it's always amazed me
in music how with 12 notes you know that
everything can just be created that is
created from that and it's the same
thing with the marijuana yeah so if you
could give some advice to some of the
breeders starting out what would be some
of the things you try to emphasize as
you know the more
things to be keeping in mind I'd say you
know there's a tendency to want to try a
lot of different things and bring a lot
of elements and there's the old adage
you know too many cooks spoil the soup
or you know adding too many ingredients
is you know keep it simple the kiss
method if you know know what you're
working with
and realize that you don't really
necessarily need to have any wild swings
and variation of what you're breeding to
start moving your phenotypes toward the
phenotype that you really want you know
I've gotten such a good lot of variation
from such similar plants that you know
imagine you know they're only sister
they're actually sisters of each other
genius and princess and the different
things that have been created out of
them can show you how from very little
variation and the gene pool you're
starting from you can achieve what you
want and you don't have to overshoot by
introducing more elements than necessary
or two too great of a difference in
where you are to what you're crossing it
to so keeping it simple always be sure
of what you're actually what you really
have you know never take something from
somebody and trust that they say it's
what it is and you know I believe them
you know really do your diligence and
make sure that it is what the person
says it is I can't tell you how many
times I've turned down people offering
me cuttings and seeds and anything else
and I just say dude you know thank you
for your generosity it's very nice of
you to offer they send me free stuff and
you know I just don't philosophically
fit into the kind of breeder who tries a
bunch of odd [ __ ] you know I have very
definite idea of where I'm going with
something I know I already have the
tools in my
toolkit here I don't need to reach
outside too much when I do is for a
really specific reason it's something
that I think like okay that really makes
sense and I really know that this is
what it's supposed to be and I'll take
it from there
and I would advocate that people be a
little bit more choosy I guess and ask
yourself when you do buy seeds and you
know to have a starting point what am I
really looking for what characteristics
do I desire in the plants that I want to
grow is there anything that already
exists that does all that and you know
matches up to my wishlist why don't I
try buying some of those seeds and if
they aren't exactly what I want isn't
that a great place to start your
breeding project with something that was
geez you know touted to be what I really
want and it wasn't quite what I wanted
but if I were to breed it a couple of
generations just some back crossing
maybe I might have something here but
you know she was a good starting place
no I don't know so that make sense yes
so with that same kind of thought in
mind and how do you feel about breeders
using your work and more specifically
I'll give you a few examples how do you
feel about a breeder using one of your
strains in an f1 how do you feel about a
breeder selling say not Cindy because
you'll understand why but maybe say the
Apollo and just say the pure f4 form and
how do you feel about someone selling
cross that maybe they have knives even
f1 Cindy then tighten to the f4 as
opposed to just the pure Apollo a Titan
to the m4 I feel that it's always a
compliment whenever anybody uses
Brothers Grimm seed stock and creates
something from it if they've taken
Apollo 13 to f4 and it's done
intelligently I mean it's another thing
that I think that newbies don't
understand is that they think maybe a
bigger number means better you know like
a four-star general is you know asthma
higher rank than a three-star general
and a f3 f4 is better than an f3 well
that may be only if the steps along the
way from f1 to f2 to f2 to f3 and so on
were done intelligently and correctly
then yeah you are improving in each
generation but just don't go by the
number as long as people understand what
that all means and I know that you know
the general public probably doesn't to a
large degree understand the terminology
and what they're really buying and so on
so you won't be able to reach everybody
but you're asking for advice to people
who are in the know and would know
better and so on and my advice is yeah I
know I had a good point going there
don't let me lose it what was the
question again
oh you how they how I feel about them
using my stuff so it's a compliment that
they do that the people who are the
buyers are probably not savvy enough to
really in in any great numbers
differentiate you know what's going on
there but I believe that it'll all sort
of settle to a common denominator where
everyone no matter who you are whether
you're buying soap or electronics or
whatever it is you don't buy the
knockoff you buy the real thing if you
know it exists it's and it's available
and there's no real price difference to
consider you go with the name-brand
you know and the originator of
Cinderella 19
his Brothers Grimm so if someone were
doing a knockoff of Cinderella 99 two
things come to mind about that you know
for the present I think of it as well
the guy who's doing that is probably at
this point gonna want to just either
sell out all of his stock or realize
that it's sort of worthless because only
somebody who's not in the know and
doesn't realize that they could get the
real thing would even want to buy that
so she'd probably have a fire sale and
just get rid of as much of it as he can
as freebies for buying you know here's a
promotional pack of our knockoffs t99
that you is free with anything we sell
you know and get rid of it because it's
like stock that has suddenly dropped to
zero values over holding on to you might
as well get rid of it right so there's
the present that's the present situation
but the past that led up to the present
if you think about it none of these guys
ever played with Cinderella 99 made
crosses with it Polo's and the names
weren't bandied about for this last
dozen years and I come back into the
business where would I be I'd be sitting
here trying to remind everybody who the
hell I was what my strains were you know
the so they actually kept the buzz alive
and I am complimented by the fact that
they were so you know driven to continue
in our absence the the work if you will
I've only tried a couple of people's
knockoffs and you know obviously
something went awry somewhere they got
something from somebody who claimed that
it was c99 it wasn't or something
because the plants that I've seen that
were grown from the seeds that I've been
given by the knockoff companies just
come out looking like Cinderella 99 or
anything that no it's not it's not
really even close so story yeah and that
happens it's like the story that tell is
told at one end of the classroom gets to
the other end of the classroom and it's
totally different from where it started
and you can imagine in the 14 years that
it took to go from shutting down in 2002
and coming back up in 2016 now that
story has gone all around
upside down and who knows what's what
anymore so push reap now push the reset
button then you can obtain the original
strains from the original breeder and
you know easy now to and now we're
internationally distributed worldwide
and easy to get no more complaining so
there seems to be a current fad in the
breeding community for people wanting to
take things to like say the f2 or the f3
as opposed to say doing a B x2 or a B X
3 how do you think these two techniques
compare to each other they've obviously
got there's different reasons why you
should do them but I'm of the opinion
that maybe some people just do it
because it seems like they've put in a
lot of work or something like that like
how do you feel yeah you know I'd say
exceptional people are in the minority
by definition right I mean the average
person is probably gonna make a lot of
mistakes and do a lot of guesswork and
say well maybe this will you know they
don't have a rhyme or reason for what
they're doing so that's a major fault
right there but then when people are
intelligent about their choices and they
say okay what am I doing here and they
ask all these questions that I always
advocate you ask yourself like you know
what is it that I really want my ideal
plant where am I going with this what's
the end what's the end goal and
traditionally you had this crossing of
one land race to another and so you'd
have your p1 generation these two land
race strains and then you create a
hybrid from that an f1 generation now in
that f1 generation you're gonna see a
certain ratio that everybody's familiar
with 1 3 1 and you then decide if you
were crossing these two to start with
neither one of them p1 generation
parents was the ideal plant right but
must have had some characteristics that
you felt were important and the other
one did too and that's why you're
bringing them together otherwise you
would have just stayed with either one
of those plants and said hey I'm
with these what's the point of trying to
improve on something that I feel is
already perfect why reinvent the wheel
yeah so you're constantly asking
yourself where we going why am I doing
this what is it that I what are my goals
and if back crossing comes into play
it's because one of those two parents is
heavily carries he's carrying heavily
many of the characteristics that you are
trying to go for in the goal and the
other one was contributing for some
minor reason okay but if they're sort of
equally contributing there's not much
reason to back cross but then you start
looking at that larger group that came
from the f1 generation that has the
variations in it that isn't the oh these
are just you know clones the mum this is
just the clones of dad you know that
that jet that part that proportion of
your progeny that falls into that
category and you concentrate on the ones
that varied and are some mix of the two
because isn't that what you're going for
right you're looking to mix them and
blend them in some way but it doesn't
always work like a blender but in the f1
generation that larger population is
generally like a blender so there is a
great tendency for them to be an equal
balance of the two and if that's what
you're going through you've already
arrived you've got the pack of seeds
that you just keep crossing that mother
and father ad infinitum and why go any
further is there a reason to create an
f2 or a three or four no no we're the
end goal is and stop there so what's
presumably from that f1 generation the
person who looks to make an f2
generation is saying I see a phenotype
in here that I want to isolate and then
further refine in the next generation
such that more of the progeny are of
that type yeah yeah so you have to
intelligently choose the F ones that
you're going to use to make your f2
generation maybe do it with several of
the brothers and sisters so that you
have a few different groups to try to
see
now I'm starting to see a rhyme or a
reason here which ones actually do what
I want to do then you intelligently
choose from them how to make your f3
generation if that isn't where you
really wanted to go yeah and then you're
looking for stability are we starting to
get now all the females are like you
know and they all have the great
qualities that I want you know and those
are the reasons to accept the challenge
of going one more generation and trying
to find the right mothers and fathers to
give you that seed that you can throw in
the ground and reliably say I know what
I'm gonna get here every time if that's
your goal
okay but yeah I mean that's that's how
an intelligent breeder goes about
working toward creating a strain or
getting a plant and I think that
listening to going back if you rewind
through this and you see how starting
from a and B mother and father blending
them together and having a goal and
asking yourself in each generation am I
getting there and what am i doing right
or wrong and adjusting for that that's
how each generation gets better and if
you don't get a better generation you
better go back and you fix something
because there's no point moving on when
you have an f3 generation that just is
dismal compared to f2 you better go back
in the f2 generation either across
different brothers and sisters to get a
better result org realized that f2 is
where you need to stop with this and you
may actually have created a seed strain
that that generation when sold to the
customer is producing an amazing plant
however if he tries to play for us his
mother the females and males he's going
to get [ __ ] they need to buy back seized
people in many other communities not the
cannabis community as much or maybe not
as vocally have used that strategy you
know for all of history basically
sellers of seeds of all different types
of flowers and so on and veg
and prized tomatoes or what have you
they want you to not be able to just
make more of their seeds that they sell
do they want you they want to come back
and they want you to come back to repeat
business they and that's the sort of
thing so that may have been a part of
somebody's goal in a breeding program
right yeah so that might have been like
wow this is great look at the result
we're getting the f2 generation is like
this is amazing plant but when you press
the brothers and sisters the f3
generation just falls apart
perfect let's keep making F twos and
selling those seats yeah and you're good
yeah so there's some on the santur level
stuff yeah so yeah it smacks of Monsanto
but you know I'm just talking about
every possibility what could be possible
whether you know sounds of morally just
or nefarious or what you know so I mean
if we were to think about the
epigenetics of seeds you mentioned
earlier that the soil we have now is
much better than the soil we had before
how do you find the seeds we have
Cinderella for example are coming out
now versus before do you see they're
about the same germination ratio or do
you think that as our you know input
ingredients have improved so as the seed
output quality no I don't think so I
mean they because of a better
nutritional program that they're on now
you think is that what your question
like they may have we've got dentists or
a better understanding of how slow truly
built-in complete I don't know it's
difficult to say we had great
germination rate back in the 90s with
what I was doing then and you know I
think when I see this form that's formed
it's you know it's gonna be healthy it's
it may be larger you know if it had it
had more energy devoted to it while it
was growing many times we see that like
when you just pollinate a few of the
sort of pre flowers on a veg plant and
they end up growing you see that's often
time a big one isn't it yeah so when the
plant has a lot of energy to be able to
devote to it the seed gets larger so I
would say if I start just to notice like
the seeds now that I'm making are bigger
and darker and healthier than the
I remember from back in the day then I
would say yeah that's right
I don't think it's to a degree that's a
you know noticeable though I haven't
said to myself wow it's not like the old
days these are really much bigger and
darker I think I had healthy seeds then
you know yeah so would you consider
doing a limited release kind of similar
to how the original Apollo 13 was done
and if you did would you do it in a
similar way because there is a small
trend in the breeding community for
people to do very limited release
batches and consequently that the cost
per pack is sometimes astronomical
sometimes quite justifiable uh-huh how
would you feel about doing it if you
were to do it well I think just doing
something in a limited quality as in
limited quantity so that you would have
fewer of them to sell and drive demand
and price up and that's not how I would
like to do things if it were released in
a small quantity it's just because we
only had this small quantity we don't
intend to do anything more with this it
was a side project and I would tend to
charge a low price for it or give it
away as it free me when people bought
our other strains you know and I guess
that was the case with the Apollo 13
kind of back in that time I was giving
them to Richard at heaven's stairway and
he was sort of making those marketing
decisions as to should I sell these or
you know and how many of them he had and
he decided to sell them but it was only
the one batch and I didn't have more so
he sold out of whatever 500 seeds or
maybe 50 packs and and that was that and
so we recreated it this year but I
didn't want to again you know do it
forever but we made a lot more than the
first time so that there's plenty
available for everyone so they can
really see what that was but Apollo 11
was really the goal and we'll make that
as a reliably you know appearance
appearing on our menu all the time kind
of
strain but Apollo 13 for the moment I
think we made quite a good lot of it and
when it's gone
we won't immediately replaced with okay
yes still semi semi unique so people
sometimes talk about returning to our
land race roots and we already mentioned
that Brothers Grimm is working with the
Durban would you ever consider crossing
it to another land race or heirloom so
to speak and really trying to work out
those raw genetics you know like a
somewhat unseen waiver for sea that's
always on the table I mean when you feel
like hey I've been thinking about a
project and it doesn't necessarily have
to come from what we already have on our
palate you know I could be out on a trip
somewhere and make a point of going to
someplace where I think I'm gonna go out
and do like a land race seed expedition
and come back with some cool stuff and
who knows in our future you know I'm an
adventurous type of person and I'd like
to probably do that one of these times
so yeah what would be wrong with that
I would only hesitate to do that if it
was just like you know to slap two
things together we don't do that you
know we always have some purpose like a
forethought of why are we crossing these
two what's the what's the goal and make
maybe at some point I go somewhere and I
find something unique and interesting
that I think like oh this would be a
great project to cross this with
whatever else I mean then I'd do it but
you know it'd have to be thought out a
little bit say you know just just from
the way your brain works you kind of I
get the feel that you're always intended
to be afraid of
was it the discovery of those seeds that
really plant the seed in your mind to do
the greeting was it like these seeds are
so amazing I've got a breathing or were
you always kind of proof we think
dealings with SS SC I think it was more
a sense of preservation of the judgment
genetics for myself and not not losing
them I kind of wanted to say like what
if ever you know I shut down and I want
to be able to start up I'd like to have
seeds that could replace the clones I've
been drawing it growing you know or
whatever that was one emotion I had and
I just feel like growing the plants and
is one part of it but seeing that
progression of when you're crossing them
and breeding them is fascinating and to
try to get handles on that and you know
learn how to control it like anything
you know like became an engineer I think
because I was always curious about how
does that work I don't want to walk
through the world and not know why it
takes five seconds for the ball to fall
from the hundred foot bridge or whatever
you know Matt I'd like to be able to
work that out so when I see all of this
coming together like building blocks and
you know it gives me great joy and
satisfaction to feel like I have some
control over that remember when I first
got sparked my interest to be a grower
in the first place is learning that you
mean that photo period and the 12 hours
of the 18 I can stall time or forced it
into flowering learning that was so you
know inspiring that it really launched
me my motivation from that point so were
there ever any strains you smokes
while you were in between the first and
the current incarnation of Brothers
Grimm
you were smoking them and you just kind
of thought well like if I ever come back
I want to work with that or maybe now
I'm also thinking back you thought of a
certain strain you had during the hiatus
and thought yeah we need to work with
that hmm yeah you know I always come
back to the Durbin tie and say like you
know that was something that I would
love to try to get get ourselves back
into and we're working on that and I
think we will have a good one very soon
so and then like I said you know there's
a sense that during the time I had those
seeds and the access to everything I
never tried as much of it as I would
have liked to have done and learned you
know like what I was missing Bey tricks
and Williams wondered those kinds of
things that huh I wonder what they were
like you know if I went over the menu
and I looked at you know item by item
which ones I grew and which ones I have
some experience with you know there
would definitely be some where I'd go
yeah I wish I had during that time had
thought to myself to grow a little of
this and see what that was like but
remember earlier when we almost started
the thing up you know there was that
question about you know do you realize
you're making history when you're making
history you don't you know and at the
time you're not really thinking like
well one day this won't be here I won't
have it to try that other cam you know
over there of seeds and I just always
thought you know yeah I'm messing around
with this one and that one and that one
I'll get around to those ones someday
and then that someday never came and the
rug was kind of pulled out from under me
and I got married to a woman who wanted
me to give up marijuana so yeah let's
talk about lab percentages and most
specifically if you guys started getting
numbers that were like you trusted them
and they said why legitimately 15% but
you were really happy with the high you
swear I was killer
would you be happy to tell people those
numbers like I you of the belief that
the numbers of really kind of not a true
picture of what you're getting or do you
think that they are important in the
current climate
I think the reliability of the labs is
in question I know that there's a
motivation whenever you're in a business
like that and one of the biggest
examples I could give you a standard and
poor's and moody's when they were
evaluating stocks during the the whole
housing bubble they were competing with
each other for their customers business
and so consequently there they had to
rate the stocks higher than they would
have normally done if they didn't know
that their competitor would have rated
them high just to get the customers
business there's certainly that going on
right now there are labs who are just
bumping numbers more and more just to
say jeez you know where'd you get your
tested you know then the guys talk to
one another and then everybody goes
scrambling for that lab because they
give the big numbers come on I mean I
don't know I don't believe the numbers
it's there's there's no I don't think
there's enough standardization and
enough reliability to those numbers that
anybody can really say much about it
yeah maybe there are people who can do
but I don't think that those people are
the ones that most people are listening
to or working with but some group of
scientists say that oK we've done all of
the necessary testing and such just to
prove that this is true then it's
believable you know but I don't think
that everybody's using the right
equipment or interpreting it properly
but if like I say you know the right
equipment and the right people who know
how to use that are saying that we've
calibrated all of this this is the true
number we'll stand on this you know for
all time going forward you'll never find
that we did this wrong we got it right
right you know but I don't see in the
forms that people hand out you know like
oh here's the piece of paper that said
you know the results come on a child fit
of Korea
the software program kicked those
numbers that make it look just the same
as that piece of paper right doesn't
prove anything
yes so I would like to see a lot more
you know a proof of is that number
believable is that something that's a
standard that everybody's using and and
everything else I don't I don't think
we're there for that yeah so and then
there's the greed and the motivation to
yeah have a higher number than the next
lab so what do you think is the future
of growing if we was sighted kind of
break it down into components of say
lighting technology growing mediums and
nutrients genetics what do you think
will be the next big leap we make it's
probably pretty easy to say that the
most recent leap is being in the
lighting with the advent of the
double-ended bulbs have you seen any
kind of new prototype technology we'll
just caught your eye nope the lighting
is the main thing really you know
because everything else is basically
HVAC and soil and what do we have
I don't know eyes own at MIT I missed
some things I don't know what do we talk
about yeah yeah
the technology of in a soil for sure
yeah I think so
technology so to speak has improved a
lot but then again so is mine
now there's so many there's a lot of
little subtle things and you know I tend
to just sort of make broad sweeps with
my brush sometimes not always to great
effect but anyway okay today what yeah
stopping yeah you know I'm just gonna
say we we see a lot of news about the
new skunk lines coming out do you guys
have any plans to release any other old
staples and do you want to give us any
more info on when we can expect to see
these skunk varieties available when you
say old staples not necessarily our old
staples yeah things that we're going
back to yeah well it's all about back to
the future a little bit with us I guess
you know we we we'd like to go back to
the roots and bring people the old
original strains reliable consistent
plants you know that our seeds aren't
all over the place and they are what we
claim them to be in the descriptions are
accurate and such but going back to any
particular crosses it's not necessarily
always in mind as to which ones they
might be but I guess I go by feel in
life quite a bit and those those things
aren't something where I can say like Oh
over the next two years there's a plan
to do this that and the other thing but
three to six months out we usually know
what we're doing and it's kind of like
who gets me the projects suggest
themselves to us you know yeah so when
you go back to when you were first doing
the initial backcross project to even
now who is some of the breeders who you
looked up to slash do you still look up
20 breeders or is it more so now I just
I mean necessarily no favor knew who
were I mean Nevel was the name that was
bandied about back then as a breeder who
you know was in the news and in the
magazine high times and such and so I
did know of him and then you know
there's DJ short and breeder Steve and
dick high and you know the mates that I
knew off of the internet that we were
all kind of colleagues at the time doing
similar things and like I say no
competition really it's just everybody
doing their own thing and kind of being
friendly about it that was my little
community but I didn't ever know any of
the big you know like a name like
Neville somebody who's not on the same
continent as me and I'd cross paths with
and the communication and information
was not as good then so we found out
that cash was actually Neville probably
and he you know and he wanted to work
with you on something is that something
he wanted to do or you think it's just
divorce I mean I'm I like you know I'm
friendly pursed and I've always been
open-minded and I'll talk to anybody
about anything and I have respectful I
have respect for him so why would I turn
down a conversation you know I'm trying
to make these dtc 9,900 yeah well if
he's got the other half and yeah there
was something in said he does have seats
yeah yeah I'm sure so he's waiting the
pro he knows what he's gonna do with
them so how do you feel about the
Colorado kind of us seem happy and you
know and specifically do you think
Colorado has it the best so do you think
maybe some other states have figured it
out
I don't have a lot of experience in the
other states and in Colorado the
cannabis scene is almost you know read
aBSI you know like it's not a cannabis
scene so much as a DAB scene and a glass
scene and a pecking order of folks who
are sort of trying to find their place
here and you know there's a lot of very
heady no pun intended
you know very heady atmosphere them for
them to at a young age come and have an
exposure to so much freedom and an
ability to be in a community like this
where they may have had a dream of what
it was going to be like before they got
here and found that the reality wasn't
quite what they thought it was going to
be in many turn around and have to come
go back where they came from so you see
all of that sort of thing and then you
know you also have at the other end of
the spectrum folks who have made a
business of inviting all of these folks
who do very well in the business out to
big parties and they have after parties
you know the coming elbows with you know
all of the muckety-muck of glassblowing
artists and who knows what else you know
so it's a that's what I've experienced
and I don't have another state to
compare it to but it's a vastly
different terrain and growing up you
know you consumed in cannabis as a
teenager and a young adult
throughout the other parts of my life
the dabbing and glass alone is a
game-changer it's just like this oh my
you know it's it's not a whole different
way of doing that enjoying this cannabis
which you know a little bit neutral on I
like it sometimes but I don't make it
you know my main thing at all yeah so
we're at the end of it and we just got
some little short answer questions to
blast through quickly yes and no yeah
I'll give you two questions you can
answer with yes I'm sorry you don't have
to give me yes or no question so true
influence what's your favorite strain
right now I am pretty partial to the
genius haze that's a you know really
nice a new strain that we have
and Apollo 11 I mean I have to pick a
favorite right now so you know it's
we're playing around the princess Phase
two we haven't released it yet because
we don't have large enough quantities so
yeah you know that's tough Sophie's
Choice you know and what's one of your
favorite strains from the past that's
now lost you know lost huh it wasn't
anything known to anybody else but I I
grew you know across from when I was
working with this I says see that I just
thought it was encased thought as well
when I shared it with them I told them
what I had done and I'd taken that
Derbent eye and crust it to a skunk
number one and got these early maturing
purple abutted outdoor plants that were
absolutely killer in both flavor and
aroma and great potency I sold some to a
guy thanks I sold some to a guy who
worked in a restaurant and I only had
the bit that I sold him and he came back
to me asked me for Morris that I don't
have the same one I have something else
even though the second one was a very
good weed he came back to me complaining
later like you know that first one was
killer you know the second one what the
[ __ ] was that you know I'm like I'm
sorry dude you know it's perfectly
respectable weed it's just that that
first one was like this mind blowing
[ __ ] that I grew outdoors and I lost the
seeds from that so I I guess that would
have been one of the biggest I wish I
had those seeds today that that was
quite amazing if you could go to one
place geographically and one place in
time to get scenes where
Wow what a great question huh hey ma'am
back in time Julie I guess you know it
would be thrilling I guess is that go
back and be in Vietnam with the during
the war and Thailand or Cambodia or one
of those places and and get you know
have some adventure that I don't get
killed right but I have a bunch of
really exciting moments where you know
yeah the whole you know raiders of the
lost tomb' for a weekend or something
where i get laid three times and let me
know find a whole pile of cash and come
back with sacks of original seeds from
these amazing plants yeah I'll take that
thank you
so what's the worst strain in your
opinion or you know in maybe a more
politically sensitive way would be
what's the strain you just didn't agree
with personally the most hmm didn't
agree with me when I spoke something and
it just didn't really let me see about
that you know it's I don't want to try
and slag anybody's feet or anything but
I can't even say you know it would be
embarrassing to someone and it's just
stuff that's been sent to me and I grew
it out and said hmm oh right
at least then it kind of lets me know
what that person thinks is good you know
but and then it kind of confirms why
when I send people samples of my buzz
they raved and like oh my god I'm like
really it's that good seriously so but
yeah I wouldn't put single out anyone
strain or any any one person who has
sent me something that didn't work out
but you know those that would be the
basket I would turn to this to answer
that question and say this is something
that was a disappointment okay so what
did you want a disappointment or
something that just turned me off
altogether and I hate it I don't want to
smoke that pot yeah I know you're not
that exciting it's really a wonderful
answer there the dramatic answer it I
kind of do have a common denominator
feeling about smoking marijuana that you
know it's all getting high on marijuana
there are a lot of subtle differences
between the strains and valgus type of
thing but there's a common denominator
there where it's like did you get high
on pot yep I'm high on pot you know and
they all do that to you to some degree
and with some flavors of one thing or
another either psychoactivity or actual
taste bug palates but it's all pot you
know maybe I can simplify sometimes a
little too much but it's all pot you
know you smoke some hash it's different
than smoking flowers you spoke some
debits look different than the other
thing but there's you still know you
have a marijuana hide I'm sure you know
yeah so so final question to disappoint
to my point so yeah the final question
that are you gonna do any more photo
exhibitions and when probably not in any
time soon if the the bug strikes me and
I start to work a little bit more at it
but I've been lazy and photography ever
since leaving New York and you know I do
a bit here and there just for my own
pleasure and to keep gonna be so excited
I don't know yeah I'd like to think so
I'd like to think that I could take
stuff that I did and the style of
photography that I developed for myself
and I'm adapting to what we do here and
I've done that a few times in different
ways if I had work enough body of work
to put together to say like you know
here's some interesting spins on
cannabis photography then I had maybe a
dozen pieces to show or something I
might you know but it's way down the
list of priorities there's so much to do
all the time now listen so I think that
just about wraps yeah I love two things
self coming on the show and giving us
some awesome stories and a wealth of
knowledge there any comments or
shoutouts you wanted to make before we
wrap it up shout out to the grouse
stones folks and the dragonfly folks
green house green house hydro supply
down in Longmont on Main Street they've
been so good to us
you know High Times I guess I have to
give a shout out to Danny Danko he's
been hanging in there with me and
communicating with me recently we're
gonna get some articles written about us
in high times and some of my photography
will appear in the magazine as well so
watch for that sweet thanks and then
yeah
[Music]
so there you have it a huge thank you
again to the soul brothers green organic
garden solutions portray Australia
[Music]