[Music]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts this episode as
always was brought to you by 420
Australia your premier lifestyle company
as well as Johnston genetics makers of
awesome strains such as the grandmas
sugar cookies and the newly released Ron
Swanson couch in this episode we're
joined by Johnny of Johnson genetics who
fills us in on some of the details
around Johnson genetics as well as some
of his plans for the future and much
more so here we go he's a big welcome to
our guest Johnny from Johnson's genetics
and thank you so much for coming on the
show today pretty good so just jump
straight into it so the first question I
like to ask everyone growing up what
were some of the reasons you decided to
get into cannabis and what was your
first experience with it was it with
some friends was a with your uncle in
the backyard Wow
that goes way back I got into the
cannabis industry at a young age earlier
than 13 I don't remember my exact age I
started smoking just hanging out with
friends as everyone did it was known to
me that's what my dad did grow oh no you
know so it wasn't anything new to me I
wasn't doing it to repeal but that was
kind of the original time of whenever I
had my first instance with marijuana
just hanging out with Brent busted out a
joint and so I was just like yeah let's
go for it and I fell in love immediately
I think I have kind of a hyper mind and
settled settled me down and that that
was just amazing for me literally at
that moment that joined was
life-changing for me yeah
and so when you first started growing
what were some of the first strains you
were growing you mentioned that you your
dad was already doing it so did he have
kind of like a library or radio we you
guys kind of trialing out breeders at
the time and if so you know who was some
of the breeders around at that time you
know like when you dad was doing it over
with it no breeders yet there were
breeders but not in our local area we
were kind of it was extremely
underground we started in Oklahoma which
is completely no tower and state zero
tolerance and so breeding was not really
talked about among its groups of people
it was done basically back then as a
necessity to have the next round of
seeds to grow for the next year and we
basically had a lot of our more of my
dad had a lot of his old stuff that I
don't know all of the exact sources and
stuff but he's he's acquired them over
the years and whenever I first started
he didn't give me anything it was me
starting out on my own I didn't exactly
have like a free gift of genetics
priming but later on I did
let's see but he he picked up seeds from
all over he picked up seeds from Africa
a lot from Africa he spent 12 years in
Africa so yeah all over and then in
Middle East he it was basically that was
the real two main locations he acquired
from and then some through some South
American travel but he spent 12 years in
the Middle East in Africa so that's
where a lot of my influence comes from
is what his kind of choices were growing
growing out that I watched that's
incredible so did he kind of work these
lines out himself or where they just
kind of run as they were and probably
would have been pretty game-changer to
have afghan seeds at that time right I
mean I'm imagining this was probably
20-30 years ago
correct yes yeah that's one of our
biggest I guess you could say staples
that I have
in the storage of all is old-school
Afghan and that's I'm going to be
breaking that out very soon for my next
breeding projects in the next six months
or so I think but basically when he
started the seeds they were just
landrace essentially they he just
brought them back started and then we
would just have to like it would be each
year the best that would be selected
we'd keep the seeds that we ran from it
and then every year we'd progress with
it yep
so I mean what generation do you think
that would be at just you know like
since he's had him probably like you
know f20 or something or they won't work
that much no I don't know he's his
health isn't very good anymore he's he's
no longer doing anything himself but
when he stopped they would have probably
been in the team's possibly at least we
don't always grow the exact same thing
every single year but I would make sure
to get seed stock of most things for the
next year and that's kind of where that
love of that and watching things
progress change watching the genetics
mix with each other and you know from a
young age that's what inspired me to
want to start doing this then with the
switch of legalization here that kind of
just gave me the kick in the ass to get
it going yeah so it sounds like you were
pretty self-sufficient for quite a while
at what point did you decide to bring in
kind of you know some foreign genetics
so to speak maybe some clones from some
other people or you know you bought some
seeds from some other people or was it
really just working with your own stock
until then well I felt like a lot of
stuff I don't always just smoke what I
grow and I smoke things from other
readers I probably smoked something from
everybody out there but I have my
favorites and my favorite smokes
as a tip of the hat kind of respect to
the breeders that did breathe some of
the genetics of use that's the main
reason like I if they bred something
that I you know fall in love with I'll
probably be throwing something of mine
that I think would work out well with it
you know genetics come into it's mostly
as a show of respect to the other
readers yeah but yeah but and that
really started around the legalization
time for here maybe a year or two before
that you know cuz medically here it's
been you know quite open for a long time
so I've been working with other genetics
for a while I guess I could say yeah
well I mean let's talk about some of
your strains because in my opinion
almost all of them use what I would call
like a unique strain in that like one of
the parents is not used by really any
other breeders so we'll start off with
what I assume is probably the main study
in your garden the black sugar berry
I've found at least eight or ten or so
crosses that use it as the male it's
obviously pretty good in your opinion
but there's not a lot of info on it on
mine you know how would you describe it
to someone who is interested you know
like what's your sales pitch for the
black sugar berry as a male it was
pretty underground when it came out
that's why there wasn't a whole lot of
info out there I guess you'd say but
it's it's big winning traits or for the
most part just nice size colas good
purple hues with a good even base flavor
I guess you could say it's it's just an
all-around real winner in my opinion as
far as like production I guess you could
say and so I that was my main focus was
to use that larger blood pattern to add
into some of my other favorite genetics
to see if I could push that purple into
really was one of my big pushes which a
lot of them did take so another line
that I think is really interesting of
yours is the [ __ ] Valley line and as far
as I know I mean I'm probably wrong but
I can only off the top of my head think
of you and two other breeders who have
done a similar project where basically
they they work the one line out in
multiple different directions you know
like model different phenotypes and
right I was wondering what's the
inspiration behind this you know was it
like a pre-planned idea or was it just
like a happy mistake where you know
maybe you pop the first F ones and you
found that there were two fairly
different phenotypes and both were stand
out or did you have a plan from the
start and you knew the pocky valley was
something that was going to be worth
digging into mistake I I ran into two
fennels that when I was you know
selecting down to my always I'd select
down to my best and that's what makes it
to the next generation for breeding that
when I came down to making that choice I
just couldn't decide between two and I
out of I couldn't throw one away I
couldn't do it and so I just went the
tooter routes with that one number one
and number two the magenta and the white
as a lot of people call yeah and how
would you describe the two different
lines I've been able to find some
information that says you know I believe
it was the magenta is you describe it as
a little bit more of a medicinal line
but yeah how would you describe the two
lines and how they differ from each
other yeah the the magenta would be more
along the I don't know how you'd explain
it
medicating it was more heavy in the
medicating feel like heavy indica a fact
I guess you could call it it really
would sit you in your seat the the white
was a little more on the brighter flavor
note and not quite so couch locky and so
the the
variants of the smoke between the two it
just was completely different to me and
as was the flavor profiles so I just
went ahead and split them up and kept
running with them that's that was my
real basis for keeping to going cuz it
was a hard to see to get rid of one or
not yeah painstaking choices yeah so I
actually had a lot oh no no no keep
going please I was gonna say I've
actually had a lot of people who sin
thank you emails saying that they've ran
both and they proved they appreciated
the flavor effect of one more than the
other and they said thank you for giving
them the option of both you know so yeah
cuz at first I was kind of self battle
whether I was going to do that in one I
think it was a good choice I think is
it's something unique and something that
needs to be done more you know and I
yeah I definitely agree that um we're at
least in my mind it seems like you know
there's this seesaw so to speak of
breeding and you know and in my mind
there's kind of like flavor on one end
of it and yield and potency on the other
you know and I always tend to think you
know you're always kind of trying to
balance it out so I try to hit both if
you can make to that kind of sit well at
either end right right exactly so that
brings up kind of my next question a
little bit tied into that um on the pro
the website strain lynda.com or seed
find off basically it says the the [ __ ]
run was from world of seeds
I was wondering first of all is that
true because it seemed a little odd to
me and then to how does a site like that
interact with a breeder do they request
the information from you because I found
that like a lot of their stuff is wrong
so I tend to think that maybe they Scout
the information themselves and that's
why the errors are there or I think they
do they have touched base with me on a
couple of my things because kind of as
you say I have several things that are
very underground not much info on so
they have touched base with me on a few
things but and and actually the
world of seeds deal is correct I I did
have a good amount of world of seeds
patchy valley that was gifted to me and
i ran a good number of them and i found
a couple that i like that's where that
comes from
i believe so that was a couple years ago
but i but that do believe it was world
seeds yeah yeah i've actually had some
alright success with world of sees
myself but I've heard some conflicting
reports but i I also just thought given
what you said earlier about the the
Afghan land race stuff maybe it had been
stuff you doubted maybe collected no no
it is no I don't I don't want take
credit for milk it was I and I will say
you know honesty I ran a good number of
seats to find the ones that I found it
had I just had like a ten pack and pop
them I probably would have came out with
a complaint that I ran more than that
and but I did find what I considered to
be some good winners so it's you know
with numbers you'll you'll find winner
yeah but yeah sure yeah so on to what I
think he's maybe kind of your new main
breeding project the pine tar cush all
sorry that it was used in the making of
the Ron Swanson so back to the Sun the
pine tar cush was made by Tom Hill this
is a strain which is actually been quite
a demand for a while a lot of people
have been calling for its resurgence was
that part of the inspiration for you
working it into the Ron Swanson line
like did you think to yourself I'm gonna
make this new strain and I want the pine
tar cush to be a part of it because
there's certain traits that I'm looking
to put into this new stud for example
well there I wasn't aware that there was
a very much of a movement going on with
it I it was a favorite of mine I had
been growing it for a couple years just
for personal smoke and I at some point I
just decided hey and I well I started
running it outdoors instead of indoors
and I was getting
very large plants 910 feet tall on
average and you know several feet around
and so I wanted to take it it had a full
bushiness where you know it but all the
way down the branch very tight and so I
I wanted to take it with a couple of my
other strains and I did several readings
with there only a couple were released
but I I just really enjoyed it
personally as a smoke and it was one of
my kind of personal pushes in my
genetics I do about 50/50 half of what I
would like to see bred and half of kind
of what I feel like the industry would
like to see bred so it's kind of a
balance I don't know like forcing people
at point only what the strains that I
would like to smoke so I try to give a
good variance I guess yeah and so in
your mind did you just kind of think
that the black sugarberry given how you
mentioned earlier that it it adds those
nice collars did you think that would
just kind of complement the pine tar or
was it for different reasons you chose
the black sugar berry to may with it
yeah I was trying to make a super plant
the way that the pine tar grew for me
consistently for a couple years and my
love for the black sugar berry I I knew
that they had worked well together I
just didn't intend to I guess I didn't
know that I would like the Ron Swanson
as much as I did it turned out to be a
long term personal favor of mine yeah
how would you describe that to anyone
who is interested in just the pure Ron
Swanson Ron Swanson by selfie it tends
to grow very much like the pine tar with
a heavier lemon line influence it's
whereas my the fennel I was running up
the pine tar was very floral
it had a I don't you know you understand
floral flavor you know it right yeah
yeah it was very for and
it kind of shocked me that it came out
so lemon lemon lime being bred with the
black sugar berry but it it translates
real well pure Ron Swanson and if you
ever run live resin it's one of the most
flavorful live resins I've ever smoked
no attitude yeah so in the case of maybe
the Ron Swanson or just any any of your
own projects where you feel they really
stand out have you ever considered the
idea of maybe doing like a deeper
breeding project maybe maybe a back
cross or taking something to the f2 f3
or do you think that a lot of your
strains are kind of more suited as F
ones well actually I don't post a lot of
my old breeding but most of my stuff
when it's released as f2 or f3 the there
aren't there have been a few that have
been f1 breedings but for the most part
they are f2 or f3 I am actually about to
start and have one only project that
will allow people with a wider variety
of options you know like that kind of
lottery tickets seed yes some refer to
it but they would be sold at a
discounted rate you know I'm trying to
get people that were they can feel like
they have something that's a little more
special than other people may have like
that's what the whole reason I do is a
limited edition I could run a lot more
seeds and sell a lot more seeds but I
think when you know people can trade
cuts of something that's a little rarer
I think that adds a little more I don't
know prestige to the strains themselves
free every breeder yeah of course I mean
you can look at examples from say the
Brothers Grimm with Apollo 11 and 13
where you know I think they're pretty
good examples of how you know the
limited stock is kind of added to the
the mystique of them right it's
interesting you say that about how their
f2s do you choose to not list on because
you know like a lot of companies will
you know these are f2s I've never seen
that on energy any of your packaging do
you purposely choose not to do that I
just I guess I've never considered it
I'm fairly old-school I have I have
designers that do most of the packaging
design for me and stuff and I basically
send them a list of what I want on there
and that never has been a part of what
I've sent them I am gonna be redoing my
packaging soon though which would
probably include what generation it
would be yeah I think it would be it'd
be cool to include that because um it
kind of makes sense that you said they
were f2f threes because I've always
noticed you know a lot of consistency
with your stock I guess the next
question would be though in terms of
that limited-edition and limited
releases back to one of my favorite
strains from you the it's such a
mouthful the granddaddy platinum berry
cookies this is one that came out
initially and then I've seen it on one
other seed banks since then but as you
said you don't really restock it too
much when we see this with your strains
is that due to the fact that year you
are just pretty much following that
limited edition route or maybe some of
them you just later on decided I'll look
that strain doesn't really stand up to
some of the others we've got now I'm not
gonna redo it for that reason it's a
mixture of both actually it gives me it
doesn't lock me into something that I
don't feel confident about breeding in
the future if people like it then they
had it chant get it well it was limited
edition but it also gives me time and
room to work on something new but along
with this f1 line that I'll be coming
out with in the near future I'm also
going to be coming out with a classics
line which will be the granddaddy
platinum part berry cookies grandma's
sugar cookies and a few other strains
that have been requested heavily for
returns so those will become
back out and that's part you know though
then those will be less of a limited
edition release they'll still be
numbered as of right now I limit
everything no matter no matter the
strain I won't sell more than two
hundred and fifty packs of a strain on
the classic line and the f1 line I will
probably both allow those to be 500
packs maximum so they'll still be
limited I just not quite as limited yeah
a little more available but maybe the
people who are after it right and that's
that's part of my my plan is you know
there's certain people that want say
granddaddy Platinum Park Berry cookies a
known and trusted strain but it's not
available to you know but if it'll be in
the future within the year probably I'll
be dropping and actually another drop of
those yeah fantastic
so moving on
you've got your CBD diesel and this is
kind of a broader topic I wanted to talk
about when you were creating your CV DD
so obviously you were probably thinking
something along the lines of I would
like to make a CBD strain what type of
lab testing goes into the making of a
CBD strain or if there wasn't any how
much kind of testing on the but itself
do you have to do because I've as much
as people might kind of cringe at this
idea I have spoken to a breeder before
who said they didn't use a lot of lab
testing to make their CBD Australian
like they did at the very last step but
up until that point they had just gone
on kind of you know anecdotal results
from people of you know what what is the
most medicinal in your opinion and they
said that they kind of got to a good
point using that method but a lot of
people would kind of disagree and say no
you should be using lab tests every step
of the way you know how did your project
work you know what kind of side of that
argument do you fall on really have an
argument there I dunno where I lie as in
the testing for myself I run final stage
tested flour product but I start with
known genetics I work with few
dispensaries here that
trying to put out you know medicine for
the patients and they give me a cut of
something that they have that they know
what it tests at and then I work with it
alter it change it for what we want and
then send it back to be tested you know
multiple batches to find out which Fenno
and then we keep progressing on from
there I've actually been working with a
guy here in town know if he wants me to
call him out my name and I don't have a
permission yet so I'm not going to but
he's got an extremely high CBD extremely
low THC
canna tonic that I'm working with that I
really think is going to put out some
good medicine for the patient's know and
so nice sorry and so what's your kind of
you dream for your CBD lines you just
want to make a really good CBD strain
and kind of leave it there for people to
do what they want with it or are you
thinking no there's a specific kind of
illness I'm actually looking to target
so I might refine it towards that for
example well I
I'm actually the reason they to get into
it and if my dream come true I'd be able
to come up with an amazing CBD strain or
multiple strains some high THC V strains
something that will be free to anyone
that needs it any dispensary that wants
to provide it to a patient any grower
that wants to grow for themselves that's
the true medicine side of the industry
and I don't want to be a pharmaceutical
company ever I want to be a helper of
people so if that could ever be free to
the people whether it's from me or other
growers or whoever that would that would
be my dream for the CBD field my CBD
project says if now have basically been
to start my working in it and try
inspire some of the other people around
me that hey you know we're not after you
know 35 percent THC but that can be a
goal but there's other stuff that you
can be doing also
yeah exactly death so um your your made
a og this is an interesting one to me
because a few people have done a similar
route to you where they decide to leave
one of the parents kind of non document
and you know like they're they're not
gonna fully release the details of it
what what in your mind is the reason for
doing this it obviously adds a bit of
mystique you know I think in my mind the
first person who comes to mind is you
know the cookie fan with the Girl Scout
cookies that's probably the most notable
one where we don't know the full
genetics do you think that it's a little
bit of a marketing move and if so I
think it's a good one um but is it maybe
something else for you maybe maybe you
don't quite know the father what's the
reason for that no it's actually like
kind of a it was a marketing move but in
a way that you wouldn't think there have
been several genetics that have been
swindled from me I'll call it I won't
call people thieves on that but and I
don't want them getting the credit
locally to me so I just I sometimes keep
that certain things secret to not blow
up the strain that they're holding yeah
so it's it it's not for my market being
it's for like anti marketing to the
people who have my strains that
shouldn't have them we search a few ones
that I didn't one out there and they're
out there so I just don't give them the
credit so they don't you know yeah and
so that kind of brings us to an
interesting point what is your thoughts
on sharing of genetics and I guess more
specifically for someone who buys your
genetics maybe even a future breeder
well what would be your kind of your
protocol or you know your recommendation
for them for using yours or someone
else's strange do you think that as long
as they ask you first you know like hey
I'm gonna make this strain I'd like to
use this that's fine with you or do you
think nah they don't even need to ask or
you know what's your thoughts on it I
think asking is polite but people are
gonna do what they want to do and as far
as like I was gonna be kind of a
smartass and answer your your protocol
call question all they got to do is
in the ground that's all they have to do
but like I said asking is polite I
appreciate it when people ask me and I
feel honored when somebody feels like
breeding with my stock
I'm never pissed about it that's you
know there's nothing but love in the
industry it's a plant we're all just
working to try to make it better
yeah and so I've spoken to another
breeder before and they said I think
that people should should try to make it
their own in a way you know like if
you're gonna breed with my work take it
to the f2 first and try to refine a
characteristic you like about it first
and then you've got more of a claim to
say that you know like this is my strain
I've actually done you know I take it to
the f2 and then use it to make your new
strain how do you feel about that or do
you think like now if someone just wants
to use my strain straight from the
generation they get it I'm okay with
that I think putting work into it is as
part of paying the dues and calling
yourself a breeder if you just throw
pollen on a plant you successfully bred
something but I would call that breeding
yet you know put in a little put in a
few groves get it stabilized a little
bit in what direction you want and then
let people know about it yeah okay
ci so people shouldn't announce the the
new best breeder in the world when
they've made their first f1 get on the
mind of a lot of breeders it must be
really annoying yeah it happens a lot
and nowadays just more ore than ever I
remember when you could count the
breeders out there on two hands you know
now they're theirs you need pages on the
internet to list the breeders yeah so
how do you know sorry going yeah I was
gonna say how do you manage to kind of
stay relevant in the industry in your
mind do you just take the approach of
I'll let my work speak for itself or do
you feel that as you kind of reference
there are just so many people breeders
at least
it's kind of hard to get lost in the sea
of you know marketing almost what do you
think is required these days for a
breeder do you think you know as you
mentioned before the interview do you
think having a social media presence is
like a good or a bad thing or what do
you think these days in 2016 it's
definitely a good thing I wish that I
could be better at it I'm kind of old
school I don't get on the internet much
I don't serve I recently figured out
what a meme was so I'm not real big on
the internet stuff but and I'm going to
work on at it like that's something no
to the other growers the people that
want knowledge about my strains that you
know connect with the fan base I've got
to get better at it
posting pictures is not that hard and
answering people's questions is not that
hard so I'm going to get better at it
but in this day and time it is it's
almost a necessity I could up here for
money or fame or anything like that
I'm here it's a behind-the-scenes
breeder that is you know doing the real
work in my mind to get this industry
headed towards towards a even more
positive progression yeah so do you like
to go to you know like the cups and the
events and to meet the guests or do you
think that's something I'd like to do
but I don't do it quite yet no we we've
had a couple booths at because I haven't
competed yet I don't know call it nerves
or not wanting to be disappointed but I
haven't competed yet so I'm hoping that
whenever I throw something in I'll get
it cut my first go-around I highly doubt
that that would make me feel good though
yeah sorry meeting but oh no you're good
I enjoy meeting the fans the
customers the growers people that come
up to the booth and don't buy anything
and talk for 20 minutes that's some my
favorite people I'm not there for sales
I'm there to meet people and hang out
with people with like minds you know
yeah for sure I've actually I was gonna
say I've spoken to similarly in these
stories they're all the same breed I
just don't have a their name to give out
but um they they were saying that
winning a cup as a breeder is not the
be-all end-all because you know like the
the cut that wins a cup it could just be
like a one in a million I like that
strain could be garbage overall but like
that one being was really good you know
what I mean yeah so I think that was
kind of saying as a breeder yeah it's
it's not the biggest reflection of your
skills as a breeder that definitely
that's why I haven't competed there's at
least to a small extent I want to pay my
dues in the industry a lot of people are
like who's this new guy we're not
actually that new we're just new to the
mainstream scene I guess you could say
we're pretty leery like I said we came
from a zero tolerance state and you know
over a decade ago though I moved to
Colorado and that's kind of opened my
mind and opened the doors to this yeah
so what was what was it like to
transition to a full-time breeder as
your job especially I guess when it when
you're in that legal environment you
know was there a kind of a defining
moment where you just thought yeah now
is the time this is what I want to do or
did you just kind of stumble into it
there was well I guess it's a mixture of
both
I've always bred I remember breeding my
first personal like for me growing I
probably like 18 years old I started I'm
now 34 but that was when I started off
on my own I'm sorry I'm smoking a blunt
right now and I told the guys side track
hey basically in between working I
decided hey
I could start now and start putting my
full attention to this and really kind
of make something not even for myself I
figured you know it could be something
for my children as as the u.s. kind of
started changing its laws and things
started opening up I figured it might be
good to put my name out there as like
hey you know this is what we've been
doing for a while we're ready to
announce it and be out in the industry
with everyone else there was a moment
and that was basically when everyone's
seen everything starting to come online
that was I decided like hey it's just
time to put your name out there and then
and I was going through a lot of flack
from family from friends everyone was
like man you're gonna get arrested I
said you know somebody's got to do it we
got to let everyone know this is the you
know what we got to do yeah and have you
ever had any run-ins with the law after
that point like after the you know like
they kind of looked like things we're
becoming less and less strict so to
speak no I've not had any altercations
or issues at all
and where I'm at locally though things
are pretty relaxed Colorado's very
relaxed on the marijuana scene so as
long as you mind your P's and Q's and do
what the state tells you to do there's
you know nothing to fear yeah
and so the johnston farm you guys
organic or synthetic and what's your
reasons behind that well through at our
location it's organic but we do have
other growers that grow by other means
everything from everything from
aeroponics hydroponics and more so i've
seen my strains tested locally you know
amongst my grower friends before they
hit the mark I see what they do on
almost like every setup with every
growing feeding
schedule you could imagine almost and
which one do you think do planets come
out the best in or do you think it's
that may be a grower by grower basis I
would probably say VY grower basis I
recommend growers when they asked me
what nutrient line to grow if I asked
them whatever they're comfortable with
that's the main thing having experience
with the line or knowing the line and
knowing how to run it that's gonna give
you the best success I've seen amazing
buds grown every method my personal
favorite is organic but yeah including
insecticides that no insecticides my
seeds like even though they would be an
expensive treat I will compete Bordeaux
Papa pack in their mouth and chew him up
and eat them they're quite healthy I do
with them yeah my own slope maintains
his defense will always be that it's its
bird feeding it is actually years and
years ago I started thing on a I think
it was on a UK chat forum that I was on
and I started something called Operation
bird drop and I was just promoting
everyone to put their seeds whatever
spare seeds they had in their bird
feeders and you know if everyone did
that could you imagine what the wild
marijuana population would be yeah you
couldn't you couldn't have something
that was you could make it illegal if it
was on every street corner literally
yeah they'd struggle it works
I had pot plants all up and down my
neighborhood cool so just going back to
that point you made about you know no
insecticides keeping it nice and healthy
have you ever noticed a difference in
the quality of seeds produced from a
plant that is say treated you know
organically really healthy the way you
do it versus say maybe one that's not
grown with the same love you know not
the same at end
have you ever noticed that the seeds
maybe from yours come out better or
maybe worse than the other you know the
less well maintained plant and I can't
say specifically but comparing my seeds
my average seeds to a multitude of other
genetic company seeds I see a size
difference and that to me speaks for the
health of the seed you know a teeny
teeny tiny seed that's not well colored
to me you know it's just not as healthy
as a big fat plump you know properly
colored seed and I don't know if that's
coming from use of chemicals or not
that's why I can't really say but I do
see a size difference between mine and
some other companies not all other
companies there are definitely some good
breeders out there yeah so um recently
we've seen that there's a bit of a crowd
mentality in terms of hating on blue
dream I'm sure you're pretty familiar
with it yeah what what do you think
about this and what do you think about
the idea of like the straw it's blue
dream hate today but like what will it
be tomorrow and the reason why I asked
is because you know you breed with the
Girl Scout cookies and I'm a firm
believer that one day Girl Scout cookies
will be on that bandwagon with blue
dream or maybe blue dream won't be on it
anymore but you know what I mean people
will be hiding on it do you think that's
already started anything that gets real
big starts to get too much positive
attention someone out there is gonna
speak out and bring some negative
attention towards it and then mob
mentality you know somebody's always
gonna be there to jump on the bandwagon
that's really all it is in my opinion
yeah so do you just kind of disregard
that when you're breeding and like so
like I guess maybe the bigger question
is are you not scared to breed with
certain strains based on maybe how
they'll be perceived in the future are
you just like nah if it's good today I'm
gonna use it yeah not at all I there are
the only things that I have like steered
clear from are some some strains that
have some
like outrageous name aims or kind of
names I wouldn't want to keep going
that's the only thing I've stopped not
because of people's views on what the
strain will be now or in the future
though no ok and by when you say the
names of strains you means like maybe
the more hard drug referenced ones
correct yeah I don't want to name one
out but yeah yeah yeah how should I keep
a positive vibe or you know or at least
a not a negative vibe yeah
yeah so like the name with the strain
carries a little bit of like I don't
want to call it karma but you know it's
the name associated with it
yeah you don't want some to happen name
so how do you feel about people who make
f ones giving the strains names before
they've even kind of grown them out I
guess it's maybe ties into a breeder
type of question but if you're a breeder
and you make a new f1 and you're just
giving it out to your friends straight
away you haven't even tested it yourself
and you're giving it this you know some
crazy you know purple spaceship or you
know just some some crazy name or
whatever do you think that that's like a
bit of a miss service to the people who
like you have done the work like in my
opinion if you're just goofing around
you make an f1 I don't think you should
really name it until you've like you
know like I think a name should kind of
reflect some of the characteristics of
the strain like do you think the same or
do you think like now you might just
have a hunch before you've even grown it
out and you know what I mean I
definitely agree especially like you may
name something this cool last name that
and now you put it paired with this
stupid plant that you grew and now that
cool names taken you know you should
have saved that for a cooler plant yeah
that's a good point yeah yes
save the cool names wait till you know
it's a legit plant and then give it its
badass name so yeah so if we looked at
on a typical Johnson breeding project
what would you list as in and this might
be a hard one in in order of priority
what are the traits you're breeding for
do you
you value you know flavor as the utmost
priority or potency or you know bag
appeal like we're how do you kind of
rate these traits in terms of what
you're aiming for I always throw one in
that my number one is one that I never
hear anyone name its structure the
structure of the plan itself is my
number one
hey having a healthy plant body is my
first that that's what I'm looking for
once once I have that I look for you
like you say that Holy Trinity of like
flavor potency yield that's that's a
hard one to balance and those three
obviously come right there in second
third and fourth my favorite though
would be taste the flavor is number one
for me
potency would be second and yield would
be third in that order of those three
and so that's basically how I judge all
of them now certain strains they get
restructured in that in the priority
order they're yeah mostly for like
medical stuff and so I was like a bit of
a follow-up do you think that kind of
how I mentioned earlier with that kind
of cease or an allergy do you think you
always are kind of trading off some
traits for the other or do you think it
is possible to kind of get that the try
factor in one or if you do it's very
much like a one in a million
yes you can you can find that perfect
one or what will be right then at that
moment seem perfect but for the most
part be plus percent of the time it's a
seesaw effect as you say you're giving
and taking but you will find every once
in a while that one plant that just even
amongst all its peers it tastes better
yields better you know effects better
everything you will find some but it's
rare yeah what type of testing do you
like to do on a strain ideally like you
what you know what
numbers would you ideally like to run
before you're confident a strain can go
to market at least 100 le at least 100
sometimes I don't get happy with my
breeding project and I start over I've
I've had to run things you know over and
over to redo my breeding to a different
they know and start over throw the seeds
away I won't let them out and so
sometimes for one strain to get out
there it'll be a lot more than 100 it
could be three or four hundred that I've
ran to get that strain going in out
there yeah
and during this stage where you've got
these nice big numbers is that where
you're also potentially looking to maybe
find a male for future breeding projects
or is that a different project and maybe
even more numbers than a hundred no I do
in the hundred I look for both always
the veiny plant any planning of any
strain that I do I look for a winner
male and a winner female or at least
even a few you know but I'm sourcing
down in the end result to one or two but
I I do always search for the males while
I'm running numbers with the females yes
once they're sixth separately I don't
want people to get confused and so
what's it like for you as kind of you
know I'm not gonna say a smaller breeder
but maybe as you a lesser-known breeder
what's it like for you to interact with
the the big seed banks you know
obviously you gear is on attitude which
is really cool how what was that process
like to get on there because a lot of
breeders I speak to say it's actually a
harder than you think to get on there so
you seem to have gotten over that hurdle
what's it like for you to interact with
the seed banks and the distributors and
you know all of that behind the end of
the seed business in a short word weird
new to me but it's it was it all came
real fast I had started uh giving seeds
away
like I said I'm not I wasn't ever there
for the money I didn't even expect to
gain the attention that I did I was just
doing what I wanted to do and giving
people seeds and then people were asking
me how how they buy my seeds and I
didn't have any avenues to send them to
I didn't even have anyway so I told them
well if if there's a demand for it hit
your seed banks up and ask them to hit
me up and so in the end and quite
quickly actually several seed banks
including attitude we're contacting me
saying how do we carry your gear and
then I we just you know we had to work
out the business side of things but as
far as dealing with the distributors and
stuff they everyone contacted me awesome
so yeah what would be your advice for
someone who's in a similar position to
what you were before you were selling
would you just say yeah just get your
stuff out there you get a good name and
ask people to hit up the the banks yeah
bill you know pay some dues first get
some credit to your name do the right
thing that's you know number one don't
don't be in there just to try to get on
attitude to try to make some money and
stuff because in my opinion karma will
catch up it will you know things won't
work out something will trip up along
the way
just do what you like doing if you
really want to be a breeder cuz that's a
long time consuming thing and you got to
be very patient it's you know just stick
with it
if you put in the work the work will
show you know people want to grow those
seeds everybody else doesn't have the
time to do all that work to try to get
you know quality seeds for other people
to grow yeah exactly
okey dokey so just going back to one of
the points we spoke about earlier
you mentioned that you know f1 seeds
being the kind of you know this lottery
idea of a seed a fairly well-known
breeder made a statement a breeding
panel at a few years ago and basically
said we make F ones because that's what
the market dictates that really sounds
like it doesn't sound entirely
do you think that's the truth do you
think people want F ones because I
always say to people you know a clone
only isn't three different phenotypes
it's just one you know so what yep
no I agree 100% stability is king there
is a place in the market for F ones now
because people do want something
different and and that's why I decided
that here in the future I'm going out
with F one specific line stabilities
came though the work that the breeders
put in to to make you know the strains
come out the same it's that's what
really shows a breeders skill and gives
gets my appreciation there's some
breeders out there that have put in many
years of art work to achieve the
stability so so to say that only F once
is that all that people need that almost
like discredit all the years of like the
founding fathers of breeding yeah and so
what would be one of your little tips or
tricks you're willing to share for your
selection you know when you're looking
for a male what's one of your go-to
techniques you know a lot of people they
they love to go to their stem Rob what's
what's one of your tips for all our
viewers on how to pick a good male well
the stem Rob is you know classic but in
my opinion also generic it's I look for
white it's hard to explain I kind of
like since the plant and look at it and
I look at the plant as a whole how is
its flower production yeah
how's its flower production like the
density of its clusters the structure of
the plant as a whole like robustness of
the individual branches they look for
you know what you would picture in a
male of any breeding program of other
animals I look for a good stud healthy
big robust for its strain profile young
well smells can be varied I trust
usually with what I'm working with I
kind of know the smell profile with what
I'm working with so I'm for my breedings
I'm looking at its structure a lot yeah
so kind of on an idea you just picked up
on is breathing a art or a science to
you you know like like sort of put it in
you know the the most extreme terms do
you think a robot with a set of traits
to look at would be able to breed as
well as a human or do you think no
there's always that that kind of that
hunch that vibe which makes maybe a
breeder
the difference between a good and a
great breeder no I don't think robot
would be able to come close they would
be able to grow a plant but they
wouldn't have the same love connection
where you could feel with what the plant
needs what the plant you know you could
see capabilities and plants that a robot
wouldn't be able to there's no
connection there's no love with the
machine like that I definitely feel a
deep connection with all my plants so I
for me personally it's a got a huge art
form to it or at least some form of
connection between the growers or
breeder or you know the plant yeah so
how do you feel about um kind of these I
don't know I don't think it's the case
in America but in Australia for example
there's proposals of having these really
big kind of you know almost like your
tobacco conglomerates like you fill up
Morrison's would be the ones owning and
operating these big warehouses producing
the medical weed for the Australian
market do you think in that situation
where you say got you know one grower
looking after a thousand plants you know
obviously they can't give the love to
each plant that you would be able to on
a smaller scale would you think that
that would really impact the the quality
or do you think that at the end of the
day it may be a little bit you know it's
not going to impact it as much as you
might think to be looking after tons of
plants and to not be able to give them
that little bit of extra love well I
think when that starts
it will start at some point I think that
the people that are doing it will have
enough money to figure out the systems
to run it will they won't have the
connections with the plants because the
numbers are there it'll be a
commercialized product it won't be like
what is in Colorado right now that's
more like a craft product like a
microbrew of beers there's will be the
you know the natural light and so yeah
I'm sorry going no go ahead I'm sorry
yeah well I was just gonna say so with
just kind of you just spurred the idea
the natural light you know how do you
feel endure rates to outdoor in terms of
the medicinal quality you know it's that
time of the year where I me personally
I'm seeing Instagram flooded with
pictures of how outdoor is better than
indoor blah blah blah you know I don't
really care for the debate myself but do
you think it is just like a baton thing
or do you think there is a legitimate
argument to be had everything has its
pros and cons with outdoor you you can
have a longer season as far as one
individual plant have the right amount
of light and space for it to grow but
indoors you you can have a more isolated
controlled environment and you can do
things outdoors that you can't do so
they both have their pros and cons I do
I appreciate both I can't say that I
like one better than the other I do a
lot of work indoors but I also have
greenhouses so we we appreciate both its
you just have you have different perks
and different downfalls for each one yep
and so we often hear people talk about
this idea of how with hybridized strains
- we need to go back to our land race
roots and we need to you know start
fresh
this idea has been around for ages D and
you kind of referenced earlier that
you're gonna
yourself do you think the general
mainstream will actually do it though
like everyone always talks about it but
no one ever actually does it also it
seems do you think that we will just
keep hybridizing I think it'll stay
getting more and more hybridized and
then at some point the land races will
be looked at as a prized possession I
don't think that most you know the
profitable breeding companies out there
are looking at restarting with new land
races and taking up parts of their grow
for that it's I don't think it is that
profitable but it's something I'm going
to be doing and look forward to I go eat
I'm old school like I said I go back to
my roots I watched black-and-white
movies all the time so I have more
appreciation for the old school so I
think it'll be good to go back to the
roots of some of the old genetics that I
have and bring them back out and a lot
of people like some of the old school
smokes I get people all the time saying
you know where's the old weed at this
stuff's too strong that's not it's not
me personally but some of the old-timers
say that and you know the why are we
gonna try to you know not grow for a
certain group of people that still want
something that used to bring them back
to that era of thought
yeah well I've actually thought about
this topic a little bit myself and I on
a personal note think that whether it's
consciously or subconsciously the the
the brand TGA seeds I think they are
kind of filling that nation away because
I mean it's my opinion and I think a lot
of people's opinions that their weed
isn't the most potent but it's really
flavorful and so you can kind of you
know like smoke a bit more of it without
getting knocked about and so I think
it's interesting that we are seeing that
the rise of I think it is probably
subconsciously in their case but um you
know like breeders filling quite
specific niches and maybe not even
realizing it right and that's the way it
you know everything works everything by
it's a way every puzzle has its place
every puzzle piece has its place whether
it knows it goes there or not but as far
as me I I try to make a lot of my moves
and breeds intentional whether they all
come out across that way I don't know
but it but I try and then on you'll see
here soon because everything will be
breeding except for the f1 line
everything will have an average
percentages for its potency on the on
the seed package because I'm doing
everything is getting heavily tested now
so you'll see some here in the future
that will probably be lower percentage
numbers and that will be on purpose
that'll be in in reminiscence of the old
school strains because some of them
aren't gonna be that high and I'm gonna
bring them up to what I can but I'm not
gonna try to exclude the old school
traits that they had so um so you're
stuck on sour is a new strain you've got
and that uses the Sour Diesel in it what
are some of the other you know clone
only slash elite clones you know we
spoke about the pine type course earlier
what are some of the other coins out
there that you would love to work with
in breeding projects you know I consider
them to be quite good and worth working
with that's hard there's a few that my
buddies have that are just old unknown
genetics they call them whatever but
they're not you know anything no they're
just stuff they've ran for a long time
there's a sin sin d99 clone locally that
I had for a moment and I didn't breed to
it and I lost it you know you know I've
done some shirt um but I never got
around beating it and I'll still want to
someone get back to it and then there's
a lime Chernobyl cut around locally that
I'm about to start working with
hopefully it's lime Oh was that you
talking about
I don't know I don't I'm not real
up-to-date on all the people in those
like you know
yeah I'm pretty is the golden ticket
thinner I think that's what they called
it the golden ticket yes within the past
I have the seed stock that I used when I
worked with it and I'm gonna try to get
it back again and do some more work with
it so I can stabilize something I like
and get it out to the public because I
like that one a lot
yeah for sure so you know just having
mentioned the Cindy 99 before being
friends with Duke that made me realize
who's a breeder you would like to do a
collaboration with them and do something
with them as opposed to just you know
buy a packet and go from there right
well I mean I have I guess you'd call
them heroes that so many heroes in the
industry I there's a good handful or two
breeders out there that would love to
work with just it would it would make my
day you know I bet really man feel free
to lease some off if you wanted to well
there's Brothers Grimm would be a cool
one there's what is it called I for a
while I wanted to do something with
Moxie yep yeah they're not old old
heroes of mine or anything you know
they're know like that but I had respect
for what they were doing for some of
their concentrates that are coming up
I'm always involved in the concentrate
field so I got a hold to Center
concentrates and then you know I had
kind of thought like me and I'd like to
work with yes so sorry I'm just gonna
say for a lot of people who don't know
there'll be some people to know that
Moxie is are a seed seller and they do
pretty good seeds but they also
primarily do a lot of concentrates over
in the States
from what I've heard it's some of the
it is yeah it's very good and so I would
really like to work with them like old
old school like some shanty baba action
I would like you know some of the I
don't want to name out some of the
larger companies I'd like to work with
because it would probably never happen
and I'd look dumb but like it would be
worth it would be cool to work with rare
daintiness I'm like it seems like when
I'm at the cups I'm always like near
home at the booths and we never talk
really or anything but I don't know you
know a lot of a lot of the people here
it seems like or had their real clipped
up and it's hard to get into the clicks
like you're not cool with certain crews
or something they don't you show you any
attention and I don't go out there
putting myself out there to get any
attention anyway so it's kind of hard
like I don't really talk to that many
readers around I'm pretty pretty I'm
pretty much a hermit I just stay to
myself and breed yeah but yeah there's I
would be in heavy respect to work with a
lot of people I just leave it there like
I get my list would go on because I love
a lot of readers yeah well I mean just
in terms of that clique eNOS I mean even
from overseas I can kind of observe that
quite clearly I was talking to a friend
the other day and he lives in LA and he
said he couldn't get a certain cut that
I comment which one it was but I thought
it was it would be pretty easy to get it
living in LA I need echoed the same
sentiments you know like our nights it's
still very cliquey as to you know you
can get what and who helped you out I
thought that was a bit so yes it is
because I'm not that way I I want to
work with people that are like-minded to
me there's other companies out there
that have things that I would like to
breed to that you know I just don't
because I don't know some of the some of
the companies are a little too big
they've already got their own style
don't need to bring any more attention
to them you know yeah buy something of
theirs so
what's one strain that even you yourself
or just you know his society the
community in general has lost that you
really wish you had back and then why
that's the easy one skunk
good good skunk is hard to find I mean
that was like the original and now it's
lost like that it seems outrageous in my
mind I mean it's not i'm elite lee lost
but as far as the main string goes like
he you know scones just not really that
heard of yeah it it needs to be there
more Hayes's as well like Hayes's need
to make a comeback skunks need to make a
comeback that's yeah and so did you ever
get a chance to grow the roadkill skunk
I know no unfortunately no I did it big
dream of mine but never happened yeah
he's interested in asking people about
that one it's it's got you know one of
those ones where everyone's interested
in it but there's so little information
about it well there's there's a little
old lady that lives down the road from
me and uh I got when I go for walks I
see her sitting out on her porch every
morning and she keeps she keeps the hope
alive for me because she he's got a
pretty large greenhouse in her backyard
and it reeks of skunk and some high
quality skunk so it's still out there
very slick I mean she's a little little
old frail gray-haired lady and uh she's
she's keeping the skunk alive over there
at least I mean you can walk a few
blocks on the right day and you'll see
four or five people sitting outside in
the front yard token a bowl it's pretty
funny yeah it's it's not supposed to be
that out in the open but it is if you
look if you keep an eye out yeah and so
you mentioned earlier you're gonna pack
up your packaging and have things like a
lab percentages on them and stuff this
kind of brings me to two questions one
how do you feel about lab percentages
you know like do you feel like
a lot of people I've spoken to said that
the the industry is very driven by
percentages and so it's easy for you
know them to be inflated just for
purposes of wholesale and selling them
whatnot so you know one how do you feel
about that I feel like the industry
concentrates on it too much I can sit
down with anyone that talks about
percentages and without some thing that
tastes good smells good smokes good and
makes them just as happy as any high 20s
you know that you can pull out yeah I
was gonna say when someone says they've
got some 30% weight you what do you
think I don't know how I feel about that
that's why I said hi 20 yeah I would
like to see paperwork and I would like
to do research afterwards to see what
that laboratory how their testing
methods are and stuff yeah cool and so I
guess when we expect to see your future
packaging we're not gonna see mid 30s on
it or anything like that 30s I'm gonna
have to send some more in to get tested
again no yeah I don't I don't see that
happening on anybody's near future but
the you know I'm gonna post realistic
numbers I'm gonna post an average number
I can't post 20 3.87 you know on the
packaging but I'll post a realistic
number I'll do multiple and I'll
probably Instagram a picture all the
test sheets just you know for the public
cuz that's unfortunately the industry is
concentrated on numbers but so I'm gonna
give them those numbers but I'm not
going to strive to try to shoot for only
the highest of high numbers I'm gonna be
testing as well and so you know that's
that's my big my big focus is flavor
yeah for sure so the follow-up to that
was I don't know if you've seen it but
there's a few breeders now who have kind
of this template for their new strain
it's got a lot of really good info on it
you know it gives like the number of
phenotypes what you can maybe expect
from each phenotype as well as your
general flowering times and how much
it'll stretch would you ever consider
giving information like this I mean I
would assume that based on the work you
do you know like growing out the strains
to test it you would have a rough idea
of say the number of phenotypes there
are in each cross and what to expect
from each do you think that that
information is overkill or you'd maybe
be interested in including that in the
future I think in the past I think that
was overkill a lot of people just wanted
quality seeds and wanted to grow it out
they needed a rough number of when they
might need to harvest it because in the
past people did take a lot of pride on
you know a check and try trichomes or
tight let me head trichomes yeah sorry
I'm itching a mosquito bite from
yesterday anyways people used to check
the color of their trichomes and take a
lot of pride in when they harvested
knowing that you know it was to the day
when they wanted it and stuff nowadays
people like to see a number on the
package and if it says nine weeks
they've been checking it on their
calendar and they're gonna harvest it at
nine weeks so I think that the new
information for the new growers and
stuff because there's so many that don't
have years of experience and stuff that
are growing legally and illegally no and
so they need a little bit of more
reference now I think so I think in the
future you'll probably see more of that
from me yeah
so maybe the dreaded topic for you not
for some feminized seeds what what's
your thoughts and will we ever see any
from Johnston genetics because I'm sure
you've got some killer females that you
know like people would say that if you
put them you made some s ones you know
that'd be pretty cool oh yeah they
there's uh yeah there's definitely been
a lot of talk of it but if you were to
see a feminized [ __ ] for me it probably
wouldn't be coming directly from me it
would probably come from another
breeder that does feminized seeds that I
would do a collaboration with it's not
something that I do and I like doing
things I feel comfortable with then
feminizing isn't something I do so I
used to say you know it's polluting the
genetics genetic pool now I like I
understand that it has a place in the
industry and not everyone can you know
weed out the mills and not everyone has
the skill and stuff some people just
want the reliability of plant a seed and
having bud to smoke so I would be okay
with doing the collaboration breeder
with someone that knew what they were
doing there but and it just like autos
like I might work with a couple auto
companies where it's actually being in
the discussion so I may do some work
with the couple auto companies this year
to do it John says genetics collab on
auto yeah awesome you know against it
yeah no I'm not against it and I'm just
you from your experience do you know if
those orders you were thinking about
doing that's something we've we often
hear spoken about as like you know the
European market is very after autos do
you find that there's much demand in
other parts or it really is just in
Europe
Europe's obviously the big breadwinner
for the auto market I think you know
just in America how size yard size and
everything is just on average its larger
so people have more space and feel more
comfortable well with you know even just
growing a shorter indica or something
that's that team tends to be a bill be
the real winner around here
yeah there's yeah but in in Europe I do
see that that's my biggest request area
for autos and you know you may see it
come from me as a collaboration breeding
with another company here in the
next year so awesome you mentioned
earlier that you're a big fan of the
concentrates how do you feel about kind
of this rise in the former old
traditions of people like Frenchy
cannoli and just kind of this artisan
hash market how do you feel about that
and how it compares to say our more
modern concentrates like you know you
Rosen and your live resin and all these
things I hope that we never lose the old
traditions it's in fact something I'm
going to be working on personally I
don't want to see the art of good
quality hash go away because there's
none oh like the new market is obviously
about all these modern concentrates
that'll just keep growing there's always
going to be a ton of people wanting to
work with that but I think that if you
know enough people and the right people
get into bringing more attention to what
the old-school real high-quality hash
was I think more people will catch on to
it again in the future it's definitely
something I love to smoke yeah nice and
so at the end of the day what would be
your favorite form of concentrate like
you know live resin harsh dry Civ
Wow Wow the favorite that's a real tough
one because you know real good quality
live resident or distillate that's made
now some of that can just be amazing the
flavor and the high associated with that
just amazing but it sits right there
with smoking it and old like you know a
temple ball or something you know they
both are very high on my my scale of
respect for the smoke but it's hard to
beat a good distillate that's it's an
amazing hit for those that haven't hit
it it tastes outrageous and it is very
high potency
you know sometimes over 95% in some
cases Wow
so it can be high and that's other
people's nervous I have not ever
personally tested any form of distillate
but just from seeing what other people
say you know yep
and so if we were to take a look at your
garden right now what type of lights do
we have in there I'm always interested
to know have you made the conversion to
you know like you double-ended bulbs you
know like the I hate saying it but you
know you can meters or you know do you
still more of an old-school guy you got
your hid lights or what type of
technology do you use LEC yeah
light-emitting ceramic or some people
call it like CMH ceramic metal halide
and I think there's even another acronym
out there for it but yeah the 315 what
Philips bulbs they're amazing I love
them
soon soon to probably be running double
bulb fixtures yep and so you know you
may or may not have an answer to this
but have you heard anything at all you
know maybe whispers or rumors what do
you think is the next step of growing
you know have you heard of any maybe
major innovations that are maybe coming
through the pipeline and we might see
them in the near future you know like
maybe for example you know a few years
ago someone would have said oh you know
there's this new lighting technology
coming out soon these double-ended bulbs
well I think the things that are gonna
blow up are things that are already out
I think that in the future the plasma
market will get bigger I think it will
grow it's it kind of look for a second
and then it kind of went away not that
many people are running plasma but LED I
think is the big that's what a lot of
companies are spending the money and to
do the research on and even companies
that aren't making grow lights right now
they are doing you know just led
research there
they're making some big steps I was
working with a company for a while and I
may in the future but we were working on
developing new spectrums they were
asking me you know kind of what what I
would like to see and so we were working
on stuff like that but yeah there's a
lot of growth in the LED market yeah
yeah but I would like more attention go
into the LEC market I would like to see
higher power Ellie sees there is a
company out there that has a 400 watt
LEC you can find them one on the
internet' I'm sure but it's in that that
bulb is actually made by GE okay so yeah
but it's a it's also the same technology
I'd like to see more into that
technology if people could be running
thousand watt Ellie season in a small
grow room or ten or something they would
have amazing spectrum and amazing light
output yeah yeah it would be insane and
so on to kind of a bit of a more
political based question what do you
think was one or some of the the
pitfalls of the American legalization
model like what would you have improve
if you could have what about like
they're standing laws that we have in in
office right now and what would our land
change yeah I think they did very good
for coming up with a complete new law
system or something that's just been
ignored there are some small loopholes
that need to be covered like there's a
lot of growers here in in Colorado they
grow over what they need you know for
their they harvest and they trim down
and they weigh it and they say whoa I
have enough to last me for a year and a
half you know and they don't need all
that product because they're gonna be
growing again next year
the Colorado doesn't have a system in in
order for them to take in
a product to be tested and once it's
been tested maybe going for approval to
be sold back to a dispensary so it can
go back out to the you know the patients
yeah
little little things like that kind of
need to change sorry so are you saying
that at the moment in that situation
they would just be sitting on a surplus
and not really have anything to do with
it all they can do with this smoke yeah
okay yeah and I mean I guess you're the
implication is it's kind of pushing them
maybe towards the black market of
selling it under the table because
they're just sitting on it definitely
yes I mean kind of like they say idle
hands you know you know when you have
something it's just sitting there and
you see it and in temptations around
there are gonna be you know percentages
of people that will you know take that
route I you know I recommend everyone
here and at least in in Colorado where
everything's legal you know abide by the
laws we were gifted and we're you know
this this luxury of having all this
weight lifted off our shoulders and it's
not hard here to abide by the law I mean
the law is extremely relaxed I guess you
could say there's people with crazy
plant count numbers that can grow you
know crazy numbers at home which they
shouldn't be you know you can have a
doctor right ship where you're allowed
to buy a pound a day
you're allowed yeah so in that that's
getting rarer cuz they're cracking down
on stuff like that but your average you
know you when you sign up I think you're
allowed to buy two ounces any day every
day so you know for a medical card for
recreational I think it's an ounce a day
yeah a minute yeah so you know that's a
pretty relaxed law I mean even if you
were a real heavy partier because
smoking good Colorado buds it's hard to
smoke an ounce a day with your friends
you can do it but you can always go back
tomorrow and buy another one so just
getting to the last part of the
interview now we're just gonna do some
kind of
light-hearted questions this is one I
always love to ask everyone if you could
go back to one place you know
geographically at one point in time to
get some land raise seeds where would it
be and why
Wow it would have probably been a couple
thousand years ago Asia I would have
liked to add some of the early early
stuff that would I'm still after some
actual true Asian land race seeds
anybody out there that's listening so
yeah I I'm really after that so I would
really like I could just take even a
time period of seeds that would be you
know a couple thousand years ago old
school yeah never thought of that
better be almost scary to think of what
it would be like right take something
with a base foundation you know genetic
structure of old school back then and
hybridize it with something from now I
was gonna say you're gonna work it out
in a different direction for the next
thousand years
yeah that would be interesting to see a
whole new evolution of the point so what
do you think is the worst thing to
happen to the kind of a scene in America
well as far as politically yeah well
maybe even just in general you know
maybe maybe you know people are more
more in it for the money now you know
that could be a movie one thing yeah
that's that's one of the things I don't
like seeing now it is going to be a big
money industry but there's everybody
doesn't have to be focused on that right
now you know the money will come put in
the work and do do what's right for the
seed do what's right for the plant and
for the grower and for the people
everything else will come you know like
I the the greed that's associated with
it and and the click enos that we talked
about earlier all that needs to go away
that's not stuffed
associated with people that smoke weed
that grow weed that's like new
modern-day weeds culture now that thing
that needs to go yeah yeah and so what
is the worst strain in your opinion
that's crazy
well worst is a funny word like the
worst for me like there's like a strain
or two out there that when people bring
it around I won't smoke it so if you
want to call first and it's only it's
funny for me because it's great white
shark
it gives me an absolute like panic
attack every time I smoke I get the
jitters and I am so anxiety filled and
everyone else around me is just like wow
this is great smoke so I pass on that
one this so I call it the worst because
it just hammers me I don't know why
there's something about it I get high
anxiety so so it's not because it's bad
at all but for me it's the worst yeah
and conversely what's what's the best or
your favorite strained Wow there's I
have probably a top-10 of strains but
I'm three Wow okay that would probably
be kosher kosher Kush chocolate and
that's hard it is I feel like I'm going
in order now I'm trying to I think I
enjoy a good old-school haze like
they're getting pretty hard to find so
like the old Hayes's that no one cares
to take the time to crow anymore
that would just in general that would be
what talking also yeah no yes
what is your kind of growing tip for
everyone what's something where you know
like most of the time when people
contact you and they've got a problem
you know it's this or just in general
you know like what's something where
people normally just maybe could improve
in some way in terms of growing well
there'll be like a kind of a three-part
answer to the I guess one would be just
really be in touch with your plants
spend a lot of time with them watch them
you know watch them grow especially if
you're new at this that they should be
your babies you know that you should
probably watching them like probably too
often you know when you start growing
out you're going to see every every ten
minutes you want to look at them so I
just say spend a lot of time with them
number two talk to other growers
nowadays with with the internet there's
a lot of information to be had even
without asking a question you can type
in something on Google or in any kind of
these platforms and your questions
already been answered somewhere along
the line but there are people to talk to
so that's like them that's the biggest
thing you could do to help yourself is
you know go to other growers when you
have an issue don't just try to take it
upon yourself and assume you know what
you're gonna do to fix an issue and in
like three you know bug mitigation you
don't want bugs of any kind but unless
you use good bugs harder bugs and you
know things like that
so keep an eye out for bugs and if you
have to use something to control them
there are organic options out there that
do a pretty good job so look into those
like because you will be smoking this
product or eating or ingesting it in
some fashion in the future I see yep and
so what is your random product
endorsement I I would say like for an
ingredient like a little tip looking
into like insect frass it's you know
insect
I believe that's what it is
I'm pretty sure it is but it's look into
that it's it's got quite a few health
benefits to your plant it's a natural
thing that can help the plant in
multiple ways if you if you look it up
insect brass fr a SS for those that
don't know yeah they're like something
you mix into your soil or like a top
dressing thing or you can actually do
both but yes it's it's something you
would add into the soil
yeah and that it gets it has some kind
of low numbers of nutrient but it's
stable and it actually has I I think
they could call it tighten its chemical
that's in there that helps the plant in
a couple ways of kind of like its immune
system I think yeah else what yeah right
yeah yeah it's uh it's good stuff and
that would be like a simple thing I
would say to like look into for people
like a little I guess additive tip yeah
awesome
so the Emerald cup this year's looking
like it's gonna be a really cool event
is there any chance people will be able
to catch you there and may have anything
maybe four so they will be able to catch
me I won't have anything for so we'll
probably be running around checking the
place out in the crowd and then you know
a couple times throughout the event
you'll be able to probably catch me at a
Drazen Thals booth we'll be hanging out
there so yeah I'll definitely be there
that's really cool so what are you
actually with Ed resent oh yes it's
actually pretty cool he contacted me
here a while back asking if I wanted to
come up be in his upcoming book which
blew my mind is definitely one of my
heroes for many many many years
so when he contacted me I was just
ecstatic and honored to be able to have
that opportunity and we did some work
he'll be featuring the grandma sugar
cookies and the granddaddy platinum part
berry cookies he'll be showcasing both
those strains and talking a little bit
about us as a company but we though
originally there was going to be one
book and it was going to be the greatest
hits and I believe it was gonna be
called greatest hits and rising stars
edition of the big book of blood series
and that that book got too big he had he
had too much too many pictures and so it
got split into two books so right now
the big book of buds Greatest Hits is
coming out and here shortly there will
be another book coming out and I'm not
sure of the the title we'll have an idea
of the title but I can't release that
but that will be coming down soon I'll
be in that one fantastic that's um
that's some awesome news to hear
especially you know on a personal note
it must be great to be getting some
recognition from someone you know you
look up to why literally there's no
words that can expel when at that moment
when you contacted me and then actually
last year having a booth in the Michigan
cannabis cup he popped by the booth and
I was sitting there you know talking
with customers we were pretty busy and
he walked up and I looked up and I seen
him and I am never starstruck I've met
multiple celebrities and hang out you
know they're just people just like you
and me but when I saw and I was
starstruck I didn't know what to say I
basically could just answer his
questions with short answers he asked us
to get together for a picture we took a
picture with the group and we talked a
little bit and then
headed out and after he left I turned
the rest of my crew and I said guys I
just met Rosenthal and I was almost
shaking that's so cool yeah yeah so um
you brought up a good point there your
grandma sugar cookies that's a strain
that looked like it was kind of in the
run for like you're kind of just staple
it it's been worked a lot it's been
worked in a few different directions
what is it about the grandma's sugar
cookies that stood out to you that's one
of the few scenarios where I was looking
at the industry and kind of what they
wanted and I was trying to bring
something of mine to the table mixed
with you know an obvious favorite the
cookies at the time and so I you know I
was trying to get something for my
customer base that where they could have
a cookie option for me is really where
that started from I had no idea that it
would turn out to be like you said it is
it is pretty much my staple which is you
know cool for me because that's actually
reminiscent of my actual grandmother and
her her actual sugar cookies that was oh
that was the whole painting behind that
process and she's long since passed
which so it's nice to see that strain
get a little bit of attention and you
know it's a kind of a nod to her yeah
nice it's really nice and the fact that
you then decided to work it out you know
we then got the Double Stuf cookies and
the all-star cookies was that kind of
just a testament to how how like solid
of a base that strain was on its own it
was through multitude of feedback that I
got from people people were coming to me
saying they they liked it better than
the original cookie and then it produced
more and different things so you know I
did I won't be the one to say that but
that gave me an enough of an you know
enough of what I needed to know to keep
working with it yeah
yeah great all right so I think that
brings us basically to the end of the
interview was there any general comments
or shoutouts you wanted to make yeah I'd
like to give a shout out mainly number
one to my fiance Kristen without her
none of this would be possible really
she puts up with a lot from me and lets
me do basically whatever I want I so I
definitely give a shout out to her I
want to give a shout out to Adam my lead
grower without him a lot of this also
wouldn't be possible because he handles
a lot of stuff when I'm not able to and
then to my mom pots without them I
wouldn't be here yeah awesome just
sounds like there's always a strong
woman behind every breed oh yeah they're
always by in one form or another there's
always I was a great honor listen so
everyone should keep an eye out for some
Johnston genetics and there will be some
new releases in the coming year I'm sure
yes there probably be two drops one here
in a couple months and then one towards
after the first of the year for sure and
then yeah we'll have some new t-shirt
designs out some happy ins and stuff
working on more gear we've had a lot of
requests for gear so yeah I was actually
gonna say can I get a shot definitely
we'll talk in a minute about that Oh
awesome all right
no sorry yeah no problem no no I was
gonna say and for anyone else
hit me up I'm not stingy with the shirts
I'll say that awesome all right yeah so
again thanks so much for joining us
no thank you a huge thank you to Johnny
from Johnson genetics again and 420
Australia make sure to grab some Johnson
genetics scene exam
[Music]