[Applause]
what
[Music]
[Applause]
hello and welcome my friends
to another episode of the podcast a
cannabis podcast for fighting
enthusiasts
as always this show is brought to you by
our number one sponsors
seats here now you know you love them
all the best breeders the best prices
satisfaction
guaranteed
get into it
as well as a big big shout out to radio
ridge nursery the one and only
huge huge huge shout out to green
sleeves merchantile
got them dope graphics and logos on pack
hit em up whatever you need
[Music]
and as always big big big shout out
to the family at
dragonfly with medicine and the patreon
gang we love you guys you're amazing
thank you so much for everything you do
[Music]
on the episode today
we have
truth from true counter genetics
dropping all knowledge about the eu
scene spain what he's been up to
and what we can expect going forward
let's get into it
alrighty guys a big thank you and
welcome to our friend true of true
counter genetics for joining us today
hey bro how's it going
good my friend good so we're going to
start this one off with our new favorite
one to start off with which is what are
you currently smoking on today
uh today i've rolled up
a joint of true love which is a cross of
a filipino land race and the truth which
is the strain i won a high times with
back in 2014.
wow okay there's a lot to go on there
let's go on the one i was a little more
interested in touching on first because
we'll obviously touch on the truth quite
a bit the filipino land race how did you
come across that one i've never seen
anyone with a cut like that
this is the most incredible story for a
strain this one like
i love this train for so many reasons i
had a friend i met when i was in
amsterdam a jewish friend of mine
called zohar one of the most adventurous
quirky characters i've ever met in my
life
i love him he's just a just an oddball
of the highest caliber and that's why i
probably like him because we're so alike
and so different in that regard
and
after living in amsterdam for a few
years he then moved to barcelona
i moved to barcelona
haven't been in touch with him i'm
walking along the street and see him
coming towards me with her with this
girl hand in hand
so i'm like bro he's like oh barry what
are you doing here i'm like oh i'm i've
moved over i was staying at a friend's
at the time just kind of looking for
somewhere to live and get everything
settled in
turns out he was doing tours of the
cannabis social clubs in barcelona and
it was an idea that me and him came up
with when i was in amsterdam because
instagram had kicked off by then and i
said to him like go and do the tours
take people around to the different
clubs you can basically what happens is
people take people around to the clubs
and they just charge a small fee or get
a cut of the entry fee but then they're
able to take people to like three or
four different clubs during a day uh
find out kind of what kind of people
they are and pair them up with a
cannabis social club that suits that
kind of person
so he while he's doing it
he meets this filipino girl who's on
like her first
big holiday away from her mom and like
on a kind of journey of self-discovery
so they fall in love
he pretty much jacks in his job and he's
just on like a whirlwind romance at the
moment so he tells me like that's it i'm
in love like i'm going back to the
philippines to meet her mom and her
brother like he's that's what i love
about him he's one of those people he's
like he just goes he's everything
wholeheartedly there's no like messing
around this guy he puts his whole heart
into everything he does so
i go meet them and she's just the most
beautiful
kind-hearted wonderful person and him
like i said he's just the most
wonderful guy and a super adventurous
person so for him he's down for a trip
to the philippines so within like a
month i think they were maybe like
together for a month in barcelona and
then when it was time for her to go back
he went back with her
so he goes back
he's over there i get a phone call from
him and he says like bro
this is not looking good the mom is so
upset that my girlfriend has kind of
just had this journey of self-discovery
falling in love and come back with me
that i am not feeling welcome the
brother
is like the dictator from north korea
and he's looking at me like he wants me
executed at any moment so i'm saying to
my friend like bro be careful this is
the philippines
these are rich people
they will have you go missing like for
pennies just like be careful and he's
not an idiot so he said to me like now
don't worry we're doing some sightseeing
and we're coming back next week like
we're out of here don't worry so
i don't hear from him from a little
while and then all of a sudden i get a
phone call from him
while they have gotten to the airport
and are about to board their flight back
to europe
his girlfriend has been arrested
i'm like you couldn't make this [ __ ] up
i'm like bro like what what are you
doing so he said he's then missed his
flight
and he's now trying to get in touch with
her friends to find out what's going on
or trying to get help and alert him
and luckily he had like her facebook
login had been done on his phone
so he was able to try and reach out to
some friends and try and get help
but literally like spent maybe a week or
so doing that during his adventure he
met another jewish guy and said to him
brother i need to smoke some weed i am
under pressure you need to help me find
some weed
so this other guy goes out of his way to
find him some bud
and gets him like a filipino land race
in that filipino land race there's five
seeds
so my friend saves those five seeds and
then after a week or so of not being
able to get in touch with his girlfriend
and not being able to find out what's
going on he comes back to barcelona
he comes back and stays with me so while
he's staying with me
i start the seeds
after a couple of weeks
he gets a phone call from his girlfriend
she's in a mental institution
she's managed to get one of the girls
that works there to let her use the
telephone
secretly away from everyone
and tells us that they've
diagnosed her with love addiction
and they're literally drugging her
and giving her counselling
heavy
rose
if i hadn't have heard
the conversation myself and been there
and then heard the voice messages that
succeeded i would have been doubtful if
this is even possible bro it blew my
mind to think that something like that
can happen so then my friend as you can
imagine he's like there's nothing he can
do and he's super upset about it
but he kind of like
has constantly got her in his mind
after a little while he gets a letter
and this letter is just like a dagger to
the heart letter
you know like it is the most damning
like
by going on my facebook you broke my
trust like it broke down so many things
said
just destroyed and broke his heart
basically and i had to say to him that
look bro
this looks like someone put a gun to her
head and made her write it
but at the end of the day you're in
another country
there's nothing you can do you've got to
get on with your life
this is kind of crazy right now i mean
like it's so wild and i can see it's
depressing you you need to get on with
your life
so
at that point i decided to call
to strain that i was growing
lovesick the filipino
because of the love addiction diagnosis
that she was given
hot damn that's a neat name to a
potentially really dark story
well the craziest thing of all bro is
that
a month or say six weeks into veg in the
plan
i took a cutting from it
and it bled red
ah that that's exists in like you know
one of bodies strains that's so rare
though right yeah i think it's it's like
amphocyanins or something like that i'm
not sure the exact pronunciation i've
only ever seen it written but yeah i
think bodies got a strain called
dragon's blood that does it
yeah yeah yeah you know about that one
sweet
yeah yeah people have pointed out to me
when i actually found it people have
pointed it out to me so
yeah that strained air it goes like dark
purple it's the most unique hardy strain
i've ever grown in my life i've seen it
grow in a propagator in a dark room
where the rest of the tree cuts i had
discarded all molded and just fluffed
over and when i went in there the
filipino cuttings had grown to the roof
of the propagator and were trying to
find light
damn and what's it like as a plant in
terms of like flowering time and the
high and all that stuff
the flowering time is quite long like i
i've i've got it to finish it's in it to
an acceptable degree in barcelona
outdoors because i flowered it all the
way until the first week of december
okay
that's quite a while but indoors you're
looking at like
you could get away with 14 but really 16
weeks is where it wants to be and i
think if i really wanted to you could
probably push it to 20 weeks it's one of
those kind of strains like
it's weird like that and
the truth is indoors it's never as good
as it is outdoors
ah that's cool
yeah like what what my plan is to do
next year is to start flowering indoors
like
six weeks before the outdoor
schedule flips to flowering and then
take it outdoors and finish it off for
another 10 12 weeks outdoors so it gets
like 20 weeks altogether
oh
that sounds nice and so what's the high
like
it's a beautiful cerebral
low anxiety
i i haven't got the luxury of being able
to get things tested easily but i get
the feeling that it's got cbd in it just
for the fact that there's none of that
heart pounding
sativa anxiety from it but it's got a
beautiful cerebral calming
euphoric kind of
mildly psychedelic high
nice and so what um have you been able
to get the flowering time down to when
you crossed it with the truth
yeah do you know what i finished a whole
bunch outside first week in october
some some stunners so you get 10 week to
12 week
finishes lovely and and what kind of
flavors do they have are they leaning
towards one side or in the middle or
what do they do
with the regular version way more
variety it's all over the place with the
regular one the flowering time is more
varied as well but with the feminized
version that i've just done outdoors it
was a little bit more
balanced you know there wasn't so many
crazy sativa ones and there weren't
really
truth dominant ones it kind of evened it
out a bit more across the board which is
what i find with femme seeds it kind of
evens things out a lot more
so
yeah with that the flavors are weird
i'll be honest it's so hard to describe
bro i i haven't got a point of reference
for it it's kind of
in a floral direction
but i can't compare it to anything so
it's making it super difficult and
that's the same with the
with the lovesick cut itself i can't
give you a point of reference to tell
you what i think it smells like or what
it tastes like so
it's one of those ones i need to i need
more people to try it because there'll
be people with more experience you know
how it is sometimes someone will smoke
one of your strains like i've got a
strain truezilla which is terzil across
to the truth
and when i when i'm smoking it or
smelling it i can pick up on fruits that
i know so i'll pick up on a mango note
or
like grapefruit i can discern easily
you'll get a little pineapple smell that
one i can pick out but when someone else
comes along i've heard someone go like
oh i can smell papaya i couldn't tell
you what [ __ ] papaya smells like for
the life of me so i just have to take it
that that person has got more papaya
experience than me and they're just
picking one of the notes out because
it's familiarity which often makes them
jump out to you yeah that sounds like a
pretty sound theory
let's go back to the start though what
was your first experience with cannabis
do you know what yeah
i think
literally my first ever experience with
cannabis was from like a super
irresponsible like family member where
one of my aunties who's like
semi-degenerate uh basically my little
cousin when we were going on a walk in
the countryside
suggested to her to let me have a pool
on a joint
and that was my first hoke of a joint
was from my auntie when i was like
probably about [ __ ] 11 years
old so super irresponsible like not the
kind of thing that anyone should be
doing but
i guess the [ __ ] up thing is that
your favorite auntie when you grow up
you realize was the most degenerate and
now so that was the gist of that so that
was my first experience and always like
i remember seeing her and her boyfriends
and older cousins whenever they would
roll a joint and smoke a joint i could
see from a child
the difference and how happy they were
when they were smoking that joint so i
think there was always an interest from
when i saw people smoking when i was
younger i could see the change that that
made in people and how everyone was
laughing and smiling a little bit
happier and there was from a young age i
kind of had that interest and
fascination
yeah okay that makes sense and so where
did it go from there how did you
continue to smoke as you grew up um
beyond 11. no
no it was like a concept that couldn't
eat like the idea of it was baffling was
like i don't even know even when i think
about it like i was baffled by that i
think the only other thing i maybe tried
was like i tried smoking a cigarette one
time and then i didn't smoke again until
i was like i think maybe 14
in secondary school
and i started smoking with one of my
friends
a crazy uh little indian kid that i went
to school with that was just
wild and i got smoking with him and then
another friend of mine
his dad was moroccan and he would always
get hash
and he would uh smoke house with me
lovely and so that would have been
interesting having access to such a
kind of
much more high quality and more potent
high how did you feel is did you realize
like that was something special or was
it just kind of whatever
hash was so prevalent where i'm from i'm
from like northwest london originally so
that's not far from labret grove lebron
portobello road market and there's loads
a huge moroccan community there there's
loads of moroccan calves and things like
that and because of the moroccan
population in that part of london you've
always been able to access incredible
moroccan hash
and also back then even there was a lot
of good indian hash as well there was a
lot more variety but the moroccan has
always been around so you kind of took
it for granted that was the real first
experiences there was a lot of hash that
was smoked my early experiences were
going half
on a five pound draw of uh hashish with
a friend and getting two pound fifties
worth each and that's always that's a
lot of reason why you kind of start
smoking with tobacco
and that becomes the culture in the uk
and
even when you smoked flowers people
would say oh you need a little bit of
tobacco to help it burn so there was
this kind of mythology around needing
tobacco to combine it
so what were the first strains that you
can remember the names of smoking
growing up let me have one guess uh
skunk
well bro that's the funny thing yeah i
remember the day my best friend phoned
me and said
barry
get whatever man you can and come round
we've got this new weed
it's called skunk it feels like my
head's a balloon on a string
and i'm like okay i'm coming and at that
point it was like five pounds for a gram
of like imported bud or five pound for a
gram of moroccan hashish and this like i
think it was like 10 10 pound for a gram
or maybe more but it was at least double
so the idea of all of a sudden having to
spend double that for this
tight little s
a luminous green
stinking bud that
just was called skunk it was like a new
thing this was like 95 1995 when we
started to get that beginning of 95 i
think it was around then
love it man and was that like a kind of
a paradigm shifting moment for you or
was it like
huge massive
massive that was like wow it
the high and the difference in the
effect was so impactful the smell the
flavor everything like that
it's like in your mind as a kid you're
like my god what kind of laboratory did
this come from like this is like
this is incredible what scientists
provided this
uh i'll happily pay double like it
changed everything we were just like our
heads were spun that's great so how long
was it between that point to when you
first started your own grow
i would have been 15 then so but i
basically had like a journey from the
age of 15 to like
20 when i started growing properly where
my dad and his best friend
would grow a couple of plants in our
back garden
and as kids we didn't know what it was
and then as we got to the age of 15
we realized and that was part of the
whole thing this is so this is a great
story that you'll love bro it's like
this is the kind of funny [ __ ] that just
like you have to laugh
i when i started smoking at 14 my best
friend i wasn't smoking with him
and he found out and told his [ __ ]
mum
and his mum was best friends with my mum
and now dads were best friends
so one morning i go to school to meet
him and his brother and cousins to go to
school and his mum says to me barry can
you come hear me now i'll have a talk
with you
and then she pulls me into the bedroom
and gives me a lecture about smoking
cannabis and the fact that i'm a 14 year
old and that cannabis isn't the worst
drug in the world but it's not
appropriate for a 14 year old i'm at
school i should be learning my brain's
still developing i shouldn't be smoking
and she gave me such a legit talk
and said to me like look i'm not going
to say nothing to your parents but stop
don't do it it's not it's not
appropriate and it was so
on the level that i literally stopped
like i was like brah i've got such a lie
like i believe that she's not gonna say
nothing and for that reason i'm just
gonna stop because
i've gotten off lightly here but how
harsh my friend i'll be honest what it
was my friend at the time he was so
jealous that i was smoking i'm so afraid
to do it himself and get caught that he
ended up snitching on me that was like
he's like outlet so
bro literally for then for maybe
six months or nine months i didn't smoke
and i would have like
friends at school particularly these two
girls that i always used to smoke with
yeah and most of the time they would buy
the weed and i would always roll it now
they would come to me and i would have
to roll the weed and i wouldn't smoke it
i'd stand with them and i had such like
good like restraint that for like six or
nine months i didn't and then one day my
friend comes into school and says to me
oh
me and my cousin smoked weed last night
we asked our pet my parents and they
said yeah
so he's now
got permission from his parents to smoke
so i'm like my mind's blown and what it
is is that his dad used to grow some
outdoor plants every year and he'd like
give away 95 of it and maybe smoke the
odd joint
for himself on his own like one night
when all the kids had gone to bed but
really he just enjoyed to grow in the
plants
and
it got to the point where my friend and
his cousin
went to his parents and just said look
we want to try cannabis we'd rather do
it at home and ask you
and see what it's like
we've tried alcohol it's like the
english culture is that you're allowed
to drink alcohol
parents will let kids drink alcohol no
problem there's nothing for them to go
like ah you're 14 yeah you can have a
beer at 14. oh yeah you can have a
shandy at 11. you know i mean like
people will give their kids alcohol from
early i'll be honest my parents were
very liberal with uh with drinking
alcohol so when we went on holidays for
instance like like a summer holiday two
weeks to cyprus we were allowed to drink
a few cocktails we're allowed like two
cocktails a night and that's when your
kids
and it's nothing can that's like a
normal thing and the bar staff wouldn't
even care for you to ask your parents
they would just serve you
so the alcohol culture in the uk that
exists is just extraordinary and people
just get into a negative kind of
social state of like thinking that the
only way you can socialize is to drink
alcohol and go to places where
everyone's paralytic drunk
people prey on one another or hitting on
each other you've got girls worried
about getting drinks spiked about being
too drunk and people taking advantage of
them people getting into fights because
of the alcohol and the stupidness and
all of these kind of things so although
to some people it may seem crazy for
kids to go to their parents and ask them
that it was probably a sensible thing
because i'll be honest what it done is
in the long term what it done is that i
then asked my parents
if i could smoke they discussed it with
their best friends who had more
experience about people that smoked and
they come to the decision that look
if they want to try it let them try it
if they want to do it let them do it in
the safety of our own home
on a weekend as a sociable thing
one of them is 17 almost 18 the other
one's 16. they can leave home now they
can have sex they can get married soon
if they want to try it then really it's
better that we know what they're doing
and we have an honest dialogue with our
kids because otherwise what will happen
is they will hide smoking cannabis and
then all of a sudden
that just opens up a gateway of deceit
that that whole dishonesty thing and my
parents never bought me up to be
dishonest that was the one thing that
was always instilled into me i was like
look you can come back from anything but
if you're a liar
it's hard to bounce back from being a
liar that's who you are it's like if you
[ __ ] up if you make a mistake whatever
you do
admit it own it up deal with it but
don't be a liar so when it comes to that
it was like my parents it was kind of
hard for them to get their head around
at first but in the end they just kind
of said okay let's do this and then what
would happen is they would give us this
is the funny part they would give us
like a little bit of bud from the crop
that his dad had like grown outdoors but
they didn't have an idea about what we
smoked so we were asking them for like
weed for the weekend and they were
giving us like a half ounce of this bud
and we're like yeah yeah that should be
about okay for saturday and sunday and
then we would have enough to just like
slowly last us throughout the week and
you just slowly become regular smokers
from the age of 15 i was like
consistently smoking and
it was uh
it was only hash that we would buy from
other people to begin with then the
skunk came in there was commercial bud
like jamaican
i missed out on thai
i think like once we had something that
claimed to be thai but it was dubious
because
i don't know if it's the same with you
but now they send bud from anywhere in
the world with just string thrown in
it's like there's no stick but they
think that if they put string in it
people just think it's time so in
england you'll get people always posting
pictures like yeah i've got this
authentic tie and it's got a bunch of
string in it and i'm like guys that's
just from africa it's [ __ ] weed they
just put some string in it to like as a
unique selling point so that they can
convince you this thai stick or
something
i have to send people like pictures of
like a thai stick look this is what it
is it's a whole process it's not just
got some string [ __ ] wrapped around
it come on guys
yeah wow so
tell me about your first grow what was
that like
the first thing i grew was one small
plant outdoors and it yielded about 10
grams
and it blew my mind how good it was and
then literally
i i had my best friend he had two plants
growing outdoors vegin
and i decided that
i was giving up tobacco
and uh
the best way to do it was to start
growing on my own so i got these two
plants off of my friend put them in the
corner of my bedroom went to ikea and
got a blackout blind
went to the grow shop
got some bottled nutrients
then i got a 400 watt hps i never had no
fan no filter no tent no nothing i
literally just had it in the corner of
my bedroom with a wardrobe kind of half
boxing it in
and at night i would just turn
everything off and i'd be in my bed even
i'd watch a little bit of tv because i
was like you know you have no concept of
like a hermaphrodite really at that
stage like i didn't really know what i
was doing i was
i was kind of like
winging it it's like so i just grew that
in the corner and
the real inspiration that got me like
that made me want to grow was the book
hashish by rob connell clark
before i before i fully grew indoors
from one of the head shops where i would
buy like high times magazine rolling
papers bongs and things like that i saw
the book hashish in there and i got that
book and read it from front to back and
literally when i got to the end of that
book that's when i decided like
never mind a little outdoor plant every
year just like they didn't matter i
wanted to become a grower i felt like
i understood so much about the plant
from reading that book that i wanted to
grow and from that i got jorge cervantes
book the grow bible and i literally read
that in something like
10 days
i went insane reading this book front to
back
and literally
finished it the next day that's when i
went and got all my equipment
good effort and so
how long was it before you found your
way onto the forums
well in jorge savannah's book
at the very back of it
it had
seedsdirect
and overgrow.com it actually had the
website links so as when i read that
book i actually discovered overgrow
and seeds direct
so i was able to get my first ever seeds
from gypsy nirvana's original website
and also go on to overgrow which just
blew my mind
wow what are some of the memorable
things you remember being around for on
the overgrow website or forums
i was just so overwhelmed by
everything that was going on for me just
a strain base i was obsessed with the
strain base with all the information
about the strains
it's like if there was a jeopardy
special subject thing on
strain base of overgrowth and genetics
released from like 2000 to 2010
that would be my specialist subject
because i would go through that in such
detail i knew every breeder every strain
name what the background was it was just
incredible to go on there and
to see some of the growers on there was
just wow
and so who are the breeders you were
looking up to at that time
for me it was always like
to begin with it was always the dutch
breeders like i was always like a big
fan of serious seeds
it's like serious seeds to me the way
they actually done their breeding and
came with everything was incredible for
me so that made a huge difference but
once i got onto the forums and started
to see all this american genetics that's
when things really got interesting
because
everyone in the uk was growing the dutch
strains that i was familiar with it's
like the people that i knew
those strains were available and it's
always the interest of getting something
unique that kind of got my eyes so the
minute i saw all of these uh unique
breeders like i remember getting bog
seeds one of these boggle gum and some
other things that were like
deep wreck things that like you know if
it had an elite clone involved in it it
was some kind of american genetic that
was like a clone only if someone was
working with something like that that is
what attracted me it was like i wanted
to grow things out that i knew when i
passed a joint to someone in the uk they
were going to be looking at the joint
for answers you know when you pass a
joint around to people they take a toke
and then they look at the joint as if to
say hold on a minute and then they look
around for some answers that's what i
wanted and it was it was things like
i remember getting sour bubble from fog
way back in the day which is like a
barbecue crust bubble gum and that was
just a game change and flavor bro that
kind of flavor is just next level same
with sour diesel same with
like
train wrecked herbs same with o.g
kushter the minute chem dog flavors came
along like i grew out
a lot of those flavors
pre-2010 and
it was like revolutionary when when
oregon kid done those og kush s1s that
was just insane for us bro to have og
kush like
in the early 2000s was just wild so
i always looked out for those boutique
breeders the little like
crazy guys that had something with a
story behind it something from
that no one else was growing that had
like documented photos that you could
see you you're onto something special
wow what a cool backstory and so
what's one of your favorite um kind of
nabs in terms of packs you picked up off
the site just off the top of your head
do you know what there was this is this
is one of the ones that deserves a
mention yeah there was a guy called jlp
john lee pettimore this was probably my
greatest discovery on over bro
and he transferred over to icymag.com
when that started up and he was a guy
called jlp which stood for john lee
pedimore and what he done he would make
seeds and give them out free and he was
the only person that was allowed to like
get addresses from people directly on ic
mag and was allowed to do that and deal
with people direct and he would send out
thousands upon thousands of packs of
seeds and he'd done the most incredible
seed projects with all the latest
greatest genetics that maybe other
people weren't able to snag and he'd
done cool projects where he'd done like
he'd done a cross once which was a i
love the concept he he done
two strains called romeo and juliet and
i can't remember what the genetics were
but it was the same cross done both ways
so he used like a male new york city
diesel crossed something and then he
used the female new york city diesel
versus the opposite male and then he
released them as both romeo and juliet
so that people could grow both of them
together
and get an idea of what the male and
females impart differently and have some
kind of side by side comparison to see
what the results were for that
yeah that's a that's a cool little proof
of concept of doing side by sides with
people i guess the question that jumps
to mind immediately for me is
do you feel like when you do a kind of a
sense check yourself like that with the
two variant strains do you feel like
really at the end of the day what you're
testing is
your ability to select a good male
because what if in just one case you
pick a dud male and then in the other
you pick like a good one and that's the
reason why you get such different
results
yeah 100 100 percent
that's exactly it bro at the time like
the concept
is wonderful but
depending on the work that's gone into
it is how it's variant you know i mean
it really does make that difference like
it's a huge difference because like you
say without the male being without
knowing what your male does to begin
with that's that's one of my favorite
things is to actually figure out what
does a male do
yeah i guess that should be the goal of
all breeders to have that as a bit of a
pastime right but um
shouldn't be a unique thing it shouldn't
be like a mind-blowing concept to people
but they should be able to give you a
list of what a male does and be able to
show you in a variety of crosses those
results consistently so
yeah yeah that's a good one and i think
we'll touch on that in a bit but i just
want to rewind for a second so you were
snagging some cool packs off overgrown
something i picked up on which is really
probably one of the most obvious things
people will pick up on about you if they
google you is that you're quite well
known for your cut of casey jones is
this where you picked that pack up from
no do you know what casey jones
basically around 2000 i think it was in
2004 so like maybe
three two or three years into my being
on overgrowth uh maybe two years i think
i'd been on there overgrown now would
like kind of got
clogged down and there was loads of like
it kind of
it lost the community vibe the bigger
and bigger it got
and then i see mag started up
and because i had discovered that the
website gypsy nirvana seems direct they
had a shop
not far from london which was like
within driving distance to me and back
in the day you're so paranoid about
dealing with anything in the post online
anything like that that i contacted them
and said like oh i do work down there
there's only chance i can pass by and
they said like yeah we've got a shop and
they had like a little head shop where
you could go in and see them so for me i
went down there and actually met them so
when they started i see mag
that was kind of
like a big massive thing for me and
i i got into ic mag and that kind of got
the icy mag cup going and that's when i
started to meet
american growers and breeders at the icy
mag cup and through icy meg is where the
world of the industry and the community
really opened up to me because
i was able to see other people's flowers
that had been sent from america i was
able to try
cup entries for the icy mag cup from
res dog and
jimmy knits and
smokey the puff master all of these guys
that had the east coast sour diesel cut
and got to try elite genetics and
got to have my own blood there i was i
was always someone that sent a shitload
of bud over or took it with me so i
always had a rucksack with like five
tupperware containers fall to the brim
with different flowers and always wanted
to like see what was around and what was
available and see what people thought
and try better things so
that was when i i got the casey jones
seeds was when i met the heads because
they were visiting europe so
i met them at the icy mag cup got the
seeds off of them and
then the next year i entered it in the
ic mad cup in 2007. i think i met them
maybe 2005 and then 2007 i see my cup i
had grown it out
done massive selection i kind of like i
selected not massive selection in the
amount of seeds but massive selection
and like dialing in i was so obsessed it
was the first real time that i decided
to like keep clones from seed selection
so not only did i do the selection but
then i grew it out so many times and i
flowered out like
40 plants and chopped it every single
day from week 8 to week 11 and then i
had them all jarred up with the exact
day on them and then i would smoke them
and whittle it down to the to the 10
best days and then i grew it again and
then i'd chop down like five plants on
each of those 10 days and then i went
through the best ones and whittled it
down and then i'm like all right day 64
is the day for this casey jones cup
now this plant here is the best one of
that batch this is the one i'm going to
enter in the icy mad cup this year and
i really thought about my entry a lot of
people don't put fall into an entry like
for me the key to winning a cup like
that is if there's a 35 gram
requirement
you want to provide 35
buds that weigh approximately 1.1 to 1.2
grams so that by time the person takes
out the twig and breaks it down they get
their gram sample it's one but
no one has to break up big buds of your
entry
because when competitions have to start
dividing things up and doing those
they're under pressure and they haven't
got time to gently break up your big bud
that you sent in because it was your
best bud that doesn't work in a
competition unless it's one where
they're keeping half of it for a judge's
panel that want to examine it in that
detail when it comes down to individual
judges you really think about
presentation the trim job a nice boulder
don't use the top buds that have been
directly under the light go for the
second shelf i always pick those like
you know like if you're picking one
grand buds it's never going to be those
tops it's kind of the middle level ones
that have got the best frost that have
had a little bit of protection that are
just
stunning those are the ones
of course yeah in the words of peabod
the shoulders of the plant
that's
you entered the cup and what was the end
outcome you got to you got to finish
your story for us
yeah basically i entered that year and
at this point a lot of the uk
were entering but everyone was smoking
with tobacco in the uk at that point
even a lot of the growers from ic meg so
although other good growers entered when
it came to all these americans being
over and judging
i was growing cocoa and had been growing
pure for seven years like six seven
years by that point so i was so obsessed
with the flush that mine smoked so well
and i had such a good entry and it went
off so good that i finished second place
to
john lee pettimore jlp with sour diesel
he grew out sour diesel and got first
place i came second with casey jones so
for me to come second to one of the
internet legends
was just like a dream come true that
just like
that for me still was like just the most
incredible one because it opened up a
whole world of like friends and
amazing contacts and just
lost everything blossom from that point
onwards
yeah it sounds like an awesome win i
guess the thing which immediately jumps
to mind for me is when you first started
growing it out and dialing it in did you
realize how special of a cut it was or
did you think like it was just pretty
good
no i knew it was nuts bro it was nuts
the thing was yielding ridiculous like
my first plant of it i yielded like 12
ounces from the seed plant in a 10 liter
pot of cocoa
it's like it was just ridiculous and the
turps on it were just insane it was like
it was one of those ones like i said if
you're at a party
and you roll a joint you pass it round
and as it goes round you see people toke
on the joint look at the joint and then
look around the circle to ask someone
like what the [ __ ] is this
because it's literally hitting them with
so much flavor that it's just in their
mouth
hell yeah that's that's the goal right
it was all unique it had like the
background of casey jones is orient
express which is billy goats bangkok
betty a chocolate tie cross train wreck
and then that was crossed with sour
diesel
so
completely unique things like it was uh
there was no familiarity in any of those
flavors to the to the palette of like a
uk smoker
hell yeah so
there were some other cuts of casey
jones that went around there was like
the schmo cart but yours was um
considered the best for sure but what
did you think of the others did you ever
get to try them
you know it's funny i had two cuts
myself i had a typhino as well that was
incredible
but
i let it go it's like i was then still
at the mindset of like oh i can't have
two katy jones you know like i'm trying
to only really keep six mothers or
something like that and i always love
the like
mindset of like
a new one's gotta come in and knock one
of those off and eventually i have to
whittle down my selection so that i have
one of each strain i was naive to the to
the reality of
two of the same strain being unique
enough to warrant both being kept
yeah i can uh
i can certainly feel myself being guilty
of that one as well at times regrets bro
regrets but you know what
the strain was passed out and i smoked
it a couple of years later
and it was given to me as something
different they had mixed it up they were
calling it the mass sour because we had
a massachusetts super skunk cross sour
bubble and they gave me the bud and when
they gave it to me i go this is the
casey jones cup i didn't even need to
smell it nothing i goes that's not mass
sour that's the casey jones but the guys
wouldn't believe me
it's my cuts both of them but they
ah there you go
well
full circle right so
were you breeding at that point
no do you know what bro i
i wanted to become the best possible
grower i could and i held breeders in
such high regard
that breeding wasn't even on my radar
until it was until i was asked to do a
project
for someone the idea of breeding is like
i had friends around me that were like
growing hobby growers like myself like
my friend dr d online
he
i would grow out his seeds and he'd do
little hobby breeding projects and even
at that stage for me i was like
i knew that there was there were levels
that i hadn't reached as a grower the
idea of breeding was like to me a slap
in the face of people that were doing it
because i thought you had to i thought
you should get to a certain
like master your craft in one regard
before you try and get to a next stage
so
it wasn't until
i
competed in the ic mad cup
i saw that my bud was on the levels i
met mrs uh grateful grateful head's wife
she was in the uk and i got to spend
some time with her and she got to smoke
everything i had and she told me like
barry
just true your stuff is on point like
you're on the level of all of us in
america
like did this is the truth of it bro the
best growers in the world are a nine out
of ten
that's my thing there's no diet there's
no tens because we all know that for
every single minute of every single day
of an entire crop to go perfectly
doesn't happen
eventually it will get to that point
because technology and
room
setups and grow techniques are evolving
but at the moment it's not at that level
and how i feel is that the best grower
in the world on a day-to-day
is an eight out of ten occasionally when
you hit a nine that's when you say to
your peers
check this one out this one's special
that's when i will like bother saying
something i'll maybe have 30 jaws
sometimes and offer them up just like
yeah i've got this i've got this i've
got this but there'll be one that i know
pete
one
that really stood out and is on that
level it's like ironically enough that
spannabis last year i grew a cheese
plant that was that level it was like oh
this is as good as i've ever grown a
plant for whatever reason this one had
the right
fruit zone it was healthy happy the
light was correct the temperature was
right and people was were going crazy
about it i've never had people people
were just shocked they're like [ __ ]
hell brianna cheese like this ever like
people were like really really excited
about it and it was one of those ones
that i knew it was the one i was saying
to people like look these are all my
things but even though these are all my
creations this [ __ ] cheese just came
out crazy check it out and
that is it really like i i realized like
once i realized i was in that realm of
being able to attain
eights and nines occasionally that's
when you kind of i was willing to take
on the concept of doing some breeding
fantastic so we're gonna we're gonna
lose our linearity in time for a moment
fast forward for a second i've heard
from a few various sources that you
frequently have the best flower at
spannabis most of the time
do you agree with that and what do you
feel is the kind of state of affairs
with the flower at spanibus in general
also there's turps army farm there's
there's i've got to mention them because
there's a couple
a uk girl and i think a boyfriend's
italian they're called terps army farm
on instagram first of all i have to
shout them out because
i have a massive amount of respect for
them they grow on that level their
people that i would say are on the elite
level of like
yeah they're growing eights nines
consistently they really put into work
and they really have a love and a
passion for it so
before i pick myself up i definitely
gotta give them a shout out because i
love what they're doing and there are
other people that have got some amazing
buds but
like
i always plan for spannabis especially
it's like
from
from always if there's an event
nothing pleases me more than being there
in my element around my peers and people
that when you show them things they
appreciate it so i go above and beyond
and out of my way to try and make sure
that i've perfectly dialed everything
down to the time in so that the flowers
haven't been cured for too long they're
not too fresh try and get everything
right and
really just flush everything it's like
my genetics i believe in and i know that
if i flush everything right and it's
clean then that makes it stand out
because i know there's a lot of like
oh why ash is a myth and all of these
kind of things it's like i'm no
scientist but i know the white ashes the
more i enjoy it so
i don't want to talk for anyone else i'm
not saying i haven't had things that
don't burn
a little bit gray that weren't nice but
whiter ash is a smoother cleaner more
enjoyable smoke for me and
those results
are shown by the feedback that i get and
you'll notice that anyone that's ever
talking about my bud in a good regard is
often talking about the flush and how
clean it smokes
yeah for sure so let's go back in time
now and go back
tell me about the first cross you ever
made was it intentional or was it an
accident
you know it's funny the first the first
cross i ever made i lost a project
before i ever got to
harvest the seeds or grow them out
that's kind of what got me
on the path of breeding i was doing a
project for someone else
so
for res dog from reservoir seed
like that will have people like that
that'll get people super like that
triggered a bunch of people now but it's
like don't worry guys
i learned he was a [ __ ] scumbag too
just like everyone else but it's part of
my
my history nonetheless so yeah i
i was actually doing a project i was
doing a chem dog ibl
so i had uh started doing that project
for res
uh
because he knew that i knew the chem d
i had got a lot of
uh familiarity with that cutting by
being around it a lot on the east coast
so
when he actually asked me to do a
project it was the chem ibl because
i realized two reasons one i was
familiar with it and two because it was
the ibl he realized that he could ask me
to do the project without having to give
me the cut
because it was just
crossing the seeds and crossing and
doing an ibl so inbred line so
i didn't need to actually use the
cutting he just wanted me to select
multiple males
and hit
the best females
yeah he did a lot of interesting stuff
where he'd like you know bx it then f2
it or f3 and stuff like that did he
explain to his rationale behind that at
all
he was a fan of
mr souls
and the cinderella 99 and the back
crossing theory
so
that was his thoughts on that
some of it
as people will tell you there were there
were versions that were good there were
ones that were bad there were ups and
downs some of it he did himself some of
you farmed out to other people often it
was farmed out to friends who [ __ ] it
up and
the seeds still went out so there were
bad batches so it was all there was
always crazy stuff like that going on
the last batch of cell diesel ibl wasn't
made by him that was made by
basically connoisseur genetics who
just used two clones that weren't even
given to him by
res dog they were two cell diesel clones
sourced by someone else and
it was just easier for rez to do that he
was so burnt by getting
scammed for the east coast sour diesel
cut anyone who remembers icy mag will
remember
the friendly friend fiasco where someone
came
uh that was their name friendly friend
it's like if someone's professing
themselves to be called friendly friend
it's like
you're pushing it a bit too hard this
friendliness you know i mean you should
have been suspicious with the name but
he ended up getting the east coast our
diesel cut off res and starting his own
line where he used that cup but called
it indonesian diesel and there was this
big drama on icy mag and it was
hilarious but after that res dog like
didn't want to give out the cut ever
because
you if you know the forum world back
then cuts were so guarded that
once it was out and people had it they
were using it breeding it trading it it
was it was a crazy world for cuts back
in the day you had to earn your stripes
to get a cut in things have changed so
much these days it's like
yeah back in the day it was like it was
a sign of respect to know that you had
like certain cuts because you had done
something to get to that point where
someone offered you a cut you wouldn't
go out asking for cuts you would earn
your stripes by putting in the work and
then the right people would see what you
were doing and offer you the right
things
yeah wow
so i guess the question that i want to
ask is how did you lose the project as
you said
basically being in a prohibition state
like the uk where i used to live
the house got robbed for the growth
oh no
which is
it's like
the way things always work right like i
say loose lips sink ships and what
happened is that the business partner
who arranged a property
had a best friend and that best friend
robbed us
because
sadly with prohibition and the way
things are it brings a lot of negative
attention from the wrong types of people
and people will get into their heads
that they can justify doing those kind
of things and
all of a sudden you lose a project and
it's like
it was a sad thing to lose it's like i
had two rooms one was the seed project
and one was the flower project
it's like
to lose the seeds was more heartbreaking
it's like you're [ __ ] idiots you've
stolen a bunch of seeds that are
worthless to you like
and now i've lost everything so that was
that was the first loss i ever had it's
like the first time i ever did anything
with anyone other than myself
i lost the
project so what happened after that you
just started working with res
after that by that stage
i then stopped working with res res was
doing all kinds of weird [ __ ] he
basically blocked a mutual friend from
giving me the east coast sour diesel car
like to some super slime moves and
he had like uh just generally started to
show his true colors and reveal himself
not to be
like this is the thing with res his
perception online
was a scumbag piece of [ __ ] he used to
come across so rude and abrasive that he
wasn't likable i clashed with him online
the only reason i ever got to know him
is because i was friends with grateful
head and mrs grateful the creators of
casey jones
i was friends with them and they in turn
were friends with res dog
hmm there you go and i guess they just
had a better relationship with him than
most i guess
yeah and
that's how i met him by going to america
to visit them and then in turn meeting
him
and i got to be in those circles and be
around him
then over a period of time he just
turned out to be a [ __ ]
a major major piece of [ __ ] in real life
but
as with a lot of people who have like a
certain degree of intelligence they're
able to say the right things at the
right time to people tune into their
frequency and use them to their own
ends and gain so
that's that's the kind of person he
turned out to be and then
yeah i was kind of lucky that
when they had
a whole bunch of drama and all got
busted
i was in prison myself so
i wasn't visiting america seeing them at
that time gladly
wow jail how did that happen
i got busted with my partner at
connoisseur genetics basically after the
first res dog project
i had all of my
female selections
from the chem project plus i had all of
my female selections from just growing
as a grower because i would have like i
had a variety of different things i had
mo breath from jimmy knits back in the
day this is like 2008 2009 i had it
before it had a name it was just crosses
that he gave me when i went and visited
america because i've i met jimmy nitz in
america he's one of the best growers
most humble and he's the guy that
changed my whole thoughts on feminized
seeds
his san fernando valley reversal that he
done to train wreck and to the chemd
are to this day
my top
10 femmes i've ever grown
probably mo breath motograf's in my
probably top five ever
well it's interesting you say that
because i actually had the question i
wanted to ask you
do you ever feel like motor breath is
kind of similar to the truth on paper
they look like they've got a lot of
similar elements
basically i've tried to get that same
chem
terp is what i love they're far gas 80s
joke shop fart gas that's hurt that
smell that people smelling a rock that
smells like fart gas that is what kim d
smells like to me in its essence so with
the motor breath you had like an og
structure
with
that foul
rotten
chem d stank
and that's what i like in the truth
right that does come through in the
truth that that's a terp that i love and
i i've often like worked
towards would you consider the truth to
be kind of your most well-known strain
yeah terpzilla as well is like
quite well known that one
like was grown out by a good few friends
and got into some good growers hands so
it won a few cups that's another one
that's real well known and hyped up but
i've had that for a long time as well so
and i've never released it so it's kind
of i think that's more kind of made it
more well known as well the fact it
hasn't been released it's just been
grown and people have got to smoke it
and it's picked up a few cups
it's interesting you mentioned the terp
zillow because that one uses the
terparella and that one caught my eye
because it's got that chocolate tie in
it and i was wondering where did that
come from and do you think that maybe
plays a role in why terp zillow even
though a bit of a distant relative why
it does kind of shine through as one of
your more well-known crosses
do you know what it is i think it may be
getting them mixed up yeah it should
have sent chocolate that i'll be honest
with you that strain there is a femme
seed that an icy mag member made and
when i started true kind of genetics
i'll be honest i never i don't like
making femme seeds that's true from it
so when i originally started true
candogenetics i was under pressure to
release some femme seeds
and one of my friends had made the
cross supersorba haze which is
turperella so he had those seeds and i
just said to him look bro i'll release
those through true kind of genetics
because i need to sell some femme seeds
because the market is just going crazy
for them at the moment and i don't want
to make them i want to focus on regular
breeding
so that one isn't even made by me that's
the one and only time a strain or
anything has ever been released by me
that wasn't made by me myself the seeds
so it's nice to get that out there
because you know what i mean it's like
it's not something i try and hide and
generally it's not something i would
ever do but
that one yeah that one isn't made by me
yeah that's all good we've heard other
breeders talk about doing similar things
so i mean we've talked about how the
truth is one of your like more
well-known strains but let's put that in
contrast to what do you feel is your
best strain like it may be there's
something which kind of flies under the
radar a little bit what's your personal
favorite
i'll be honest with you you know what
the real like the real king strain for
me
is my chem valley cooks
but i've not released it because my
whole philosophy behind that is that
when i got the forum cut i got it from
an ic mag member called crunch bubble uh
he got it with the crew
that he's with in san francisco another
grower called abba roots whose
seed company is called always be
flowering i think it is
and
they passed us the cut like i when i
came out of prison in 2011
they sent me the forum girl scout
cookies and that was a groundbreaking
strain but when i bred with it i knew
that like i get no pride from breeding
something that just tastes like cookies
so what i'd done is when i created chem
valley cooks and crossed it with an sfv
chem dog mail i never wanted to release
that because really it was very cookie
dominant the females what i wanted to do
was search for a male that when i bred
with that male
it gave all of the bag appeal
and favorable traits of the cookies but
allowed me to impart all of the flavor
from the mother plant
and that's why i love the chem valley
cooks because it's allowed me as a
breeding tool to release a variety of
strains now that are giving me deter
profiles that i want
but the bag appeal that the modern
market is obsessed with
so i've got one at the moment like
called
crimson cookies and another one called
cheminade the cheminade everyone's
loving at the moment and that's a great
lemonade across with the chem valley
cooks
and grape lemonade is a
lemon larry og cross chem dog cross
granddaddy purple
wow okay and so when could we expect
possibly i would possibly be able to get
those for ourselves
that one's available at the moment the
cheminade's available in regular seeds
now those are out there all my seeds
come in packs of 15. the reason i do
that is because you know what i'm
obsessed with
like
as a grower i always wanted to be able
to have
my selection and then keep a few so for
the average grower i'm confident that
from a pack of 15 seeds you can pot 10
seeds
find at least one amazing keeper and
then have five seeds so if ever anything
happens you've got five seeds from that
original pack because there's something
in growers heads that no matter what
if they've had a keeper from a pack of
seeds and they lose it
even if it's the same
like strain same parents
they really have an affinity for that
pack of seeds that it came from so if
they've got a few left over that they
can go back to they've got like they
feel more happy that they've got that so
i kind of feel like 15 seeds in a pack
is a nice number for a grower to have
and
give them a little backup
yeah i like that applied psychology and
breeding and marketing there we go a new
one but um
i just want to go back to a minute
because i was actually talking to our
buddies from always be flowering just
earlier today in fact and he mentioned i
mentioned i was going to be chatting
with you
and he actually basically kind of
relayed similar information to what you
just said but what i wanted to ask was
he said you know you were one of the
first people if not you know the first
person in the uk to get the forum cut
how did that change the scene was it
like what happened at that point when
you got it
without any shadow of a doubt
we were the first me like i
the cuts were sent to me and immediately
shared with my business partner at the
time uh ojd of connoisseur genetics
that's who i was working with at the
time
we i got those cuts it was incredible
bro i couldn't believe how
how
how they got to me like literally we
come out of prison got messaged by my
buddy crunch bubble and he said look man
we love you guys we love what you're
doing we've got something special for
you we want to send you and he fedex me
cut
and they were there within three days i
had six rooted cuts of the girl scout
cookies and six unrooted cuts
they all rooted and all of a sudden we
had the most insane
mind-blowing strain we had seen in
[ __ ] years it was a game changer bro
it literally
like
people
in london
in 2011 2012 we're paying
10 000 pound a kilo for girl scout
cookies
10 pound a gram
all the way you want a kilo cost 10
pound grams per kilo
and that was people were buying that
happily doubling their money and it was
selling out people were like going home
raiding their bank [ __ ] looking down
the sofa people like
okay i'll get 10 10 i'll get 10 20 draws
like people were just going crazy for it
it was a game changer bro it's that
level where every now and again a tert
profile
a look something comes along you know
like at one point it was purple but that
was so rare when the blackberry uh cut
that was on overgrow popped up it was
like my god purple bud like and that's
how it is when new buds come along
they're just game changers and cookies
did that it's like it was crazy the
people that got it were going well
hell yeah and so
were you breeding at that point or were
you looking to get back into it after
your little steve yeah
yeah we were breeding at that point it's
like the
the truth of it is is that at
connoisseur genetics when when we were
making seeds ojd was making seeds i was
making seeds and ojd had another friend
who was making a lot of seeds for us too
so when we were locked up we were still
having seeds produced so we were never
stopping me and oj
we're no longer friends we don't get on
things happen perspective different
views such as life but we went through
some adventures and when we got locked
up and we're in prison for trying to win
a high times and getting busted
we sat in prison made strain names up
made phone calls relayed that info had
us work still released
and
lived on in prison we did not stop i
made a point of teaching at least five
people how to grow when i was in prison
i made a point i was like you think
you'll stop me but you will multiply me
because i will teach
as many people as possible how easy it
is and what a wonderful life you can
have from growing and that's what i made
a point of doing we continued to run the
business i learned photoshop and use it
in my business to this day it's like i
made the most of it i was like you won't
stop me i'll use it against
the the system and i'll use it for my
for my cannabis business
fantastic so at what point did you
diverge and start your own company
basically after we came out of prison me
and oj tried to
work together and as with a lot of
people that do business together
business and friendship doesn't mix so
it got to the point where i walked away
from connoisseur genetics
would have been like
it had been around
2011 end of 2011 or maybe
early 2012
and then that's when i started true kind
of genetics it's like in order like
when i walked away i wanted to try and
salvage a friendship so i started fresh
it's like my original release is through
true kind of genetics rather than do
anything with anything that we've done
i released a couple of femme things that
i had done that he hadn't so it was kind
of unique like turtzilla originally did
get released in limited packs on icy mag
so a few packs went out and was sold but
it was small amounts same with the
purple halitosis the grape lemonade and
a few other femme crosses i released
those through true canon genetics
originally but they were small batches
when it actually came to full
distribution i started with fresh
palette and i went for regular seeds and
i've always wanted to try and stay on
that line so what i did is because i'd
become such a fan of the chem dog
profile and from growing the chem dog
ibl and the chem dog back cross work
that i done with connoisseur genetics i
got some sfv cross chem dog
and
that is what i used as a male to hit up
a few different things to start the
foundation of true kind of genetics and
one of the original strains was ken
valley cooks also the truth
uh
sagan star which was a scentsy star
cross and then broadleaf black which was
a black domino cross or black demeanor i
never know how that was pronounced
i think you said it right one of the two
times i don't know which one either but
um
it's interesting you bring that up
because i wanted to talk to you about
that specifically the sfv chem dog
component
was that one of the various sfv ibl's
crossed to the chem dog like how did the
genetics work because on face value it
sounds like two clone onlys right so i'm
wondering where the male part is
that is res dog's
chem d back cross
it's this it's the back cross ii the
second back cross
a male from that
was hit to the san fernando valley og
kushka
haha okay cool well when you put that in
context it then actually kind of makes
me feel like
the chem valley cooks is kind of like
it's not all that different from a gmo
thing in a way you know like it's got
the similar components
yeah the gmo kills me because it's like
i love that it's taken
like it's taking this long for everyone
to fall in love with the chemdita it's
like it had to look like cookies for the
modern generation to fall in love with
it because that's what the turp is you
know i mean that is straight chem d
turps but it's just got all the bag
appeal that everyone goes wild for so
yeah that's like that a is it's a good
look and it's a beautiful turn it is
so how would you compare the ken valley
cookies to something like the gmo or one
of the very other various other chem dog
girl scout hybrids like chem scout or
whatever like the gmo like most notably
has that horrendously long flowering
time right how does the chem valley
cookies compare to those ones
well what it is yeah with the
to really get that turp from the chem d
i've crossed the ken valley cooks with
the truth
so then what you're getting is you're
getting the sfe chem
from both sides
that one i've called trudeau
and that one has got the chemter to
perfection it's got that wicked fart gas
stink and that one finishes at like
eight
nine weeks 10 if you really want to push
it and that one's got all of the bag
appeal it's got low leaf to bud ratio
it's like super super dense
and it's got
super super high resin content it's like
oh i've been pressing rosin on my
sasquatch and my god it's just amazing i
showed my friend yesterday and i love it
because it was one of those times when
you let them smell it and they tell you
the thing that it smells of before you
give them any hints and he said straight
away that smells like fart gas and it's
like he goes not in a bad way but do you
know what i mean and i'm like yeah i do
know what you mean that's exactly what i
wanted you to say the fact you said it
just put a big smile on my face so
yeah i've i reckon it's there in the ken
valley cooks itself
that one the flowers the one that i've
selected as a keeper
i've kind of gone away from the chemter
i've gone for like a sweeter
more
floral doughy kind of turp for the
actual ken valley cooks itself
so that one i'm i'm testing at the
moment i've done the set like uh
an incross of that and i'm waiting to
see what they're like i haven't had an
opportunity to grow them out but
i've not been rushed to get the ken
valley cooks out as a strain itself
because like i said for me it was more
about selecting a male
to use as a breeding tool than releasing
the flowers
yeah of course
so
if we're trying to continue on the story
so to speak at what point did you say
did at what point did you decide to
leave the uk and head over to spain
do you know what happened after after
originally getting busted going to the
high times and going to prison
i decided to send bud to amsterdam
and that was a nightmare when it got
there i just wasn't happy with how it
was after having sent it
and
i literally decided to myself
the only way i'm ever going to win a
high time is if i am in a city
grow the [ __ ] bud out
put it into tupperware walk up to the
people and hand it over like that that's
how i need to do it
and i decided yeah that's what i'm gonna
do and tied in with that as well at the
time a crazy a [ __ ] up thing happened
is that my girlfriend at the time came
to visit me from america
got refused entry into the uk
and
i ended up just saying to like look
move to amsterdam like i'm going there
to grow now anyway it was only a matter
of time i need to [ __ ]
do do a high times in amsterdam so it
was like it was kind of perfect timing
for me to leave england and go to
go to amsterdam and be in the city and
win a high times which
from being a kid before even growing you
know like seeing the high times and the
high times cup it was always so
prestigious and it's like a lot of
people want to criticize it and
yeah i could probably talk some [ __ ]
about high times too but at the end of
the day uh
proof is in the pudding and the fact
that someone like me could place and win
in the high times the fact that someone
like lady sativa genetics can win the
fact that someone like karma genetics
can win all those times that is the fact
that fino finders the fact that all
these people
can win is proof that smaller people
can win these cups and it's not all
about who does the big sponsorship who
does this who does that it's like for me
to win a second place high times blew my
mind it's like the reality is that the
small guys when they go to the high
times
your first place is third place
you expect the big boys to sweep one and
two and then the up and coming little
guy who's making a name and putting in
some work
might snag a third place but then
five other guys equally deserving are
gonna lose out so when i stood there and
they said second like they said the
third place
i looked at my cousin and said oh well
it's been fun and then they said second
place winner that just blew my mind just
like
and
it shows that like putting in work and
[ __ ] dedicating yourself to something
can can pay off
cool so you're in amsterdam and you'd
won second place
at what point then did you travel like
where'd you go at that point
amsterdam was such a crazy adventure
anyone that's ever lived in amsterdam
knows that it's the most
like you can you can smoke around smoke
and go to coffee shops smoke all of that
but trying to grow there is so [ __ ]
difficult
it is mind-bending like you will
literally move into a place and the
neighbor will come and knock on your
door and ask you who you are and what
you're doing
as if that's just a cool thing to do
like they want to know and they are on
to everything so when i originally went
there i had a huge grow with a coffee
shop and the grow got robbed
so before before i ever even got a
harvest out of it it got robbed and then
i was left in a situation where i
literally had to throw two 400 watt
lamps into a room in my apartment
pop
four packs of seeds
i had to grow the seeds out for eight
weeks harvest to eight weeks
dry for two weeks and then i had one
week
to trim and hand into the high times and
i literally for my high times entry i
entered a whole plant including the tiny
little like point three gram nuggets and
everything because it was just a whole
plant i had to enter it without smoking
it i just had to choose
what plant i was going to end up
gee whiz and what sorry what plan was
that
that was all of them i ended like i
entered the truth that year
uh i entered
i think maybe we entered ken valley
cooks we entered a few different things
and
sorry that's my dehumidifier going crazy
i ended a few different things uh
but uh truth is the one that wants
second place and i literally had to like
i said i had to just choose the plants
and enter them because each plant
because i only had like a couple of
weeks to veg and had to do everything in
such a small space of time because of
losing the other grow
i didn't have big enough plants to even
really do selection i just had to kind
of eye it but
i was going to say the truth is in this
ironic that i say that is that i knew
from week five to winning plan
like
my my friend i was living with at the
time who runs an extraction company
called yellow brick labs
we knew like when i showed him like
smell this one he was like yeah he just
confirmed to me you know when you know
the standout plant he just gave me the
nod just to say yep that's [ __ ]
abrasive it just had such a beautiful
aggressive smell so that was the one
that i knew was special and that was the
one that got me the place so
very special place in my heart that one
lovely
so how long did you continue to hang out
in amsterdam
bro like i said it was so difficult to
live there everything was so difficult
to do and it was so expensive
that i won a high times in november in
december i went to morocco to like a
beautiful farm over there to like do
some like
some research for them they basically
wanted me to find out
what was left on the material after they
had done four grades of hash
after it had been hit four times that
got everything off of it was there
anything left on the material because
imagine if you've got five ton of
material
and there's
resin left on it and you throw it away
what's the potential
a little bit accumulates
yeah so it's incredible to go there and
find out that one of the strains had
four percent return and another one had
seven percent return
with just a crude simple like open
blasted like bho extraction just to get
numbers
so
as far as distillate
somewhere like morocco just has [ __ ]
incredible incredible potential
so
was it then you transitioned over to
spain
yeah my plan was always to go to spain
uh after i went to high time so after
that it was uh
a couple of trips to barcelona to settle
things up and then i moved there in the
early part of 2015
and barcelona the cannabis social club
scene had always appealed to me before i
even moved to amsterdam i had said to
friends like yeah eventually
spain and barcelona with the cannabis
social club scene is going to be the
place and
once a bunch of friends were living
there and i'd met loads of people that
were
were over here with clubs and doing
things the opportunity was here to
to come over and people kind of invited
me to work and a lot of opportunities
opened up
and so is the european scene kind of the
mecca that it's made out to be
especially spain
barcelona is the epicenter of the
european cannabis industry
by far it's taken over amsterdam this is
the place where people come on a regular
basis you know as a kid like from the
age of 15
onwards i was going to amsterdam
constantly like most english people it's
a 50 minute flight it costs less than
100 pounds you can fly to amsterdam
for a day if you want you know what i
mean and hang out it's like people i
know people that have been
50 times in their lifetime to amsterdam
because they do they view it like
a weekend away like you can spend more
money getting taxis around london
than what you do if you get a
last-minute flight over to amsterdam
so people would do that so regular but
as amsterdam has tried to push out the
cannabis
culture
and kind of
fancied the whole place up
it's kind of
given the opportunity for barcelona to
have a thriving social club scene and to
start to draw all of those same people
over here and with a variety of
different like airlines
with the seasons that are quiet mild
over here everyone loves it and i've got
friends that
nobody i know who's been here once
has only been here once they all come
back many times and often two or three
times a year
what a what a little ad for it all
so what's the barcelona seem like in
your opinion are you in the heyday
currently or is the best yet to come
it is awesome it's uh it's it's
incredible to be in a place
where people have the opportunity to
make something of themselves you know
like to be at the start of any industry
where people with passion are able to
put in the work
find their niche
fine-tune it and then put it out to the
world and build a brand it's amazing to
see from all the different social clubs
that have a variety of styles to them so
that no matter what kind of person you
are you can find somewhere that suits
your vibe that has your kind of people
whether it's one up which is like
full of retro computer games with an
amazing menu with a cereal bar with like
50 different breakfast cereals all the
american fancy
fruit loops with marshmallows and all of
that kind of stuff there's that
incredible place then there's
trestle which is like the most insane
artwork it's got like
already like 20 plus pieces of art from
some of like the world's most incredible
street artists
uh
there's places like la colada which has
got the most amazing murals and like a
real laid-back vibe with like lots of
in-house work same with we flowers where
they do a lot of their own growing
extracting
our social club there's so many good
ones
and
there's something for everyone it's like
there's places like the plug that are
for the like younger guys they're like
like the trap music and like the like
all the hype strains and all the like
super like latest greatest
cali this and skittles that and all of
those kind of things
it's like yeah it's an incredible place
with the clubs now you're starting to
get shops are popping up you know you're
getting like real high-end head shops
there's a place called hedge barcelona
that now have anything that touches in
america glow trays
the puffco peak attachments they've got
everything so you can go there and get
all your backwood clothes you know like
i'm pushing 40 i'm not going to buy
backwards clothes i don't even smoke
backwards but i i know what these 20
year olds are like and it's like to be
able to get all of this stuff that's in
america that everyone's seen on
instagram to now be able to get it in
barcelona you'll get people from england
flying over just to get the latest
greatest stuff from this shop because
they've got all the like exclusives that
you can't get anywhere else so it's
adding to the culture and the scene it's
like there's a new place that's opened
up called the wacom bakery which is like
a stoner friendly
food spot that's got loads of baked
goods so
they're just stoner guys that have
opened a place and they've used the old
uh
name wacom bay free which is an awesome
one because i knew a place on the east
coast called the wake and bakery so
slowly you're getting things with the
cannabis museum the scentsy you've got
you know you've got other things
starting to pop up so that on top of the
social club scene
you've got other things for people that
are in that scene to come and see and do
and it's adding to the to the culture
massively out here
yeah what an awesome description of it
all so one thing i wanted to touch on
which you yourself referenced the hype
game it's a part of the american scene
which i don't really enjoy that much
myself
you kind of referenced it but i'll
outright ask it has it infected the
barcelona scene and are the plug kind of
like the equivalent of the jungle boys
of barcelona
uh
the plug's just like
incredible basically he's built the most
incredible
like spot like what he's done there
people try to replicate and anyone that
tries to replicate it they fail
he came and done the perfect spot
for people who are interested in the
latest greatest things uh the latest
kind of like
music like that the uk scene's putting
out the american crossover he's got a
record label so he's got all the like
best music playing for that age group
and that that genre so
it's not my style of place
but it's incredible and what he does is
he not only
has all the latest greatest strains from
kelly but he also has
loads of stuff grown locally as well he
does source out good local stuff so he
has everything across the board that's
the truth of it it's like a lot of
people want to hate on whoever's doing
really well and and and that's that's
just uh that's just a modern day
mentality it's probably been the way
since day one since existence but what
he's got there is an incredible place
but it's not for everyone that's why i
said barcelona's incredible bros like if
you like guitar music and acoustic
stuff you you'll find a club that's got
free guitars set in the corner for you
to go and play guitar if you like the
latest greatest grime music track music
the latest
strains have just dropped then there's
somewhere for that if you like oh
there's somewhere for that if you like
computer games there's somewhere for
that so
with the plug
like
they are
killing the hype game but they're doing
it properly and they are getting the
best stuff do you know what i mean they
have the connections to get the flavors
what annoys me is some of the other
spots that are just like
trying to be that
but they're getting [ __ ] cali bud
and trying to charge through the nose
for it and promoting that massively and
trying to convince the world that cali
buds better because their markup and
profit margin on that cali bud is higher
and that's where the problems are the
problems are places that are trying to
get the best thing for people to try the
latest greatest things the problem is
places that are getting
sub par but
pricing it crazy and then
all the staff pushed that over local
grown stuff to people who don't know any
better and that is rife and the hype
game with that regard is kind of [ __ ]
bad in barcelona because
unless you go to clubs where there's
educated staff who can educate people
about a grower and the genetics they
just sell the latest greatest
yeah
yeah yeah that's that's the same
everywhere i think but
i want to touch on something you
mentioned that you know you said that
there is a variety of different things
on offer depending on where you go
so i'd love to talk about some kind of
spain specific clone onlys and your
experiences with them and the one i most
want to ask you about is a plan i've
always had on my mind forever have you
ever smoked that clone only of queen
mother that goes around spain
no i don't what is what's the background
on ah so it's from the delicatessen crew
who are kind of like friends with
cannabiogen
and it's a cross of like a reunion
island with like this congo hybrid so
real raw sativery land race but
apparently there's this specific cut
that goes around spain of it that's just
meant to be insane
i think there's a cup that's a congo one
called lily or something like that yes
yes yes yes that's that's the name of
the cut lily
yeah yeah yeah yeah so incredible bro i
have smoked here it's one of the best
it's one of the only standout things
i've ever smoked in barcelona that when
i first came here
in 2015
i think i was given that in la colada
and we flowers they both have that cut i
think i was gifted in la colada and it
was the best example i've smelled of it
what a beautiful profile i was like
congolese is this really a congolese i
was like [ __ ] this is so tropical
beautiful bro beautiful
yeah cool that's one which doesn't get
talked about a lot but i mean on that
point
what's going on with ace and cannabiogen
do you have any contact with those guys
at all i just feel like they've kind of
fallen off a bit
did they was there like fallings out
between them was there some craziness
where
ace was meant to have taken the genetics
of cannabis and they split up or
something and
he's like yeah there's some kind of like
conflict i heard from someone
okay yeah i just noticed that both of
them have seemingly stopped putting out
new releases whereas they were on a bit
of a good run for a while
basically what i got told now i'll
speculate it's a total speculation this
is what someone told me someone
basically told me that cannabis was the
one who was really doing the work and
that ace kind of half-jacked them so
that's the story i heard whether that's
true or not it would explain why
they both stopped doing it because if
one guy didn't make it
yeah the other day jacket
yeah and now it's all gone and he can't
make him again because he jacked him
or whatever who knows but
yeah it's a strange one
yeah well i mean it's totally possible
in the sense that charlie garcia is well
known from the kind of biogen crew as
being a legit breeder so it would make
sense that they're the ones doing the
work
um but anyway you know well maybe we'll
find out the answer to that one another
day
so
is there anyone doing anything over
there that's kind of really innovating
in your opinion
yeah do you know what there's a few
crews out here there's like a lot of
hash making crews spain is a hash making
culture so because of the hash making
culture there's incredible thing people
doing like
amazing work out here you've got like
eminem extracts la sagrada familia
extracts
the guys from wheat flowers
uh alma social club
la callada
nerd extracts who has a
one-up club
also you've got a uk guy called
ah his name will come to me in a minute
i'm having a brain freeze but yeah
there's loads of good people over here
bro doing loads of good work and
building brands because
there's like growers
there's a grower called nectar monkey
that i know that does like live soil and
like he really puts in the work to like
put out an incredible high-end product
and you get a lot of people that will
like do everything in house where
they're growing things they're pressing
stuff themselves they've got rosin
they've got flowers
which i mean i've got a friend that does
edibles as well so him and he's white
like his girlfriend he grows she makes
edibles that they sell to the club it's
like
that they're called fresh flower farm
and fresh flower edibles it's like
that's the kind of thing i mean there's
like they came here from england and
were able to build a life for themselves
by taking some risks putting in a bit of
work
persevering
going through some ups and downs but
having a goal and a dream and wanting to
come and do something and barcelona
allows you to like
find your niche and find your spot and
like build something so
there's lots of people doing cool stuff
that's another one i have to mention
growers with attitude they are doing
incredible stuff over here
yeah shout out to those guys for sure
so i guess the next question that jumps
to mind based off that is how hard is it
realistically for someone to pack their
bags and move over there give me a
little bit of a rundown is it feasible
or is it quite easy
basically you've got to have enough
money to set yourself up for six months
really that's what it boils down to it's
like you've got to be able to come over
here and afford to lay down deposits and
rent on a house for the first six months
so you can find a house move in
set yourself up get a crop down and then
the ball's rolling so anyone who can set
themselves into a position to do that
and can get it right can do it but it's
not that easy you've got to find the
right house you've got to make sure that
you can rent that house you've got to
make sure that you've got the
documentation and the bank account that
you can show someone that you're
self-employed that you're a computer
programmer artist designer and that you
work online and set yourself up and get
a house and then once you're in a house
you can set yourself up and
be a part of the scene but it's not that
easy bro it's like it's easy if you can
make it happen
but it's not just pack your bags turn up
and it all falls into place it takes a
lot of planning and
a lot of [ __ ]
determination and a bit of cash as well
it's like it's not cheap to you know
what it's like with anywhere you've got
to pay
one month to the agent maybe a couple of
months as a deposit and then really you
need to
have your first three or four months
rent
ready to be paid so that you can get a
crop out
yeah
pretty sound advice
electricity is always an issue here
the houses are wired so bad that most of
them are limited you can barely run any
electricity so you've got to find a
house where you can actually run enough
electricity to grow properly
so there's a lot of factors like that
where it's like
once you're here
there's a wonderful sense of privacy and
your house is your castle everyone minds
their own business and a lot of people
grow my neighbors grow they go into
their grow room when they open the door
it opens out into their garden they
don't do it discreetly they don't give a
[ __ ] it lights up the hill that we live
on i live on like a mountain it lights
it up that at least six houses down the
hill
know these guys are growing they had 20
like 15 20 foot plants in their garden
it's like they harvested the whole thing
in their back garden it's like they
don't care and i've got other neighbors
that have got plants in their front
garden so it's like
people mind their own business out here
if you haven't if you're not showing off
if you're not a flash [ __ ] who's
driving a fancy car
around working-class people stinking a
weed all the time and making a noise
you're going to be cool it's like i most
of the people i know that come out here
and live well it's like the guys
turps army farm and fresh flowers
farm days guys
peaceful people
not flesh people have come out here set
themselves up well and
keep themselves in themselves are polite
don't don't be too in to the locals
because
you don't want to get into too many
conversations it's like i tell people
i've got a t-shirt company because i
have a t-shirt company it's like so
that's it i can run my t-shirt company
from
spain that's why i live here and i go to
the post office send my t-shirts all the
time so
yeah makes sense
it is wonderful it is very private but
it's not like i've seen a lot of people
think
because they see a lot of people like
myself over here doing it well that
people just think it's easy to come over
and do it's like but everyone has to
realize what i put on instagram is what
i want the world to see that's my
business [ __ ] page like you'll get a
little bit of who i am but i can't tell
you every up and down and trails and
tribulations i'm going through so
when people ask me i will always
encourage them but i'll give them a
heads up and let them know like look
these are the pitfalls you've got to be
aware of this this is what you need to
do but it is possible if you have
a real passion for growing and you
really see yourself wanting to do it and
take that risk and come and live
somewhere because there's always risks
to everything you know i mean we're
still in a prohibition state
things are crazy in barcelona at the
moment the
spanish police are beating the [ __ ] out
of protesters and
yeah it's a it's a very volatile spot at
the moment but i love it here
it's given me a wonderful life even
through the ups and downs that it
provides
yeah right on
so
in the in the scene over there what's it
like with the growers are they looking
to pop new things and find the next best
thing or are they all just trying to get
like the hype clones from the states
it falls into the two categories bro
if you can't like for our maker our
maker like this is like a
like a dick this is like a digger people
i already know before i say it yeah
so i'll be honest i'm saying that way
there's two types there's the people
that can't grow quite well enough
to make
and select something and make it shine
and make it sell on that merit so they
need to go with hype strains
to sell their bud
and then there are that level of grower
who grow so well and have so much
passion that what they want to do is
select their own thing because they're
growing
is able to make that shine as much as
any elite and they can get the same
money as someone selling a skittles cut
grown out or a gelato cup grown out so
there are a lot of people that are like
no do you know what i can do my own
selection and find something unique and
grow it to that level and
that's what i like to see it's like it's
probably evenly split a lot of people
are just jumping on the hype and trying
to get the latest greatest cuts that's
always going to be the case but
a lot of the time there's a lot of
sharing in barcelona and you do see cuts
passed around so it's kind of more like
i'd like to say it's more on the
positive side where people are hunting
for keepers in the uk that's happening a
lot now that that i've seen blowing up
more and more in the uk recently
i've noticed that because cuttings are
going to the worst growers
you know like people who are like
average growers
will buy cuts
and because of that
the elite growers that used to get those
cuts because that's let's be honest this
is how it used to be in my mind when you
were at a certain level of growing cuts
would come your way it's like i got to a
certain level and i got the cheese cut
from bright side it was an icy mag
brother and it's like that is because i
had grown to a certain level it's like
you would never
give that cut out
to someone who wasn't growing to a
certain level because you want that cut
reputation to be withheld
it's like that was the whole thing is
like elite cuts went to elite growers
and that's why they were elite the
minute they go to average growers they
lose their shine and their reputation is
ruined
and now the uk is seeing that because
all of these hype cuts are being grown
out by average growers which is then
ruining the market and they're realizing
there's more longevity in finding
something unique themselves and building
a brand so that people come back for
that specific thing
yeah no truer words ever spoken but to
loot back to a point you just made about
how cuts are shared around in spain
i wanted to ask you you've bred with a
plant called nicole is this the same
nicole that the dna crew got from that
spanish dude and what's the plant like
either way
nicole is the cut from marimbarros he's
a colombian guy
yeah yeah that's that's the one
yeah he's uh he's a friend that gave me
that kite it is the same one that uh dna
used to make the
uh
what is it they made with it i can't
remember kosher no the nicole kush they
made nicole cooter a bit by crossing it
to the kosher kush
okay and so yeah what's what's nicole
like as a plant and what do you think
pairs well with it
to be honest with you as a plan
as flower form i'm not a fan of it like
i didn't like the way it smoked the
unique thing about nicole is the resin
type it has a type of resin
that comes away from the plant
and is the most solid resin you can
imagine to make static sift with it and
to do extracts and things like that it
makes just ridiculously rigid extract it
it's an incredible hash making plant and
that's why it's become one of the
biggest hashmaking strains in morocco is
the nicole kush
when they crossed it with the with the
kosher kush it's kind of giving it a
a little bit more to it added a bit more
flavor and
really allowed the resin to just drop
like crazy i heard that they were making
something like four times the yield with
the nicole kush
from crops to like their own
stuff so
crazy yields it's an incredible hashmate
so i looked up the genetics on it and
it's largely just a mixture of kind of
like blue satellite and shishka berry
and a few other blueberry type of things
mk ultra
yeah yeah that's in the mix as well
how do you feel about the blueberry
flavors and does that shine fl through
in that clone at all
yeah it does you know there is that blue
like it has got that blueberry like
there is a hint to it that kind of
stands out it's very unique it's very
very unique like in the market you know
like there's nothing do you know what
really it smells like it reminds me of
uh
one of the
the great gardener strains because
that's also got the shishka berry in it
so it's like it's the shishka berry terp
that kind of dominates because i've
smelled it also is it
one is it from the great garden i can't
remember what strain it is is it the
barbara budd or one of those ones yeah
barbara bud afghani crushed fishberry
yeah that's it it's got to say it's got
a familiar terp so basically whatever
the shishka berry is if you ever get a
chance to smell something with the
shisha berry no that's very similar to
the nicole
yeah okay interesting interesting
and so while we're talking about flavors
what is your favorite flavors in
cannabis
you know what i like
tropical that's the like you know real
tropical floral notes
i like those but i also like
it sounds crazy but i remember once a
girl texting me and saying
is purple can purple be a flavor and i'm
like that's what i'm working towards i
hope so kind of thing because she had
dabbed something combined and wanted to
know if purple was a flamer and like
that's the flavors that i like i really
love the purple flavors and depending on
how i breed with certain things it
reveals different kinds of purple
flavors so you get all the like
lavender-y what i described as like
grandma's purse candy you know like old
lady perfume incensie those kind of
floral kind of purples and then you get
all the grapey merlot wines berries dark
fruits those kind of purples so there's
so many
purple flavors that come through
depending on what direction you breed
things in that i do love all those
different purple flavors
and broadly speaking what type of highs
do you like the most
i like hugging a butt pie
the bud that makes you feel like you're
just wrapped in a warm cozy blanket of
wellness and
well-being and like not overly narcotic
but that nice little fuzzy feeling of
wellness
that's why i smoke cannabis that's
defeat that's the that's the higher most
go for even in even in the sativa lines
i'm trying to breed with i'm trying to
cut out the anxiety the heart racing all
of that i want a cerebral like euphoric
high that kind of can allow you to relax
into it and that's why i like that calm
something with a calming effect and i
think cbd being in things
is intricate to that and not being
completely bred out
yeah it's interesting i've been thinking
about that same kind of thing myself for
a while i would be interested to know
your thoughts on this then do you think
that's a quality that you can try to
breed into a strain or do you think it
just comes down to kind of like an
individual connection with a certain
strain you might have
i think it's both
i think you can breed towards it based
on your own experience and what's
available to you
to get from friends you can get to try
it but because everyone is individual we
do all need to find the perfect one for
us
and that's why i think like it's about
selection and growing things out and
when people grow things out grow them
out three or four times don't make your
selection off of the first seed run
because not every grower is dialed in
sometimes the second run plants are
completely different sometimes a third
is better it's like give them all a good
try try them at different flowering
times and it's like i think that's the
real key to get into that where
i want to feel from my smoke is actually
dialing in your plants and doing the
selection and looking for things that
are kind of
that do
connect to you like do you know oh these
are these are the strains and often the
terpene is the thing that connects to
people that entourage effect is like you
get people that connect to certain
terpenes so it's obviously like there's
certain things they need to look towards
with certain terp profiles is often what
will help them so it's like i wonder
often if like lemon sativas and lemon
indicas will be good for a certain
person that that particularly connects
to them and then they go off it works
both ways
yeah for sure i mean while we're talking
about breeding for a moment a question
our viewers always love
what are some of your tips for picking
the best male possible
oh do you know what i'll wait this is
how i look here when it comes to a male
i never search for males i wait for
males to identify themselves
as the one
it's like
i never like to think oh this is this is
the cross i'm gonna do i'm gonna select
a male from this i like to wait for a
male to pop up that's incredible you
know often when you're growing out
plants you have a plant it's happened
like
i remember probably like before i
started breeding it probably happened
three times in like five plus years
where i had a plant that was my favorite
plant out of the pack that i was the
most excited about and then it turns out
to be a mel and i'm heartbroken because
i'm not a breeder and i just chop it and
i want females
those are the males that when they've
got everything about them that just
stands out from the structure it's like
normally you will see a male it has
single branch some [ __ ] like side
branching that you can spot a male like
the females are the ones that have all
the candelabra big wide side branching
it's normally obvious just from
structure so when you do get a male that
has the perfect structure
and then you touch it and it stinks
then you're on to something then that's
the start of this could be a good mail
cool cool so i noticed on your instagram
you've got some photos of the cam valley
cookies crossed afghani and it
immediately made me wonder where'd you
get the afghani from and what kind of
traits did you look for in that mail
afghani is the craziest thing i've ever
found it's my greatest ever random
discovery i got contacted by someone who
had a friend that had come back from
afghanistan in the british army
and had some seeds and the guy offered
them to me so he sent me these seeds and
there was like 37 seeds i think
i grew them out
out of 37 seeds when they started they
all look pretty uniform except for one
that was growing with single blade leaf
and it looked like a run it was like
growing shorter than everything i had to
prop it up on a couple of pots until i
get it up to the height of the rest of
the canopy and i thought to myself let
me mark that one with a little star on
the number you know like so i remember
it was looking weird at the beginning in
case later on things grow out
it turned out to be
the most incredible plant
you could imagine bro the rest of the
plants were all very similar and had
varying degrees of like
wackness basically it's like they were
like
no resin no yield
slightly nice smell a little bit
perfumey i had one nice maybe two nice
ones that were very similar in profile
to all the bad ones so
smell profile was across the board on
say 30 or 25 of them that were female
was all across the board very lemony
floral this one plant looks like
an og kush it's an exact it makes me
believe that og crush is at least 50
afghani
without any doubt in my mind
and what do you think could be the other
i don't know if if i'll be honest with
you if if i hadn't heard the stories
recently about what the crosses were
because there's like it's actually down
now from that tk origins guy it's like
one of the strains that he says is half
of the genetics
is a cut and i'm presuming that that's
an afghani strain that's my presumption
and that this that is afghani dominant
because
if you see the pictures of the plant
that i'm growing bro honestly when i
when i say about it being a single blade
leaf it looks like an og crushed cotton
when it was growing
and i actually thought like that's got a
bit of an og crushed look to the cat
like to the seed plant when it was a
baby
yeah no i i don't doubt you at all like
bodhi and doc d have got the iranian
which is like a dead ringer for cookies
right
yeah that's it bro it's like honestly
it's like it makes me believe it so much
yeah okay interesting interesting well i
guess time will tell with those ones as
to what they turn out to be i want to do
a bit of a throwback to something you
bred a while back i noticed in one of
your posts you said
you also bred a grand doggie perp strain
was that different to the one that was
offered by connoisseur or is that the
same one given you were there and i
guess the follow-up is how come we don't
see or hear much about it from you
basically that one what happened is
when i lost
the res dog
ibl project
i had another grow house where i had all
of my female selections
and
[Music]
my males and then there was a security
breach at that house
so what ended up happening is oj at the
time had connoisseur genetics and the
only crosses he had done was using a
g-13 haze male
that had come via soma
that's like the one that he used for a
lot of his crosses
yeah that one that one got shared around
amsterdam a fair bit
oh yeah that one got pimped out hard so
that one uh that got traded over to us
for the casey jones cut the casey jones
cut went back the other way so
oj had bred with that and what happened
is i
had to
remove all my plants from the house
so my dad who's just a [ __ ] legend
he's the most straight going guy that
just does anything for me to help me and
just supports me so much he
literally had to like come to the house
we loaded up like 35 foot plants in big
flat screen tv boxes for removal loaded
them into his van and moved them to a
grow that oj had
and then oj
rather than just holding onto my plants
just pollinated all my selections
with my males and made seeds with the
whole lot
for connoisseur genetics
so at that point it's kind of took my
project from me and i kind of said well
how about i come in on connoisseur
genetics together
and that's when we become partners at
connoisseur genetics
so
when we were working at connoisseur
genetics
that was the kbx project so from that a
whole bunch of things came out so the
first batch of seeds he made using my
mail selection of chem with all my
females like
motor breath
train wreck cross sfv
the casey jones
a whole bunch of other things
anyway they got made and then i made
another batch of seeds the bachelor i
then made i remade a few things like the
kemi jones
i also made the only batch of grand
doggie perps
because
when when he done the original batch of
seeds we didn't have the gdp cut in that
room because it was my genetics the gdb
the gdp the granddaddy purple cut oj had
actually sourced that one so when he
gave it to me i did a batch
of grand doggie perps
and that was the only batch that ever
got made because after that it was not
long after that we lost the cut
of the male so we weren't able to make
any of those strains again with the same
male so it's been remade by connoisseur
genetics a female version but it's
slightly different the actual regular
version has never been remade
interesting and so have you ever wanted
to work with that or is that just kind
of falls under that banner of like fresh
start thing
uh do you know what the grand doggy
perps that is in
the purple project that i had done and
the purple project i've used for
breeding so i have kind of took it with
me because i've used a couple of
different things like that i've gone
forward with and done like when i first
came to barcelona i literally just went
through like 400 of all of my seeds that
i had made that i had and just done
selections through all of those
and started re-selecting so i went
through some of my granddaddy purple
hybrids from when i done a reversal so
the grape lemonade purple halitosis
rainbow jones and a few of those things
are all
seeds that both me and oj had made
and
had
stopped to go through when i got here
yeah interesting okay that was the last
project of
connoisseur genetics the last project
i'd done was basically we done a gdp
femme project and then when we got the
girl scout cookies together we done a
girl scout run
but
the most horrendous thing happened is
that i
was fighting broad mites at the time
and i was using the swarovski mite
i had beaten the
broad mites but i was still using the
my as a preventative but i didn't
realize they eat pollen when they
haven't got bugs to eat
so i'd done a reversal of the girl scout
cookies pollinated the tent
and literally got like
three seeds out of this plant five seeds
out of that plant two seeds out of that
plant it's like reversals are hard
enough but when you've got a bug that
eats pollen
it turned out to be that was like before
that was the last project i actually
done with connoisseur genetics and then
he dumb across and then we walked our
separate ways and yeah that was just a
funny one to learn a very valuable
lesson about what bugs eat when they
haven't got bugs to eat
yeah wow there you go the more you know
so
i forgot to ask you earlier when we were
talking about the truth but you know
just in line with if we look at a lot of
your strains are on offer now a lot of
them have got the truth in it
when we look at your keeper cut of the
truth what type of characteristics does
it pass on in terms of the female and
then also in terms of the male
with the female
when when i've hit like
what i've done is i i decided to go all
with my own lines it's like i don't
really want to be just
breeding other people's stuff and
other people hype work and this and that
everything i've got has got like i've
got some kind of hypothesis and idea of
what i'm trying to get towards so
really what i've done is i've got my two
males
that are the truth male and the ken
valley crooks male and the idea of them
is to have breeding tools one that adds
all the favorable characteristics of the
og kush which has proven itself to be
the one of the most if not the most
legendary like popular strains in the
world and the other one to have all of
the bag appeal and characteristics of
the ken valley cooks
and that's the key thing is like for me
i want
low
leaf
ratio to bud i don't want to be trimming
loads so
with the truth it gives
hardly any leaf like it's kind of like
the double-edged sword is you never have
no trim from it but you hardly have to
trim so
for me
when you're doing lots you don't want to
be trimming a lot and as things become
bigger and bigger the less you've got a
trim and the less people are in if you
can flush a plant to where the bigger
families fall off and then you've got
just a
a basic little manicure that you're
doing a couple of pounds in like a
fraction at a time then people are gonna
that's gonna make a difference and
there's even like any grower that i know
doesn't like trimming so that's one of
the main characteristics the other one
is branchiness it's like i like good
side branch and i like plants that
respond to being topped well so that
they get a good amount of heads on them
and you can top and train plants so i
always go for that in my in my breeding
and try and go from now that's going to
give good structure
solid answer and you just referenced the
idea of using your own lines do you
think that breeders should look more to
using females they've found themselves
or just in general from their own
projects or do you think there's also
kind of a space for people who just want
to repeatedly cross one male to just a
bunch of clone onlys and don't really
search to their own female stock too
much
the second bro i think there's a room
for everyone to do everything
as prohibition comes to a close there
will be a niche for everything there's
always going to be people that need to
do the latest greatest thing
cash in on hype and do well and i'll be
honest with you if i was doing that i'd
be making a lot more money than what i
am because i have the opportunity to get
whatever cut i want
as quick as i want and then do those
kind of crosses but
i i get no real pride from that
i get much more pride from creating
something unique and having goals and
aims and
seeing people be able to find something
unique that then stands out and gives
them something that they're able to work
with and
turn heads with like for me just
crossing things if it just gives
something that already exists i get no
no joy from it but
i love the fact that anyone can do
whatever they want that's what
breeding's about the key thing is people
just need to do their homework it's like
if you're buying seeds from someone have
a look see what they're doing see where
they come from see what it's like see
see if it's hyped see if there's any
real work going in ask a few questions
do your homework just
you gotta put in the work otherwise you
will end up wasting three months of your
life growing out a bunch of [ __ ] and if
you do your homework it's easy to find
out who the legit ones and
get something incredible
yeah of course
so
there are a few other notable breeders
who are in the spanish scene do you
socialize much with them or is it kind
of like it's a bit hard to meet up or
whatnot and people just kind of doing
their own thing
i'll be honest i've had such a hard
couple of years the last couple of years
i've had a few issues
with my housing that meant me having to
shut down to a minimal minimal basis
which has made things super difficult
for me and it's meant that most of my
time is just spent at home working
keeping to myself so sadly i haven't had
as much time as i would like to be
socializing with the scene but there are
lots of people doing cool things over
here and it's like i'll be honest like
that's why i'd love spannabis so much
it's like it's the one time of the year
when everyone's out
i get my dad to come and house it for me
look after my dogs and my plants so that
i can be away for the whole week just
socializing catching up with everyone
seeing what everyone's got seeing the
evolution over the year and
i do get into the city but not as much
as i'd like but there's amazing amazing
things going on as far as breeders and
people trying different things and it's
that it's a lot of like spanish
underground guys doing cool stuff with
like old neville's haze cuts i've seen
around the little things like that those
are the ones that interest me there's a
couple little things like that
yeah i heard there's a crew of guys over
there who have been safeguarding the a5
and c5
yeah i've got some friends that have
recently got those as well as well as
the s s is it an s5 is there an s one as
well like
i think there's one with an s the s5 as
well maybe i recently heard some friends
had that i want to get those myself and
play with those they're definitely
special
yeah certainly certainly okay cool well
why don't you tell us what's your new
project you're looking forward to doing
or you've currently got underway even
the projects i'm most excited about is
like we said earlier is that afghani the
land race afghani that i've got and also
i got given some pakistani land race
seeds from the neelam valley and i've
done some selection from those i did
those both at the same time the
pakistanis and the afghanis and the
keepers that i've got from those feel
like real building blocks you know
they've got like such
strong unique flavors
such good strong resilient fast root in
healthy genetics i'm super excited about
working with those as well as with my
filipinos so
it's kind of the mix of those at the
moment testing those lines
is what i'm going to be focusing
probably the next year is going to be
focused on the land races
and at the moment i've got a good
selection with my chem valley cooks mail
and my truth mail that have been
released i can kind of
let those sit for a while
and people are going to be able to enjoy
those i've always got many strains that
are made that i haven't released so in
the vault there's probably another 10 or
15 strains that slowly while i'm doing
all the testing and working on the land
race projects i can also test some of
the things that are in the vault and
slowly if they make the mark or not
release them to the public
every now and again like for spannabis
i'm looking to release something
a purple halitosis across the chem
valley crooks so that's one i'm working
at the moment
that sounds exciting you just referenced
the idea of working with some land race
stuff i'm always interested in knowing
would you ever be willing to travel or
want to travel to collect some land race
stuff yourself
do you know what
the ideas always appeal to me
and if i wasn't so busy and had the
funds i would definitely do it but i'm
so lucky that i've got people like
uh himalayan connection and land race
genetics and a few other good-hearted
people
from instagram that have reached out to
me and i've been gifted some very very
special seeds i've got some is it
sumatra tripping weed that from
indonesia some seeds from there that i
was given by himalayan connection that
i'm going to be working with soon and
things like that for someone like him
who searches out genetics at source and
has an incredible network of people to
reach out to me and give me something so
unique that he searched out for years
and years and him to see
something in me to say look bro i think
you could do something special with
these that's that's incredible so i'm
excited about working with those soon as
well
so i looked through some of your work
just on online and i noticed in a few
places that you had essentially worked
with some super silver haze stock i was
wondering where did you get that was it
from like the pre-2000 stuff or is it
more newer
that's the
that's this ssdh that was uh basically
there was a cross from res doctor oj at
connoisseur genetics done a selection
from and got a super silver sour diesel
haze and that is crossed with the
cookies which is in my cookie fever
and that one yeah that was res dog's cut
which is like old old black pack when
shanty barber was breeding that was a
very special cut say what you want about
res you may have been a bit of a [ __ ]
but that was a wicked cut
yeah it's funny that that sentiment
comes up a fair bit so
um i've noticed more recently you've
been doing some collabs with ocd labs
what does that mean in practical terms
like what do you do what do they do and
what's your ideal collab like
to be honest bro what that is uh that is
uh that was something i started myself
with a friend of mine way back in like
2013 maybe
yeah about 2013 a friend of mine who i
don't work with like i'll be honest ocd
labs now is kind of redundant because i
haven't been really doing much
work through it it's me that's doing the
work now because my partner went off and
done his own thing now so really it's
just me making rosin now through my own
genetics and the concept behind that bro
was just literally when i saw how the
american industry was going i knew that
an extract company was essential so i
started an extract company and i had a
friend who runs uh
at the time he was just like a
a forum guy that was on the forums and
he was like in the uk he was working for
like an estate agent but he was so on
point and obsessed with like the extract
game he was one of the first people that
ever had shatter that was super on point
so me being on the pulse of things i
just decided i'm like bro let's start an
extra company like
you can be the front man like i'll
provide the genetics let's have an
extract company everyone's doing it in
america let's just do it i'd rather have
an in-house one and being able to put
out all my genetics and do that and then
because of all my friends in the
industry we just
made some amazing like links in
amsterdam and we just had a wonderful
golden age in amsterdam where
myself
ramon from yellowbrick labs now and
another guy called rick who runs
something called
i can't remember the name of his company
now but he's an amsterdam based guy we
all ran ocd labs together when i was in
amsterdam and we did work for soma we
did work for dna we did work for
marimbaros and we done all the stuff for
true kind of genetics so we were putting
out so many extracts at a time when
there was no scene in europe there was
the only other extract company that
existed was nerd extracts
and that was literally it so we kind of
wrote the birth of the revolution of
extracts and from amsterdam we just had
people coming over constantly from the
uk just getting tons of extracts and
just blew up the whole european scene it
was incredible to see that change like
the amount of people that we gave first
dabs to that now have
glass shops extract company edible
company
clothing line like just crazy like just
to see that everyone who's been around
this scene has been inspired by the
whole birth and their influx of social
media the way that's affected it it's
crazy it's crazy to see
yeah huge progression right
the amount of extract companies that
exist in england
and it's a country that's where it's
illegal and there are like
extract companies to build amazing
brands all kinds of edible companies
it's like it's wild to think that it's
got to that stage now
yeah 100
so
i don't know if we've touched on it
already but i'm always keen to know what
style of growing are you a fan or are
you into the no-till you're into coco
what do you like
i've been like my first ever grow that
i'd done was remember i said i got two
friends off my like two plants off my
friend that he dragged him from outside
and they were soil when i went to the
grove shop and like got set up properly
the guy advised me to grow with cocoa
so from that day forward i grew a cocoa
and
because i was always so obsessed with
getting it clean i've always loved cocoa
for that reason the way i could grow
multiple strains
not have any real deficiencies
and get it flushed out it's like
my examples of soil growers and organic
was never great until the last few years
since no-till really blew up
there's a guy called roadrunner 420 uk
who's in the uk of course and
he does incredible no-till
he is one of the people that showed me
what the results can be it's like i know
that the best of the best is always
going to be soil grown but the problem
is
it's so hard to get that right and to
dial that right it's like i would do i i
once took over growth from some people
and it's like out of the room i had some
plants were like the best thing i've
ever smoked but
it was like 20 of the plants were like
that i couldn't get them all to be right
i had some deficiencies here and some
bits there
and
now
as a breeder grow in so many different
strains
all the time cocoa is easier for me to
maintain
but as far as smoking than the best of
the best
my outdoor no-till dragonfly of medicine
in the ground in the sun
that's probably my favorite thing ever
it's like that's what i really love it's
like i love to grow outdoors if i could
be somewhere at the perfect climate had
a long season outdoor sun grown is
something magic about those turps it's
like indoors
yeah if i had a small tent i would do no
chill i'd keep it like that i may
i may move into that over time but it's
something i need to practice on a
smaller scale dial in become confident
with and then go towards i can't make
such a big jump when i'm dealing with
like
30 to 40 different mother plants that
i'm keeping healthy and making seeds but
as far as seed-wise the best seeds i've
ever made are the ones i made
outdoor organic grown they are the
biggest fattiest
healthiest
most
incredible looking seeds like you have
yeah i have problems putting them in a
vial because they're so much bigger than
the normal seeds that you just about get
15 in a vial
that's uh that sounds lovely
like eventually that's where i would
like to get to it's just going to be a
progression where i get the tech right
get myself confident and then i will
eventually move to a no-till kind of
grow set up that's like that's that's
the goal you know what i mean i don't
know how close it is but i think that's
that's the goal at the moment i'm very
lucky that i've got a couple of good
nutrient companies buddha's tree and
shogun nutrients that i use and they're
both uk based companies
i've said to people as a uk breeder
although i'm not living in the uk
i expect the uk growers to support a uk
breeder so
i myself try and support uk industry as
much as i can so when it comes to me
getting my packaging or stickers done i
use sticker express if i'm getting my
nutrients i want a uk brand if i want
lights i want crop master led you know
like i will always try my best to use a
uk company if possible because
i'm trying to tell people look i'm a uk
guy breeding i've got just as good as
anywhere in the world
geograph geography doesn't dictate
quality genetics it's about the hard
work that you put in
and
the genetics that you've got so i can't
push my brand to uk people and not do
the same
yeah of course and that's exciting to
hear that you're almost fully there with
the no-till and a quick shout out to
road runner and vic firth two homies
holding it down in the uk
um so
we've talked about how in barcelona this
is a established concentrate scene as
well as in the broader spain in general
is there a similar phenomena going on
where vape carts are taking over the
scene like we see in the states
yeah sadly vape carts are like the
casual smoker kind of thing that people
who can't roll a joint or whatever just
want to buy them so there has been a bit
of an influx and amongst all the [ __ ]
that people have been bringing over from
america there's like a bunch of like
renamed carts that you could just tell
with like hot dog water with extra eagle
20s you know i mean that's
like micro butanol tips wow and so what
do you think we can do to help counter
this and get people to realize that you
know like a really good grown flower or
really nice made concentrates or a
superior product
i think you've got name and shame i
think people need to go around take
samples from a bunch of places get them
all tested and then name and shame
people that are putting out products
with these things on them and then
slowly the people that put in the work
and work hard to get a clean room and
not use pesticides and not spray things
on it's like i go above and beyond to
only use
beneficial
microbes and things like that because i
don't want residue on my plants because
any residue is going to come off in an
extract so to keep a clean garden and
not have anything with residue
it's horrendously [ __ ] hard to get
to a level where you're happy and
keeping a clean garden
so
it's hard when that's not appreciated so
when testing becomes more prevalent i
can't wait because everything i put out
will get tested
and that will be one of the points that
i want people to understand is
clean well-grown product that hasn't
been sprayed with [ __ ] is not easy
and until people actually know it's like
i i
it makes me
shake to think
the things that people are consuming
because
the export market that's happening from
a miracle of stuff that's going to fail
the standards is just terrible bro and
the distillate that's coming over it's
like
man people are using distilling things
and it's like wow you just know where
that's coming from distal it's you can't
get enough distillate in america to fill
the demand so if it's getting out the
prices it's getting out at
no wonder it's like it's a price is
where i've had to say to people like
that's not feasible bro go look in
america where it costs to get clean
distillate just tested and ask yourself
how you're buying it for that price in
europe
it's like
people need to wake up and really pay
attention to things because
sadly the market is making too much
money and i mean anything makes a lot of
money it brings in the wrong type of
people and there's opportunists they're
taking like how can there be
fake diamonds out now what the hell is
going on in the world where people are
selling tree sap diamonds and things
like that it's like it's just crazy so
the black market causes these problems
bro that's the reality of it the only
thing we can do is just work towards
some kind of
regulated market to avoid all the
fuck-ups
so what do you think is most optimal
legalization or decriminalization
decriminalization
yeah i think decriminalization and allow
people to use their intelligence and
allow people to test these things and
that to be part of it it's like i think
that makes more sense for people to like
bro if you if you want to be an idiot
and you want to get the cheapest thing
and you don't care that's going to be
your mentality no matter what goes on
you'll always go to a backstreet person
but if you're sensible you'll look for
the right things that have been tested
and all of that so the people that do
that will have the best spots it's like
if there's a place in barcelona that all
of a sudden everything's tested and that
certificate so say it's clean mold
pesticide fungicide free all of that and
they've done it off of their own back
they know the ones that people are going
to pay attention to they're the ones
people are going to want
so i think that brings us to our
quickfire questions before we wrap
things up so
first question i wanted to ask you
what's your favorite food
curry
what type
you know i'm from northwest london so
i've been bought up around west indian
and indian people so people from jamaica
[Music]
people from grand
grenada people from like barbados so
hot
jamaican west indian curries and lots of
indian food i was brought up around a
lot of indian friends so the best indian
food in the world outside india is in
london it's like we've just got
incredible spots so yeah those are my
favorites i actually miss the indian and
the jamaican food from england more than
anything
for sure so what's your favorite thing
to do in your spare time
spend time with my dogs just enjoy
living in the mountains and going for a
peaceful walk with just nothing around
other than beautiful scenery
that's really the
the most enjoyable times when i'm most
at peace road
have a nice few fat dabs and set myself
off on a nice little walk with the dogs
this sounds lovely so next question what
has been the most memorable canvas
you've ever smoked in your whole life
i smoked african land race when i was
like 16 and it made me go blind for like
three minutes on a high street
chasing that high
bro i've been looking for that one ever
since
i've done so many other psychedelics and
drugs in my like adult life and never
once has it been as terrifying as those
three minutes
wow best and worst three minutes
okay so on the other end of the spectrum
what was the worst strain you've ever
smoked and my follow-up is
what's the worst strain you've ever
smoked part one and then part two is
smoked that somehow got a lot of
commercial traction and other people
liked
worst dream i've ever smoked
i'm from the days
of
sticks and seeds
so
when i was like
maybe 1999
or 2000 yeah say 98 or 99
98 it would have been yep that's it i've
done a mental mess in 1998
i was getting weed that was coming in
with albanian guys and i think it was
like from albania or somewhere in that
part of the world and i was paying like
25 pound an ounce now bear in mind ounce
of weed normally was like 140.
so 25 pound an ounce for this weed it
was
it was horrendous bro it's like you lit
like it was one of the things that
started making me smoke pure because i
was just had so much of it and you
needed to smoke so much of it you could
actually just leave the tobacco out and
just smoke two grams
so that was the worst weed i've ever
smoked but it was just funny because i
was getting so much of it and moving so
much of it but my god it was terrible
bro it was it might have been hemp i
don't even know
and then so what's in your opinion is
the weirdest strain which you didn't
really like but it's commercially it
seemed to take off
do you know what yeah
i'll probably seem like a [ __ ] hater
for saying this
but for me i don't i've never been that
taken by july
it's like for me like i can understand
why skittles is hyped
it's got a profile that makes people go
wow like it's incredible to profile i
can understand why sherbet is like
sherbert's got a wicked like i love that
profile i can understand the height
behind that it's like
lemon tree it's like when that kick got
hyped up i'm like i've got something
that smells like lemon tree you know
like a lot of things
i've got something i can go like i've
got something that smells like i've got
someone who smells like that so
i can see hype when things don't but
gelato
disappointed me every time i've smoked
better crosses of gelato than gelato
i've been disappointed by all the gelato
but some gelato crosses i've been
impressed by
there you go the inception so our next
question
you're on a desert island you can only
take three strains with you what are
they i would take
my chem valley cook's mail
and then i would take
my
grape lemonade 23
and then i would take
a term silica
lovely and then you'd get to work
yeah and then i'll be good i'll be able
to go in many directions
that's a tropical fruit on the tropical
island
lovely lovely happy with your coconuts i
like it so the next one is
if you could have one clone back that
you've lost or one that you wanted but
we're just never able to get your hands
on what would it be
there's two there's one i can get back
and i'm gonna get back at some point and
then there's one that i can never get
back
yeah yeah do tell more the one i can
never get back is a cut of sour bubble
that i had
which is from bog
now bob will say publicly that that's a
freak fino of bubble gum
i've heard from someone that he
privately said it's a sour bar but it's
a bubba cush cross
every anyone who knows anything about
bubba kush knows sour bubble is a bubba
cush cross i don't want to hate on bog
he's a lovely guy i've got a lot of
respect for him but
sour bubble is bubba crush on bubble gum
i would bet my life on it may i be
struck down by lightning if i'm telling
a lion anyone who smoked it tell me what
you think i would love to see comments
on this one but that for me as much as
it was that it was incredible so it's
like i criticized him for not admitting
what it was but i'll be honest it was
probably the silliest thing he ever done
because if he would have said back in
the day what it was it would have blown
up even more and been even more hyped
and at a time when
it was kind of like reservoir seeds and
bog were the two kind of hype companies
online and it was all about being sour
because sour diesel had blown up and bob
was trying to capitalize and get in on
that hype market so he done that cross
called it sour bubble but said it's a
freak sour fino of bubble gum because
his whole line is bubble gum based but
i've heard
he said to someone in private that yeah
it's a bubba kush hybrid so there you go
we've heard that sentiment before and
then what about the one you can get back
the tk the triangle cushion i'm waiting
for that one to come back to me but of
all the things yeah the triangle
cushion's the one i'm missing i just
i haven't really
made an effort to get ropes like it'll
come back eventually it'll come back i'm
like i'm not a
chase chase chase things a few people
know that i want it eventually they'll
come to me
yeah i share that sentiment she's a
amazing plan i am i miss her quite a lot
so
the next one the final question if you
could go back in time anywhere any place
anytime throughout history and get some
seeds
where are you going and when
i would go back to when thailand
had loads of thriving things there's
something about thai weed i love all the
different variety and the one that i
really really
crave more than anything is the old
juicy fruit type
i would go back to when the juicy fruits
i was there and was undisturbed and was
just
ready for the plugin and get that to
work with
really really solid answer so any shout
outs or comments you'd like to make
yeah shout outs to all of the uk scene
so the guys that wrecked my stuff mr
matic south smokers club to ice toker 75
mr green fingers 420
to the whole uk scene like bone mouth
farms and bezel who are doing projects
together now getting into breeding and
doing cool collabs and
everyone the whole uk scene that's
thriving there's so many like
yeah there's so many good companies
coming up you should everyone should
really pay attention to the uk scene
it's a small island but my god the
passion there is incredible and
when
prohibition eventually ends you're going
to be able to see some incredible
growers and people that are just
doing amazing things so
all of those people in the uk
my cousin
raw phantom on instagram
the barcelona people
turps army farm fresh flower farm
those good good people that have offered
me seeds over the years all the people
that have offered me clones all the
people that have sent me clones
everyone that's helped me get to where i
am supported me through hard times
people under the stairs genetics who
helped me out of a difficult difficult
situation and auctioned some seeds for
me during a difficult time and basically
covered my rent when i was in dire
trouble so just know that this industry
has got community in it it may be
turning into a big
industry but in its heart there is a
community and there are people out there
that do this for love and passion if you
pay attention you'll see who's who
yeah what a lovely sentiment so again a
big big big thank you again for coming
on sharing all your stories and setting
the record straight on a few things
barry of true canon genetics
awesome talking to you bro it's been a
pleasure i love your show every episode
is just engrossing i love the history
and hearing all the different stories
from everyone can't wait until the next
one's out
so again a huge thank you to true for
taking the time stop by chat today
[Applause]
[Music]
i'm digging the eu vibes guys i hope you
guys are as well
as always huge shout out to seeds here
now radio ridge nursery organic
gardening solutions
[Music]
green sleeves merchant tile you know you
love them they're the sponsors that make
this one happen we appreciate them so
very very much
and as always dragonfly fam patreon gang
we love you to the moon and back thank
you so much for all you do
[Music]
i'll see you for the next one guys
we'll see
[Music]
you