foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts
[Music]
you're joined as always by your boy
heavy days here from the upside down
library and as always this episode could
not happen without the amazing support
of our sponsors speed here now number
one seed bank in the game guarantee on
satisfaction not just germination why
grow anything else you might be unhappy
at the end go to seeds here now they
promise you'll be stoked at the end they
only stock quality breeders and if
you're not hit them up they'll sort you
out with some new seeds what more could
you ask for well you got to make sure
you get the crop right first and to do
that you should go check out coppet
biological systems with the largest
range of predator mites and other
natural enemies in the game be sure to
check out their new spydex vital a
predator mic with proof of predation
color changing system where the personal
smites will change from white to Red
after they've eaten spider mites so you
can sure they're doing their job
likewise make sure to go check out our
new sponsor promix they've got a
fantastic new product called Pro next
connect which is a mycorrhizal document
that'll help ensure you have a robust
Harvest
you after increase yield increased resin
density and all the things that make
your crop stand out from the rest make
sure to check out Pro mix mycorrhizae
via make sure to check out Pro mix
connects your number one micrizal
product in the game
foreign and last but not least we would
not be able to do this without all the
Fantastic sponsors over at the patreon
Gang
if you would like to help ensure that
future episodes continue to happen
please go check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast you'll get exclusive access to
unheard interviews bonus content
giveaways and so so so much more please
go check it out
on this episode we are extremely lucky
to be joined by one of the land race
Legends of the scene doobie of Ace
genetics here to give us the rundown on
all the different land race hybrids he's
working on origins of different genetic
lines the culture in Europe and so so so
much more we are so excited for this one
so without further delay
let's get into it
so hello and welcome to the next episode
of the podcast we are very lucky today
as we are joined by one of the land race
Legends and preservers of our sin Dooby
of Ace genetics thank you so much for
joining me today
thank you all very much Happy Days it's
a pleasure to have you here at the
podcast
and to be with all your audience
I really appreciate this opportunity
and yes as I told you my English is not
the best but I hope you
I hope make me feel understand and I
hope you enjoy the conversation thank
you very much
uh you are very humble don't worry your
English is great and I'm sure people are
still going to enjoy it because you've
been one of our most requested guests
we've had for a while how does it feel
to be so popular
um yes I have I never expect that I
think
that's uh that's really touching so no
thank you
not a problem so the first guest we've
been asking people sorry the first
question we've been asking our guests
lately is what are you currently smoking
on
at the moment a
I have some New Caledonia boats here I
have
a some CBD one I have some Moroccan hash
I have some a bit of Indica airport
across pck
and a few more and I have Chinese Cali
China and yeah a few other sativas yes
wow that's a really nice selection you
have there can you tell us a little bit
about the new Caledonian that sounds
very rare yeah yeah yeah it's um
that we worked last year and it has been
released this year
it came from a grower through
interchange a swap of genetics we I did
with him
he was a very established grower there
in New Caledonia
and he was interested also in ursativa
so we did an interchange he sent me a
lot of seats from from the island the
sativasi grew up there
um
yeah I think we did the seat swap around
2012 and only at this time I I consider
the silver getting too old so it was
time to germinate them and explore a bit
the genetics
um knowing that we work with landrage
with sativas he sent me a lot of ships
toward them and to refine the line and
spread the genetics honestly I didn't
know what to expect at the beginning
um certainly was something really new I
don't know how we will link with other
genetics I'm more familiar with
and yes we grew like last year like we
still like 100 plants of the New
Caledonia from I have like three
different seed Lots uh two with more
seats it was the seed lot a and the
signal of B we took like 50 seats from
each
um and Grill all of them together
indoors and yes initially the the grill
like wolf like really tropical sativas
um
very slow to reach the sexual maturity
to show sex
indoors they grow really big very big
Rose
and yes I was thinking that uh we had
something really really tropical on
hands when we switched Switzerland to
flower they also took their street time
to to really start to flower
so yeah yeah they were in the really
tropical or a list of tropical yes
because New Caledonia is around 20 in
the South hemisphere latitude and is not
really very close to the equator but
it's tropical
um
and yes once the plants start to to
flower yeah it was really tropical it
took the shooting to to flower
and we found like maybe a third pla
like a third part of the population was
a hermaphrodite
so here's the this is very typical when
you when you explore new land races
especially sativa and races from the
tropics is quite common to find a lot of
Hermes in the first P1 generation
and yeah we will eliminate the
airmaphrodites we saw some plants
adapting better to to in the growing
reacting better so start to form resins
so interpense also so we had the chance
to start to evaluate which one were more
promising we clone
when we started to eliminate the
hermaphrodite we start to clone all the
rest of the plants that were sexually
stable
uh like it was like it's quite common
also with tropical sativas is that
usually the the Sati the the female to
male right here is very high uh that
means that you find maybe 78 of the
males and the rest only males and within
this tool also a lot of fermis in this
case a third part so yes at the end we
remove like half of the plants after
eliminate the Hermes and plants that
after many many many ways didn't respond
didn't do anything or or comparing with
other were lacking of racing after pins
so yeah the MVA we came out like with 30
plus really nice females
um five sexually firm males
and then we'll open pollinate the um the
with the finals all different males at
the same time as I told you we had all
clones from all these more promising
females in the mother room or backup
copies
um yes and then the the reproduction was
a success we pollinated all the more
than 30 females that were sexually firm
that were sexually firms too
and and then when they finish the the
reproduction they're ripe I was able to
evaluate better which were were more
rationals and with better the pencil
also they were seated
so the most promising was I I broke
clones to all the growing to do uh since
a media cycle
that means without pollination to to
evaluate properly the flower without
seeds Outdoors which is I feel you that
this strain Express itself better
Outdoors than indoors at least in this
initial generation so yes it was
surprising because we moved the clothes
a bit late in August
which is a bit late for planting even
for tropical sativas but they catch up
very very fast the smoke clones grow up
almost like two two meters
and and around late October they were
already
finishing uh yeah maybe they will need
one two weeks more but they reacted
Outdoors much faster and better than
indoors yes
and another time when when they were
starting to write my God I was really
excited because I started to smell like
incredible refined to the fruit the
Aromas the the um the reasons were very
good and normally signs in the plans we
we were testing Outdoors so our
selection were in the right direction
regarding regarding quality too
so yes at the end we we end up with
evaluating like eight females the most
promising females from the silver
production we evaluate them Outdoors
without seats then we start to smoke
them we brought them to the lab for kind
of we know they enter pen analysis I
already did some genetic analysis a few
years back
so yes with all the smoking tests the
smoking The Growing Experience the
silver production yeah we decided we
were extremely
uh excited about this news genetics when
we I when I started to smoke it I was
wow it has been so long that I don't
feel this quality of high in a sativa
like you smoke it and everything becomes
super clean Vivid you you feel like the
the colors more intense
but not with Distortion Like Everything
More Alive the the sound also you you
can hear even the father-son super
strong then you feel like a big energy
growing up from from inside like you
become creative connected with your
surroundings uh you you feel uplifted
motivated your psyche is well focused
it's a very very good quality High very
very good
um to be honest about the origins of the
genetics I think is not so linked really
with uh
alandres I would say the Finnish product
has
quite tight qualities in the smoke like
especially in the taste it's a soul lime
lemonade taste that is quite common on
on Time land races
and the effect is quite thai-like very
clear up
but the flower structure
is more a bit more like a Mexican or
like American sativa it's not so Lucy
like the ties that the ties usually have
a very Lucy flower structure or very Fox
style not not dense a real pure ties
never dance but this one makes a
quite quite quite dense buds for for for
a pure sativa traits flower instructors
that I have seen more in certain
Mexicans or even more modern Colombians
uh but there is my feeling is someone
like uh take like a Thai American sativa
mix that makes sense to the audience
regarding the Finnish blog and it's very
interesting line we have released this
year and we cannot wait to to hear the
opinion of The Growers and sativa lovers
about this new line yeah
wow what an incredibly comprehensive and
detailed answer I'm very excited to ask
you some more questions I think this is
going to be a great interview
I'd love to know you mentioned kind of
how you went about weeding out the
hermaphrodites at first and sort of
stabilizing the line when you get a land
race line from seed do you find that you
have to selectively breed out the
hermaphrodisms or it just over
Generations naturally stabilizes
usually it depends how domesticated is
the land race but there's usually
for example if you get cyst from a
language that has been refined and tame
but very
properly by a grower like taking very
well care of the gene pool and all the
individuals involved in every generation
in this in these cases which are very
rare you can expect lower hermaphrodite
rates in in these cases in these land
race but most of the times the land
races are grown uh
you must feel like many plants every
generation whether you see in
Afghanistan Pakistan or India or in
Morocco or in Colombia they grow many
many plants and not all the farmer not
all the traditional farmers are very
diligent or or very efficient to remove
to fully remove their Aphrodite traits
in in the people in their population
that is for example because usually in
houseplant population and they don't
mind all the plants are fully seeded
whether it's in Morocco or Lebanese or
Afghanistan or Pakistan the the plants
get completely fully seeded so they are
not not very worried most of the times
that they select Pro they choose a good
males that are sexually firm but
sometimes uh some male hermaphrodite
hermaphrodites can Skype they can escape
sorry and they can also pollinate so
yeah big populations libraries like this
usually have in some in given plants
some hermaphrodite
traits somewhere in some land races it
could be more evident in others not
but yeah most of the times when when we
receive the uh the P1 generation the P1
generation is I refer to the the first
generation seats collected in C2 in the
place of origin of the land race okay
um usually when we start to work with
the P1 land regeneration is very typical
that I find a lot of hermaphrodites and
it's very common that I need to clean
a lot the the land race in this first
generation
some language tend to be more or they're
lesser and also most land race are Auto
genetics obviously so when you bring
them to indoor for to evaluate them to
to select them and and all this
the auto genetics that have been grown
for many many generations centuries
Outdoors they don't really like the
indoors suddenly like you put them in
with artificial light like short stable
photo periods that they are not used to
it so they they very easily show
more in my for the trash that they will
do outdoors in in their place of origin
so but it's a good thing because you
force the the jump pull your of the land
race you are working with to to show any
problem any problem indoors any kind of
indoor habitability
any army tendency you can detect them
much easier indoors and yes I try to
remove all the hermaphrodite plants from
from the first generation
only if I don't have any plans to work
with I will reproduce using maybe one is
likely hear me but it has never been the
case usually if I have no plans I remove
Fuller me and then Focus only in the
sexually stable I I have
yeah great thank you so much for that
answer
I noticed that when you were talking
about all the different things you were
smoking at the moment you mentioned
Earth or however you pronounce it it's a
it's a very interesting strain I think I
read online that it was sort of worked
on in Sweden maybe and that it has like
a strawberry flavor can you tell us what
you know about the back story yeah yeah
yeah and I know I read this
these are quite interesting story in the
the airport is a a neighbor which in
German means strawberry
it was a an Afghani an Afghanistan that
was very widely grown in Switzerland uh
almost 20 years ago in Switzerland they
have like a
the Hella the the Golden Era of the
Swiss cannabis time that was almost 20
years ago they legalized for a few years
also the TA SQ cultivation Journey was
around that time when breederer Steve or
Mr Nice and other breeders went to
Switzerland to to legally for a few
years I think get out of control and
then the Swiss government stop it out
and now that it was Switzerland was
quite straight for 20 years and now with
all the CBD scene they are in a new
golden era in Switzerland but more with
the CBD produce but at that time they
were growing uh CBD sorry DC secretive
streams and one of the Clones Afghani
clones that they work uh and grow a lot
it was the Herbert we was in Afghani
that they used to grow indoors in big
indoor rooms for to sell in in the
coffee shop in the Swiss officials at
that time and it was a quite popular
Afghanistan in in Switzerland like 20
years ago also a
in at that time in Switzerland there was
also a local seed bank it was all all
seats
the breeder was Felix
and and he used to grow outdoors in
Switzerland he was a Swiss Auto grower
and and he got a purple suicidal line
from some old ladies he said that it was
the purpurati finances okay because it
was grown in pichino
it was purple so so it was called
corporate titianensis it was a very it
was more sativa a happy strain
the origins of the populated finances
are not clear some people say it could
be an Himalayan strain
is not clear but it was already an
outdoor restraint that was very adapted
to Swiss
climate and it was very purple very
early flowering very resistant so the
indoor airport
was closed with purpuria to titinances
okay uh and then it came out the airport
okay
uh when airport came out uh
the the Golden Era of the streets THC
times and up
um I'm some Danny's breathers like has
been a nurse and nosbe work the their
poor genetics
one two three generations that are in
there in Denmark
and in Sven which is a friend of mine is
a great
breeder a very kind person uh I
encourage or obvious to discover more
about his seed bank he is hybrids from
hell I don't know if you know about it
he's specialized in in breathing
Northern lines for yeah for called
Northern climates and he has many
interesting semi-auto flooring strains
that finish very well in in Denmark in
northern Europe countries
um and he passed me the airport after
work with Australian outdoor two three
generation in 2000 I grew up I grew the
stream from him in 2006.
but he gave me the Cs to start to work
with them in a more serious way in 2012.
um in 2012 we we start to work the
strain indoors Outdoors we saw some
Aphrodite Tendencies when we brought the
line indoors is what I told you with the
land race it's very typical when you
take another line that has been work and
selected many generation Outdoors when
you're bringing indoors is very typical
the the some some parental plans give
some some hermaphrodite problems okay
um so we work the strain indoors a bit
to try to adapt the the genetic centers
to to remove this empholitism indoors
mainly
um and and yes one thing that was never
done with airport their pool was already
a very consistent line for earliness for
cold resistant
um for very beautiful colors okay the
the airport has like two main phenoms
the Herbert was a green Afghani and the
corporation finances was a very colorful
plant so the mix between the Green
Albert Afghani and the purpose finances
produce like a blend of colors and some
leaning to the Green Airport so more
green in color and others leaning to the
very colorful to the purpley tendency
with purple red black colors and
sometimes also in between
and
and yes the qualities of this line for
earliness for cold resistant that were
clear and The Taste is quite nice like
the the colorful have a berry taste the
green Afghani
phenotypes have a more earthy has
a taste of when it taste very classic
Afghani taste and these are the terpenes
that you can find in the line
but being an Afghani line
uh you know Afghanistan don't really
they could be problematic with the
buzzword
uh in late flowering you know because in
Afghanistan
is a very dry climate so all the
genetics from there are used to to
flower with very dry conditions with
very strong temperature but with low
moisture that's why a lot of the Indica
Afghani genetics are very
uh susceptible our very prone to to
bathroom to about treating solder okay
and that was the case also with airport
because it contains a heavy stronto of
Afghani genetics both in Denmark that is
a wet country and here in my Coastal
climate of my my climate here in Spain
is very warm but I have a lot of
moisture because I live very close to
the coast so yes we we found there put a
bit problematic with the with the
bathrooms
air since 2012 we worked like maybe
until now we have worked like maybe four
generation indoors and three generation
outdoor in regular and feminized format
and through all these Generations we
brought samples to the lab and then we
identified no one did before that the
airport
also have a CBD content like it's very
typical from Afghanistan language
population this is a topic that we can
discuss later and no one knew this
before the airport whether it was a DAC
reached strain it was clearly secretive
so it had THC but we we thought
evaluation work and study at the lab we
conform scientifically the airport was
also CBD Rich strain most of the
phenotypes are a one-to-one THC CBD
chemotype balance usually with 780c to
70 A2 CBD so quite balanced it gets you
high is not the most strong Indica but
it's not a notificative is scheduled
quite quite High and and yes there are
some we found some very rare phenotypes
that only have CBD but a little THC but
more or less it's like a balance THC CBD
strain barriently flowering the good
think of of the air put is that it has
the same out of semi-auto-florine trade
from the finances what does a meal to
flowing means that it's a a concept that
is a bit confusing for for many it's
semi-auto flooring because it's not
fully autoflowering it means that you
can keep clones in the mother room you
can keep them for long term you can even
try to Rebecca the plants this is
completely impossible with fully
autofluoring genetics okay but yeah or
monally they tend to flower at the
anytime for example when they feel Rock
bone they they try to to flower when
they feel that there's just a slight
decrease of photo parallel outers they
try to to flower and so they have a very
early flowering flow very early flow
flowering on set outdoor when you when
most of the Afghani in the restraint
start to flower in maybe in August in my
latitude to finish in early October the
airport may be starting July and
finishing late August early September
okay the flower is 45 50 days but it can
start to floor one to one month and a
half ahead and other Afghani strange
that had no similar to flowing so this
is an advantage for call for Golden and
yeah and for an early Harvest and this
is more or less the quality and the the
history of the airport we have made some
high-risk with them
song with THC some with CBD
and yes it's a very interesting plan by
itself for medical because we have both
TSC and CBD it has a very relaxing high
and good for pain good for for muscles
for insomnia
and
yes and it's also a very useful plant
for breathing for alieners and for
interesting chemo types
wow what a brilliant answer thank you so
very much speaking of CBD you also
mentioned cbd1 and I noticed you had
made that more recently what inspired
you to make that and do you want to do
more CBD lines in the future
when the the CBD is honestly a very
interesting field is as you well know
that we have had 10 years or more like
uh the CBD Revolution
like
people realization of the medical
benefit of CBD and there's now a
completely uh boom in the industry for
for CBD products in a tall range of
products whether it's a genetic seeds
extraction flower Edibles
for medicine and in the National Health
Systems everywhere so yes when we asked
I start with this I am not going to like
you I was more interested to get high on
the recreational side of the of the
Cannabis like many people but yes and
obviously understand and not all the
people
approach to cannabis from the
recreational side and some people really
need it as a medicine
uh I I also was started to last years
like a bit of anxiety and myself so yes
I I feel like like it was also a good
moment to to focus more on on breathing
with CBD also for myself but also for
others
um and yeah I saw that at least here in
Europe in in
United States the thing is much more
advanced because with the legalization
and all the resources and the qualified
people they have there they have a lot
they have advanced a lot in in the hand
breathing and to develop same lines with
CBD that are very very interesting they
have they have done and they are doing
an amazing job there in in United States
but here in Europe the the pioneers of
the movement to
to put in that way that where Jaime from
racing seats here in Spain yeah
curiously the the main lines the main
CBD lines
that came out to the scene to the CBD
game and the CBD breeding that were more
useful
um
I'm more appreciated that Growers came
from Spain
it was from Jaime from racing seats
which was the the first to identify in a
in a
you know the SL hybrid CBD and then he
call it they call it cannotonic it won a
cannabis capture in Spain and then you
got a lot of reputation after won the
cup and after being analyzed for CBD
and then the the origins of of the
Canada were
were not clear and finally we knew that
it came from another Spanish event
called Dragon seats that they were also
working with many the the SL hybrids and
Richard CBD DSL hybrids mainly
and these were the the main source of
the CBD richer strains that later make
the woman in Europe and later were
brought to United States they were very
interesting because they taste like and
look like the best DSL okay
DSL
and but they they contain lot of CBD
okay
yeah so with this moment the Jaime
created the Russian seeds offering some
CBD strains and then Jaime from Russian
sheath I think joined with is called
Blake from Santi Baba from Mr Nice to
make CBD crew and I think CBD crew were
giving a breeding CBD breathing services
or to many other companies in Europe
like serious cities
and that's passion
many others so yeah eventually many CBD
strains came out from all the seed banks
but all these strains
yeah
and didn't have the the chemical type
stabilized they were very irregular in
chemo type so
when these signs were offering CBD
strains but the chemothai was not
stabilized and they say yes you could
have 50 percent of balances
CBD 25 only CBD and 25 TC with TSC and
no CBD I said well this is from the
medical point of view is crazy because
the the grower don't know what's the
chemotype of his plants and he he or she
cannot tolerate well the THC and he or
she got that is he planned from
so-called CBD seeds is is not a good job
so yeah at that moment people were
releasing it really strange like
Non-Stop and then I had a friend that
used to work for Jaime many many years
ago and he got some kind of tonic as one
sits from the original clone from
cannotonic
he got sulfates or of that club my
friend got this is for for many years
and he told me lubi these things are
getting old do you want to do something
with them
we will check it out
um
and and and then we
he for me and he told me at least I
think I have some interesting things
from these plants I was about to take a
flight to the holidays
okay you just give that glance when I
come back here from holidays we will
check it out yeah I came from holidays
we check out the plants and brought all
the samples of other plants to the lab
and then we realized scientifically that
the catatonic original clone that was it
had a balanced chemotype it was uh yeah
I cannot remember maybe eight to ten THC
to 10 CBD was like this
and when you sell fit and you grow the
S1 seats okay
and we we found out uh
uh all the main chemo types in the S1
and this one should behave like an F2
for the chemotypes in the as one sees we
found THC Rich plants
balance THC CBD plants like the original
canatonic and then we found we found
also only High CBD plants with very
little Tac
from one of them we found one that was
27 CBD content which is the the plan
that with a lab report not that
someone's says that no I have a 30 CBD
plan okay so you show man analysis we
did it we have an analysis that proves
that the cannotonics as one plan we
selected
um
it contains 20 some percent CBD and
around one THC then we have another
system with a similar chemotype that was
17 18 CBD and 0.7
a THC okay the most interesting was the
CBD one the one I tell you that had 27
CBD
and the other was cbd5
and uh it's some very easy when you say
okay we already have phone uh from the
cannotonic population the the ones we
won with the very high CBD and OTC chemo
time we just need to to cross this the
the plants from the cannotonic as one of
the chemother we want between each other
to stabilize this camo type okay the the
plan so someone quite easy but
unfortunately
they were infertile
this is a problem that sometimes you
find in S1
in as one generation as one
self-pollination is the highest form of
embredding there's it's like
having kids only with yourself there's
not other higher form of human breathing
you maybe could have kids with your
sister it would be a very high form of
inbreeding but it's even highest in
writing to totally produce Offspring
with your genotype without introducing
any other genotype this could
this one is a very interesting tool for
fixing trades for inbreeding very in a
very strong way but it can also lead to
to health problems like lack of vigor
mutations and one of the problems that
some of the S1 lines can show not all of
them is unfertility in this case was so
we try to pollinate cbd-1 with with CBD
file reversal
we try to pollinate a
cbd5 with cbd1 reversal it didn't work
so we we had like a wall we didn't know
how to advance in in the breathing at
that time I say okay where we have the
airport which is also a CBD Rich line it
has nothing
stabilized to be only CBD
reach the airport but it's another CBD
Rich that is fertile and we can try to
introduce to the unfertile uh canatonic
S1 plants that we cannot reproduce
unfortunately it was still a bit
infertile but we managed to do a cross
between the CBD one and the Green
Airport okay and this
F1 cross we it was the CBD cross Airport
uh
it had like 50 percent the the balance
uh THC CBD chemo types like Airport
and 50 only High CBD
and low TSC chemo types like this CBD
one kind of tonic S1 parental plan we we
selected
and and the mix of the pain of the pins
and dresses was amazing the Canton it
has very nice it'll be from from the
soul diesel Generations like a skunk and
all this
foreign
it was great so we want to focus only in
the high CBD plants
no TSC from the cbd-1 airport cross
we selected the the once I like move the
smoke and the love have the highestivity
we select the fourth elements of the F1
hybrid
and then we try we reverse again the CBD
clone It produced very very very little
and we managed to to pollinate these
four selected female of the F1 so
produce some somewhere like a back cross
okay uh CBD one airport close to 71.
okay then we grill the this back cross
the seeds and then we found that all the
seeds had stabilized the chemother
now we did it and it was not very
difficult obviously with you need help
from the lab or otherwise you are
selecting numbers blindly yeah but if
you have a lab and
yes the the way to stabilize follows
simple mandolin radius
you know it's it was the in the
canatonic S1 it is split in basic
Mandalay and radius also and when we did
the F1 cross we we cut a bit the chemo
times but also the the frequencies were
very mentally mandolin
uh and and finally we managed to
stabilize we we brought to the lab we
confirmed that all the plants uh were
like like we wanted then we selected
again the the four that we I like more
of the smoke
and I have a slightly more CBD than her
sisters and then we inbreed each other
we didn't cross again to the CBD one
clone because we wanted to make a a
commercial reproduction sometimes so
something that we can came out with a
lot of seeds okay and if we use again
this the series one original plan it
will ask to to very small reproduction
to the internal infertility so it would
be impossible to make a commercial
release so we embred the the Microsoft
parental place that I like the most
reproduce between them so in Red Line
what is embedding through the line
there was some slide fertility problem
but we really managed to produce
thousands and thousands of seats and
finally release the line with the
chemothers stabilized so summing up it
takes the best from Canada tonic with a
bit more of earliness from airports the
chemotype the best very chemo type of
the cannotonic was stabilized and this
is the work within the the other seal
companies
brilliant brilliant story they are
taking us through the whole creation
process that was fantastic so take me
back to when you were younger what was
your first experience with cannabis
yeah it was like a classy storyline
uh any any person could have I started
smoking in at the school around 14 years
old
and yeah my history is my story is quite
normal because nothing but it
illustrates quite well how is the
the how we grew up the Cannabis scene
and the Cannabis industry in the last 25
years
because it was quite on hand my
um
so here in Spain in the mid 90s we are
very close to Morocco okay uh the south
of Spanish just a few kilometers from
north of Morocco and the plantations of
Moroccan of Morocco is also in the north
not exactly down to Spain but but it's
very very close to Morocco and Morocco
has been since the 80s like the the
biggest fast producer in the world
so the the Cannabis culture in Spain has
been
until this new century has been always
been harsh Moroccan has always always
always always okay so you get a big of
the picture because here the the house
we we had all kind of quality of
Moroccan has very cheap
uh very easy to access and so
yes for us is it was the the Cannabis
culture in in Spain the the Moroccan has
so yes I started smoking Moroccan has
like in most Spanish did in in the 90s
or before
um yeah I love the
the the creative effect the relaxing
and many many friends love it also the
Cannabis is is called as the the great
times and memories great memories I have
from the child who I'm as a teenager
around cannabis and with my close
friends
is is countless so it's really a part of
of our life
uh we we grow up with it daily daily
and many of my close friends are really
passionate kind of his lovers so it's
it's really in our culture you know here
and here in Spain has been always quite
quite tolerate to smoke cannabis
so yes yeah the the Cannabis culture in
Spain regarding
regarding cannabis and specifically has
is very very strong
then uh yeah during my job and teenagers
what was available was mainly has
I had a good luck to experience
in the good time of of Moroccan has all
kinds all the good quality of hash
and around
96 97 here in Spain they start to appear
the Cannabis magazines and the first
Grow shops and this what this was really
the the revolution for the Homegrown
okay because previously
on these are
didn't know how to grow the plants they
didn't know anything about genetics the
the house was so cheap and so easy to
access the people just by has and smoke
has cannabis in that form so very people
agree and they grow very badly they
don't know what went to harvest they
don't know what it was a female or a
male it was not of me so but there was
not uh good books there was not internet
there were no good genetics
so yeah the people also strictly has a
few a few hippies maybe travel to India
and Nepal to buy some clothes or bring
here and they go some marijuana there
brought the seeds grow here or some
people here in Spain we have a lot of
contacts with the Latin American
countries and Mexico Colombia
Etc so to to get [__] from Mexico
Colombia it was quite common that's it
from Morocco also so some hippies Grill
some genetics that were from
displacement mainly Mexican Colombia and
a bit of Moroccan and also some Indian
Nepal mainly
they were sativas it was what and this
genetics they were grown very badly they
were reproduced with no criteria but
they had very funny effects they were
because they were satibas and they have
many very funny effects but with with
around 96.98 with the introduction of
this the magazines like kanyama which is
shrimp in English and and the first grow
so that they were selling well all the
cities the Lambs the fertilizer the
books with with information about how to
grow cannabis from books from the United
States then and people start to travel
to Holland to get seats and and all this
so the pictures started to change the
the has continued to be the main thing
but
I I remember in my case I started to
grow my first seeds that I grew were
Nepalese
Mexican Colombia and Moroccan yeah
um and and so that's That's genetics the
the first the genetics I grew was in the
96 and was in Hawaiian skunk
um when I harvest my friends were
tripping they had never seen we we with
such quality completely organic
we could Harvest like half kilo when you
are 16 years old this is so much money
and instead of buying and crafts with
your parents money and all this then we
say well we may need to start to to grow
but obviously with 16 years I was
dealing with with my parents my parents
didn't tolerate but I was so passionate
that they always allowed me to to put
some plants at home
with many many
discussions but yes I always had plans
at home always always had plans at home
then when I go to the university I go to
live alone with my friends
um
then I already have a few goals on on my
shoulders we grew in 1997 we grow like
many good lots of strains at that time
96 97 the the Dutch bank where at the
end of the the best time the Golden Era
of the Dutch breathing that it ended up
on around 96 97 when the Dutch
government
stopped the the seed banks they no
longer can build legally
so after 1997 The Shield guns they still
have a lot of good sales because they
produce before it was illegal and this
last until the new century a few years
later maybe 2005 so during this year we
got very very nice and it is the very
best genetics from Holland and at the
same time we we agree with the land
races we we were collecting so it was
very interesting because in the early
days me and my friends managed to to
realize
the
and we have very good climate here we
can grow almost all kinds of tropical
sativas and all kind of touch strain so
we we have the chance to compare the
super refined hybrid from the Census
seeds done by Nebel that put a lot of
work and a lot of a good job on them and
then go compare them with the land races
and then you see something so refined so
tame the the genetics and uses the the
land Race So raw but with some very
unique traits characteristics you know
so so
we how to say we appreciate but we've
seen since the start we we appreciated
both the super refined hybrid from
Holland and the unique qualities that we
will start to find in the land races and
this is how how big how we started and I
say and I asked to myself
I I will be able to to bring some things
as good as the data strange starting
from Land races
and that was a question that that arises
the early moment and
and I said well if others did I'm sure
uh I I will be able to to do it because
at the end
all the super strainers we have today
the course
or gym skank they they all came from
Land races obviously they have been
refined for so many generations that
they they are now very distant from the
land races but everything started from
the land races
so please give me uh another time the
internet was not not sure why you spread
so it was not yet so easy to get
information about land races
uh so I was testing both into know the
very very best at that time was in
Holland because in the mid 90s in
California they were starting to
legalize but Holland was still the main
half for genetics
um
and just like and try to bring learn how
to bring and try to to to come out or
breathe something really different and
unique from Land races that I could call
my work
and that hopefully as good as the best
status train on American strength
that was my my expectation when I
started but but more with the the
willing to learn not to achieve you know
that time was more like a hobby more
like a passion there was not any
business involved not even
a expectation to have a business about
it it was just patient yeah
fantastic you know an admirable goal to
be trying to improve on sort of those
early strains that really paved the way
for the future I guess I was wondering
was this sort of the moment when you
thought I would like to start Ace seeds
and what was it like when you first
started what were some of the first
projects you were working on
when I went to to continue connecting
with the previous question when I went
to study at the University
uh
uh there was it was not a big city
and the mangrove shop uh the the owner
hired me to to attend the Growers to to
we go working on on the grow shop
attending the Growers at that time the
the this was the
the biggest growth shop in the whole
Province so all the Growers not only
from the city but from the province came
to the grow shop to ask about seeds
about genetics about growing so for me
was like I learned a lot I learned a lot
because yeah now there are many growth
shops around
um and it is no longer the same but at
that time all the Growers from The
Province came to me so and I sell to
them all the genetics and and they grow
graduate and came back to me with
flowers with clones so
I managed to
to get the incredible clones the best
clones the from the refinance Trend like
the best the best skunks the best AK-47
Kali Mist
from magogenetes the Warlock
from homegrown genetics the everything
we got everything the the very best and
I learned a lot because all the Growers
came to me I had to to explain I learned
a lot because at that time the
information in 2000 was
very very short
so after working there for a few years I
I learned a lot and and I get a lot of
genetics I get a lot of contacts and it
was also the time that the internet
started okay I really uh and so and
there were some iconic uh old forums at
that time that were overgrow was the
main one and cannabis world
that very early times of the of this in
21st century the the worldwide cannabis
community that that was on internet we
we were posting and we were connecting
in mainly and overgrower and also in
cannabis world so it was a very
beautiful moment because it was the
start of Internet
in in managed to connect many Growers
from all around the world that
previously were all isolated one in in
North California and others in in Europe
others in in Latin America
Etc and and what that was like like a
wealth of information
it was incredible exchanging genetics
people from
from countries where the land races were
produced also started to connect to
these forums and we started to to to
exchange language genetics
and I'm from Spain there were not many
people interested in land races the only
a few
and it was mainly me Alex manonegro it
was a breeder from Canary Islands
in Spain and then kaiki Charlie Garcia I
I know him skyke from canabioghen
okay and then we all three met on the
forums
and
and we we really have the same
the same passion for the land reasons
so we we were talking a few years
exchanging seats
maybe was around 2002 then Alex
manonegra came to live to my city from
Canary Island with his girlfriend his
damn girlfriend
then I meet him in person kaiki was from
Madrid he had his company already there
Canada which was the first Spanish seed
bank the first Spanish cement that was
established
um and we all meet in person
and and then the the first years were
very very nice
we will have the same passion we have
different characters
uh kaiki and Alex were one generation
older than me there were around 50 plus
around that time I was just in my 20
plus I I was very young so they could be
always I was almost like my parents you
know
um I learned a lot from them because
obviously they have much more experience
with me in life and with plants
it was very enriching experience both
regarding cannabis and
friendship
and then we start to get in touch more
in person like in 2002 and then we start
to work the idea
to to make here in Spain like acid Bank
working more with land race with land
races
because it was our main interest not
many people were were doing it here the
the sea band that were appearing were
just interested in replicate the the
business model of the Dutch company and
to copy their genetics saying okay why
we know black domino are the best seller
in in Holland then we take lunch from
from from there we feminize and we make
a c bank in Spain that's how many
Spanish came out street series Dina fam
Etc okay but we wanted to make something
different like yeah like the the
planche from Holland were amazing but we
wanted to do something different and
from the scratch from the land races to
understand with different traits we to
to came up with something different and
learn through the process and
and yes and around 2005
the the idea of creating a seat was
already more mature we already have
collaborators
kaiki have a few friends collaborating
for him I had my friends
I had my other friends in in the
University I study I like his friends
but the the core of faces these early
stage was Alex Mano Negra kaiki from
Canada and me okay that was the the
pillars the three
foundational person
that created acids and then we came up
with with our first catalog
in 2005.
if we if one we can talk about it
yeah yeah I mean what were some of the
first projects that you were looking to
release as a company
we were really a few years in touch so
we have some hybrids already in progress
so when we came up with the the first
catalog into
a
there were five strings okay all in
regular seats at that time the
we didn't offer feminine seats yet
the the strange where the first six are
quite famous and are still available it
could be considered acids classes they
are Banky Hayes Congo Nepal Jam Orion
Express Panama
and then for more that were only
available
a very short supply in this first
catalog they were Renata which was a
Brazilian Cambodia case
hybrid then garage
which was a Nepalese Commando cross
lesoto
timan Firehouse this was from Alex
manonegra which was uh Cape Verde Mali
Nepalese sativa and Canela which was
from kaiki it was a northern Indian
cross Jamaica
and this was a first tennis streams the
the first six
uh have been available for for for the
last 16 years
our audience are more familiarized with
these ones
yes most certainly I think almost every
strain you just mentioned rings a bell
and I hope we can talk about them a
little more I just wanted to quickly ask
you
a lot of people were saying that uh
Charlie Garcia from Canada used to work
with you at Ace and I was wondering what
sort of projects did you do together was
that the first release and
um how come you guys decided to sort of
end that collaboration
it was more of what each person could
could offer to the project you know a
Alex Mano Negra um
a had a lot of experience with a African
sativas he lived in Canary Islands which
is is it belongs to Spain but is an
island that are quite far from Spain
very close to the African continent is
closer to Senegal than than to spend to
say it in that way
tropical is is like Hawaii for example
so you can grow excellent
sativas there the soil is volcanic the
radiation is strong the the temperatures
are warm the whole year there's still a
bit of photo period
so it's even better than than Thailand
or
or or Congo that there's no photo period
at all it's the whole year exactly the
same uh so he had a lot of experience
with with African land races sativas he
grew I don't know one of his most famous
words the angerless angerless red liamba
he also agrees from Senegal from Mali
from Cape Verde
Congolese
Mozambique
he was the African expert
and and kaiki he was one of the
foreigners Charlie Garcia is the person
that you you recommend he was one of the
founders of carnaviohen
and kind of your hand with when they
came out they already have like a few a
few strings that were very very very
good so
kaiki it was not new on the game to to
say in some way he has his parents he
already had lines there he has all the
with Canary handle really really strange
that were extremely good at that point
so
each of us contribute with what what we
had at that time was when I was starting
I was working with the Nepalese and the
Chinese
and the Vietnam Black so my
contributions were in the first catalog
were a Orient Express which is my first
hybrid
is Vietnam Black Cross China unan
and also to the Galleria hybrid
which is a
Nepalese Commando The Nepalese with the
Lesotho from Canada
is also a hybrid that I did with a
Brazilian by a sativa
pollinated with Cambodia Hayes from
brieferman
and the other restraints
for example the Banky case was a
Congolese hybrid that came out from Alex
Mano Negra it was a a very
very energetic
sativa hybrid with congoles genetics
but the problem is it was still a long
longer flowering
and the effect the effect was great but
it wasn't fertile okay and as time is it
was a colleague of of Charlie Garcia of
kaiki like a lot this clone from Mano
Negra and agree with
they told me was a an Annapolis
I managed to get some seeds and and with
this they managed to stay used to
breathe in in Galicia which is the north
of Spain is a very rainy part it's
colder the weather is not very good so
he managed to adapt this or original
long flowering Congolese hybrid to his
colder climate Okay in a fast flower in
sativa he also adapted to indoor growing
it making it smaller faster flowing 19
weeks
um but still capturing the hydration
production and a very electric effect of
the Congolese hybrid from Mano Negra and
he establized it
uh chainsaw big the conf the concept of
the plan agreed
the faster flooring more cold resistant
better adapt to indoor growing after
showing after free for generation
it came up with Banky case that's the
name they give to to the Australia each
one was free to to name his his
strengths in the in the way they wanted
so yes but you guys started from
Congolese hybrid from Mano Negra then it
was worked by a style a friend
of of kaiki
and
in
years later he was working by by Charlie
Garcia and since 2012 until now I wore
the line myself so yes the history of
the line if I tell you is a bit long and
we have contributed
each in different stages on a different
moments yes then we have the the Congo
the Congo was
uh uh
Charlie Garcia had a Congolese sativa
not from Mano Negra from another person
uh he crosses with the the chitrala and
Canada he made a Congolese Pakistani
traveler hybrid he worked and he left to
a free generation
and then to this Congolese
[__] F2 F3 hybrid I cannot remember it
was the 3D spot
reduce
which is Congo
it's a Congolese that is that has a
shorter flower in time okay
and um so Congo was originally a
a hybrid that was 75 congoles
and 25 percent Pakistani
and and yes it was work mainly with
genetics from Charlie Garcia and a bit
from Mano Negra
okay
um yes it was very very very nice it was
not so electric like the
like the banking case it had a more warm
foreign effect with a bit more of body
for both Australians were mainly Congo
is a strain but both are quite different
to each other okay
and um yeah uh later I never understand
why my colleagues wanted to name bangi
Hayes
like haste when the magical was not
infancy or didn't contain his at all
or why they wanted to call Congo I know
to Congo Pakistan when the hybrid was
originally a Congo Pakistan highway but
I was just a job man it was not my
strengths and everyone can name their
sins it's up to them so if they came up
with his name and until today
yeah we had some people ask sort of
about that but that answers a lot of the
questions so that's great I was
wondering though do you remember much
about what the Nepalese was like in its
pure form like do you remember how it
grew and what it smelled like or not
really the the stabilization of Bankers
was all done by a style the colleague of
of Charlie Garcia told you
what happened there
Cornelia I asked a few times
[Music]
they were not very very very very
concrete you know it was not my strain I
was very young at that time I didn't
want to be
but but yeah the strain that came out
was really something different it was
it was something something really you
know but yeah to answer the question I
don't know exactly what Nepalese train
go into the banks and how it went this
is a detail I escaped to my knowledge
yeah sorry
yeah no that's fine that's fine I was
hoping I could ask you a little bit
about the different Thai strains you
work with I had noticed many of them
looked really nice and I was interested
in how you would say the The Mao Thai is
a little different to maybe some of the
others
yeah the the Thai strengths
well as you know that that is
for for the sativa lovers is
one of the most important sativa land
race of all times regarding quality so
when we started to investigate and
looking for high quality peer sativa
land races from tropical origin
obviously the thighs were the ones that
interest as the the most in the in in
the first place
and yes
at the beginning
we have like
four to five
ties I like the Taiko Chang then we have
the Melody from Canada
that he was the one that was used used
by kind of your hand Destroyer a string
then
lately in the last decade has been
working with uh another from
from Chennai
and I used to grow another one that it
was terrible I did in my early days
there was this car very early on and I
feel that was called I-79 but I think it
was a highway this one came from
Australian grower called 20 Thai I have
the feeling that was a high will I
thought it was fantastic but not really
pure time
so here's the the three times the high
quality ties that we have been working
with acids
the kochan
the male type from Canada
and and lately more more Detachment you
can see really a lot of similar
similarities with between them and if
you compare with other green Vietnamese
or
or older Cambodian
[Music]
is what I call the green
stuff Asian sativa archetype
okay you can find in in the lowlands of
Laos Thailand
Vietnam Cambodia
a
genotype of greens solar station sativa
that is spread in in all those in all
these areas of these countries and they
share a lot of similar traits they are
green even with colder terms they remain
green
they have a long flowering time usually
four months or more
and they have a rich THC chemotype with
zero or with perilita or no CBD
that the terpene profile is also very
common in in
you know the different strains that
belong to to this archetype there are
Woody spicy
sore lime lemonade okay and the effects
and they are very cerebral not body
effects some are more nervous like would
be the male Thai some are pure joy super
clean uplifting refreshing
uh good energy goodbye like it was like
the kochang and others are more in the
middle like like the Titan mine
um yeah these are the three that that
I've been that we have been working more
we started first
with the
the multi
from Canada
um
gave us one a clone of a male that he
had of the pure milk Thai and I am and
where they have a lot of many crazy
sativas so in 2008
with the help of a friend of a colleague
we put the the pure Meal toy mail
to pollinate all of our best sativas the
green case the Purple Haze the taikochan
the pirangola the pear thermal
yeah well it was crazy we were the pure
Vietnamese
Vietnam Black
uh many interesting sativas and then the
next the next year we came up with
many interesting F1 type hybrids as
limited edition that were green high
style purple hairstyle Vietnam Black Tie
double tie that was kochan close to male
Thai
were given mostly As freebies the
Vietnam Black Tie was also released
um yeah they were extremely good where
they're extremely good uh sativa hybrids
and around 2015
I started to to grow some old tights on
my seats I had
I like it I like it a lot
and I made some hybrid
um with Kali China it came probably one
of it came out taichi which is probably
one of the hybrids I'm film or sprawled
off
and his Titan micros kalichina F4 and
it's amazing
and yeah we would these are the the time
we have been working lately
and we and also similar plans like the
green Vietnamese
and yeah if you go to to Northern Laos
the the strains are different are more
purple strings the effects are different
uh and if you go to Philippines the
strings are slightly different also if
you go to
Banda chain or Sumatra or the very
famous I'd say goal is slightly
different
yeah so I I believe the the green ties
the what people
recognize more or as Thai is belongs to
the green
suggestion archetype I describe
just now
yeah brilliant again just really did how
it answer thank you so much one of our
listeners wanted to ask the question
they're looking for a recommendation
from you that's either a tie or a Thai
hybrid that's got that really sort of
archetypal soaring soaring nice tie high
but something that's a little bit on the
shorter flowering side if possible what
would you recommend
oh yeah yeah we have a Tai Chi the the
date is amazing the
um
how to describe this
it has the the most exotic intense
Aromas from the Cali China is extremely
intense
exotic like liver roasted meat in terms
hash
with Violet flowers with tropical fruits
mangoes a creamy
sweet and short like a taste of a
Chinese restaurant is super completely
the terpene profile of a good college
China and when close with the Titan mine
uh in the Kali China is my my best
Chinese hybrid it's a Chinese Indica
very fast flowering I added a bit of
Cali Mist to reinforce the the intense
Aromas and a bit more sativa effect on
Kali China
and I find the Cali China with thus
wonders when grows with with good
sativas because the Kali China is not so
it has the the very low infants that
many people is looking inside the best
strength or it faces strange but in an
Indica strain the high is very positive
not a stone no intoxicating nor narcotic
like it's like our afghanian strains
most of the people have tried to to grow
to to lower down the an Adaptive
genetics with Afghani I think is a
complete failure because the secret
activity they are completely opposite
make a complete opposite you can come
out with a very potent hybrid but it
will be a a hybrid a hybrid of hybrid
effect
so the Italian mind for me is my
um
[Music]
best success on capturing the the sativa
qualities in a an enhance
the Exotic the Exotic sativa side with
the intents of the Kali China and the
positive sativa side and awareness of
the effect from the Cali China
and with all these qualities making it
easy to to flower indoors and in
temperate latitudes I think my more
successful is
is
tight tight
and another that people like a lot is
Thai cross Panama
this is also very very nice is the same
Titan may I use for taichi but it's
instead of Crossing it with kalichina F4
I cross it with my Panama goddess Elite
F10 which isn't
in the best Panama I have seen in after
20 years working with Panama 10th
Generation Panama the Thai cross Panama
is is also
you you can find a lot of Thai qualities
the Panama and Haze enhance the the
lemonade
Thai bouquet so they match very well
that the Panama helps with a lot of GL
but still keeping the 100 sativa
personality okay no Indica these two are
very very nice for people that want to
to grow
Thai with the Thai qualities and don't
wait more than three months of flowering
yeah brilliant answer while we're on the
topic of Thai I'll also quickly ask you
what were the different time others you
used in the golden tiger cross
okay okay there the first golden tiger
it came out with the the the multi
fibers I commented you in in previous
question it was Malawi cross okay
um
yes it came up very very well that was
the first version of of golden tiger
and the goal with that Highway was to
yeah to to come up with something with a
extreme potency of the Malawi
but make it a bit more up from from the
time more energetic more more cerebral
because the the Malawi has a body stone
that is incredibly strong and it came
out very very very well the when it came
out quite well but I was not fully
satisfied with the
with other pimper files of the Malawi of
the golden tiger first version which was
Malawi mother Malawi all Malawi killer
crossed with a military male okay
so after a few years I was working with
a double tie which was a kochan
close to meltai okay you have a pure
time
and then I selected a female that I like
a lot
and I said uh
I think the golden tiger can be a remake
in status Malawi Thai as Thai Malawi
and instead of including one time
including the the two types of double
type because regarding pure type feel or
best job was double time double time F1
generation it's not something I've been
able to replicate again
the timel is no longer alive
and so so yes I wanted to do something
better with a golden tiger making it
more Thai improving the the terpene
profiles and in
um putting putting
breathing Duvel tie into golden tiger
not just the military
okay so what I call Golden Tiger 2 2.0
is double time
then grows with Malawi killer okay
then I I have selected a
d i I selected different phenotypes one
one more question one more male tie one
more Malawi's
and and lately I'm introducing the the
more Thai phenotypes I'm inbred between
them to produce golden tiger so it's
basically
do Dual tie with all Malawi killer
what a Powerhouse combo right there the
I'm definitely going to come back and
we'll talk some more about some Malawi
stuff but I just wanted to finish on the
ties by asking you
I noticed that you used to sell a strain
called Thai stick do you still sell that
one and was that one one we've already
spoken about or a different tie
foreign
this is a different type and this was
from Gypsy do you know yeah I think in
2008 he made a a trip to the station and
brought back to
uh
three so the station land race it was
the Laos prabang
Thai stick and Camargo
and at that time he he had some problems
with the law in Philippines and all that
so I I held them to to his Partners in
UK the one that had I see Maxi Boutique
and see they to distribute through
through a seats the the disease that
Egyptian Nirvana collected these three
strengths and the Thai stick was one of
them to be honest
I didn't find it as good as or ties
it was extremely long flowing
super hermi and I I I'm not saying it
doesn't have potential
but
I I prefer the times that we already
have over the the Gypsy State yeah sure
so I've been wondering for a long time
what is the mile like as a line itself
it's you don't get to xaml you don't get
to try it pure how would you describe
the hive the xaml
it was thanks indeed thanks to Egyptian
Urbana the the introduced
to to the cannabisco community because
around 2000 it was a strain that it was
only known in Reunion Island by the
French people living there
however for our audience that don't know
about Tamil family an African gray
strain that comes from reunion Iceland
Leon Iceland is a French Colony that is
close to Mauritius islands and
Madagascar okay it's a very beautiful
volcanic island isolated and
and the local people not the French but
the the the the the
local indigenous African people from the
Island used to grow
a very very strong
um 3pa exotic sativas in in the most
isolated parts of of the volcanoes in in
Reunion Island
uh and that's the tamales
subtropical
wise is one of the three pieces sativas
in the world
is
I I find it consistently more trippy
than for example dice
or Colombians the the song The some
sativa lovers considering like the old
Colombians and they all die like the
very very very very best
I have I have found someone else that
are much more trippy than that yeah and
it was you know first early days at that
time we didn't
we didn't have much resources
uh knowledge but with its own early
thermal hybrids and they were a scary
trippy like almost like the closest
a psychedelic experience I have had with
cannabis similar to LSD or something
like that or something like that is
incredible but there are also some
famous super strains
the most trippy ones are the the booty
ones that have the the Less Pleasant
terpene profiles okay
then you have the
the the the colorful ones which are very
very very nervous energetic almost like
cocaine a lot of coffee type of high
okay and then you have the mango carrot
which is the fruity mango
but this this is the one I use for the
modelica yes this is is
cerebral barbaricas a more kind and warm
effect than the the others that are
super trippy or too nervous or whatever
the mangoca road has the most refined
pins
um the kind there are
and best focus is not so dripping also
aggressive
still are you ever gonna release the
really nervous one like I want to smoke
some weed that makes me scared
[Laughter]
the the scary type is there the purple
tamale is what we call the purple
thermal and we we selected a purple from
our mother like five to six years ago
and he's really really strong we have
made a few hybrids with them in in their
we have a section on our website that is
called research and development and
release their the latest hybrid with we
have made that
we have not tested yet that has not been
officially released but by looking at
the research and development section you
can so coming there what we are working
lately and there you can find some
purple thermal hybrids we also released
Tamil Bliss which was purple thermal
cross Nepal jam it was a limited edition
from two three years ago yeah I I have
released a few hybrids but like a few
purple summer highways but as limited
editions or with little stock I haven't
done any big release with it yet
yeah but with the time will come and
um very recently also this year we have
released a tamadelica breeders pack
and I've been doing it includes five
different thermal lines and one of the
line is purple thermal grows with
amadelica
in which we include two different types
of family in this purpose of Microsoft
readers pack yeah so yeah we are working
on it slowly while doing things yeah
that's exciting I'm gonna have to look
into that just as a side question I'm
not sure if you're aware but that uh
just the term the carrotfano of the
zamadelica it has like a cult following
I don't know if you're aware you created
this but uh a lot of people in search of
the carrot terms
it can be found in
in not only in in samal but in other
African sativa and races
like for example I found it in Mauritius
I found it a bit in English
I found it uh
Congolese
yes but the most refined in the
mangocarote in
in some in the mother of the modelica in
this this clone do you know Jared from
micro genetics I don't know him but I've
heard the name
okay now he's a very he's already
retired he sold the company to to Simon
of of cereal seats but when he was still
running his company magogenetics
Jared is a very very kind person and we
met at the first so cannabis events and
we have very good relationship he had he
also received some of the original
pharmacies from gypsy
but if he was working Marcus was working
more Dutch strain like warlock which was
a skunk a planning or
or or others that have not realized so
why we don't so he grew a bit of the
samal but it was not his style and
knowing that I was a
quite a sativa man he he sent me the the
clones from Holland to Spain in in Korea
company uh the first two time they
arrived completely rotten
but at the third time they make it um
and I got uh uh a very nice summer clone
that he selective also with the man
Walker rotor pins
it maybe was not so trippy and strong
like the ones we had but little pins and
the quality it was very good it's the
one I decided to use for tamale
samadelica is this thermal mango Carol
that Jared from magogenetics give me in
Chrome 4 and I pollinate it with uh
golden tiger F1 hybrid the golden tiger
first person so is
okay
fantastic so I wanted to ask you if you
could give us a little bit of the back
story on how you obtained your Malawi
stock it's very famous
is
quite mysterious extreme because when I
was a study uh at the University uh
it was a small town so more or less they
I had a lot of friends we have a cycle
where we sell a lot of clothes okay
at that time
we every one grower had a clone of of
Malawi that he said that it was engraved
powerful this and that say okay then he
gave to us and some friends that were
collaborating with me at this is uh at
that time
and my one of them was a very very good
in the grower and he grew the Malawi
indoors and we could couldn't believe
what it was it was
so sticky that you you cannot
uh
I like that I don't like the greenness I
always do it by hand so I can toast
everything's to be in contact with the
plant with Malawi it was impossible it
was like complete the hand completely
black
the pieces of of bad stick to your
fingers it was incredible and then you
made a joint
do you smoke like yeah oh yeah I have
high tolerance I can smoke a lot of
people smoke have joint you can you see
his face
and I have so many stories of a strong
smokers with Malawi like I could I could
be I was talking about them but it's
completely devastating is like maybe
eight to 12 hours High you do you go to
sleep you you wake up still high
like you cannot drive
you cannot move you you you have a panic
attack and you want to go to the to the
hospital you fall asleep and you didn't
know what happened things like that very
strange methods very extreme and then
it was the the what I call the old
Malawi killer clone it was that it was
that clone
and then I asked where did this clone
came out is from Antonio he's a crazy
grower that now is living in Japan and
he was crazy with the Africans and this
and that and the Malawi from Anthony was
for us like then we grow it we brought
it to and all the people that trail say
what the [__] is this I haven't tried
anything so strong in my life
this was the the consensus from many it
was that that their princes very rude he
was everything
Dusty bully turpins oily is not
nothing refined no fruit to be nothing
it's very very rude interpense but the
effect was so strong so long lasting so
profound
that we can never
only a few times in my life I have seen
something like this
and and then again a lot of
popularity the Malawi clone
then I start breeding with it and then
coming up with golden tiger with some
adelica then I release him when we
release the the Malawi
2012 in 2012 because we we were growing
this this club since 2000 for so for 10
years we only grow it
um but not much into breathing but uh
I I just I decided that Malawi would be
a really really interesting line to
dwell to the assist catalog so around
2012 with the last original seats I I
have from
that were
the siblings of the Clone or the old man
I will clear killer clone
I've reproduced them
I I get to know other females
siblings of the old Malawi clear that
we're not so strong but I found karate
types in Malawi okay that is like what I
call the fruity Malawi and if you go to
the Malawi breeder packs is the only
Malawi line that have
quarter pins
say in some way okay and then I
reproduce the the Malawi yeah and it was
loud released in regular season 2012.
later he came there
the the
feminized version
and it was
around
2014 two years later in the
peace regeneration
well the the grandsons
on ground and ground doctors of the old
Malawi killer when I found a new Malawi
killer
which is the the second most important
plan
in my Malawi reading okay
and with these two the iPhone also in
the P3
generation the another freaky Malawi
that reminds me
a lot of the 3D types I found in the p1s
that I couldn't Preserve at that time
and a colorful Malawi in the second
generation that was the the park on my
hallway
there were the ones that only that were
killer for FX was the old Malawi killer
and the new Malawi killer okay the
fruity was nice but just for terpenes
and and the purple was nice but for
colors the the winners for potency and
jail where the old killer and the new
killer and then I start to to breathe
the new killer into the old killer to
make the the latest feminized versions
so so I make sure that I combine my
strongest Malawi killer phenotypes in a
single frame line
uh so the The Growers can buy a three
five pen pack and we'll get
killer phenotypes that are outstanding
just by germinating one two three seats
are we a few years later here the
Antonio the the source of the United
from Japan
he he lost all during these years in
Japan or his genetic library and was
very happy that I used to represent his
malawian clone phone and I have been
working the line to keep the the line
healthy not only as a clone but of all
sorts of seed line
I give back to him the clones and the
seals so he can work again and
unfortunately he passed away two years
later of a heart attack
that's unfortunate to hear
the Malawi it has been one of our
flagships or
most important is training in the last
decade and I have created many many good
Malawi hybrids many many like Malawi PC
games Malawi Pakistan Malawi cross
Panama is excellent
a golden tiger samadelica are very
popular they are very cool
I I have many many many lovely life is
and they are very good
yeah we might go with them allowing
hybrids was keep the potency of the
Malawi hybrids of the Malawi sorry with
the Malawi killer but try to improve the
terpene profile of the Malawi for
example with the Pakistani that works
great for that the Panama is also very
therapy
and yes awesome so one of the listeners
was wondering what is the strongest land
race you sell and it sounds to me like
maybe that old Malawi cross new Malawi
might be that but just for clarity what
is the strongest land race you sell
what are we
yeah
yeah so another one of our listeners was
wondering how rare is the purple Malawi
phenotype
very very very rare
it was very rare
um honestly I
I only found it in the in the second
generation I never saw it again
I never saw it again and I I selected
one
and I pollinated with the purple
Pakistan chitral and then I created
Violetta which is a
uh
yeah like a improved purple Pakistan
version where the Malawi improves the
the bigger the gel the potency but
keeping all the consistently the colors
and that are pimprofiles of the purple
Pakistan
so I noticed that some of your crosses
are regular and some are feminized and
it made me wonder
what sort of traits or outcomes from
across make you think it's better suited
for feminized versus regular
yeah
we are only there one of the few
seedbanks the that is still offer
regular and Femme so I think the people
is
two extra minutes uh you have one side
of the big sellers events that they say
no
to to sell well must be only Fame and
they are right because what people
mostly want is is feminizing
and then there's other extra images that
say no no true reading they're real
breathing
is only regular with classic males and
this and that
and usually the the reality or
or that
interesting position is is more in the
middle you know you can breathe a line
in regular and in feminize and moreover
this can complement each other
okay the problem
if for example a
people that say only the regular
breathing is there is the right thing
no scientific evidence sayings that you
cannot fully bring fully breathe doing
it only feminize okay
and when you are breathing in that
regular way you are including males
obviously
and when you are breathing only with
feminized only female plants are
involved it means that although you are
in a breathing for in the same strain
and even with similar parental plans
examples that will create different
lines
you know even when breathing let's put
our example
okay
you can continue with with the the Kali
China regular and maybe you find some
traits in the regular and you continue
with the feminist and you are more
successful in racing and fixing other
trades in the feminis then you can take
a male from the regular line and
pollinate the financial deferment all
the feminine or the FML line you know
and you can combine the the success you
have made in in one of the branches of
the feminized breathing you you can
combine with your
success on the regular lines so they
complement each other you we we want we
don't need to be so extra missile black
and white people say no no no only
regular seeds is the only good breathing
because other ways they become a muffler
that is not true there's no scientific
evidence
that if you breathe with feminized
breathing the lines became hermy this is
if you breathe using Army parental
plants but if you breathe regular
classic breathing with my with family
males and you don't select well your
males and your females you will breathe
regular lines that are hermaphrodite too
so that if a line is hermaphrodite it
doesn't depend whether it's regular or
feminized it depends on the work and the
less on the genetics and the work and
selection of the of the Breather Quality
quality is the same you can breathe
excellent mediocre and nasty regular
lines the same for the feminized lines
you can breathe
excellent quality feminized lines
normals and terrible
people mix things and they take
absolutes like it was a fact and it's
not I tell you from my business
experience Fair first-hand experience
that you can fully breathe a line
through feminized breathing and only
with the males you can do it also with a
regular and if you do it both sides you
will have more success more expression
more genetic variability more lines of
the family
it means long term is more successful
for breathing that if you only do one
regular or only as one or only by cross
into one one one one or only selfie
selfie that's where the problem creates
but if you embrace
with different parental lines in its in
Reading step it creates different lines
regular feminine you combine one with
others at the after three four five six
seven generations you create a very big
family with many different branches
and you can combine the best parental
plans from different branches in mid
long term to avoid inbreeding the
depression after many generations of
breathing
yeah that's some awesome information
there
I wanted to ask you I see that you have
been working with the A5 Haze and the C5
Haze I've been lucky enough to have
tried both of them and I really like the
hive the C5 but I feel like most people
say they prefer the A5 which one do you
prefer and what's your thoughts on the
two
also nice I'm very glad you had a chance
to to smoke both yeah I was just gonna
say I was lucky I got to try them when I
was hanging out with Bodie
okay I think you you may know the the
story The behind but maybe we can
comment about it to put a a bidding
costs or audience
yes well as you know uh Neville
in the latest this make the First Legacy
Bank of the world in Holland called the
seed bank
moreover he was a very very talented
breather
adapting he managed to to get excellent
lines from some school man to breathe
with him legally from the seed bank
he got the
the haze and the skunk and dual Vans and
Afghani one from samuskong man
and he also like to work a lot the
with with other Indica strains the
northern lights and the house plan and
the gd13
and the police from
from Wilson these were basically the the
indicates he liked most and the sativa
that he liked most the case
and enable was also the
authorities
credit what is the where is deal and
obviously without some without some
scanman we won't have the scam
Revolution that happened in Holland or
the race Revolution that happened
worldwide
so but it's true that Neville was the
one that through the seed bank
make a spread make the name of the haze
really big and well-known worldwide with
his head with his head hybrids
surprisingly
didn't have much his plans from the
original stock from some school month to
choose from
he only had one Superior he I think he
had the beef two two females one that
was a bitterly flowering and he thought
it was a gross and he avoided one Ultra
long flowing a female that I think he
called a b female that was so Ultra long
flowering I think he was not used to and
he avoid that plant but I think
she will later
rejected of of that moment of kill that
plant because probably there was fire in
that plant so he ended up having only
two two males the male a and the male C
uh as a sign told you uh when I was a
kid I smoked a lot of hybrid from senses
from all the naval work because since
you see both the feedback from Neville
many people many seed banks were using
their face Harvest vulnerable to to
develop their face hybrids
so yes I smoked the very best from
Neville and even in Hollande Hawaiian
chase the Mexican Haze the
Northern Lakes everything and and a few
years back
and Neville gave developed some face
hybrids the the most famous is Northern
La Hayes and Super Silver Haze or later
but he also had some other direct
everyone has hybrid that are not so
famous like the Northern Lights
it was the husband face
the G13 case
and the
well the the Neville case we was a naval
Haze and the and two Northern Light case
one one was Northern Light five clone
pollinated with the Hayes male a
and the other was Northern Light
five phase number sorry Northern Light
five clone pollinated with hairy female
okay he also lost the the male a barrier
Leon so he never released commercially
the northern life fight crosses with his
a
but this one is the one that that
produced the loader in fence
they're they're very low in fence that a
lot of people in Holland
relates to to the best case
came from the day from the eight that
the the the see that for I have
experience
in in the in the Clones view command
that you also have a small Jordan
I I think is
more a tie like
the that their pins are more lime
lemonade and the effect is more
uplifting
Crossing with northern light is still
quite dirty to my to my taste but it's
correct the the
from the enable gave to to some growers
in the south of Holland uh some selected
clones of his fibroid face hybrids
it was the A5 case the C5 case
the mother of super silver haze
the one you smoke
the Neville house which is A5 has
crossed racy mail
and the GE 13 which was G13 cross we
Haze a ml
and after smoking the The Flash from
Holland and now I which I know with this
understand our descendant from the case
email and the Hasty I can
really appreciate the difference the the
terpene signature of the female the
turpent signature of the a male the a
male is
people was confused
they may lose more intense and some and
the intense comes from the American
sativa so the a male is more Colombian
or maybe Colombia Mexican but
Americans
This the sea male or thousands come and
say that origin original Haze never have
a tie that it was all Colombian
it's indeed I like I'm not saying the
the the Hasty malius original with Thai
that could be because in later
generation of original Haze same
schoolman also
this song has Thai hybrids in Indian
face hybrids
but I qualify the the haze female and
it's office spring as style like
no no Thai Domino because I don't have
the the proof that is study but it's
very tight like interpense and effect
that's true
um the good thing is that I was in touch
with yosemi we was part or was is part
of the member of this group of people
from Holland that have been preserving
the the highest hybrids from Neville for
30 years
maybe I'll lose them when he left
Holland
and
they said
many with us and we have been
introducing for men's like a dream come
true like to have the parental plans
that maybe used to develop the the super
hybrid that changed my life and that had
such an impact over me
and to have them now in my library of
genetics and to be able to combine with
my sativa because I don't want to
embrace or try to replicate or something
that hasn't been already done
I think with what I can contribute in
this field is more like to cross
having his habit from Neville with my
own different ideas and try to bring it
to a more sativa Direction and with
different psychological genetics
so there you have it my friends
what do you think do be dropping
knowledge bombs
[Music]
do you want to get some of the excellent
genetics you've just heard about head on
over to ACES website check it out grab
some Femme seeds today Cali China hybrid
sound like they're popping to me
[Music]
but you know what sometimes you want to
grow other stuff if so go check out our
fantastic sponsor at seeds here now they
have a wide variety of both modern and
more land race Pipelines
anything a seed addict could desire
they're going to be able to help you out
they've got all the top quality breeders
and a guarantee on satisfaction at the
end of the Harvest not just on
germination why would you go anywhere
else there might pick go check them out
likewise you need to stop on by our
friends are copper biological systems
with the largest range of predator mites
and other natural enemies in the game be
sure to check out their new spidex buy
tool a predator might with the proof of
predation color changing system where
the person Miller smites will change
from white to Red after they've eaten
spider mites so you can be sure they're
doing their jobs
and next up who could forget our friends
at promise they're here to help you get
the best crop possible check out the Pro
mix connect microrizal inoculum to
ensure that your crop is productive
resinous dense flavorful all the things
you want we know mycorrhiza is important
the god Jeff lowenfeld told us what more
do I need to say guys Pro mix connect
it's a fantastic product go check it out
finally the patreon gang you guys know
it I love you you are the lifeblood of
the show and you get access to episodes
early as well as bonus unheard content
so if you want to be a part of the club
go check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast The Early Access bonus content
giveaways and so much more
foreign
guys thanks for hanging around till the
end
[Music]
appreciate y'all as always
this is heavy day signing out from the
upside down libraries
[Music]
we'll see you
foreign
[Music]