foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
welcome to the next episode of the
podcast a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts as usual you're joined by
your boy happy days here from the upside
down library and we want to give a
massive shout out to our sponsors who
helped make the show happen as always
see tear now your number one seed bank
in the game all the latest drops all the
hottest breeders you're looking to score
some of that ever elusive heavy days
gear go check them out they've got some
of my stuff right now available for you
to snatch up with extra freebies on
offer for each pack purchase trust me
guys grab the kaifi or the Key Royale if
you're loving that Indica Madness or
check out some patanga if you want some
uplifting social give me fun times
next up we've got to thank copper
biological systems you know him you love
them all the best pests and Predator
technology able to keep your garden
pumping on all cylinders Pest and
packaging free check out the appy param
if you're battling aphids or the spidex
vital if you've got some spider mites
trust me guys you want to release this
stuff before you have a big issue it's
going to save you a whole world of
trouble stay on top of your pets and
pathogens check out Copa today guys best
in the world Copa biological systems
thank you so much for your support
likewise a massive shout out to our
friends at Pulse sensors whether you're
running a single tent a single room or a
multi-state operation pulse sensors are
going to help you to have the best
Harvest to date through careful tracking
of parameters you may not even be aware
of like VPD ppfd a whole bunch of
parameters that aren't obvious or picked
up by your standard temperatures a pulse
sensor is going to help you to have
increased resin increased yield increase
flavonoids the whole gamut trust me guys
get serious get a pulse sensor today you
won't regret it thank you so much pulse
likewise we've got to give a huge shout
out to the patreon gang if you want to
help support the show and ensure that
episodes continue to happen please go
check out the patreon at
www.patreon.com forward slash thepodcast
or one word Early Access in return
you'll get early access to upcoming
episodes unheard special episodes with
the likes of Bob Hemphill Mr meme Gene
Bodie trichome jungle so much more we've
also introduced a Discord giveaway
sessions every Fortnight we do a live
smoke with heavy sash win yourself some
genetics basically pays for itself check
it out guys patreon gang we love you so
much thank you again we really
appreciate you
in this episode I'm joined as usual by
Mr Bean for the 2022 breeder awards for
the year
who have you picked
write some ideas down see if you agree
with us
alrighty friends we're back for another
one and as usual we're joined by the man
with his feet on the ground in the
industry Mr James being for our breeder
Awards of 2022 thank you so much for
joining us
hey hey thanks for having me again uh
it's good to be back on the show for
another another year down
another you go down another year in the
books I gotta say we've had a quick one
or should I say probably about eight
months this one's been a little
truncated because we did last year's one
a little bit late but I decided you know
get us back on track we'll do this one a
little bit early but needless to say
we've had a few notable changes going
down in the industries we've seen a few
breeders come a few go a few incarnated
it's going to be an interesting Awards I
think how about you what's been going on
for you Mr Bean
definitely I was thinking I was saying
that about that as well um I was
thinking uh you know when we were
talking about breeder of the year and
whatnot I was like huh this name has
been up there the last two years this
name has been non-existent in the last
couple months I wonder what's going on
with that one so we'll definitely talk
about that but uh just just um you know
I think the whole industry on the whole
is down or the I think uh possibly the
seed sales are down a little bit this
year over year over year uh people got
out of their houses of course we had two
Banger years 20 and 21. uh but people
actually got other houses got them
moving around so
uh sells a little bit down but we had
made made our sales even better right
even better deals for everybody else so
that's exactly it and um I think this
might be a good point to review some of
our predictions and some of our results
from last year because uh we haven't
done that yet I think it'll be good to
sort of check in and see if they stand
the test of time albeit eight to 12
months so uh the first award from last
year will check in was the clone of the
year we gave it to Apple Fritter how
does that feel you still stand by it
yeah I still think it was a uh they
thought I tried to look back and and and
know now that you know and not think
about that and and compare like oh we
didn't know about this one back then so
um I prefer definitely I think I think
it was good I think it was solid pick
um
you know for for sure because because it
wasn't wasn't the reason recent apples
but I think it definitely started up the
apples the Apple's phase Trend if you
will
yeah certainly and and something that I
was very happy to see was that uh it
hasn't been adopted by absolutely
everyone in their breeding project so
there's it's not completely
oversaturated so I agree I think it
still definitely stands the test and uh
you know shout out to lump status it's a
cool one for sure and the flower is
really nice I've seen it used in a lot
of projects the next thing I wanted to
mention though was when I asked you last
year about the clone of the year your
guess was the jealousy from jbz and
guess what leafly's just come out and
called it their Australian of the year
so what's interesting is we sort of made
this same point around three years ago
when we first predicted the upsurge of
runs when it came out and then what do
you know Leafly strain of the year the
following year so I guess at this point
it's safe to say we're not doing too bad
on the old betting odds are we no I
think uh if I was a better man which
which I generally am I do I do play with
the cryptos uh I would definitely put
our money on us to to pick it but you
know not to not to blow my own horn here
but
when you're in the industry and you're
in the seed business you're in the seed
game and you see what's coming in and
day in and day out and see all the new
strangers and what's on the market you
know kind of uh it's it's it's humbling
and it's and it's cool to be able to hit
things on the head sometimes of course
of course if we move on and we look at
our hottest newcomer uh we had Bloom
Seed Co really solidifying himself as
you know in that tier one breeder list
nowadays I can definitely get behind
that I think Bloom's sort of gone from
strength to strength now doing some
collabs with Boston roots
definitely and uh I I just had what was
his Maple uh Maple oh the black maple
hybrids like black maple yeah that had
that that lion release uh just sold the
last pack of those the other day uh
those were uh commodity definitely a big
pack
um he's a good guy uh he likes fast cars
you know
yeah
he's got some nice Parts on his
Instagram well there you go yeah shout
out to bloom for that one in terms of
our most anticipated sea drop last year
we had crickets and cicada Mr Bob and
Hannah bolt with their puck back cross
one line I think it's safe to say we can
stand by that one pretty firmly
yeah that's uh that's a given that was
uh yeah definitely uh he's he's he
happens to be in the running for this
year with his bc3 in fact so yeah
they've gone from strength to strength
yeah at least for for me that's uh it
was a hot one for this year for sure
almost shut my website down
that's it that's good to hear so uh in
terms of our Hall of Fame strain we had
blueberry from DJ Short you know I don't
think it needs too much said there
clearly Hall of Fame worthy strain
yeah I mean every reason anybody smoked
clearing them growing up I think I mean
you know they had it even if it wasn't
the true blueberry you you got you were
given a bag and it was told he was
blueberry you know I mean you know it
smelled like it's May smell like hay
sometimes it wasn't it was clearly
beasters but they told you the blueberry
so it was one of those the first knocked
off strain if you will yeah gosh it must
be knocked off more than basically
anything right
yeah pretty much I remember God remember
did you guys ever have beasters over in
Australia what I'm talking about these
two said yeah we got the equivalent yep
I think the it later came out to be like
a like a M38 or 27 or something from
Canada but uh horrible horrible weed
yeah yeah M39 or whatever that skunk
cross NL fast flower
um and then uh we also gave a Lifetime
Achievement Award to Mel Frank for all
of his work so I think again that one
stands the test so looking back pretty
happy with those results I don't think
we've got egg on our face in any real
meaningful regards so let's move on to
the awards for this year I think a good
place to start we always like to start
we're not always but we last year I
should say I listened to the episode
before this so it's just fresh in my
mind last year we started with clone of
the year so I think it's a good place to
start again let's do some honorable
mentions before we actually announce the
winner so for me I want to start out by
giving an honorable mention to something
that I don't think many people will
expect which is that I want to give an
honorable mention to RS 11 bred by deep
east and an undeniably popular
commercial strain the Doja crew has
wrapped this one they've done super well
with it they're on the record of saying
that the Clone drop was the most
successful in history doing I think they
said it was like one and a half million
or something it'd be JB's jealousy one
and it's beautiful flavor that really
sort of incorporates uh the best aspects
of the parents being the pink guava and
the Oz cush so yeah I want to give an
honorable mention uh to the rainbow
sherb 11 you know super popular shout
out deep east yeah no definitely I I
remember
uh uh when I first saw that strain come
across the list I thought it was
roadkill skunk
I was like a guy somebody's got a
roadkill Scott how dare they how dare
they and I saw then I saw Grandma
working with the [ __ ] he had a a
drop this year with uh with with PBX uh
BX and he had the RS and I was like he's
got a roadkill Scott he's like oh no
it's a rainbow shirt yeah good good
strain though for sure I've seen that
everywhere Exotics guy he's usually
coming up and a lot of people you've
been using it I thought it was vertical
skunk obviously fairly not
no look I can I can understand the
confusion so yeah a shout out to the
dojo crew and all that another honorable
mention I want to give is to Archive
Fletcher for the rainbow belts 3.0 the
next installment in the rainbow belt
series from archive many people still
infatuated and in love with the flavor
of the rainbow belts and for good reason
it's very terpy with a little something
special on top of that so if you're into
that Skittles dimension of flavor this
has got that plus more as well as super
aesthetic a very popular clone and Seed
release shout out to Archive for the
rainbow builds 3.0 yeah definitely I had
I had people calling me they're like
yeah you got any rainbow belts they're
safe you got any rainbow belts I was
like no why why do you want those you're
like oh man I need it I need it so uh
definitely uh you know Fletch always
comes correct with uh serious strains
he's been in the game longer than than
most people I know
um definitely does it for the right
reasons uh and he's one of those guys
that has a he's going to wreck he's got
a wreck license so he can run numbers
fine everybody wants to run find what's
good final works for him and then uh you
know rest on the Shelf so to say
a hundred percent and then the final
honorable mention I want to give is to
none other than Boston roots for the
sherbanger Clone this one has started to
make its way into many more gardens
after being held for a couple years now
uh the plant's been used by many and
he's got some notable collabs going down
with uh the likes of Bloom which we've
already mentioned so that's cool shout
out to Boston roots for his showbanger
well for sure um I I Gotta Give a couple
shots out real quick at least at least
one
um it's gonna be for exotic and his work
with the Gary Poppins
which is the Gary Payton crossed with
red Bop
yeah I had seen that one Duo yeah we
sold a whole bunch of that maybe you
know four or five hundred packs of that
thing I think was was a hot hot
commodity
um
uh also he had this this year uh he also
had his red runts that's true I've seen
people in Australia harvesting that and
it looks great so not only have they
bought it I've seen the flower on
Instagram looks good so shout out to
Exotic Mike so let's get to the winner
this year winner is uh clone only of the
year goes to none other than Apples and
Bananas from Chris compound apples and
bananas has undeniably been the biggest
clone of the year for the 2022 period in
my opinion we have seen a number of
breeders not just Chris using it in
their projects not just as female
acceptors but also even other people
reversing it themselves like raw and lit
Farms just to name a few it's got an
undeniable nose that has the ability to
dominate any bag it's in it seriously
reminds me of that sort of Tangy thing
where it just fully cuts through the
rest and the bud structure in my opinion
beautiful that spiraling calyx sort of
pyramidal or fractal looking structure I
really like it beautiful stuff the high
is great composed of some interesting
genetics now in laters crossed to gelati
this one I find particularly interesting
because it utilizes some unique work
from Sin City who yet again have proven
themselves as the breeder's breeder with
their work also notably appearing in
JB's wedding cake so apples and bananas
is hot in every dispensary you go to
especially cookies not surprising given
Chris helped curate their menu but
you'll find it in many of the Exotic
style Brands pushing it for good reason
it's really high quality Bud lots of
people growing with it lots of people
breeding with it what's your thoughts Mr
Bean agree disagree
uh I agree Apple's masmus was huge last
year
um and uh 2022 was just it was a big
strain we saw coming at the end of the
emerald cup with the big lines Emerald
cup uh when I met with Chris down there
that whole kind of snapped through that
happened
of course Chris is no longer with
compound now
um he and them split ways uh at the
beginning uh of this year you put a post
out he's now Cipher genetics which you
know but um that Apple has been as it
was it was money and uh the cross on it
I've got it as I've just got the full
thing right now on my on my website
because I was just like it's not such a
jump guy that's four which is platinum
cookies Gran that he purps that crossed
the blue Power which gives us now and
later as that cross back to gelotti
actually sorry so that Platinum cookies
Granddaddy Purple that's that's
incorrect it's sorry like it's correct
but instead of saying that they should
say what it actually is which is it's um
it's Candyland that's what Platinum
cookies Granddaddy Purple is
huh
yeah what I think the most interesting
part which I mentioned before is like um
yet again Sin City sneaking their work
into one of the hottest strains utilized
by another big breeder
yeah Don's Don's a great dude I've known
him since 2014 probably hooked up with
him at Denver cup uh we sell a lot of
gear we have Sin City Saturdays 20 off
down stock but he's been putting out a
lot of good work for a long time uh
usually always does merge with each
release and you know tests his work and
does a lot of solid solid stuff
so what's your thoughts agree disagree
apples and bananas
I think you already answered it actually
am I am I just too stoned right now yeah
no answered it uh it's definitely the I
mean it was the highest strain last year
for sure like I said we saw it coming
through the end of the emerald cup the
lines of people and stuff and you know
it's also just for the for the history
books it's odd how you know that cut was
out before he even did the seed release
yeah so you know because I got to kill
people over that not being the real deal
and find out it was a real deal and just
a whole bunch of problems there with
that uh that whole
you know if that you know good story
makes a great strain they say well I
strongly suspect that um the cut getting
out before the seed drop happened is
maybe one of the factors that led to
Chris's ultimate split from compound
yeah I mean if I was you know if just
let's say I was
a breeder working with a tissue culture
lab hypothetically
if somehow my cuts started to get out
and I didn't give them to anyone
I would be pissed
I would I would you know you got to
figure out you got to start going
backwards and be like well if I didn't
give him out how the hell they get out
yeah yeah yeah interesting stuff so on
to our next award let's do the hottest
newcomer on the scene so this award
historically does not go to people where
it's say like their first year breeding
in past years we've had winners such as
Bloom Soul fire AK Bean brains and I
think the idea of this award is more to
acknowledge that people who are notable
names within the industry have very much
established themselves in that next sort
of level if you're going to say tears
establishing themselves as a the next
tier of breeder in a higher status where
you know that their offerings are
generally quite high quality and uh
they've made some waves over the past
few years
so to start off I want to give the first
shout out I want to give the honorable
mention is to none other than Tiki man I
actually think he's had a super
productive year doing a bunch of collabs
with some cool people including the
likes of raw and Umami Seed Co and he's
had a number of successful releases in
his own right I've got some friends who
have found some killer stuff in his gear
I think Tiki man deserving of an
honorable shout out
definitely I think I just saw him how to
collab with uh super seed kill I think
they did something that it had release
but no it's uh so it looks like this guy
he's been killing it looks like uh we
met him two years ago I believe in
Emerald cups talked with him for a bit
uh seemed like a real nice guy but uh he
has his uh I've seen a lot of his stuff
looks like it's uh looks like it's
coming out like fire yeah shout out Tiki
man likewise another honorable mention I
want to give to my buddy skunk Tech
who's done some great work with both the
headband doing some feminized hybrids as
well as doing some root beer work in the
form of uh bx2s and the root beer freeze
work really cool work overall many
people excited about it so honorable
shout out skunk Tech nice I've got one
uh animals our most honorable mentioned
a guy that I think is uh upward coming
it's gonna be Nash genetics in Asha uh
they had a really good year with this
year they had a red strap early in June
um had their Oreo runs their Rocky runs
and their runs Crashers
um a really good then their gushers drop
which happened uh late December um it's
actually on the website now I had the
miracle gushers Apple gushers
so we're gonna edit the we're going to
edit that out
so so uh nasogenics with their investors
drop and the gestures uh they did that
the gesture drop in June and that saw
the miracle gushers Apple gushers ice
gushers
um then they just had their runts
dropped recently and that's available on
the website right now they had like the
rocky runs the Oreo runs you know wrench
Crasher
um really Frosty stuff great packaging
great guys
um we did an interview with him that's
on the website there his neighbors ran
uh real cool guy
but uh he's sort of like gear and like
we've been really happy with this stuff
love it shout out Nasha love to hear it
I think they've actually got a um
a hardcore OG hybrid or some work
they've done with hardcore OG in the
past which is piqued my curiosity so
shout out there yes they do in fact I
was gonna mention it but I was like ah
No One's Gonna Know The hardcore it's
like hardcore gushers or something it's
hardcore gussers yeah yeah cool that's
an OG that I've sort of popped up more
recently I've been keeping my arm so
this brings us to the hottest new camera
on the scene award this year it's gonna
go to someone who is in fact fairly new
on the Block and someone who I think's
been making waves and they themselves
may be a bit surprised to hear this
because I've never spoken to them but uh
I want to actually give it to Blockhead
buds if you have been paying attention
you will likely have seen Blockhead buds
Making Waves and I first heard about him
about 12 months ago when I saw a number
of cannabis cups being won in either
first or second place often multiple
samples in the top five for a strain
called superboof and I was like what's
this and you sort of start following it
and eventually it got renamed to
blockberry and Blockhead buds is the
creator of this cross it's it's a strain
that's comprised of black cherry punch
by Tropicana cookies so it's obviously
boasting like a super terpy high but the
difference and the reason why this is so
popular is that it's also potent with a
unique Twist on the flavor it's very
immersing dominant but it translates to
like you know that typical strong Citrus
nose but it's also got like an earthy
cherryness to it which is really
interesting so this one grabs your
attention with both the nose but it also
keeps you focused and interested in the
effect so much so that it's been winning
cups left and right as I mentioned it's
often taking out multiple spots in the
top five such as the New York Growers
cup where it took both first and third
by two different Growers respectively
and entering their block Berry samples
there's also been a number of other cups
one but I think the most interesting
twist in this Saga is that Mr Blockhead
himself thought he had given away slash
lost the last of the F1 stock so he
wasn't going to be able to produce any
f2s or breed with males he just had his
breeder cut however recently he put a
post up saying he got sent some seed
back from a friend he had sent some of
the f1s to and so there's now some more
projects on the horizon including maybe
an F2 line he's done some cool other
breeding projects utilizing males such
as a triangle Kush bx1 lemon Rose and
blueberry frosting just to name a few so
a big shout out to block Berry buds
particularly for his block Berry Cross
or otherwise known as superboof hugely
popular I suspect you're going to see it
more over the coming 12 months Mr Bean
what's your thoughts uh I I haven't seen
the Blackberry buds but I have seen the
Super Bowl and so I was like oh that's
the guy but yeah it's got one of those
names you're just kind of like oh
um no sad the cross sounds great like I
would love to dab some right now if you
wouldn't mind uh get some of that like
Dabber
um
but uh but yeah uh sounds like some good
stuff I've I've taken note of it sir and
I shall be in contact
yeah I like um I like all those points
[Music]
all righty gang we're back for another
one and in this episode we are extremely
grateful to have none other than
Blockhead buds joining us today to
accept his Awards so to start off a big
congrats Blockhead for taking out the
hottest new breeder on the Block award
thanks for joining us how you doing
today
that's awesome man thank you I'm doing
well thanks for uh thanks for giving me
I didn't even know that uh I was up for
the running so yeah I appreciate it
thank you
that that's brilliant I have to I have
to give you some Kudos because in in
past years the hottest newcomer on the
Block award it actually never really
went to anyone who was sort of like in
their first year or anything like that
it was sort of people who'd been making
little waves but had managed to really
establish themselves but I think you're
the first person in the three or four
years we've been doing this where it
seems like you truly have just like
busted down the door of the industry and
charged in how's that feel oh man yeah
that sounds that sounds awesome I love
it
um
I've actually I've kind of been doing
certain things for a long time I'm a
little bit older but yeah so I think
it's just kind of all come to fruition
at once so yeah it uh
feels great so I don't even know like
how does this how does it how did it
work with you guys like how do you guys
come up with you know the new breeder or
whatever like because you guys are out
in Australia so there's only maybe a
couple people that have had my seeds out
there so is it for like continental US
is this out in Australia or like how do
you guys come up with the with the
winners or whatever
great question we are um largely
speaking an international show and I uh
you put me in the hot seat here largely
speaking the awards are determined by
both myself and I have uh James Bean of
seeds here now one of our grateful
sponsors
um he also helps guide the selection a
bit but I think together we were both so
blown away by how well uh superbooth AKA
blockberry has done over the past year
that it was sort of undeniable that um
you know amongst all the people who were
not already really well known breeders
that you you certainly have elevated
yourself to that level and as a quick
caveat
um one of my one of my buddies on
Instagram osgrown he's been he's got
this beautiful cut of the blockberry f1s
and and I have to acknowledge he was
part of what put me on to that because I
was like this looks interesting and then
and then it just all exploded have you
found um that sort of organic growth has
been the reception you've got yeah so
here's the thing that guy I I'm pretty
positive I know who you're talking about
so he was like one of maybe two people
out in Australia to get the seeds so uh
initially that whole project wasn't
supposed to be a project it was just
something for me personally so going
back to what you and I were talking
about a little earlier is that um when I
first started I bought some seed packs I
just wanted to kind of dip my toe in to
see if I liked it you know what I mean
like I've grown a little bit as a kid we
would just throw bag seeds out out in
the yard but all my plants would always
get stolen I was a little kid probably
talked about it you know what I mean so
somebody would always Rob your house
steal it steal your plants so I never
ever got to actually
um Harvest anything so in in California
I'm in Southern California so in
California it went like fully legal so I
was like all right well now nobody
should be stealing my plants right so
bought some seed packs and I was like
man this is crazy to me they were 150
bucks for a seed pack and I was like we
used to get these things for free like
you know what I mean nobody wanted seeds
so I was like well I'm gonna I'm gonna
buy these so I bought two packs about uh
it was like papaya OG from uh Ani seeds
and then I bought um triangle Kush from
sea junkie so I bought those and then
planted them went through my whole thing
and then you know piece by piece got
bigger and bigger started growing more
and more and then went indoors because
Outdoors was just a
bug Fest it was just it was just a lot
of work wasn't give you know grew kind
of Booth you know what I mean didn't
have a market for it so
um
but based on the fact that those seeds
were so expensive to me I was like 15
for one seed so uh maybe on my second or
third pack I bought Tropicana cookies
and then I bought um the black cherry
punch from uh in-house Tropicana cookies
another Oni and uh Harry Palms creation
so I bought those found a male of the
triangle or excuse me of the uh
of the Tropicana cookies and I was like
I'm just gonna make my own seeds that's
so that's how that whole project
happened I was like this is so expensive
they're freaking 15 per seed I'm gonna
make thousands of them for free and then
that's it so basically just you know
found this Banger mail threw it on this
like to me it was like the terpiest
black cherry punch that I had
you know had them do their thing and I
just got you know however many seeds but
that's how that project happened it
wasn't supposed to be anything other
than just like a personal fun project
and I was just like cool I'm just gonna
Bank these and I probably was never
gonna pop them to be honest with you I
was just I just had them and then that
started my whole thing so I started like
I would collect all kinds of seeds I was
kind of like a I wouldn't say Pokemon
but like a record collector for seeds
you know that was a true sea junkie so I
started buying all these seeds and all
this [ __ ] and then uh that guy mobile
Jay and I were friends on Instagram
so we would trade seeds essentially
and so in one of those trades I I gave
them like five of my my little project
didn't have a name or anything like that
so he actually popped them so if it
wasn't for him I would have never popped
him so he popped them threw them in the
back of like his Warehouse or his his
basement I think at the time
and then he's like bro you gotta you
gotta check this out dude these things
are these things are crazy like he just
he forgot about him and then he started
sending me videos like holy [ __ ] and
looked like a lot better than a lot of
the stuff that we had been going through
and growing I was like God damn so I got
to pop my seeds right so he kind of
started the whole thing he was like
the pr he would uh I I kind of like it
into like a dojo and me being like Deo
Farms so he was like the hype man he was
the guy that started selling all the
Clones he named it superboof I never
named that that's a little side topic
but
um he called it super boob it's kind of
like a joke he's like razzing me a bit
you know and then he started cutting
them out sending them to everybody and
he's in Michigan so he started the whole
thing in Michigan he was just like you
guys got to get that he was selling them
clones and everything so that's kind of
how it spread and then from there I
popped my own seeds in my own little
hunt
got my breeder cut and then that's kind
of how the whole thing started and then
the seeds coming to you guys like I like
I said I didn't have I only had like one
plant and it wasn't like a you know it
wasn't supposed to be a project per se
but then like people started seeing all
the stuff on Instagram and mobile J
started getting a bigger and bigger
following and so like all kinds of
people started hitting me up so I was
like [ __ ] it what I mean they're just
gonna sit in my fridge anyways right so
I was like might as well get these out
to the World by the time I'll go through
these
I'll be 100 years old you know what I
mean like there was no way I was ever
going to have time to pop all of them
plus all the stacks of seed that I
collected so that's how I started
selling um and then I remember the guy
in Australia there was like two guys I
think but yeah he actually popped him so
he has he has his own uh Finos by the
way so his aren't super boof and his
aren't my breeder I keep telling people
Mike there's so many bangers in there so
Jay he found his super boob cut off of
five seeds I also did five seeds and uh
I got my breeder cut and I think I got
like two or three males one was and then
and mine was by by default I had a
female that hermed and then that was it
and then the other one was the breeder
cut I was like sweet and then his he he
had uh mobile J had like three females
two males and then you said all three
were bangers but he only kept the one
because he didn't have room or something
like that wow what what an organic story
but yeah so you guys have your you guys
actually have your own stuff out there
that's different from mine and from the
super Booth cut so you guys have your
own stuff so I'm I'm excited to try it
too if I ever get out to Australia for
sure yeah right on you know and uh it
goes without saying huge shout out
osgrown the the homie down under who's
uh growing those out it's him yeah it
looks beautiful and and that story so
much about that which is so organic and
beautiful and it speaks to the fact that
you know some of the best strains are
not exactly all fully planned out on
paper and you know sometimes they're
just these sort of little happy
accidents yep I'd love to quickly ask
you what stimulated you to change the
name from superbooth to blockberry
never change the name so I actually
called it blockberry and he didn't like
that name he being mobile J so he and
since he was like the the uh the uh uh
what's his name the DJ Khaled he's I
guess he's like the DJ so yeah him being
the hype man him being you know he
already had like way more followers than
I did he was like that was what he was
doing just for his career you know what
I mean he was the one that named it
super Booth I never named it that it was
never supposed to be that initially it
was a joke
um and then the name stuck and now it's
kind of in the Lexicon now so at this
point I don't have any
um ego about it like I can call it
whatever you want you know what I mean
like I don't it is what it is it's
already out there but you know I just
want to make sure that people know that
that actually wasn't the name he named
it that as like a Razz and then but yeah
so Blackberry was the initial name and
he said he's like that name sucks
because like we were like he was like a
little brother you know what I mean it's
kind of like a little a little bratty
brother like when we first started like
yeah hanging out kicking it you know
what I mean but yeah
um so he he named it that I never named
it that there you go I love it that
makes sense that makes sense
um and I would love to ask you I saw
recently you put a post up talking about
having gotten some of the F ones back
and maybe doing some future Line work
yes yeah tell me a bit about that Did
you sort of accidentally lose them and
then get them back or how did that all
work no so yeah so I sold you know
basically the bulk of them off because
like I said there just sitting in my
fridge and I was like I already have my
winner you know what I mean I was like I
don't really need to do anything besides
this
um but I know so from the black cherry
punch there was uh it had blueberry
bread Terps it was like blueberry
muffins it was insane so uh most of the
Blackberry
um I guess venos from what I have uh
they have Tangy Terps right so but I
know that they're the blueberry outliers
because uh Jay had one he said dude he's
like I had one he's like I should have
never tossed it so I'm looking for the
blueberry Terps right so anyhow so I
gave and sold out pretty much all my
seeds I had I think I kept like 30 or 40
for myself
um and then those 40 that I got back or
those ones that I got back were from a
homie in the Bay Area that I sent to
um because like I said at first it was
just it was just a passion project you
know what I mean so I was just giving
them out to homies like here dude pop
them right so I sent him like 40 seeds
and then he he hit me up and he was like
hey man I still have those seeds like if
you want to do a hunt and I was like
[ __ ] yeah so then he sent them back so
that's how it happened so
um currently just so you know I'm doing
a a femme release right now so they're
uh they're baking right now so I'm gonna
do some s1s of the Blackberry so and
then a bunch of other Femme crosses
um so the because everybody's asking for
Femmes right so I'm gonna do that and
then the F2 I've got a couple Femme
projects on the way and then after that
I'm gonna be looking for some f2s so
it'll be probably next year by the time
I find something but they're coming
beautiful I love that and uh yeah it
certainly seems like there's a lot of
demand for Femmes at the moment and you
you gave me a perfect segue because I
wanted to ask you I noticed you did work
with some other males one of them that
caught my eye was uh the blueberry
frosting can you tell us a little bit
about that one oh yeah so that's from a
guy he's uh his uh his handle on ideas
Party Time Farms so uh same kind of
thing like we've been kind of homies
through Instagram
um I don't know what happened but
somehow we started chatting and I was
talking to him about getting blueberry
Terps right blueberry are great and then
uh he was like oh I got this mail he was
basically just telling me about it and
he was like he's like I'll send you some
I'll send you some pollen I was like no
way so he ended up sending me some flour
some pollen and like a [ __ ] ton of his
new blueberry frosting crosses I was
like dude thank you so much like he's
such he's such a badass he just sent it
to me
um most people talk a good game in this
industry you know what I mean but they
never do [ __ ] so this guy actually did
it I was like wow so and then you know
anyhow so that's where I got the pollen
from and the blueberry frosting I
believe is like Wedding Crasher crossed
with blueberry cookies form cut or
something like that but that's his
creation so we just did it as like a
collab I was like here I'll just give
you seeds you know what I mean so it was
kind of real it was really loose
um crazy part is he just took off I
think he's in like Columbia now he's not
even I've been hitting him up like dude
where can I send you these seeds
ghost but uh yeah so that's that's how
that uh that project kind of started in
um turns out
I crossed the holly berry which is ice
cream cake crossed with Blackberry I
crossed that with the blueberry frosting
and it does have blueberry Terps so I'm
like super excited about it so I still
have some uh some of that pollen I'm
gonna do and use on some other strains
but uh yeah I'm excited for that one for
sure that's incredible and you've you've
got me wondering as time gone has gone
by I've realized more and more that
largely speaking you can divide people
into sort of you know this is very
simplistic but two camps of flavor
people are either more into the gassy
stuff or more into the fruity stuff
sounds like you're like myself and
you're more into the fruity stuff is
that how you would put it or is it not
quite that clear-cut oh no I did a full
gas line
um it hasn't taken off because people
haven't popped the seeds and I'm like uh
I keep doing more and more seed projects
so I haven't got to hunt them myself but
I did this whole triangle Kush cross
line and it was from the actual triangle
kush for my very first CPAC from sea
junkie it was a triangle Kush bx1
um so I do have some super gnarly gas
right now uh that I did hunt so I've got
um I don't know if you've heard of the
soap so I crossed the soap to Triangle
Kush that's one of them it's like super
gnarly I also have a
it's gorilla butter F2 AKA white truffle
cut I did that I crossed it with uh
blackberry and then I only got a couple
seeds out of it popped that and then I
crossed that to Triangle Kush and then I
only got a couple seeds out of that as
well so I have that one it's insane just
heavy heavy gas so
um no I don't just like Fruity it just
kind of is something that kind of
started off that way
um and I still have a lot of gas [ __ ]
that I'm working on right now
um so it's not yeah it's it's basically
what I'm gonna try and do is honestly
now at this stage
I have it all mapped out of my head
hopefully it works
um I need to make strains that everybody
can grow I don't want to make it to
where they're hard or finicky or you
have to be able to do a b and c to get
it to yield or look right a lot of the
strains out there especially the hype
strains either they don't yield or
whatever there's always something right
they don't check all the boxes so I'm
working with a local facility here in
San Diego and
um they're you know professional
facility they're they're on the legal
side and they actually hit almost four
light with my with my breeder cut and
that's insane the the main guy there is
like dude I've been growing for 20 plus
years I've never had anything like this
in my life so if I can get something to
get three ish per light three pounds per
light with every type of terp profile
like that's it that's what I'm trying to
do so I look for certain things I want
to make it so like and if you talk to
anybody blockberry slash superbooth
whatever it's like the easiest plant
they've ever grown it yields super heavy
it's got great Vigor structure Etc
the flowers great tastes great smells
great you know what I mean so basically
what I'm trying to do at this stage is
make
already got the orange Terps right so
that's already or Tangerine whatever so
I got the Tangy trips down now I got the
grapes or the or excuse me the
blueberries I'm gonna try and do some
grapes uh maybe papaya and that'll be
pretty much it for the fruits and then
I'm just gonna do a bunch of different
gas ones and if everything works out the
way I hope it will then you know what I
mean then it's gonna be like production
strains left and right everybody's gonna
be stoked so that's that's the plan
we'll see if it happens because breeding
you never really know what you're gonna
get you know what I mean but you can
hope
yeah that that's brilliant and you sort
of got me thinking you know it sounds as
though you're helping step us out of the
metaphorical Corner that some people
believe we're in in terms of like you
know the hype strands are just getting
smaller yielding and they're not great
and they are you know yeah right and so
I I wanted to know do you think that um
this sort of strains you're making that
are you know yielding better and easier
to grow do you think they're going to
become more popular or do you think
that's just something only you will
probably be able to do
um here's the here's the thing that I've
been seeing too exactly what you just
said all I see a lot of people doing
that are current breeders are they just
cross hype strained hype strain and
that's it and then all these pictures
that I'll see there's these tiny little
Frosty buds uh like satellite sites
gangly and I'm just like I don't I don't
get it like for me I want to grow best
dreams what I want to do personally this
is what I do is like I'll look for the
Beast right that like has a big old
frame structure
Etc right I wanted to check pretty much
every single box and then I want to pair
it with something that has maybe a
little bit of different terp or whatever
so I'll look for something that has a
weakness and oh this one has that
weakness in it so they'll breed those
two that's kind of the way I look at it
so blueberry processing I don't think
anybody's ever heard of this because
it's not a hype stream right Halle Berry
I created
um there's I'm not reading height strain
the height strain although I'm going to
have to uh at some point you know what I
mean to sell some seeds about want
because that's what people want but I'm
gonna basically have to use a bunch of
[ __ ] that nobody's ever heard of or that
nobody gives a [ __ ] about because I know
that it's gonna contribute so to answer
your question yeah eventually
um in terms of
on the legal side here everybody needs
yield prices of tax here in in uh
California and America in general are
going down so the days of these one to
two pound Delight super Frosty little
buds are gonna be over like people can't
get by anymore so they need to maximize
their space that's why I want to make it
so it's like they can grow it because
here's the other key thing as a breeder
people will look at your [ __ ] and
they'll maybe they suck as a grower I
don't know what they're doing right so
like if I can make it shine and I'd beat
it up because I'd go through all this
testing and whatnot make it you know try
to [ __ ] it up as hard as I can to make
sure it's stable and then if I can make
it shine and I want everybody to make a
chime and so certain people will start
talking [ __ ] on the breeder even though
they may or may not know what the [ __ ]
they're doing right so so I want to make
it to where it's virtually impossible
for them to [ __ ] it up you know what I
mean yeah because they're always gonna
be like oh it harmed well maybe maybe
it's because you made it her you know
what I mean or did this or did do that
whatever like maybe it's because of you
maybe it's because of me maybe you know
but I want to make sure before that it's
going to be like as easy to grow as
possible so that everybody can have
success from the small hobbyist tent
grower to the you know facilities and
then in the production strain world
they're going to need these heavy
yielding strains that check all the
boxes to stay afloat wow yeah brilliant
stuff I love that there's a specific
conscious focus on trying to make it
easier for the grower and every point
you said is uh a totally relevant but
it's interesting because as you said you
know other breeders May recognize some
of those issues but maybe not
necessarily actively trying to combat
them through their breeding so that's
really cool to hear
honestly don't see I don't yeah I
honestly don't see anything like I just
saw a clone drop today from
um compound genetics and like their
their picture that they're showing it
just looks like a little baby Bud looks
like a side branch and I'm like damn
that's like the best picture that they
have and they're putting that as like
you know here's our cone drop Etc I'm
like damn like to me just already I just
wouldn't get it you know what I mean I'm
like I don't
because I know it's not going to yield
you know what I mean I'm like and
everybody and so I'm you know yeah but
yeah you're right man everybody
everybody I don't think anybody
I don't know what's in everybody's head
but from what I see from the end
products it's literally just hype
strained hype strain and a lot of it is
not even like I don't know what they're
thinking you know what I mean like I
just don't know I think a lot of people
are just throwing [ __ ] against the wall
to see if it sticks I don't know if they
have plans or not
um but yeah I don't I try to just stay
in my own lane I was trying to do you
know what I'm doing so
um but yeah a lot of hype to Hype so
that's what I'm trying to stay away from
man that's brilliant I love that and um
I think we're gonna have to definitely
get you on for a sort of extended show
on on your your work I'd love to chat
more I think that that pretty much sums
up the questions I had for you in
regards to this award in terms of the
final thing I'd love to know what do you
think is going to be the next big flavor
that's going to dominate the industry oh
that's it yeah that's a good one so
basically from where it stands now at
least here
um everybody likes gas it seems right uh
and and nobody likes or everybody has
their own flavors of this let's let's
just say that everybody likes their own
flavors so
what everybody I think wants currently
right now is a is a gassy candy strain
that also you so but those don't really
exist usually there's going to be like
the gassy strains are usually like lower
yielding from from my experience
um harder to grow uh sometimes they
don't look that great and then you know
what I mean so it's hard so they
basically want The Best of Both Worlds
so somebody want I think the newest
thing will be whoever comes up with like
this candy gassy super heavy yielding
covered in trichomes that also has power
right that's the other key thing like
a lot of these strains they'd say oh
they're not they're not that powerful or
whatever it'll check like three boxes
you know what I mean so
um in terms of the terp profile it's a
candy gas like a still fruit but like
heavy gas if that's even I don't even
know if it's possible though you know
like I've had some stuff that kind of
almost checks those boxes but it doesn't
doesn't check them all so I think that's
going to be the next wave but I don't
know man it's kind of like asking like
you know does everybody like ipas you
know some people like Chris beers lagers
some people like ipas some people like
Stouts you know or ice cream so
I don't know we'll see though we'll see
we'll see we'll see we'll see what takes
off I love that so again a huge
congratulations on winning the hottest
newcomer on the Block award to blockhead
of Blockhead genetics what did I win
yeah good question right we'll send you
a uh I'll I'll paint something up in um
Microsoft Paint for you yeah
awesome man I can't wait for that
um so before we wrap up did you have any
general comments or shout outs you
wanted to make for sure so
um shout out to mobile J uh for
basically popping the seeds right let's
start off there uh I've without him and
he and I have had these conversations
multiple times without him I probably
would have never popped him without him
I probably would have never even started
anything that I've started you know what
I mean so uh Big Ups to Jay
um shout out to uh
man shout out to uh Harry Palms right
because without him there would have
been no Tropicana cookies shout out to
in-house there would have been no black
cherry punch for me
um let's just let's start there there's
a ton of shout outs but uh yeah I'll
just I'll just kind of leave it in the
in the uh in that for the Blackberry you
know what I mean so shout out to those
group uh for starting with they started
and and you know for letting me [ __ ]
with it you know what I mean and
creating blockberry yeah that sounds
like a very well-earned shout out so
thank you so much Blockhead for joining
us today and congrats again on the award
for sure thanks brother
[Music]
congrats hottest newcomer on the scene
shout out Blockhead buds so on to our
next award we have the hottest seed drop
of the year so to start off let's give
some honorable mentions I want to give
as mentioned earlier an honorable
mention to crickets and cicada for their
park back cross to work which has
garnered a lot of success utilizing
males such as the puck to create the BX
or the bc3
also using a a skunk as well as an
alternative Shoreline skunk clone two
different Scentsy star cuttings Bubba
Kush and more they've done really well
on the back of last year's breeder of
the Year award and building a
continuation of the puck Line work
they've been doing so huge shout out
honorable mention to crickets and cicada
likewise I want to give an honorable
mention to Exotic Mike his power sureb
work definitely causing some waves uh
being popular I know Mr Bean's a big fan
of it Mike breeds with many of his own
Creations which I give him credit for
many breeders line up comprises mostly
clones they were likely gifted however
Mike does Fino hunt his own work and
breed forward with it which is a cool
feature Mr Bean got any honorable
mentions for the hottest Siege off of
the year uh yeah well for for me I'd
definitely shout out to Mike on those um
you know it's cool to have been with him
from the start so to say like you know
we were Distributing for him since 2013
not from the start she's going to start
reading by 2009 right
um so we've been with him for a long
time anyhow uh and it's cool just to see
his work evolve and
and and and now start to see it in a lot
of other people's work and and it being
like like one of the like you're not
surprised like you're like wow they're
he's using Mike's kind of this so well
I'm not surprised right like it's just
it's you'd be surprised if you if they
didn't have one of my Scouts and then in
their lineup so to say
um so this is kind of cool to to mention
that one uh then for for me this year
Mike had a lot of good drops with us had
those two drops that were went really
really well
um the uh the uh red pop drop and the
red wrench drop but for me this year it
definitely is going to be the Crickets
and cicadas uh the the up bc3 drop
um I couldn't keep that thing in stock I
was calling I was calling an old bob
every other day
I'll send him an emails hey it was sold
out you crashed my site down can I get
some more of those
see check your mailbox get some more of
those so yeah I felt like you know a bit
like uh two guns Tommy at one point hey
man you got any one of those that bx3 so
he was happy we were happy to have that
in and you know it helped like I said I
met him last year and
he gave me a big jar of that [ __ ] and it
just kept knocking me in him knocking my
dick in the dirt every time I smoked it
I couldn't figure out what the hell was
wrong with me for like a month I was
like oh it's probably this weed it's on
my desk now I'm smoking uh just couldn't
function it was just serious serious
weed so that's you know the ones that
I'm most looking forward to and
um I mean I put I put a bunch of packs
aside uh that one and of course shout
out to Thug pug
um he's back uh he's got he's over his
surgery now he's feeling my better still
hungry as hell but feeling a lot better
um and he had his uh peanut butter BX
drop
um we are actually doing a pre-sale of
that right now if this is redrop because
he ran out of the first one so he did
another one
um and it's been two months and three
months in the making
uh so
we'll have that uh he has that rs11
rainbow shirt not not roadkill skunk uh
uh so those were two two really good
drops but uh where where are you going
with this one yeah I was gonna say shout
out Grandma glad to hear you're doing
well after the surgery I think that um
overall for this year the winner for me
was was pretty obvious and it feels like
almost sandbagging a bit but the hottest
air dropper this year I think is
undeniably Chris compounds apples and
bananas its success was simply
unparalleled the compound drop garnered
a huge amount of support and attention
even featuring nft drops to accompany
them and some top shelf pricing the
drops sold out extremely quickly and
from what we both saw at the emerald cup
had people lining up around the corner
for it high times has in fact recently
named Pink certs its strain of the year
for 2022 which was included in this
apples and bananas drop other notable
strains from the drop included
gastropops which has garnered a lot of
popularity utilizing the white runts
mother and the overall success is a
testament not only to the power of good
marketing which is undeniably played a
role in the success but also to have
when good marketing combined with
quality genetics will make for something
truly special having tried the apples
and bananas myself I can say it's some
beautiful herb grapey Berry sort of hard
to describe at the same time it
dominates a bag and these hybrids are
offering Growers many of the best
qualities of both what's your thoughts
Mr Bean apples and bananas
uh well you know it goes back to where
I've always preached and said some of
that some of the best guys the guys that
can run the numbers because it's a
numbers game folks it really is
um we can all go by the same clone and
we're all going to have the same kind of
the same clone of the same thing or we
can run from seeds we're guaranteed
something uniquely ours something that
nobody else has and it's like baseball
cards right you could have the you could
have the first five pack you could get
that Babe Ruth
but but Hank Aaron is always out there
or you could collect cards for 10 years
and pop ten thousand beats and never get
it right it's always out there floating
around you there's always that better
one
um and these these breeders are these
giant facilities you know they have the
opportunity to run five thousand at a
time
um and so when you're using that kind of
numbers for final hunts you're able to
find that that that's something that
something different I've always heard
breeders say that you know if you look
for it it's in there don't don't overdo
it don't keep doing the line if you it's
it's in there just keep looking what you
want to find is there
um and so I think that you know they
have these the the ability to run these
giant populations and see these plants
and see the subtle differences in them
um to see that one that really sticks
out you know I think that's uh it's
truly special and I think all the guys
that have that ability definitely shine
huge shout out and congratulations to
the apples and bananas drop by Chris of
compound genetics
yeah Chris Lynch so because now the
compound the other there's two Chris's
there's Chris Lynch and there's the
other Chris which is also one of their
scientist guys and so now they're like
they just did a thing on future cameras
project they were like I said Chris with
compound and I was like what Chris I
know he's along with a [ __ ] compound
I look at the TV and it's they keep
saying Chris with a compound but it's
not Chris compound it's the other Chris
super smart uh Chris from node Chris
from node Labs okay interesting
interesting so up next we've got the
Hall of Fame strain
what's what's your predictions you got
any got anything coming to mind for you
um yeah I mean I can I can talk about it
like when you talk about what you want
to be but I I was thinking about that
like what would be my hall of fame
strain but that that's just giving it up
that was just I don't know what I would
do like that I would be
you know uh like ruining a future strain
for us to talk about I guess that's true
that's true no I like that angle okay so
the Hall of Fame strain for this year is
Haze by the Hayes Brothers in all of its
incarnations we have certainly seen a
recent Resurgence of popularity for
Hayes I think there's initially got some
momentum probably around the time
Neville passed the nl5 came back into
the Limelight but more recently with the
Advent of things like the Colombian
black Haze or the pif as well as work by
people like Tom Hill and Mr Bob's
reproduction we are seeing Hayes yet
again more the focus of attention in the
Cannabis Community Zeitgeist and it's a
strain that I think is well worthy of
the Hall of Fame work done by Sam and
then the work of countless others around
the world the likes of old timer one and
many other unsung heroes Hayes is a
truly special plant I don't know if I
can do it justice in just a few minutes
so I hope I can cover some of the main
points but Hayes gave birth to a wave of
smokers who pursued the euphoric and
cerebral effects that Hayes has become
iconic for it is certainly a white whale
in its own right claimed by countless
ogs to be the Pinnacle of smoking and
combining some of the oldest building
blocks the Cannabis genome has to offer
Haze truly is unlike any other strain
having countless incarnations varying
from mixers of pure Colombians through
to Thai hybrids through to nl5 Haze
hybrids it's made its mark on History
without any doubt a recent Resurgence
has been brought on by several people in
the community notable ogs the likes of
Tom Hill have launched into massive Haze
funeral hunts to show everyone just how
Kick-Ass the keeperfino is that many
have spoken so fondly about as well as
others the likes of Mr Bob who has
carried on the Pres Innovation work by
continuing the Tom Hills Haze and
releasing it commercially as well as
making a haze hybrid featuring old-timer
ones Haze Tom Hills Haze and original
Haze
descending originally from the Hayes
Brothers to Sam and then to the world
Hayes is truly something unique
something in its own category and
something clearly worthy of the Hall of
Fame category maybe more simply put
Hayes rules everything around me what's
your thoughts Mr Bean pretty awesome
what's that uh you know I thought we
were going a different direction with
that one in fact you're going for Blue
Dream which is you know a Hades
derivative you could say
um but the haze is a classic a wonderful
Choice
um the Hayes Brothers got that thing uh
uh 12 to 16 week strain most people
don't grow it out or won't grow it out
because they don't have the time for it
um super uh super huge uh like it
stretches like no other they like it
right
um so uh so it's very uh
you know definitely like that strong
um super capacity smell but it's
definitely definitely something that's
been worked
um by many people and and uh I don't
know that many people nowadays have
smoked a haze a lot of the new new
smokers I don't believe have
um because I don't believe that shops
pay for the hate and today's growing
economy of you know you know that that
plan has to pay for its way
um a 16-week strain or 12-week strain uh
doesn't really pay its bills to be there
next to an eight weeks train
you're going to pay the same price per
pound price per gram so uh but the hazes
are phenomenal um like I said it's it's
I just uh I don't know many people that
can grow them or they haven't because
they do take so it's such a long time
but it's worth the wait for sure uh that
it is but you know what
what is it those who are patient or
rewarded I'm excited to try to get into
some of it myself in the near future but
again a big congrats to the strain Haze
and all those associated with it so many
people so many unsung heroes I'm not
doing it justice but everyone who's
played a role thank you so much yeah
just just I mean because because those
guys weren't they weren't funeral
hunting in the 60s right because that's
where I mean we can talk the haze goes
all the way back to the 60s so I mean
anything that that's that's that's LED
that's held the test of time for like 50
years people still have it or still talk
about it right that's it's got to be
something special there because these
guys weren't doing funeral hunts back
then they were just you know or they're
smaller scale they just so it's for
something to work and spread that far
and wide that's gotta be all right yeah
100 percent
stayed in the test of time for good
reason
so our next award we're going to do the
Hall of Fame breeder next so following
the same Principle as last time I guess
I I won't get you to spurt out what
could be next year's suggestion so I'll
get right into it so for this year the
Hall of Fame breeder we want to induct
is none other than Bodhi of Bodhi seeds
do I really need to say any more truly a
name that needs no introduction Bodhi is
a pillar in our community the most
iconic yet simplistic seed packaging the
community has ever seen
but if you see that green bag and that
Gold Label you know straight away what
it is bodhi's worked with countless
cannabis lines countless proven males
that have yielded amazing clones that
the community has benefited from the
snow Lotus has given birth to famous
lines such as the go gog the ancient OG
tranquil elephantiser so many more and
his beloved 88 G13 hash plant male has
given birth to some undeniable Legends
the black triangle as well as the
infamous entire deep line Alchemy range
which is paired to other old world
indicas his preservation work with
norika seeds is up there with some of
those who dedicate themselves
exclusively to that sort of preservation
he has countless lines from afghanis to
Africans Colombians to Nepalese and Thai
this work is utilized by many other
breeders both for selection and for
their own reproductions ensuring future
Generations can continue the work
furthermore his creation stemming from
Supernatural selections where he makes
raw F1 hybrids with land race and
heirloom varieties remixing like a DJ
trying to give the people a new unheard
sound he's involved in countless charity
projects he supports the community
Through still using testers which most
breeders are phased out he's also more
recently taken an active role in trying
to facilitate the broader cannabis
Community to experience a new and
enlightening cannabis effect with his
assignment as the head of genetics at
cookies something I'm extremely excited
to see happening truly one of the most
standout humans I've ever had the
privilege of calling one of my friends
the 2022 Hall of Fame breeder Goes To
None other than Bodhi of Bodhi seeds
thank you so much for everything you do
Buddy's an icon I mean another another
one to knock it out of the park as far
as far as uh Hall of Famer for sure
obviously he's an icon in the industry
I've had the pleasure of meeting him a
few times
um he's he does have the simplest
packaging out there but that goes to
show you you know it's not it's not
about the packaging it's about what's
inside the packaging I don't know of any
of my breeders like 70 of them I think
everybody
has a pack of Bodhi seeds in their
collection if they don't they should if
they and if you don't buy them for me
buy them from one of those guys so he's
uh but he's an amazing an amazing
breeder
um he helps uh he doesn't he says he's
not a breeder he says he helps plants
have sex but uh he's got for sure a line
she's got a seed collection that uh
would die for for sure
um so it wasn't definitely surprised
when cookies want to get the best the
best out there who's got the best
collection best Library
it's going to be body
so and and uh definitely if you've seen
the baggie you've seen it once you've
seen it twice you know what it is that's
exactly it okay you're the Gold Label as
you said simply iconic so huge huge huge
thank you to Bodhi for everything you do
my friend we're so appreciative as a
community and it is with great sadness
we bid farewell to our friend Jaime
Chiba AKA James shank aka the Alaskan
Santa Claus one of the kindest people
you would ever meet and a man who
dedicated himself to the plant the head
honcho of the Alaskan cannabis seed
cache sadly we lost Jaime just before
our last episode and we are truly
devastated to see him pass he is
associated with countless strains such
as the roadkill skunk the mud blight
delight and the Alaskan Thunder [ __ ] he
specialized in older strains often from
the 80s and 90s and focused his work on
preserving genetics for future
generations to enjoy truly a gentleman
of the highest quality I'm deeply sad to
have lost a valuable member of our
community Jaime Chiba thank you sir ride
on into Infinity
yeah and then I have a an rip as well uh
this year also we lost Matthew to sale
of goat monkey seeds
um goat monkey did like a chocolate dog
if they did the triangle Kush S1 star
runs uh Matthew I first met Matthew
about six years ago he you know answered
one of my ads to work at booth in
Massachusetts
came out and worked the booth and uh you
know later I was it was cornbread
Ricky's suggestion that he he worked the
booth and I said well that's as bad as
good as resumes anybody can have uh so
he worked for us for a little while was
our East Coast rep and workout uh in the
East Coast with us every time we'd hang
out with the gym dog and started
breeding and uh real real good guy did a
lot of good work
um but uh he passed away uh on September
this year so
uh rip to him
yeah a huge huge shout out to his family
and uh yeah R.I.P zochi a valued member
of the community
Caleb of CSI has recently done a
reproduction of the Sterling skunk which
comes by way of by way of uh both Bodhi
and zochi so hopefully his work can live
on through that line but that's a you
know another sad farewell we have to say
good good guy he's a good guy
well that must bring us to the big award
for the end of the year
the breeder of the Year award
there's a few people in contention and
so it's only right to give some
honorable mentions and one that we've
done a few times already none other than
Mr Bob Hemphill and Hannah bolt of
crickets and cicada they've had yet
another super successful year coming off
the back of last year's breeder of the
Year win they've continued to blaze a
trail forward with their Puck line this
time working on the back cross two
making a range of hybrids including the
shoreline skunk the Scentsy star the
Bubba cushion more as well as doing a
haze preservation project among it the
Tom Hill Hayes F3 as well as a hybrid
Haze project incorporating Old-Timers
Haze Tom Hills Hayes and original Haze
so well well done qriket's in cicada
yeah no Cricket's a kid has definitely
uh they had uh you know really happy
there there that Tom Hillis Hayes drop
and then of course the [ __ ] PC3 uh was
like I said crazy I was burning up his
phone trying to get more of those and
also for for me and I will mention uh
one of my guys that I like to you know
that exotic you know he had you know at
least three drops this year um each of
them sold and over 100 packs and we was
a good good guy uh good good breeding
technique is his gear is solid as hell
um I've been repping this stuff for a
while now and uh uh always I've never
had any problem with any of my scare
really good stuff nice and I will give a
third honorable mention to someone not
too many degrees of separation related
to Mike none other than soulfire he too
has had a very productive year with a
number of releases the Bahama triangle
the hood candies and the mind flayer
series all dropping within the past 12
months he's certainly blazing a path
forward not too dissimilar to Exotic
Mike
however
the breeder of the year
going to none other than Chris Lynch of
compound genetics that's right our
runner-up breeder of the year for last
year has gone on to take the head spot
this year he's worked his ass off doing
compound drops cookies collabs nfts
doing deals and more it's undeniable
that Chris has been one of the biggest
movers and shakers in the scene over the
past 12 months so much so that all of it
uh sorry it's undeniable that Chris has
been one of the biggest movers and
shakers in the scene over the past 12
months however all this has been made in
recent with the reveal that he has sold
and left compound genetics to start a
new Venture called sci-fi genetics let's
hear more from the man himself now
[Music]
alrighty my friends we are back and this
time grateful to be joined by the man of
the hour one of the hottest dudes in the
industry a big congratulations to Chris
on winning several Awards this past year
including most anticipated sea drop
breeder of the year and clone of the
year so first off thank you so much for
joining us today Chris how you doing
excellent man thank you good to be here
I'm so grateful I imagine you must be a
very busy man given everything I just
said so we're very grateful to have your
time how does it feel to win these
Awards do you feel like you've had a big
year the past year it's an extra man it
feels good to get the recognition from
the industry and from my peers it's
always very humbling to receive Awards
like this so thank you for the um
recognition and the award it means a lot
I feel the series might be a big year
for me with all the um wins I've had and
all the new obstacles that I've had to
overcome with compound and with my own
place in the industry I'm looking
forward to work 2023 takes me and what's
next
yeah incredible I know that all of your
fans are equally excited for what you
have for us over the coming few years I
would love to start let's talk about the
uh clone of the Year award so apples and
bananas took out clone of the year I
think you'd probably have to be living
under a rock to have not heard or
experienced apples and bananas at this
point I guess the place I'd love to
start is
um maybe going back to the Genesis you
know do you remember that pollination
where you made it and um what was it
about those two parents that Drew you to
it because I think it's something I
really like about apples and bananas is
that it utilizes genetics you don't see
as much and I think that helped made it
special but I'd love to hear your take
on it
yeah any other cross back in 2019 I
believe I was working in a small
basement I had access to in Portland
Oregon
um I received the now and later cut from
my friend Clearwater genetics in
Colorado I traded him some cuts for it I
think it was a gelato 41 I traded him
for the now and later and so I received
that cut I immediately put it to work um
I didn't really expect anything special
to come from the cut so it's really
awesome to see how far it's come
um yeah it was really cool to see that
recognition I received and remember
giving the uh the the phenotype to him
and the selection to uh burner when I
started working with cookies and he's
the one that kind of really put apples
and bananas on the map so I have to give
him all the credit and got all the
credit but you know part of the credit
for basically creating The Branding and
helping with the recognition that this
Cuts received and the momentum it's
gotten so it's really cool to see what I
come full circle
wow there you go I didn't know you had
made it that long ago and that's cool to
hear the back story on it something
which grabbed my eye about it is that
this is the second big cut that has
utilized work from Sin City genetics and
I think they largely speaking sort of
fly under the radar but people may know
that um jbz also used some of their work
in the wedding cake so I think we've now
got two nice clones that sort of
illustrate some of the um the quality of
their genetics
um is this is this a thought you've ever
meditated on maybe Sin Cities like
secretly the Breeders breeder or do you
think like a bit of a coincidence
I'm not sure it's probably coincidence
and some aspects but definitely know
since city does lots of solid work and
the blue Power they they created has
been a big part of um jvc's genetics in
his work so yeah they definitely have an
eye and a taste for quality and good
good Gen X so I think that there's a
reason that their their work is known
for its backbones for so many privileged
breeders
yeah amazing and in that recent answer
you mentioned working with burner and
how he helped promote the strain I've
got to ask what's that like because
obviously the the media Powerhouse that
is cookies is undeniable right it has
the ability to really Market strains
better than 99.9 of people can is that
is it a bit surreal to see your work
gets like showcased so well or like how
did how did that come about I guess
yeah it's very humbling I'm still uh
take it back by it every day it's a very
awesome experience to have I'm grateful
to work with Burr and the whole cookies
team I remember when we first linked up
about around 2019 in San Francisco he
was asking for some jars of flavors and
the apples have been as well maybe that
apples apples cut which was didn't have
that name at the time I had in a jar and
I gave it to him and he immediately
gravitated towards that so I have to
give him props for he has a very strong
eye for a taste and for what's going to
work in the market so I don't think
without him selecting that Fina with me
and getting the name Apple Savannah it
would be recognized where it is now so
it's really cool to be able to work with
someone like burner who has that that
ability to basically put a string on or
off and having select strains that I've
created obviously decided to put them on
the map so it's a really cool experience
that's incredible I love to hear that I
wanted to ask you about something I I've
I've been um grateful to have received a
few samples of apples and bananas while
I was in the states recently and they
were gorgeous and something people said
to me and that I also experienced myself
is it has this quality to it that is
similar to like some of the Citrus
strains in the sense that it's not
Citrus but it cuts through like you have
one butt of it in a bag of stuff and
it's like that's all you smell it really
cuts through I was wondering because you
look at the genetics and I like I wasn't
really sure where that trait was coming
from do you have any speculations on why
it's got such a dominant profile to it
I don't know I'm not exactly sure maybe
it was back to the work since city did
that blue power or it could be a mixture
of the GDP or just a combination of all
the genetics in the crust together I
tend to get more of a gassy unique
profile from it but everyone has their
own kind of um trait there or or they're
tripping they pull out from it but
simply it simply is something that makes
it unique with the cut server so yeah
it's definitely a strong one
yeah sorry I should clarify I I just
wanted to say I don't think it smells
like citrus it just um I actually can't
describe the flavor profile to be honest
and I think a lot of people said that as
well it's like it's a mixture of yeah
gassy unique berries grapes it's it's
beautiful and I agree with you it's
something about those genetics just seem
to really work well which is lovely so
next thing I wanted to ask you is one of
the other Awards you want is the hottest
seed drop of the year and if I had to do
a single one I would say probably the
apples and bananas drop but I want to
give equal props to the grape gas drop
which I think also did really well had
some standout strains what's your
recollection on those two drops and is
one of them more memorable to you than
the other or you think they're both sort
of equal
um the real special in their their own
way for me I think the grape gas
um created more of a wave on its own
because the baby has to really have any
recognition going in the in the
collection it was kind of uh uh
away from cookies prior to the release
so I'm grateful and surprised at the
whole the whole momentum that the king
sources received in other strange
commitment The Collection like the
Mellows pink shirts those are all very
um strong strains they've done well in
the market since the season release so
I'm proud of that collection I think the
Apple has been as also unique on its own
because it kind of was a combination of
all the workers burner and was cookie so
it was a special in a different way uh
yeah they're both really collections
good Collections and I think they both
have unique profiles the admin to the to
the um the gene pool and we'll be here
for a while I love that that is that is
really cool and and as you just touched
on the the pink certs has done really
well High times recently named Pink
certs as the strain of the year were you
anticipating that to be the one that
stood out of the grape gas drop or was
there another one that you maybe
suspected might have done a little
better
I was actually surprised by that and
it's still awesome to see that that
success that strange then so it props to
the service guys and everyone from the
service family who's kind of been on
board for this this as well I kind of
made that whole branding and naming on
my own and it really rejected to those
guys prior to doing it so it was kind of
cool to see that whole
thing come full circle you get to create
the wave it did so
um it's definitely unique and strong
across I I had a a idea I feel like it
would be a Powerhouse but the amount of
momentous received in where it's gone is
nothing I expected so it's very cool to
see that
incredible incredible now I'm gonna I'm
gonna put you in a hard spot here if you
could only pick one pack out of the
apples and bananas drop and one one pack
out of the grape gas drop which would be
your pick
that's a tough question very tough
question
um from the grape grass I have to pick
pink stores just it's it's it's the one
for sure and from apples bananas um and
things like that either the uh the
goofies the uh the uh Jewelers 31 by
apples of bananas or the the Exotic
squared the red pop by apples and bears
from from yeah those are both very
strong ones
nice one that's that's cool to hear the
red pop um hybrid in there getting a
mention I love that so I would love to
know because I think you would you and a
few other people would have a good idea
of this what do you predict will be some
of the big flavor profiles we see roll
in over the coming year or so any any
predictions for what might come back so
to speak
um I think the purple gas is here to
stay it's not going to go away anytime
soon I think um we'll see more of like
mixtures of old lost strains or more
unique profiles mixed with the current
strains like purple gas makes with some
unique cultivars that I've been
forgotten about or is it was hot you
know five years ago it's going to come
back as a new version mixed with purple
gas or mixed with runs or mixed with you
know some hot strings or mixes z-trips
something like that you know the new
mixed all that I kind of see that is
kind of a new way for the next wave a
very smart terms you can find some more
original sculptures it's kind of always
been a desirable thing but yeah just a
mixture of uh new and old I think it
will be possibly some new some new stuff
we'll see coming forward and just you
know things are on the radar I think
there's so much of the scene right now
people are looking for things that are
different so anything that's different
that stands out that checks all the
boxes I think will do well
too true too true I think we're seeing
that in the industry for sure that some
of the olds coming back but there's
definitely some new Staples and I like
that term purple gas I'm gonna I'm gonna
adopt that term into my library because
I've never heard it but as soon as you
said it I knew exactly what you meant so
yeah or purple candy purple candy purple
gas they're both very hot right now yeah
yeah yeah I love that okay so final
question for this little award segment
what can we hope to see from you over
the coming year do we do we think we
might see a sea drop at some point or we
just need to wait and see what happens
yeah I'm working on some new projects
right now you can't see too much at the
moment but you'll see some Steve Jobs
coming soon in the next year hopefully
and uh also we'll try to work on some
stuff with Burner in the museum I have
some new projects I'm working with
Burner as well so you'll see some some
new stuff from me on my own and some
collaborations with various people
beautiful I cannot wait to see so again
thank you so much for coming on and
chatting to us today were there any
general comments or shout outs you
wanted to make yeah thank you to the
community and for everyone recognizing
my work and supporting me throughout
this journey it's been awesome to see
the amount of feedback and love I get
from the community I'm always grateful
for that as far as shout out to a shout
out to Burger shout out to um shout out
to the service guys shout out to runs
shout out to him RN from greenhouse and
the strangers crew shout out to dp's uh
shout out to wizard cheese Julio Julio
the C plug everyone supports me you know
thank you for all your support and love
amazing thanks so much again Chris for
coming by thank you
foreign
[Music]
big thanks to Chris for giving us that
Insight so again a reader of the Year
Chris Lynch of compound genetics huge
shout out 2022 absolutely crushed it Mr
Bean what's your thoughts was Chris your
pick uh
um I would have gone with exotic that's
it with exotic just because I think he's
had more of those drops
um you can find so so Chris also did the
the Joker's line right
yes sir and what happened to Joker's
line I'm not sure actually it didn't
hasn't come out through compound yet has
it so uh
if you go on my website
under breeder X
and you look at the mail I was used in
all those trains
female Poland
that might be the hidden Joker's line
unreleased released
oh what sort of fell off a truck Vibe
are you given here
just just saying maybe I mean I don't I
don't know that the community would
really go for somebody else using that
many of somebody else's work so to say
like if you look at what was used
but all that all that media and all that
hype goes to nothing that would be a
shame so check out breederax on my
website get yourself a few phenotype the
gastropop I have heard is something
special for sure
um and and uh and the pink shirts
um that's it's great here to hide you
know on stream of the year and their
packaging is on point and those guys
that's that's how they got that special
thing is by running numbers that's what
you're going to get when you run numbers
you're gonna find just because you have
a pack of something doesn't mean it's
the best something
um or sometimes you might need two packs
so very nice and tomorrow if you know
hunt more have fun
well that just about brings us to the
end of it thank you so much as always
for joining me Mr Bean oh thank you for
having me and I appreciate you I
appreciate your audience and I love
listening to all your stuff over the
years
um I'd love to get uh Bob Jr on with you
I'd love to sit down and uh and have him
talk with you I know that you did an
excellent uh great podcast with his dad
and I think it'd be really cool to get
you a name going
um on a follow-up
um I've got him and Duke uh talking as
of last Saturday together they're going
to do their first collab together
that's exciting because as he mentioned
as Bob mentioned on your show he
mentioned that I had it set him and Duke
up to do a collab and then he
unfortunately passed away before they
got it started and so this just kind of
finishes that project up that's lovely
and cool to hear we'll have to follow up
with that stay tuned everyone yep and
you can check out my YouTube channel uh
get real seeds here now uh YouTube
um and you've got the interview with bog
on the the done show that you just we
talked about basically the gear that I
have that I'm selling came from his dad
and whatnot
um and then hopefully we'll get the full
sit down three hour in-depth interview
with with you yeah it'll be cool to
cover that one
again thank you for joining me and to
everyone who's made it to the end we
appreciate it that's us signing off oh
hey by the way anybody that that you
will listen to the show if they uh use
podcast free ship
gets 10 gets free shipping uh on their
order that's a stackable coupons that
works with any other coupon it's not
usually it's usually either or but this
is works with all of them so all your
listeners uh podcast free ship and then
we'll get free shipping wow killer thank
you so much everyone jot it down
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
friends what do you think
agree disagree let me know
who was your breeder of the year what
was your seed drop of the year
as always got to give a massive shout
out to the people who helped make this
show happen seeds here now guarantee on
satisfaction not just germination why
would you go to any other seed bank if
you're if you finish your Harvest and
you are not happy with the end product
hit them up they'll sort you out that's
how confident they are with every
breeder they select including the one
and only heavy days genetics get on that
hitter guys
likewise corporate biological systems
the best in the business you know them
you've heard of them these guys are
world renowned they need no introduction
get the happy param if you're battling
aphids get the spidex vital if you're
battling spider mites I promise you you
will not regret releasing beneficial
Predators into your garden before you
have a problem
get peace of mind sleep easy at night
Copa biological systems thank you so
much we appreciate you so much just like
we appreciate pulse sensors these guys
have the best senses in the game the
latest real-time information sent
straight to your phone you can track how
your rooms are going even if you're
nowhere near the facility nowhere near
your house nowhere near your tent no
matter what your operation is it's time
to get serious get a pulse sensor pulse
is the way to go if you're looking to up
your game huge shout out pulse sensors
we appreciate you
last but not least the patreon gang they
got to listen to this early probably by
a couple months even that's how good the
patreon is you're going to hear stuff so
much earlier if you support the patreon
please consider signing up if you want
to help to ensure that episodes continue
to happen
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast it's a bit of a mouthful but
you'll be able to find it if you Google
it
as usual thank you so much for getting
to the end of the episode and for the
support in general I appreciate all of
you guys that does it for this year's
awards ceremony
huge shout out to Mr Bean for joining us
as always
and I think I'll see you for the next
one
[Music]
foreign