[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
this episode as always was brought to
you by our amazing sponsors see you here
now your number one place to get seeds
guarantee on germination and
satisfaction why would you go anywhere
else they got all the best breeders in
the game check them out if you want to
grow some of that fire for yourself
likewise coppet biological systems they
got everything to keep the garden happy
healthy and pumping out that killer
whether it's beneficial bugs microbes or
feeds they're your One-Stop shop
likewise huge shout out to the patreon
gang you guys are the lifeblood of the
show helping to make episodes happen if
you want access to exclusive content
Early Access to episodes and more go
check out patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
this week we are thrilled to be joined
by the genetic Maestro himself Chimera
to talk about all things cannabis
science and so much more I hope you're
ready for a big one guys this is going
to be a three-parter first one ever
let's get into it
alrighty so a big thank you and welcome
to the genetic Maestro himself Ryan of
chimerogenetics thank you so much for
taking the time to chat with us today
my pleasure Heavenly thank you for
having me here
not a problem so the first question we
like to ask guests these days is what
are you currently been smoking on
you know I'm actually I'm not really
smoking a lot of flour these days the
last couple of years I've really been
focused on vaping concentrates I'm not
even really dabbing them on a hot nail
either just with a torch or
uh you know a lower temp kind of Vape
device
I find it's a lot easier on my lungs and
you know as we start getting up on in
age it uh
you know I I I kind of when I when I
hang out with friends at conferences and
stuff we're used to do that back in the
day the emerald cup or whatever we do
there's a lot of really really heavy
smoking that goes on and I just find
that it doesn't it doesn't really go
well too well with my lungs
um I'd rather do a smaller inhalation of
something much much stronger and more
flavorful so I've kind of been staying
away from the flower to be perfectly
Frank
um so just really smoking on Fresh live
rosin and really nice fresh dabs that
kind of are popping around in the
community these these days here
yeah I can certainly relate to that
sentiment having recently put down the
bong and picked up the Vape myself I
guess my question is do you feel like
there are any specific cultivars which
really lend themselves to being
um smoked through a vape in concentrate
form
I think they all do
um you know a really good a really good
live rosin or a live resin kind of
extract
is really just the essence of the plant
and the THC so you're you're removing
all that you know that leaf material
that really is not adding anything of
Health to your lungs and it's certainly
not anything adding anything to the
experience of the of the smoke or of the
consumption so
I really think that that kind of
Direction whether it's a high quality
CO2 or whatever the extraction method is
as long as you remove all the
um the solvents and even better if
you're using solventless techniques
you're really just getting the the part
of the plant that
you know is really is is what we want
right
um and it's just an evolution from from
you know started office and then we all
kind of got into the bubble hash and the
and the dry CIS but the these extracts
they use as you know probably they use
heat and pressure to to pull the
essential compounds out of that kind of
more natural Matrix of the of the resin
and uh your you know if it's processed
and cared for carefully you end up with
a product that in my opinion is a lot
healthier to smoke than you know sucking
on half gram joints all day
yeah certainly I think the the amount of
tar consumed is astronomically different
right so for that reason alone I'm on
board in past episodes we've had
breeders talk about this idea of
breeding for the end goal of making
concentrates and sometimes they would
reference you know big land heads things
like that would you ever consider
something like that or do you just think
like a good strain will translate to
good concentrates and you don't need to
specifically set out to do that yeah
good cultivar should definitely I mean
if it's grown well that's what you're
trying to do is bring out that Peak
essential oil expression and I think
that any kind of variety is really good
for that there's definitely something
going on with the size of the resin
gland and either the ratio of the
thickness of the gland to the internal
diam or the you know the internal
diameter essentially so think of it like
a we call it a waxy pillow so like the
the pillowcase is made of something that
is somewhat fibrous or waxy material
it's got you know there's there's
actually no drug content in the in the
structure of the trichome itself but the
inside of that pillow is where all the
um the essential oils are produced in
the plant and certainly where the
cannabinoids are produced as well
and um
yeah so really being able to like take
those compounds out or the oil that is
in those compounds which is really what
I call what I consider the essence of
the plant
um
yeah I'm not so sure that we've really
do understand whether it's there's a
specific gland size or maybe when the
glands get to a certain size that the
the you know the membrane that surrounds
that waxy pillow gets thicker so it can
can hold in the the uh the contents and
like I said that's not those those
that's made for material that is not
um really what we're after is consumers
it's just kind of in the way
and so I think a really a good extract
is about removing the things that we
want from the things that we don't want
without changing the chemical profile of
the plant
um and that way any extract really will
let there any good quality extract will
let the plant shine in its in its best
form right
and we like them all I mean it's it's
expensive to deal with the with a tire
um you know a haze or something like the
Lyman Pine that I was using for a while
they make incredible extracts but you
know the ratio the return is not very
good
um so as a breeding goal really it's
just about you know producing biomass
with enough what we call oil content
um you know so that you they can shine
in extracts
sure and I mean a great point you just
touched on there about you know Hayes
and some of these smaller yielding
sativa varieties you know making it a
hard sort of argument for the return on
investment I remember in an episode with
DJ Short he discussed how some of these
varieties have like a higher proportion
of the systolithic trichomes that don't
have that kind of pillowcase that we've
been referencing would you think that
there is still a lot of room to make
concentrates because I think DJ said
that you know they tend to secrete the
oils onto the surface of the plant do
you think that you could still get a
good return from that given that the
oil's there somewhere it's just maybe
not in the trichome head or do you think
the trichome head is really
fundamentally necessary to get that good
concentrate
yeah so but you know I don't like
creating drama with people but that's
he's actually not correct to say that
listen systolithic errors are
non-glandular
um so they actually don't really uh
produce an oil
um that's extractable or that is
secreted by the the structure it's
really like a thought long thin kind of
pointy thing
um
if you look at a resin gland under you
know some kind of microscopic picture
and there's all sorts of them on the net
you know bubble man is they've got a lot
of great great ones if you follow him on
Instagram
um but you can kind of see that the
actual structure it's really about
what's inside that glandular head and
there's shorter you know gland there's
also there's a few different types of
glands on the plant there's these non
you know non-capital glands and there's
the bulbous glands that sit on uh on the
leaf like you were saying they're kind
of more down towards they don't really
have a kind of think of it like a golf
ball on a tee that sticks into the into
the leaf surface so they don't really
have the tea part it's just like kind of
a little gland on the
on the ground but I'm not sure that
those are really
um too important in the overall
processing you know in the overall space
there is some definite differences in
chemistry but I think with our current
extraction methods
um unless you're actually physically
separating those gland heads by size
we're really just going in with either
heat or pressure or a solvent to pull
those things out
right so you're gonna for the most part
you're gonna get it all anyway
yeah sure so a question I'm very
interested in but is one that's kind of
hard to talk to people without a
scientific background so I've been
waiting for you to come on so you could
give me your opinion I remember in that
same chat with DJ we were talking about
like the biochemical nature of like what
makes you feel a strain as a sativa
versus an indica and it's obviously
still a bit of a cloudy area where we
don't really have it down pat but
something which always comes to my mind
is that even if you take a really racy
sativa and make a concentrate it doesn't
tend to have that same racy effect like
you might still perceive it as a bit
sativary but it's certainly mellowed out
what's your thoughts on this and do you
think that it maybe indicates that
there's something in the plant matter
which isn't being extracted which
contributes to the perceptual feel of a
certain strain
yeah so there's a few things that we
should probably touch on that let's come
back to the Indica sativa thing and just
talk about the chemistry thing for a
moment
um and actually we can use Dan as a
great example
um
you know DJ he had these great you know
all these great varieties but his whole
thing has always been he you know he he
came from a lot a time period where we
weren't breeding using a lab right we
were always selecting plants based on
how they make you feel not how much THC
there is in the plant okay and so when I
I was doing some work down in the states
and you know I collected a whole bunch
of Dan's stuff uh both in Clone and and
from seed and we grew up a fair amount
of it
and the the one thing that I noticed in
general was that the plants were
actually relatively low THC they were in
most of them not all of them but the
vast majority of them fell kind of in
the 8 to 12 to 13 range which is pretty
low for the market
um Market average these days at least in
in North America and California
specifically
um
and I've also noticed this with you know
other if you listen to experiences of
people that take the Sesame which is a
you know a synthetic THC it's actually
not see it it's a yeah it's a synthetic
THC in a peanut oil
Matrix kind of a jelly you know a jelly
type pill capsule and if you take those
things
or you ask the patients that are using
them what they feel and they always say
they get really tired
and I've kind of noticed after having
access to the lab and playing with a lot
of these different varieties and smoking
them and also having the ability to run
them through to understand their
cannabinoid profile is that when you
start turning the THC way up you really
do get that lethargic property and I
think that what a lot of people
sometimes confuse for the effects of
miracine is actually a result of a high
THC concentration whereas Dan was always
selecting for plants based on
they're again how they made him feel not
on the basis of a lab report and so I
think that there's something to that
ceiling lists high that really Clarity
that you get from smoking you know what
you're
referring to as the the sativas I call
them equatorials those more equatorial
plants
um that they were not really bred for
high cannabinoid content they're really
in that lighter
what I would call the lighter class of
of cannabis
and you know for for you know I I'm I'm
mid 40s so I'm going to say younger
generation but you know obviously we're
now not the younger generation anymore
but I think in regards to the folks that
were smoking a lot during the 60s and
70s and and early 80s and and working
back then
you know those types of headspace you
hear it all the time where these these
older hippie Elders are from our
community say you know today's cannabis
is too strong and we don't have those
unique head spaces that you used to be
able to get from the Acapulco Golds and
the Hawaiians and the ties
and I have a theory and I you know I
haven't confirmed this 100 obviously but
but my theory is that a lot of those
head spaces that you that you could get
back then were because the Cannabis
actually wasn't stronger than you know
even 15 cannabis right
in Canada I mean I'm in Canada and now
we have this legal you know this
National legalization system and the
provincial Distributors that buy the
Cannabis from The Growers they really
don't want to even look at anything less
than 20 percent
um which is crazy because I mean if you
make that if you if you transfer that
analogy over to the alcohol industry
that would wipe out most of the wines
and all of the beers and the you know
the ciders and all that kind of stuff
and really push
into
the the spirit world right the the
whiskeys and the Gins and the vodkas all
that kind of stuff
and I think that having a regulatory
system where
that that encourages us to just start
chasing high THC numbers is actually not
a great way to be producing cannabis
because again we're not
we're not
considering the way that these plants
make people feel the younger generation
that's all they've grown up with you
know they a lot of these kids start with
dabs and stuff so you get a lot more THC
they they get a lot larger dose of THC
and it's again like I said that's my
personal
my personal belief that that's actually
one of the things that's leading to this
what I call THC lethargy
right we try to
in in the community we try to say oh
terpenolene or limonene or pinene they
make you up they give you an up
perspective
um but and then mircin brings you down
but the truth is is that we actually
haven't done those type of studies yet
to be able to say that conclusively and
and legally in most countries you can't
do that kind of study
um for example in Canada the the
licensed producers here
they need a special license to consume
the Cannabis that they're producing on
site right if they want to if a grower
wants to smoke his own weed and they
don't have that license they have to
sell it to the liquor distribution board
and it goes out to the distributor to
the the retailer and then they have to
go and buy their cannabis retail before
they can even try it that's kind of
bizarre right like imagine you're you're
a winter or a master Brewer and you
couldn't taste your wine or your beard
during the production process it's kind
of it's kind of insane but that's what
we've ended up with in the regulatory
system so
um
being in this legal system has really
forced people to start saying okay we
can't smoke the plants so what we're
going to do is send them all to a
laboratory and then pick the one with
the highest THC well imagine you did
that for whiskey or wine right you don't
go into the wine store and say okay I
need a I need a nice raw with the
highest alcohol content it's just not
the way that we consume those products
and so it's kind of weird that that has
been the way that we're now marketing
and advertising cannabis
yeah wow what a phenomenal explanation
right there you raise such a brilliant
analogy in regards to you know like the
high alcohol content and something which
has been brought up in Prior episodes is
this idea of should cannabis be treated
just like tomatoes should it be treated
like alcohol I guess it is a bit of a
sort of complex question where do you
sit on that one what do you think should
be the general regulatory framework
around cannabis or does it need its own
new one
I think we have to take pieces of all
the different regulatory systems I'm of
the opinion that cannabis is a drug
right it's a psychoactive substance and
that doesn't mean that it's dangerous
but it does mean that we don't want to
be you know I I was I was in high school
and I was smoking cannabis but I think
if I was designing a regulatory system
as an adult that I would probably say
yeah like kids under
well I don't really want to set the age
because it would probably be younger
than most but um I think that there's
probably enough scientific
data to say hey yeah we actually we
shouldn't provide high THC cannabis to
um to kids under 18. and you know
not that I necessarily agree with that
as a personal ethic but I because I
don't believe that it's that as
dangerous as it's made to seem
um but part of using psychoactive
substances in any culture is a a taught
experience right that's
cultural information that's passed down
from the elders to the younger
generation and I think that you know
people need to be of a certain age to
really appreciate
how to truly start using these
substances properly
um you know when I was like 13 and 14
and sitting around the table at
Christmas dinner you know the kids in my
family my brother and I we were allowed
to have a very small glass of wine
um you know all the parents were having
it and this is kind of one of those
things as kids it's like why don't we
why don't we get to have a little taste
too and I don't think there's anything
dangerous of letting
um children have or not let's not say
children but young teens have a small
taste of wine in the context of a family
celebration
um at the dinner table do I want that
child then going and taking a bottle of
wine and hanging out with his friends
probably not right even though you know
obviously Most teens do that they try to
get beer or alcohol for the weekend
I think again as an adult if I were
designing a system for that I probably
wouldn't
create a situation where it was easy for
them to get access
right yeah look I wholeheartedly agree
with you and nothing new here being said
but the the study is pretty conclusively
show that a lot of European countries
that follow the sort of style of
introducing small amounts of alcohol in
family settings like it's shown to be
beneficial because you're kind of
normalizing it right
yeah well you can't I mean if you want
young adults to make responsible choices
you have to respect them and treat them
as intelligent enough to make their own
choice right and part of that is giving
them the tools so that when they do
encounter these substances on their own
later in life that they know how to
interact with them and you know
reasonably and that's kind of what I
think where my mom's
um
you know her idea was was behind letting
us have small things about it is again
it's cultural knowledge it's part of
teaching people how to interact with
these substances substances in a
responsible way
um and I think this is don't you know
this just say no all drugs are bad
approach I mean it obviously doesn't
work
um and I think it sets up children for
to believe you know because again you
hear drugs are bad drugs are bad don't
touch cannabis it's bad too and then
when people try cannabis they realize
that it's not what
the elders told them it was right and
then now you've created a situation
where the younger generation doesn't
trust the people that are trying to
teach them life lessons on how to
you know how to go about interacting
with these substances through life so my
personal opinion is to just be
responsible and educated and arm the the
kids with as much information so that
they can then go on and make responsible
choices right
Yeah a hundred percent I am one of the
biggest Advocates you'll find of like
harm reduction and I think that it's
totally in line with that sort of
philosophy
a question which kind of stems off that
a little bit which I have been pondering
myself especially since picking up the
Vape as my preferred ingestion method is
that I do wonder if as you reference you
know a lot of the younger generation
they they might have started out on dabs
and I feel like the question needs to be
asked if that sort of excessive
saturation of the THC receptors could
have some deleterious effect just in
terms of maybe even just your own
ability to enjoy the plan I know that at
periods of time when I've been smoking
particularly heavy you can kind of
notice like you're not getting as high
what's your thoughts on that do you
think that like some amount of
self-restraint actually could lead to a
more long-term enjoyment of the plant
and the concentrates in general
yeah absolutely and we you know we know
this with opioid receptors and it's it's
showing true as well with cannabinoid
receptors is that when you drive one of
these neurochemical systems with an
excess of the ligand or the molecule
that is binding to these receptors that
The receptors do something called they
go undergo a process called down
regulation where they actually become
fewer receptors and that's kind of like
a way to balance for you know your they
the cells want to maintain that level of
signal that is being passed from the the
post-synaptic presynaptic nerve to the
postsynaptic nerve where the receptor is
located right so essentially we have a
natural or endogenous signal
you know you can assign it any kind of
value you want call it a hundred that
goes from the presynaptic nerve to the
postsynaptic nerve terminal and when we
when that you know your body has a
natural level of endogenous opioids that
exists and work in that system and so
when we smoke cannabis what we're doing
is we're driving that system harder
we're we're putting in a molecule that
mimics the endogenous ligand and that
essentially overdrives the system so
we're now we're giving the The receptors
a much greater signal than they're used
to and so for them to compensate what
they do is they they down regulate the
number of receptors and it kind of
brings the the nut the amount of signal
going from the previous nerve to the
post nerve down into the similar type of
line
and when we when we then pull away
that exogenous signal we stop smoking
cannabis your body is now compensated so
you're actually now getting too little
signal and that's a case of
um you know that's what we call
withdrawal really right
um
so yeah I think that it's probably it's
probably it's you know in terms of using
cannabis and being a cannabis user
tolerance breaks are really good for you
um people obviously need these compounds
for using for medicine but I don't think
any of these you know I'm going to call
them quote sacred plants
um
or medicinal plants I don't think it's a
great idea to be using them all the time
right there's there's something to be
said for taking breaks and having
moments of clarity and you know if you
do that you take a couple of weeks off
of consuming cannabis you will find just
like you said that when you go back to
it the same amount that you were using
two weeks ago has a much greater effect
um so that's one thing on that topic
another thing that's kind of interesting
on the topic
that I don't think any
um any markets have really truly
embraced yet is the type 2 cannabis so
cannabis that has a balance of CBD and
THC of you know most people know the the
variety catatonic from from resin seeds
in Spain
um and that's that's a type 2 plant and
the thing that makes type 2 plants
you know different from the high THC
plants is that they produce about 50 of
their
um total cannabinoid fraction as CBD
rather than THC and there's just the
beginnings of uh scientific research
that are being done in kind of the
Neuroscience community in the Health
Community that show that having that
little bit of a CBD buffer in your
experience
actually might provide some
um some safety against the things that
you were talking about you know
over over driving your system with
massive amounts of dabs all the time
right
um so there might even be a safety
aspect too to having CBD in in the
context again of what we were talking
about before with children or kids under
you know maybe the solution is to have
them only have access to type 2 cannabis
right they don't get access to have
access of the really truly potent stuff
until they turn 18 or 20.
um I don't know how you would go about
enforcing that but it's you know it's
something to consider I think that that
whole area of the CBD buffer is
something that um
really hasn't been explored very much by
the community and I think it has a
potential for use
yeah of course of course and I think a
topic in general which we're kind of
skirting around slash touching on a
little bit is something which a lot of
people really don't want to acknowledge
is that there can be like sort of
downsides or excessive use of cannabis
and I think a lot of people are really
just so invested in this idea of
cannabis is 100 safe it's non-harm for
you and I always have a bit of a problem
with that because it's like there's many
cases of like people smoking cannabis
and then unfortunately running in front
of a car like not on purpose but like I
just find it hard to stomach when people
just raise it like there's no possible
downsides to her kids I I started
smoking 12 years old it should be fine
and as you've said like it is worth
considering if that's actually a
realistically true statement because
you're a kind of experience as a child
doesn't represent everyone's and it's it
is worth considering what's best for a
12 year old a 15 year old or an 18 year
old so yeah I really like that sentiment
you'd Express right there yeah well and
just like there's different types of
cannabis I think people need to be aware
that you know human are are individual
neurochemical makeup is different from
person to person
um and so it's not only necessarily
about the chemistry of the plant there's
variability in the chemical in the
neurochemistry of the population and we
really don't know
um you know I have a lot of friends and
they're just like cannabis isn't for me
or I had friends that were in you know I
was in high school with and I used to
smoke with them and then they got a
little bit older and they they tell me
you know I just I just realized it
wasn't good for me it wasn't making me
feel healthy mentally stable I I knew
another lovely little not a lovely
little girl but a lovely girl and she
was in her early 30s and when I met her
she was smoking Fair bit of cannabis and
she got right into it and I watched her
go through a mental spiral like I've
never seen on anyone and you know to the
point that she thought that there was
people in the in in the light switches
in the you know the electrical outlets
and then you know she was putting like
tin foil on top of light fixtures and
stuff it was really bizarre behavior but
she definitely wasn't using any other
drug
and the canvas wasn't helping her
so
um to have this and I actually
substituted her cannabis I took all our
cannabis away from her gave her a bunch
of CBD cannabis that had no THC in it
and um
it seemed to help a little bit but at
that point in time I think again she had
she had overdriven her endocannabinoid
system so hard that just with her
particular neurochemistry it didn't work
for her
um so anybody that says you know all
cannabis is medicine and you know it's
no matter how you use it it's medical
that to me is just not true
um because I've seen it right I've seen
it happen and it's well documented in
the scientific literature in the medical
literature
um that there is a small subset of
people and we don't know whether it's
their genetics or their Euro
neurochemistry but whatever it is
cannabis doesn't interact well with them
and
um when you're looking at creating a
regulated market or a system as a
government official you have to be
thinking about
the lowest common denominator right you
have to make your safety barriers safe
for everybody not just the top 90
percent right it's not okay just if 10
people suffer from using the product so
um
yeah being aware of the different types
of cannabis I think is important
but also this idea that all cannabis use
is harmless is probably not I don't
think that's a really responsible way to
think about it you know
so just to jump back to the concentrates
topic we were discussing a moment ago
something which has always been an
interest to me is that someone I can't
remember who it was unfortunately but
they pointed out to me that a lot of the
technology and especially the techniques
used in extraction processing these days
are actually very old school technology
like there's patterns going back to the
1920s and 30s which outline a lot of the
methods currently being used and sort of
presented as like The Cutting Edge I
figured you'd be better to ask than
anyone have you seen any genuine new
advances in extraction or do you feel
like it's true to what I said where it
is all kind of rehashed old technology
yeah I mean all the old you know we've
had a lot of really great Chemists in
the world phytochemists in the world for
150 years at least
um and it's kind of one of those those
stories where there's nothing new Under
the Sun right
um maybe people are modifying old
techniques but yeah this is all like you
know even distillation for THC or you
know fractional distillation or for
example the the butane extracts
um those type of of alkane carbohydrate
or uh
those those alkane extractions they all
really have their roots in other
Industries and maybe people are changing
things a little bit temperature all that
kind of stuff
to optimize it but I think for the most
part it's not most of it's not that new
um it's just new to cannabis because
cannabis is because of prohibition it's
been left out of so many different
systems a lot of people just couldn't
touch the plant
right you know 30 years ago you had to
be pretty rebellious to actually be
braving the penalties
um
and it just it kept a lot of people that
can teach the Cannabis community
different techniques or sets of
knowledge
it just kept them away
um so at least in Canada
now we're starting to integrate all that
you know we're able to collaborate with
people and in existing Industries
and tap into all that that knowledge
base that they have right because again
cannabis is just another plant
um it's a different plant but you know
we can use all the same kind of science
that we use on all the other plants in
the world
Yeah a hundred percent and I mean in
line with that idea I think I was
reading an article written by a CBD
extractor who was trying to figure out
why they were getting such high Returns
on their CBD extractions and what they
hypothesized was that some of the
terpenes you find in CBD cultivars the
type 2 cultivars may actually be acting
as kind of like almost an industrial
solvent in the process and helping to
extract more things through that solvent
being present have you heard anything
about this and if that were to be true
do you think that might indicate that
breeding for certain terpene
predominance could be like a good idea
if your main goal is extraction
um
I don't know if they would Aid in
extraction you can definitely optimize
cultivars through breeding for
extraction
um that was one of the things that we
did when I was down in California is we
were we were not only looking at the
terpene profiles of plants but actually
measuring their overall terpene output
we were kind of one of the first groups
to do that
and
um you know we were finding plants you
typically we had a we called the you
know our friends at SC Labs called it
the swag flag but we typically
would eliminate any plant that was under
one percent total terpene content if it
didn't have
um you know
10 milligrams of terpenes per gram that
was out it just didn't make the list
unless it had some other characteristic
that was so unique about the plant you
know for example we came across a thcv
plant that we kept
um because that's a really rare
cannabinoid but the terpene profile on
the plant sucked it was horrible it's
not like hemp and it just wasn't it
wasn't oily it was just not really tasty
to consume and
um so that became one of our lower
limits and we through time we would
raise that number
um you know one and a half two percent
for of tripping content and anything
below that we wouldn't keep because the
idea was to be making these plants
produce as much not only the right
complement of terpene the right set of
terpenes but also we wanted to have them
produce more terpenes
right and there's definitely a whole lot
of world there where we can be take you
know because it might be for example
we're talking about making dabs and you
want to have a full I'm going to call I
hate the word but I'm going to use it
anyway these full terpene extract
plants you know you might want to have
end up with a dab or with a you know
your concentrate that is
really high in terpenes but say it only
has 40 total cannabinoids right as
opposed to a lot of terpenes and 80
total cannabinoids and I I'm sure most
of the community is probably listening
to me say those things right now and
thinking well that's not what I want
um
but again getting back to this
discussion where we were talking about
how things make you feel
um there definitely is going to be a
whole subset of the population that for
them you know they're not they don't
want to drink whiskey they want to drink
wine right they want to they want to
Vape on a pen all night not have one
puff and become a toast
and this is something that I hear from a
lot of you know the older hippies that
I'm in touch with in the community
because you know it's kind of it's it's
kind of funny when you say it that way
but it's like you know it's like oh you
kids today your music is too loud it's
like are you kids today your weed is
just too strong but it's true for them
right you know I bring over an OG Kush
to a party at like uh you know a family
or so older family member's house and
pass it around the campfire and they're
out right they're staring at the wall
for the next three hours
and they don't just they don't want that
right why would you want that that's not
fun right I mean for you know for every
occasional kind of thing but that's just
to them that's not what cannabis was
right cannabis was something that they
could sit around the campfire and smoke
all night and enjoy the flavor of their
of their Dube right
um so there's something to be said about
about breeding plants that have lots of
flavor and they don't punch you in the
face when you smoke them
right
um it may not be for you it may not be
for everybody but I think that we have
to start thinking about making cannabis
more accessible to other people and how
can we do that right what are the things
we need to do that is it using these
type 2 varieties with a little bit of
CBD in them you know maybe even even in
in Switzerland you know I don't know if
you've heard about uh the CBD markets
they're now selling CBD cigarettes and
grocery stores in Switzerland
and um their type 3 plants which have
you know lots of CBD and almost no THC
in them they're they're effectively hemp
but if you can make hemp taste like an
OG kush or you can make it taste like a
really flavorful Haze or something
really nice that's it's nice for people
to consume
again it might not be what most of the
people listening to this podcast want
but if we can create a whole nother
segment
of the population that are embracing
cannabis and benefiting from cannabis
um
I think that that's great and they don't
need to be high you know it's it's I
think it's just great that we can have
more people having a relationship with
this fantastic plant
yeah I wholeheartedly agree and I think
it is one of those things where when you
are an everyday smoker just puffing away
on your OG cush it does seem like a very
foreign idea and I am a little bit
guilty of falling into that trap you
mentioned of you know old people wanting
the the less strong weed and just kind
of being a bit perplexed at the idea but
nowadays I find myself in that same
position and I've got this newfound
appreciation for the orange strains
which maybe classically aren't
considered as strong but boy is the
flavor nice
yeah yeah and the truth is we can bring
breed those things to to be high THC we
can breed them to be a mixed ratio of
CBT to THC and we can also breed those
same flavors to be in the CBD plants
right that's just a matter of of making
the right crosses and selections and um
I I one of the things I love about
cannabis is the diversity that it brings
as a plant
and you know who am I to say now only
these ones are the ones we're going to
use I I kind of see my job as a breeder
is to make all the different types
available and then the doctors and the
Stoners and the and you know everybody's
going to figure out what works for them
the patients
but at least they have the opportunity
to do that when we can provide this
broad selection of chemotypes
um
you know not everybody needs the THC
stuff that's great if you like the THC
stuff I like the THC stuff I mean that's
kind of where that's kind of my go-to
I'm not saying don't use high THC
cannabis but I'm just saying if if we
can have more people have a relationship
with cannabis because we make them tasty
tasty cultivars of high CBD low THC you
know flower that's to me that's a win
yeah no I I wholeheartedly agree so uh
just to jump back to kind of some
terpene talk for just a moment I'd love
to hear your thoughts on whether you
feel that it's becoming a more common
Trend that people are adding terpenes
either to concentrates maybe even trying
to infuse flour that is maybe a bit less
than ideal in its terpene content with
external turpins do you feel like this
is deleterious advantageous and do you
feel like there's any benefit because
there's a lot of discussion around oh
it's non-cannabis derived terpenes and
that's inferior to cannabis derived
terpenes but the the inner chemist in me
thinks mess ends missing man like you
know what's your thoughts
yeah same I will just bring it back to
water I mean you can make you know you
can make water in a lab by combining
hydrogen and oxygen or you can take
um sewer water and distill out pure
water right which one would you rather
drink
the truth is if you purify them both
they're both just water right it's the
same thing no matter what the source is
so to me water is water is water it's
what's what's it contaminated with and
that's the question there's two
questions a is it contaminated okay so
we're getting miracine from a different
plant that's fine are we co-extracting
anything else with the mirror scene
you know so what are the contaminants in
that that bottle of miracine that you're
buying to dump on your flour or add to
your concentrates that's the question
um so what's the contaminant what's the
levels of those contaminants and what's
the health consequences of those
contaminants
um because plants make compounds that
are poisonous to humans it's right
that's what they do they try to defend
themselves from us
um and from you know any any plant
that's a herbivorous
um someone that's a test you know plant
or an animal that's attacking a plant so
these defense compounds can actually be
bad for you so maybe we're going into
some you know call it some weird
lemongrass or something like that to try
and find some terpenes to put into our
cannabis
it get the the potential is there that
if their work
um a secondary metabolite produced by
the plant that was poisonous to humans
that we co-extracted and now that's in
with the mirror scene right and then
that mirror scene enters the or that met
that contaminated mirror scene enters
the supply chain well that could be a
problem
the other thing that could be a problem
is when we when we consume cannabis
there's natural physiological levels of
these chemicals that the plant can
produce
and
the last 30 40 Years of science seems to
show that there's no deleterious effect
on human health by using those but it
could be if we start making you know it
might you know
a lot of these these limonene
terpenolene pinene a lot of these
terpenes as you were saying earlier
they're solvents right they they can
dissolve cannabinoids but they can
actually also dissolve like certain
types of plastic or rubber you know
Sam's Skunk Man was telling me a story
but they had this Haze plant that they
used to harvest in California I believe
it was
and if they had these rubber rings that
sat on the top of the jars when they
would close off and the rubber would
seal in the jar but if you lit you left
the them in there for three or four
months the Terps would actually dissolve
away the the rubber
um so there's a potential issue with all
these Plastics that we're using to you
know to hold cannabis especially the
cheaper stuff and again in a
non-regulated market nobody's paying
attention to these things
um and they could have potential Health
consequences for example if you if
you're making high terp dabs and you're
putting them in these plastic containers
you can actually see sometimes when you
when you clean out the container that
the plastic has started to melt and did
that did that plastic then melt into the
dabs right are you now consuming these
things so there's a lot of health issues
um that I think we have to really keep
at the Forefront of our planning as we
go about creating regulated markets all
over the world
um and it doesn't mean that we shouldn't
do it but it just means that we should
have some kind of thought and really
careful due diligence before just doing
whatever we want as if you know as if
the way that we have done things in the
black market have have been the right
way to do things right we've done them
out of necessity
typically for the past 50 years but it
we might learn and we are learning with
some of the chemicals that we spray on
the plant that these things stick around
right the the story used to be all you
have your veg if you're in veg don't
worry buddy you can spray on the plant
that's not going to end up in the flower
but [__] we started doing the testing
and it's like you know what it all ends
up in the flower
right so a lot of the practices that
we've had in Black markets
um they're not going to be the practices
that we use in regulated markets and
that's okay right it's all about
advancing our understanding and creating
a safe industry where people can use
cannabis in as you know like you said
from a harm reduction point of view it's
as safe as it's safe as it can be
yeah yep words of wisdom right there and
I think you know you touch on a
brilliant point that we've come a long
way since the days of mycobutanal and uh
butane soup but I guess a topic which
stems from that and what you just
discussed is there's a lot of current
discussion and maybe even a bit of
necessary discussion around vape pens
particularly the ones that come from say
China or other areas of the world where
the the manufacturing standards are
maybe a little less than what they are
in other Western countries do you think
that because of this issue and the
necessity for there to be high quality
assurance of quality that basically we
will see the falling off of that or do
you think that you know China and maybe
even African produced products will
eventually creep into the market over
time and become the new dominant Force
at Play
with I think China is the dominant Force
at play in all the Vape technology that
we have at least in North America most
of that stuff's not produced and I think
I actually don't know any of it that's
actually produced in North America
um it all comes from China and you know
I've I've got friends and relationships
with people in some of these large
Canadian multi-billion dollar companies
and I know you know through speaking
with them about
um the issues that they've had in doing
the due diligence I mean if you're gonna
if you're a big massive company and
you're going to put vape pens onto the
market you know we've got call it 35
million people here in Canada it's a
little more but call out a market of you
know call it five to ten million users
that's a lot of that's a lot of Hardware
that you need to ensure that you're not
going to run out that you have a supply
and being able to do the due diligence
on the safety of those products coming
from China I mean you know if you're
ordering 500 000 vape pens or a million
vape pens you're buying from one company
and then they're like they're like we
can't actually produce those all
ourselves and they go and they Outsource
them to another company
right so you have to be doing all this
batch testing because again if you're
putting a product onto the market it's
your ass right it's your responsibility
to make sure that it's safe if it comes
back and it's not safe it's your
shareholders that are going to suffer
not China
um so they have to do these really deep
dives into the you know Upstream to the
manufacturers they go over there they
check their metals they check the
solders that they're putting
that they're using to fuse the parts
together to wire the you know the pens
and everything so you really
again all these things cannabis has been
left out of all these systems for so
long because it's a black market and
people could just do whatever they want
and you know I remember being
you know in my younger years and it's
like if you couldn't score and finally
you you got something you were stoked
right just because you got something you
were able to you're able to
to find your wheat I wasn't a Beer
Drinker or anything so when I was in
high school and University I didn't
really consume alcohol
um
cannabis was my thing and so if I ever
didn't have cannabis and you had to go
and buy you know you're on the street
looking for something and it was just
supply and demand it was what was
available
um and if you could find something then
you were satisfied but that's probably
not a very good you know way to go about
doing things right like if you're if
you're looking for steak you're not just
going to pick up any old meat that's
lying on the on the supermarket floor or
on the road right you want to be buying
high quality products where you know
where they come from and you know that
they've been made with respect
and treated with respect and the plants
have not been sprayed with pesticides
right you don't want to consume all that
kind of stuff it's just not good for you
and inevitably in a black market
you do see a ton of that I mean in
California we did some studies and vast
vast amounts of the the Cannabis that's
on the market is like you said it's got
microbutanil in it or it's got mold on
it or it's got a bacteria growing on it
um
and that's not all right you know in in
the legal food production systems when
there's you know we had one couple weeks
ago the onions were coming up from the
states red onions and they had uh
salmonella on them
so a legal Market we have recall systems
to recall all that product and make sure
that it doesn't get into the hands of
people and when it does get into the
hands of people it's on the news so
everybody knows hey don't eat your
onions right take them off the menu
um because people are going to get sick
and black market cannabis systems don't
have those safeguards
um
and we need them right
a lot of Growers are you know they get
week five
week four even all of a sudden they get
a big spider mite
um infestation that's going to kill the
crop
and they got two choices you kill the
crop and start again
or you spray it with someone God the
chemical
and cross your fingers and that way you
can pay your mortgage unfortunately
you know paying the mortgage is it's one
of the major excuses for for many many
evils in the world today
people are just doing it because they're
trying to get by and so you can
understand why it happens there's not a
lot of Honor in putting those products
in the market but again when people are
desperate for money or just paying the
bill or they're just trying to get by or
feed their families they often make
choices that aren't in the best
interests of the people that are going
to be consuming their plants and really
and again in Black Market systems they
don't know the people that are consuming
their weed they sell it to a guy and it
gets shipped or it gets you know sold to
a bunch of people they don't know and so
there are a certain amount of people
that will they'll just spray it and and
not care about the consequences
Downstream
so regulated systems there they there
are a lot of good things about them it's
a pain in the ass to work in them but
it's kind of the right thing to do
yeah of course and I think that a lot of
the frustration that comes from the
Growers and in engaging in these systems
is an idea you touched on earlier in
that because historically they've never
had to really pay attention to Quality
Control quality assurance it now seems
like this big Boogeyman when in reality
it's a part of every established
industry in the world and I think that
if we do want to end up being like a
wine industry or some sort of terroir
based industry then there has to be a
certain acceptance that these are just
the necessary scaffolds that need to be
put in place
yeah and it's about pride in your
product
right
um I know there's people that just make
products because they just want to sell
them make some money and but those
aren't the products that I want to
consume right I like products that are
made by Artisans or that are you know
grown by a farmer with pride for as for
what he's making
um
same with wine you know
but same with vegetables too I mean and
and meats it's the same thing when
people they understand the art and the
science of their you know their chosen
field they take pride in the work that
they're doing
and I don't know how you could be proud
of putting
cannabis on the market that you knew had
a pesticide or a fungicide sprayed on it
yeah of course so on to a little bit of
a somewhat controversial topic but it's
one I do feel really personally invested
in tobacco and cannabis given we've
discussed how we should be doing
everything we can to kind of minimize
the potential harmful compounds that are
within cannabis pesticides heavy metals
from Vape carts do you feel like there
should be somewhat of an active effort
to discourage the use of tobacco in
conjunction with cannabis like what we
see around General tobacco use or do you
think it's just an each to their own
sort of thing no I I think that we
should actively tell people not to put
back when they're cannabis it's insane I
mean tobacco is a bronchial constrictor
right if you smoke tobacco your lungs
close on you automatically when you
smoke cannabis your lungs open up it's a
bronchodilator and so when you mix the
two the healthcare the health minister
in Canada I think it was like about 20
years ago it might even been 25 years
ago I remember her coming out and saying
we're really not too too concerned about
people consuming cannabis what we're
concerned about is the mixing the two
together because again the Cannabis
opens up your lungs and it allows all
those really bad things that are put on
into tobacco and that just that those
chemicals that a result of of
tobacco combustion
we don't need to be breathing that in it
doesn't add to the experience
um
and it's again it's a cultural thing
it's you know I think it's it ties back
to the use of tobacco and hookahs
um it became the norm in in Spain before
the Cannabis culture really got going in
Spain kind of in the late 90s early
2000s it was a hash consuming country
and so that they would get hash in
Morocco and they'd mix it with tobacco
and they'd smoke it that way and that
became the norm same with Italy
both countries are really quite
accepting of tobacco it's just a
cultural norm
and even in Holland right like I don't
know if you've ever been to Amsterdam
but if you go to a coffee shop in
Amsterdam you'll see a Dutch guy come in
from the end of his work day and he'll
sit down and ask for
um a half gram or a gram of hash from
the dealer and they'll take out a full
cigarette and a one of these long jumbo
sized papers and they break the entire
cigarette out and they might take you
know
a tenth of a gram or two tenths of a
gram and break up the hash into that and
then they roll that in their entire
cigarette and smoke the whole thing to
themself
well that's to me I mean I
the taste of that alone would be enough
for me to say just don't do it but from
a health perspective
I think that it it really makes the
worst things about the tobacco more
harmful right so from a harm reduction
perspective
don't smoke tobacco with your cannabis
from a taste perspective
Jesus please don't smoke
cannabis right and I listen I grew up in
Ottawa um which is very close to
Montreal which is a port city kind of on
the Eastern side of of Canada and so we
would have a lot of hashish that would
come in through the Montreal Port you
know being like two or two and a half
hours away that was the predominant form
of cannabis that was available when I
was younger and it wasn't until I was a
little bit older that we started seeing
some cannabis flowers
um back then whether it was the police
or the genetics that were available to
be grown outside or the availability you
know the lack of supply all these things
together
created a situation where we just didn't
have cannabis flowers it was we were
hashmokers and
I lived right on the border of Quebec
which is the French speak uh speaking
part of of Canada and they have a lot of
ties back to France of course culturally
and again in France you know it's in
between Spain and
and Italy
that's you know they're they're also
hashmuckers and and great tobacco
smokers it's just it's part of the
culture
um
so I believe as our you know I came to a
point where I was like I'm gonna try
stop not smoking with tobacco I was
buying cigarettes just to have tobacco
to be to mix in with my joints
um
and you know I got to the point where I
was like forget this I'm just going to
start smoking with cannabis and I
remember I was in a music man at the
time and some of my friends that were in
the band they were like oh we can't you
know it's too harsh it's when you smoke
it without it's too harsh and it feels
that way for about the first two weeks
but after you get accustomed to smoking
without cannabis you actually change the
way that you smoke you draw the air
differently in
um I think you rather than taking these
long draws on the joint you take smaller
draws with larger breaths of air at the
same time so you're kind of titrating
down the smoke
and uh you get to the point where where
you just it tastes so much better you
wouldn't go back if you had to
and when someone passes you a joint like
if I'm you know if I'm out at a party
Sam on the east side of Canada again
smoking with tobacco is a lot more
prominent than it is on the west coast
and so if you're at a party someone
passes you a joint you have a taste of
it you get you know you get it halfway
down your throat and your lungs
immediately slam shut
um because they just don't want that
tobacco smoke in there
um so I I'm really against it I'm really
against tobacco as a whole I don't I
think it's I've seen the damage it does
to people
um and I just don't think it's a good
thing to be consuming if you don't have
to and you certainly don't need to be
consuming with cannabis and it's kind of
like putting orange juice in a fine wine
you know
yeah well so many things you just said
which are just so heavily relate to you
know I think I just agree with
everything you said and as someone who's
never smoked a cigarette in my life but
at one point was addicted to Tobacco
purely through smoking it with weed I
think that I can agree with you that
that after you get through that first
two weeks you're like wow this is such a
better world to be in but I'd love to
just quickly jump back to something you
touched on because we did have uh one of
the friends of the show direwolf submit
a question which relates perfectly to
the hash sort of comment you made and he
was wondering what's your thoughts on
the old school Moroccan imported hash
did you love it did you hate it where do
you stand
what it's kind of like everything in the
Cannabis world I mean I love it for what
it is I've been to Morocco a couple of
times now
um I've traveled there a little bit on
my own and I actually went with Rob
Clark and we had a little trip and went
and saw some Growers that we need down
there
and really got to see all about the
culture
it
it's a great thing to see
I think from um
you know when I went the last time I had
already been working in these regulated
models so when I started going back and
seeing the way that things were done on
such a massive scale
there's a lot of gross things that are
you know there's no real high just no
real sense of hygiene in the process
or in the cultivation it's just not
really thought of and and we've seen
through some of the studies that have
been done even in like Dutch coffee
shops that
you know for example like if you're
trimming your weed and someone goes off
the washroom doesn't wash their hands
after they use the washroom you can get
like E coli on the flowers right
and that's pretty gross
um
and it's not it's it's completely
avoidable right this is the other thing
um and so these systems they don't they
don't they don't have any of these
safety protocols they don't have
standard operating procedures they don't
have
protocols for maintaining the quality of
the flower from a consumer safety
perspective
um
the other thing about it is it's the
market has changed so even even when the
first time I went which is I think it
was 2011. it might even have been a
little before then but around that time
it was they were going through a
transition where
the Moroccans had started adopting
um Advanced agricultural techniques so
for example they were growing feminized
seeds from Holland
but rather than just scatter C I mean
the way they used to do it they'd
Harvest all the seeds at the end of the
year when you when you're harvesting
Acres of cannabis it's seeded like
Moroccan is
you separate the the the resins from the
plant right through screening or this
this batter beading technique which I
don't know if you've seen online but you
know people can Google it and you can
look on YouTube they essentially put in
the bag and then they beat this the bag
with sticks and the sticks knock the
resin glands off the flower and then
they collect the resin glands so there's
no real there's no real safety
consideration in doing that it's just
kind of done right because for them
they all know that it's Black Market but
the truth is if you're up in Morocco up
in the in the rift mountains
and you have land like you're paying for
your house and your way of life and
everything
by with cannabis I mean if you go up
there and you drive around you'll see
driving through the riff
the biggest houses they're all
surrounded by cannabis fields
right and so this is what the point was
is that they're they're bringing in
these feminized seeds and now they lay
drip emitters down
and they plant the feminized seeds on
drip lines whereas what they used to do
is Harvest all the seeds after they'd
beat the resin glands off the hash
they'd collect the seeds and then the
next year they would actually just walk
around the property with bags of seeds
and Scatter seed them by just tossing
out handfuls of seed
um so you get a lot of it's kind of
grown a little bit more like hemp than
they do drug cannabis you get a lot more
plants per square foot
um they grow very tall and thin
um with top colas and not a lot of side
branching and that was kind of the
traditional method of of production for
farmers in Morocco
now if you go down
and you go up into the Riff you'll see
they've got these like you know they've
dug into the side of these mountains
like pretty much Olympic swimming pool
sized pools to hold the water
um so when it rains in the winter they
collect all that water and they line
them with with big Plastics a big
plastic or rubber mats
and that holds all the water in so they
have these huge reservoirs from which to
feed their plants and they take that
water and they pump it out and they
inject chemical nutrients from
a lot of it comes from Holland but you
know it's that it's that same kind of
chemical fertilizers that everybody else
in the blue crystals kind of thing
um
because the the places that they're
growing in Morocco it's not even really
soil it's more rock and dust than any
kind of organic material in the soil
and so they really just turn it into a
massive hydropanic hydroponic bed right
with the drippers providing all the
nutrients that the plant needs
um and again growing feminized seeds by
the 10 20 30 acre plot
um
so not a lot of love given to the plants
it's all about bulk
um
they don't understand the concept of you
know you know Howard Parks funnily
enough went through the same thing in
Morocco when when he was there he was
asking for you know I don't want as much
hash I just want better quality and they
just didn't understand that it was like
we'll just we'll just make more right
and it's like no we don't want more we
actually want less of the stuff that we
don't want in there
um
so do I think that those things will be
available as they are in the New Market
no they won't
right because it's probably not it's
probably not the best way of doing
anything doing things can you take those
production practices and make them
um applicable or safe to do in a
regulated market absolutely you can make
products like the Moroccan hashes
um and some people will love those
things
but again just transferring over the way
that it's always been done into the
regulated market I just don't see it
happening
along with what you just mentioned is
what's your opinion on people going to
these sort of land race or indigenous
areas and trading modern feminized
genetics for the cultivars like notably
Strain Hunters and RN have done that a
lot and they cop a lot of flack for it
do you think that's deserved or do you
think it's not as harmful as people
might make out well I think there's two
things to realize like for example
Morocco cannabis wasn't grown in Morocco
until like 1300 years ago so they were
brought those populations were brought
there really what they were growing even
until a couple of hundred years ago I
remember 150 years ago maybe it wasn't
even that long it could have been less
they were it was actually really a hemp
variety right it wasn't they weren't
really potent cannabis and that's why
they made it into hashish because it
concentrated it enough that you'd get
high
but the Moroccans that's not how that
they would consume their cannabis and to
this day they still don't consume the
resin glands they mix flower tops with
little bits of tobacco and that's how
they smoke it it's not it's not used the
way we smoke it to consume the same
concentration of the drug they they kind
of again like maybe like DJ's ways that
they were they were
they were using a less amount of the
drug than just to get a slight effect
and that was the that was the really the
purpose for them
truthfully the DEA has gone around the
world I mean they've spent the last you
know maybe not the last 20 years but
that's certainly the 20 years before
that
going around the world and paying the
Thai government and paying the Indian
government and paying the
afghanistani government to go out and
conduct anti-cannabis
um
raids right go out go out and have these
programs to go out and cut the fields
down in fact at one point in time it was
the UN
the the U.N office of drug control it
was their policy to actually make
cannabis extinct like that was one of
the un's world goals was to make
cannabis extinct
right that's insane like imagine the
un's
having one of their mandates to make a
species go and say it's extinct it's
just bizarre
um
but it was all ideologically driven
right so
I think the truth is is that most of the
Cannabis that's been grown and those
land what people call land race
populations and the cultures that grew
those land races for example the Thai
culture that grew the the really Fine
Thai sticks that's gone like those
things just don't really exist anymore
they might have like little dots of them
around the country in very small spots
but it's not a cultural phenomenon like
it used to be it's not a way of life
and so the lessons that they had to
teach the cultural practices they had to
teach those ways are probably gone the
genetics at least the diversity is
mostly gone
um and from a farming point of view I
mean if you're a farmer in Thailand or
India or the Congo you know you're
talking about The Strain Hunters
if you're a farmer in those places
you want the best
product that you're going to grow like
if somebody has a a variety of corn that
yields 10 times as much
and that means that you can have 10
times as much
you know profit or return from your crop
or 10 times this much food to feed your
family you're gonna do it
right because these folks probably don't
understand the
the
intricacies of
protecting the global diversity of
cannabis
um and that's kind of the way we are in
most of these species with most species
now is that these centers of origin as
we call them or centers of diversity
of most crop species are gone or they're
threatened all around all around the
world just because of human activity and
so at this point in time we really rely
on
what we call ex-sit you or or you know
collections that are taken and capped
out of the place where they were
produced because
the environment's changing and these
these ecosystems are threatened and
that's what we do we have at the point
unfortunately the point that we have to
do that now
is that we just have to collect these
things as they are and try to preserve
the diversity and I think that if we're
trying to you know blame Ariane or blame
anybody for going and polluting
polluting these germplasm these genetic
pools the truth is those genetic pools
are mostly depleted anyway
um and those Farmers have ju have you
know I think it's kind of hard to argue
that those Farmers don't have
every right that all the local Canada
you know all our domestic cannabis
Growers to to to to produce the newest
most commercially viable plants that's
what that's what Farmers want to do they
want to stay competitive right
yeah and I I think that you know when if
you if you look at it on a human level
you can totally relate to the point you
made about you know people are trying to
feed their families you know it's not
it's not all this like Grand oversight
driven sort of actions taking place an
idea that one of our past guests errors
and brought up and he's a lovely guy
from India who's done some land race
Expeditions and preservation efforts of
his own he raised this interesting idea
which I think makes a lot of sense to me
in that he said as you pointed out these
These cultivars are disappearing on
their own for various reasons it's not
like Strain Hunters is the sole reason
for that but he raised this idea of like
if you do have these seeds it's kind of
your due diligence to try to get them
out there and not just sit on the stock
forever and like sort of hoard it in a
way do you feel like that's an idea you
can get down with
well yeah I mean and that's kind of you
know it's it's it's interesting because
again we have systems in the world for
regulating the use of plants or you know
for example yupov kind of oversees the
the naming and
describing of what is a different plant
type and they award you know rights to
the the plant breeders for you know you
breed a new Apple for example you you
get the commercial rights to produce
that apple
but one of the things that comes up with
that is that yeah you get the 20 years
of commercial rights to grow that apple
and profit from it exclusively but the
trade-off is that you have to make that
apple tree available to other plant
breeders
and the idea behind that is that plant
genetic resources are really a global
um you know I'm going to call them a
it's going to say it's a human right to
use them but I think that humans kind of
we we put ourselves first on the planet
a little too much
um but the truth is is that everybody on
the planet has the right to access
different types of germplasm if you
protect if you invent a new plant and
you want to you want to get intellectual
property rights on it that's one thing
but really
that's fine to get the commercial rights
to benefit from that exclusively but
we we also do have a duty to maintain
these plants and plant species and plant
populations in a way where they're more
accessible
um to everybody and again call it an
echo of prohibition I call you know
Echoes of prohibition being the things
that we've that we're still doing wrong
because we learned to do them through
prohibition one of the Echoes of
prohibition is oh if you want
that you know if you want the seed that
I have then you have to pay me for it
um
and it's kind of just the way it is you
know I and so I have all these
populations and I you know the idea is
to eventually get them all out and share
them all in some regard
um
but it took a lot of work to create to
collect these things and I don't want to
pass them on to someone that doesn't
know how to to preserve them properly
right because the idea again is that
we're we're really custodians of the
Cannabis gene pool it's not ours it
doesn't no plant breeder owns all the
Cannabis that they have it's just that
you're a custodian for it for the future
generations of people that are going to
use it
um and I think that that's a really
important
attitude to have when when going about
cannabis preservation work is that no
it's not your alcopolitical gold or your
Mexican variety or your Indian variety
is like these
you know these seeds have cultural
heritage attached to them and there's
there's history in people that preserve
them
for us right in fact there's you know
there's something called the CBD which
is funnily enough CBD it's the
um
what is it again
I'm having a mind mind moment here where
I'm not recognizing what it is but
essentially it's like a a program of
biological diversity
um an agreement of biological diversity
between all these plants or all these
countries to protect the diversity
because what's typically happened is
Western countries have gone to these
poor third world countries
looking for plants to
collect and take back and turn them into
a pharmaceutical product
right where the culture that maintained
that plant or discovered that plant
they don't have any benefit from them
right they don't they don't earn any
benefit from them so there's something
called the Nagoya protocol and people
can again Google that but the Nagoya
protocol essentially says for all the
signatory countries
but if you know if you're a Spanish
company or you're a Dutch company
they're both signatories you can't just
go down to Africa and start
pilfering seeds right and then taking
them back and profiting them and in that
sense you know it could well be that
Ariane is actually violating that
product that protocol
um that agreement that his government
has signed to where
if you're going to go down and exploit
that genetic diversity or that cultural
diversity that genetic diversity that's
produced by the culture that they're
entitled to some of the profits
um
and it just stops the more advanced
countries of the world or the more
developed countries of the world from
going around and exploiting the the
folks that aren't quite as developed yet
yeah definitely and I think history has
shown that a lot of the less developed
countries have sadly copped the the
short end of the stick without these
sort of regulations in place so
hopefully our buddy are in hasn't
violated any laws in that regard
um a question I'd just love to run by
before we jump back to the beginning so
to speak is on the topic of indigenous
land races one of the really good
questions we got from one of our
listeners was they were interested in
knowing
you know in line with errors in a former
guest of ours having done some of the
Andreas Expeditions and he did hint that
there are still some indigenous stuff
out there it's obviously just near and
far when you come across it are there
any indigenous cultivars or land race
strains that in your mind you would
really love to work with if you had the
chance
I mean it would be really nice to be
able to go back to those varieties of
yesterday with the Technologies of today
and start doing some real exploring
using science
um I've you know I've got little
collections of
relatively exotic things in the
collection I've got some ties and you
know some Mexicans the Highland Mexican
and some other these you know all
different Colombians all these different
things the truth is when you start
exploring land race population there's a
lot of dogs
right there's a lot of plants that are
way way substandard in there for
whatever reason
um and so honestly it's kind of a hassle
to be working with land race populations
um even if you're breeding modern day
corn you don't go back to the varieties
that were collected out of the Wilds you
know the teosantes of the world because
you're losing all that genetic progress
that you've created right the breeders
of the world that have ushered it
um ushered cannabis to us in the state
that it's in today
yeah they've made a lot of mistakes
because again they're typically not
professionally trained scientific plant
breeders like the rest of the world's
crops right
um
the Cannabis world is kind of funny it's
like plant breeders are celebrities and
I don't I don't you know I don't know
any celebrity wheat breeders or or
cornbreeders right it's just not that
kind of thing they're kind of bred by
like big time nerds you know
um which is great but um
it's just kind of the way it is so
um we try to work with you know we go
back to those
what you call land race populations or
those more wild populations typically in
a plant breeding project when you're
looking for a trait that has been lost
over time
um
so for example it corn in the United
States
went through this vast bottlenecking
process because they were trying to make
these high yielding sweet corn varieties
and they did they created these
incredibly bulletproof sweet corn
varieties that were high yielding and
you know you'd produce
50 times the amount of corn per acre is
that you would but if you're using a
variety say from 20 30 years ago
um
but one of the things that they learned
they realized is that the plant the
plants became susceptible to pests in
the root in the soil so the roots would
be attacked and The Roots essentially
they had lost these compounds that would
protect them so one of those compounds
was beta-cariophyllene which is one of
the major sesquitur beans that's
produced by cannabis it's in all the
Kush varieties OG Bubba all that kind of
stuff is high in high in beta-carotylene
and beta-carotylene makes the roots
unpalatable to certain aphids right well
they accidentally bred it out because
they were so focused on the big sweet
corn that the other traits that they
weren't really paying attention to a lot
of them got lost along the way
and so they had to actually when they
realized hey all the modern corn doesn't
produce beta-cariotylene in The Roots
they now had to go bait way back in time
in their breeding programs to find
plants that had those to try and
re-introgress that trait back into the
population and so I think for me that
that's really where
the the major benefits are going to come
from those land race lines
yeah you're probably getting some
interesting head spaces again because
the plants are in the like eight to ten
percent THC range not the 20 plus THC
range
um and maybe some of them have unique or
interesting terpene profiles
but funnily enough most of that stuff
has actually been preserved pretty well
because
Growers and smokers have always liked
the interesting smelling plants right
and there's always been one grower
that's you know he's like I really like
this type of smell and in that Pursuit
he's managed to breed
for the predominance of one terpene over
another right and so right now we
actually have an incredible amount of
genetic diversity and flavor
whereas where the plant is probably
most going to be able to be to be
improved in terms of things like disease
resistance and pest resistance right
resistance to powdery mildew botrytus
yada yada all that kind of stuff
yeah definitely definitely and there's
many subjects we'll touch on in the near
future of this chat especially
preserving old school skunk that's
something I want to talk about with you
for sure but before we do that let's go
back to the start what was your first
experience with cannabis
well I was hash someone had brought some
hash to a party
and it was you know it was rolled in a
in a a joint with some tobacco
and uh I think I felt a little high I
remember we smoked it and we went
outside for a walk and I remember
feeling weird on this walk as we went
from one party to another
but it wasn't really that uh
of a profound experience I kind of came
away from the whole thing thinking well
that wasn't really a big deal
um and then it became something that we
did you know I'd go over my friend
Costa's house
uh on weekends and his older brother
you know would would get us the hash and
we would sit around and listen to Led
Zeppelin and and smoke hash joints
um
so it wasn't it wasn't it wasn't really
about the diversity and the flavors for
me then I remember then
you know I I met another girl in school
just a friend of mine and her older
brother was a dealer and she said you
know you smoke cannabis you should I
should teach you to my introducing my
brother because he's got really good
stuff and so this this kid became my
connection and he had all this like
exotic stuff that I'd never seen before
like he had he had the purple weed that
I'd never seen for the first time
and you know Manali finger sticks and
these like kind of surfboard looking
flat plate hashes that were imported
um for whatever reason through his
connections he just happened to have all
this kind of diversity
first time I saw a really nice indoor
weed the first time I saw like a cherry
oil you know all these kind of things
and so when I met this guy he really
opened my eyes
um and he was actually quite
instrumental in in my future cannabis
use because
a couple of years in knowing him he had
a couple guys break into his house in
the middle of the middle of night with a
shotgun and they took his all of his
weed and all of his money and they
kidnapped his roommate
and left his roommate you know
100 kilometers outside of town on the
side of a road at cross streets in his
underwear and uh that was enough for my
my my friend's older brother to be like
I want nothing to do with this business
anymore I'm out
which really sucked because I had
learned to have this appreciation for
all the diversity that he had and and
showed me and then I was forced to go
back on the street
um to try and find things of significant
quality like he had he always had the
quality
and I learned within about eight months
or 12 months that most other dealers
didn't care about buying them you know
you got to imagine like for any product
there's a wholesale market right and the
wholesale Market has a variation in
price yeah you can pay for the the
really expensive stuff but a lot of the
dealers are at least the ones that I
knew they all wanted to buy the lower
price stuff because they could make a
higher margin on it
um and that was really contrary to my
goals right which was to have the really
nice the really nice flowers
and that was kind of right before I
entered the university and and was
getting out on my own and at that point
in time it was like wow you know what I
know that these things exist
they have to be that you can clearly
produce them
the channels that I have are clearly not
interested in bringing those things to
me so I'm just going to start growing
and so I went out and I bought every
girl book that I could find in some
seeds and I read them all cover to cover
like you know way too many times
and that was the beginning of this
what's become an obsessive insane
Pursuit I think you know for
over the past 30 years I think the first
15 or 20 of them most of the people that
I knew thought that I was insane right
was like why are you spending all of
your time
focusing on all this weed it's really
you know
I could have done a lot of different
things I think in my life and so for a
lot of people to think to see me
focusing all that attention on cannabis
I think they thought was a waste of my
potential
and then
funnily enough the world turned around
and they all realized that I wasn't
insane I was just ahead of my time
um
and now you know that we have a legal
industry
I'm able to you know positively
influence the industry through this
massive Gene collection that I've got
um
which has always been what I've been
interested in doing you know I mean I
got when this system developed in Canada
all the pub covers went I was offered
millions of dollars for my seed
collection and
you know when someone offers you
multiple millions of dollars you have to
seriously think about you know why
you're doing what you're doing you know
do you take the big payout and then just
go and live a comfortable life
but the truth was is that that's never
why I collected I didn't do all the work
collecting all these seeds because I had
hoped that one day that there would be a
payout
right I did it because I loved it
and I enjoyed what I was doing
and
so I turned all these offers down
because it became about no I don't I'm
not looking for a buyout I'm looking for
a home right for a place where I can
actually
get a farm and some nice greenhouses and
actually take all this hard work that
I've put into collecting all these
things
and start bringing them back to the
world like you said right how do you get
these things out and share them with the
world
and so the new world is really about
dealing with the regulatory challenges
to make that happen how do you how do
you sell seeds internationally legally
how do you do all the stuff right
because we have to when you start
working in a regulating system you can't
live in both worlds
right you can't be one foot in the black
market and one foot in the the legal
World it just doesn't work
um so yeah it's really about
about the work and not the money right
it was a good it was a good lesson to
learn right it was a good thing to kind
of be faced with and and come to the
realization that no you know what I
don't do this for the money I do it
because I love it
yeah I I so so much Vibe with that
message because so often a lot of the
the decisions that get made that lead to
deleterious outcomes in cannabis are
done because people are looking to make
money and as kind of as much as it might
irritate some people I always kind of
say like it's worth considering having a
day job so that you don't have to grow a
certain cultivar because you need to pay
the rent with the yield you know what I
mean like it gives you that freedom to
be able to pursue your passions and not
like the bottom dollar
yeah it becomes about
again the Artistry or the that artisanal
aspect of whatever your art is whether
it's planning making guitars or you know
raising and curing pork or vegetables or
cheese or whatever it's all you know
there's some people that are doing it
for money and and the commercial aspect
for it and then there's some people
doing it just to make the finest product
right because that's what they enjoy
doing they like having the finest cheese
in the world or the finest wine in the
world
um
and I think that there's a you know
a lot of people say oh it's like oh
you're a scientist you breed weed from a
scientific perspective it's like yeah
well true enough but I'm also an artist
right it's like you can if you're an
artist you can use science as a tool in
your toolbox right it's like just like a
specific type of type of paint or a
specific paintbrush
right just because you're using science
it doesn't mean that you can't do the
art aspect of it as well right so to me
it's a it's a fusion of those two yeah
the science is just a set of tools that
help you execute your art
yeah I wholeheartedly agree so if we
kind of touch on that same theme what
was your first grow like I find the
viewers are always extremely interested
in hearing you know like do you remember
this the first strain you ever grew and
the sort of Technology was it like sort
of all MacGyver together give us a
little rundown if you can remember yeah
so it wasn't it wasn't a known or a
named seed light it was you're probably
noticing I don't use the word strain and
we can touch on that after but um
yeah it wasn't a known variety it wasn't
a labeled variety it was seeds that I
got out of some bud
um I was young I was like too young to
be growing weed that way
um I'd heard stories of family members
that had grown weed in the past and I
just kind of grabbed some seeds and I
was like I started them and I told my
parents and they're you know one of my
parents were separated at that point in
time they didn't live together anymore
longer so you know I said to my mom I
said yeah I'm gonna grow some plants and
I think that really what happened is she
was like yeah okay sure thinking that I
would completely fail of course
you know I was I was still in high
school like I was you know I think I was
14 or 15 at the time
uh my mom's gonna be rolling her rolling
her upset if she hears me telling this
publicly but anyway that's another
conversation so
um so I started growing these plants I
went to the Hydra star and they set me
up with a you know I told them you know
we're growing some Tomatoes at our house
and I want to do this and they they were
like okay well they sold me a one foot
by four foot
um kind of like a window box tray and
and a
um slab of rock wool that fit perfectly
into that one foot by four foot
um tray I got a bucket and a pump and a
and a short piece of hose that became
the drip dripper line and it just you
know we designed it into the what I
later came to learn was a recirculating
drip system
took it home put it in the window
planted a couple of seeds right into the
medium and for the next year and a half
I had these stupid unhealthy plants in
my basement beside my guitars and all my
friends coming over to smoke dope on the
weekend
um and I would turn the lights off when
I would go to bed and I'd turn them on
when I'd get up in the morning
right and so these plants of course
never flowered they do they weren't
getting any kind of consistent light
cycle
um
and finally I think it must have been
like it must have been like you know 13
14 months or something and finally my
mom was had enough and she's like that
those have to go
and so I moved him down to my dad's
house and put him in a window that
happened to be west facing and I didn't
know anything about it but just
coincidentally it happened to be fall so
the plants flowered
right and we cut him down and it was
terrible smoke because the genetics were
crap and
but I but it was a learning experience
right it was like huh you can actually
get these things through to the the
cycle
um
and I put it away for a couple years I
didn't even really think about it again
because it didn't again it didn't turn
out well and I was living at my parents
foot my folks house
but when I moved out on my own I was
like okay I'm gonna figure this thing
out and learn how to do it right
so the second time I started growing I
went and bought a little 400 watt light
from the grow store and uh you know I
think I was growing in 20 liter buckets
reading the old Mel Frank books and some
of Ed rosenfolds all books and you know
obviously marijuana botany was my Bible
um
and it just went from there I started
screening and I remember going down to
the the Hydra store and I was kind of
friends with the guy and I subtly said
to him I was like hey man you know do
you think I can get some clones is there
any way
and he gave me the the stock answer was
you know he's like no we don't do that
and part of
growing cannabis is cutting your teeth
on seeds and finding some good plants
and working with those
and I was like well
[__] you you know what I did that I went
and went insane with buying seeds and
started growing all these different
varieties and about a year later he was
asking me for cuttings because I had
better you know I'd found better plants
than what they were growing
um and I realized that I really like
that that part of the the grow and I was
you know I was in university and started
I I think I had a genetics course and
from that point on I just got right into
it
um
and was almost immediately bringing you
know I brought
I brought the the flowers that I had
produced back to the storefront that was
selling the seeds and he was like wow
your flowers are really good like can I
get some seeds from these and so I made
a couple of crosses and I donated them
to one of the early medical uh cannabis
challenges that were going on in Canada
and they sold them through this head
shop
and the feedback was really good right
because I had found excellent plants for
for the parents
and just having a little bit of
Knowledge from you know my plant
breeding courses or my genetics course I
was able to make better choices for what
constitutes a good parent and I guess
the seeds turned out well
and
you know when I went in one day and the
guy was like man your seeds are getting
great reviews from all these people we
want you to start making more seeds
and that kind of just fit in really good
with what I was doing so I from kind of
from the start like I didn't
really grow cannabis to have largest
amount to sell it I always just became
the guy that was growing lots of plants
from seed and keeping clowns and finding
interesting plants and and working for
them that way and it it I found it
really enjoyable right that's kind of
what I love about cannabis is there's
such a diversity in the
morphological and chemical profiles the
scent as you know the cannabinoids
everything like it's it really is a
remarkable plant in that way
unlike many types of plants which are
much more uniform
and less diverse and so cannabis has got
so much that we can do with it that it's
really kind of a fun plant to play with
wholeheartedly agree wholeheartedly
agree
the thing which jumps to mind for me
when I hear that amazing story is
obviously a lot of people talk about
having looked at Rob Clark's books and
people of that early generation who
really laid a lot of the the paving for
future breeders and for future Growers
but the thing about Rob was he wasn't
like as notable of a breeder as he was
sort of like a guru and an instructor
were there specifically any breeders who
you looked at when you started your
projects and thought this person has a
good feel for what they're doing and
they were kind of like a um like you
know a figure you looked up to in a
sense well I might say I'm pretty early
on right
um and he kind of we we kind of
connected over the Internet because he I
think he recognized he's like wow this
person knows what they're talking about
and so I went over to Canada the
Cannabis Cup I can't remember what year
was it was pretty early on and
I met I met Sam
and when he found out who I was I think
he was kind of taken back that I was
much younger than he had thought that I
would have been
and and he kind of like brushed me off
and you know he was a little bit like
dismissive of me and I was like whatever
I just I don't know this guy that's fine
and I got I remember leaving you know
completing my trip and coming back home
and
I went home found an email waiting from
David from from Dave Sam David and he um
and he essentially apologized me he's
like I'm sorry I was kind of rude to you
and he was like next time you come back
to Amsterdam you come over my house for
dinner and I got a bunch of stuff to
show you and you know I don't know most
a lot of people might not realize but he
was also the president or founder of the
international hemp Association so he was
a pretty central figure in the Cannabis
world
um
and his connections are just so deep
um and
I honestly don't know I've ever met
anybody
more than than David that is more
passionate about cannabis than David he
really is like you know a lot of people
slag him on the internet and there's all
these stupid just totally wrong rumors
about him working for the DEA and the
CIA that get passed around about him
online and you know I got to tell you
it's just not true like all that stuff
is just it's all got like tiny little
bases in reality
but you know for example like he did
when he started he was licensed to work
in Holland and so the University of
Mississippi which was the only licensed
DEA grow at the time they wanted to get
genetics to improve their their work
they reached out to David and said hey
we're doing science over here in
Mississippi and University of
Mississippi can you send us some seeds
you're you're legally allowed to grow
them in Holland can you export some to
the states and so they went and got a
you know they're a DEA licensed producer
in the States they're one of the only
ones or I think they're the only one now
but there used to be two
and
and the DEA granted them an import
permit to produce seeds and and so David
was able to export seeds from hortifarm
his company into the United States
completely legally
but somehow the community
thought oh well David's working with the
DEA he's got these abilities to do these
things
and the truth was is that he of course
he wasn't working with a DEA there's
nobody that would work with the DEA less
than David right like he's completely on
board for the cause like he's not
helping out the CIA or the DEA that's
just Stoner nonsense
um
but there was a lot of animosity towards
David because he had figured out how to
do legally what everybody else couldn't
do right they everybody else was playing
in the in the black market world and he
had learned how aide figured out how to
get a grow licensed how to do research
on plants
how to start looking into the different
chemical profiles in the plant the truth
is he was like one of the very very
first people
in the western world that was
promoting medical cannabis or the
medical use of cannabis and he firmly
believed that you could you could take
all these plants and create all these
different chemical profiles from them
when nobody else even was even close to
considering doing that so you know I I
have a lot of respect for David he's
really like he's kind of like a father
figure to me
um and he's just he's just a great guy
he's a weirdo for sure and he'll tell
you that straight out of his own mouth
um he's really quite eccentric but he is
super smart
he is super focused on cannabis and
collecting as many different types as he
can from all over the world and learning
about the plant
um you know he's in his 70s and he sucks
up information all the new information
like a vacuum cleaner it's really
unbelievable
um
so you know as a role model from people
to look to look at from as I was kind of
starting my career
he and Rob I mean there was no better
there was no better people to know right
because I got to learn through him too
the truth behind
the the Dutch Seed Company at the time
and honestly
these stories of these massive breeding
houses in Hall and doing work on seeds
is that's nonsense it's a it's a fable
it's just not it's not what happens
right A lot of these guys produce seeds
in closets and it's no different than
the work that anybody else is doing
anywhere else in the world it's just
that they can legally sell the seeds and
create a marketing
um perspective that makes it look like
they're doing the work well the truth is
they're not doing the work
right so David was really one of the
only people that were you know he built
a laboratory he started looking for THC
and CBD and all these other cannabinoids
and they even started looking at
terpenes like way before their time way
before anybody else was
um so yeah I think if you're asking who
my
the people I looked up to it would be
those guys you know other people in the
Canadian space I would just collect
everybody's seeds I would buy seeds and
sell seeds and
it was all about just getting everything
right there wasn't any ego attached to
it the first person I was kind of really
excited to work with was DJ
um and the blueberry
um that was kind of fun because he was
just you know his stuff was just so
different than everybody else's
and from a genetic diversity point of
view I thought that it was
you know it was a good addition to your
your pool of what you're working with
it's like a whole new little subset of
genetics to create hybrids with
um
but by that point in time I was starting
to be really disenfranchised with the
rest of the seed business so I think for
most people I don't you know there's a
few people that are doing it right like
Simon serious seed Simon he's
um he's not a trained plant breeder but
he really understands what he's doing
and he he understands trying to create a
uniform product and and uh you know I
think his work is really good
um
some of the younger guys there's a lot
of younger guys that know what they're
doing you know Caleb
from uh
CSI seeds
he does some good stuff
there's a whole bunch of people that are
doing it right now and they're starting
to do I think we're kind of in a bit of
a Renaissance
for cannabis there's a lot of people
that are just hacking plants together
and creating an image and you know being
really popular on Instagram and
that's all fine and dandy but I think
for most of those people it's about
making money not really about improving
the plant
um but I'd like to see more of these
people
invest in a couple of plant breeding
textbooks and put some effort into
trying to learn about
you know the biological
basis for for plant breeding because
when you understand all that stuff you
can just you're really more effective in
your work
right and I think that the people that
really care about the plant and
improving the plant they do that
and a lot of the people that are more
concerned about the money and the
celebrity don't really do that and
that's a shame
yeah certainly and just a plethora of
avenues we could go down in terms of the
discussion before we jump on to some of
the other breeders you mentioned I'd
love to just chat about David a little
more if possible and specifically I
think the question which I most commonly
hear around that sort of DEA mystery
sort of thing is that I think a lot of
people have a hard time understanding
how that story about how the warehouse
got raided and then like he was Henry's
colleagues were able to like get the
plants out of the dumpster and then bail
do you have any Reflections or insight
into that story like do you think he
just got lucky or what do you think the
situation was with that the story is not
even true that's the funny thing is that
David was involved with I think he he he
technically wasn't even involved in the
bust he had moved to Amsterdam or he you
know he went over to start work in
Amsterdam
um was kind of exploring because you
know if you were in the drug scene and
you heard that Canada that Holland was
popping off and you could go there grow
weed I mean that was a pretty exciting
thing for people
so he went over there and started doing
some work and you know realized oh this
is the place for me I got to go back to
California
and close up my life there and I'm
moving over to Amsterdam so he did and
he went back and you know got all their
stuff dealt with and then he moved to
Holland
and
his wife at the time got busted and it
wasn't the wife it was their roommate
had a male plant in the window
and that was the oh and so Dave but
David wasn't even there that's the only
California like cannabis bus that even
has any remotely closeness to David
right
um
so all these stories about like the
sacred seed Collective and all the this
is just these are nonsense stories that
people just make up on the internet
um
and I've done you know I've I I'm a
pretty interesting person when it comes
to things like this of history and I've
done a little bit of looking into it and
I tell you man he's not like that didn't
happen so I don't know about the story
in the warehouse and the plants and
saving the plants and all this kind of
stuff it's to me it sounds like internet
fantasy but there's no basis in reality
to it as far as I'm aware
and I've asked him all these questions
you know I've asked David all the hard
questions
um because I wanted to get to the basis
of it and the answers are always
very like it's you know you know the
concept of Occam's razor or persimony
right it's like
the simplest explanation is usually the
true one
right and I think that with but listen
I've had people do it with me we'll
probably get to that later in the
episode but there's a lot of Fantastical
stuff that's written about me on the
internet that's just has no basis in
reality so I've seen it you know I've
seen it happen
um and I you know
getting to know David as I have over the
last 20 years
I just I just don't believe any of this
that stuff right and you talk to other
you know I've been able to go back and
meet like other people that he worked
with in California and you know he knew
Rob back in the day and I've talked to
Rob about all this kind of stuff and
it's just I think that
a lot of it spurred from the fact that
he was able to get these licenses that
nobody else was able to to do
um when GW Pharmaceuticals
got the go-ahead from
um
the home office in the United States to
set up a grow and start working there
obviously you know because they
understood that there was pharmaceutical
potential in cannabis and so they
started doing everything you would do to
do that you you set up and grow you
start doing some science you make some
extractions you figure out what
molecules are in the plant and you start
testing them
and
they needed a genetic Supply they needed
to turn to somebody in the world and say
hey do you have these rare varieties
with all these different chemistries and
sure enough they found hortifarm because
horror Farm was the only company in the
world that was doing that work
and
you know David had David kept quarter
farmer alive with his own
he didn't he didn't have a bunch of
people giving him money right there was
no public markets for raising funds to
support that kind of business he was
doing it with his own work and paying
for that kind of work with his his legal
seed sales right seed sales were always
legal in in Holland and so he was able
to sell some seeds and pay for
you know pay to do his work but
when GW really approached him horror
Farm was struggling right because it's
really it's really expensive man when
you start doing science on cannabis I
mean you're spending like 50 100 for a
lab test so if you're running
you know thousands or even tens of
thousands of plants that gets really
really expensive really quickly
and when you're legal your compliance
costs are huge you have to have security
you have to have
you know record keeping like it's it's
not it's not done the way the people in
the black market do without having all
these different reporting duties and and
Regulatory duties
and so when when GW came along
they offered
hortifarma Lifeline like it was really a
Lifeline at that point in time so that
David could keep doing the work
you know he had Staffing costs they had
they had it was running a business when
you're not making an income and you're
doing research is a really really
difficult thing to do I don't think
people really understand that
um if you haven't done it but
yeah that's kind of what he was doing
and um
because he was doing that and because
you know that the community's always
thought a big Pharma they're the evil
people the guys that run GW they like
helping patients just like anybody else
right where I know a few of the
scientists work for that company and
they're
you know I I hear them tell stories that
bring yeah you probably know some people
that you know they produce weed and they
give it away to a medical patient of one
type or another child that's got Apple
your epilepsy or something and
you get a lot of Pride from doing that
like there's really kind of no better
feeling than than helping someone with
your work with a plant right like if you
can grow a plant
and take that plant and extract the
flowers or whatever you do make an
extract that's not the important part
but if you can like bring a plant to
life and and harvest it and take that
medicine and give it to somebody and it
really changes their life there's
nothing that feels better than that and
it's like it really is just a completely
satisfying altruistic thing to do and I
know that a lot of the research
scientists that work in at GW they kind
of feel the same way as The Growers up
in California that are growing medicine
for for children with an epilepsy right
it's it's really altruistic and the
community
as a whole not everybody but as a whole
has this bias against big Pharma and so
they look at anything related to do with
big Pharma as oh you're selling out or
you're taking our plant and giving it
away
you know to the man and like I said
earlier to me
these plant genetics are a human
resource that should be accessible to
everybody
right
um
whether you're with a big company or
you're a little guy like it doesn't
matter right
I don't think the big guy should be
stealing from the little guys
but
I think having access to the tools is
kind of fair game across the board
right you're certainly not going to keep
wheat seeds or corn seeds or potato
seeds out of anybody's hands right like
if you want to work with a plant as a
human I think that you've got the right
to go and collect some seeds from
wherever you can find them and start
working
yeah definitely definitely and I I
certainly agree with the sentiment that
there is a lot of like anti-big Farm a
sentiment in the community and you know
I can understand why in some respects
you know like the the opioid crisis in
America is an obvious thing you could
point at and be uh quite skeptical of
their motives in that regard but I
understand what you mean where it's like
I've met a lot of people who work in big
Pharma and a lot of them want the best
for their patients and they're not doing
it for financially driven reasons and I
I always love how people are like super
critical of big Pharma but no one ever
has a problem with antibiotics it's like
we you know it's you know it's like we
just agree that it's actually being done
for the good of people but like it does
cost money to produce them
yeah well we're getting to the point
though where we have this whole anti
like anti-vaccine movement now right
it's like there's we used to take pride
in in having knowledge and now there's a
large segment of certain countries maybe
nameless that they really take pride in
the ignorance it's like if you're if
you're an educated person person they're
like oh you're up in your Ivory Tower
you're not in contact with the regular
the regular man and it's gotten to the
point where they think that you know
Bill Gates is trying to chip people he's
trying to like
right and it's like I saw a sign the
other day it says it was a picture of
Bill Gates or uh they'd put his head on
on someone at a Gates and it said um
you're not worth microchipping change my
mind right
it's like why would you think that like
the guy's just given away like most of
his wealth and somehow the conspiracy
folks of the world have turned around to
oh no he's actually just trying to use
it to get more money
it's kind of insane I don't think if you
have any understanding of Science and
virology and vaccines that you know
especially in a coveted world
how you could be anti-vaccine I just I
don't get it
yeah it's it's pretty wild
[Music]
[Applause]
well there you have it friends a huge
shout out to Ryan of chimerogenetics for
helping make this fun happen
I hope you learn a ton as always big big
shout out to our amazing sponsors CT now
best seed bank in the game go hit him up
if you want to grow that fire they got
all the best breeders in the game the
one you need as well as puppet
biological systems best Predators
microbes and feeds so much more go check
them out to keep your garden happy and
healthy likewise you shout out to the
patreon gang we love you guys so much
thank you for your support you truly are
the lifeblood of the show
I hope you learn a ton
stay tuned for the next two parts to
drop soon
I'll see you for the next one
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]