foreign
[Music]
welcome to the next episode of the
podcast a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts as always you're joined by
your boy heavy days here from the upside
down Library
and we are incredibly grateful to all of
our sponsors
seeds here now number one seed bank in
the industry all the greatest breeders
the hottest drops the latest strains
anything you could want they got it and
they offer a guarantee on satisfaction
not just germination check them out guys
they got what you need
[Music]
likewise huge shout out to our friends
at Copper biological systems with
everything you need to ensure that your
Harvest is pumping on all Pistons firing
on all cylinders and giving you the
highest grade Harvest to date free of
pests pathogens with their wide range of
beneficial Predators including the
active RM and the spidex vital they'll
keep your garden happy and healthy
huge shout out to our homies holding
down the fort down under top shelf seed
bank and organic gardening solutions for
all the greatest breeders for all the
best organic gardening products check
them out it's the organic products I use
and the seed bank that I sell my stuff
through
and last but not least the patreon gang
thank you thank you thank you the one
and only this could not make episodes
happen without use
if you would like to get early access to
upcoming episodes
exclusive unreleased content bonus
episodes with Bob Hemphill Mean Gene
body 707 Seedbank truck home jungles the
list goes on please consider checking
out the patreon
www.patreon.com the podcast
on these episodes
we are incredibly grateful to be joined
by both Sea Ray and Gabby some white
buffalo seeds
Legends of the Canadian scene old school
land race preservers hunters
appreciators and Heck if you've ever had
the Roberts Creek Congo you owe these
guys I think
foreign
[Music]
genetics
outcoming crosses
plans for the future
old client history
so much more
let's just get into it
[Music]
alrighty my friends we're back for
another one and today we are incredibly
grateful to be joined by the crew behind
White Buffalo seeds land race Legends in
their own right maintaining one of the
most unique collections of cultivars
I've seen thank you so much to see Ray
and scabby of white buffalo seeds for
joining us today
hey guys hey everyone how's it going
nice to be here
the first question we love to ask all
our guests what are you guys been
smoking on today
oh we're just generally smoking some
stuff that we just grew um
we're just testing out some of our new
uh hybrids uh one of them is Irene cross
original Haze it's a really nice one
and another one is the Congolese cross
Iraqi pilgrim
um and some other stuff that we just
harvested uh like Angola red
what else have you been smoking on uh I
just rolled up uh Angola red and Irene
Hayes and I was peeking a little bit
there but we're we're coming into the
zone or flying kind of land read in
there
yeah
I am thoroughly jealous right now
because as someone who loves sativas but
uh like most people doesn't have a ton
of them hanging around to smoke that
sounds like exactly where I want to be I
was interested I mean I'm probably going
to ask you a bunch of questions about
all those varieties because they all
sound great but the first one would be
the Irene couldn't cross the Hays it
sounds like it's more leaning to the
haze side is it
that one's pretty uh
pretty balanced I would say because
um apparently the Irene is is a self
like it's a self uh progeny
so self progenies in in crosses tend to
be um tend to be you know reasonably uh
consistent in the uh now in The
Offspring
so yeah they that one actually turned
out really well like as far as
uniformity from plant to plant to plant
um we grew about
uh 16 females
um a pretty good sample and
we ended up keeping about uh probably a
dozen of them to check out again you
grow again
lovely I'm gonna have to ask you some
more questions about your finger hunting
but just to confirm for everyone
listening are we talking about the the
Irene OG or a different Irene yeah it's
uh well I don't know if it's an OG per
se but it's like a
it's a OG ish plant but it's like a kush
yeah does it have the weird buds growing
from like the internode
uh I've only grown it one like twice
um and I didn't experience that yet but
you mean like little but let's set grow
off the stems or something yeah I've
just heard people saying that you get
like these weird little buds growing at
the internodes on Irene I was just
curious if you'd experienced that at all
uh not yet I think that's like a
phosphorous thing if I remember no like
a potassium or potassium high potassium
yeah you know it gets you can you can go
buds right off the uh the stock if you
hit the hit them with uh the right type
of potassium at the right time
apparently
there you go that's some cool info I
wasn't aware of I like that what was it
about the Irene that Drew it to you
because I think if we look at your work
um there's often sort of an older World
strain and sometimes a newer World
strain and I'd be interested in hearing
like what sort of characteristics of the
modern strain attract you like you know
I haven't seen you grow a cookies hybrid
but the Irene is pretty modern what what
do you like about it
um well it's I mean we've only grown it
a couple times it's just one of those
things you grow it and you like you
taste it and it's like this is the good
[ __ ] yeah definitely the terpenes are
what was most interesting um this is and
it's got a good high like yeah for being
um
we we're kind of uh critical about
um more of the Indica commercial Indica
push type stuff
um and that were because we're really uh
like we're really sativa connoisseurs so
we want we want to we expect all our
plants to have like you know some some
sort of profound profundity in the in
the stone you know like that's what
we're that's what our goal is you know
um so this uh the Irene's actually got a
little bit of a
got a decent uh you know heavy heavy uh
effect to it yeah it's like an easy man
high you know after you get up the
little rocket boost there for a minute
or two and then it's nice and easy right
you're you're grooving down the street
yeah I love the sounds of that and you
know what just based on hearing that I'm
confident it's the uh the Irene cut I'm
thinking of because that's what everyone
says they were like above all like the
high on this plant is exquisite so that
all makes sense I think the bud shape is
like not very like uh
alluring to most people and I think the
Iraqi kind of sorry the Hayes kind of
stepped that up a bit in that cross for
sure
yeah beautiful beautiful stuff there and
I mean while we're on the topic of Hayes
I had a few different questions I guess
I'd be interested in asking I know that
you guys have worked with many different
hazes over the years both you know some
of Neville's work with like the haze a
and Haze C progeny and I think you guys
have even worked with some of the
original stuff from Sam himself I'd be
interested to hear like is does that all
check out and is there one sort of stock
of haze that you think is better to the
other or it's all just like a family
uh well as far as I'm concerned it all
came from uh skunkman stock like I mean
what everyone's growing you know there's
obviously
stuff that uh people I say predates that
but um
I mean would everyone refers to as
original Haze came through
uh the seedsman well not all of it but I
think he sold a bunch like privately
skunkman sold a bunch of seeds privately
before that but a lot of this stuff came
through
um the seedsman
um seedsman company seed company or
whatever
um like if you look if you go on to
Archive
archive.org and look up seedsman.com
and go back to
uh it's like I don't know what it's like
a couple years after the earliest
centuries you'll see the original
um release of the sea like the
skunkman's uh you know uh breed that he
did at that time which is like a bunch
of uh
original Haze and there was some
a few land races and then there is a
bunch of uh crosses and there's uh I
think some
Afghani South Indiana Afghani Durban
Durban
um yeah I think that's it probably more
yeah anyways you'll find it on
archive.org
it's pretty uh interesting to go back
and look at that
yeah not and when you say seedsman are
you talking about like the the generic
label that the seed bank offers or like
Sam's that's right no I mean I'm talking
um the original like the seed bank
seedsman
I believe like I don't know the story
but I've heard you know bits of the
story that it was like a collab between
either it was a collab or it was started
with basically it was started with uh
skunkman seeds like that's what was got
it going
um and he had like uh kilo he had like
that guy bought like a kilo of all the
different varieties I think is the story
um
and I don't think it lasted very long
because if you look at archive.org you
can kind of see where like it was like a
couple years of skunkman stuff and then
it kind of transitioned to uh Dutch a
bunch of Dutch stuff
yeah interesting stuff I do think I
remembered hearing that story from Todd
so that that all sort of checks out I'd
be interested to hear in terms of your
experience with the hazes
have you seen stuff come out of it that
is similar to some of the well-known
stuff like you know the the black Cuban
Hayes you know a really famous nl5 Haze
cutting do you ever see any of the
characteristics in the haze you've
worked with that seems similar to the
other famous Haze work or it all seems
like quite unique
uh well every like we've grown the
original Haze stock from a few different
sources now like four or five different
sources
um and everyone you dip into is
different it's all depends on because
everyone started with a little a small
Subs you know a sub selection of
original Haze you know they got 10 10
seeds or whatever so based on on uh luck
of the draw you know everyone got a
little bit and then they selected you
know certain things
um so there there's quite a bit of
variation
um in our experience
and like most of them are most of them
are not worth growing you know
in our opinion like uh you really have
to find the right uh bag of seeds
um and to get the they get the really
good ones that are worth growing like
most of them like 99 of them uh most
people would not want to grow
okay yeah that's that's brilliant
because it sort of parlays into the next
part of the question that I was going to
ask which was that the impression I
always got from the work that came from
Neville's Hayes stuff was that although
he got like a small number of seeds or
males or whatever it was from Sam it
seemed like the males he got ended up
being pretty bloody good is that like
your perspective on it
that's a good question like um
I mean I haven't grown I've grown a few
of uh Neville sings um
but uh
I mean obviously they were good because
they stood the test of time time and we
and we grow we grow some of that stuff
like we have some
in all Hayes uh
seeds that are good so
um I don't know I can't I don't know if
like like I don't really know
um the difference I mean I can figure it
out the difference between the A and
this email just because we've grown
a little bit of both like we haven't
grown the C5 or the A5 cutting but we've
grown
uh C5 f2s and we've grown um the A5
BX from Karma bx1 I guess it was yep
um so you know we have a rough idea
um
there's definitely uh they're definitely
very different males like the A5 is
really savory
um and kind of charcoaly that's what I
get out of it like charcoal and like
uh Woody incense whereas the uh the C5
side is uh sweet
um flowery like perfumey
well pencil shavings
on the C5 yeah
yeah that checks out I uh I've been
lucky enough to try both of those and
your descriptions fairly perfectly fit
it
smoked I smoked a bunch of the stuff of
the uh of like a bunch of haze like what
they call Haze in um
Amsterdam
um so
I probably have smoked both of those
when I was there because I was smoking
stuff from like uh
uh Neville's buddy the uh Steve
um he had some something something and a
bunch of dispensaries at that time
um
like I don't know I I assume some of
them had the real deal you know like
real deal whatever
uh that they were just marketing as NL
Hayes at the time
sure
so I don't know I can't I can't confirm
without going back in the time machine
but
I mean out of curiosity I've always
found that people tend to fall on one
side of the fence they're either like I
love the Hayes C or I love the haze a
and notably a lot of the Breeders I
speak to they all say the haze a they're
like yeah that Colombian sort of vibe
whereas I myself I love to how you see
that more Thai floral sort of thing do
you have one useful more preference wise
I think I'm in this the seaside of
things
yeah I like both qualities but yeah see
yeah that makes sense and actually you
know the the BC uh sweets cutting the
breeder Steve cut um that one is very C5
dominant very C5 dominant like after
growing those C5 f2s and then like
revisiting that cutting it's really
obvious that like originally when the
sweet skunk was sold
um by Mark Emery um
he marketed as snc seeds big skunk cross
grapefruit but
um the original story was that he uh
Steve got a tray of cuttings and there
was a male and they weren't like yeah it
ended up being males instead of females
and stuff like that that's where that
male came yeah and it was they figured
out uh later on it was a nanole haze
mail
that made the sweets go
yeah that's that's definitely the story
he told me and it checks out I I sadly
haven't been able to try sweet skunk but
it looks like n05 Hayes doesn't it oh
yeah it's very and it's very uh an
offline based on like you'll like it
it's a good smoker we have way better
ones I think now as we've worked down
the lines in terms of qualities that are
better for growing like hardiness
powdery mildew ease of growth flowering
time stuff like that but it's definitely
a good one got your teeth on another uh
another plant we grew that was what I
would think would be like the A5 is the
Band-Aid Haze number seven
what was your thoughts on that one it's
pretty popular
it's it's all right but it's um like we
have better stuff in our collection that
we like personally more so
um it's it's a good plant a lot of
people like it so there was a newer
fennel that I tried that I like way
better uh to an appendages too yeah our
friend uh down the road here we got a
pack of 10 original Band-Aid Haze f1s I
believe they were yeah I think so and he
just screws it like he just screw them
out and uh he must have got two packs oh
no maybe there was there must have been
like more than a pack there or something
anyways the number 12 uh was really nice
like better than for us it was better
than the number seven was it two yeah I
think it was two wasn't it I can't
remember yeah it doesn't matter I got it
on a jar back there I think yeah
that makes sense right like it must have
been um two packs if it was number 12
and I I think I've seen people posting
did you know did he give that out at all
that might be a like a cutting that gets
passed around now
no he just he just uh popped those uh
recently yeah it was more recent kind of
thing the high on the new one is like
very uh you smoke it and then it's like
very immediate up and you're like holy
[ __ ] and then you know it comes into a
better relaxed high but I find it's uh
much better higher than than the seven
people junk around
I'd be interested to hear because you
mentioned that uh you said yeah look
it's good but we've got some better
stuff I was actually looking at some
Band-Aid Haze crosses going is this the
sativa I've been searching for it sounds
like you guys have got other ones that
might be more up my Lane if I'm looking
for that racy sativa sort of thing what
might be some recommendations from your
catalog for someone like me who wants
that sort of effect
uh well everything yeah we really try to
like we really sample everything we
really go by the highs and the smells
you know that sort of those are the
things that we really go by because and
we smoke we like to smoke so
um yeah that's something that we really
try to you know involve in everything we
do uh personally I enjoy the Columbia or
the Angola red uh Colombian black Haze
some of those were really awesome but
you find it in lots of different stuff
that we have you know various pictures
yeah everything we have is uh been well
tested and uh like we've gone through
and made sure that it was
um up to
well it's basically what we're looking
for in in a smoke and
um yeah
interesting look I know our listeners
are going to Heckle me if I don't get
some more sort of indoor friendly ones
out of you what like for someone who's
because that's the complaint I hear like
I'm I'm like you guys right like I'm
trying to get people to grow sativas and
they always say you know it's I'm
growing indoor it's tough do you have
something that's like quite indoor
friendly or manageable oh yeah
like uh we have uh Congolese cross Iraqi
is actually uh sativa Dom but uh it's
very manageable our um Iraqi Pilgrim we
grew out uh three packs to like 36 seeds
and uh
there is two males in there that were
semi-auto
that uh there's a few more that were
semi-auto but there was two good
semi-auto males that I specifically used
in the pollination of those crosses so
they're very uh
like they're a lot faster
um yeah I kicked down on everything for
sure and uh pass on Uber good qualities
to everything it touches a lot that
Congo clone is really easy for a sativa
you know nine or ten weeks and uh you're
good to go so it satisfies most of the
guys who are you know looking for
something newer to try that's not so so
long crazy
yeah yeah the count the Congolese is a
very good um commercial plant
and most of the most of the guys that
grow it commercially they cut it at nine
or ten weeks even though you can like
there's a whole range of you know you
can cut it early uh or you can let it go
a little bit later
um but it is it's actually better
turpwise in the early part like most
people would prefer it as nine or ten
weeks because it has uh
as more of the lemon peel Terps at the
beginning yeah the Blue Polish lemon
boot polish yeah
we're gonna get to the Congo later
because I I love that cutting thank you
guys so much for that but uh I just want
to look back quickly to the Iraqi
Pilgrim stuff you were talking about and
you you mentioned um that it was
semi-auto flowering is do you mean that
in sort of the way that some like I know
that for example blueberries a bit like
that where it's like once it gets root
bound it just tries to flower is that
sort of what you're talking about or do
you mean like in a true sense it's a bit
autoflowery
uh I have a very basic definition of
semi-auto
it's semi-auto is something that that
triggers and that it'll start flowering
but you can re-vege it
so if it's Auto basically you can't
revege it you can't you can re-vege Auto
stuff like with a bunch of techniques
um
but semi-auto
like semi-auto you can re-betch with uh
like pretty normal
techniques yeah time and size of bucket
you know
yeah like uh or just take cuttings
Revenge cuttings
okay cool yeah that sounds like sort of
what I was thinking like just I I guess
some strains I'm familiar with fall
under that category I just call them a
bit temperamental but worth keeping
around but um the uh the Iraqi Pilgrim
is uh it's what I would call a pseudo
land race well it's not even really a
pseudo land roof but it could be a
pseudo land race because if you look at
the description for it on seed Heaven
um
the the guy that collected the seeds he
just he went on a tour of Iraq and uh he
just collected seeds from everywhere
that that was that were good and put
them in a bag so it's like it's got a
little bit of everything so yeah when we
grew them um most of them weren't they
were they're okay but most of them were
not things we would grow again
um unfortunately we found a good female
and a good male and and the rest is
history
and we made up twos out of those so we
got what we needed
that's awesome I was gonna specifically
ask I noticed on the website that you
did after it and I was wondering was
that just to have like a bigger pool to
select from or was there like a specific
reason you did that
well it was because it was good that's
the main reason to make more seeds when
you come across something good sorry
maybe I should be more specific was
there was there a reason you didn't just
use like an F1 mail and you went for the
F2 mail instead
well the more in bread something is the
more uh you're able to predict what the
outcome is so I'm always trying to you
know increase the predictability in the
in the hybridization
so my goal is always to um
if I have a choice between uh inbred
male and a nodding not inbred male I'm
always gonna choose the inbred male
unless there's some specific reason that
uh you know you want to choose the other
one but
yeah it's always preferable to uh
um the male side of of your hybrid
equation is always the one that has the
most questions so
um I'd like to use something that's
inbred because then we have like we can
you know if we have something that's
inbred we've grown it before
um and it's relatively consistent from
plant to plant then we have like an idea
of what that male is going to be like
more of an idea basically
yeah phenomenal and I guess one of the
sentiments you hear commonly expressed
when people are talking about using
inbred males is that the more inbred a
line is the more it tends to dominate
The Cross do you find that to be the
case or is it more like what you just
said before where it's just more
predictable but not necessarily
dominating
I think it depends on what it is it
really depends on what it is because it
like some things that are like that are
Blueberry Blueberry is super dominant in
hybrids
um yeah definitely yeah the blueberry
Vision was very when we grew that out
yeah you could see the dominance like
kicking down halfway or more all the
time and something I didn't like
preferably but yeah
definitely a dumb one
um but
um some things are are not non-dominant
and actually uh for breeding sometimes
you want a non-dominant male
um because like let's say you're doing
uh a shotgun breed where you have a male
and you're bringing in
you're loading your room up with uh
everything that you can get your hands
on
then
uh by having a non-dominant male then
you you're allowing all those other
things to express themselves in the
hybrids and you're not ending up with a
bunch of stuff that's you know really
similar
or more
I think that's such a valid and valuable
point because I always try to say to
people
I think probably upwards of 90 of the
time when the average person buys a seed
they're buying it for the mother like
they want that clone only sort of mother
like most of the time of course there's
some variation but that's and that's why
what you just said is perfect right like
if you've got a father that just allows
the mum to shine through then you can
give people sort of the Clone only could
that they can't get their hands on
well that's that's a tricky question
because clone only these are often like
poly hybrids
they're just weird things that are not
gonna ever pop up again
like sweet skunks the plant we were
talking about for instance
um we've tried breeding without so many
times and uh what comes out of it is
never
as good as the original cut so we've
just eliminated that from our breeding
program at all uh you know completely
yeah a long time ago so
yeah that's that's really interesting to
hear so I guess that ultimately you you
refine your females you work with over
the years to be ones that work well in
the breeding sense not just like it's a
popular cultivar
yeah that's where we're always looking
for stuff that um works well as breeding
like in in hybridization
um
like
a good trait in a hybrid you know in
hybridization is a plant that
the hybrids are better than the original
and one plant that uh is like that is
very reliable like that for us is the
the grapefruit cutting the BC grape
cutting
pretty much anything that you put onto
it
um if it's you know half decent you'll
end up with something cool that's that's
going to be more fun to grow than than
the grapefruit
and how do you find the grapefruit is in
general because obviously it's like this
popular strain it's been around ages
um do you think that the smoke itself is
good or it's more what you said that
it's like it's a good tool for the next
step
it's all right it's uh
like it's not uh super
um potent or anything but it's really
nice it's got a nice flavor it's it's
the kind of weed that a lot of people
like to smoke because it's just it's
like Savor weed you know it's weed that
you just smoke to savor it it's not like
super potent so you know from what
there's a lot of people that they don't
want to get whacked out of their head
you know they just want to smoke
something that's really nice it's got a
bit of a relaxing High to it and uh it
yields well too is the other thing yeah
it's a really big yielder
um and it's fast yeah like they used to
harvest it at six weeks wow yeah I
remember I used to be skeptical of the
49 day Cindy 99 but you got that beat
well it wasn't it wasn't necessarily you
know
um
or South Asian Brothers
uh it's the same in Australia um out of
curiosity I I've spoken to Steve in the
past and I said what do you think
grapefruit was and he said I think it's
just an Afghani what do you think and
are you friends with Steve because yeah
I noticed you had the grapefruit cut and
I was like I don't think even he has it
anymore
I my opinion is it's an NL hybrid
okay
yep yeah we've known Steve a long time
he's a real good guy
um Lots he's broad lots to the table
over the years and uh he loves to talk
he's got that big boom and noise and
people like to listen to you know that
is the best description of his voice
isn't it very booming yeah he's one of
the uh grandfathers yeah he's like in
the grandfather category for sure you
better respect
so I just want to link back for a moment
you were talking about the Iraqi Pilgrim
and you you answered this in the
question that I think you sort of said
you got it off a website but our
listeners are always curious to know
where do you Source your land race seed
from is it always sort of just haphazard
or is do you have like a go-to method of
trying to get new stock like or is it
just sort of opportunistic
a lot of it is just random very random
yeah
um
some like I I actually like uh buying
seeds personally like when I see uh land
races on on um
uh the real Seed Company I like to buy a
lot of stuff from them and uh like
everything I buy I'll buy three packs
minimum because
there's so much variation in that stuff
um that you really need
you really need to dig through multiple
packs to find stuff that uh like to get
a really good idea of what's going on
there to you know and to figure out what
you're looking for
um are you either that or you're really
lucky
yeah but yeah I like the real Team
company I'm a big fan of those guys and
uh like all the guys in India the Indian
Land race guys I was just gonna ask you
beat me to it yeah
um we've got some stuff from them
through other people that other people
have sent us
um that we're going to be dipping into
at some point yeah
um and a lot of people like random
people uh contact us and uh
uh trade us stuff
uh yes like people from Angola you know
that have lived there just get a hold of
us see our stuff you know send us a
bunch of seeds to try and uh yeah like
lots of sharing back in the CW days you
know lots of sharing back then you know
yeah and lots and some of our friends uh
have been traveling around and now
bring back seeds like our one of our
friends
was in Kenya and he he took the last
plane out before they shut down uh like
the cover yeah after covid and he had a
bunch of seeds from he said yeah I got
some seeds from some Rasta
um in Kenya
yeah that's that's great to hear and I
think that that's sort of the way most
breeders I speak to get their seeds you
know it's sort of just like where you
can you mentioned the Angola and we
actually had a listener submitted
question and they were just curious they
said what's the difference between the
two different angolas you use I think
one's the number 13 one's the number A10
from memory
uh yeah uh well uh well smell and high
for one and uh varying rate of intersex
traits you know you want to explain how
they how how where they came from uh
yeah they they came from they were sent
to me from La Mano Negros collection his
wife Katarina
and it was given to him from a guy who
uh sailed ships up the coast to uh what
was the name of that Island
so like a sea captain from Capo Verde I
guess gave him the seeds and they were
sent out to us after he passed and um
and that guy was like getting seeds at
uh like uh um
places where they were like oil refined
yeah like a big oil refineries going up
and down the coast you know and just
collecting things that he had liked yeah
he wasn't like he was just buying he'd
buy weed and get the seeds from postal
ports you know so he wasn't like uh you
know in the bush so I'm playing all the
plants no no and uh most of it was like
garbage like a lot of it was garbage
very uh heavily intersex and uh the 13
was more Earth EP kind of smells I I
liked and very little in her sex and uh
the uh 18 was more of a citrus thing
like I had a higher Citrus like you get
that Citrus out of the 13 too but it's
like muted a bit it stands out a little
more in the 18 so yeah I just decided to
keep most of those smells around for
future
uh projects
yeah nice and like is there a certain
variety that the like the strength the
effect is similar to like you know if
you were to say like oh I feel like
super silver haze you'll like this
obviously super silver has bad example
but you know what I mean
um yeah like I put it in a category
called the spiritual eye
I guess not to get too like Wavy Gravy
or anything but uh different people have
different experiences with cannabis and
one of them is definitely spiritual I'd
say in the way you can connect to
yourself to that inner voice right kind
of thing and I'd say that those uh
angolas and like the Malawi's and the
stuff like that it seemed to have that
really uh up high that's introspective
and friendly you know not too racy
yeah we're always we're looking for
stuff that's not necessarily racy but
more like a creative high uh a creative
and like positive you know it opens up
your uh heart chakra kind of stuff
like your heart chakra and your throat
chakra and your
third eye chakra Etc
um
yeah beautiful I I've always felt like
they're a really underrepresented sort
of sativa most often sativa and I I like
I think I probably haven't thought about
this enough really but I always sort of
would tell my friends like I feel like
there's two types of sativas there's
like the the one that annihilates you
and makes you paranoid and just like oh
what am I doing and then there's like
the real clear-headed one that's sort of
more like what you're talking about
where it's like you're not riddled with
anxiety and you're like actually upbeat
and having a good time and feeling like
hey I'm really connecting with this
actually
um yeah definitely an underserved strain
in a sort of a type of strain in our
community I think
take turns the music up in my head like
those are the kinds of things I look
forward to you know the beat that's
going it kind of takes it
yeah I like to um I like to count the
the number of different uh ringing
sounds in my head
if you get more like more than two or
three different sounds you know you're
on to a good one yeah
that's interesting I mean
um I think Gabby just mentioned the
Malawi I mean I did want to ask you
about that quickly just because you
don't really see people outside of say
like yourself and maybe like ice or
canobiage and really playing around with
the Malawi where'd you get yours from
and how would you describe it to people
is it like a haze or more like a
different sort of sativa
there's the African yeah those Africans
they're not like long flowering sativa
types they're like in the shorter like
10-12 range you know uh so it's a bit
more manageable in terms of uh the
timely and uh yeah you can find some
really really interesting things in
there but you've got to look through a
bunch of seed and make some f2s but uh
to further answer your question oh yeah
we got the seed from uh lemono Negra
yeah yeah so the same stock is what
those guys use yeah
I would send a big package when after he
passed that his wife made up for me and
there's there there still is a bunch of
uh his old stuff in there you know we've
grown through quite a bit of it but uh
yeah he had a really good touch you know
in the hit with plants and uh yeah I
definitely respect his collection and
I'm glad that we can share some things
you know with the world
yeah nice okay so yeah it's up there
with that same proven sort of stock that
the other guys have played with
yeah there's um uh what was that guy the
the guy that was selling African seeds
out of the UK that passed away like
seven years ago
um afro Clips oh yeah yeah I feel good
he had in Malawi as well but I I haven't
uh experienced that and it's like it's
like all things um
when you get into those those types of
seeds you have to grow a bunch of them
or be lucky
to get the you know to get the really
experience what what it is you want to
experience you know to get to find the
really good Malawi or whatever yeah so
if you're like a cash proper this is
that's not the kind of thing you're
going to want to like enjoy it all but
you know if you're someone who loves
cannabis these are important lessons to
learn and important things to share and
pass on you know or do you
yeah definitely definitely
all right so
take me back guys what was we might have
to get two independent stories here what
was your first experience with cannabis
um well my first experience of wondering
what cannabis was was
um in the late 80s
um I was in something called the Navy
League Cadets
um which was like uh basically like Cub
Scouts with a navy theme
um and uh I was in uh the band and uh
one of the officers one day we're up
there about we're up there with the band
and he's for some reason he's talking
about hempro and he's and he said uh
yeah this hemp rope is uh
it's made of made from the same plant as
marijuana and then he had this really
goofy smile on his face when he said it
and my uh I was I'm I think I was like
10 or 11 years old and
um just the way like the way he said
this is like this is from the same plant
as marijuana and had this big smile on
my face I I knew there was something
something about that
um
but it wasn't it wasn't until
uh I was in my uh
like I'm I'm kind of late to the scene
um
yeah basically when I was around uh 19
or 20 is when I is when I finally smoked
it for the first time and and actually
the first few times I smoked it I was it
was um
it was probably just the particular type
of weed that it just was not you know it
wasn't that wasn't for me but um
uh once I S once I um
found
like I made a new friend
um who is a big pothead and uh
he properly introduced it introduced me
to it when I was about 21 in uh in
Vancouver when I when I moved there for
uh for the second time
so yeah
uh yeah okay well when I was younger I
lived in uh fishing Village on the east
coast and we would get uh bricks of hash
that would wash up on the shore or out
in from the fishing boat boats that from
Runners that would go by so we would go
up in our little camps in the woods and
get some hot knives going and we we do
these saltwater hash dabs right and uh
they were pretty gross now that I look
back on it and they used to call us
animals and stuff like that but I know
it was really fun and uh one of the
first weeds I ever really loved was um a
guy that was on my Island had been
growing for a long time and he had been
inbreeding this Maui Wowie that was
finishing and it would just get you
[ __ ] lit you know and uh
unfortunately you died in a car accident
and I never got to as I got older I
never got to get those seeds from them
but uh I grew with them a year or two
and learned some things and he he put me
on my way I think it was maybe 14 or 15.
but yeah I knew that weed would be a
part of my life you know like you have
the drinkers and the weeders and as soon
as you experience
um some of those uh awesome highs yeah I
knew it would be a part of my life
wow that's that's that's cool you got
that sort of mentoring so early on and I
think my new phrase is gonna be like
don't tell me you're heady unless you've
done a saltwater hot knife
that's great that's cool and it's one of
those ones where it's like
people will hear that in front of funny
but it's like it would have given you
this type of high that you just don't
experience anywhere else you know like
as well as the set and setting I'm sure
yeah yeah definitely and we were really
close to Montreal too so you you have a
lot of different Ashes coming like the
east coast of Canada it was all hash
right so guys would go to work in the
factories and they buy their quarter
ounce or half ounce of hash for the week
and mix it with their tobacco or
whatever you know weed wasn't really a
big thing on the East Coast like it was
on the west coast when I came to the
West Coast you know and that's changed
over the years now but that's just the
smuggling Roots I suppose yeah
yeah like hash's hash was traditionally
not very popular in western Canada
except for places that you couldn't get
good weed like I grew up in the Prairies
and uh
there was
like I never saw weed when I grew up I
only saw uh people doing hot knives
that was my only experience of like or I
I would sometimes I would smell people
smoking really rough uh joints on the
street like
and wondering what you know I was I
would smell that stuff and wondering
what the heck was going on there because
I didn't quite smell like a cigarette
but
I never like where I grew up
um I grew up with uh the uh motor like
the
um
muscle car crowd
and we weren't really big into smoking
weed
we were into uh heavy metal and uh
drinking booze more or less
and so I'd be interested to hear Siri
what was the moment that you realized
cannabis because it sounds like it
wasn't until a bit later on so what was
the the Eureka light bulb turning on
moment for you where you were like this
is what I gotta do
um
well initially it was just
I was working as a machinist so
um it was for me initially it was just
the Curiosity
um and uh I just started growing like my
first grow was under some step under
some stair like a stairwell
and I made my own
uh fluorescent uh fixture with like
six little two foot long fluorescent
bulbs
and I was like two foot by two foot
square and maybe like two foot tall you
know just
hardly any space
um so yeah I was just more I was more
Curious with uh like I I come from a a
line of farmers
um on my mom's side of the family so
I'm I'm kind of like a gardener farmer
by Nature so I was just curious about
growing it and the fact that you could
grow your own was pretty cool
um
but it wasn't really until
uh until maybe like 90 1998 I met a
friend of mine who was
I was going to
um school learning machine like uh tool
and die I was learning two on die uh the
trade and uh I ran like uh I was at the
school and they had this environmental
kind of like uh
one day environmental conference
and this one guy was there talking about
him
and uh
he just said like you know he had all
sorts of different things that you could
make out of him and things that were
made out of him and uh this kind of blew
my mind at that point I was like whoa
this is pretty wild like that was that
was that was a point where I was I
started um you know
thinking about how it could be a part of
my life basically
wow that's like that's like quite a
unique one like I think most people
including myself it's like after a
really good hit but you're at like a
fair or something that's pretty cool
um okay okay cool cool well we were
getting we were getting high the whole
time too but okay well that adds to it
that adds to it so what were some of the
first strains you guys were growing when
you started growing and was this at the
time when strains had names or it was
like just the kind or whatever
super sativa seed club like lots of that
stuff goes around yeah uh freeze land uh
the old old trees land with some of the
first stuff some of my buddies Maui
Wowie and uh like we would just order
whatever we could off Mark Emery site or
whoever's you know the Dutch scene the
gray area wherever you know uh yeah grew
everything just lots of different stuff
but that freezeland really finished
outdoor in the east coast so you'd see
that a lot a lot around yeah yeah scabby
grew up on the east coast and I grew up
on the west coast so our experiences are
a little different
um I got I actually got to be I actually
got to go into uh Mark Emery's uh little
grow shop and buy seeds so um
I knew all the varieties I was a bit of
a seed nerd at that time
but the first seeds that I grew were
sweet skunk from readership uh spicy
life seed company and they were very
different from the select cutting they
were
uh
very
a lot similar to a lot more similar to
grapefruit they were like Indica hybrids
more or less
so I think that um I think the mail that
got used in that cross looking back was
probably enough possibly an F1 or it had
variation in it
um and it was probably selected for
Indica traits but it's spat out a little
sativa fennel every so often because
like would I experi what I got out of it
was
uh very
um
thick kind of NL
uh like and I'll uh flavors
um
mixed with like Savory thick Canal
flavors mixed with uh very citrusy
grapefruit flavors
which is pretty different than what the
the
reader Steve Cutters like
and did you get the cutting like around
that time or it was much lighter you got
it and you were like oh this is pretty
different
yeah I didn't grow it until the cutting
until the early 2000s
uh okay I don't I don't think that that
cutting didn't uh merge till later right
no well yeah it was a later thing like I
think the I don't know if you told the
story pretty excuse told the story but I
think I uh something along the lines of
they they it's like they uh older like
it was some leftover stocks that they uh
Mark Emery yeah Mark Emery had that they
grew and found that particular cutting
in is there a story like one in 500 or
something but I don't know I've heard a
couple things that's best for Steve to
like billion on that yeah
uh yeah look I can't remember
specifically but um
um I'm sure it was a special plan
yeah that's it right yeah yeah uh the
cowboy maybe something like that if I
remember correctly I don't know it's
been a long time
yeah okay and as a follow-up for you
scabby I'd be interested to hear out of
all the sssc you grew which was the one
you missed the most
oh Jesus [ __ ] uh
honestly that trees land uh was some of
my favorite stuff ever because there was
uh fennels like I've tried fennels now
in the future like uh and uh they just
hit harder there was like something I
don't know what the [ __ ] happened but
something happened in their genetics
like the stuff I'm getting nowadays the
pink uh Pink freeze and stuff the all
the other cuts that are around they
don't hit quite as hard as that old
freeze land like it was a very narcotic
uh Buzz right and the weed was uh so
potent like it'd be drying in your house
and you like come out of here you know
you can't even stay in the house it
would make you sick right so uh yeah and
uh I don't know why it changed but
something definitely happened
and you grew a bunch of that right oh
yeah yeah for sure and we grew it in the
future too uh like in the future uh like
around 2003 and stuff we got a bunch of
uh M39 M36
uh M38
uh and uh it was uh reproduction stuff I
I bet but it was all very uniform and
the same but no real Punch Yeah the
original was probably an F1 yeah that's
that's probably what was happening and
uh like yeah that same time uh when we
first grew the uh
ah what was that one by Steve that was
so nice the first seed latiana
no uh
yeah yeah that first seeds of shishka
berry that we grew I it was just really
powerful and beautiful and everything I
ever tried after that it just didn't
didn't uh stand up to it but now that I
look back that's probably what it was
that's the F1 yeah
yeah I think that you have certainly
nailed that shishka bear one on the head
I think it was either Steve or DJ I
can't remember which one because we've
spoken to them both in the past and they
said that it was like the mail they used
it's going down and he like there are
like fans who can quote this male too
it's like
B150 something but it's got like a label
and people know it and it's like yeah it
made some incredible stuff it was like
that first shishka Berry as well as the
other stuff when they were doing that
when DJ and Steve were doing that work
together it's it's uh it's kind of
impressive I guess that like your
palette picked up on that on its own
well yeah that's one of the fun things
about wheat is we're uh bio essaying all
this stuff and we're building a little
computer in our brains you know and
that's the real fun thing to me like we
have all these uh THC limits and you
know this terpene and that turbine but
to me and I I think the funnest thing is
just building your own library in your
brain you know and the smells the
memories that the smells kick out you
know uh they take you back or in your
therapy in myotheric brain yeah
definitely
so moving forward what was the first
cross you guys made individually all
together but I also want to know tell me
about the cross was it intentional or
was it like a happy accident
uh I my Original Seed set I ever made
were actually just sweet scum captures
just the only reason I did it was to see
if I could do it
and I actually I don't and I grew I
agree actually grew some out but
I like I don't even remember I don't
even know because I was so inexperienced
at the time like
some of the stuff I was doing I was just
I would laugh at I would laugh my ass
off with some of the [ __ ] I was doing
back there
but I mean I was only uh 20 years old or
whatever 21 or whatever
um
and I I was uh I kept to myself so I
wasn't um
like I wasn't in the scene learning uh
cannabis uh cultivation techniques from
other guys that could have taught me
some good [ __ ] I was like uh just
reading gardening books
because I wasn't I wasn't that serious
about it at that point but I was um
yeah it was just a curiosity for me
uh some of the first ones for me excuse
me uh would be like uh unintentional
stuff almost we were doing a lot of
Gorilla growing at the time I was in the
wilderness and uh like uh it was very
cold back there so I would come back in
the springtime and oh my God I had some
seeds that were growing up you know from
the old holes or whatever right those
were some of the first crosses so they
were like inbred Maui Wowie things that
had been inbred for shortness over and
over and over again in the in that
season to get something to work uh yeah
nice nice and as a follow-up what was
the first cross you did where as like I
guess it's what was the cross you did
where you looked at the end results and
you were like this is really good like I
need to sell this and like was that the
first cross you brought to Market or was
it just what
it was great it was it we came through a
weird time like with prohibition and
stuff you know we it was like a war zone
right like people were getting arrested
everywhere and going to jail and
um it was just fun to make seeds and
share seeds and get it out there and you
know stick one up to the man kind of
thing but uh
I think it just grows into a lifestyle
the more you do it in your aptitude for
it like you know he's really into
gardening and stuff like that so it's
just it's kind of a natural thing that
comes about I think for both of us
really
yeah I don't even remember like I can't
even honestly answer that question to be
honest because I I was young and I was
just so uh
so stoned like when anything anything
that I can think about related to
cannabis I was just so stoned at that
time
like
um there's such a difference between
um the reasons I was smoking weed for
back then and like my experiences of it
back then and uh and now I'm like or you
know in the present uh era so
um
yeah I was just uh just doing like this
making a bunch of random stuff
um but yeah when
um when I started working with uh when I
worked with reefer Mountain that's when
uh like I made a whole bunch of crosses
and invariably some of that stuff worked
out even though I was you know still
not really really understanding what I
was doing learning on the job kind of
thing
we've heard many people get such work
experience and I'd be interested to
delve into that a little more like I
know that you got your start with uh
sort of the prairie fire and reefer man
days
what what sort of genetics were you
working where then
um as you sort of just alluded to were
you aware of sort of the popularity the
work was going to go on to receive or
was it all quite a surprise to you
uh well I didn't like I didn't really
know like reeferment or a reefer man
um I just met him randomly
I was living on the Sunshine Coast
um yeah and I just met him one day and
he's
we clicked and uh he said come work with
me and uh
the rest is history
and I just uh I was just a guy and I
knew a little bit about growing weed and
making seeds um
enough to get by and uh
he basically you know set the agenda
like uh you know like I you know I I
hadn't I was not part of that world of
making seeds and selling seeds
so yeah I just uh just learned about all
that stuff on the job and uh you know
figure things out uh just through trial
and error
um and eventually I'm you know we would
get feedback uh like from the seeds and
somewhat of a good idea of what worked
and what didn't work
but uh I didn't get to grow old
you know all that stuff so I don't know
exactly what worked what didn't but you
can like get an idea of some stuff that
works because people are still growing
it so
you know some things I know are good
so what sort of parents were you working
with and did any of them leave a lasting
impression on you or you were like oh
you know that tie was really good
um he had a
he had his own seeds and he had some
seeds from
Steve tuck
um hair wall the harijuana guy yeah he
got a he traded a bunch of seeds with
Steve tuck so he had some cool things
from him he got like Nepalese and uh a
bunch of random he had a bunch of random
ibls he had like pass plants uh Steve
tuck that he traded with us um the
jackassani
Uzbekistan
there's like four of those uh Middle
Eastern house plants so I got to grow
some of those
um I mean a lot of it was uh he was uh
more
commercially oriented like uh like cash
pawns and stuff so like that era
for me the like the early BC days was uh
it was all about commercial plants like
wood plants
look good in a bag uh smell good in a
bag and uh yield really big
that was that was basically the
like a lot of the plants that were
mass produced at that time
um
there was a plant called Romulan or like
uh Joe Romulan that people are familiar
with uh Tom
that uh it uh it's not around anymore
because it was not a fun plant to grow
and it was
it made a lot of small buds
like it was like a like a sativa frame
uh with in the little Indica buds on it
so it probably was pain in the ass to
trim
um and probably not
they're probably just not a good sea of
green plant I imagine based on the
description that I've heard of it
um but yeah it wasn't like like you see
a lot of uh Romulan stuff around and um
her friends I grew Romulan say that uh
like none of that stuff looks like the
original rum like the original Ramen
that they grew back then was um
Little Rock rock hard buds that didn't
get uh any bigger than uh than a like a
jawbreaker like really small round Buds
and I remember getting the uh like we
bought some
some jars from Joe when he was bringing
them into Vancouver and they came in
half size jars what we call salmon jars
the ounces came in house sorry Stars
so it was super dense
it's like uh
form cookies you can get it pretty dense
too like it'll fit in a smaller jar
um
so yeah it was really raw card stuff but
um where am I going with this it's about
like Pine
yeah Pine and uh meat really meaty yeah
and kind of like uh
Curry uh lemon Curry
um sounds delicious yeah it was really
nice really nice read
yeah I never got to try it so I'm a
little bit jealous right
I'm there with you man I didn't get to
try it either but there's so many things
we're gonna have to loop back on but
seeing as we're talking about Romulan
let's let's smash a few out of the park
do you have any idea or just any general
guesses as to what the genetics are you
know it's one that's so up in the air
and I just I don't think like there's a
lot of things we don't know about right
like chem dog and OG but like a lot of
those things we have an idea but with
Romulan I'm like I just don't know
I think that's one that uh the story
went to bed with uh the last like the
people that have passed away yeah kinda
I think so too because it seems like
there's a lot like we've seen a lot of
weird stories
um come out of stuff that we know the
real story of so it's one of those
things where the story is so ridiculous
that I just don't believe it you know
like I don't I'm highly skeptical of the
different stories out there so I think
uh what is it Leafly says that Romulan
is derived from a Korean land rice yeah
it could be but uh like big big uh Big
Stone big Korean skunk no I know it's
like Korean and then they they added in
Colombia yeah yeah that's right way back
in the 60s yeah okay yeah and then they
added in well that's the story it
started off with Korean and Thai and
Colombian or something like that every
so often they would add in some stuff
that was coming around that was good
right yeah and then they added in uh uh
Afghani in the story
um and then they didn't no no that's not
the end no they didn't like the
direction oh yeah that's right yeah so
they added in more Colombian or
something that's right yeah but yeah
apparently it came from Romulan
according to the story we heard from
Ernie raised yourself came from a hydro
store yeah foreign
it came from the original hydro store on
Vancouver Island in uh well it was one
of the original early hydro stores in
Port Alberni and so I don't know who
called it Romulan but it was a plant
that was circulating in that that
Community which is uh
it's on the west coast of Vancouver
Island so most of the population of
Vancouver Island lives on the East Coast
so I guess it's a little bit uh off the
Beaten Track Joe would have been working
at this Hydro shop at that time is that
right yeah yeah so do you think the
people who had Romulan back in the day
did have the real Romulan oh yeah yeah
yeah yeah definitely I talked to Robbie
about it uh a vision Creator uh he grew
lots of it when he was living down there
in the city in the early days you know
he had a couple houses of it and uh they
had cut houses it was one of the major
cuts at that time that was circulated
and it just kind of disappeared it's
like the era of pink Kush it's
disappearing in front of our feet right
now right it just happens people get
bored and move on with stuff right
better stuff yeah like there was uh in
back in those days there's eras based on
the predominant cuttings yeah that were
circulating
it was the cuttings that the cutting uh
houses were choosing to propagate and
sell that determine what was ultimately
ending up in the market yeah definitely
because yeah the cutting those cutting
houses were rocking up
that's interesting and and like I mean
you often hear a lot of people talk
about the cuts in circulation at the
moment not being real and I guess let's
put that aside for the moment and
instead talk about how there's like
these alternative lines like I think
like famously there was Federation seeds
which crossed like white rhino and then
did like this whole BX thing on it have
you ever tried those alternative Romulan
cuts that like aren't the real ones but
are still out there oh yeah yeah do you
think do you think they're good or
they're not like it's not the same
they're okay but it's not it's totally
not the same yeah they're okay but
totally not the same for sure yeah like
the Romulan I mean what I could believe
about the Romulan story is that it was
there was a crew of guys that were
not had seeds like back in those days
you know you gotta imagine that just to
be able to get seeds that were like were
something worth you know possibly worth
growing those would have been like
hugely valuable
at the time so yeah there was seeds that
would have come from Oregon and
California
um
I made it up to Vancouver Island it was
a lot of um Americans in BC back in
those days so draft Dodgers yeah so I
could see that part of the story where
there was guys mixing up genetics trying
to find some stuff that would work
um but yeah I don't know about the
validity of uh but yeah okay to
to uh elaborate more on those new
romulans
um
there's a cutting that's circulating as
a 7 79 Romulan
um we've kind of figured out just by
looking back and you can look at on
archive
.org Emery seeds.com
if you go back into next Generation in
whatever whatever year like 2000 early
2000s
um they had a Romulan seven of nine so
that was
I think it was uh like I can't remember
the description but it was like a
seven times black cross or something
yeah something like that yeah
so that's just an example of how like uh
stories can kind of get out of whack you
know like they're
they're just cutting being circulated as
as 79 Romulan but it's actually seven of
nine see how it got misplayed right all
of a sudden now it's pre-98 right but
it's just it was seven of nine uh just
the word playing telephone how it works
right
yeah definitely look it sounds quite
plausible I'd be interested to hear have
you tried any of the other related cuts
to sort of Romulan like these are just
some fan submitted ones so like the
Alberni Pine bud or the Romney yep yep
do they stand up to Romulan or not
really no no it's like we were always
like looking for that [ __ ] whacker
and uh yeah there's a uh there's a
cutting I got from an old-timer friend
of mine that came from Salt Spring
Island um but it turns out it was one of
those uh Next Generation or Federation
seed line uh cuttings that they just
selected out but they've been growing
for years and years but it wasn't the
same like this the cutting height the
um Salt Spring Brown million cut that I
grew um it was very uh single Cola
dominant whereas like the original this
supposedly uh lots of bugs like yeah
like a big mess of branches and buds
little buds popcorny maybe what's that a
word well they're not really popcorn
because they were yeah yeah hard yeah
yeah okay and I just want to loop back
you were talking earlier about some hash
plants and we we got a number of really
good questions from some of our
listeners and one of them sort of asked
uh that specifically there's like a
number of the BC hash plants and cushes
that were associated with facilities on
the Vancouver Island back in like the
late 90s uh sorry late 80s early 90s and
the Rumor was that like they came from
seed that was brought in with hash like
maybe like King hash or queen or
champagne or something notably White
Buffalo has worked with most of if not
all of them do you know the back story
on any of these cushes or hash plants
um and do you think they stand up to the
stuff we see today
oh yeah they're good
um do I know the story about them no I
don't know the story about them I just
know that they uh came out of the the uh
motorcycle guy motorcycle club breeding
Collective
um
like Nanaimo the Nanaimo motorcycle club
they were the predominant importers of
of uh of Central Asian Ash in Canada
probably in like possibly in North
America at that time
so yeah there's probably more Afghani
coming through the west coast and the
East Coast right yeah definitely yeah in
that way yeah so those I mean I could
believe it like apparently they pulled
seeds out of uh blocks and past was the
story but I don't know about that like I
don't know if I believe those stories
just because I um some of those seem
like poly hybrids to me so I don't I
don't know if I believe this story
they're just they're pretty nice so I
would tend to like my in my mind
um if I didn't know anything about it I
would say they're probably like a lot of
stuff in like uh early Canadian stuff
was
that
um that early Canadian stuff came out of
was from Holland hauling seats I think
my favorite like cushy thing from back
then is like the Special K that's
probably one of my favorites that stood
the test of time but that's that's even
later than that yeah yeah that's even
later than that stuff definitely yeah
but uh yeah so those
when I was working with reefer Mountain
he got three hash plant cuts
and uh two of them were related one was
called it was called Purple King
and then he uh like renamed it to Pink
Kush because it had nice pink stigmas
and the other one was called they just
called it the king and
like at that time I just knew their you
know they're related possibly related
because they're both named King yeah but
then we we've done a bunch of breeding
with them over the years so we've hit
them with all sorts of things and grown
out the progeny
um and actually just by uh like growing
out this stuff I would tend to think
that they're not land racy things
because
the stuff that comes out of them is
really like uh it seemed like they're
poly hybrids yeah they're less than of
the whole some of the whole a lot of the
time right and uh yeah
but they're really the the thing about
them is they make really awesome uh
bubble hash bubble hash yeah definitely
they definitely there's something
special about those two plants
that they make a type of hash that you
very rarely see in commercial or like in
any weed plants that when you go to push
the house together it doesn't stick
together it pushes apart yeah weird dry
Chrome yeah almost like there's like
static when you apply pressure and it
just pushes it apart or something that's
really interesting yeah it's like
they're really hard to push into uh when
they're when they're really fresh like
when you're um you know not cured or
anything
um they're kind of like just the Terps I
guess or whatever compounds are in there
but um they're really um it's really
really nice hash uh yeah like the the
flower is not like uber potent or
anything but the hash is really nice
candy yeah yeah those two particular
plants the king and the pinkish yeah
look that's great because as you might
have imagined we got a number of
questions from the fans about the pink
cush because you know like it's so
prevalent and popular over the past you
know decade or two and yet there also is
so much sort of mystery around it just
to confirm are you saying that um pink
Kush comes from a cutting that was
originally called King and then he
renamed it to Pink Kush and then there
was another cutting and he called that
King thereafter
well no it's what they were they were
called they were already called Purple
King and
the king
um but my friend I haven't like I met
another friend later on who was growing
those
and uh
he called them
purple king and you said the other one
was white king or green King so they
were just calling them but um I mean it
was just you know
they were I think they were probably
selling most of it as king you know
whether it's purple or green you know
you'd be like oh I got a bag of King and
it's like oh did you get the purple king
or the green King I think that's how it
went down if I had to guess okay but
yeah those those particular cuttings
were really
um tightly held for the longest time and
so when reefer man got him he was
probably one of the first guys outside
of the circle to actually get them
and like my friend that I met later he
was also one of those guys that he said
he would have got in trouble if somebody
you know the wrong person found out that
he was growing up
wow very tightly held yeah
oh yeah yeah yeah this is like tight
tighter than tight
there you go and like if you had to
guess the genetics you said you think
it's a polyhybrid of some sort do you
think it's hash plant cross something or
it's probably like uh if I had to guess
um and like like I said before I have no
idea but
in my mind it would be a cross of maybe
it could be a old world uh hash plant
that they pulled that they pull out of
bricks that they were hitting it with
um seeds that they were getting from
home that would be my guess that they
got something like Afghani or like they
may have gotten some hash plant seeds
from Holland and mixed it with you know
what they were getting out of bricks or
maybe they got a bunch of different
plants out of bricks uh seeds out of
bricks and we're hitting like mixing
them up so I I mean I just can't say I
but I do think that it was a poly hybrid
that's basically all I'm trying to say
is I think it's
uh a poly hybrid or both of them are but
yeah after after doing a number of
different hybrids with those King
cuttings um
it would seem to us that the the green
King is the mother of the of the pincush
yeah
because when you hit the pink Kush you
get way more Thanos out of it and
they're like way all over like all over
the place like they're yelling it's like
a really good
um it's a really good plant for finding
uh wild stuff because uh like it spits
out stuff that you wouldn't predict and
come out of there yay but on the other
like on the other side of things it's I
would think it would be a really hard
plant to Ingrid to try and like uh
capture you know what it uh what the
cuttings like
unless you're like uh feminized it
to try and make a seed line out of it I
think would be fairly challenging very
yeah
okay and out of curiosity do you think
it stands up to the stuff today and if
so why do you think it's sort of falling
off in popularity
um well this is stuff for today yeah it
is big and it's hard to grow too I mean
it's not the easiest [ __ ] to grow yeah
King Kush is the number one Aunt uh
grown in Canada right now I would say
yeah definitely I can't think of
anything else maybe GMO is probably
um
but yeah pinkish seems to be like at
least here where we are where we are it
rules the market yeah where we are it's
just it's all pink Kush like literally
nine out of 10 people are growing fish
uh in the whole west coast of BC
seriously
so just to clarify you think like it's
sort of still on the uptrend or like or
at least it's not falling off at all
oh no it's filling off the cliff and
it's like doing a 9 000 foot uh free
fall into hell right now as we speak
yeah it's it's its errors done it's over
yeah it's like sticker fork and it is
hopefully this fall we'll see something
pop up and you know we'll see this kind
of yeah there's definitely like uh I
think the next trend is going to be some
uh flavor a bunch of flavor weed
um but I think uh I think we're gonna
see a bunch of different stuff instead
of one you know instead of pink Kush
dominating I think we're gonna see a
bunch of weird stuff
um because like all the guys out here
growing it uh
they now have uh Pink Kush uh PTSD so
for sure the blue dream of Canada well
it's just been overgrown and they
uh the combination between
the last six months in the last six
months the Canadian legal Flower Mart
like the Canadian legal cannabis Market
has flatlined the sales have not
increased
um so those guys are dropping all their
prices so they're like
there's like a huge War basically
between commercial legal weed and
Commercial black marketweed so
basically uh at the end of the day
um there's too much pink Kush
and uh the price has has to drop down to
nothing basically because there's no one
no one's buying it like they're like
yeah I got like you know the guys that
are buying already have what they have
you know they don't need anymore
and the guys that and Farmers being
Farmers
um
when the price of a crop goes down
double down yeah you got a double your
double your production and uh so we're
we're uh seeing that yeah we're gonna
have obviously that's not that situation
it's not gonna work out too well
and to add a curiosity do you think the
you mentioned like you know the next big
push will be like Fruity flavorful
strains any predictions at all do you
think it'll be something that jumps over
from California or maybe something
unique will come out of the Woodworks
um well in Canada a lot of guys
uh pull stuff out of random seeds stocks
um and a lot of it is just like uh you
know BX uh whatever or it's just you
know a lot of it is name cross name kind
of stuff um you know that's just uh it's
got the right names
um and they'll pull stuff out of that
um but definitely there's uh
ton of stuff coming up from the states
like we actually have
the amount of um Elite cuttings in
Canada is pro is pretty huge like it's
pretty impressive actually
um
so I'm just saying like I think uh
I think the fruity thing
is going to be the next thing just
because uh
it's you know that's the big Trend down
south so
um and we're already seen
um what guys are asking for and it's you
know it's
uh it's stuff that has uh you know like
Fruity
um
I call it like Flavor weed
I don't know how else to describe it
yeah no that works that works I
understand
let me take us back for a little bit to
those earlier days and uh we've got some
really cool fan submitted questions here
again and they just sort of asked you
know in the earlier days there was like
a number of seed companies that were all
operating out of the same post office on
Nana Mayo the normal is that how you say
it the normal Vancouver Island yeah was
there like much collegiality like
cooperation between the different groups
or was everyone just like keeping their
head down doing their own thing
um I would say everyone was fairly
independent back in those days and um
the fact they were using the same
mailbox just means that that was a
tolerant uh Meal box
it was the same thing in Vancouver
there's a mailbox by Emery seeds that
when the seed Market in Vancouver opened
up like they all got mailboxes at That
Money Mart
um
by Emery seeds
yeah okay so thinking like did the mile
staff ever say anything because like you
get like these hordes of a mile from all
over the world and like the volume of
packages you're sending
uh like I don't I don't know you know to
be honest I don't I just know they
tolerated it and
I mean I don't know like you can't uh
there's so much privacy with uh male
laws that uh I don't think it's really
up to the stuff you know to determine
yeah
um I think that's the jurisdiction of
like the Postal Service to determine if
there's something not you know not right
going on
um yeah now that makes sense yeah well
another question we got sort of around
that time was did any of the DEA raids
on Mark Emery or the general Crackdown
around that time ever affect you or get
you sort of concerned and as a follow-up
did it did it affect seed sales either
going up or down
well it definitely effective the seed
sales that he was generating
um well you know what though like
there was there was there was a ton of
other seed companies so
um the seed sales were just exploding at
that time you know whether you bought
from Mark Camry or kind seeds or a bunch
of the other ones there's a bunch of
them I can't remember them all but yeah
at that time there was
uh there's a place called the potluck in
Vancouver and uh
there's some buildings there that like
uh landlords that were tolerant
landlords and they would rent out to uh
various seed guys uh like uh smoking
Sean was one of them
grind seeds uh Legend seeds
Emery seeds of course a guy down around
the corner
yeah yeah
um there's a few others
uh Canada see Bay Canada Seed Bank of
Canada it was super sketchy
um but yeah those were the original seed
uh Canadian seed bank pioneers and there
was a few in uh the East Coast there was
the uh London seed bank yeah Chris Clay
you know
um
um Quebec seed bank yep
of course Heaven's uh Heaven Stairway
yeah
uh who else would be in there
uh
so yeah yeah interesting so this guy did
it spook you at all oh no
I mean uh like the main concern is uh
just being rated at your personal you
know grow or whatever
yeah I've been rated like three times
and through the uh through the whole
regular role right so
uh luckily we had excellent lawyers like
Kurt Tusa who stood up for lots of
Growers around this around the west
coast and you know helped pave the way
for the uh
mmar program and then the AC NPR on and
on we go
interesting interesting just to to Chuck
things over to an older strain I'd love
to grab some perspective on the Texada
time warps probably one of the most
widely dispersed outdoor genetics in
Canada and it originates from like you
know the VC Island do you think this is
probably the oldest Canadian clone going
around because I think it was it comes
from like the 70s or something doesn't
it
well there's some uh I mean there's
questions about anything that that's
that's that all there's questions about
um but I mean I've grown it since uh the
early 2000s so it's at least 20 years
old
um you know it's hard to say like some
of these cuttings
that people think I think people's uh
memory you know there's a little bit of
memory loss uh involved you know with a
lot of these cuttings they people think
that they're a lot older than they
actually are like uh
just because uh you know maybe
you know the people weren't they weren't
there and they you know they weren't
they weren't there when they're like it
emerged onto the scene and um
they don't really know you know like
just uh
we'll go back a little bit the guys at
that time on techseta uh they were
getting seeds sent up from Humboldt
County uh as well all over the hippie
hash Trail you know and um you had a lot
of people that were uh you know they
weren't uh Rich they uh barely had
electricity or if they had electricity
it was the house down the road that they
used once a week or something you know
so when that in that time frame I think
a lot of uh those things are mixing and
there was a fella on the island that
made some seeds Mr Lambert and passed
the move to uh the the community and
they kept looking for the fastest
finishers right uh every year and I
think in four or five years that
something like the time warp came up is
the story I've heard and uh in the late
70s in the late 70s around 79 and those
guys didn't even have electricity they
went to their parents house and put a
fluorescent light you know in the closet
and took a cutting and revedged it kind
of thing and yeah they had to learn
about uh re-veging and cloning yeah that
was like all new and like light like
what's the kind of light you use to grow
a plant indoors to keep it alive over
the winter and over the years you know
we've seen it really take a beating in
terms of uh like how it grows you know
it's become powdery mildew susceptible
that thing powdery mildew wasn't even
the thing when we were like young you
know you never saw it ever around right
so how the [ __ ] would that plan even
know right but uh
yeah it's it's an interesting story
right and the like I personally I assume
it's an old plant just because back in
the day the old time the old timers um
held it with you know quite a bit of
irreverence so I assume it was
I assume it's like maybe 30 years old at
least maybe
um I know the guy that I got it from
um his son he had had it the whole time
his son was alive and his son died at
the age of 20. so I mean it's at least
20 years tagged on to what we've got
yeah I mean theoretically it could um
could be from 1978 but I you know like
maybe there's something added on in the
in the early in the 80s or whatever that
we don't know about yeah there was like
a lot of Camaro driving people back then
and uh like one thing they like to do is
they'll uh like I've been around here a
long time and they'll take genetics like
Time Warp Indica A3 but they'll just
call it Time Warp and they'll give you a
cut okay Yep this is my time workout you
know but uh when you go and sit down and
smoke with them they're like no that's
the mighty might Afghan Time Warp Indica
A5 A3 blah blah blah you know it's got
all this [ __ ] in it that they cross
together every year to get something out
of the season right so I think you know
there's could be a little bit of that
that play too but yeah there's so many
there's so many uh Cuts over the years
that people have called Time Warp that
they have been handed around that word
yeah it's the same thing with Romulan I
bet you there's like 50 Romulan cuts out
there
but the one we have is the original one
that all the old people grew and uh yeah
verify so and it's good it's good we eat
yeah yeah so we we think it's you know
it's it's good enough to keep around for
however long experience I mean it's got
really cool qualities too like the uh
the way it flowers and passes on those
flowering genetics to other plants yeah
it's got uh it's got Autoflower in it
so it it's it has Autoflower in its
genetics but as a plant it's a semi-auto
plant yes so when it gets root bound it
starts burn generally
what do you think the genetics are
because it's obviously a sativa right
you know the closest thing I've seen is
uh something called Nigerian Nightmare
that kind of reminds me of it which is
like a Nigerian hybrid
um
it's it kind of seems like it could be
something like there's some uh African
or Southeast Asian or who knows like
some sativa that's reasonably fast you
know in in there that would be my guess
that there's it's a mix of uh
something semi like something
autoflowering that they mixed with
something
um with maybe a little bit of Afghani
but maybe not not a whole lot yeah
because uh like that in those days
Afghani wasn't even really like not a
thing yeah it wasn't even really a thing
until the 80s and uh I like when I grow
it inside I see like a a plant that's
Southeast Asian and Thai like you know
and when it gets into the sun it gets
more of the hashiness of like something
you find in the Middle East come out
kind of a little bit
um but uh we sent it into what the [ __ ]
was that company called again silos
nothing banged up on the family meter I
don't think did it no it's there's
nothing related nothing related to it I
mean you hear the the guys who were
running around the house Trail you like
uh you hear yeah it could be like a
Nepalese Cross or something yeah yeah
something weird like that right uh one
of the cuts that came out of tuxedo was
A3 indica and it came out of hemp seed
you know people were throwing hemp seed
in there in their yard and it was a
plant that came up that ended up you
know getting grown for years and years
so
um had a really nice grape smell big
buds but it the weather was better back
then I think too we had longer longer
summers it's we've gotten more rain in
the balls easier so I think uh you gotta
keep up with the breeding right well I
think also um
plants are used to a specific time
period as crazy as this sounds
um they're used to their the environment
they were born in and obviously the
Earth is slightly it's more than
slightly different the Earth is
different they like the climate is
different from when it was back then so
there's a lot of different things that
have changed since those days so I don't
think like a plant is has evolved for a
specific time period and like we're way
past that time period so
it would make sense that that plant is
is not uh adapted for the conditions
right now
yeah I can get down with that and just
as one final question to sort of wrap up
on the time warp questions
I noticed you guys work with a plant
called Pine warp is that one that's just
in your opinion sort of like an
all-round improvement on the time warp
or is it different in sort of its own
thing
uh it's a commercial plant yeah it was
during the time when there was a lot of
outdoor growing going on on the coast
and they were looking for something that
was like
and uh just harder nugs that would uh
bigger nugs that would fill a bag faster
faster faster finishing the market was
changing yeah easier trimming for sure
more weight totally and uh it was across
the tree frog was it sister I think and
it was uh possibly a cream soda yeah it
reminds me of the cream soda uh times
the time or yeah that would be my guess
for sure that's what it is nobody will
tell you that but that's what it is
yeah cream sodaka was one of the
original building blocks back in the day
ah okay okay yeah there you go
yeah a friend of ours uh on the island
grew some uh some some of the mix that
came from hexada like from the Texada
crew and it was
um definitely had some cream sodica in
there
in my my guess I mean my my uh Theory or
whatever but yeah um the cream soda cup
it has like every when you cross it with
something it'll give you every single
color combination possible
so that's kind of why uh
um some of the stuff like uh Pine warp
and tree frog has got some cool colors
going on the original ones were like uh
baseball bats you know you could knock
your friend down
you know super thick and Hearty and uh
yeah the pine work was definitely an
improvement on that but the thing that
sucks about the pine warp is it has
those terpenes that don't hang around a
long time so when you get into a bag of
it you know two months down the road
you're like oh what is this you know
it's Gotta Go first right and that's the
way thing you know it was early so you
get a higher price for your weed uh if
it was in if like that three weeks
earlier than the market you know you get
a little bit of a bump so people were
always chasing that over the years right
yeah because there'd be a drought in
August yeah there wouldn't be any weed
around right we'd be out and those days
don't exist anymore yeah so it that was
part of like how they end or
um being involved is because there was a
stroke in August and uh to take
advantage of that you know you'd want to
run a indoor crop because like the
prices you could sell everything at the
highest price
it could be wet and you get like 3 600 a
pound wet American back there yeah
exactly so
interesting and another variety I wanted
to quickly ask a question about was I
noticed that you guys use a plant you
call the special Kush in the special
Kush Haze what's the backstory on that
kush
uh that one is actually related to the
Kings
the mother of special Kush is a plant
called Queen which is somehow related to
the Kings
um and crossed with an Afghani yeah the
it's called Queen Afghani and uh by
Vision Creator yeah and uh it's a really
good coach that's uh I mean we we smoke
all the American things that come up and
it really it is complex it hits hard and
it always has right yeah it stands up to
most anything Indica that you can grow
yeah for sure
I noticed on your site you've also
worked with an x18 plan and I wanted to
hear your thoughts on some of the
various Tom Hill lines you might have
worked with because I think you see a
lot of DC like deep chunk stuff around
but you really don't see much x18 or
like pine tar cush stuff what's your
thoughts on his lines
um they're very uh consistent yeah
um yeah
the pine I think the pine turn the x18
came from his father and there was those
who were his fathers the the chemist and
the Deep chunk was from Tom Hill if I
recall
the Deep chunk I mean the x18 out of
those three like I've grown all three
the x18 seems to have the most
um the best flavors
and uh
um
it seems to be the most commercial like
the better yield out of all of them and
more um
vigorous the most bigger like that was
the problem with the Deep chunk is it's
the ones I grew anyways were very
they're highly inbred so they're uh
very slow very slow vegging I think the
pink I I don't I can't really like I
can't remember the pine tar push but it
was very uh inbred too
um and you know interestingly enough the
pine Target you've ever grown it it's
one of the few plants that reminds me of
pinkish
your listeners wow that have grown my
entire requests it's fairly similar
but I I haven't grown it for a long time
so
um I don't really I can't really say
much about it but I can say that the
the
XT the x18 is really nice
um it's got a nice high it's not like
super potent
um but it's really like it's got a
pretty good quality
that's cool and did you ever see the I
always read about this fabled green
apple Fino have you ever come across
that in the x18
yeah there's lots of those green apple
and uh parrots and uh like uh
gin there's like gin in there
yeah they're pretty common actually
those spinos oh yum I gotta get into it
yeah
here's a random curveball question I've
got for you guys what are some of the
more rarer narrow Leaf varieties that
you think the general public are not
particularly aware of in terms of like
the quality of the effect or maybe the
unique nature of the effect are there
any things that you think are a bit
underrepresented
uh well I think Bruce to preface that
question we need to
we need to like look at
um the various lawn races what they are
is they've taken Regional seed stock and
applied a generic name to it so in truth
there's like
each one of those has infinite variate
versions of it with a general theme
within a general theme but um
as far as answering the question what
are some things that I think everything
like except for they're like the real
old timers
um I think everything's been you know
Miss been missing for a long time like
uh yeah I mean all that's you can find
good stuff anywhere in the tropics it's
just a matter of finding the guys that
kept the you know that knew how to
select uh good the good [ __ ] from the
bad [ __ ] if I can
it's a good flower from the hemp
yeah so like
you can cut the good [ __ ] can come from
anywhere in my in my mind yeah it's more
like a land Rave is that a land race in
my mind right
um yeah that's the that's the word I
like to use in my brain
yeah uh land race is kind of uh it's
kind of a a controversial term to use
do you mean like in the sense that it's
just like so widely misused uh well it
to me the word land race means
uh plants that are selected by the by
the land
um Without Really without human
intervention
um because when they're like the
Breeders the old school breeders when
they're breeding wheat or whatever they
would go out into the land and they
would get they would do their selections
from the land races yeah interesting so
what would you call like a strain from
like that a certain Afghan Village has
worked for you know however many years
historically I would call that a
uh heirloom or a regional cultivaria
cultivares meaning something that's
cultivated and they're like
intentionally selecting seed
yeah okay I mean it could it could have
it could have aspects of a lawn race
like the Palms coming over from the lab
so yeah it's basically heirloom I guess
yeah I mean
yeah in my mind right now I'm thinking
maybe that is an Elon race you know if
it's got Pawn coming over from the land
it's got the influence of land race
um
um but if they're like somehow
non-engine not to get cross-pollinated
uh from
the outside
um
like if you're let's say there's an area
uh of Afghanistan or Pakistan or
whatever where it's only just Farms
where they're it's like so dry that you
can only grow your
your weed plants in certain spots and
it's all being farmed yeah the nuts
that could be a bunch of different
heirlooms
um with some slight cross pollination
or maybe extreme amounts across
pollination yeah it's pretty interesting
to talk about though I mean to like to
think about yeah how far do you go I
mean
it's really funny though right yeah
um like I I find it interesting how uh
the terminology is constantly changing
like uh you know is this kind of a
sativa is this uh is this a narrow Leaf
drug cultivar it's hard to like it
there's a lot of uh you know different
changes in the
nomenclature that have happened a lot in
the recent history
yeah definitely and I was gonna even say
like I I agree with um many of the sort
of ideas you just put forward what I've
noticed is that people like to use the
term heirloom to I mean it's in in all
honesty if I'm going to be very
reductive it's probably just ultimately
a sales thing but people will use it to
describe like a clone that's been in a
certain area for a long time like and I
think when I asked someone about it I
can't remember who they said oh you know
if you've been growing it in that area
for 10 plus years it's acclimatized to
that environment and it's an heirloom
well heirloom is uh just means something
that's passed pass along like it came
from the errors it's a loom that came
from the errors the thread was woven by
the loom that came from The Heirs I like
it I like it um so I mean you can call
whatever you want heirloom if it came
from someone else I was hanging on to it
because it was good you know I mean in
my mind anyways that's what matters is
that the people are doing the things
that they like and keeping them from
generation to generation and year to
year you know yeah and I do believe that
clones can acclimatize because uh
every time you grow it
um the plant is always adopting them
where you select the actual the
the particular part of the plant where
you select your cuttings from will
actually have slight variations in
genetics
so
uh if you take a cut from the top of the
plant it'll be more it'll have more
silica
um dominance
to the top and the outside of the
branches is more silica dominant to the
bottom and the inside of the branches is
more calcium dominant so uh like the
north side of the plant will be
different from the the south side of the
plant for instance
um yeah there's slight very slight uh
differences in the genetics
that's really interesting stuff you
don't hear that talked about very much
while we're talking about slight
variations in genetics I I forgot to
bring it up earlier when we were talking
about the Iraqi f2s you did did you see
anything come out in the f2s that was
like recessive and not in the f1s or
were they like quote land race enough
that it was like largely speaking
homogeneous because the line was sort of
pure
uh no it wasn't pure at all it was just
uh we only did a it was a one-to-one
selection so it would have been those
two individual funds so you got to think
of that as a
uh the f2s were kind of like a hybrid
them
they're probably it's like probably more
like a hybrid like a F1 yeah um because
it's just it's just a [ __ ] mix you know
of Iraqi genetics so
um you know we're still it's gonna take
like there is all sorts of variations of
stuff in there
um so it's going to take a few more
generations to to uh you know get it
stabilized looking consistent
like some um
some interesting terms that are used in
uh reading terminology are um
stability
and consistency
and I like I like to think about these
things sometimes and to me stability
means
a plant that you can use for breeding
that the progeny are are not all over
the place
but a lot
a lot of people use the word stability
to mean plants that don't don't uh get
like term flowers
what would you call a plant that doesn't
produce hermaphrodite flowers
uh
uh true a true female straight yeah like
true female an arrow I don't know
it's interesting isn't it because like I
I have this discussion in one form or
another with lots of guests because
there's it's not just in this particular
example it's it's replete throughout all
of our nomenclature people misuse it and
I guess it sort of all boils down to
this issue of like you know because some
people like to be like oh an Indica is
actually is meant to mean Indian which
is sativa and you know like they they go
through that whole sort of thing and I
guess it sort of boils down to this idea
of we'll do do I use the technically
incorrect term because we both know what
we're talking about and it's like we're
we're talking we're trying to represent
that we're talking about the same idea
um it's interesting or or do we like
draw a line in the sand and say like we
have to like you know really get on top
of it
in what in my mind one of those terms is
an academic term and the other one's
like just a regular regular day language
yeah yeah do you like most donors they
don't really care about like narrow Leaf
drug called the bar you know broadly
drug cultivar they just want to know
does it have a cerebral effect or does
it have more of a relaxing body effect
you know so and so I think that uh I
mean that's ultimately the question
yeah that's definitely a hard question
like how do you uh amplify those
qualities that are important enough to
uh you know give it a name or give it a
category I guess yeah it's interesting
we'll see what we come up with lots of
people smoking weed now so
definitely and it's definitely something
that evolves over time
yeah but eventually they're um is
probably those terms are probably going
to be thrown up like completely they're
going to just uh
be extinct at some point
just because like it just it won't make
any sense at some point
um because everything's you know
everything's hybridized and
um
there's just so many variations that you
kind of just like slop a label like this
one's in a sensitiva
um
but I think you can definitely say like
this one's got more cerebral qualities
yeah that's the way I like to do it when
a bio was saying is like you know the
qualities that you like as a person how
does that reflect out in a plan you know
and um depends what kind of person you
are if you're creative you're mathematic
you're whatever you know
uh so like uh it's just uh yeah it'll be
interesting to see I [ __ ] lost myself
[Laughter]
yeah another thing about it is um sorry
um another thing about it is um with the
new all these like we've read out not us
per se but the community has spread out
all the alternative cannabinoids so as
we ReDiscover all those alternative
cannabinoids we're gonna have to come up
with the new definitions for things like
you know what is what does CBC bring to
the table what is uh um age
thcv like you know when we started
having more complex uh combinations like
thcv mixed with uh high THC with you
know if you had like the uh relaxing the
non-cerebral terpenes uh mixed with thcv
and high THC what's going to happen you
know like
um and then throw in some CBC like uh
like a big shot of CBC or something like
that you know
um we're going to be moving into
Uncharted Territory territory
like we're only dealing with two
cannabinoids right now or you know for
the most part
yeah look it's it's gonna be wild and
wonderful and we've had a range of
different uh
predictions in the past including um
people won't even be smoking weed in the
future it'll be all produced by yeast
and it'll just be like kind of annoyed
in a few beers and that's all we'll do
so it's some interesting uh ideas for
the future I just wanted to quickly
bring us back though to the Past for a
moment well it's the present but it's
also the past I know that in the past
you guys had um ran some ads in high
times and I was interested to hear like
what's your thoughts on High Times Now
versus in the past and specifically do
you think it has any sort of real value
at at this point
um I don't think it'd add much value
um yeah you know other than uh
it was something for people to you know
get stoned and look at right or just it
was just something in culture to bring
the Cannabis culture bringing that
question into the mind it's like uh to
me it's like uh
national no it's a National Enquirer the
the
news the newspapers you see at the at
the grocery store in the lineup you know
like uh with like uh Kanye West did this
and
Etc you know it's it's a it's a it's a
it was a delivery vehicle for
advertising like let's be uh let's be
straight yeah
yeah sure okay and I think it was uh
yeah like it was started by uh law types
or something like like they knew the
laws and [ __ ] so they they knew what
they could get away with but it's cool
yeah it's cool like it was
for it's cool for what what it did like
break ground and you know like get the
cannabis in the general Consciousness
um
as far as like
the quality of what it was
um maybe not
and there you have it gang what a Killer
part one huge shout out to see Ray and
scabby for joining us and a huge shout
out to you for getting to the end of
this episode
make sure you check back in for part two
it'll be up shortly
make sure you also check out our
sponsors seats here now best seed bank
in the industry you know you love them
they got the best breeders check them
out
corporate biological systems all the
best predators in the game beneficial
feeds to keep the good mites Happy who
will in turn take care of the bad Minds
get on top of the guys after param
spider vital two killer products from a
killer company
[Music]
top shelf seed bank organic gardening
Solutions homies down under check them
out guys I promise you will get killer
results if you use their products
and one final word for the patreon you
guys know I love you please check it out
we're now doing monthly giveaways on
genetics
we give away seeds every month how crazy
is that
crickets and cicada trichome junglers
heavy days genetics
plenty more to come
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
I'll see you for the next one
[Music]
foreign