[Music]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts
this episode as always is brought to you
by our amazing sponsors
seeds here now your number one seed bank
in the game
check them out not just for guarantee on
germination but also satisfaction
why would you mess with anywhere else
they only stock the best
[Music]
also 420 australia your number one store
for 420 lifestyle and apparel
and finally
our big thank you to organic gardening
solutions your number one stop for all
your organic garden needs
as always big shout out to our friends
at dragonfly earth medicine and to the
patreon gang you guys help make this
show happen we love you so much
on this episode we're joined by our
friend from europe karma to answer all
those questions about ogs sours
and the old school dutch
genetics stick around guys this one's a
good one
let's get into it
[Music]
alrighty so a big thank you and welcome
to
the one and only the og master himself
karma thanks so much for joining us
today
hello
good to be here
so the first thing i wanted to ask you
what are you currently smoking on
um i'm smoking on some sour mamba at the
moment
ah what's that one again
that's a
mamba cut
times a sour diesel
okay and
how do you find that one more sativa
more indica
and this fino is a bit more on this sour
side but it's it's like typical hybrid
weed
yeah i wouldn't call it sativa even
though it flowers a bit longer it's a
bit looser in butt structure
okay and overall would you describe
yourself as more of an indica or a
sativa guy
no i really smoke
the whole spectrum
but um
like
depends on what i'm doing
like for every occasion yeah there is
like a different weed
um
so i i do like smoked sativas i smoke
sativas more during the day or when i'm
um going into nature
when i'm doing uh artwork things like
that then i like smoking sativas um
in the end of the day in the evenings
and stuff yeah then i'm uh i'm all about
ogs and heavy indicas
yes i can very much relate on that point
so
take us back what was your first
experience with cannabis
um
well um well let me start off with uh um
i'm dutch
um i was born in the 70s um
so yeah when i was like pretty young um
it was pretty accepted in holland
so i smoked my first joint when i was
like 13.
it was moroccan hashish ah hell yeah
because the
in those days there wasn't even that
much wheat here yet even
there was like jamaican
and thai weed
a little bit of the first dutch type
growing weed yeah which was
not that impressive to be honest
um
so yeah most people smoke moroccan hash
in those days so
yeah i got a little piece of moroccan
hash and
it's right smoking it
and was it in a joint or just through
like a pipe or something
no it was in a joint with um
uh dutch tobacco and uh
oh yeah it was it wasn't that good to be
honest either yeah i had to cough a lot
because i didn't i never smoked anything
before that
so did you get high the first time you
smoked
yeah you know i didn't get high
i did get high
but i was really nauseous as well i
think from smoking tobacco first time
yeah definitely it's it's interesting
how interlinked tobacco and hash are
within the netherlands scene is that a
trend you continued to do as you kept
smoking
uh no i smoke my wheat pure now these
days i still smoke um
like a moroccan and nepalese hashish i
do smoke dead with tobacco
i smell wheat pure because tobacco like
[ __ ] it ruins the whole flavor of it
i think yeah um
so i always smoke weed pure
i smoke mostly bongs
not so much
weed in
in in joints
ah you're a man after my own heart we
need to have a session hitting all the
points that i do
so
so what i found very interesting is my
first ever weed experience i think it
was
2009 2010 i went to holland and i tried
weed and this was before i was really
into weeds seriously so
i
well it was just when i was starting so
i don't remember too much like sadly you
know i didn't try all the different
strains all that type of thing but i
remember trying the hash and i tried it
with tobacco and there's this undeniable
actually i say kind of romance within
like when you mix tobacco and hash and
though i'm pretty strictly anti-tobacco
i'll i'll ge i'll let people off if
they're smoking hash with tobacco why do
you think it blends together so well
[Music]
in the in the dutch culture yeah um
the first hashish that came here came
from
morocco and nepal and afghanistan
there they all smoke it with tobacco
yeah
so
i think that has to do with it what
started it off yeah um
these days people here they're
it's just how they're used to it as well
yeah so there's not much people that
smoke pure wheat here even
most people here still smoke with
tobacco and that counts for a big part
of europe as well
last years it starts to change a little
bit but
yeah okay
so i mean bodhi raised this point many
many moons ago the the art of you know
mixing
or blending different herbs together
hasn't really been explored too much
especially outside of amsterdam if you
rule out hash do you think there's
something more there that we could learn
kind of in the way that concentrates
evolved or do you think it's kind of
limited
i definitely think
different herbs in combination with
cannabis can give different effects
because um
i mean
the tobacco even when you smoke weed
with tobacco yeah it makes feel
you get a very different high than when
you smoke wheat pure yeah it's very
different like the moroccans used to say
that
by if you wouldn't mix tobacco with it
yeah you would fly away yeah they say
that it keeps you on the earth
i like that that's a cool idea
so what type of hash is your favorite
then
um
i would prefer like high quality
nepalese
but that's very rare these days uh also
here
um
but moroccan i still smoke mostly uh
moroccan um i'm very picky though so
from what's here i probably can only
smoke like the f top five percent
yeah no i think a lot of people can
relate to that point even if it just
came down to flower but i guess i'd love
to know from you what are your top picks
for the coffee shops in amsterdam or do
you just not even go to them
um these days i almost don't go to them
anymore but
for good hashies
and
nice hazes
most of the time
it's the old damn crane on the hanbok
strat
that's a great coffee shop yeah very
fair price
the names are real
you get really what's [ __ ] on the
menu
um
who else um if you like all the modern
stuff um one of my young friends he does
the plug he has all the modern
new stuff that all the
younger people like
um
well good voyager voyagers really really
nice people they have a smaller menu but
it's it's always nice they care a lot
for what they put on
those three shops are probably
good ones to visit if you go to
amsterdam at the moment
yeah solid advice i mean the uh i can
never say it right is it the damp king
damp damp king whatever i'll just
probably cut cut and paste your one in
it's the
dump king
that's what they say in dutch yeah okay
yeah i hear about that all the time
it's a smoke circle it's kind of if you
translate it yeah
ah okay yeah it makes sense makes sense
how do you think they they became like
the cream of the crop because everyone
talks about them
well they always been
very good yeah um
and now a friend of mine runs
uh the old dank ring and he's just a guy
that cares a lot about all of it yeah
he cares a lot about of it um he's been
in it really long yeah um
he has
a great network he just he's very honest
and he cares about it yeah so um
he's willing to pay a bit more when it's
really good um
and he just he's just a fair
a fair guy yeah um which for a lot of
the amsterdam coffee shops they're so
commercial now yeah um
so they'll put on names um
all kinds of stuff yeah um
this is still like an old style fair
honest
menu and and also um the good people
running it yeah
yeah that's really good to hear that
there are a few shops who are still
embodying those good traits so
i'd love if you could just take me back
for a minute what was it like through
you know kind of that renaissance of the
cannabis scene probably you know late
80s early 90s when all of the big dutch
companies were still in existence like
you know neville was kind of there doing
his thing and all the rest were you a
part of the scene back then
now i started um growing in the late 80s
early 90s yeah
and those first times were just like a
few plants outdoor and stuff i was still
pretty young at that time
but from the 95 i really
really started to kick it in yeah um
well the fun thing is like these days
here it's not as free as it used to be
um i remember back in the day i could
have like cannabis plants in the front
of my house yeah and i was living behind
the police station and there was never a
problem
um now you can't do anything like that
yeah
that's definitely not possible
yeah okay
and so was there like good quality
genetics floating around at that time or
it was still a bit limited
no i think that um
until early 2000s um there was quite a
lot of diversity yeah and that's because
um there was a lot of small growers
um
uh
like um
moms
uh people that only live in like a small
house do a little bedroom yeah so you
get a lot of people that are like home
growers that do like small rooms um so
you have a lot of diversity and also a
lot of quality yeah
then they changed the rule here that
they could kick you out of your house
and then all these small ones kind of
stopped yeah which was in early 2000s
um and that really changed it yeah so i
think there was more diversity um before
2005 than after then it started to go
down
and what were the first strains that you
were growing
my first things were
viking
early girl
silver pearl
those were some of the first things i
grew
it's very interesting that you mentioned
viking because that's one which gets
thrown around a bit in australia is one
of the possible strains that's used for
the commercial cash cropping scene did
you get the impression that that's what
the strain really was
that was a
like a
pretty early finishing um outdoor
variety um
it was very wild so it's very it's very
leafy here um but it was very strong it
made it makes huge buds as well yeah it
did yield a lot and we grew it outdoor
that's what it was for here here at the
time
yeah i got it as a clone
interesting and so were clones passed
around rather freely back at that time
yeah it was it was even legal so you
even had ads in the newspaper and stuff
and so do you think that this may have
kind of led to people getting
questionable clients those days it was
not
that commercial
um
and it was still everybody that ran it
and they're like old hippies and the
hippie people and
you know so it was very different type
of scene in those days as well so no it
was all positive yeah
it was all positive
wow what a different world back then and
so
when was kind of the first time you
started to look at the idea of breeding
um
i
that was when i was working
in a coffee shop for a couple of years
and
the things you get offered um to buy
because that was my job i used to
um like stand at the back door as they
call it in holland
uh
well there wasn't that much diversity
yeah
um so and that that was because the grow
shops which is where the clones were
sold in those days yeah they only had
like two or three different things you
could pick from yeah so everybody in
that neighborhood would grow only those
two or three things
almost no one grow the dutch people
didn't grow with seeds a lot yeah
they all you they're so so spoiled by
having those clones from early on and
just getting them at the shop where they
needed to buy their light and everything
else as well yeah
so um
yeah so that's when i started to
like grow from seed and after i grew
from seeds then it went really fast yeah
then it went really fast
yeah definitely okay and so do you think
that having an environment where clones
are freely available does hamper people
popping new seeds and finding new
genetics and it kind of bottlenecks
things
it definitely makes that less seeds are
popped yeah so um
yeah
of course people are
lazy i guess yeah or they think it's
it's easier or they're scared for
germany if people never
grown from seed um there's a bit scared
for it as well yeah i can see that with
some of the dutch people that i know
people that growing for
many years and they've never germ to
seed
they're just scared of it
they're like oh no i heard about you can
get a mail or um you can get a
hermie yeah and then everything can be
full of seeds yeah so they're scared
yeah um
which
they should not be to be honest even
though i always advise people if they do
selections to do it separately from your
cash crops and
your income type things so
yeah i mean it raises an interesting
point
how do you feel about people who
live in say
countries where cultivation is illegal
and they they don't want to pop new
seeds because they're too dependent on
the money for their livelihood i guess
in general do you feel like people
should try to keep an external job to
cannabis if they live in an illegal
country so that they have the freedom to
experiment with their grow or it's okay
to be locked into that production mode
i think
it's okay to be
locked into a production mode but um
i mean if you can spare one light yeah
that's all it takes yeah you can just
pop seats under even in a little tent
yeah with just one large you can just
keep on popping seeds there in the
corner
um
if you only have like one light yeah
then
you're not the type that will keep moms
but if you like diversity and it's for
your own smoke oh then i would always go
from syria
i would just keep on popping seeds and
you get a lot of diversity you see all
different kind of things because
cannabis is so wide yeah
most of us have not seen a lot of things
that are there yeah
yeah most certainly
so if we just loop back to yourself
again
what was the first ever cross you made
when you did start breeding
uh my first crosses were um with uh
jackhammer
um
sage
those are some of the
earlier things jack harry is what i
started with yeah that's what i started
to play with and that's just
um
with regular seats from sansi um
and just starting to incross them and
stuff not even
crossing them out to anything else just
keep making seas every generation yeah
and just playing around and stuff yeah i
was just
learning it myself
um
yeah that's that was probably the first
okay and and were you aware of
kind of how good the genetics around you
were like i'm assuming you know it's
kind of 95 you had access to scentsy
stock this is often regarded as kind of
the golden period
did you feel that way at the time
um well i think at the time all i knew
is that that was the standard
so
at that time i didn't think
i mean i popped other things that i i
didn't like as well yeah
in those years
um
but if i look back now yeah there's a
huge difference that everybody knows
yeah since
the law changed here and they couldn't
we're not allowed to grow for seed
anymore
a lot of people lost a lot of genetics
and a lot of moms and stuff yeah when it
all had to go underground
so that's why a lot of that changed
um
which is a big pity yeah um
i mean the dutch are very good at
doing these things yeah but then if it
becomes small and uh illegal and
you lose moms and stuff which happens um
yeah then it can be really hard yeah
and what do you feel was the ultimate
downfall of the dutch breeding scene
given it was at the pinnacle at that
time
that's 98 when they changed that law
that that really that's the start of it
yeah then people had to move all their
plans underground
um
some of them
kept them for a few years some of them
lost them really fast yeah um that's all
those are all police busts it's that
simple and they they couldn't even say
that of course as well yeah they're not
going to make a public statement saying
oh yeah well
we're doing illegal stuff and we got
busted
yeah they so
they never told the people that
um it changed yeah
yep i can understand that
and so i guess the question has to be
asked do you feel like any of those
really really elusive old school clones
are still around or do you think they're
all just gone now
no they're still there's definitely
still some um
old plants um still alive yeah um i mean
i keep some of these uh the old neville
cuts um i i keep those for a long time
already um i have a really old hindu
kush cut which is like uh more than 30
years old
um i still keep a k2 cut
which is from
late 90s
um
no there's still some plans around um
that kept the time and stuff yeah
and but they were like
cared for by like a little
group or cells yeah um
things always need to be on multiple
places for it to survive longer times
because everything goes wrong
sometime yeah it's that simple yeah
definitely we'll have to loop back have
a chat about those neville coins in a
minute but just to kind of keep the
linearity of things
when you were doing your breeding and
you're kind of first starting out
was there anything else besides just
that allure of new variety which
attracted you towards it did you kind of
think oh you know what i think i could
do a probably a better job than what's
been done thus far
no that didn't come till
like a few years ago to be honest that i
thought [ __ ]
i think i'm pretty i'm pretty pretty
okay at doing this yeah
um
that only came when like huge numbers
were grown out yeah
in in the states yeah that's when i
saw the difference like then you can
really see the difference between
those and uh some of other people's
seeds yeah
um if you grow a bigger groups of all of
them next to each other
and then you can see the difference here
which is which was um
like a bit more vigor um
less pheno variation um things like that
yeah certainly
so when did you think to yourself
you know i'm going to take this
seriously you know i'm going to pursue
it kind of full time and i'm going to
make this my my new gig
um yeah i always was just breathing and
i was on the forums and stuff and it was
all hobby um
i shared some seeds with some friends
but i didn't want to sell anything yeah
then i entered an icy makeup because
they asked me
and then the guy running that um he said
to me you're gonna you gotta sell seats
uh yeah you sell seats to me yeah
so that kind of pushed me yeah um and
that kind of started it to be
yeah honest
that's like two
yeah that's later like 2007
probably
maybe even yeah 2007 2008
before that i never sold the seed i made
a lot of seeds and gave them away and
all my friends and we all grew them and
people on the forums i shared them and
things like that but they were never
sold before that
okay and what was the first project that
you created that caused you to go down
the rabbit hole and you kind of thought
you know what i might work this one a
bit more forward
um
the happy brother which is that old
hindu kush cut
that was a thing that was a
it it was like a clone only thing here
yeah and i thought oh this needs to be
in seed yeah
um so that was kind of my first like
release
aimed uh project um i did um which to be
honest in my eyes was not the biggest
success that's why it's not there
anymore i'm gonna restart the whole
project
from
um zero
okay
it's interesting you bring that up
because i had some questions about that
because i've actually i got the uh the
genetics in front of me
in terms of what you did with the happy
brother and to my surprise
you paired it with the chem d which i
like i mean that's not too surprising
but what i found surprising was that
like people in the past you had felt
that like the hindus or the afghanis in
general were a good match for the chem
dog genetics do you still stand by that
if i had like if i had to do it today
i'm probably going to restart it uh i
would definitely use something different
yeah but i will use an afghani though
i think an afghani be good to be honest
so like an afghani in cross type of
thing
yes
and how would you describe the happy
brother clone in general
um
well at the time that was the
strongest tasting weed that i've ever
smoked at that time and now there was
some a few things that went over it but
at that time there was and it was
extremely strong yeah it was like really
hard uh small nuggets
um
and it was really strong yeah like
really really strong it kind of
has a little bit of an og type structure
in the butt but it's more leafy
it's very resonance light green um
it has a very specific flavor as well
which i don't see in cannabis a lot to
be honest
do you think it's one that's just not
quite valued and has fallen by the
wayside or it's just that unique
no
i think there's someone uh must be a few
other people that still keep it as well
yeah
so it no it is a very it is pretty
unique plant from what i see today yeah
and from what i have seen myself coming
from seed from all kinds of sources
but i've never grown
certified hindu kush land raised seeds
that are
like 100 percent
behind
um which is hard to find any
certified land race today to be honest
yeah so um
yeah
there's no
material for me to compare it with on on
that yeah
so if you have if you could just kind of
click your fingers and get access to any
land race you wanted which one would you
want to work with the most
um
i'm probably gonna have to pick two and
that be afghani and thai
oh good selection did you ever get to
try any of the old school thai
yeah i we used to have a lot of thai
imports here in the old older days so
um yeah i would definitely do a thai
thai is all about for by the higher
um
and then the afghanis would all be about
their power here and also i like the
flavor of
i think a lot of the strong flavors and
smells that people like in some of these
strains are afghani based yeah
yeah certainly certainly and so
just afghani in general or is there one
specific you kind of gravitate towards
because these days it seems like we're
starting to see more diversity within
afghanis and they're not just one group
they're kind of subdivided into the
different regions is any one region
particularly calling out to you or
you're just happy with whatever
um
no i do like well i wouldn't go for
pacific
region but i do like the shorter broad
leaf
type versions yeah
for sure for sure i think that's kind of
the ones that speak to me as well so
it's a perfect little segue question
what do you think about the history of
og overall you know you kind of made the
reference earlier on that the happy
brother reminded you a little bit of oh
gee in some ways what do you think's the
backstory behind it
yeah that's uh
well all these years yeah and all the
stories and everything and stuff um
i wasn't there
yeah so there's not much i can really
say on it that
would be like genuine and certified all
i can say are things that i hear read or
have been told yeah um
yeah
and i think most of those things are
already like open in there yeah um
i do 100
um
think it's genuine that my friend josh
was one that grew it uh the first in uh
california and stuff and blew it up
there
um but yeah it came from florida um
then what happened before that i don't
know yet and what it is i don't know at
all
so um
yeah definitely shout out to josh d
really nice guy
um i was gonna follow this question up
by saying you know we've seen that the
whole tk origins crew is slowly coming
out of the woodworks do you tend to
believe their story i remember i spoke
with josh at the emerald cup and he said
yeah he's pretty sold on the story
yeah i don't know um like i said i
wasn't there so i have nothing to verify
anything what anyone says about it yeah
i mean i know josh well um
but i don't know anything before that
kind of thing so
okay and so how do you think we went
from having let's just let's just for
arguments like say that the josh d cut
was the original or the tk they're kind
of very similar let's say that's the
original
how do you think it went from there to
the point where we've got all the
different og cuts do you think that they
were just like crosses made with the
original or it was just stuff locked
within it and they were kind of bag seed
how do you think we got there
um well there's multiple things
happening there at the same time yeah
one is um it did make like every pound
would have probably like four seats or
whatever yeah um when josh and his crew
and everybody grew it yeah in the
beginning
um
so those seeds would be germed yeah and
then there were a lot of people when the
cut kind of were uh shared with other
people and stuff yeah um people wanted
to know like this is my og i grew this
yeah this is mine so they all started to
name it different as well yeah so the
that's where
kind of the mess started to be honest
yeah
um
and then you had that people started
calling the backseat the same thing
as the plan that the bots they found it
in
um and not labeling it like that yeah
which you see a lot today as well
um
so yeah then it all gets
like so messy yeah and because this is
all like
underground and everything yeah it's
gonna be hard to
really find a solid or like a hundred
percent proven type of thing yet yeah
it will always just be people saying
things now
yeah okay and so do you think that the
idea at least when you look at some of
these og cuts the common story i hear
from people and it's always like i
always get the impression that they're
kind of a bit new to the scene because
they come up to me and they say it as if
like i've never heard it before and
they're always like oh og's just like
lemon [ __ ] crossed into
you know hindu or something like that
you know like that really typical
genetics which is probably not true
do you feel like that does explain why
some of the og cuts are really lemony
and yet you know the josh d cut it
doesn't really have any lemon at all or
do you think it was just locked inside
it
um
well here's another thing yeah some
people will call some smells lemony well
other people say that's not lemon as
well yeah
um
i thought i see that when i give like
wheat and so i can give uh some oh gee
nuggets yeah to a few different people
let them all smell it and some people
that almost never smell weed like it
they say it smells lemony while the
other ones that smoke oh geez oh this
doesn't smell like a lemon yeah
yeah
so i think there's it's pretty hard with
that even on that part as well there is
lemon more lemony type oh geez more pine
soul more piney and more earthy yeah
all those flavors and then in different
percentages yeah they're all og yeah
that's all in og yeah so when you start
breeding with it or when seeds or s-ones
yes some of these percentages it becomes
way more earthy yeah um it becomes way
more lemony or pine-silly or pine yeah
just like that yeah
um then the way it's grown also makes a
clear difference with og's as well like
if they're grown on soil
if they're grown outdoor
which type of nutrients make a little
difference as well yeah
temperatures um those things make the
same clone come out very different
sometimes as well yeah
like if you give the same og clone to 10
different growers and they all return it
there will be quite some differences a
lot of times in it yeah
it doesn't look like exact the same weed
yeah definitely and i i can't remember
who said it but i think it might have
even been caleb from csi forgive me if
i'm wrong but basically
someone told me something along the
lines of like they rounded up all the
different og cuts and grew them all out
and there was really only like two or
three different og's across what was
meant to be like 40 different cuts they
were just as you said just different
grow conditions different noses
describing different flavors
would you would you be like
would you be happy to believe that that
could be true
uh yeah i i i'm a bit surprised though
one that on 40 it would be only three
different
things yeah i would expect it a little
bit more but um
yeah
multiple the same yeah under different
names 100 if you all collect all kind of
og cards from everywhere
you'll definitely have the same clone
under different names
yeah yeah yeah i think i might be
mistaken on some of the finer details of
that but yeah i think you got the point
more or less correctly and i think one
of the things people say to me is that
the the sfv cut
so to speak people will call that a
myriad of different names like people
have said to me that the larry is
definitely different to the sfv and
there's a few others that are definitely
different but you know some of those
other ones you hear about with like a
little bit more obscure that they're all
just really the same thing like just
like a lemon og
yeah like we would um with short um we
grew probably like seven or eight of the
cuts like at the same time and they were
different yeah
yeah so
they're all like bit older type cuts
yeah they were all different
they were all different they were all
straight og but they were all different
yeah so um
and then sometimes i think as well if a
clone is like
not kept right yeah or um it's in a too
hard of a room for a long time all these
things it gets like ptsd yeah and then
it changes some people call it genetic
derived but i don't think it i don't
call it genetic drift yet because if you
keep that plant really well for a year
and you treat it really well it comes
back by itself as well
so
hell yeah so that's an idea which has
been kind of expressed by a few of our
guests in the past
do you believe that there is a way to
rejuvenate the plant indoors because
most of our past guests when they kind
of echo that sentiment you just
expressed they'd say oh you kind of got
to get it outside get it under the sun
and that'll really rejuvenate it a bit
do you find you're able to do it indoors
just in a really well maintained
environment
no i didn't with all the old cuts i have
they go outdoor every year
yeah okay really
reinvigorates it with that life
yes yes very rich soil
and then um like a few weeks before
flower that's when take off
new cuts and then move them inside again
yeah definitely well we'll loop back to
that in a minute i guess the last
question i want to just quickly ask on
the topic is
how do you feel about the rise of tissue
culturing and kind of the merry stem
culturing as a way of rejuvenating these
plants and getting them back to their
former glory do you feel like it's
something you'll explore more or are you
still just kind of waiting to see how
that technology pans out a bit more
oh that's that that's that's the whole
future yeah
no it's perfect it's ha it's great
it works really well as well
do you see the price point coming down
to the point where
pretty much every old clone will be
tissue cultured eventually or it's just
those really select standouts
well no i think there will be huge
uh genetic libraries in made into tissue
culture 100 percent yeah 100
and and the more legally becomes all
over the world i think the whole future
will be just that yeah
why would you i mean it's gonna in it if
it would be legal in the whole world
it would push away the
big part of the seed market 100
you would sell a tissue culture yeah you
would create and breathe things but you
would sell the tissue culture to people
then
yeah it's definitely a
a future outcome which isn't really
discussed as much
no but it's i mean you look at it from a
client point it's very logical yeah it's
very logical so
yeah i agree so
this brings us to the first big question
that i think people were waiting for
when and how was it that you came about
to decide that the hell's og was the og
that you wanted to work with
well those
cuts um
i got in
let me think must be 2a 2008 2009.
um
i had that and as a v yeah but the sfv
died so this was the only
original well one of the older og cuts
from the us i had at that time as well
the rest i had was all from seed
so that was one of the reasons to be
honest yeah
apart from that i like it a lot yeah
it's very strong
it's got a serious kick to it compared
to some of the other ones
it's not as light green as most of the
ogs
the cut itself doesn't show much purple
but the gene pool definitely has quite a
lot of purple in
it um
yeah so
and the cut that i got
did have some ptsd problems and not that
much vigor and stuff as well yeah it
took like almost three years before it
really
came back to good power
um so yeah seeds are always a good thing
then
definitely i mean limited availability
can often be the reason for a lot of
things you mentioned there's not a lot
of purple in the gene pool and and it's
amazing you mentioned that because i had
a question specifically about that where
i was saying a lot of the biker or the
hell's og lines that you've worked they
tend to be pretty green there's not a
lot of purple in them and it's kind of
like a bit of a polarizing thing for
people some people see purple and
they're just put off they think it's
weak can't be good
do you tend to fall into that same camp
or do you think no it's just purely a
genetic thing
um
i think the strongest weeds that i've
smoked were not purple
yeah
and there is definitely weaker purple
things just as there is
weaker green things as well
um
so yeah
there's there's some strong purple type
things yeah um
like even the cookie type gene pool and
stuff yeah that's not
that's not weak weed yeah
they're stronger much stronger stuff but
it's not weak yeah so um
then there's some other strains which i
think are pretty weak they are purple so
i understand why people have that
thought or say things like that but i
don't think it's that easy or you can
put it over like uh that easy yeah
there's definitely strong purple weed as
well
it's that simple yeah okay i agree with
you on that one so
just to quickly loop back to the hell's
og if you weren't able to work with the
hells angels og and you were still
limited by that selection you had
which og would you have opted to work
with next in line
um
the og jg card that's the some people
call it jew gold
wow that's a rare one we don't hear
about that outside of the dna crew
yeah
um
that cut comes from a friend of mine
at bibi he's from calicus farms
they're the originators of they they
have that cut since they did
since the old days yeah and it has that
name because um
when a one of a kid in their crew when
he grew it yeah and he's a jewish kid
yeah
then it was word gold yeah because he
just grew it the best
that's the oh that's why it was called
that yeah
it was the little kids they called him
the jew so it was the jews gold yeah
that's why it's called that yeah and
it's not negative at all um
that's just a very flavorful very strong
um it yields really nice as well yeah um
that's just like for me that's an
all-rounded uh oh gee that i personally
like probably like the most of mo of all
the older og cuts
yeah it's an interesting one i've spoken
to many people about it and i mean the
first kind of point of view i heard
expressed about it was that
some people kind of doubted it existed
like in the sense that no one disputes
kosher as a good strain unquestionable
however when i was asking some people
about the jew gold they were like oh you
know what you never really saw photos of
it or anything until well after kosher
was out and
some people had even thought well maybe
maybe you know the the original is was
produced just to explain where things
came from if you get what i mean
no it is a clone um
i don't know the
background before much before that to be
honest but they've been growing that for
a [ __ ] long time yeah way before
uh dna entered it um and then made the
kosher cushy eats yeah way before that
that cuts been grown a long time before
that
i smoked it way before they andrew
ditched that's why
yeah okay and so how do you feel about
the dna crew they're quite polarizing in
many people's eyes
yeah
i have no problem with
dna even though
like this kosher thing there's there's a
lot of
i don't know
those are not things that i
um i'm good with everybody yeah so i
don't like to go into those things i
know everything let me put it that way
yeah i know all the backstories and
everything that really happened anything
like that
i just don't like talking about that
stuff
yeah okay what about some of the more
blatant
kind of uh
questionable breeding practices that
have occurred like for example we've had
guests on in the past such as brita
steve who have had their issues with
barney's farm
given that you know they're blatantly
ripping off one of his strains how do
you feel about those situations where
it's a little more clear-cut let me just
be honest about it then yeah about
almost the whole
dutch thing and what these companies do
kind of these days and what a lot of
them kind of are yeah
um yep
yeah they'll find something from someone
and then just
make it theirs that's what happens here
um it's the same with the kosher thing
yeah they bought that wheat they entered
it um
and then made the [ __ ] strain out of
it and then then called it that yeah
they didn't even have to cut so that's
how those things go and then yeah
barney's there's loads of them i don't
even like to call the names because then
i'm like pointing at them yeah but they
all do this type of stuff yeah and
they've been doing that for many years
most of these things are not bred by
them yeah they'll find someone like you
or someone else or like me or whatever
yeah and you show them something
it'll take it
certainly not a point of view we're
hearing for the first time a lot of
people have said things along this line
but it's nice to get clarification from
someone who's so
you know kind of connected with that
scene
yeah no i'm i'm connected like i said i
mean in all these
different
lines in in the scene yeah so um i'm
still connected to everyone in the down
market
in the shade um but i'm also connected
to people in that are standing in the
spotlight yeah
um
and all of these people love cannabis
though don't get me wrong yeah
it's just that i think
the commercial and then the pressure
and everything like that yeah um
made it go that way and you also have to
be honest yeah um
you have to start somewhere yeah jeans
don't fall from the sky yeah
yeah so you always have to get it
somewhere or from someone as well yeah
yeah most certainly most certainly
so
i guess my next question is it's a
little different but i'd love to get
your perspective on it
how did the dutch scene react to when
cookies first came out because it kind
of you know took over a lot of scenes
was that the same case in holland
well
first time cookies came here is when
jiga came over here as well i don't know
which year it is
2013 or
2012 or 14 i don't know it's one of
these years that the high times copy
came here that's when he showed people a
lot of the people that didn't have that
didn't go to the us had not seen it
before that
um
when he was away that same year you had
uh girl scout cookies on menus yeah but
it was not girl scout cookies yeah it
was weed that was purple
um
i think it took like probably
three years something like that when the
girl scout cookie form cut kind of went
to europe and things like that then you
started seeing it but it's more like in
the still in the underground yeah with
like smaller growers and the foreign
people
and these days yeah you can get buy
cookies these days it's like yeah it's
there not many dutch people grow it
though because they don't like it
because it doesn't yield enough for them
they're used to growing amnesia
which yields a lot yeah it's very easy
to grow no matter what you do if you
feed it too much it doesn't matter
so yeah they all grow amnesia here
how do you feel about the fabled core
cut of amnesia is it a staple for you or
it's just a bitter
yeah that's funny thing that it's
labeled core cod these days but um yeah
so that's a cut that
went from sweep which is the owner of
high pro which is kind of the base of
that amnesia gene pool yeah
um
from other to other people and then into
the forum and then core was a member of
the forum yeah here in europe and he
sent it out to a lot of people that's
why it's labeled core cut yeah but
that's a high pro amnesia cut there's
two or three of them around in europe
um that's kind of what the staple is for
amnesia
there's a few that are a little bit
better but they flower a bit longer or
things like that
yeah okay so it's just kind of that nice
balance of all things
yeah that it's a really good plan yeah
um
it's not my favorite we me personally
yeah but um it's easy to grow it's very
strong it can take a lot of abuse it has
a high pr thc percentage yeah um
it breathes pretty nice as well yeah if
you like that stuff yeah so um it's a
good overall clone and plant yeah
yeah
okay
so if we jump back to your own breeding
for a moment it seems to me like your
first major cross that kind of started
to get you widespread attention was the
biker kush would you agree with this
analysis and how did you feel when it
initially took off
yeah i think
og is definitely the thing that made me
noticed and i think the reason was at
that time yeah when that came out
almost every ogc that came out no matter
if they were regular or whatever
they had like a lot of herm problems
here
and this line had way less here
like it's just a small percentage yeah
um and i think that's the thing that got
noticed
yeah so do you feel like crossing og
with things there is an intrinsic risk
with it because there's this debate
which surrounds og and how it's a little
bit herme prone
and people often give the example of
well you should never cross girl scouts
and og together because it's just
guaranteed to get you hermes how do you
feel like about that idea do you feel
like it's intrinsic and inevitable that
you're going to get some hermes with og
and would you ever cross it to girl
scouts
um well the girl scout gene pool if you
take one of those old cuts they're way
more terrible for her type things yeah
cherry pie is even worse than that
um
i think if you clean up an og lion yeah
meaning if you do like back crosses and
in crosses and every time you select
away from it
um you can
the lower the percentage here
og is not as bad as
some of the chem and the sour gene pool
bar in the
um girl scout cookie cherry pie those
two are like i haven't been able to get
those
really clean
yeah so i don't like to work too much
with those two lines oh geez i'm very
confident these days with my own lines
yeah so um i dare to cross it with all
kinds of stuff
um and i'm not worried about herms
coming from that side
yeah okay so what what would be the big
no-no for you in terms of crossing
genetics together would it be og and
cherry pie
yeah that's
i mean i did hat stash which is girl
scout cookie cherry pie nog
and that's the only line i have not been
able to clean yeah so um
yeah no i don't i try to stay away these
days from the girl scout cookie cherry
pie
things
okay so let's just say that you didn't
create the biker og line
which out of your own creations would
have been next in line for you to
consider working forward or using as
kind of a line you wanted to represent
yourself
oh it definitely would be the the
headbanger i think is the strain that's
became most popular from me
um
and that was all because everybody wants
sour dia
um
which
is normal because i think it's some of
the best weed in the world so um
yeah it's kind of the headbanger yeah um
and then that's kind of what i did now
with like the back crosses to that sour
d cut
um
and that's that's what people always
asked for kind of but i didn't ever did
it before
yeah okay and so do you feel like sourdy
just totally overtook the og craze when
it came
about i think um
og is way easier to grow than than sour
d is yeah sour d is not easy to grow a
lot of people won't have
the big success right away with it and
stuff yeah it's uh it needs a different
feeding
than most other plants yeah
so
it's it's certainly one of the more
unique ones and what do you feel about
the history you know it's it's almost
got a more disputed history than og
itself
yeah that one's like even a bigger mess
than
than the og background um
i've been so interested in trying to
find that out for so many years
at the moment i don't even
care that much anymore yeah and i think
people really care
when they don't have it
once you have it that's kind of the most
important thing yeah and
even though you would still like to know
what it is it's less important than you
smoking it
yeah i can i can certainly agree with
that point that's a good one to make so
it's interesting because as i'm sure
you're probably well aware there's
there's a bit of drama that surrounds
your sourdy climb because it
specifically comes from a res dog
release which kind of adds a extra layer
of complexity to the whole situation
how do you feel about working with you
know people's gear who
other people may not drive with or be as
willing to work with
well in this case i understand a hundred
percent which is one of the reasons i
didn't
backcross it before either
i mean
that's why i even try not to call out
his name too much yeah but this plant is
so special yeah this plant is so [ __ ]
good yeah that people just deserve this
yes that's simple um these seeds just
need to go [ __ ] everywhere and then
everybody needs to have this yeah
everybody needs to have smoked this at
least once in their life um
it's just that so good of a weed yeah
if i had to pick one thing that i could
bring to me um to an island i would
bring that 100
and so how many seeds did you pop when
you initially found this clone
i got two packs
wow that's a good answer i guess that
goes to show all you need is one or two
packs and you can find something really
special
yeah oh yeah of course you know
definitely definitely and those seeds
then um
i mean this is very simple yeah you get
lucky sometimes yeah it's that simple i
got really lucky and why did i get lucky
i got lucky because this
plant did not herm
and its offspring doesn't hurt almost
either yeah which is very rare for
all those seeds from res and from those
days yeah
because they were pretty messy if i'm
honest yeah they were like hey finos
there were herms in it
it was just messy yet but then there was
some
like diamonds in there as well yeah um
my card comes from the same badge that
another cut that's around in europe
comes from which is the reary cut that's
from exact same c badger which is the
first time he released his sour d ibl
which is not ibl by the way yeah
it should not have been labeled ibl but
um yeah that's 2006. i bought them in
2007.
do you feel like people tend to view
reza's work with kind of rose shaded
glasses like a lot of people acknowledge
the controversy surrounding him but at
the same time a lot of people won't deny
that the gear was really good or at
least so it said do you feel like people
gloss over the fact like what you just
mentioned that there were a lot of herms
and a lot of junk in there
um i think for that time yeah
those genes were not spread yeah when
things go into seed they go over the
world yeah and then it goes really fast
yeah
um
so
just for people seeing that for the
first time yet the good things that were
in there yeah that just made it like
that yeah the time and being the first
with that yeah that just made it to what
it is because he was not a nice guy on
the forums either yeah not before all
the snitch problem and all this other
stuff happened either yeah he was not a
nice guy yeah
he always was [ __ ] cursing at people
on the forums he was not a nice guy it's
that simple
yeah okay well we've seen him pop his
head back up i was probably about a year
or more ago now on instagram and they
quickly kind of ducked out again
just to play devil's advocate how would
you feel if say res dog came back
and he bought five or ten packs of your
sauer dbx2 and wanted to work that
forward would you see that as an honor
or an insult
um
not
you gotta see that as an honor yeah
because that means
he [ __ ]
admits that i did it better than he did
even though i started with his stuff i
cleaned it out it's that simple there's
no her almost no herm in it yeah and it
breathes um
if you pop these back cross two seats if
you look on my instagram there's so many
people i had had them grow out before
they were even released yeah and you can
see it in there yeah every female is
sourdy yeah
um there's variation in that of course
yeah um
but they all have that smell and that
stink
and most of them have the high which
it's very important about it as well
yeah
so yeah
if you pop two of these pack of seeds
you'll definitely get
a better choice of
what you want to keep compared to what
it was then
yeah certainly and i i definitely wanted
to make the point of complimenting you
on that when i look at those photos that
absolutely imma unmistakable undeniable
that uh very swollen calyx look that the
sourdy has all the females i've seen
from your
uh bx2 they've got that look and i kind
of on initial glance i'm like is that
the clone and then uh but then you're
like oh oh it's the bx2 that so yeah you
did an amazing job on that
yeah that's that came out really well um
the backross one i didn't release
that was kind of iffy yeah um that was
not good enough to be sold as a seed
yeah there were quite a lot of weaker
plans in it um
and i think the
headbanger meal i used um
probably was not the best pick
that's probably why that's what i
started it off with
um then from the back cross one i found
some really good males here and
i used multiple males as well in this
back cross yeah
hell yeah hell yeah
so what do you feel is the proper
breeding etiquette for using someone
else's work do you kind of think that if
you bought it you don't really owe them
anything or how do you like to deal with
other breeders when you're using some of
their work well what i did here is
normally wrong yeah
i think yeah i think it's wrong um if
you buy seats and this is all about
commercial sales yeah if you do whatever
you do for yourself your friends and
trainers that's a totally different
thing yeah um but if you buy someone's
seats
um you don't in cross them um and then
sell them like a pure version yeah
that's that's kind of a no-go thing um
but outcrossing yeah yeah you buy those
seeds they're yours yeah so when you buy
my seeds cross it with whatever you want
yeah that's of course and you can sell
it as well that doesn't matter at all
that's freedom if you don't want people
to do that then you shouldn't sell seeds
yeah it's that simple yeah most
certainly and so
do you like to if it's at all possible
kind of open lines of communication with
someone if you are going to use some of
their work or you just tend to use it
and do your thing well apart from this
sour d thing because i didn't uh talk to
raz dog about that one um all my other
things like co-ops or other things
they're all like in agreement with these
people yeah most times they give me this
stuff to do that with it yeah
so if you look at sour power og hordy
lab gives me that cut yeah i'm very good
friends with camarado he gives me stuff
to do things with yeah i do it the same
the other way um
i mean i share a lot with a lot of
people yeah also a lot of people that
have seed companies and stuff i share
stuff with them which is not for my own
work as well yeah like i have a very big
um genetic seed stash here um i shared
stuff from that through the years with a
lot of people online and
a lot of people made things with it
started lines with it and stuff like
that
yeah most certainly so it's interesting
that you bring up the sour power because
i think it's it's an interesting strain
for mostly one reason but it's probably
more
how do you feel about undisclosed
genetics and would you ever release a
cross where you didn't
release the genetic information around
it
now if i know it then i will i'll always
tell it yeah but
because with how things are you
sometimes don't even know yeah
yeah okay so do you feel like with hordy
labs they truly didn't know
what the uh the star bud was or do you
think that that was a bit of a marketing
ploy
no i think you really don't know
and the other question about them i
wanted to quickly ask was i had heard
some whispers saying that
old dave watson a skunk man sam is the
the mastermind behind hordy labs do you
know if that's true or not
no i know
the
guy behind horny lab that's not david
watson
he knows him though
i mean
he knows him though i i i think he knows
them
i mean david is in is in amsterdam um
hardy used to be
in amsterdam a lot as well um they have
an acquaintance
you know so
yeah no they do they they must have met
each other a couple of times but he's
definitely not behind it yeah
okay cool
so the sour power og your your work with
the sour power is a lime which
definitely gets a lot of attention and i
mean the photos on your instagram
they're gorgeous how do you feel about
that cross of yours is it one of your
ones that you're more kind of proud to
put forward or do you feel like there's
kind of other ones that you'd be more
looking to get people to grow if they
had a choice
um i think flavors are always very
personal yeah i mean i like sour d most
of everything
and so i kind of always pick something
that has
so i mean sour power og has sour in it
yeah but headbanger is way more like a
sour d-type hybrid yeah so i would
prefer personally to
smoke that
and when it comes to growing sour power
og is very sturdy plant
um it's very easy very resinous yeah it
looks beautiful as well
um
and it's pretty powerful as well yeah um
so a lot of people find things in it
they they keep and they can produce yeah
definitely
so
if we just jump back to biker kush for a
moment i noticed in an instagram thread
you said that the initial mail you used
on the hell's og
was an sfv bx2 that you actually got
from swerves gear
swerve's a guy who gets a bit of flack
from some people in the community so i'd
be interested to hear what's your
opinions on the cali con and swerves
gear in general
well let me say i got those seeds from
captain [ __ ] yeah um but uh swerve said
he he makes them um
those two people used to work with each
other so whatever it is i don't know
don't know yeah um
as for swerve um i know him as a person
um
he may have made some mistakes here in
the area he was young um
i don't know when it comes to
when it comes to the breeding or
how he runs his business or how he named
some of his strains i have a very
different philosophy on that yeah and
how i do things yeah i would never cross
call across the name of the clone yet
um because when the people grow them out
after that yeah everybody starts to call
it that and that's where
all this mess comes from yeah like in
europe there are so many people who say
i have sfvog
i have a
larry og yeah and this larry og is larry
or g times whatever it is yeah
um so yeah i have different views on
things and stuff um
but he's definitely not a bad guy yeah
though
as a person he's a really nice guy
yeah for sure
so when you're thinking about oh gee in
general i'm i kind of already asked this
question in relation to happy brother
but in specifically for og
what in your mind is the perfect partner
for an og cross
i think og
does not cross well with um like very
sativa type things like the real hazes
and stuff yeah i don't think that
crosses well
um what i think crosses well with ogs or
um
to be honest kind of tighter body type
things yeah like um
[Music]
there was a good example um
like oh geez chems and sours yeah which
are all kind of pretty maybe even
related yeah um those things all mix
with each other pretty well as well yeah
it makes yields go up um
it does keep the flavor kind of pure um
i'm not the biggest fan of crossing them
out to like fruity things and stuff it's
kind of like most times it weakens both
of them yeah
yeah definitely i i would tend to agree
that the the cam and the og do tend to
blend pretty well together and what a
perfect segue in terms of talking about
that collab you did with jj from top dog
how did you find the road dog came out
and did that stimulate you to want to
look into the chem genetics a bit more i
like chem genetics a lot yeah
i prefer chem 91
probably most
because probably because it's more gassy
i guess
i think camdee is one of the strongest
um
that's star dog that i use that's from
one of his earlier releases as well
at the farm
and
that's the own selected cut as well
and i i like the i like the outcome of
that a lot yeah um
it's very
gassy mostly most of them um
the only problem with that line is and
with i think with some
most of these scams yeah is they don't
have that long of a shelf life so if you
make a lot of flour of it and you keep
it for three four months
it tends to
like get a darker tint and stuff like
that faster than a lot of other strains
so i kind of like to smoke it a bit
fresher as well i like to smoke it three
four weeks after it comes down
yeah most certainly i can attest to
the more fresher stuff just being so
punch in your face strong so with that
comment being said though what strains
do you think have a good shelf life and
that longevity within the flower
oh that's with the hazes they they're
really good at like they're even better
after six months
and if you take them out of the bag or
out of your jar after two years
they are still 100 dead yeah
sour d does really well as well yeah you
can jar that up for a long time yeah
yeah very very interesting i think um it
was in fact aj who put a post up
yesterday of some six month old
uh sour and he was saying yeah it
definitely tastes better
yeah the longer sativa type things are
more sativa genes they tend to
cure a better for long term
i have the same with og's i like my og's
to be smoked within six months after
harvest
yeah okay i think i've sadly never had
the production capacity or patience to
wait that long to smoke any stuff i've
grown but i've got a new benchmark
yeah you'll see with most like tight
indica type buds yeah um
they are kind of better smoked a bit
faster and then the hazes they they're
kind of better if they've laid like at
least three months
yeah okay and so in general what are
some of the other strains you find that
are best fresh off the bat you know just
a few weeks after coming down
um i think like um
these more fruity type things yeah um
that people like a lot these days yeah
that type of stuff doesn't cure well for
long term as well yeah um which is also
kind of why the live resins and
everything of them are way better than
the cured resins of those type of plants
a lot of times as well
yeah i can definitely agree with that
the the live resin from some of the
fruity stuff is off the chain so just to
jump back to uh some of the
collaborations you've done before i
noticed you you've done a plethora of
collabs it's quite impressive out of all
the ones you've done
what were you most surprised with and i
shouldn't say surprised but which one
were you most pleasantly
surprised to see the end outcome like
which one was just really good and you
always you always go into something
thinking it's going to be a good outcome
but you were just blown away by the
result
um
i like a lot when i the camaraderie og
came out as even though it's og and i
already had a lot of 4g
um
i just like that a lot um apart from
that something which is not that known
yet is um african dream
which is jj's nigerian haze times wide
a5 that came out like wow as well yeah
yeah i mean that that's a really diverse
mix of genetics in there like the
the sativa african with the uh the a5
white that's that's got to be special
yeah those are really nice yeah they're
really nice they're very sativish style
in grow and stuff like that yeah so
they'll be
mostly 12-14 weeks
yeah okay it's only for the truly
committed sativa heads
yeah if you want to grow real hazes you
you got to be accepting to go
between 12 and 16 to 17 weeks sometimes
even
yeah
yeah okay so this kind of brings us to
one of the
questions i've been most excited to ask
you about going into this
a little birdie told me that you have
some projects in the works with bodhi
would you be able to elaborate a little
more on that for us
um
i don't know that much about it yet to
be really honest um
my friend
is settling that up yeah so i haven't
that's not fully worked out yet so
there's not much i can say yet to be
really honest yeah
so your bird flies fast your bird flies
really fast
yeah i got little birds everywhere but
but um
the question i'd love to ask then is in
in your kind of dream situation what
types of things would you want to bring
to the table and what types of things do
you think that he has that would be cool
if he was bringing that side of the
cross to the table
um
i'd love to
have um some involvement with his nepali
gene cool
definitely that's what i brought
yeah
um what would come from me um knowing
him and what interests him i think it
would be the hazes though
i think that's what
probably i have that probably interests
him the most
i mean oh geez or and sauer he he has it
all yeah and so i think he would prefer
those gene pools more
because he did the band-aid haze which
was done with the a5 tie those seats i
sent all over the world years ago
so i think it would be like probably
that gene pool a5 c5 um dosas
yeah okay so
funnily enough this is a good segue i
heard from a different little birdie
that and you referenced it before the uh
you might have access to some of
neville's original breeder cuts like the
c5 and the a5 for example
is this true and what plans do you have
with them
no i've
in the
early 2000s
i used to make a lot of clones
of all these plants for that group
i've been kind of part of that southern
which is where i live as well yeah i
live in south holland
um
so i've been connected to this group
since i was really young
okay and they're the crew who kind of
safeguard the c5 and the a5
yeah they worked with neville's as well
when he was here
okay so i guess the thing which maybe a
lot of people might be interested to
hear is that like a lot of these breeder
cuts do still exist which i was
surprised to hear myself initially
yeah now these cuts are um
well some people call them breeder cuts
they they come out of his breeding yeah
so c5 is is the nl5 times the haze mill
c um the a5 is nl5 then the haze mill a
there's not even one cut yet there's
more cuts of it as well when that
selection was done yeah but most people
only know one or two
um then there's hph which is the hash
plant haze
the ag-13
there's a couple more even yeah um
like for instance the a5 is which most
people are interested in yeah
there were five cuts of that they are
labeled one to five
number five being the most sativa
um
the number two is what some called the
diesel cut which is the cut i work with
the cut that i gave to sammy and which
is
went out a little bit to some people
and that's the number two
um the number four
is still around as well but that never
forgot grown that much it's way more
hazy
and do you feel like these are really
kind of
the benchmark to try to aim for with
breeding or do you think they're just
impressive for when they were produced
given it was you know 30 years ago
no those cuts are very special still
100 very special
[Music]
i think it's the combination with the
nl5 uh and those haze that really makes
it yeah
um
like that haze pure from those days um
kind of tickles me way less than these
two plants yeah
yeah a5 is a really special one to be
honest
yeah okay yeah i remember i was lucky
enough to try some of the c5 when i was
hanging out with bodhi and he too said
that a lot of people think the a5 is a
little better
[Music]
yeah a pipe's very strong weed um
and it's the type of wheat you kind of
need to smoke quite a lot of it and then
you can get to a level you don't get
with other wheat
these days at all yeah it is a lot about
uh how it works this weed yeah how it
makes you feel yeah that's very
important with that weed
um
like the c5 if you smoke a lot of that
you won't almost won't be able to sleep
yeah
like you won't be sleeping well at all
yeah um some people get very paranoid of
the c5 as well yeah
um
it's also people that only smoke indicas
if you let them smoke a5 they'll be like
blattered yeah they don't know what
happened to them yeah they'll be like
out of it yeah yeah now it's really
funny it's really funny and sometimes
when i go to like one of these coffee
shops here then um i'll bring some of
that and all they smoke is amnesia and
oge yeah today
and you let them smoke like two or three
joints of that yeah oh they're all like
flat out yeah
it just makes them feel so different
yeah they're not used to it
i love it yeah the the sample i got to
smoke it was actually seeded so it's
probably nowhere near as potent as the
scentsy but that c5 i can totally agree
it was so
uplifting and stimulating that like
paranoia was the next logical step if
you kept smoking it
yeah and then i got the this cut the
bandaid hay seven which
bodhi bread the line then duck selected
that cut um i've smoked a couple of
hundred grams of that now
that that got a really good high as well
yeah that's comparable to like a ca5
yeah it really is on that level yeah
that's a really nice plant they did that
one really really well
definitely definitely a shout out to doc
and bodhi that's uh that's another
really good one which i don't think is
on the radar of enough people
but just to jump back to where we all
started this question which was in
regards to kind of neville
where do you think neville rates in
terms of the the great breeders
throughout the dutch history and and of
all the breeders throughout history who
has had the greatest influence in your
opinion
i think
if you really look at all the work that
people done
he i mean he did quite some work with
his very early days as well yeah so
it's just him and a few other people as
well yeah when it comes to the seeds
that go out and get sold
um
so i those plans are very special yeah
and he is very knowledgeable on it as
well
um but i think like uh simon from
serious seeds
that guy has been doing it way
that guy really did a lot and um
still does it um
you know he's really good
um someone that most people don't even
think or know about anymore casey brains
did some nice things as well um
there's a there's a couple of people
most of those people are not that known
yet because they're not the ones
out there or doing the sieve company
yeah so casey brains is a very
interesting one because he's famous for
never releasing any of the information
around his genetics i mean in some
instances he says himself he doesn't
know and in other instances i think it
was just also the way he named his
strains how do you feel about his
strains i think earlier on you mentioned
that you've got a special k2 clone does
that come from him
no no that's not uh that's not from him
um
no it's his strange um
even though some of them have quite a
lot of variation yeah um his seeds from
what i've seen it been a little while i
i just had new ones of it so i'm gonna
germ them all see if they're still the
same and he says they are so um he said
he's still using his old mom's
um
they have some very fruity interesting
flavors in there yeah if you like all
the fruit things it's definitely a
really nice source for
all kind of different things to be
honest yeah
um he used a lot of um
brazilian and afghani genes
yeah the brazilian is one which doesn't
really get explored outside of his work
do you think there might be something in
there that we're just brushing over and
missing
yeah i have a couple of brazilian
friends here um
yeah i think that's why i'm doing this
project with them i'm popping all those
feeds with them because they know all
the old brazilian things that were
around you
um
now they definitely say there there has
been a lot of lime and melon um those
type of terpenes and smells that they
were there like long ago
yeah okay and so i think most people at
least when i talk to them the only real
exposure they have to the brazilian
genetics is
that mango bishop from b
and i think that you know maybe
sometimes it gives things a bad rap you
know how do you feel some of these
genetics would go if put in people's
grow rooms do you think people would
give them a second chance or they're
still not quite refined to the poly
hybrid level we're used to
um
i think some of casey brains ones
definitely
could be like
being commercial produced here
for today's market and being like really
wanted by the people that smoke it
afterwards as well
yeah i think he's very open
yeah i think i just opened a little hole
for everybody to
find a lot of i mean everybody wants all
these um
fruity type flavors and things like that
yeah well this guy definitely has a lot
of it
yeah okay
so getting back to a point i've been
bringing up in recent interviews do you
see this as a way to reinvigorate modern
genetics like a common complaint is that
we've worked ourselves into kind of like
this dead end polyhybrid type of thing
where there's this same same quality
amongst a lot of strains do you think
that we need to go back to basics to
some of these land races or just some of
these more unworked lines and generate
new hybrids
oh yeah definitely man i think i think
a lot of people have
it all depends with the goal you're
making seas for yeah and most people
that do it today or start today
they make those seats to sell them
um and they look at what the market
wants or that's easy for them to sell
sell yeah and they get noticed for that
everybody wants cookies so they all
crush it with cookies yeah
which kind of takes away their personal
creativity and for me a breeder is like
an artist yeah like a painter
yeah so
if everybody starts to make similar
paintings it kind of gets boring very
fast
i think today's gene pool and the seeds
that are on the market there's so many
of the similar type things yeah and
that's because everybody just takes all
the cuts that are shared
um and then pollinates it with something
that's just been released for a year or
whatever
yeah so yeah
you just get everything crossed with
each other now yeah
um so yeah i definitely think it's good
for people to
or
seek a goal in like a terpenes or
whatever you want to make lemon then
find as much different lemon genetics as
you can doesn't matter what it is what
the name is or whatever and then start
searching in that yourself yeah
same for all kind of other terpenes or
other things you want to do yeah if you
want to make a haze try and find as much
different haze genetics
as genuine as you can germinate mold
forget all the names and just pick what
you like and start from there
yeah that's that's a good idea would you
would you actually do that yourself in
terms of say like popping like a hundred
seeds just losing all the name tags and
just seeing what came out
um
yeah i'd love to do it to be honest i'll
be honest i've never been as bold to
really do it in the end
i always put the tags in though
but yeah that's kind of that's the best
way to be really honest yeah um you
should just put a number on everything
write it on a paper lock it up
do the whole grow do your selection pick
what you like most and then look what
you
what it was that's kind of the fairest
and the honest thing to do as well yeah
we all get influenced otherwise yeah
yeah i mean names can have a really
powerful effect on the way people
perceive them
how do you feel about the whole candy
rain situation from cookie fam do you
feel like they really dropped the ball
on that one
no they definitely dropped the ball
yeah that's just effects to be really
honest yeah um
i mean i'm not scared of
germinating um i call it messy genetics
yeah i'm not scared of everything i'll
germinate by the thousands i don't care
i kill all the intersex or whatever and
things like that i'm not scared for
those things but um
those seeds
clearly were not even tested yeah
yeah otherwise this could never happen
it's that it's that simple so um
everybody knows i'm like very strict on
everything needs to be tested you cannot
just make seats and start selling them
yeah that's like
for me that's like not even possible to
do yeah even though in today's market
that's like probably [ __ ] more than
50 percent
yeah people can't pay to be a test
yeah so how do you feel in general about
the price that was charged for those
seeds whether they had issues or not do
you feel like
it's an ever growing precedent for there
to be these premium price seeds or do
you think it was just a bit absurd
well i think it's absurd i mean look
what i sold the sour d because too i
could have sold those for whatever i
wanted yeah and people would have bought
them right away i sell them for a price
that i think is like almost the max of
what
seeds should be costing yeah
i don't think seeds should be going
above 150
i think that should be kind of a cap
yeah even though that has changed
totally today
and but i will i personally prefer not
to sell anything about that
so do you think that there should be
kind of like
i i don't want to use the term but
there's nothing else that would fit as
well but kind of like a union for
breeders where like you agree on like
price ceilings and price flaws and kind
of like structure among seed pricing
like an f2 you can charge this much and
f1 you can only charge this much how
would you feel about that concept
no i think it's got to be a free market
i mean
every every other product is a free
market yeah you can buy sunglasses for a
euro
you can buy sunglasses for a thousand
euro yeah
you know what i mean uh
i don't think that
no i don't think there should be a stand
rule i think it's a principle yeah i
think seats are worth that and you
should
if you take a lot of time reading
something you're not
gonna sell it for once yeah or only sell
two or three hundred packs yeah you're
gonna do that for years
yeah so you don't need to ask 500
or 400 to 500 300 for a package of seats
yeah
then these they all they do is like oh
this is limited yeah this will never be
there anymore these are very rare uh all
these things and then that it should be
expensive for that yeah no that's not
the way it works only thing that can be
more expensive or seeds that are harder
to make
and take longer to make
things like that yeah or that took a lot
of money to make so a lot of breeding
steps yeah so yeah they need to be a bit
more expensive to recoup your investment
yeah no i mean that certainly makes
sense so on a slightly related topic i
noticed on your ig that some of your new
seed packaging the what the pack i
noticed specifically was the guava
gelato cross sourdi sounds amazing by
the way but i noticed on it that said
premium seeds and it got me thinking
about this idea of like breeders having
different tiers of genetics like a
premium line where like kind of like
more work had gone into it or just kind
of like more of like a quicker project
but it was still ready for market
do you think you'd ever look into
something like this
um i always try to like classify some of
the seeds like i i do a lot of things
that they're not normally not sold or
released yeah but then sometimes once a
year i'll bring them out to like a
spannabis or whatever um i'll call those
exclusives
yeah
um then i will only like sell like 10 20
packs or whatever things like that um
but normally um i'll breed a line and i
intend to sell it for many years yeah
and i spent a couple of years to make
them as well yeah
um
[Music]
then i think it's very
reasonable to ask like 100 euros for
those seeds as well
yeah certainly i mean just to clarify
i'm i'm a hundred percent uh in favor of
the free market approach
so a question which i get drilled by the
fans if i don't ask it and heck i'm
interested as well what traits do you
look for when you're trying to find a
good breeding male
okay
let me
[Music]
start here then if you want to be able
to pick a good male
out of a gene pool
you have to grow that gene pool
first
yeah so you cannot have a gene pool that
you have never grown so i get these
afghani seeds yeah i've never grown this
these seeds that i have in my hand now
yeah i may have grown of ghani's but
that doesn't count yeah yeah so i'll pop
these seeds here i need to grow
quite a lot of those before i really
know the percentages of everything that
pops up um
how common it is um all these things
yeah and you get a relationship with
that gene pool then as well yeah so you
recognize things even without being able
exactly to say oh it's because of these
leaves oh it's because of that yeah
because you grow them you know that
family yeah
um you need to have that before you can
really
select the mail
and predict um
all the trades that it's going to give
yeah this is going to make your chances
way bigger of picking the right male
easier
then of course there is the stem rub the
structure
all these other things yeah
i'd always say with breeding and
selecting the most important thing is
killing a lot yeah
you don't start by picking the best
thing no you start by
taking everything out that's not good
whether it's weaker structure
not strong against illnesses all these
things yeah and then what you're left
over that's where you're gonna pick it
from
yeah definitely and so are there any
particular techniques or
um traits that you're specifically
looking for like i mean a really common
one we get told on the show is the old
faithful stem rub are you are you a fan
of the stem rub
i always do the stem rope as well yeah
i do stammer another good trick we use
is uh works with a lot of lines yeah um
like when you've grown everything before
yeah like i just said yeah um
you can
the females yeah um
the females you like the most yeah if
you write down the day exactly on when
it started to throw pistols
yeah
and then when you look at all the males
here and you look which one is closest
to the same day starting its sex yeah
and then you compare all the leaves
shapes as well between these females
then you can kind of pick amelia which
has similar genes to that female
yeah just by picking the day that it
started to flower yeah
yeah definitely
so
with that being said have you ever
considered or done a male reversal
before where you you know turn it into
the female so you can smell the smells
look at the structure and whatnot
no i haven't yet i'm very interested in
doing that though and then it would be
mostly for smelling it
and do you feel like that there would be
a good chance that that smell would
correlate to like what the male is
actually passing on
if when you grew that gene pool and you
grew all those seeds before
and you've seen um that smell being a
higher percentage in that group yes then
yes because then you can almost you have
a big chance that it's a dominant trait
yeah okay
so i mean while we're on the breeder
topic in general i mean you could
probably say that about the whole
interview but um
in just relation to that candy rain
situation we mentioned a few minutes ago
what do you think is a breeder's
responsibility in regards to seeds do
you feel like it's you know the breeders
responsibility to replace seeds that
have poor results or do you feel like
their obligation ends at the wholesaler
well i think that if you release c's and
you tested them and stuff then you know
what's not wrong with them yeah
um
so if then someone comes and says oh
everything herms or
everything does this yeah you know
that's not right yeah or you know that
person did something wrong yeah and well
you can't do something wrong that
everything hurts by the way yeah that's
that's really difficult yeah so if
everything hurts there's a problem with
those seats it's that simple
um
yeah definitely so i mean just to really
play the devil's advocate if someone
comes to you and says oh you know i grew
out of pacquiao seeds and i had one herm
out of 10. i'm not real happy would you
try to explain that that's like a
possibility or would you just be more
inclined to just try to make the problem
go away so to speak
oh i would definitely say that yeah
that's i tried to find out why first
yeah
with him yeah because if it's something
to do with the way it was grown or
he triggered it yeah
then it's nice for him to know as well
yeah because then it won't happen in the
future um when it's like one herm
in certain strains well it comes with
the territory as well then yeah um
so but i if people are unhappy i always
give them seeds yeah
that's that's that's not even a question
yeah
um
but i if i think it's right if one plant
herms in a pack um
like for instance with a cookie or a
sink hybrid no that that's to be
expected
yeah
most people won't complain even about it
when it's those though those gene pools
yeah because people know it already yeah
um i mean i have the same when i pull up
someone else's seats i i've
it doesn't matter if there's two three
herms i i i would never complain about
it to be honest personally yeah
yeah i i certainly feel like it's it's
part of the territory a lot of the time
so a topic i really wanted to ask you
about is just in general the concept of
cali import how do you feel this affects
local markets like i mean in the uk and
in holland i'm sure that there's plenty
of cali import do you feel like it hurts
local producers or it's too simplistic
to view it like that
no i was at the spannabis uh this year
and what i've seen is that the higher
quality local grown yeah that price went
way up and the only reason that went so
up so high is because that import weed
that was there before you
because that is so expensive it kind of
changed the market price yeah so um
i think if local growers grow really
good weed they get more money for their
wheat because the import was there yeah
and that changed the market prices
and so how do you feel about the hype
strains in general do you feel like it's
a good or a bad thing that certain
strains just get these
mind-boggling mass followings
oh that's that's just it's like fashion
yeah
that's just like fashion um
a lot of times it's not the best wheat
it's not the best flavor or things like
that yeah it has to be decent for it to
become a hype though um
but yeah some things just look good yeah
like
a purple punch yeah it looks great yeah
i i i i don't care for it at all yeah
um but it looks great um so yeah people
like that yeah then you have to think
about a lot of things that get hyped is
by
the younger people as well yeah
um what have they seen
before
what is the knowledge they have yeah um
they can only learn from the things that
they see yeah so if only thing they've
seen is that og
that gelato and that cookie
which is better than
the local swag or whatever yeah then i
understand that that's that's gold yeah
at that moment
yeah most certainly
so while we're on the topic of hype
strains it feels like gmo and even mac
have kind of had their time in the
spotlight what's your prediction for the
next strain that's going to take the
international stage by storm
um
i think the skittles and the papaya are
doing really well on that scale to be
honest
when about something new um
that's hard to say yeah because it's
like a fashion or like a music uh number
one hit yeah
um
never kind of know where it comes from
do you ever try to predict what will be
the next big thing and almost get ahead
of the curve in that regard
now to be honest i don't really i i
prefer i try to just work in what i
really like yeah um
[Music]
i try not to jump too fast on all the
hype i'll work with the strains that are
the hot thing though don't get me wrong
but i'm always a bit later than the rest
um
i always like to grow all of them before
so yeah so like i just did that gelato
crossing um
that's kind of bad as well yeah
um it's taking some of the hype yeah and
i'll cross with it what i like more yeah
so i crossed it with sour d
um
so yeah no i i definitely
use some of the hype strains but i'm not
trying to like
when something new is the hype and it's
not my hype that means it's from someone
else yeah i'm not the type of guy to
then uh take it fast um make it and be
the first to throw those seeds into the
market yeah
yeah of course
so um if we just loop back to the mac
for a moment i noticed a while back on
your instagram you put a post up and you
had managed to accumulate 10 packs of
mac how did that fino hunt go for you
did you ever get a chance to do it yet
i think um i didn't have ten packs of
mac one though
um
but yeah you know caps and
sent me and my friend stewart
multiple packs um those selections are
just
just happening now yeah
okay are you excited for that one
oh yeah yeah i'm definitely excited for
it definitely
definitely i haven't seen them yet yet
my friend is running them in the states
awesome and so what type of work would
you want to pair with that
um
for me that would be too early to say
yeah i got to see and smoke those before
i can like
before my mind starts to work and
picking like the combinations and stuff
um
i mean i'm i'll
next coming one and two years i'll be
crossing a lot with the sour d line yeah
um so everything that really interests
me probably also get crossed with that
for one thing
and
i don't know i think the mech is a
pretty
hashy type strain and
i know he did a bangers and mac which is
my headbanger times mac
i'm very curious to see what comes out
of those
and how did you feel about the mac in
general i'm sure you've had a chance to
smoke some of it
yeah
cap came to bring me some when i was
there
i think it smokes very smoothly yeah
it is not my
personal type flavor
and things like that yeah it's very
strong weed it is strong um
looks great nice nuggets everything
about that is really nice it's not 100
my flavor
um that's the only thing it's very i
think it's pretty hashy
in the way it smokes
it burns really nice yeah which is what
when wheat looks like
white yeah that means that the
stock that the trichome is on most times
are longer that makes the wheat look
white it's not the trichome itself yeah
but those type of strains that have a
longer stock they seem to burn different
yeah so they smoke really nice for that
like the sour d has really short stocks
yeah
it has a lot of trichomes but really
short stocks
which makes it a good strain for dry
screening
and the strains with longer stocks they
they get more dirty their ice cream
easier yesterday harder to screen clean
um i think the mac could be
when you breed with it i think it could
be a good strain to grow in like morocco
and for hash fields and stuff like that
to be really honest
yeah it's certainly undeniable the
overwhelming resin content of at least
the mach 1 cut
some little controversy surrounding it i
wanted to quickly ask you which you may
not have too much of an opinion on but
there's been some whispers recently
about
the the genetics of mac being possibly
inaccurate most notably the colombian
aspect it's it's kind of been suggested
by a few people that it just could
actually be some sort of super silver
haze cross
most of the evidence from that derives
from the fact that by cap's description
it just doesn't seem to fit the
flowering time of colombians it's just
too short at nine weeks
did you ever suspect something like this
or do you have any opinions on that one
i think that what the the plan that he
calls the colombian yeah he got from
family
from colombia
um
they said they were very special um
so it's not 100 sure that they're a
colombian land race yeah and
um i smoked it by the way yeah he
brought me that as well yeah um
and it definitely has a recognizable
thing with like a super silver type
terpenes yeah that i know from holland
um
it definitely had a
similarity to things like that yeah but
he's
like i think kept very genuine though
yeah um in where he got it from and what
it is and what he thinks it is yeah
um
but yeah i i don't think it's like what
the colombian like as most people know
yes and it could be
in some hybrid
siege that came over from europe before
there yeah and and that's why the person
says they're very special yeah i mean
there's a lot of possibilities in it
yeah i agree with you in the analysis
that i believe him when he says that
that's what it was given to him as for
sure
um so just on a kind of oh and the other
little caveat when i was at the emerald
cup and i got to smoke some mac from cap
it was by far the stand out of the cup
so
good smoke no question um
he grows great well yeah his crew and
they grow great weed yeah they grow such
nice weed yeah
yeah especially in the context of anyone
who's ever had some mac from him
there's no dispute they're like yeah
that's some of the best sweet i've ever
had but then other times you get other
people who have grown the mac one and
it's really just not even in the same
ballpark and so to me that highlights
the skill that they've got over that
plant
oh yeah 100
and that's with a lot of strains yeah
and
some of them
have like a certain way they need to be
grown
or um best way to say it is yeah when
you select plants for a greenhouse or
indoor grow you select them on that
system yeah
which made that plant very perfect for
that system as well yeah like you would
probably pick a different plant if you
grown indoor on soil then you grow
indoor on hydro yeah
yeah definitely i mean i tried some
outdoor grown mac and it just wasn't the
same
no but if you would have select a mac
outdoor you probably would have selected
a different plant as well yeah certainly
i i definitely agree with that just it's
very catered to what it was selected in
yes
so
last little kind of hype question for
this little block did you ever get into
the tangy craze
i did do some things with orange type
strains and also tangy jelly bean
um i'm personally not the biggest fan of
orange
flowers yeah
um they get sickening really fast then
the extract of it are amazing yeah
the extracts are always amazing yeah but
um i'm personally not the biggest fan of
the orange flavor i think it's a very
good strong terpene um i think
it's very nice and unique
um it has a lot of character
but it's not my personal smoke
okay so with that being said what are
your favorite
terpenes um i i like to smoke sourdis
cams
ogs
i gotta be honest i kind of enjoy
skittles as well the last few years
smoking that during the day um
what else do i like um i like like
afghanis that have that hash type flavor
in them yeah that hennessy
type thing and stuff as well yeah i like
those as
well so with that being said what are
some of the terpene profiles that you
really wish were still around but have
seemingly vanished
back in the day i used to grow a plant
that has that really smelled like
blueberry candy type smell yeah and i've
tried to find that i've grown so many
different blueberries and from different
people and from dj
and i never found that
typical
terp like that uh ever again yeah
yeah that's it's such a common point
made you know that everyone knows and
recognizes dj for the amazing work he's
done but at the same time it's so
goddamn hard to find that bang on
blueberry pheno which most people have
had once in their life and so you know
it exists but it's just like god where
is it hiding
yeah yeah it's exactly like that
it's exactly like that
and then i'm still looking for
a jack harrow
um there used to be a jack haircut here
in the south of holland yeah which was
uh selected by neville's
um he sold that cut to a group that runs
a coffee shop um they lost it they
bought it again
um
neville's didn't keep it yeah and they
lost it again yeah so it was extinct and
that cut off of jack herrer is nothing
like i've ever found in the seeds not
when i'm breeded with it or anything
yeah
and i just got some seeds
back seeds that came out of that time
from that weed in that coffee shop yeah
so now i got hope again to
maybe find and revive that one yeah um
that one smells so strong of [ __ ]
church incensia um
none of these other hazes have such a
strong incense smell as that had and it
was not a high wheat it's a very strong
stoned weed yeah which is doesn't really
fit the haze profile either a bit faster
flower as well yeah it should be done 11
12 weeks
yeah wow i mean i've i've been lucky
enough to try the
what's referred to as the 10k jackhair
cut
to other people
it's known as just
jack herrera's personal cut of jack
herrera
but um it sounds quite different to what
you described but i mean everyone knows
that good jack herrera is kind of
unbeatable
yeah this weed when it was here um you
could only max buy two grams of clients
yeah because otherwise they would run
out too fast yeah so everybody every day
went back to buy those two grams yeah
and you would try to get your friends
yeah to buy you two grams as well yeah
um
like total craze here in the city
yeah that was a big hit everybody in
this city that's my age still remembers
that like uh
one of the best weed that was in town
yeah
yeah okay so
brings us to an interesting question
what is the best bud you've ever smoked
ever period
sour diesel
easy answer or is there a close second
no that was the third thing i i thought
of but then i thought let me think about
let me go through all these things in my
head yeah but there's nothing that
can top that to be honest
it got all the flavor yeah and it's
really strong as well yeah
um
yeah it's hard to beat
for sure so something we've touched on
loosely but haven't really delved into
thus far
how do you feel about concentrates and
you know the rise of all the different
connoisseur concentrate varieties
well i like it a lot i think it's a big
part of the future as well yeah
um
i definitely like all the solvent-less
stuff
um
i like smoking that as well
um yeah i also think that it opens up a
whole new window yeah because um when
life extracted yeah um a lot of these
fertile terpenes and stuff yeah so you
get a very different product as well
yeah
which kind of makes that um that flower
you can change it in different type of
tastes and stuff as well yeah even
though it's the same source
i like that as well
i think medically it has a big purpose
as well
and so i guess the extension of that
idea how do you feel about vape pens and
the way they've seemingly kind of taken
over the
casual enthusiast community especially
within the states do you feel like it's
a good or a bad thing
i personally don't smoke any
distillate nothing
okay and what's your reasons for doing
that
well
a lot of it is not
i i i
i don't like the way it smokes um in
um
makes my throat tingle and and stuff
like that um
i know today there's like very clean
distillate yeah um
a few years ago most of it wasn't even
fully clean either um we all know what
to get made from yeah
um so
no that's not my
product to be honest i would prefer
a solvent-less or i do smoke some of
these saucepans though yeah
but this i'm not the biggest fan of to
be honest
so what's your favorite type of
concentrate
for me that would be
fresh frozen isolator
and so what do you tend to do with your
trim when it's ready to be processed
um
i mean
when i see crops i i dry screen
everything before the seeds are taken
out yeah so i most times have more dry
skin to my disposal
than other things um
but the fresh frozen uh washed hash yeah
and then
freeze dried um
i think that's a really nice product
yeah
yeah definitely i mean
a lot of that really high quality
concentrates made in that regard it's
not really available in many countries
outside of like
say america and
holland maybe spain
yeah no it's true i think spain is even
way more than it is in holland that type
of uh hash
um
yeah now it takes a lot of material as
well yeah um
it's an expensive product when uh
cannabis is very expensive in your
country or when it's fully legal yeah um
then why would you
then you're probably better off smoking
flour yeah
when it comes to um worth for your money
kind of thing yeah um because these
products get very expensive of course
certainly
so in line with our comments made about
the vape pens and kind of how they're
taking over the the amateur consumer
market do you feel like it's going to
more or less be inevitable that we'll
see the takeover of corporate cannabis
and is this a bad thing per se
um
we will definitely see were we already
seeing a takeover of corporate cannabis
everywhere it's
legal um
i personally do think um that in the
coming years that market will even out a
little bit yeah they will first take
everything over and they'll kick
everybody out kind of thing yeah
um but then the people
are not happy yet because then they only
kind of get the mids to smoke yeah it's
that simple to be honest
and don't get me wrong there are some
big people that do it well as well yeah
they're not the biggest yeah but in the
mid size there's a lot of people growing
really good flour on a big scale yeah as
well
um
and don't get me wrong when it's legal
there's a lot of weed that's needed yeah
as well um so
even though we all want it to be all
small um home and mom and pop type
grows i don't think that's realistic
when it's like a fully legal market yeah
um
it's same thing when you look at beer
and wine yeah
a real wine drinker yeah he would like
the wines that get produced on smaller
scale and very special and things like
that
but then the big messes yeah
they only care for that cheaper red wine
yeah they don't mind that much you
understand it's gonna be the same with
the cannabis market yeah the big masses
yeah they're not like um all the really
uh cannabis heads yeah that are really
like patient and totally into it yeah
so they don't even know that many
strains or whatever and things like that
yeah not everybody is smoking every day
or like we do
so i think that's the biggest part of
the
public that will smoke yeah
so um there will always be a place for
big corporate and for
as we call it midsuite yeah
it's that simple i think the market for
the high high quality and the
specialized things yeah is smaller than
most people think
in the big mass
yeah of course so how do you think the
connoisseur community will survive and
adapt during this inevitable takeover
like we always have man no matter what
happens people will always no matter if
it's legal illegal um whatever
the real people that are really
interested in they will always keep on
germinating seeds they will always be
growing the better wheat um
yeah so a lot of times that will still
stay in the
gray market for
a while i think yeah because in these
legal places it's not possible for every
these licenses in some places are so
expensive it's so hard to get them you
have to go through so many things yeah
you already need capital to even start
it off yeah it needs to be a legal
capital as well yeah so it's not like oh
i made a hundred thousand growing wheat
legally now i'm gonna start go legal and
i'll use this hundred thousand to start
up that's not the way it works
yeah so legal money needs to come in for
something big to happen yeah so
there's kind of no other roads than
there is yeah
so how do you feel about the idea of
companies or even individuals like say
breeders who want to patent their work
do you feel like this is just an
inevitable fact of the legalization or
do you feel like it's a significant step
in the wrong direction
um
well it's always been free because it's
illegal
so you wouldn't copyright anything
but if you look at any other
seed or breeding
with other plants um it's very normal
kind of to be honest and i can
understand for some people as well yeah
it's going to be abused though that's
what every everybody's scared about
being abused yeah and i'm scared about
that as well yeah so all these bigger
people just taking [ __ ] away that other
people made and things like that yeah
um but if you really worked for things
for many years um
and you could i i can't [ __ ] be angry
at people to be honest for that yeah um
there always will be a huge [ __ ] free
market anyway yeah because anything
that's already been sold or that's
already won a prize that you cannot
copyright that anymore
yeah it's already a free-for-all it's
that simple so um
to copyright the strain um it's not as
easy
as it looks yeah
it needs to be unique you need to prove
all these steps before
so yeah a lot of these things can't even
be copyrighted yeah it's that simple
i agree i agree they're kind of already
in public domain so
just jumping to a slightly different but
related point how do you feel about the
rise of celebrities jumping on the
cannabis bandwagon like specifically i'm
sorry i'm sure you've seen that seth
rogen has launched his own brand
and you know we've had that dan
bilzerian guy hovering around for a
while do you feel like this is good in
the sense that it's just giving greater
exposure to the masses or do you think
in general it's just a move towards
generic negative bud
i think it's both
um i think it's very good for the big
public opinion um and making it accept
it for like all the public that didn't
accept it before yeah
um i think it's very good for things
like that um
and no matter what it is that's gonna
make money yeah people that have money
invest their money in those type of
things now if you smoke weed yeah i
understand they will invest into weed
type things yeah um
we all know that if you're a good actor
that doesn't mean you have a good
cannabis company yeah that's
i mean
if you're good before the camera that
doesn't mean you can grow good weed yeah
but if you have good people the weed can
be good just as well
um so i guess we just have to test all
of them yeah it's that simple
yeah okay would you ever buy cannabis
that was labeled simply as hybrid or
indica
um
no
we need to have something more than that
it needs something more than that i i
hate buying weed that i cannot smell or
touch to be honest yeah i understand you
can't touch weed in the dispensary or in
a coffee shop anymore today but um
i want to feel and smell it yeah before
i buy it
yeah of course it's a very
understandable sentiment so sadly i
missed you at the last emerald cup we
were both at but i'd love to know your
opinion on the event overall and what
event do you enjoy the most
i love the emerald cup when i went there
i was
i was so i didn't expect it to be like
that yet there was so i thought it was
very crowded yeah maybe a little bit too
crowded for the space there was
um
i've never seen seed sales as happened
at the emerald cup i've never seen
anything like that before the span abyss
it's not like that spanish this is a
really nice show yeah it's really good
for seats as well
but the emerald wow
i've never seen anything like that
and what was the most impressive
cannabis you saw at the emerald cup
um
i'll be honest i didn't see that much we
you have to understand when i go to the
these events yeah there's so much people
that want to see you or you're trying to
meet or having a little talk to you
that the days just fly by there yeah and
i almost never can see the whole expo
yeah no don't worry i can i can
definitely agree with you and the
interesting thing is is that you would
expect pretty much everything that you
get shown is pretty good but
sadly there's only a few standouts
oh yeah definitely definitely definitely
it's always the private weed yeah so um
it's kind of people that are visiting
um that grown out stuff
some of those people will have the best
most times
yeah for sure
so
what do you think is one of the most
underrated clones and why do you think
people seem to flock to specific clones
like cookies given that even by your own
admission they've got a lot of downsides
like the yield and the stability
yeah that's just the
hype and market value and uh
people need to have it
that makes it still
that yeah the cookie thing
um
so what do you think is one of the most
underrated clones in your opinion
um
i think a clone that has a very bad name
but if you look at all the concentrates
from today it kind of should be in there
it's the critical
yeah wow i was not expecting you to say
that
no it's a really nice fruity weed yeah
um
it's not my personal thing but i pray
extract and it's fast it yields it's
really easy to grow i'm surprised that's
not
a big thing to be honest yet everybody
hates on it because the spanish always
use it to reverse and hit everything
with it because it produces so much
pollen when it's reversed
and it doesn't give much hermione
offspring so that's why they love it so
much and they cross it with everything
um but on itself pure um that cut that's
everywhere in spain yeah um
life resin from that is gotta be really
good yeah
so i don't understand why that's not
being grown in [ __ ] piles in the us
yeah i can certainly attest that i've
had some critical jack in the past and
that was extremely memorable a really
good smoke so
with that being said what do you think
overall about the spanish scene is it
something you're looking to explore
further yourself and do you think it's
going to be the new big place to be
well i lived in spain in
2007 2008
um
it was very different then than it is
now but i've always been coming there i
come there a couple times a year
um i have many friends over all of spain
um the scene there is really nice yeah
it grows every year and the vibe is like
it used to be in holland now yeah
because all these smaller passionate
growers um
so for that i think it's very it's it's
making a lot of progress and i think in
from europe it's definitely the place
most things happening at the moment
um so yeah that's really nice
um it's still everything is illegal yeah
people think it's legal there it's not
um you can grow some wheat for yourself
yeah but
not in the way most people do
yeah so do you think that a lot of
amateur people have the wrong idea and
it's a common idea or sentiment to hear
people say you know i'm gonna pack my
bags and move to spain do you think that
that's a bit of an ill-conceived thought
um no when you compare
in europe where you're best off to grow
wheat it's still spain
um
because if you don't do it too big yeah
there's not much of a problem to be
honest
they don't come into your house very
fast yeah which has to do with the
history
houses the rents are very cheap um it's
very socially accepted as well yeah
so um even though it's illegal the
chance of getting cut or getting into
trouble
is way smaller than in almost every
other country in europe
yeah okay so there's still some hope
there
and you can grow really good outdoor
weed there like really good yeah so um
that's a cheap way for people so making
this step even though you're not having
a lot of money and stuff yeah um spain
is not that expensive as well yeah so a
lot of times it's cheaper to live there
than where people live in currently yeah
and then if they can grow some plants
outdoor
that doesn't cost much money as well
yeah so the possibility is there for a
lot of people as well
yeah yeah okay
so spain commonly known for its
feminized seeds
will you ever offer feminized seeds i
know you've been asked this in the past
i do some
feminized seeds
i've only sold them in europe
and i am currently making feminized
seeds as well um everybody knows i i i'm
all about regular seeds but the market
definitely demands feminized seeds yeah
um
like most companies they only sell like
five or ten percent
seats yeah if they offer them and then
the rest is all feminized and that's not
because they make that but that's also
because that's what people buy in europe
yeah
yeah certainly and so do you think that
there's a misconception within the
community that feminized seeds are
better for growers
i think the reason why they sell so well
in europe is because
a lot of people only want to grow a few
plants
and they grow with like one light um so
they cannot keep moms yeah they only
want to have five like in holland they
only want to have five plants yeah
because if they have five plants they
won't get any punishment if they are
caught
yeah so
yeah then they prefer feminized seeds i
can understand that
if the plant number is not a problem i
personally prefer to just
pop twice as much seeds and
pop regular seeds
speaking of growing what is your number
one grow tip for our audience you know
what's something that you commonly see
that gets overlooked or an aspect of
growing which is fairly underrated
um
well the thing i see here in europe
a lot
is
people only really start to concentrate
on um
their yield and their flour
once plants are in flower for four weeks
the most important thing about growing
cannabis is the starches the roots
it's all about the roots if you don't
have any roots you cannot get a lot of
fruits it's that simple
um so i think people should con
concentrate a lot on
rooting their plans really well yeah
yeah a point that i've discussed with uh
the legend himself duke diamond a lot is
that people don't pay enough attention
to the root system and even a way in
which people can select males is
when you're doing the selection of the
males
to literally tease the
the medium out of the root ball and take
a look at the root ball like kind of see
the male that i think is the best does
it have a big root ball because i think
that that's an interesting idea
i think it's a very interesting and very
good idea as well
cool so
the inevitable question what medium do
you prefer to grow in and what
advantages do you think this has
okay i am
me um i grow
all different mediums
but i mostly grow cocoa at the moment
when i look to my like my group and my
friends there are the people that i work
with
i have one group that only grows hydro
then i have one group that only grows in
greenhouses they grow mostly organic
that's when i grow for myself to smoke
um i prefer
soil
but then i'll grow like 80 organic and
20 mineral
and do you feel like you're getting the
best of both worlds because i i know
some really good growers who do exactly
that
well i'm a very strong advocate of
always telling people like um or i grow
80 mineral 20 organic yeah and that
would be on cocoa or a hydro system
when i grow on soil i'll grow 80 organic
and 20 mineral you take the best from
both yeah
um
it's very smooth weed it's very clean um
you get a lot of good
a lot of flavor points and stuff from uh
organic weed yeah um
but you can get a lot of strength um and
a
nice structure and things like that very
easily with a mineral supplement
so this might be a bit of a hard
question for you to quantify but over
the years how many different plants do
you think you've grown and do you think
exposing yourself to a wide variety of
genetics makes you a better grower or a
better breeder
a better breeder i definitely think yeah
because
it's just like a cook the more different
food you've eaten and tasted yet the
better you can work with flavors yeah so
um
how many
oh man i i wouldn't even dare to put a
number on it yeah
um
but the last years we did such big
germinations of so many different seeds
yeah that um it really flew up yet the
last years
um
i must have grown
more than 500 varieties
more than 500 for sure
jesus
that's a lot
so when you popping a new strain whether
it be yours or someone else's how many
seeds do you like to pop to get a feel
for it and the reason why i asked this
is because often in australia where i'm
from which a lot of people probably
already know
um you see people popping like three c's
out of a ten pack and i just like you
know i try not to be harsh but like i
just have to shake my head
then you only see like that's like
opening a box of bon bons yeah which are
all different
um and you taste three yeah
it's the same thing yeah
let me well it all depends on the source
of the seed as well the three seeds are
not enough um but let's just say most
seed packs are like 10 seeds yeah um
if you pop that you
should see a part of the whole gene pool
if they're good seeds yeah and if you
want to see everything that's in there
and they're really good stable seeds
um
then it's probably like 200 seeds yeah
and then it's already good if you grow
like a land raise yeah you probably need
like five thousand yeah
yeah i can certainly agree and and it
makes me look back at some of the work
the earlier guys did where they had to
breed things for multiple generations
just to stabilize it before they could
even think about outcrossing it
oh yeah for sure
for sure like if you start with
um like really raw land raised seats or
even hybrids that are like messier as i
call it um so they have a lot of
variations and herbs and everything in
it
then you need to grow
a lot of seeds yet to
make a group out of those
that all don't have those bad things in
it yeah and you need to cross those with
each other the whole group
and then germinate them all again yeah
and then the percentage of all the
problems should go down and down
um that's why you can start only yeah so
it all depends on your starting point
how many seeds you need to germ yeah
if you want to be really serious and
want to do it all at once
um i think with modern hybri
bread seeds if you pop 500 c's you
should be enough
um you don't need 10 000 like with land
races or 5 000
yeah so with that point in mind what
requirements do you place on your own
strains before you deem it ready for
market and what type of things would
make you reconsider whether you're going
to release a strain or not
okay my my aim my aim is um
to when you pop one or two packs of
seeds
that you find the type of plant that um
i wanted you to find yeah that
what i think the strain represents
um or that is like the cut that i picked
myself
that's what i try to do
um
this is not on every strain yeah but i
have quite a few strains which are like
that yeah that's why i like the back
crossing so much so i can
corner some um
traits and pinos uh in that gene pool
more yeah so that there's less variation
and you have a bigger chance to fight
that thing in less seats
um so like for example the headbang area
if you pop two packs of seeds
you some people have a hard time to
really pick what they want to keep yeah
um there is some variation in it but
it's not all over the board yeah
every plant is clearly the same strain
with some of the seeds of today if you
pop them
some things from me as well like let me
give an example a skull cap yeah um
that's a sour hat stash
times biker yeah um that has way more
variation than uh a headbanger for
example yeah so you will find very a lot
of different things in that yeah so um
that's not like what i would normally
sell or release yeah
but people do love
the variation these days yeah
i think there's also a very big
difference in the market
like in america people
germinate these seeds to select a plant
uh a clone to keep as a mom
to be cropped yeah for production yeah
um
here
it's a lot of times not like that yeah
so people
kind of want to buy a pack of seeds grow
them and then two three years later they
think oh that was nice yeah i'm gonna
grow that again and they want to buy a
pack of seeds and find the similar
things that they found before yeah
so um
that's a bit of a difference yeah um
when it's for selection um
and for a commercial market as a
producer people try to have their own
thing yeah so then they want kind of
more variation today
when it's to american people and stuff
yeah most certainly so
what would you say would be a
kind of a deal breaker for you with a
strain so the the hypothetical i like to
give people is if you had a strain and
you just thought it was amazing it was
unique it was gonna take the market by
storm but the downside was that there
was like one herme in every pack just on
average
would that be a deal breaker for you and
if not what would be the definitive deal
breaker if everything else was just
perfect so to speak
um if my own test grows um like if it
would be one herm in a pack that would
be like 10
i probably
that'd probably be the max yeah i would
probably still release that
i would it would be known though before
i release it yet because i'm very open
about every test grow all these other
things and stuff so everybody i would i
would clearly state it as well
um
but when i don't like to release strains
is when um
the album is weaker than both parents um
or the goal because i most times breed
with a goal before i even start
selecting plans and doing things yeah
um
if that goal's not met i'm kind of not
really
i lose interest i don't want to release
it yeah as well
um
and when i what i really don't like to
release is when um
you get like
females
in in those seed packs that are like
really
not worth smoking yeah then i don't like
to release it yet even a bad plant in it
yes you'd still be okay yeah it should
still be nice okay to smoke and
things like that um
of course for people when they only grow
like five or ten plants and there's like
two plants that's just not enjoyable to
smoke yeah that that's terrible yeah
that's just terrible
yeah so
while we're talking genetics what is one
strain or just in general line that you
love to work with but you just don't
have access to
um
i gotta be honest jeff
i've been in this i've been growing for
almost 30 years now i was in the forums
very early as well yes i have like a
really
big white network um and i traveled a
lot as well
most times if i think of something yeah
um
and i really start asking it kind of
almost always really comes out yeah but
then there are some things that are
probably like maybe not even true yeah
like um
they used to be talking about this cut
called asia fantasia yeah
um i never seen that um
i would be interested to see it if it's
even real um
outside of that
no
well maybe some land races but then i
just don't know i'm looking for them yet
so is there any land race that you don't
have access to that you wish you did
i have different
nepalese yeah and i have something with
nepal as a country yeah i've spent there
months
before
um
but it's so diverse
yeah all the weed that i've seen there
in different places so many different
smells and things here that someone says
nepalese well that could be so many
different things yeah
um
but yeah that definitely intrigues me a
lot yeah and it's something i haven't
[ __ ] or spent a lot of time in in
germinating
seats from nepal so
that's definitely something i want to do
i don't think it has a huge commercial
aspect though but it definitely has a
big personal interest
yeah of course and i guess that just
reinforces that point you made about b
and what he could bring to the table but
with that being said are there any
countries you would love to go and do
your own little seed pilgrimage in
yeah i'd love to go to afghanistan to be
honest
um i love to go back to nepal as well
yeah
and hindu couch yeah i'd like to
yeah i like that region i would like to
it's not the time to go there now yeah
for me um but i would lovely like
to search around there
yeah so do you feel like there is still
some really good stock to be gained from
these areas or do you feel like it's
already been watered down and as an
extension of that
how do you feel about the actions of
some of the people who have gone there
in the past and diluted the seeds with
more modern genetics
as for the
well i think some of these places are
not that welcoming at this time yeah um
those places is there will be loads of
little cells and stuff here
which are now kind of hard to get to
yeah
there's definitely a lot of stuff there
yes still i'm 100 sure also untouched
yeah when it comes to afghanistan
definitely in nepal yeah because you
have to understand those are the
mountains and the himalaya here so even
when you
bring in seeds yeah and then most bigger
growers are always in the valley and not
on the top
um
that pollen doesn't travel as far
as in like a flat dry country here
so um
and it kind of breeds itself out as well
pretty fast in most places as well like
in morocco yeah um
if they would not bring any more of
these seeds in there yeah in a couple of
years a lot of things will turn back as
well yeah which has to do with that uh
different flowering times of these
genetics yeah so that it kind of starts
to separate each other as well
if you just let it go
and so
where do you think would be
the highest chance of getting pure land
race
um
i think the
himalayas like like i said i think
mountain regions are very good just
naturally yeah because it's harder to
get all these cross-pollinations and
stuff and you get all these little cells
that evolve themselves
um so i think those are always good
places
um yeah then places where it's not that
welcome and there's not that many people
as well yeah um so um yeah i mean uh
afghanistan used to be very open and
very welcoming and stuff and you can
still go there don't get me wrong but a
lot of people won't go there now yeah
so um yeah then it's protected more as
well yeah
yeah most certainly let's just jump back
to the modern world of breeding for a
moment i was cruising through your ig
last night and i saw some photos of the
white og
god they looked awesome reminded me of
the old school photos of deep chunk from
tom hill so two-parter question
what did you think of the white og
and what do you think of tom hill
um
tom hill
i've grown deep chunk before i like tom
hill in the back in the days on the
forums and stuff very knowledgeable gaia
and someone that
yeah did it kind of really and also
teached a lot of us all kinds of things
here
so yeah no i have big respect for tom
hill
um white og y2g that's
the strain that i had my first prize at
high times cup with and i think in
2010 or 2009
um
after that i lost that original milia in
the police bust
um
so i made a new version here
um which is the v2 which is what every
which everywhere now and what i've sold
all the time um now that won almost
every first prize in spain years ago
yeah
um
it's a very good strain it kind of came
out a little bit after
the wide fire from og rascal that was a
feminized thing um
this was like a regular
og times the white yeah at that time
that there were not that many of those
things around to be honest as well now
there's a lot of og times the white
yeah certainly do you think that if you
had for example jungle boys do a massive
pheno hunt of your strains it would help
put you on the map a bit more
oh yeah of course
everybody looks at
that yeah and they're very good at that
as well yeah um no of course if someone
like jungle boys or if burner or
some of these other promoting or people
that really get looked at
if they grow your things
it always makes you noticed way more of
course
and so how do you feel about companies
like jungle boys and even cookie fam who
are expanding out into kind of the
clothing domain and becoming more of a
lifestyle brand than just a cannabis
brand what do you think of this idea and
would you ever consider it for your own
brand
uh nah not me man
i'm like a garden guy i'm not even a
business or a seed company i've
i'm not that good at all that part of it
even yeah
um
so no no
me that won't happen for sure and i'm
way too sober i'm like a sober dutch guy
yeah so uh
no
i go to hollywood and la a lot and
the difference is too big i cannot
become that yeah it's just not possible
yeah it's not in my nature um
but um
yeah i think it's good that they do that
to be honest yeah i think it kind of
fits
a wrapper more
to be busy with a clothing brand and
lifestyle
than a wheat brand if i'm honest
yeah of course of course
so with that being said what would be
your advice for a newly starting out
breeder what's the best way they can
kind of get themselves and get their
name a bit more exposure
um
well the first thing i think if you want
to like i get this question so much here
people want to become a start a seed
company and want to begin in breeding
and things like that yeah
now if you want to sell seeds commercial
with how the market is and how the
public looks at it yeah
you
one you have to be a little bit more
original than it is at the moment yeah
that's one thing i think yeah
the other thing is if you're gonna make
regular seats
put some effort
in your meal yeah because the meal is
what it's all about yeah you gotta breed
your meal you don't pick a meal from
someone else's seeds you always create
your own meal you can create it with
stuff you buy from different people and
things like that but you create your own
mail by crossing things a few times or
things like that yeah um then you have a
unique mail as well yeah which also
makes it you don't get copied the same
thing like i all these other people are
yeah
so i think that's very important then i
personally think it's always best to
select everything from seed that you use
yeah if you just use the cost that
everybody use you're just gonna be one
of the rest and you're not going to be
noticed that much either yeah now by
doing that you do have to prove more
yeah
because then people say oh yeah well i
don't know what that is oh yeah you know
that's from seed yeah what a lot of
people say these days which is of course
is nonsense every clone comes from seeds
then i think you do need to enter some
cups yeah because
that's kind of the starting rolling
point that's what these cups are still
good for
if no one knows about you and you win
these cups or you win one or two of them
and then it get that dust get the ball
rolling yeah that will get a few good
growers interested to try out your seeds
then when good growers grow your seeds
um and they post it over social media
and things like that then the flame
really starts to burn
yeah what a fantastic sentiment that
kind of echoes my exact personal views
so a question i do want to quickly ask
though how long or what process should
someone go through before they start to
label themselves a breeder it seems to
me as though as soon as people first get
the idea that they would like to breed
they're immediately a breeder
do you care about things like this and
what do you think are kind of the
necessary
steps before you can really start to
label yourself as such
i didn't label myself a breeder to like
a couple of years ago
i mean
when you
cross things you're breeding yeah so in
all honesty
yeah they are breeders yeah um even when
you start you're kind of are a breeder
yeah
um
i think if you use it as a
classification yeah you gotta have some
experience and some knowledge though
before you put that on i mean i hate the
name master grower for example yeah so
the master breeder that that's like a
no-go for me
that's like a no-go if anyone calls
himself a master breeder
yeah no i don't think
i don't think people are capable to
learn in all of that in even one life
yeah most certainly just
i had i had a
someone email me
asking if they could get on the show and
i was like uh no sorry um
the show's really just kind of for
breeders and as tongue-in-cheek i was
like oh and also master growers and they
replied and they were like well i'm
actually a master grower and i was like
dude i was joking
yeah no that's a terrible term master
grower yeah
we call them head growers yeah i think
that's a good name for it
in these bigger operations if you're
like that guy that has to um
manage everything and uh or the one and
responsible and stuff yeah then you're a
hat grower yeah that's a good term for
it i think a master grower that's like
uh that's like kung fu movie it's that's
not the way it is
i think it's kind of like you don't
acknowledge that there's we're all
students you know there's still more to
learn
oh yeah there
this is so young yeah definitely now it
gets legal and open yeah you see
everything moving way faster yeah oh
there's gonna be so much in the coming
years yeah that's gonna
change yeah so oh
yeah
none of us know it all yet
of course of course so
what do you think about clone hoarding
do you think it's kind of a necessity
when you're breeding to just keep
certain things to yourself or at least
out of the hands of public so that it's
kind of like makes your work a commodity
or do you think overall it's somewhat a
hindrance to the community
the only thing i don't like as much is
like
when all your clones get into the hands
of these other seed makers yeah
um i kind of like it if my
uh breeding clones get grown for flower
and the flower would be everywhere yeah
i kind of like that yeah but
you have to protect something sometimes
when you're a commercial seed company
though um outside of that i like to
share stuff yeah i've shared most of my
things with a lot of people
so a question i wanted to quickly run by
or probably could have segued it in
somewhere earlier but here is as good as
any point i figure would you ever
consider working with companies like
philos and do you have any concerns
about these kind of genetic mapping
companies and the potential implications
in the future of what could happen with
this data
um
well my friend sure he had some things
tested from me by them as well and we
are doing like a breeding type thing
with them now but then i did pick
what we're gonna do and which gene pool
kind of carefully as well yeah so i
picked super silver haze because it's so
widespread and there's nothing to
protect about it but it's very special
on all those seats
so i thought that'd be a good one to use
for that
i did not enter all my special or unique
things in there though
and i'm not gonna do that either
but there is some clones from me that
did get into filos
i'm just not the one that entered them
the the a5 cut is in there now
one that i know is that came from me um
and went to someone and that person gave
it away to someone else and that one
entered it and i know that one's
certified yeah um that came from me uh
so i know that one's genuine yeah um
that's a seats they entered it
um so you can check that up then my cut
my melon cut is in there as well this is
the mom of the seeds of the dum melon
um that one's in there as well
um
and they think there's another one in
there as well
um
yeah do do tell us a little bit more
about the melon or the the melon cut
itself because i saw that one when i was
looking at some of your strengths and i
was like melon's one of those terpene
profiles you you just don't come across
as regularly you know it's kind of like
a hot commodity what do you think of the
melon cut
well let me just say um
i named this cut
melon yeah this is this is
probably
yeah
um
and people always ask me what is it i
said well
they come from seeds that i traded on
overgrow and they were labeled fruity
skunk
number two or three
and i had a few different bags with just
like different numbers on them there's
definitely no skunk in it at all um it
is more has more og type thing to it and
then this one had like a
green melon candy yeah type smell and
flavor to it yeah that's very unique
um my other friend says it smells like
lychees yeah
um
it's not
the watermelon or the jeans that
afterwards um
came into cali and stuff like that this
was there way before that
do you have any plans to work it further
at all
oh yeah 100
the
that weed i used to always only grow it
myself and smoke it
myself it's like one of my favorite
indicas to smoke
so if i could only pick two weeds i
probably have that as my indica and then
i have my sour d as my like sativa type
hybrid
yeah i'm definitely going to work more
with it i'm selecting males at the
moment
yeah okay interesting interesting so i
just wanted to jump back to a point you
you didn't specifically say but i think
you're alluding to it before you've been
working with the dutch consulting
company how's that been
yeah so that's a company i've put up
with
two friends and then another person
that's like the financial backbone of it
um
yeah that's that's really great yeah
that's really great that's me sure tam
and roger um
yeah that company's
like one was needed um and i think it's
a big success and it's it's only just
started that as well yeah so um
yeah no that's a
match made in heaven there
fantastic and what types of things can
we expect from you guys moving forward
um
so we do a consultancy for
most times it's bigger bigger projects
yeah
a lot of times this project has already
been running and then
kind of don't work yeah so we come in
and fix the problem kind of thing
now i'm the genetic consultant and
genetic guy yeah so i'll bring in
a lot of these seed batches not just
from me but from friends and everywhere
um then shirt which is a gene finder og
on
instagram
um he's like our growth specialist yeah
um he's very special um nan got tams my
other partner he's like um
he's our business guy yeah um
he's the guy to sit at the table with
all these
corporate type people and stuff like
that
um roger as well he has like a banking
background yeah so there are
i i call it our
bridge yeah between like um
our
group and seeing like morally
alternative hippie really garden
cannabis type guys
and then they're like the bridge in
between us and the
guys that don't kind of don't grow weed
yeah and it sits behind the desk
yeah so
that makes it work yeah you need that
bridge in between it for it to work with
better
and that seems to work really well
so when you get brought in to help fix
up some of these problem operations
what's one of the most common things you
see that they're getting wrong that you
need to fix up for them
well all the things that we've done now
they're definitely the genetics was like
very boring and just like what you see
all these big people grow yeah they
they all grow a lot of gorilla glue for
blue dream all those type of plants yeah
um
so you can already make a big change in
that um then ipm is always a huge
[ __ ] up
um
all these grows most times are too dirty
yeah um
and don't get me wrong it's very hard to
grow clean good cannabis on a big scale
yeah it's very difficult
it takes a very
good management and
system yeah
for that to work yeah because you work
with a lot of people
um it's not easy to do yeah
once you turn it around it it's like a
huge difference yeah it becomes a huge
difference
yeah okay so when you're dealing with
these large commercial operations what's
the type of lighting technology you're
usually advocating for and does that
differ from what you would use on a
small homegrown level
um
no
it would be pretty simple now that
aspect would be
a responsibility for not for me but for
a gene finder yeah
that would be his part of the thing he's
like way more knowledgeable and on all
those things than i am yeah there's so
much test experience with all these
different things as well um me indoor i
i run gravitas yeah
if i put up a room somewhere
um
but in the bigger greenhouses now that
we're running there um we're putting in
led lights in the one in california and
seems to work well as well so
yeah okay
and
do you have any concerns about
the gavitas and how they were bought out
by bayer or whatever the monsanto
whatever it was a while ago i heard
rumors of that
um
i i don't like it
when it is like that um i'd be honest i
got ones that are very old yeah they
they're from way before that time
but uh
now it sucks if you support something
wrong yeah
and there is different ones these days
as well which are just as good yeah as
long as the double ended and the 400
volt technique is what really makes
those lights
yeah definitely definitely
so
with that being said
i wanted to ask you a bit more of a
general question
what do you think is one of the most
commonly misunderstood parts of breeding
um
oh i think that
like today everybody is like yeah no
that's an f1 it needs to be an f4
i'm like well what does that mean then
yeah
none of those things mean anything yeah
um it's all about the selection and the
stability of the parents used yeah like
there is not even that much of the true
f1 for sale in the market yeah everybody
calls across and have one these days
yeah that's not a true f1 a true f1 is
bred by two stable parents here that
don't give a lot of variations on
themselves yeah
so um
and then they think the f2 would be like
more stable and f3 would be more stable
and f4 that all depends on how you
select
on the guy that bred it and how he did
his work
that number doesn't say much like that
yeah so i think that's a big
misunderstanding at the moment
so what type of labeling or nomenclature
would you want to use for kind of the
poly hybrids where it is just you know
two unstabilized things whacked together
is that like a
we can't say p1 but maybe poly hybrid
one
no we can't call it a p1 because that's
what we call a stable parent um
i don't know to be honest yeah i think
they should not they
it should be it's just a cross yeah
it's just a cross that's that's what it
is it it um
i think that shouldn't even be labeled
it should definitely
not be labeled in f1 or we should label
the true f1s through f1 like tf1
yeah
certainly i mean i i always think about
this in the context of like someone like
dj short who's very much worked his
lines from the bare land races it's like
it must be frustrating when you're
seeing people label things and yours is
the only thing that actually complies
with it
oh yeah for sure oh for sure
for sure
for sure like
ibl i hope to in my life uh make two
ibl's yeah which will just be like
working on the lines that i'm already am
because how many ibl's you think you can
make in a lifetime yeah
yeah i mean if you we go back to
afghanistan right it took families many
generations to do it so
yeah
yeah okay so with that in mind what
keeps you motivated to keep breeding in
an ever more challenging environment
i will never i always say you only lose
when you quit yet
but trust me in all these years i've
bumped into a lot of problems
yeah um
i lived the life of the snake and ladder
a lot of times yeah so you climb up but
you get trouble comes and you fall down
to the ground again yeah
um
but i will never ever quit you yeah i
like i st i sell seeds so that i can do
more breeding yeah because it costs a
lot of money
um
the passion is bigger than
than anything in it yeah
like i i've got away from my family for
months
i've taken risks all kinds of things
yeah
and then people think
how the hell can you do it for the i
just have to do it yeah
it's the passion in it you had to drive
yeah
i would do anything to keep on doing it
yeah okay so
can't take the plan out of the boy
no
it's one of the most important things in
my life it's that and then my fam and my
family yeah that's it
those things are like they're they're
almost they're almost equal to me
yeah no i agree
so
next question i had for you who is your
favorite breeder who's currently active
and have you ever considered doing a
collab with them
and
i have a couple of breeders that i
really like yeah and i respect
all of them are pretty different um as
well yeah um
like i have a lot of respect for simon
from serious seeds um
then two of my friends which is jj and
camarado i like them a lot and then
bowdai as well yeah
those are people i really
like and i grow a lot of seeds from as
well yeah
um and then when people ask me or my
friends i say oh you gotta try some of
this guy and that guy those seats are
good as well yeah so those four people i
really think are
definitely deserve
a lot of recognition
yeah for sure
so
with that being said i noticed that in
the past you'd done a collab with moscow
using the c99bx so the first question
that jumped to mind was
when
seoul and duke re-brought back brothers
grimm
did you immediately think to yourself oh
cool let's let's redo that project with
the real c99 or was it very specific to
that relationship you had with moscow
yeah i know moscow for a long time
personally um
so
and at that time there was no other he
was the only one offering c99 at the
time as well it was what he was known
for at that time on the forum as well so
that was the thing to do if we do a
co-op that it was very obvious it needed
to be dead
um i have not grown the re-releases of
uh brother grimm's c99 yeah um i still
have to do that to be honest so i
haven't grown them yet a really good
duke did an awesome job bringing that
one back so
my next question is
do you think it's possible to
selectively breed cannabis for specific
medical properties like for example do
you think you could set out to create a
strain that's going to help with like
crohn's for example or do you think it's
just kind of luck of the draw in terms
of if the strain happens to be
specifically good for a certain ailment
no i think with lab testing these days
um i mean you it needs to be tested
people need to test it yeah and then
when they find out this works way better
yeah and we have have that happen with a
couple of different strains
then we can compare all these lab tests
here and then we can see
which terpenes or which cannabinoids um
are like similar in those different
strains then we know what to breed for
and what to select for and then we can
make that way stronger for that so yes
then we can
read strains specific for certain
illnesses and certain things
and so if you had the time or the space
what ailments would you most want to try
to breed some cannabis for is there
anything that's on your list that you
feel is not currently being catered to
um
well i think
like me personally i have like a
add which is like a raising brain
syndrome
um
i would like to make something for that
but i think it's a
pretty difficult one it needs to be this
tifa type gene pool i think it's
probably going to be found
um
so i have like a lot of thoughts that go
really fast inside my head it's like a
ping pong ball yeah um i'm looking for
something that gives me like a rest in
my head without losing any energy and
all those type of things yeah which kind
of only get with some of these aces
um
i think some of these hazes are like
very
not unexp unexplored on the medical
part and i think they
definitely keep some very
strong medical value which has not been
used
so
a bit of an odd question but i love to
throw it by all i guess how important do
you find it is to engage with social
media as a breeder because we see you
know breeders on both sides of the fence
where do you personally sit
um i think social media is a very um
very valuable tool
it's definitely not as pleasant as it
sometimes can be
but that happens everywhere it happens
on the forums
i've been online so long on all these
forums and stuff that i'm pretty okay
and pretty good in handling like all the
negative type things and stuff yeah
which if you handle it the right way it
doesn't become too big yeah but then
again
um
i'm not that straight or i don't always
tell my opinion or things like that yeah
just because you don't feel the freedom
for it yeah
um and on this these days on social
media it's okay you constantly have to
prove yourself or um
you have to be used to answering the
same questions like every day yeah
like i'll get the same questions every
day
from different people um
where can i get this or
what is this and it doesn't matter if
you said it five minutes before yeah
people don't see that well on instagram
yeah so no matter what you put on there
that info is gone kind of in 24 hours
yeah so um
yeah you have to repeat yourself a lot
on social media
then how do you feel things online rate
these days compared to back in the day
when the forums were much more active
and popular
oh the forums in the old days that was
yeah that like overgrow when that was
almost the only thing and then
definitely in the earlier years of it
that was like so special yeah that was
the first time um
a lot of
underground breeders
um connected with each other yeah
that normally would have never ever met
each other and we learned so much from
each other then in such a short time
yeah
that that gave a lot of friendship and a
lot of connections that are like still
solid today yeah
um
and people wanted to share everything
with each other here
everybody send it the seeds and clones
and uh
explained exactly how their system
worked and stuff do that to each other
yeah um that totally changed yeah now if
you want to do that you get everybody in
saying how you should do it
or like complaining or saying
something's not right about it and stuff
yeah so people are not it's not
enjoyable for people to tell and
um
do that anymore yeah so that changed a
lot yeah
that changed a lot
yeah definitely it's it's a whole
different world now isn't
it is it is it is
alrighty so
that brings us to our last little lot of
questions that i like to call the
quickfire questions
so let's jump into them first one what's
your favorite food
um
[Music]
indian food
like yeah like
yeah what type man madras butter chicken
i like the one with the spinach a lot
yeah oh my gosh josh
yeah dolls as well yeah
and things like that yeah
cool cool cool we can get down to some
food together by the sounds of it
oh yeah yeah that is good that's good
great so i like fruit
i i like to go for um
everywhere with all the traveling and
stuff yeah i love to go to go really
good restaurants and things like that i
think that's one of the big joys in life
yeah definitely right good food good
smoke that's what you need
yes
so
next one i wanted to ask
what is one of the most memorable smokes
you've ever had
[Music]
that's probably a happy brother dry
screen
no the a5 dry screen topped it off
yeah
static cleaned a5 dry screen is like
very special
hell yeah sorry almost me yeah
no please go on it always makes you trip
it'll almost make you trip it it gives
you a color view and stuff like a
mushroom type effect and stuff yeah
which i i never get with smoking
cannabis
so on on the other end of the spectrum
what's the strain where you've smoked it
and you haven't thought it was a very
good kind of the least agreeing with you
um
well i once
grew some plants and one of them smelled
like human [ __ ]
but it also tasted like now it also
tasted like so gross that you really
could not smoke it yeah and none of my
friends could smoke it either yeah
like it
it when you just uh lighted the joint
yeah and you took one pull yeah it it
almost like make it it makes you gark
and stuff like that yeah it was just not
not smokeable you just can't smoke it
that is truly an interesting one
it was it was oh yeah
yeah
so out of all of your strains that
you've got coming out in the near future
we're going to exclude the sour bx from
this one because we've already spoken
about it so outside of that what are you
most excited for to release in the
future
um
i think people are very waiting for it
i'm making a5s ones and i think people
are very
waiting for that one
myself
i like think i'm doing some skittles
things which i think are going to be
nice um
and then some of the brazilian stuff
um
but that will be a little while before
that comes as probably next year
but then a5 will come this year
put me down on the list i'm already
sweating thinking about it
yeah i'm crossing the reverse pollen
with the other cuts as well so i'm doing
a c5 times a5 um
i'm doing the
old-school haze which is from the sativa
seed club
that old cut from them um that one times
the a5
i got an hpa skunk in there as well
i might throw in the amnesia yeah
because
everybody wants me to do that so i'll
probably do pollinate that as well
yeah definitely
so
on the breeder end of the spectrum who's
an up-and-coming breeder who you think
might be kind of you know one of the
next big names
um
let me see
i'll be honest i'm not that
up to date most times with with these
things though um
but
let me see do you think
i think most people people know yeah but
um
you know tundra fudge
yeah yeah thunder fudge
oh bro he's his stuff is [ __ ] the
bomb
yes it's the bomb yeah he's a really
good guy as well yeah
but oh wow now his stuff's good
yeah all the sour larry stuff is
is incredible
his ultimate cam is incredible
yeah now he did really good stuff in
reviving all of that yeah so
no he
if anyone wants to buy some one seeds
that are
not that known or out there his stuff is
yeah it's really good
hell yeah so we're now on the desert
island you can pick three strains to
take with you unlimited supply what
three
um
sour diesel a5 and the melon
oh what a nice little well-rounded
selection
i need something for every different
part of the day
okay so
final question
if you could go to any place anywhere in
history any time presumably to collect
some land race seeds what time period
and where would you go
i think i'll go back like really far
here
like um
1900s and go to asia china
hell yeah get some some jurassic [ __ ]
go all the way to the [ __ ] where it
started
yeah i mean if you have that chance to
go back then you better go back to where
it started yeah so
yeah no i feel yeah i feel you
so with that being said did you have any
shout outs or comments you wanted to
make before we wrap things up
um
yeah i want to give a shout out to
all the people i've been working with
the last years um gene finder
tam
kali kush farms
an extra big shout out to emmett from
pure sativa which makes who makes my
life so much easier yeah without him i
wouldn't be selling seeds anymore i
would have quit already because i just
don't like selling seeds yeah um so yeah
those people really make
made it blow up and without those people
i wouldn't be doing it anymore
hell yeah oh yeah some solid names in
there so a big big big thank you to the
dutch og wizard himself karma for coming
on the show and dropping all the
knowledge on us
thank you thank you for having me
[Music]
so a big big big thank you to our friend
karma for taking the time to chat with
us
and thank you to you for sticking around
till the end
as always a huge shout out to seeds here
now they're the best you know it check
them out it's the only option
our friends at 420 australia and organic
gardening solutions
here in australia it's a no-brainer
big shout out to our pure family at
dragonfly earth medicine spreading that
good news to everyone
and also to the patreon gang
check it out if you want that extra
content guys satisfy that craving
[Music]
as always
i'll see you again next time
[Music]
you