foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
podcast for budding enthusiasts
as always big shout out to our sponsors
for helping to make this episode happen
see it's here now number one seed bank
in the game or the hottest breeders the
newest strains the freshest drops hit
them up if you want your next crop to be
as fire as possible likewise profit
biological systems your number one stop
to keep your garden happy healthy bug
free and the best Harvest possible I
tell you what guys you do see it here
now you do copper Biologicals you're in
for a Primo Harvest absolutely no
questions please go hit up both of them
fantastic sponsors of the show who we
appreciate greatly last but not least
the patreon gang the lifeblood of the
show where the fans hang out to help
ensure that more episodes happen tons of
exclusive interviews additional contents
and early access to episodes go check
out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast to join if you want to become a
part of the patreon gang
[Music]
on this episode we are lucky to be
joined by the meme master and Fresh
Prince Masonic seeds here to chat all
things Wilson plans for the future and
what's trending in the scenes
so let's jump into it
alrighty so a big thank you and welcome
to the meme Master himself Fresh Prince
on the Block Masonic thank you so much
for joining us
thank you for inviting me play it no
problem my friend the first question we
love to ask all guests what are you
currently smoking on
oh man you caught me on a good one this
is some uh outdoor zerbert from 365
count of farms grown by Cali kosher Sun
grown
not not outdoor sungrown is different
okay so I mean it begs the question are
you more a fan of sun grown or indoor
generally speaking
I'm fan of good man uh most of the time
most weed nowadays not most weed but
this is some good ass weed and uh I'm a
fan of good man this is some good
outdoor this is some good indoors so you
know easy does it for me for sure and do
you think that indoor will continue to
hold the kind of placeholder as the
superior quality or do you think that
over time outdoor and Sun grown will
become the more popular amongst the
masses
uh I've yet to see an outdoor flower
that kind of just hits like an indoor so
I think there's always going to be a
spot for indoor
yeah for sure for sure so I mean on that
note sounds like a very sort of terpy
strain what sort of flavors do you find
you're more inclined to you're a gas guy
a fruity guy
oh I'm a gas fruit guy for sure there's
there's way more flavors than that so
it's not like I can't choose both I
could choose both I like fruit I like
gas
I'm not too big on you know old world
Terps like you know
a brick or something
but uh yeah
there you go I mean I gotta ask them
because it costs so much hate amongst
the scene have you ever tried or been
impressed by one of the more Amsterdam
hazes like the typical Jack sort of
Terps thing or not your thing I mean I
came up on Jack I'm 28 years old so that
gives you how much you know knowledge I
got on weed I'm a [ __ ] baby compared
to a lot of foods that you know probably
got 10 20 years on me uh but uh
Jack is cool I [ __ ] with Jack man if you
[ __ ] around give me a jack cut I'll hit
it to Wilson and I've smoked plenty of
Jack and J1 and you know Super Lemon
Haze and [ __ ] like that and I mean it
has its placeholders just not my
preferred uh smoke sure and you raise an
interesting topic that I've been asking
people about for a while and that in
particular the Bay Area and even down to
LA and whatnot you get a lot of people
talking about how they're just they're
over the Jack turves it's just saturated
for them but what my perspective is is
that the rest of the world isn't of that
opinion they love it do you find that's
reflective in sort of the demand for
your seeds that those sorts of strains
still do pretty well
uh when it comes to the seeds man
there's a demographic for everything
just like you said you know like there
are people that love Jack you know so uh
I like to hit everything
and cover every every box
and uh you are right or I don't even
know if you said that but uh people do
there is a bigger calling for you know
gelatos and Skittles and and stuff like
that runs has is like the number one
probably trending [ __ ] strain amongst
Instagram or whatever weed uh Avenue
you're on but uh yeah these strains are
good for a reason you know they are good
all these strains that I name runs is
good gelato is good Skittles is great
I'm smoking a skittle's uh derivative so
uh [ __ ] yeah man I'm privy to
everything man it's just I like stuff
better than others yeah perfect and I
mean it's cool to hear that you're
you're so young and achieving what you
are and the question that comes to mind
for me is that given you probably grew
up when cookies was taking off you were
like getting into the Cannabis scene and
whatnot
what's your thoughts on cookies overall
as a strainer you because a lot of the
older folk have this bit of a you know
they're not so into it they don't like
it it's too new for them but you feel
like you love it cookies is dope cookies
is nice man ain't nothing wrong with
cookies man cookies is dope cookies has
his namesake placeholder for a reason
you know [ __ ] it's it's a good strain
you know yeah okay and I mean on that
same note you mentioned gelato you
mentioned Skittles and runts what's your
thoughts on runs do you feel like it
stands up to gelato or it's derivative
oh man it's it's two different things
gee I've I've tried it from different
people you know I've tried you know
I've tried gelato I've grown gelato I've
grown runts they're two different things
and they're both great you know and then
there's different gelatos too you know
we can talk 41 33 so on and so forth
and they're all great yeah well I mean
you you asked the question for me which
of the gelatos are you most inclined to
uh of 33 I think is a full
representation of all the gelatos you
know what I mean but uh I'm more
inclined to the 41 for show
yeah I I remember being at uh the
bobbery dispensary a while back in San
Fran and trying some of shebinsky's 41
and I was so blown away by the potency
like I really thought it was going to be
a bit hypey and I remember just looking
at my friend being like dude I am [ __ ]
up
people assume all wreck weed is not good
that's the problem you know what I mean
in generalizing in any aspect of life
man you're gonna be in for a treat you
know you're gonna you're not gonna be
open to new things you're gonna be in
your same box because you're just
everything is hype everything is
mediocre nothing lives up to you know
your palate you know people are like
that so
you know I'll power to him yeah okay
and I mean a point around gelato and
runs that I wanted to specifically ask
you because I think you're a master of
this is that
I feel like I like gelato more than runs
but it's undeniable that runs have done
a phenomenal job marketing the brand and
I think you excel in that in your own
right do you see it similar to the way
I've just put it or do you think it's a
bit different
oh man you hit it on the head uh they
pushed their product man and and that
helped shove it down people's throats
let alone solidify it as a namesake
strain in the Cannabis industry and
people should take notes on that you
know [ __ ] go make a song go hire some
dude that looks like Willy Wonka to
[ __ ] rap for you you know [ __ ]
whatever you got to do and nothing
against you know young lb or any of your
fam like that but go get your money man
[ __ ] go feed your kids go make a
legacy quit being a [ __ ] a dude
sitting at a [ __ ] table on your couch
with a bunch of other 40 year olds
talking about how you could have did it
better
yeah I mean I've certainly seen a few of
those conversations go down and it kind
of segues nicely into the idea of burner
and what he has and hasn't done I
remember watching a YouTube video from
you just a day or two ago and you were
saying you know a lot of people
criticize burner they say you give him
too much props and you were like I think
I kind of give him the right amount of
props and it brings up this idea of like
the nice Sayers often hate the fact that
he's not the breeder but then I would
always respond with but he did do stuff
like you can't deny that he hyped it to
the point where it is what it is what's
your thoughts on Burner overall
Berner is a is a is a business person
you know what I mean uh he's over there
making sure he's good you know and uh
that's just people got to understand
that in life that not everything is a
honeymoon you know and that's a good uh
he sets the bar of what you might be
dealing with you know and whether it be
good or bad you know [ __ ] I got
nothing but nice things to say about
people because
you know that's how that's how I am now
I learned to be nice so shout out big
burn
yeah I feel you and I think a point that
kind of helped me to realize that exact
sentiment you just expressed is I think
it was sticker Farm I put up a post and
he said whatever you think about burner
like he's paved the way for people to be
able to feed their family for years to
come and I thought that's actually a
really unique perspective on it because
he's created this Empire kind of more so
than what anyone else has done around
any other strain
he made jobs Point Blank period yeah
that's exactly and what you can say he
didn't make jobs but like okay he
represents cookies people work at
cookies he made jobs
easy does it for me you know
yeah all right well let's jump back to
what we normally ask people first which
is tell me about your first experience
with cannabis
oh
damn
uh well I'm from South Central Los
Angeles so there's weed you know people
smoke their weed out here so it's not
like I'm a from a conservative area that
is not accessible so it was accessible
growing up my pops always told me he
didn't want to see me smoking that [ __ ]
because he didn't see no future in it
because of all the stigma on it you know
especially being in the hood if you got
caught with weed they're probably gonna
throw you in jail real quick you know
especially being a a Mexican you know
[ __ ] boom boom
but uh so I I was always scared of it
and then I got into eighth grade summer
going into ninth grade
I think uh that's when
I found like a my buddy in in eighth
grade had like a stem of some stress
that's what we call brick weed and he's
like showing it to me and and I'm like
what's that smell like and he's like oh
that's weed and I'm like oh can you
bring me some tomorrow just being a bad
little kid you know [ __ ] eighth
grader or something yeah I was an eighth
grader and and whatever he doesn't bring
me none the next day and like we just
smell the stem and that's like my first
encounter with weed it was just smelling
the stem of it second encounter I'm
hanging out with the skaters and we end
up in a garage I was I was a fat kid I
couldn't even skate dude I would
literally run with Chase the skaters
around running because I wanted to be
like hanging out with them you know I
wanted to be part of the skating crew
couldn't escape for [ __ ] didn't even
have a bike I'm just like running behind
these kids and uh we end up in a garage
and
whatever one of their older brothers
lights up in there and dude I ran out
that [ __ ] so fast I gotta go
like this is scary
so yeah but I think finally ninth grade
came around
and I I got some weed from Javonte
he's one of my classmates and and I went
home and I rolled it up and there used
to be a cul-de-sac with like a dead end
place where all the transients would
sleep in in South Central and I rolled
it up in a joint but I didn't break it
down and I lit it up and the [ __ ] was
just falling out dude like the nugs the
compressed nugs would just fall out the
joint and I'm like whatever you know I
gave it my best shot I go back just and
whatever that was a failed attempt so I
haven't got high yet three times with
weed didn't get high with the stem was
too [ __ ] to do it in the garage did it
wrong the third time fourth time around
they have some cat piss shake and I'm
like [ __ ] it just give it to me and I
think I made like a I forgot how I
smoked it but that's like the first time
I got high and I'm like yeah this is it
right here buddy and ever since then
it's been uh you know weed weed boy
oh yeah I mean that's so like I'm so
jealous that like your first proper
experience getting really high was with
like cat piss I guess that's some of the
perks of growing up where you did were
you aware of any other strains that were
popular around that time
not completely oblivious to anybody that
smoked marijuana just like a little you
know conniving little kid just you know
dwelled my way you know Dove my way into
that world and you know here we are
today
fantastic so was that the experience
that kind of solidified it for you that
you were like hey I'm gonna be involved
in this for a good minute or was there
another one where you really like
realized hey cannabis is what I want to
do with my life
uh
as far as that that moment I realized I
just want to get high you know not all
the time little did I know it was going
to become all the time you know not that
I I just want to get high all the time
but you know yeah but [ __ ] uh uh yeah
so I didn't know I was gonna grow weed
or anything I just knew I was gonna be
smoking it
sure and what was the progression like
from there to your first grow like how
many years went by and what kind of
inspired you to first kind of plant a
seed or to grow one out
uh well for shits and giggles you know
in high school I would you know grab a
bag seed from any given stress and throw
it in the cup and put it in the backyard
and watch it grow a little bit maybe
every now and then get a lollipop of Bud
and this is what what age are you in
high school 9th 10th grade around that
age
uh 10 11 12 no growing just smoking lots
of smoking 11 12 and then my parents are
like this guy's just never gonna stop
smoking you know like we gotta we gotta
help him somehow you know so my dad he
had a buddy he was getting in he was
coming becoming more liberal you know
more open to marijuana
uh he he he's also in car clubs you know
it just so happens dudes in Low Rider
car clubs some of them smoke weed so
it's kind of like like dude you're over
there kicking it with those weed smokers
talking about I can't smoke giving me a
hard time so finally like whatever dude
uh here's uh Ray he grows weed he's
gonna show you some stuff and we're
gonna help you so this is you know
graduating you know around graduation
time so he buys me uh
like some clones and like 10 uh like 15
gallon barrels and he fills them up with
uh whatever they used to use a a 50 50
Miracle-Gro to steer maneuver like the
hottest [ __ ] you can make on planet
Earth but that's what they would use and
whatever I'm like whatever dad like I
just want to smoke weed like like cool
growing and uh and he's like yeah man
we're gonna make it worthwhile and I
just want to smoke the [ __ ] weed but
uh he ended up uh trying to grow it and
rats ate it so and then and then finally
I'm like okay uh we moved to to Compton
because we used to live like in South
Central over there by El Segundo Vermont
and uh I just I'm like I'm smoking weed
uh I had got a pound of Sour Diesel that
I didn't manage correctly and I was like
back to square one you know graduated a
little bit of college just lost in the
sauce don't know what I'm gonna do with
myself I'm a kid and uh I just started
growing for funsies
and uh I would see my wife on Instagram
and I'm like I'm in the real world you
know I just graduated high school never
was on Instagram never was on social
media I'm like baby like you're always
on social media like get off of there
you're wasting your time and then I'm
like let me see what this is about I
start going and I start getting mused by
everybody that grows on there and I'm
like what like they're strain names and
there's this and there's that all I know
is you can go buy OG Kush you can go buy
you know Blue Dream whatever strains
they have at the shop every now and then
you get a clone don't know that there's
a big you know history and makers and
like this whole thing like everything
that I know now none of that and uh just
picked up game little by little to this
day I still Soak Up game like everything
about ride I found that [ __ ] out in less
than 24 hours like I didn't know none of
this [ __ ] I'm just like boom [ __ ]
educated and like that that's the power
of the internet how fast you get
information
yeah wow a lot of a lot of questions we
can ask there I just want to rewind back
to how you mentioned your dad introduced
you to his friend was he like did you
consider the product he was producing at
the time to be good quality or do you
think he still was kind of figuring
things out himself I I I thought it was
good I thought it was cool it wasn't
like now that I look back it was you
know not that great but like at that
moment seen that much at any given time
is good
I remember what you say like your first
like 10 pounds in one space you're like
whoa it's all good I love that I love
that okay and was he just like a sort of
a hobby grower himself or did he have
some connections to some cool cuttings
and whatnot what were they messing with
I never dove that deep into who he knew
as far as uh what he was growing but he
he you know he he grew a lot of weed
that's for [ __ ] show
hell yeah
so you uh you kind of explained the
mediums what were the other aspects of
the grow going on like were they using
just like HPS lights what was the
situation oh no this is outdoor they
were doing outdoor this was outdoor
marijuana whatever indoor they did I I
didn't dive into that to this day I've
yet to like I have go walk into numerous
grows I've had my own little four
lighter that you know didn't go as
planned but I you know used it to what I
used it for and uh you know [ __ ]
you've never seen like a picture of me
like hey you know crushing my 20 lighter
never ever because it's never happened
you know
yeah sure so would you say that you like
predominantly you like to work more
Outdoors or it's just the experience you
have no that's that's what I know I just
know how to grow outdoor yeah a whole
lot of it nothing wrong with that
yeah so from that point was it mostly
this uh your father's friend who you
were kind of looking to for
inspirational knowledge or were there
any like bigger breeders you would
become aware of and you were like wow
this person knows what they're doing
well you know first it was you know uh
Ray my dad's buddy that uh you know
taught me the the 50 50 formula and then
I'd have buddies come over and be like
dude Miracle grows terrible like you're
supposed to use Fox Farm and I'm like
okay here goes nothing Fox Mark you know
and then [ __ ] hopped on Instagram and
people were like organic organic organic
and you know whatever organic at that
point I had like
figured out how to use Fox Farm and
General Hydroponics and [ __ ] like that
that's what I was using by the time I
hopped on Instagram and then I go on
Instagram and they're doing Organics and
it was like this crew called Summit dogs
they were using a nectar for the God so
I started using nectar for the gods and
then I started seeing this uh the K net
farmer dude and I'm like whoa like
that's like Wizardry dude like you're
over there [ __ ] like what like what
are you doing with that milk huh and
then I dove into knf and then I just you
know I went into a rabbit hole of that
ended up with jadam jadam said k f was
trash throw that whole book in the trash
and I'm like okay I'm just gonna stop
here go back to what I know and it's
keeping plants really green which is
with salts so now and and whatever I do
salts but I do it works now is basically
what I'm trying to say
sure that's a very interesting sort of
progression you've had through the
various growth Styles and it's cool to
hear that you've tried both sides of the
coin so to speak overall do you
subscribe to the idea that a lot of
people do where it's that like organic
is the best and product you can get or
do you think you can do just as well
with any sort of thing
oh man I've had some really good organic
[ __ ] man I'm not gonna lie but uh the
thing is I'm growing for seed production
so you know if if uh if it was up to me
I'd Bust It Out organic you know [ __ ]
when you go eat fruit was better organic
or [ __ ] the other one you know
yeah of course I think that's an analogy
that I often fall back on to myself so
from that point there what was it like
before you kind of became a breeder did
you spend some time just Fino hunting
things and figuring out the ropes and
kind of collecting clones like what was
happening before you started breeding
breeding breeding was like [ __ ] the
chocolate chip cookie for me man people
uh people would see accidental
pollinations in my yard and inquire on
them and then I'd be like whoa like
[ __ ] I should go do an intentional
one you know so
that became the the Tropicana cherry pie
Tangy Mel that I ended up giving to my
buddy uh warped he brought it back and
I'm still growing for you know cash crop
or whatever kind of blast it all into
shatter or whatever the case
and not knowing that I'm creating a dope
ass Seed where he's created a dope ass
seat at his house but I'm getting half
of them because I provided the mail or
whatever amount I'm getting and I put
them [ __ ] right for so as soon
as I got them and everybody's like dope
I want some it was agent orange
Tropicana cherry pie Tangy and it was a
plushberry Tropicana cherry pie Tangy
and people inquired and and the demand
was really high and [ __ ] I'm like
cool like I've been busting my ass
forever growing all these you know
plants in the backyard not forever but
as long as I've had then and and it's
high risk because I got to grow them as
big as possible and get as much as I can
in the middle of Compton [ __ ] and and
cross my fingers that I do it right you
know what I mean and uh you know [ __ ]
it just made sense to start making seeds
and establishing my seeds right then and
there so I just did it and my thing is
like you got to do it before it's
saturated you got to do it before
everybody else you know and you got to
do it Point Blank period so I just did
it boom we did the Tropicana cherry pie
Tangy
I [ __ ] made my uh homage all the way
to chalice and and [ __ ] in my mom's
car and it broke down on the way there I
[ __ ] smoking and steaming I'm like
[ __ ] this we're making it there we pull
up and and and [ __ ] I go say hi to
Oni because I'm already growing some of
the Tropicana uh the Cherry Pie Tangy
stuff which was uh one of the first
strains they had made for the Oni Banner
and uh I go and I meet Oni and they're
like you're [ __ ] batshit crazy like
what are you doing here like you're poor
you're supposed to be in Compton with
your shitty plants or whatever you know
and I'm like yeah well I'm here you know
he's like man here have these uh seeds
and you know have this hash and I go
home
and it's the papaya Femmes like the
first papaya availability one of the
first papaya strains on the market and I
grow those Tropicana F2 one of the first
people to grow Tropicana F2 which is
also one of the you know best strains
cool right now too everybody likes it
yeah and uh I grow them and I hit up Oni
or Harry Palms at the time he was
working with Oni and I'm like hey man I
got this Mel and these females out here
he's like [ __ ] put it to work and I'm
like hell yeah and [ __ ] it's been uh
it's been a wrap since then
wow what a what a cool adventure the
first thing that jumps to mind when you
tell me that is we had a lot of people
message and ask what's your relationship
with only like because I think some
people actually thought you were like
only like just in Disguise or something
no no only only
Seed Company
only noodles
that's uh my mentor I I learned a lot
from him he he taught me to just uh
you know
taught me a lot of [ __ ] you know a lot
of ropes uh I don't got to do a lot of
mistakes because he tells me not to he's
like nah like stay away from them that's
good and it's always been uh
it's always been for the better for both
of us it's never been like I've never
felt like
like you know if if I ever felt
compromised I just leave I'm I'm very
cool like that and [ __ ] in this weed
game I know people are like that
everybody people don't get along and I
know people are shocked that we've been
getting along this long [ __ ] people
were like that's how you know people are
supposed to break up like nah like you
know we know how to work you know
yeah great that's good to hear and I
mean there's so many things I want to
ask you about that last little answer
you had I mean you touched on the papaya
for a long time there was what I think
is an incorrect rumor going around that
papaya was just a renamed Green Crack
what's your thoughts have you heard this
rumor yeah I think my buddy roster
that's in jail he was a meme guy back in
the day he was under the moniker of the
roster he actually started that rumor I
believe because I'm I'm I don't know
like I'll be a self-proclaimed like I'm
one of the
probably original meme guys like when it
comes to the weed memes like I'm the guy
you like you know I'm one of them you
know I'll even say I'm the Michael
Jordan of [ __ ] memes I don't care
I'll take it you know but uh yeah he
started that rumor uh knowing that I was
homies with Ernie like just to like make
fun and he's like haha like I'm starting
rumors you know Green crackers
and like he'll send it to Oni and only
would laugh about it so everybody was in
on it you know what I mean so and no no
uh papaya is not Green Crack papaya is
actually a clone from I've I've
overheard stories and and I hate asking
them because you know you you know they
say you look
you you're stupider if you don't ask but
I've stupider is not a word but you
you're stupid if you don't ask but I
don't like to ask but I've asked before
or I've overheard someone ask and uh The
Story Goes that it's a cut from Pink
House in Colorado or some [ __ ] like that
that was uh that Harry Palm smoked and
he's like I really need this and he
brought it to the masses via cut you
know uh reversing it hitting it to other
things
Etc
yeah but that's what it is what what
seed stock it's from uh I don't [ __ ]
know you know uh and you know it's
something I can easily ask those foods
but it's like Papaya's papaya so that's
kind of that for me yeah sure good
answer and I mean I guess it begs the
question what's your thoughts on Green
Crack it's also like blue dream a bit of
a polarizing one
oh Green Crack Blue Dream everything has
its you know its place and those shits
are cool like I've made a blue dream
hybrid before I did Blue Dream dosey doe
you know uh and I'm Green Crack should
give me a green crack could I'll slap
that [ __ ] right now you know [ __ ]
let's do it
I love that so just to jump back a
moment you were talking about the first
kind of strains you were playing with
and they're a bit of a mistake but they
worked out being great and you mentioned
that one of the mothers was agent orange
the other was the plush berry I've for a
long time been a fan of TGA regardless
of what you think about sub and all the
rest I thought they put out some pretty
nice work what's your thoughts on TJ did
you like to grow their stuff
uh I never grown any TGA that was grown
by warp genetics he did that pollination
for me those were his moms but uh [ __ ]
man dude's an OG [ __ ] that's that's
for sure I've heard some weird [ __ ] but
like who cares I mean who cares that
like like you know show me the papers
and then I'll care but you know
everything is hearsay until I see it on
paper for me because the internet you
know don't don't hear everything I mean
don't don't believe everything you hear
and [ __ ]
sure so with that in mind what was the
you know we've heard about some of the
stuff that was unintentionally made what
was the first cross you intentionally
made and did it work out to work well or
didn't work out so well oh yeah the
first intentional crosses were uh the
papaya Femmes crossed a tribe can F2 so
that was papaya punch uh Tropicana to
uh Cato cookies drop F2
banana OG papaya trop F2 which became my
namesake uh you know Flagship strain
Wilson
dosido papaya trop F2
and one other one uh three can put by a
drop F2 and those worked out really well
to the point where Oni wanted them for
his Banner he's like hey I was gonna do
the banana OG trap hybrid for you know
Oni and you you know you did it like can
you not sell them and I'm all like yeah
man for sure I won't sell them he's like
better yet like want to work together
and I'm like [ __ ] even better and uh
that you know you gotta crawl and you
gotta you know even though I say you
know or you know I might say in a lot of
words you know the code this Unwritten
code that people don't think I respect I
still have a general respect for it you
know what I mean to the point where
early on in the game I asked now it's
I'm at a point where it's just I'm In My
Own Lane now you know [ __ ] if if I
get a cut from from a breeder and he's
like hey
respected that's different because I got
it hand to hand with a breeder you know
now if I went and bought some seeds it's
mine now you know those are my seeds and
and whatever I do with them [ __ ] it
shouldn't it shouldn't affect you
because you should be doing something
different anyways you know
yeah sure and I mean you just touched on
a very pertinent question I was going to
ask you a bit later on would you say
that generally speaking you preach that
sort of philosophy yourself in terms of
if someone buys your seeds they can kind
of do with it what they want or do you
feel like it is kind of good manners at
least just to try to reach out and just
you know touch base sort of thing
uh you can reach out but [ __ ] don't
be mad when they say no so you it's
better if you kill first and then ask
questions later you know and [ __ ]
what are they gonna [ __ ] do you know
what I mean [ __ ] you could get off
Instagram like oh man you know like
people are crazy like that [ __ ] it's
not it shouldn't bother you deep like
that uh now if you have like a
there's positions that you're in like if
you're just a random person this
shouldn't you should be like dude go
ahead you know make more seed stock you
know if it's a big person you should be
like hey [ __ ] you guy you know kind of
but like flattered because they're so
big they want to do it but it shouldn't
mess with you it shouldn't affect you
you know and and they should respect you
enough like you shouldn't make people
mad too you know because I will go F2
your [ __ ] and sell it for a penny you
know [ __ ] [ __ ] like that so like
it's just it's just there's there's
equations to everything you know not
everything is the same answer so yes and
no you know it's well yeah you know
[ __ ] it's like like for instance
calculator gave me a cut uh we did a
project don't release the seeds okay
that's because that's a that's like a
written formal contract now hey man uh I
see you made a cross with my things like
you shouldn't be selling that that's
different like was there ever any formal
thing do you have a disclaimer on your
bag like where is your backup is this
some Unwritten [ __ ] do you feel
threatened like you're having a bad day
like is it [ __ ] like that people that
get grab testers and and make seeds with
them I I could understand that too
but uh but also there has to be that
that foreground like hey these are
testers uh they're for you to have an
opportunity not to start a [ __ ] Seed
Company
you know
yeah I agree there's there's obviously a
lot of nuance in varying different
situations as to what sort of the
approach the approach to take it raises
the question for me and you raise you
raise capillator himself I often kind of
scratch my head a little bit at how cap
gets a bit frustrated at how the Mach 1
is you know everyone and his dogs able
to get their hands on it these days and
he you know he harps on about how he was
just meant to be given out to the ogs
and you deserve it and stuff but then I
also think about bodhi's sentiment where
he says look if you don't want something
getting out you just shouldn't give it
out like
um what's your thoughts on that do you
think like if you give a clone to
someone it's inevitably gonna get out
uh yeah man [ __ ] that that that's
that's you know that's
that might happen and the way I do it I
just poke fun at the situation and like
the first time I met cap
I was like how much like I think I told
him something like hey like how much can
I sell my Mac one for or something like
that and he just looked at me like you
[ __ ] [ __ ]
and like that's that was like my way of
breaking the ice you know [ __ ]
so uh yeah you know and and it kind of
like throws him off like like what the
[ __ ] guy like you know that I'm I get
mad about this and you're over here like
joking about it you know so [ __ ] yeah
yeah just break the ice
yeah I agree I think there's definitely
some humor to be had in that situation
so if we just rewind a little bit you
mentioned that you actually crossed a
dosie dough male I believe to Blue Dream
in the past
um what's your thoughts on dosey doe I
feel like it's a cool strain but it's
also kind of fallen off a little bit did
you find much success in that mail
oh uh people love the blue though man
and it was a very small seed stock and
people loved it to the point where I
have a clone of it it's probably like
two years old already now uh probably
older probably two I just love adding
years to [ __ ] but it's just it's it's at
least two years old or who knows my
buddy uh
Maga cannabis
uh or whatever his name is uh he he sent
me that cut and I hit it to Wilson again
not again I hit it to my Wilson keeper
but and I've had tons of flower of it
cash uh everybody that's grown it loves
it you know like I hate to [ __ ] put
cream on my taco but it's never been
like hey this Pluto sucks I've never
gotten that response and very very you
know it's probably like 50 to 100 packs
it wasn't that big of a drop but uh it
was very successful uh seat strap and I
put energy into it like we were talking
about marketing earlier like Bluto
happened to be the only strain I had
in the making at the time so all my
energy
marketing got put into that one strain
as opposed to now where I'm just like in
full production and it's like everything
Times Wilson so it's kind of hard to you
know nitpick which is like the one for
you you know so it's all like just go on
the site now it's not like go on the
site type in your favorite strain it's
probably across the Wilson that's what I
that's kind of the wave now
so a good answer and I think part of the
reason why I brought that question up is
because you know I I really like all of
Fletcher from archives work but
sometimes he does get a bit uh
frustrated when people breed with dosey
doe I I it feels to me as though he
wants to have sort of exclusive breeding
with males from that one did you did you
find any issues with that from him or
anything like that or it was all Bueno
I mean [ __ ] I know I'm I'm I know for
a fact he knows who I am [ __ ]
everybody knows who the [ __ ] I am but uh
when I did that [ __ ] I didn't [ __ ]
know who uh who made that [ __ ] I was
just grabbing dosey doe hitting at the
blue dream like that's how uh oblivious
I can be to you know the game The
Players
Etc like I'm just out here having fun
[ __ ] the Fletcher would have hit me
up but I'm like oh what was happening
[ __ ] to this day it's all like I'm
not here to make anybody Madden at this
point
uh they shouldn't make me mad either
[ __ ] we're all human dude [ __ ] you
don't like something shut the [ __ ] up
stay in your corner leave me alone
so and something about the Dosey dough
which a few other breeders have done
with other strains is that there's like
different releases where there's like
you know the number four the number 22
the number 18. like all these different
sort of variations on it do you think
you would ever do a project like that
with maybe Wilson where there's like
these different sort of brothers and
sisters using the breeding or you just
like to stick with the keeper
now this that's what I'm doing actually
right now I'm popping like [ __ ] 200
Wilson seeds and I'm gonna do that and I
have my Wilson keeper Mel around and you
know we're just gonna have some uh we're
gonna make all the 40 year olds and up
happy
I love it I love it and out of curiosity
do you remember which of the dosey doe
variants you used in the blue dough
it was pollen gifted from my buddy turt
Factory that he found he sent it from
Colorado
okay cool yeah so you mentioned it
earlier but I'll get you to repeat it
because the question we got more than
any other question from the fans was
what is the genetics of Wilson some
people thought it was just a trop F2
some people said banana papaya trop can
you iron it out for them
uh Wilson F1 that I made for Oni Seed
Company
is banana OG papaya from Femme seed
stock that I found
times Tropicana F2
people get it confused with Wilson zero
which is Oni noodles only seed companies
interpretation of you know almost the
same strain but with his selection of
banana OG papaya from female seed stock
hit to his Tropicana F1 that is his
Flagship Mel used in you know almost
every string until recently he's uh been
using different medals
cool cool and what sort of like flavors
and structures can people expect Wilson
to bring to crosses
oh man uh
I like to say it just
brings hash to product you know
everything seems to wash a little better
with some Wilson in there but I've never
got like a scientist or anybody to take
data like oh like this is pre-washed
without Wilson you know this is the mom
that you hit pre-wilson and this is it
like we got numbers for you buddy but uh
what what I do get from Wilson is a
[ __ ] uh it's just continuing like
lineage like isolating a clone uh
Terrapin profile Times Wilson getting a
derivative of anything and and the
easiest form as opposed to sitting Cuts
you know keeping Cuts Like You can have
a big ass [ __ ] bag of seeds with the
flavor in there you know what I mean and
and it's easy to give it to people as
opposed to a mom that you gotta keep
clean and you know hopefully it makes it
across the country because it's not
going to make it to [ __ ] Spain or
whatever it's just that's what I I do
and that's what Wilson does Wilson is my
boy that [ __ ] everybody and allows me
to get seeds of it and it just so
happens that people are you know happy
with the seeds no matter what the
progeny of it [ __ ] I just say hey man
it makes it Ashmore because you know it
probably does and that's what people
were telling me Wilson washes itself it
hits like five six any given [ __ ]
Pinot hunt so uh from the seed like you
just grab a seat throw it in the ground
you're gonna get some hash but Wilson so
we'll say it brings that brings sexiness
to the plant so you can grab a land race
like uh Malawi or something like that
and hit it to Wilson and now you got you
know not fully blown purple weed but you
know purple Hues you know undertones of
purple which is brings that you know so
it does it does some [ __ ] for the plant
you know bag appeal you know
hash that's what it does
lovely and I mean we'll touch on some
concentrate stuff later I'd just love to
ask you quickly what was the creation of
Wilson like like where did the name come
from were you watching Castaway or how
did it come about
well uh I'm not too big on naming
strains that's the thing Oni named them
uh banana OG papaya is called castaway
so I cross Cast Away to Tropicana F2
that ended up becoming Wilson like a
play on you know already
you know Castaway so that's how that
became that and it turned into [ __ ]
this whole thing you know and it's still
relevant with uh you know Tom Hanks
getting coronavirus as soon as you know
the [ __ ] and it just so happens he
yells Wilson out in the [ __ ] movies
it's just it's perfect time and
everything happens for a reason
I love it and so what was the decision
like to breed with the male did you Fino
hunt the seeds first and find a killer
female and you were like damn I gotta
find a male of this or how did it go
yeah yeah so uh out of all of them out
of all the females like Wilson was you
know the one that was different it was
something untapped you know papaya punch
smelled too much like you know either
papaya or was too Punchy the three cam
uh papaya was just too much papaya the
dosey doe and the Cato they just weren't
as good as the Wilson so that left the
Wilson and uh I went and we had a
festival in San Francisco and we all sat
down
and I had made these crosses no no
I hadn't made these crosses but I had
went back home and they're like hey dude
uh no we were in San Francisco I had
made these crosses and they're like you
got to pick one you know like to be the
one and I'm like well [ __ ] I'm growing a
bunch of them at the house right now I
got like at least 30 of each growing
right now of those five strains and I'm
like uh they're like the Wilson's the
one and I'm like yeah the Wilson's the
one and I'm like well [ __ ] I got a bunch
of males of them and I'm gonna go
through them and you know that's how you
know we started hitting everything with
Wilson and that's how Wilson became the
go-to you know strain and [ __ ] it
worked out
yeah and it was talked about it was
talked about it wasn't spontaneous we
did sit down
and we did you know brainstorming like
you know go home we being Oni noodles
and Harry Palms was at the table that
day when he was working with Oni and uh
you're gonna go home and you're gonna
get a Wilson and you know that's gonna
be your namesake you know and [ __ ]
here we are today
sure and you mentioned earlier that
oni's version of Wilson the Wilson zero
is using their selection different males
and whatnot have you ever kind of
compared them side by side and do you
think they're more similar than
different or they're quite different
because the selections just differ
oh they're different man uh uh oni's uh
trop F1 it really uh
the progeny of it is is you know
completely you know uh
it just it stands out compared to you
know my trop F2 you know so it's
different it's different weed different
selection different week
sure sure and something you mentioned
earlier which I think is a hugely
relevant point is that you've got to
like get the project made and out there
before the time comes and goes and that
was something he referenced in regards
to that truck cherry pie Tangy mail what
I'm interested to know is it seems like
the Wilson is come at a very opportune
time like that sort of flavor profile it
has is Big at the moment and it's not
like you know because some breeders will
realize something's big and then try to
get that sort of cross done and then by
the time it's out there at Market it's
it's come and gone what's your thoughts
on the current flavor situation within
the scene and do you have any
predictions for what might be the next
big flavor
oh man people I think people are going
back to the the the wheel which is oh
geez you know people are going back to
the [ __ ] that worked you know not so
much r d no more there's still the r d
but uh I mean me personally I'm I'm
going back to I'm trying to find you
know the the markers or as as as far as
we can get into the markers but you know
sadly you gotta hit up uh Matt Riot to
get the real deal so I'm I'm in for a
treat I don't think I'm ever gonna get
any real plants
uh look we're gonna have to have a chat
about Rye but we'll we'll defer that for
a moment because I wanted to ask you a
little more about some flavor stuff so
I'd be interested to know now now that
you're you're a bit more established and
as you mentioned earlier a lot of people
are familiar with your work are there
any breeders outside of ones you've
already collabed with that you think are
doing cool work and you might want to do
a project with them
I mean as far as doing a project with
anybody
I don't I don't like to ask too much for
help so that's kind of like I kind of
see like hey that's like me asking for
something almost so I've I've never
asked for anything every project I've
done has either been a forest collab
or the big homie looking out for me you
know
so uh
like right now I got a sherbinsky hit me
up through the the other day we're gonna
do a collab
uh cap already we already did a collab
it's in the works he just popped the
seats that I made in my yard with his
mail I mean with his uh female in my
mouth
uh but who would I want to do a collab
with [ __ ] I do collabs with all my
friends
you know to you know help them
you know make more seeds and just be
part of the machine
uh but I I would like to meet all the
ogs you know and and pick their brain
and let me
you know just hang out with them or
something that'd be cool but whoever OG
it is you know [ __ ] hey what's up you
know
what you got what you working with oh I
did this I did that you know [ __ ] this
guy [ __ ] that guy cool doesn't work you
know
yeah so you mentioned the term Force
collab is that sort of like a thing
where someone's a bit upset with a cross
you're making and so to kind of uh you
know calm the waters it turns into a
collab or what did you mean by that oh
that just means I just you know [ __ ]
just do the collab without any consent
kind of the kill now ask questions later
thing like hey man I popped all your
seeds and I crossed on the Wilson Force
Collette
I love that
pulls from the other side of what I was
thinking okay that's cool yeah that's
cool so what would be your advice for
sort of a newbie breeder like someone
who's looking to get a bit more
notoriety how should they go about doing
things what have you learned
oh man notoriety uh man just be be uh be
cool man be cool man if if [ __ ] if
you
like you gotta use your platform so you
know you gotta talk to people at least I
think you do I mean you so you got to be
kind of you know you gotta have good
communication skills
can't be [ __ ] an introvert you gotta
gotta put out a little bit give them a
little bit of taste of your work your
life but I mean maybe you don't maybe
I'm wrong but that's what I did I just
kept kept it cool kept it real
keep it honest if I don't know this [ __ ]
don't lie about it don't got to come up
with any story as I go just
keep it 100 man
so and I think you know that was a bit
of a segue question in terms of I think
that you've done very well on Instagram
in terms of building a following getting
people to be aware of the brand and the
crosses do you think it's possible for a
sort of fledgling breeder to be able to
succeed in the current landscape without
being sort of active on a social media
or Instagram
yeah someone asked that last time
they're like what what like what would
you be using if it was an Instagram well
we there'd be another form there'd be
another place you know it'd be YouTube
it'd be Facebook it'd be any given form
[ __ ] it'd be Word of Mouth
however you got to get it I you know
when I before I was breeding you know
making seeds whatever you want to call
it
uh I was backpacking the weed I grew in
my backyard from shop to shop you know
selling that so you know [ __ ]
that's what you'd end up doing but it
wouldn't be as successful I think
because you know it just so happens
there's a lot of [ __ ] on
Instagram it's easy to use it's user
friendly
and it's easy to you know get that
message across on here as opposed to
going on a whole last form not not user
friendly not being able to put a face to
a product Facebook a couple channels
it's just the most
convenient thing for people when it
comes to weed like that so and I guess
an extension of that would be that I
feel like you're you're quite a
polarizing figure to some people on
Instagram I think most of the people I
talk to really enjoy your content and
the memes there are obviously some who
are not so into it why do you think
people view you as a polarizing figure
and do you think that it's a case of
just any publicity's good publicity
no no not even that any any publicity
like I would I don't want to be known as
uh there's people that think that's the
case and they're like just doing
terrible like dude all the publicity
you're getting just [ __ ] terrible
like that's not the case you know so
with me I think they just relate to like
he's I can do that too you know he from
the bottom to the top you know [ __ ]
people's if they see me grow the
foundation they're like they're like
what the [ __ ] how did you do it you know
where what's like the trick you know and
and the trick is just just you know stay
grounded keep your job build your dream
and uh you know hopefully cross your
fingers and that you did your dream
writing you built it up right work hard
of course but that's all that cliche
[ __ ] that garyvee could tell you in any
given video
oh good old garyvee so you referenced
earlier that
um you know you're you're the meme guy
so to speak how did this come about you
know were you always sort of like uh a
jokester sort of guy growing up yeah man
I grew up on 4chan dude uh I would go uh
to go visit my brother in college
and he went to UC Santa Cruz and you
know there they would nerd out his
buddies and they would be on 4chan and I
just thought it was the edgiest [ __ ] in
the world and I kind of just would lurk
every day every now and then I go on
there and uh I've just been uh aware of
memes longer than most people have so
you know I got 10 000 hours of memes on
them so it's like
it's [ __ ] I'm the [ __ ] outlier
when it comes to that [ __ ] there you go
yeah you've uh what is it you've
mastered it you've put in your ten
thousand hours yeah straight up that's
facts G so I guess the question is do
memes sell packs or do you think they
just grab people's attention enough so
they can then push
Elon Musk said it the best G
memes control the world or some [ __ ]
like that
it certainly feels like it's the
Zeitgeist and that like people respond
to it definitely
yeah my wife was talking to me in the
car the other day that people were older
they're going to be looking at memes
like a piece of art like oh this meme
came out like the dong the black dude
with the dong you know in Corona or
whatever happened like they're gonna
bring that up on a screen in a college
and they're going to be talking about it
they're going to be like oh you know the
great meme of the coronavirus epidemic
and [ __ ] like that
his art
yeah it will be very interesting to see
how it's all analyzed and broken down in
like sociology classes in 20 years from
now that's that's pretty hilarious
actually
so you referenced in a prior end for a
little while ago that shabinsky's been
hitting you up to do some stuff
um what sort of stuff would you want to
maybe work with him like using one of
the gelato Cuts or what do you have in
mind yeah
yeah man uh I mean for starters I
respect
everybody you know that's how that's how
it goes and unless they're not
respectable people
and he hit me up because uh he sees uh
chiro and he he respects it and I've
never disrespected him and if I have
I've uh owned up to it because you know
I can be a little disrespectful here and
there
and he's like I like the way you roll
you know and uh I think it'd be a great
opportunity for us to work together
and I'm like [ __ ] yeah man you're
[ __ ] strabinsky man people [ __ ]
probably would say they don't want to
work with you and end up working with
you anyways because they're [ __ ]
weirdos like that but I'm not a weirdo
and I'm like let's [ __ ] work man and
you know hopefully we get this [ __ ]
cracking
hell yeah so you know another good segue
in that you've got your own store in the
works in Fairfax just down the road from
shavinsky's store what's that Journey
been like to being able to get your own
store was it just a dream you never
thought you'd be able to do or was it
just always the end goal from day one
oh man [ __ ] who who knew man who
[ __ ] knew uh first t-shirts I made
were with the same place I made this one
and it's just like the the dude at the
swap meet that will whip up a shirt for
you for 20 bucks so you know I I would
like on Instagram I was like Hey guys
like I got my cool little logo you know
that the guy my homie sent me like who
wants a shirt of it oh I'll take one
I'll take one you know and then it
became oh
I made a box of teas and they come with
free seeds or however you want to look
at it free Siege free tea free tea free
seats however the [ __ ] you want to look
at it and it just so happens the design
is dope like something you'd go and buy
at [ __ ] a store you know so it's like
you get seeds and a dope teeth [ __ ] yeah
and it turned into a monster it turned
into me [ __ ] getting boxes of
t-shirts let alone trying to find a
storefront
finding a storefront on [ __ ] Fairfax
let alone so it all just kind of just
happened man
there you go and you know do you feel
like you've quote made it so to speak at
this point
well I'm broke as [ __ ] man I ain't got
[ __ ] bro I ain't got no property when
I'm on a Beachside you know my buddy's
driving me on a helicopter from place to
place so I could go have a business
meeting and then be able to home and
sleep at night in my [ __ ] house in
Calabasas or some [ __ ] like that that's
when you made it but man I'm I'm [ __ ]
I'm still trying to figure it out gee I
didn't make [ __ ] that's all people see
what they want to see and and that's all
I let them see man they they only see
they don't see my wife throwing a
[ __ ] control at me across the house
you know they only see you know my wife
handing me this t-shirt all nicely you
know it's like
yeah okay I mean that raises a really
interesting point do you feel like there
is just like all this sort of behind the
scene Works which people often kind of
discredit because Instagram often you
know it doesn't really show that a lot
of the time
there's some shitty people out there
that don't want their shitty lives uh on
Instagram like they made shitty
decisions in the past I own up to
anything I do so I'm very open about
everything like I'm an ugly [ __ ]
so what you know show the ugliness but
try to make it look good you know and
and I'm very open like people could
[ __ ] tell you like what I did today
because I'll be [ __ ] crackhead on my
phone all day so like it's weird like
that I'm trying to figure it out there's
a balance to everything
uh I I do hide the shitty [ __ ] of course
I'm not going to tell you like like if
someone's doing adultery you think
they're gonna be like oh man [ __ ] my
wife caught me cheating today like it's
gonna be a terrible week uh the seeds
are and the plants are gonna look bad
like nobody's and if they do they're
just [ __ ] crazy like keep that [ __ ]
to yourself you know
yeah of course of course
so just to jump back to what you
mentioned earlier about how you know you
were doing the buy a shirt get some
seeds or get get the seeds get a free
shirt however you want to look at it
I've noticed that you have got to be the
king of like the insane promos and I
think that the the thing which like
really piqued my interest in that is you
were doing like 15 packs for like 450
bucks or something like that I think
you're doing even better deals than that
at the moment
do you feel like this is a really good
way to get your work out there and to
have people wrapping your brand or do
you think you're just trying to be good
to the customer
it's both gee uh these dudes uh uh you
know whatever
they want to make it like
like it's [ __ ] the Holy Grail you
know like dude you have a five gallon
bucket of those [ __ ] seeds like do
you not want people to have them you
know like like you like
there's ways of doing things you know
and I and I've managed to figure it out
how to do it my way people think it's
like they're whoring out their strain
you know well isn't that what you want
kinda you want everybody to try your
perspective nah only these select people
at this select price you know and there
are strains that you can allocate
towards that price because you put more
work into them Etc or or there was only
so many of them so you can do whatever
you it's your [ __ ] product you can
price at whatever you want and uh some
people do better than others you know
sure and I I mean it raises the question
do you feel like what you're doing might
help bring a new sort of era of pricing
for seeds and that like gone are the
days of you know the 150 pack sort of
thing
it is man everybody uh not everybody but
I've I've had seed makers sellers
whatever you want to call them hit me up
and be like dude that is you're [ __ ]
crazy it was 15 for 300 at one point and
I would let them pick the 15 packs from
a [ __ ] extensive list and uh they're
like would it like Anna had the five for
100 so if you didn't have 300 to cough
up you can get five packs but those
would be dealer's choice you wouldn't be
able to pick them from a cohesive list
but uh to date I still have that except
the the 15 for 450 is is a different
tier and you whatever I sound like I'm
selling the [ __ ] now that's not what I
want to do uh
we're talking about how we're driving
the price down uh I think they it's just
you got more work to do now you know
what I mean now you gotta have somebody
bag and tag for you now you gotta really
you know put your [ __ ] boots on strap
up because you know here comes [ __ ]
Masonic and he has five gallon buckets
of every strain he's ever made and it's
[ __ ] he can give them away all
[ __ ] day for a whole month if he
wants and then and then [ __ ] sell him
again it's like it's uh I gave away more
seeds than I've sold that's for [ __ ]
sure you know what I mean uh
and five for 100 that's what like 50 60
seeds or some [ __ ] like that is that's
not too many seeds man uh
I get it some people don't have all the
space but we're in a different time
we're in a different area era people
have to grow very secluded very
secretive back in the days access to
genetics and all that [ __ ] you know
there was it was harder now it's it's
the future and and
you know we move a little faster like
the internet you know information goes
fast
everything's faster now let alone my
seed production method
and how the cells go yeah I mean so much
to go into there I guess the first thing
I quickly ask about is your seed
production method on on the surface when
I was looking at just your your output
is insane like there's just new crosses
dropping left right and Center do you do
this by having a few different sites and
kind of Staggering things or do you make
them all at once and then just slowly
trickle them out so it seems as though
new stuff's always being made what's
your approach to that
uh well I will what I did uh this season
I just kept the Mel and I just kept
bringing out Mel's any given week from
my big mouth or or I you know let alone
brought out the big Mel at the very end
or in the middle pollinated him and kept
the cuts so it's all like there was
always polling around pretty much there
was always a tower of pollen hitting
everything whether it be a cut this big
one that grew out a little bit more you
know the Mel that I you know the whole
dad that I had and I just [ __ ]
flipped the whole thing and just you
know [ __ ] on everything and just
called it a day but yeah it's it's
keeping stages of him keeping towers of
him all spaced out throughout wherever
the [ __ ] I'm at okay yeah cool cool and
you also mentioned that you've probably
given away more seeds than you've sold I
remember in a prior episode Bodhi spoke
about how this is just sort of like a
good act to do in general it's kind of
like helping the scene out by giving
people seeds obviously it helps promote
you because although not everyone's
going to test the seeds you give the
them some will and some will post photos
and it'll help to get you a bit more
sort of notoriety amongst people do you
subscribe to that idea and do you think
that when a breed is sort of starting
out they should give some seeds away and
not just be trying to sell everything
from day one
yeah that's that's uh actually that's
some game right there that's some real
game actually uh dude you you when you
make your first cross man and you think
you're gonna just start me like uncle's
Scrooge of whoever the [ __ ] just you
know [ __ ] deep diving into gold bro
you need to relax and just start giving
[ __ ] away man you just just give away
half half of the seeds do you you're
gonna see they're gonna see other people
have them and they're gonna be like I
want some too now you can sell them you
know what I mean and it's good karma
points too so uh
uh I'm into mystical [ __ ] like that you
know I believe in positive out you know
output you and get some positive [ __ ]
back and ain't nothing wrong with you
know there's dudes out there that got a
yard but they think every seed pack cost
a hundred dollars you know they're just
because that's what every seed pack cost
until you know [ __ ] people like me
came around or been around you know I'm
not too privy maybe there are people but
they don't know how to use the Internet
or they don't even know how to go
through the Avenue of going it you know
so uh yeah [ __ ] give away your seeds
and then start your [ __ ] yeah for sure
that's gonna help you a lot
hell yeah so I mean on that topic of
making seeds what's the next couple of
Wilson crosses you want to make and are
there any sort of dream crosses where
like you're just trying to get your
hands on the female but you're finding
it hard to track down sort of thing but
you think it'll be like a winner
uh I'm not I'm not too uh I don't seek
the strains too much I'm not too like if
there's a hot strain on the market I'm
not like oh man like I need that it's
gonna really help you know me build
everything just kind of Falls in my lap
I've I'm I'm nice to a lot of people and
uh I give like I give and they give back
and it just so happens a lot of my
buddies have some cool ass cuts and I
happen to have a lot of them you know
they happen to follow my lap they happen
to get pollinated
foreign
pollinations with them so it'll be like
a g41 that I didn't you know transplant
and you know do full term or something
like that like like the Cuban black Haze
like even though I know it's probably
not going to be my favorite strain I
know a lot of people love it
but so I want to put it in their hands
and you know make some money just so
happens to be part of that you know what
I mean and people can be like oh I do it
for God nah [ __ ] like you're
doing this to you know put some food on
the table and maybe go to Disneyland too
you know what I mean so quit that [ __ ]
like you know you know you want to live
nice you know you don't want to [ __ ]
be mediocre and if you do well [ __ ]
you're ethical and you're cool and all
power too you know what I mean Namaste
but uh [ __ ] you know we're we're over
here [ __ ] uh you know we're doing
stuff for a reason you know and and the
guys that are gonna get the Cuban black
Haze Wilson Times Wilson again they're
going to be stoked for that that [ __ ]
they're gonna be like dude you grab my
favorite strain but not only did you hit
it to Wilson but you hit it twice and
and it's and it's cheap and I can get it
you know I don't got to go through you
know to this guy to get it because
[ __ ] it costs too much or whatever or
it's inaccessible like I'll make it
accessible and that strain along with a
bunch of other strains that you know I'm
stoked about like uh like the Mac Wilson
the Mac from Cut Wilson I hit that small
seed stock because Mac doesn't take well
to pollen so I'm gonna hopefully the
hybrid of it does so I'm gonna hit it
again
nice you you read my mind I was about to
ask with them with the Mac have you
figured out any tips or tricks to
getting it to make pollen or it's just a
luck sort of thing
well to take pollen to take pollen the
the cut uh I just hit it man just hit it
from from badge to finish and cross your
fingers that you get enough you know
that's literally what I did and and and
literally uh and I and I'd be like
[ __ ] like Cap's just saying that to
deter people from hitting it you know
like he's just telling you it don't take
but now like that [ __ ] don't take well
gee it really doesn't take well to
pollen and it don't want to give you
seed and that's kind of cool because
like you know that that's like one uh
one one step of red tape from people
pouring out his his uh
his you know his baby
yeah for sure and I mean I like to ask
oh guess this what's your thought on the
Mac flower and concentrate itself are
you a fan it's a bit of a polarizing
strain in its own right
uh I mean I've been to PC green a couple
times and I pick up Mac Gap skirt to
this day uh my buddy dog man was here
the other day he washed them it's its
own thing man it's it's dope Max cool
I'm not one to hate on any strain it's
just somewhere better than others
it's like man you hate weed like come on
dog chill out you know I don't hate
anything too hates or dislike like I
just don't like it I don't necessarily
dislike it
I'd like it less
yeah I feel yeah and I mean speaking
just referencing earlier I was watching
some of your YouTube videos and you were
testing like the Snowman from the
cookies crew Powers up and uh the London
pound cake these strains cop a lot of
hate not necessarily because the people
have tried them but just because they
really dislike the crew behind them
what's your take on these trains do you
feel like like some of these strains
which cop a bit of a flack are pretty
good it's just like the stigma
surrounding the crew that made them or
how do you feel about it
it's a quality control had a lot to do
with the stigma that was put on the
string now for instance Snowman when it
was debuted at Emerald cup there was
some moldy batches so people were going
to just put that you mentioned snowman
moldy you know so stuff like that
doesn't help and you know [ __ ] you
grow [ __ ] a million Acres or I don't
know how much they grow but and and
[ __ ] you're gonna you look hard
enough you're gonna find something but
uh it's just it's how you address things
too so uh
this politics and everything you know uh
the strains were good if they're good
they're good uh there was whatever when
I went to cookies burner called him
and had them help me while I was on the
phone with Berner and he made sure I got
all the fresh stuff so there goes
quality control like he made sure
like his you know that's smart on his
behalf you know what I mean like if
somebody went to your house like not
saying you sell weed but like say you
sold weed and it just so happened to be
like somebody you want to be in good
graces with and you there's there's
tears you know you're gonna call
whoever's serving that dude and you'll
be like hey man give them the [ __ ]
the head stash you know like I want them
to go home and and give me a good bias
so you know you can't blame them for
that you know [ __ ] there's there's
there's there's a product for everybody
not everybody can uh afford the fresh
batch they got to get you know the sun
grown or whatever so he made sure I got
the good stuff so of course he he was
smart about that he made sure I went
home and it just so happens I was doing
reviews at the time and he got good
reviews because everything I reviewed
wasn't [ __ ] terrible because you know
sometimes shit's bad and
you know and I and there's a complete
Hiatus on that uh on that [ __ ] because
it's just it's a whole ass job man you
you know you do this [ __ ] so editing and
all that my wife does it I record it and
I'm just like you know what we're just
gonna stop for a bit so yeah yeah I feel
yeah so something I've been personally
wondering about the whole cookie
situation is that as you referenced
there was some issues with quality
control with some of the outdoor batches
and it kind of raised this idea of like
for a longest time cookies was primarily
an indoor only sort of company like they
were selling indoor flour it was good
quality it helped get the brand to where
it is now they're expanding outdoors and
doing some sun-grown stuff do you feel
like overall that's beneficial because
it's providing like different price
points like some cheaper more available
stuff or do you feel like the potential
issues with quality control my overall
just diminished from the brand as it is
which is kind of got reputableness for
being like high quality
man [ __ ] that's that's that's a very
that that question has like 10 answers
to it probably but uh
I've never ran a big ship like that you
know uh they probably have a a dude that
does analytics on that [ __ ] you know
[ __ ] over there like dude like when
we put out you know you know said batch
from said skew you know [ __ ]
cells went above the roof and they just
keep going above the roof so they're
just like just keep putting it out that
you know and and and
and I know
you know you you get to know people and
you see what goes on behind the scenes
and [ __ ] so my thing is I like just
[ __ ] the truth always prevails so if
if they're like doing some shady [ __ ]
like they know they're doing it you know
so hopefully they're not you know who
knows I know that I got a personal call
and he's all like hey man QC but that
wasn't me that was somebody else or
maybe it was me I've I've talked to him
a couple times and I'm just like well
you know whatever uh I don't like to
dive into it because I'm not that's not
my business that's that's a big ass [ __ ]
right there you know will it diminish
the the brand I don't think so because
they're they're really really big and
and Instagram is so small compared to
the demographic that they kind of cater
to from what I see like not everybody
knows who you know uh Gage green is and
and like all these the Breeders they
just know that there's a shiny bag and
there's weed in it and that's what
everybody's smoking so they want to
smoke it too it's kind of like a
billboard you know so that's what they
are
and and if there's good product in there
then that's just extra you know what I
mean
and uh us we know
the smoke and mirrors but the the common
consumer is is is just getting a baggie
with stuff in there
yeah I mean gosh what a what a great
answer because there's so many Avenues
we can go off in to me you kind of touch
on this idea that's prevalent at the
moment and a lot of Growers really get
frustrated by it is among the just the
average consumer you know the sort of
hobby Enthusiast smoker the mylar
culture seems to be very prevalent you
know this idea of just anything in a
mylar bag with good advertising is going
to sell well how do you feel about that
does that frustrate you do you feel like
what's in the bag is more important than
the bag itself or do you just think it's
just marketing like get with the game
ah
it's it's Cutthroat bro it's Cutthroat
it's a it's like it's like a dude that
it's like hitting up the fake jungle
boys account and getting sold weed and
you're like hey they Bamboozled me it's
like
that's you see what I'm getting at it's
kind of like that so it's all like you
know what the [ __ ] you're getting into
you're in you're in uh you're in Texas
in the middle of nowhere you think
you're you're getting a real Gary Payton
cookie bag for forty dollars
like just like and and and that's that's
another thing is just you know educated
and it can go as far as remedial
education you know some dudes have a
hard time reading imagine how they are
[ __ ] trying to figure out what weed
they want you know what I mean
yeah sure so do you think that this
trend will basically continue where some
some of the things I've been told and
observed is that you know the quality of
the weed can kind of take back seat to
the good mylar do you think that that's
only Really Gonna fool the the kind of
inexperienced or do you think that Trend
will continue and weed might just go
down a bit in quality because the mylars
flashy enough
oh man uh
They're Gonna Keep uh they're gonna ring
it as as much as they can and probably
till till the end of time because
there's McDonald's and there's you know
the best burgers in the world whatever
you think that is you know so uh there's
there's always going to be that weed
around and they're gonna give it to you
in the best presentable package possible
and mylars just so happened to be the
one
sure and a question which I've been
pondering for a long time is in regards
to last time I was in the states which
was about a year ago now
um I noticed that like a lot of the weed
I was seeing and being presented to me
it looked really nice but a lot of it
didn't smell or smoke as good as it
looked and it kind of is like in that
same vein as the mylar and like it's got
the Aesthetics but there's not a lot of
substance behind it and then someone
said to me this thing which I thought
was really quite profound where they
were like
yeah like this this is what the demand
is because on Instagram you can't smell
buds people post you can't smoke it but
you can look at it and if it looks good
that post is going to be popular do you
kind of see that Trend yourself and do
you come across this sort of like weed
that looks good but isn't really quite
packing the punch you hoped
yeah man that that goes back to uh
uh organically grown [ __ ] you know
[ __ ] some weed might look terrible
and it's like the best [ __ ] ever so uh
and and and yeah bag appeal does sell
you know like that that hot girl does
sell but she doesn't cook
or do anything not that that's what
ladies are supposed to do but like my
partner you know
I want her to be smart and [ __ ] you know
[ __ ] some of them aren't some of them
are the whole package though you know
what I mean so [ __ ]
same thing with weed some of it just
looks really good but it it you know I
don't know [ __ ]
so do you think that that Trend with the
average consumer will continue whereby
like people are just looking for the
most Frosty thing and they don't
actually really care about the Terps or
the end effect
yeah it's easier to point uh to just
pump [ __ ] with hgv than it is to you
know put a little bit more love into it
you know people are doing big classrooms
teaching all these plants at the same
time
so they're only going to get so much
love
sure
and I guess the next question which I
don't think I've asked anyone yet but
it's got it ties into all this and it's
been on my mind forever there's this you
know amongst this same sort of consumer
group we're talking about like the sort
of casual Enthusiast
um the term exotic it's it's used to be
like you know that's the bee's knees
that's all I want the Exotic I realized
there's really no definition around what
exotic is like what to you is exotic
weed
exotic is uh what is exotic that's
that's like a
I don't know man anything burner is
promoting is exotic you know what I mean
like anything trending I think would be
like the right exotic definition even if
it's I don't know but what if like uh
Acapulco Gold is trending again that's
that's not exotic you know so exotic is
like you said that that's just it's
malarkey
yeah yeah so do you feel like it's more
of a marketing term than something that
actually has like a strict sort of
definition
yeah man it's it's like I could come up
with some [ __ ] like that like now this
is antique you know like we only smoke
antique weed over here
like it's kind of like that you know
it's like
[Laughter]
there you go the old school and I mean
it's probably about as good as the
Segway as I'll get as any antique you
know one of the favorite strains of the
show and I try to bring it up in every
episode because it's so near and dear to
my heart is the chem dog it's it's a bit
of an antique strain in its own right
what are your thoughts on the various
chem cuts and do you have a favorite
would you ever want to breed with any of
them
uh [ __ ] man I'd be lying if I uh told
you I had any of them you know my my
first the first time I had Kim
was from Skelly who works with 710 labs
and uh I went to his house and he gave
me some chem 91 in hash form and I'm all
like oh this is like GMO but you know no
no GMO is like chem you know what I mean
so uh that was like my first time and
I'm just like cool like Kim is GMO you
know like that's like that's kind of my
interpretation because I had smoked GMO
before I smoked Kim because I'm [ __ ]
new booty so uh
so uh I'm like so about like cam I fell
in love with Kim right away because it's
like oh you're the original one you know
what I mean to me that's how I look at
it like oh like this is where it came
from you know so uh chem and then uh
what other forms of Cam have I had
I don't know but that's like the first
time but I've had it a bunch of other
times and uh Kim's dope man [ __ ] chem
dog
has hit me up before too and uh he's a
cool cat you know
um I got the chemd I-95 Wilson that I
did that one's dope
there's some cool [ __ ] in there you know
that one was uh hit every box they grew
like 600 different plants of every
Wilson hybrid
and uh that one was the best one
so yeah chem dog wow lovely and I mean
are there any other sort of I love the
term antique I'm gonna keep using that
are there any sort of other antique
strains that you're fond of and or would
like to discover a bit more so like
things like you know like hazes or
skunks
yeah man I would love to uh dive into
the rabbit hole of haze I like the first
interpretation of Hayes that I had was a
it was called Lighthouse I think the
cross was called and it was like nl5
times nl5 times nl5 I was like they just
crossed no five a thousand times or some
[ __ ] and I'm like this is this is
different you know and like it grew on
me and then people would show me like
Hayes interpretations their derivatives
and I would have a marker for it so uh
today it's it's still not solidified yet
like you know there's other hazes and
[ __ ] so I'm I wanna I wanna meet foods
that have that like the homie was gonna
send me the A5 and the C5 or some [ __ ] I
have no idea what these are but he's all
like these are the ones you know or
they're part of you know that great
legacy of people getting Haze and then
the other day I was gonna get some other
Haze but oni's like no no no I'll do
better with it than you and I'm like
whatever dude I'm not in a rush to go
smoke Hayes I'll go get it from him
tomorrow anyways so uh yeah man I'm I'm
I'm trying to become privy to uh the old
books per se you know what I mean like
like anything like you you want to go
read the the first parts of the book so
that just happens to be some of the
first strains that were out that I'm I
want to get privy to everything
sure sure and there's I mean I'm sure
you've seen posts and heard people talk
about it but there's this huge sort of
collective push in the scene to find or
to revive the roadkill skunk what's your
thoughts on this do you think it exists
I'm kind of starting to get to the point
where I actually doubt it's even around
anymore
oh man I'm I'm like like we were talking
earlier I'm becoming aware of all this
and I've I've heard a
the funny [ __ ] before like I even had a
like for some reason I ended up in the
ITC dude's ear and he went as far as
going to my booth and showing me his
roadkill scunt and I'm all like I don't
even know you like that gee like what
are you doing here like he's like oh I
just want to make sure we didn't have no
beef like and I'm like dude we ain't got
no [ __ ] beef I ain't got beef with
nobody and he's like yeah man I heard
like people were tagging me in post
making fun of him so it looked like I
was part of the the the ordeal because
people would just assume I just make fun
of anybody but that's not my quarrel you
know what I mean but like that wasn't
cool either like dude like what are you
doing here get away and and that's it
you know like not even right now I'm not
even talking trash that's just that's
just what happened you know and and I
and I and he did show me like the the
roadkill skunk that he had and and
whatever it was just like whatever food
like that like let's just go be our own
people I wasn't I wasn't impressed you
know so uh
so you know as far as roadkill skunk
that's one interaction I had with it and
then before Matt Wright was on a team
[ __ ] you Masonic uh I would dive into
his lives and they would like talk about
and he'd like you know you know snivel
that other people even mentioning it so
it was like it's like it was always like
the way I look at it is like okay dude
what are you smoking right now all right
like you got a swisher sweet and an
eighth from the dispensary in a plastic
can like okay like as far as I'm
concerned you have no say in anything
like just shut the [ __ ] up and roll up
your weed and just smoke away you know
but like if you got some full melt and
you're over there just Fino hunting
every day you're every day you're
rubbing into plants becoming one with
the plant and you're just you're on the
pulse your fingers on it I want your I
want your perspective now you know but
uh and and if there's an old school guy
that's still on on the pulse smoking
every day smoking the new keeping around
the old that's who I want to hear the
perspective on rks you know so and and
even then I'm not like as far as I'm
concerned it's like
who cares
yeah yeah so
so another topic which I think is still
people trying to flesh it out because
there's just the ambiguity around it is
all of the ogs you know there's so many
variations in different cuts and it's
the the lineage is still a little bit of
mystery around it all what are some of
your preferred ogs and what's your
thoughts on the TK because a lot of
people think that the TK is probably the
original where do you sit that one
compared to the other OG cuts
well the thing with the OG's there was a
lot of all right here I go talking about
nothing I don't know about okay what I
know from me being a consumer in Los
Angeles where there was a lot of
dispensaries that primarily sold OG
I've seen a lot of vanity strains as I
like to call it or even renaming so that
helped pollute the namesake of you know
TK maybe you know so uh that's probably
it I've had TK by itself really really
great strain
uh but I've also had you know abusive OG
and you know Fire OG radiation OG
Spider-Man OG Batman OG [ __ ] sad OG
happy OG you know every [ __ ] OG known
man and they're all very similar and
they're all very good so uh I've only
I've grown the Tahoe I've grown the
hardcore
uh [ __ ] you know and oh gee I don't I
don't really have like a marker for
what's the the real one but it's it's
better to go get a TK cut because you
know at least you know what you're
growing
yeah kinda
so I guess the question then becomes you
know I think most people have had a cut
given to them at some point where it
wasn't what it was labeled be it either
unintentionally mislabeled or just the
person wasn't aware they had the wrong
cut have you ever had that happen to you
and which cut was the one you were
hoping to get but then like it didn't
turn out to be the right thing
uh no that hasn't happened but I have
gotten uh cuts that weren't labeled and
they were dope hit them to Wilson and
sell them as is so they'll be like hey
what's willotto it ain't a gelato cross
that's for [ __ ] sure so and
then I'll be like I don't know man like
my homie bad [ __ ] gave it to me
it was cool and I hit it to Wilson and
people are asking me what it is because
they love it and I'm like they're like
well I like it and that's it you know no
need to fake the funk be like oh you
know gelato bag seed like try to come up
with a story on the spot like no I
called it wallado because I I don't know
where in my right mind I I convinced
myself it was gelato and then I start
[ __ ] with real gelatos and that ain't
no [ __ ] gelato and then you know so
I'm like you know
a lot of okay so I mean on that topic of
you know clones and your clone Library
yours certainly seems to be very
impressive you know if you look at the
crosses you've made it seems like you've
got access to a lot of nice cuttings do
you keep these clones around or do you
just know you can access them again and
what's your thoughts on people selling
clones for like really expensive price
tags
uh [ __ ] I keep a nice network of people
that I trust to give me Cuts if I like
if I really like something you know some
Cuts even go as far as like okay [ __ ]
100 people have them already like
there's no way that's going to go
anywhere like the Compton land race
a lot Compton land race that's a whole
nother thing but like a lot of people
have that you know so like and that's
not even my cut so like that's kind of
how Cuts work for me like if I want
something to get spread I'll give it to
10 of my friends you know and and of
course other people are gonna have it
but that's the point you know so uh
that's kind of how that goes down uh me
keeping Cuts I I flip everything like
I'll keep some cuts on Mama mouth for a
while and then I'll be like okay I'm
tired of GMO I've crossed it to Wilson
10 times already like I think I can let
it go I think enough people in the world
have GMO for me to get it again so
there's never been anything that's like
like uh [ __ ] I really can't rely on
somebody else to keep it around for me
you know so there's never been anything
like that and if there is something that
I want like that I make sure to give it
to at least five [ __ ]
sure and I think the obvious follow-up
to that is was there ever a cutting or a
strain that you had for a while and you
were fond of it and then you lost it and
all of a sudden like no one else has got
it and it's gone forever
well my portfolio of uh strain knowledge
and that is very minimal so no way Jose
man you guys would be like you're stupid
if we've been you've known about strings
for four years like what what could you
possibly have that you missed so much
dude you know so I I've yet to have that
happen to me uh you know having
something like oh man this is a game
changer and I lose it now that hasn't
happened yet as far as a game changer
everything's you know everything's
everything so it's kind of just works
for me I've never had there there are
strains that excite me more than others
but I don't put all my eggs in that
basket so it never really hits me that
hard if if something doesn't follow
through like I want it to
sure and just as a follow-up because I'm
not sure we we chatted about it what's
your thoughts on people who sell
cuttings especially like I guess the
question for me is more interesting is
the person who found the cut so like
they they put in some work to maybe
either buy the seeds or Tofino Hunter
themselves what's your thoughts on
selling that at that point
so touching on uh
it's it's happening to me now where I've
done some work and they're using my name
to sell the cut for high price and it's
kind of it leaves a nasty taste in my
mouth like
so what I'm gonna do so that I don't
complain because I'm not a complainer
like that's as far as I go as
complaining is me telling you is I
address the situation
so what I do is I grab same said cut
and put it in my hands
and just lower the price
and now I'm happy
so uh yeah it can bother me so I'll I'll
put that into I'll put I'll get in the
driver's seat and just bust out a
[ __ ] million trays and stand on the
corner and [ __ ] sell it for ten
dollars just to make me happy
yeah I mean that's it is proactive right
I like that
Yeah man so you touched on just a moment
ago the Compton land race and I've been
interested in this one for a while most
notably because I think the name's
interesting it's obviously not a true
land race
um what's the backstory behind this
oh Compton land race okay so it's
Face-Off OG I-95 star dog from seed that
I got that I hunted in my end or when I
was running my indoor that I got from
secret society company and then that's
when I was like man I suck at indoor
like I I need to you know do something
with this I spent all my tax income
money on it I work at Rite Aid my wife's
yelling at me if I turn my whole garage
into a grow like I need to do something
so here goes oh willy-nilly you know all
to Wilson so boom we got face off OG I95
stardog Wilson uh one of the first uh
set of Wilson hybrids that I made so I
grow that out no no no
okay so I have that seed stock my buddy
down the way who still is in Compton
still is growing it out
he grows it out and uh he's like oh man
I'm growing out your face off OG I-95
star dog Wilson you know like what
should I do with it and I'm like just
grow it and he's like oh I got this Mac
that's when calculator had done his his
Mac uh from seed you know the first trap
and everybody went crazy for it and he
also had a meat breath Mel
and he's like well I'm gonna throw it
outside and I'm gonna let it get hit by
these and I'm like like whatever you
know like you know and then uh sure
enough he he does the pollination so
it's face off OG I-95 stardog Wilson
potential Mel's Mac or meat breath and
then cool we got this seed stock and uh
it's it's called motor mouth at this
point and I go to Oklahoma and I sell
that [ __ ] to everybody as is like on the
[ __ ] package open pollination Mac
meat breath they're just like [ __ ] it
you're Masonic I'll take one and then so
so whatever that happens and uh I grow
that [ __ ] out
and uh in my yard and and I'm like whoa
this is actually not half bad and uh I
had a peanut butter breath Mal that hit
it like uh
and that's that's Compton land race
so it's Face-Off ogi 95 star dog
potential males Mac meat breath times
peanut butter breath
and then I hit it back to Wilson again
so but that's Compton land race now it's
Compton land race times Wilson
wow that's got a bit of everything for
everyone doesn't it
I mean I mean it's just a fun little
project you know
all right that's just what I needed in
this [ __ ] love it what did you just hit
uh so when I take dabs I take really
really huge Dabs out of everything
because you know
we work hard for that [ __ ] so I'll grab
like a you know
a dab that's not gonna get fully hit per
se
you know everything on the stick's not
gonna get smoke so I'll have a container
where every time I'm done with that dab
I'll throw it in there so there's a
hundred flavors that I did that jar to
to the point where it got filled to the
brim that I had to split it in two jars
so that's what I just smoked right now I
smoked one of those jars lovely so it's
like like a bit of everything the jungle
mix
it's a gumbo for sure it's a big old
gumbo but that one tasted like the
rainbow belts that I was smoking so it
had a lot of uh rainbow belts and
Skittles if it's not I'm dumb but it
tasted like Skittles
s there's all types of Skittles tonight
oh just [ __ ] Skittles everything
I mean that's a good point to talk about
for a second I find that Skittles is
interesting because the overwhelming
majority of people love the flavor of it
right that's why it got big it's done
well for itself but you get a small
subsect of people who are like just
tastes like soap to me where do you sit
on that
I don't taste like soap to me Skittles
has its own unique profile I got preview
the Skittles not in the States but when
I would go travel to Barcelona they
[ __ ] love Skittles out there and
[ __ ] Skittles you know if it ain't
Skittles [ __ ] get the [ __ ] out of
here so uh you know I fell in love with
it out there came back home
and it's been a wrap since
and it ain't so I've had some soapy [ __ ]
before and
[ __ ] disgusting and and and that's
crazy because I've never like like I
can't even say what weed that is I I can
just I'm just like dude you had that in
the [ __ ] laundry or something you
know what I mean because there's no way
weed can be that [ __ ] bad but if it
is man that's probably like the only
strain that I'll hate you know what I
mean and it ain't Skittles because
Skittles ain't that soapy [ __ ] and one
time I did have a strain like that when
we were in Colorado I was smoking with
uh Ginger larf and and and and and
[ __ ] I forgot his [ __ ] name but
he's uh real Rocky's homie and they'd be
able to tell you what [ __ ] strain
that was but uh hopefully I can uh you
know show them this podcast and they'll
be like oh that was this train and I'll
be like [ __ ] that strain that's the only
strain I hate
there you go I mean you touched on the
the Barcelona scene which I think is an
interesting sort of scene in its own
right what's your thoughts when you go
over there do you feel like in a couple
years that would be kind of where the
USA scene is do you feel like they
follow the USA Trends too much what's
your thoughts overall
that's two whole different Vibes G uh
even amongst us in LA from state to
state city to City so
you can't replicate that you know uh the
the the
let alone the [ __ ] the city you're in
like you're in you're in like old world
you know catalonian land and then next
you know you're smoking a joint like you
can't replicate that you know so uh it's
its own thing
sure and I mean interestingly we've seen
a lot of people leave California
say since the start of the Year often
citing things like that it's too hard to
get into the legal Market rents in
California are quite prohibitive things
like that and they're moving to other
states do you feel like Barcelona or
some of these other states will
eventually Take the Lead over Kali as
the hot spot or do you think it's always
going to retain that title of like the
weed Mecca of the world so to speak
yeah the the uh Cali will remain uh the
mecca I think but other places will
emulate and innovate you know what we
got going here some places you know
already do that so uh
you know California I think is the
[ __ ] you know the place that people
you know good weed in California go hand
in hand
yeah touche too right
so on that note of doing a dab right
there and I think I can see you grinding
up some flour right now my question is
if you had to pick one or the other
which would you be a concentrate or a
flower guy oh man I'm not hash all day G
hash I love me some dab of some hash
hell yeah and what sort of style of hash
do you like water hash do you like dry
sieve like what's your preferred if you
could choose anything
full melt full melts uh water extracted
hash is you know rare but it's there and
that's my favorite full body for
everything it just feels the best uh and
second is Hash rosin
really great too
sure good picks good picks do you feel
like water hash and more importantly as
you alluded to like you know full melt
you know the five star the best quality
you can get do you feel like it's almost
becoming a bit of a Dying art I feel
like we're seeing a lot of concentrates
in the market but water hash doesn't
seem to be as well represented as say
like BHO or some other styles
I mean uh it's easier to polish a turd
with BHO and those other styles with
full melt it's fire in fire out so if
that shit's not pristine it's just not
going to be good you know so uh you
can't really hide it a lot in full melt
so a lot of people aren't the most
versed so they can't achieve full amount
and if they do it's not up to par so
they end up squishing it into hash rosin
because Lord knows
they would rather have some [ __ ] full
milk too but you know it's it's probably
has too much particulate in it or just
doesn't you know smoke as good as the
hash rosin you can make what it does so
uh
that's the case with full mouth
sure and do you think that it just
worked out coincidentally that like the
Wilson mail is really good for adding
trichomes for kind of making strains
that would suit this style I guess what
I'm trying to ask is do you breed for
concentrate production or it was just
sort of a like a happy coincidence that
that was how the Wilson mail happens to
affect crosses
yeah it was a happy coincidence because
uh it could have been I could have been
when I made that like that was it like
it could have been something else it
could have been uh
two strains from somebody else
who wasn't as good as Oni you know and
that would have never happened so it was
all coincidental and it just so happens
these wash really well papaya washes
really well banana G washes really well
chop F2 just so happens to wash all
three of them together [ __ ] you know
there was nothing that you know reduced
the quality and the genetic per se but
I'm not a [ __ ] uh
you know I'm talking about [ __ ] I don't
know about because you know I'm just
[ __ ] like you know it is what it is
so so you mentioned earlier that a lot
of your breeding involves hitting Wilson
to things and kind of seeing what comes
out of it do you ever approach any
crosses where you've you kind of think
of it conceptually and you're like oh I
think that these two strains are going
to pair really well together or is it
just a bit more sort of haphazard in the
way you approach it and you're just like
well if it's going to work it's going to
work we'll just see what happens like
how do you approach making it it's
usually uh uh what the mom's about you
know so if Mom's banging I like the mom
you know I'm like oh this is gonna be
cool you know because that's what I like
but if it's like oh like here goes
nothing you know hopefully someone likes
it then that's what that is and and
that's exactly what that is because
there's people that like stuff that
other people don't like and [ __ ]
that's how life is you know [ __ ]
colors and [ __ ]
yeah sure
so on the topic of Wilson we had a few
listeners chime in and ask what would be
some of your top picks for the Wilson
crosses if they're kind of thinking
about snatching something up from the
site what do you recommend and what's
like your sort of personal favorites
well [ __ ] uh I would ask them what's
their favorite you know like what do you
like okay I just so happen to have that
cross the Wilson go check that out I
would tell them go grab Wilson by itself
but that's gone you know so they can
have a marker of what they're getting
into and see what that Wilson even
brought to said mother said strain so
they could be like oh cool like I see
the Wilson in The GMO because I've
actually smoked Wilson before so uh
I I used to tell people go get Wilson so
now it's all like oh get what you like
oh you like gelato go grab the g33
Wilson oh you want like some old land
race type [ __ ] you want some antique
[ __ ] I got you you know [ __ ] you want
some Exotics I got you you know cover
every every marker but uh yeah I would
tell them to grab what they like
and if they they don't know what they
like I'll tell them go grab the five for
100 because you're just gonna get a
bunch of seats and [ __ ] you're gonna
have fun and you won't feel bad because
it wasn't a hundred dollars for [ __ ]
12 seeds it was you know way cheaper
sure
another question we got from a lot of
customers was regarding testing and I
think that there historically has been
this sort of
tradition of people testing their
crosses but in a more recent sort of
turn of events we've had many breeders
come on the show and say that if you're
going to make crosses and test them out
and do the whole nine yards often the
trend and the hype has come and gone
before you can get that to Market what's
your thoughts do you subscribe to that
idea and do you tend to test
that's that's a nice way of putting it
you know the way they say it you know
that's that's [ __ ] yeah that's that's
like you know you sound you sound cool
saying that but yeah straight up uh new
[ __ ] I just put it out I don't test new
[ __ ] but then again
they're not they don't have to buy that
[ __ ] there's a hundred strains that are
two years old almost to date that are
tested and I got numbers and I can show
you a thousand pictures of so you can be
like Oh I like that you know or you can
you know [ __ ] do what I do and just
grow any [ __ ] seed and see what
[ __ ] happens and and be on top of the
game and what they said by the time you
know I test any runs Cross or any given
hype strain the new one's going to be
out so [ __ ] it's just just be honest
about it [ __ ] if you didn't test it
you didn't test it easy does it and and
if nobody needs to buy it but if they
weren't tested I got that too we got a
hundred [ __ ] strains that are tested
you know [ __ ] there's a little bit of
everything so uh and everything will be
tested [ __ ] from the day you grab
that strain [ __ ] somebody else you
know three weeks later is gonna be like
boom here's the pictures and I'll be
like here's your tested [ __ ]
have a good day because that's exactly
what it is you know [ __ ] they can say
like oh you know [ __ ] I don't think
they're out there with like a chart and
like a 200 Fino hunt on every strain
they make I I highly doubt it and
they're like oh you know 20 Herms and
you know germ raid Etc no most of the
time it's all like oh the homie [ __ ]
that I never even met on Instagram that
I sent testers to popped them he sent me
a couple pictures it's tested he gave me
a cool perspective and uh some people do
have their testers and you know all
power to them like capillator the
stranded I can't really stranded until
cap is finished testing it
so you know I do abide by those rules
when I need to and you know with a cross
with cap he's not going to let you know
a bunch of Herms pop up with his collab
with Masonic because it'll be funny so
uh but but yeah like you know there's a
hundred tested strains guys you know
[ __ ] you want some tested [ __ ] I got
you you want to be you know the new guy
with the new [ __ ] I got that too you
know what I mean whatever you want
sure
so you mentioned earlier that Wilson as
a pure strain was sold out do you ever
plan to remake it or do you like the
idea of like there being some amount of
exclusivity by not just continually
remaking strains
and now F2 that that's it you know
whoever got it they got it if they want
to keep a clone of it around and let it
circulate you know by all means we're
we're working on the F3 already so you
know I already have the F3 so I'm gonna
pop those out maybe find a keeper rotate
that around and make the F4
nice and I mean another question is
about new males you know everyone's
familiar with the Wilson work so we had
quite a few questions regarding possible
new males and I noticed on your website
that there were in fact a few crosses
that utilized a monkey berries male
which I believe is from exotic genetics
is that correct yeah that's that
strawberries and cream
uh
across to Grease Monkey my high ass yeah
that's exactly what it is so what
happened there what I do every year
uh so
two years ago or a year ago I like you
grow a lot of seeds right and there's
males and and sometimes you spent money
on them and you're just like [ __ ] I
don't want this male to go to waste it's
like a cool no it has runs in it or it
has Grease Monkey in it you know it's it
looks promising amongst you know it's
counterparts so what I do what I did is
like hey Los Angeles who wants to make a
strain would Masonic and they're like me
me me me me me me me me so I was like
come okay come grab the smell hit it to
you know your selection bring me half
the seeds you know you keep half I keep
half so everything that isn't a Wilson
hybrid on my site was pollinated and and
it wasn't like a random person the
people that I did have do it were part
of uh my people that become my friends
now like you know Long Beach reefer did
the monkey Berry cross for me uh I-beam
Poppin did the uh Blissful wizard cross
uh for Masonic exceed company or for
himself however you want to look at it
he made the seeds you know that I just
so happen to have on my website that I
provided the mail for that I grew out
that I selected for them I'm like hey
you should use this it's a cool
promising strain uh same thing with slap
switches runs Grease Monkey
and there's a couple more that probably
aren't even you know up for grabs but
that I have that I've done with uh you
know a bunch of other of my buddies that
grow as well and they're super into it
because you know they get to [ __ ]
make seeds and keep them and now they're
in other people's hands because you know
I got a big Avenue to put seeds in
people's hands and they're like cool
[ __ ] my seeds are in Ecuador now you
know yeah you made that in your backyard
[ __ ] good [ __ ] we did that together
you know it's a team effort
yeah that's a good way to do collabs so
in general what are you looking for in a
strain when you're looking to pop a new
one and maybe find a male in it and I
guess in general are you a fan of
Exotics work
everything I've grown from exotic uh I
grew the the funky charms I grew the
strawberries and cream I grew the slaps
the Grease Monkey strawberries and cream
I grew the slabs and everything so far
has been I haven't been like oh that's
just not good you know everything's been
great actually everything was great
and [ __ ]
When selecting anything it's just you
know of course I'm not going to go with
the rents you know the runts it's like
all right like that's no bueno
uh just the best [ __ ] you can tell
[ __ ] the [ __ ] that Stacks the most
the [ __ ] that smells the most you know
the more vigorous ones [ __ ] like that
people want to make it like this this
this [ __ ] hard ass process but you
know you put five fools in front of me
and I can tell you who's more athletic
you know [ __ ] it ain't the food that
weighs 300 pounds you know it's it's the
six foot tall dude who's [ __ ] built
like a linebacker it's the same thing
with plants you could see it you could
feel it you've been growing for 10 years
I hope you could [ __ ] tell which one
is better than the other one
definitely and that's a great answer in
terms of seguing to the next question
which is what are some of the traits you
look for in a male when you're looking
to breed with it or is it more of a
process of like feel and like you've got
a hunch on this one
uh it's like
like the way I chose this one you just
stuck out the most you know he was a bit
more
the bigger one you know he just grew the
fastest
and that's how I chose my most recent uh
mail that I have so
it just sticks out amongst the pack and
it is a hunch if you want to call it
that and as far as like oh I look for
internodal spacing and all that other
[ __ ] like I didn't dive that deep
I'm just like that's the one we're gonna
do work let's do work oh cool everything
all the progeny from it has been A1 so
you know it worked
boom yeah you just kind of touched on an
interesting topic there and I think DJ
Short kind of summarizes it the best
himself where he says he kind of says
look you know some people will tell you
that there's certain things you can look
at in a mail and it'll indicate whether
it's going to be a good or bad father
and he was like but at the end of the
day [ __ ] all that it's about testing the
seeds and if the seeds are good the male
was good it's just that simple do you
subscribe to that idea or do you think
there are certain things you can look at
the mail and be like oh you know this
one's got the short into nodes it'll be
better
nah nah I haven't talked to
uh
a breeder and dove in that deep and and
respected that opinion to that point you
know but uh there are some there are
some things like that but you know the
other day I learned that you know the
the root ball in any given male could be
you know like a good indicator of a good
male because you know it has a bigger
stomach per se and it can uptick
nutrients and [ __ ] but uh but DJ Short
is right in the way that you know if the
shit's good it's good and [ __ ] and no
matter how you [ __ ] chose the mouth
there's no denying that [ __ ] you
could have did the any mini miny mo
method you know you could have had your
neighbor juice for you like [ __ ] you
could have pulled it out of the [ __ ]
hat but as long as the shit's [ __ ]
good that's what matters and you know
whatever selection method you have
that's good too good for you you [ __ ]
you know everything about weed you know
every [ __ ] you know I'm sorry I'm
using the f word you know every every
scientifical term for every part on the
plant like you're the man dog you know
good [ __ ] you're the wizard and uh those
guys are usually the ones that you know
like to be the ones with the crown and
[ __ ] so my thing is just do it man just
just make the [ __ ] grow the [ __ ] and be
happy
so let's say you decide to pop a new
strain you know we'll just say that the
monkey berries from exotic you've
decided you want to run some of it
do you generally have a certain number
of seeds you like to run like do you
feel like one Pack's enough or you like
to get a couple packs how does that work
oh no man um I'll get away with popping
six of them [ __ ] Doug I'll pop
half the pack and or or the whole pack
you know and and [ __ ] most of the
time you find some dope Shin there but
sometimes nothing comes out of it like
the [ __ ] seeds won't even make it
you'll get all males and you'll be like
nothing uh sometimes you get the most
beautiful female and you're just like
damn like that's that's that's some
gangster ass weed right there but uh and
it's never more than [ __ ] one pack
the only [ __ ] that I do more than one
pack is when I cross it to Wilson again
because now I I got more [ __ ] to play
with you know what I mean so I can cross
I can pop you know as opposed to you
know I went and bought a hundred dollar
plus pack of 12 seeds from any given
breeder you know I'm like [ __ ] you with
these seeds you know like I don't want
these to go to waste so I hit them to
Wilson
and then now I got a million of them you
know so now I can go play with these
more and and that's kind of when it
comes to Big Fino hunts it's most likely
going to be a Wilson hybrid
sure I mean it makes sense right so I
guess the kind of the final question on
Fino hunting I have is that when you do
run some new seeds are you primarily
looking at the females and if you're
impressed by the females you then
consider using a male or is it the other
way around where you go into it thinking
I want to find a female uh sorry a male
I want to find a male nah it's never one
to find them out it's the male is always
Wilson as is my mouth unless it's like
what the [ __ ] is that you know then then
I'll I'll do what I did with the other
ones you know where I I you know
Outsource them to another person so
there's no cross pollination going on so
uh sometimes and it's not even looking
for a Mel it's all like that has a nice
calling to it or you know we we can hype
that you know like that's runs times
this we should totally continue that you
know because people are gonna want that
you know or or that's a CBD or you know
that's freak Show freak shows gnarly you
know or that's Australian bastard
cannabis no matter what it is we have to
continue that you know what I mean so
it's it's [ __ ] like that you know it's
it's there's equations to wanting to
keep something around whether being
female or in malformed
sure so you just mentioned CBD and I
noticed on your site that you actually
do have a CBD cross using the uh I think
it's the auto Colorado Cherry mother
crossed to Wilson is this something you
did because you specifically wanted to
be able to provide people with a CBD
option or do you think that there's
actually a bit more to CBD than most
people think and you've got kind of some
future plans to work with it more
so my buddy had uh did a CBD seed stock
like by itself so he had [ __ ] a whole
room full of that [ __ ] and he's like hey
Masonic like want to sell some CBD and
I'm like man I don't know [ __ ] about CBD
like and he's like well you know he he
put me on game and he's like it's uh box
Colorado Cherry Box Auto or some [ __ ]
like that it's actually know what it is
but that's that's what it is it's auto
box Colorado Cherry Auto Times Wilson
and uh
he's all I used to sell it so I start
selling it to people and as CBD
and people are growing it and they're
sending me back results and it's CBD
thank [ __ ] God so it's CBD and I'm
all like and I'm like man everybody
keeps asking me for CBD you know CBD CBD
so I already had CBD so I was telling
them that it wasn't a Wilson hybrid yet
I was selling them to it as is and I
still have some of that stock and then
I'm like [ __ ] it you know I'm gonna grow
some myself too so I I have this bed and
I just literally just [ __ ]
like because I had a lot of it I just
threw a handful in there and I grew out
of bed full of CBD hit it to Wilson so
in that CBD seed stock it's actually
like any given mother that she'll get in
there Times Wilson but it's it's box
auto box Cherry Times Wilson though and
that's exactly what it is people are
growing at I've yet to get tests on it
but it is a CBD THC cross
and and is that something you want to
maybe delve a little deeper into in
regards to just generally CBD stuff or
do you just like being able to provide
that option
uh uh I like to cover everything and I
you know I got a lot of uh questions on
CBD CBD you know and I'm all like well
[ __ ] you know I'll this ain't [ __ ]
you know uh
I don't have like a paper and [ __ ] but
you know this is as much as I can tell
you on CBD we had like some COA and [ __ ]
but you know how from County to County
to state to state hot can you know it
can go from up and down so some places
it could have been hot and [ __ ] so you
know my buddy almost got in trouble for
that but the way I sold it is like look
here [ __ ] like this is CBD you know
like this isn't you're not getting this
with a [ __ ] lawyer or nothing this
isn't I'm not going over here telling
you to go do a whole cash crop you know
[ __ ] in in in Idaho somewhere where
they grow a bunch of it I don't know but
I'm I'm just giving you a couple and and
it is CBD but it is because I got tests
and [ __ ] you know people love it and
he did too and it's just it's just hot
in some places compared to others yeah
sure I think you know the variation is
is somewhat intrinsic to plants right
like they're not they're not identicals
of each other another cross I noticed on
your site which caught my eye was
actually uh you did a cross using the
Romulan clone and I wanted to ask what's
your thoughts on the Romulan it's come
up a few times in the show because as
far as we can tell it might be the
oldest clone in existence if you trace
it back it appears to be older than most
things
do you think your Cut's the original and
are you a fan of it
I got Romulan from three sources I got
Romulan from some dude that's pretty you
know like he's
you know he he's not like out here like
Masonic you know 40K followers but you
know like he was in the forums back in
the day and you know he can talk to you
know all these esteemed Growers and [ __ ]
and for whatever reason he reached out
to me and went as far as uh I don't know
how some way but we he ended up using my
name as his as his cloning so he's
Masonic cloner so he sent me a Romulan
cut so he's like pretty cool in the
scene you know what I mean I think you
know Growers know who he is and stuff
like cool Growers or whatever like like
old school fools you know as opposed to
you know us new guys and he reached out
and sent me a lot of old school [ __ ] and
I kind of took it for granted because
you get lost in the sauce sometimes and
you're just like yeah yeah whatever use
Masonic cloner oh cool cool send me
those clones he sends me like everything
anybody would ever want like as a
starter pack and you're like whatever
I'll hit him to Wilson and I did
but like but you lost that relationship
because I wasn't too thankful about it
because I should have been more thankful
about it because that's not just
something you get and uh
and I think back on that so
and whatever that's the whole other
story but that's who I got one of my
romulans from and another Romulan I got
from one of my buddies who just he just
trades back and forth so uh with him I
wouldn't like take it I'd take it with a
grain of salt more than anything because
you know it matters who you get it from
you know so the Masonic cloner guy
pretty tapped into the old school scene
I'd imagine he'd have some type of
Romulan you know uh other dude got it
from probably four other [ __ ] people
that's you know quote unquote Romulan
there you go and and overall are you are
you a fan of it or you think it's a bit
of a yesteryear one but the Wilson cross
adds a new flavor to it
I have no [ __ ] idea I grew it in my
Greenhouse amongst [ __ ] uh a thousand
other strains hit it to Wilson probably
looked at it twice and uh I need to grow
it out and to his full potential to be
like that's Gucci and that's what I'm
doing right now I got Romulan Wilson uh
I got six of them growing right now so I
can grow a nice big one to be able to
tell you like that's John Blaze or not
nice well there you go we'll have to
wait and see I noticed on your Instagram
recently that you had mentioned you were
doing a collab with soul fire and I I
like Soul fire Gardens I think he does
some good stuff tell us a little bit
about is it the dawn magic wand is that
how you say it yeah yes named after the
pimp Don Magic Wand
so what what do you think's gonna what
can people expect from that one in terms
of flavor profiles and whatnot and I
mean it's got a cool name how did you
come up with the name just just after
the pimp
yeah well he it's cut it's Don Mecca and
I'm just like oh don't make a Don Magic
Wand you know like the Don it just
clicked right away so I'm like let's
name it after this pimp guy you know so
that's how we got the name he thought it
was a cool name he totally rolled it I'd
never name anything so you know [ __ ]
I I had to really make if if I named
some [ __ ] it's gonna matter so it
mattered he he went amongst himself
not he when him he did the Apollo he did
all the legwork he [ __ ] found the
female hit it to his mouth I sent me the
seed stock and is like you know and win
as far as growing it all out while I'm
like selling it the whole time so uh
like he he'd be able to tell you more
like of what that plant actually does
he's sending me some you know I'm going
out there or something like that you
know I don't want to accuse anybody of
anything but I'm gonna be smoking some
of that soon so I'll tell you on
Instagram how it is
lovely lovely uh that that sounds like a
cool cross I like a lot of his work I
think you'll you'll do a nice little
combo together
yeah I love so far he's a really dope
guy uh I talked to him I grown a bunch
of his stuff I grown his mind flare I
grown his banana rods
and I I think that's it but and he grew
my papaya God that's what he hit the Don
Mecca with and papaya got his uh
papaya cake Times Wilson
there you go I think yeah I think it's
gonna be a flavor town right
yeah [ __ ] yeah
so I forgot to ask you a little bit
earlier when we were talking about
concentrates what's your thoughts on
Vape carts they themselves are quite
polarizing and I think the most
interesting thing to think about in
regards to all the Vape carts is like
obviously there they flood the market
they're very prevalent but someone made
this comment where it was like you don't
really see posts about buds with PM
anymore you just see lots of cards
oh yeah man nobody gets PM anymore I
thought you knew that
well yeah nobody gets PM anymore and
carts are mostly Miss for the most part
I actually have a good cart right here
because I have buddies that make them
and I get them you know from one hand
only you know instead of you know a farm
to here to hair to there but uh they're
mostly Miss and and it's not my
preferred way of consuming because it's
just not it just doesn't feel right I
rather drive around town with the joint
in my mouth than a vape cart and uh
[ __ ] cross my fingers I don't get
busted
a good good call good philosophy as well
so a lot of The Vape carts we see
entering the market are often as you
alluded from new producers that there's
a whole supply chain behind things and
and usually it's not high quality
because it's going through all these
different hands
what's your thoughts overall on someone
coming into the market wanting to do a
vape company or wanting to just start a
new sort of company because I think that
there's often a lot of distrust and a
lot of dislike from people who are just
entering the scene now because it's
often kind of painted as though like
they're just trying to do a cash grab
sort of thing what are your thoughts on
that do you think it's possible for
someone to come in and to want to do
something like that and to do it
properly or it's inherently like a bit
of a sketchy situation
uh there's always a harder worker so
like there's always room for that you
know don't don't be discouraged like oh
man the Cannabis scene is saturated
they're not going to want to [ __ ] with
me there's a thousand shovels to this
cannabis industry you just gotta find
you know where you belong you know like
look at look at sticker farmer he he he
doesn't sell weed but he's a big part of
it you know what I mean as far as
Instagram is concerned uh things like
that so as far as you know a vape cart
like you would have to do a lot of
homework to to get into a vape card
scene because [ __ ] it's not just
something you do because it's to this
day it's I still think there's a lot of
work to do on those because everyone has
a [ __ ] different one and you don't
know which one's the good one and I
don't want to find out either because
[ __ ] most of the time they're bad so
it's like [ __ ] you already know
you're stepping into a trap so it's it's
hard to r d on those as far as you know
mass-produced ones are concerned uh
stepping into the Cannabis game if it's
a cash crab and that's what you're going
in for [ __ ] good luck I'll power to
you and if you [ __ ] figure it out
it's because you're a harder worker and
you fit and somebody was on their ass
and you caught them slipping
uh if you're in it with good intentions
well remember there's the guy with the
cash grab [ __ ] attitude out there
that's trying to work [ __ ]
you know trying to Outsource work do
whatever the case and wait till the
institutions come in and you think these
little guys are trying to figure out
these institutions are gonna [ __ ]
everybody up now I sound like a crazy
person like what's he talking about
these institutions like yeah man there's
people with a lot of money that can just
buy everything and [ __ ] hire
lobbyists to prevent other people from
setting up shop so but we're not in that
in that stage yet but eventually you
know we will be and [ __ ] it's going
to be even harder for people to
setup shop via marijuana
yeah I mean a brilliant point you
mentioned there and a discussion which
we've had with a few previous guests is
like what is the sort of incoming big AG
movement gonna do in regards to shaping
the Cannabis scene and one of the ideas
we've heard expressed is that there'll
be like a distinction between like The
Connoisseur or like the Craft Market and
then just like the mass produced sort of
thing what's your thoughts on the big
AGS involvement and do you think it'll
pan out as though like there'll always
be this connoisseur Craft Market that we
kind of currently exist in and then the
big AG will just be booth for the masses
or how do you predict it plays out
yeah man there'll be Bud Light weed for
everybody there'll be some dudes that
end up with a sculpin company they get
bought out by Bud Light and then they'll
be the heady beers that get bought out
by all the heady boys all the time same
thing with weed you know [ __ ] there's
gonna be a lot of boof and hopefully
like like if you love weed you're gonna
learn about it and you're gonna go look
for you know the small batch great [ __ ]
yeah good sentiment a good sentiment
so the question that we've received the
most inquiries about is this ongoing
meme or you're having with Mr Matt Riot
of Riot seeds are you able to give us a
little bit of a backstory on how this
all happened
oh yeah man uh so I get along with only
seed company that's my mentor
Speakeasy Seed Company used to work with
Oni they got into Cahoots Riot try to be
like a mediator
amongst Oni and speakeasy
you know he's basically buttoned his
nose in there
he
whatever that's their deal you know
so he's like
on a [ __ ] Oni Crusade and I just so
happen to be associated with Oni so he's
like saying [ __ ] me Sonic on his live
not my heart's racing because it's
[ __ ] now he's saying like because
because I just get like [ __ ] attack
mode but so he's like [ __ ] me Sonic [ __ ]
Masonic anytime anybody uh is on his
life yo what about Masonic oh he's dead
to me you know [ __ ] that guy he's you
know he's he's a clown you know he's a
[ __ ] he's a girl like oh he's just just
and I'm just I stay quiet I stay quiet
every day I knew I knew a new message
from somebody hey fool Ryan's talking
[ __ ] and I'm Life's good like I'm I
don't need to be in a coral like I don't
need
publicity like that I'm chilling this is
old Masonic I used to attack that's all
me
and I'm just like [ __ ] and and I go on
my I go into my secret accounts
and I go onto this page
and sure enough [ __ ] Masonic [ __ ] me
Sonic and I'm like man you know what
[ __ ] this [ __ ] and I just went and I
just like man [ __ ] you dude like you
know as much as I could and now I'm
right seed company so and and blue
bonnet's mine Clockwork Orange Is Mine
those are all my streams Now 26 cookies
mine right Berry mine uh Riot Seed Co
I'm the real right seed go I'm Matt
right now that's my [ __ ] now so [ __ ]
you know don't [ __ ] with me you know
wrong guy you should have just kept my
name out your mouth I was being really
political about it too you know you say
Masonic three times I might end up being
Matt Riot so I'm Matt right now
wow what a what a ton of events there so
I guess the the follow-up question to
that is do you plan to release strains
that are using the names of strains he's
done or do you plan to make crosses with
them what's the situation now we're
doing it quick we're doing it quick so I
none of my strains have names on them
so blueberries cement shoes Times Wilson
cross back to Wilson is now a blue
bonnet
uh orange Skittles uh times banana punch
Times Wilson is now Clockwork Orange
Girl Scout cookie Polynesian thin mint
Wilson is now 26 cookies
and I'm gonna have to figure out what
other uh strains are going to take what
names for uh and we're going to sell way
more seeds than he has and people are
gonna be like I'm growing Blue Bonnet
and and [ __ ] they're gonna tag Blue
Bonnet and we're gonna have a thousand
Wilson hybrids as Bluebonnet and [ __ ]
everybody's Gonna Know Blue Bonnet
belongs to the real riot Seed Company
so and and do you think that people
would rightly or incorrectly get upset
with how like lineages are like kind of
a bit muddied when you do that not with
me Sonic they know what's happening they
know what time it is there you go okay
kind of a more meta idea to what we've
been discussing is that I'm I'm a part
of obviously the Cannabis scene along
with yourself but I'm also a part of a
few other different online communities
and something that I've noticed over the
past year or so is that the Cannabis
Community seems to have a bit of a
disproportionate amount of drama in it
considering it's like a bit of an
oxymoron like we all smoke weed we're
meant to be chill and calm and yet
there's almost more drama than other
communities where there isn't this sort
of this psychoactive chemical that helps
calm you out what's your take on that
so you know it used to be you smoke weed
you're cool you know what I mean now
it's all like I smoke weed cooler than
you or something like that I don't know
what it is uh I like to think my
demographic I'm kind of Open Arms you
know as opposed to you know you got to
know this much before you enter here I
like to think you know I cover every
every demographic you know [ __ ] I
don't care what you know like I'm I
never answer questions seriously on my
life so like you're never gonna and if I
do it's like it's like feeding a dog uh
medicine you know like I'm being funny
and every now and then I'll put some
medicine in the dog food so you know it
goes to people every now and then next
you know you got people interested in
actually wanting to know about breeders
you know so and [ __ ] like that but uh
yeah [ __ ]
I got off I got off topic on the
question but [ __ ]
yeah that's all good that's so good I
guess my question like the follow-up
would be is do you think that the sort
of you know dramas we see play out will
continue or eventually people will maybe
chill out a bit and um kind of be a bit
more like the The Stereotype and just
become a bit of a chill stoner
you know what dude I was chill bro the
the problem was I was chill till till
[ __ ] Friday
I'm cool dude I'm I'm like the guy that
would throw rocks at everybody but but
not because I was being malicious but
maybe a little bit but like it was
mostly to poke fun and to laugh at
because like if they said something that
I didn't agree with I would like poke
fun at them and it's the internet and
that's what you can do on internet so I
would make I would poke fun at jungle
boys I would poke fun at coma I would
poke fun at Cali outdoor at anybody and
everybody
next you know [ __ ] I'm on a I'm on a
meme war and then you know drama blood
what people love
and then now we're all friends and now
I've come in to this part in life where
I got a business I'm running and and and
I've apologized to anybody that I made
upset like I've literally gone out of my
way and be like hey dude like I'm sorry
I didn't know how to make friends and I
was like trying to get your attention so
I was being mean and I made a couple
memes about you so now I'm in good
graces with jungle boys burner [ __ ]
coma Cali outdoor
and and all these people they all have
different demographics you know like
like people that [ __ ] with this guy
don't [ __ ] with this guy and me I'm just
I'd rather be cool with everybody so uh
if if if they're [ __ ] you Masonic
and they're like a big person and and
they're getting that message out to
everybody I'm gonna say something about
it if they're like a small dude that
just kind of went on my page and it's
like [ __ ] you make Sonic ignore that
you know but if somebody's out there
like [ __ ] with the [ __ ] Holy Bible
like you know with their own [ __ ]
Crusade I'm like nah man I'm gonna put
this to an end and and that's the only
drama you will get from me is is is
quick drama it used to be oh you know
this guy's dumb about weed I'm gonna
poke fun at him now now it's like okay
I'm over that we're running a business
now I'm nice to everybody now I'm not
gonna poke fun at nobody
but this guy was saying [ __ ] you a
hundred times so [ __ ] him and I'm better
at saying [ __ ] you because I'm more
computer savvy I'm I've been on 4chan
I'm better with memes I know how to make
people laugh better and that's where
this drama comes and people are like oh
man like can we all just get along like
dude I do just get along this
[ __ ] over here is saying [ __ ]
you every [ __ ] time so like I'm I was
tired of being quiet so I [ __ ] said
[ __ ] you back and I'm really good at
saying it so I'd like brought back the
old Masonic
yeah good answer I just want to jump
back to something you referenced a
little earlier at the start of uh this
sort of little answer to this section
here is that I noticed you have been
posting recently about Pokemon and
Yu-Gi-Oh cards and uh it all makes sense
now because we're about the same age and
so I realized you would have been
growing up with it about the same time
as me and I I likewise very into Pokemon
and you go I thought it was a bee's
knees have you ever played the games or
were you more of like like did you
actually play the game the card game
were you just more of like a collector
and do you collect any other sort of
stuff like that
uh I played the game as a kid I wasn't a
collector so I played and uh whatever
was meta at the time that's what I was
playing so like a Pokemon we played as
kids not serious but we got him to
Yu-Gi-Oh and you know we got Yu-Gi-Oh
serious business like we go to the
trading card store every weekend mom
would give us both 20 to 40 dollars and
we'd make it work and we'd have to
really learn and my I have an older
brother so I always had a mentor and uh
he would always get first place and I
would always you know get fifth or
something but uh I got better and
and uh I don't know how to play the TCG
anymore I just played my son that
Pokemon right now I just opened two
starter decks and uh the Charizard theme
Decks that came out and we played so I
still know how to play but Yu-Gi-Oh I
bought a deck box a blister box the
other day and I'm like looking through
the cards and I'm like [ __ ] no I can't
do this no more but I did recently stop
playing when uh whenever dark Strike
Fighter was banned on Yu-Gi-Oh so yeah
I'm I did play a little bit
oh man I love it I I remember spending a
good chunk on my youth playing that one
it was it was good for the meta
yeah man it's it's a
I still I still I'm into it and uh I
noticed a lot of people like uh logic
and I think it's Jake Paul is that
YouTube sensation's name I guess they
started collecting them amongst
themselves again and right before that I
had put out a big calling on my
Instagram I'm like dude anybody have
Pokemon cards trade them to me and I did
it right before like boof [ __ ] prices
went up now people don't even they think
they're in [ __ ] and and rolling in
Gold they're just like oh this is a
million dollars and I'm like dude relax
that's like a couple dollars they're not
even graded they're probably not even
mint condition and but uh everybody has
their Pokemon cards and and you know
everybody's looking for them because of
the you know prices are skyrocketing
right now
show
so the next thing I happen to notice
which was like a bit of a rare Niche
sort of thing is that unlike a lot of
people in the Cannabis Community who are
really into dogs it appears as though
you're more of a cat person and you even
wrap the chicken a little bit which I
think was kind of cool what's the
backstory behind that with the chicken
and with the cats and is that where your
animal passion sort of Lies
oh man I got dogs too I just don't rep
them they just don't sleep in the house
man so you know you don't get to see
them as much and it just so happens
you're comfortable in on the phone the
dogs uh Dusty sleeps in the house but
you know he's not as photogenic as the
cats but I love dogs just as much so
let's not let's not confuse that I love
all my animals the chickens actually
before this interview I have to put my
chickens away so I have to put them all
in their Coop I got a lot of chickens
and the cats I've always loved cats
chickens I uh would go to my grandma's
Farm in Mexico every summer and winter
and they had chickens so I grew up
around chickens in my whole childhood
and I even had Ducks when I was a kid so
I've always been a fan of chickens and
now they give me eggs and [ __ ] so that's
cool too
then the pandemic I already had my
chickens and nobody had eggs but I had
eggs
and all my friends wanted chickens
everybody was asking me about chickens
like I was the [ __ ] chicken
Ambassador I'm like [ __ ] go read
a book next you know they're [ __ ] way
more adverse than me and I'm like good
you know
love it I love it
so I forgot to ask you earlier you
mentioned you do obviously a lot of
growing Outdoors but we didn't and you
and you mentioned that you use salts for
the seed production but what sort of
medium do you like to use Outdoors it
just just soil from the ground or you
bring in a medium and do you have a
preferred brand of nutrients you want to
mention or you prefer just to leave it
unsaid
oh man
I'll go grab a bag of roots Organics uh
and [ __ ] run Mills you know I get
Mills for free so I run it easy does it
if if I didn't have that I'd probably go
grab veg bloom or something or you can
always make a super soil and just
[ __ ] Plug and Play let that Super
Soul feed the whole time uh I had a
bunch of bags of living soil from Red
Bud soil that I ran but I'm not over
here like dechlorinating anything I'm
just running straight from the hose so
it's like it's kind of you know
oxymoronic to be growing like that but
uh yeah it's uh easy does it for me like
uh seed production you don't need to do
much uh besides make sure the plants are
healthy and and [ __ ] you're not over
there
pruning and picking making sure [ __ ]
looks sexy
sure sure sorry I wanted to ask you
about your thoughts on some of the
festivals like the weed festivals and
just selling seeds at them in general
because over the past few years we've
seen a decline of the emerald Cup in
terms of people being able to sell their
seeds legally and more recently people
are kind of like Oh The Vibes not really
where it used to be and then lo and
behold I managed to catch up with you in
person at the ego Clash last year and
that was a cool event and so I guess my
thoughts is sorry my question is what's
your thought on the emerald cup and it's
sort of trajectory and do you think
there's smaller Boutique events like the
ego Clash are going to become more
popular
dude [ __ ] Emerald cup man my ass
my dumb ass like there's you know you
feel like
I don't know you just feel poor
sometimes you know [ __ ] I'm walking
around Emerald cup
supposedly my buddy had a spot I could
set up at and sell seeds so I'm like
cool I got this huge box of meat full of
seeds you know you have a spot for me
cool we end up inside and it's not even
his program it's somebody else's there's
nowhere for me to go so I'm [ __ ]
lugging this huge box of seeds around
Emerald cup you know and and it's like
and and it feels weird because I'm
Masonic people are here to visit me you
know as well as the Emerald cup but I'm
over here like lugging a box around
looking like a [ __ ] chump you know
like embarrassed almost like I don't got
Booth space you know it's like it's
almost impossible only cap and exotic
can apparently get Booth space here and
whoever else you know but uh whatever
you grow and you make more money and now
you in a position to maybe now I can you
know what I mean get Booth space if if
Money Talks you know but then I wasn't
and and and and and [ __ ] supposedly I
had a a buddy that had a booth and he's
like hey man set up right here that's
cool and I set up
and apparently they were doing something
they weren't supposed to be doing and
like the emerald cup [ __ ] the
daughter that was running the whole
thing is like you guys got to get out of
here and like I I like uh dbg was there
or yeah yeah and and like they had all
their stuff on the table and and I think
they were like trying to like kick them
out of the whole festival entirely and I
was there but I had all my [ __ ] tucked
under the table a little bit more
low-key and like they kind of overlooked
me and I just kind of grabbed my stuff
and like went to the side and dude like
[ __ ] embarrassing and and yeah that
is The Vibes I got I Emerald cup but uh
somehow some way I managed to like on
the outskirts of you know people that
weren't peeping too hard I managed to
backpack backpack a little bit of seeds
and not have my whole catalog with me
and managed to you know push some seeds
pedaling them on my feet around Emerald
cup which is something I didn't really
want to do like [ __ ] I should be able
to have a booth you know [ __ ] this is
this is dumb you know
yeah definitely I think that's a
sentiment that many of the former
breeders have expressed do you think
that things like the ego clash and
smaller events that maybe invite only
sort of situation will become the more
popular and predominant sort of thing
that the real heads are going to or do
you think it's like the emerald cup's
still so big it's going to draw the
crowds
uh I think I think we got to do some
some more of that ego class [ __ ] but not
to the point where it's you know where
we ring it too much because if you do
something too much people get fed up
with it too so recently I I did a a
pop-up at a hydroponics store
and uh you know it was kind of it wasn't
no Eagle Clash but you know you didn't
have to go to a [ __ ] Festival to go
pick up seeds you know so we can do a
derivative of that in whatever
you know like an eagle Clash you could
have an ego clash in your city it
doesn't have to be ego class you could
just be a sesh and grab some like-minded
guys and maybe bring a star or something
because uh little by little
foods are coming out the woodworking
you know people want to associate with
others amongst themselves that smoke
weed too so you got to give them that
power you can't be like oh you guys
aren't good enough to talk about
breeding because nobody breeds in Ohio
but you know that's that's not fair they
can all gather and
have seeds too and make a cool Cedar in
their state you know so whatever the
case be it's it's early shit's growing
people are getting bigger there'll be
more breeders from more places and
there will be more like Eagle Clash
things I'd imagine yeah sure and I guess
final question before we get into some
of the fan submitted ones on the tail
end of things I remembered thinking that
it was very just you know weird
situation to be in that cave at the um
at the ego clash and like people had the
booths and you had your table set up and
you're selling seeds and stuff and I
thought this is like a really like
unpredicted sort of experience what are
some of the most weird or standout
experiences you've had while being in
the industry or selling seeds
well that one is one of them sure enough
being in a [ __ ] cave selling seeds
you know that was one of them uh
I was in Adelanto one time [ __ ]
selling seeds you know on the outskirts
of this huge
free dab Festival that was a pretty
nasty one I uh one time I set up shop
outside of a Target in Compton in the
parking lot and I just had people come
to me like if I was selling mixtapes out
my trunk and I like nitpickingly invited
people like like uh you you look okay
boom you know so I took that and just
expanded that into my pop-up so I just
screened more people via Instagram
because you can tell a lot through
somebody's Instagram like come on like
if you see some dude called Robin
[ __ ] like you're not gonna let
him go to your to your pop-up you know
like dude your name is Robin
[ __ ] like why would I let you
come with me you know so you know no no
no discrimination but if you look like
you about to Jack somebody and you have
no pictures of your grow on your your
weed you probably will never get invited
to any local Masonic Shin digs
there you go guys words so on the tail
end of things we've just got a few uh
fans submitted questions before we get
to the final five or six uh quick fire
questions first one being what's your
thoughts on shrooms your pro shrooms
shrooms man there's they're uh
they'll put you in your place you know
uh I I even micro dosing man they'll
make me Shut the [ __ ] up and just go to
my room and lock myself up for a bit and
just put my phone down for a second I
think they're a good reset
uh I wouldn't tell you to go to a heroic
dose like like that but uh
nibble at it see how you like it some
people like him better than others I'm I
get
uneasy with them so I do them
spontaneously I'll nibble at them never
more than
more than a [ __ ] point one because if
I eat a 0.3 I'm like hugging the floor
like it's that bad for me there you go
good answer so next one was do you
currently have any plans to work with
any males besides Wilson
maybe maybe in this new uh Fino hunt
that I'm doing I have a bunch of elite
crosses crossed into Wilson but it ended
up being a Wilson hybrid so
maybe maybe maybe so the next one which
I thought was interesting is would you
ever consider doing a Wilson F2 or F3 I
don't know what it would be classified
as where it's like your will soon cross
to oni's Wilson zero
uh that's a good idea
maybe that we haven't even thought of
that that's crazy that's a good idea
yeah what we're for sure doing that
tomorrow I'm gonna hit him up
so the next question we had submitted
was are you more of an intercour or a
sativa fan
I'm more of an indigo person
yeah sure if you had to pick Hazel Kush
I'll do it
so next one was out of all your strains
what's the most potent to you and what's
the biggest Yoda
well I've got uh
out of the biggest Fino hunt out of
anybody that I've got I got the chem d95
was probably one of the heaviest healers
md95 Wilson
and out of personally that I smoked I
hate to like be cliche or put cream on
my taco but I smoke some Wilson F2 that
really blew my socks off
no good answer a bit of a more random
one to round out the fan submitted one
what's your thoughts on the new Aesop
album
oh ASAP rock yep
oh man I I have I bro I don't listen to
ASAP rock like that that fool uses too
many words for me Doug I need to go pull
up a dictionary there is no way in God
anybody could recite a whole Aesop Rock
song and if they can Jesus Christ your
ass is really sitting there digesting
that [ __ ] you have to practice I'm gonna
[ __ ] a hundred times that guy's dope
though man Aesop Rock's cool I should
probably check it out
no worries and the final fan submitted
question before we do the final five
what do you think are the genetics in
cookies
I have no idea it's a it's F1 dirt
there you go I think that's what we'll
always be told
all right so final five quick fire ones
from me what is the best or most
memorable weed you've ever smoked
um
[ __ ] deserbert man I'm I'm it's pretty
memorable because I had a really uh I
was smoking nothing but concentrate like
to today at ego and uh I was just like
man weed's not cutting it like Flour's
not cutting anymore and I my buddy uh
who's my buddy now he he had a buddy
he's like hey man you should talk to him
he saw me in the cave and he let me hit
his pipe
and uh it was a zerbert and I'm like
what the [ __ ] is this [ __ ] he's like
that zerbert fool and and I'm like can I
grab some and he like literally points
at uh 365 he was right there or canopy I
think his name is and I and I went home
with an ounce and ever since then like
you know I was smoking nothing but hash
but uh I went back on flower on that
date and to this day it just so happens
you're asking me about it because uh
Cali kosher they grew a bunch of it and
randomly I'm like hey like I like that
strain a lot and they're like sure we'll
we'll give you some and like randomly
they [ __ ] brought me a quarter pound
of that [ __ ] uh lovely synchronous so on
the other end of the spectrum was there
ever a strain where like everyone you
know was hyping it up and saying it's
the bee's knees and then you finally try
and you were like this isn't that good
I tried some perf S1 that [ __ ] was
terrible dog all that pip [ __ ] they need
to shut the [ __ ] up and sit down I don't
care like it's okay it's like it's
nostalgic and it's reminiscent but it's
far from good I'm just [ __ ] around
I'm gonna piss a lot of people out it
has this place you know it's all for the
influes with the timbos the dead ass BS
foods but yeah
all right so the next one you're about
to get dropped off at a desert island
and you can only take three strains with
you you've got to smoke for the rest of
your life what are they going to be
oh
I'll take some Skittles with me
I'll take uh some GMO
and some Wilson [ __ ] it
lovely all right now flip side of the
coin you're about to drop someone you
don't like very much off on the island
and you get to pick the three strains
they're stuck with what are you gonna
leave them
they're gonna get some uh
some Super Lemon Haze
they're gonna get some Malawi Panama Red
and [ __ ]
what's and whatever soapy strain that
was that I smoked at Colorado
so final question is if you could go
back in time to anywhere any place any
time collect either seeds or a clone
where would you go and what are you
getting
um
[ __ ] I would just for my uh you know
just for the culture I'd probably go in
Mexico and find some [ __ ] over there
just because I could speak Spanish too
figure it out over there
oh yeah that's a good answer we
definitely need some more land races
from down there
yeah that'd be dope
love it all right so I think that just
about brings us to the end of it is
there any comments or shout outs you
wanted to make
no that's it man thank you for inviting
me shout out everybody
out there
shout out shout out yeah
and there you have it thank you so much
to the meme Master himself Masonic for
taking the time to join us and share all
the knowledge
thanks G you have a great night or a
great day
[Music]
[Applause]
and there you have it my friends wise
words from the man himself Masonic you
like it I thought it was pretty good
[Music]
as always huge shout out to Masonic for
taking the time to come on the show we
appreciate you greatly just like we
appreciate our sponsors and I recommend
everyone who's listened go hit them up
seeds here now best seed bank in the
business guarantee on satisfaction not
just germination go check them out now
why would you go anywhere else all the
biggest and best breeders I love them
you love them let's go show them some
love likewise puppet biological systems
your number one stop predator mites
beneficial Predators fees for your
garden microbial powders so much you've
got to go check them out I'd sell it
sure to just leave it at that you've got
to go get their stuff keep your garden
happy healthy your next Harvest be in
that Primo fire trust me guys you want
to have a beneficial Army there before
you get into trouble not afterwards
foreign
[Music]
gang we love you guys so much thank you
so deeply I really appreciate all the
support you guys give you help to ensure
that the episodes happen without you we
might not be here do you want early
access to content exclusive interviews
giveaways and so much more please go
check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
I think that's it for this episode my
friends I will join you for the next one
thanks for the support as always this is
your boy heavy days coming at you from
the upside down Library signing off yet
again
[Music]
foreign