foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
my friends welcome on back to the
podcast of podcast for budding
enthusiasts and as always you're joined
by your boy heavy days here from the
upside down Library
as always we want to give a massive
shout out to our incredible sponsors who
helped make the show happen CT now your
number one seed bank in the industry
guarantee on satisfaction not just
germination why would you go anywhere
else all the hottest breeders the latest
drops guess what they got lucky dog as
well go jump on it but in order to grow
seeds out good you need to make sure
your room is pest and pathogen free and
for that you need to check out our
friends at Copic biological systems with
all the best pest and Predator
technology they will ensure your garden
is firing on all cylinders and you have
the best crop to date trust me guys if
you've got aphids check out their happy
param you've got spider mites check out
the spidex vital these are two must-have
products for any serious grower
likewise if you're serious about growing
you've got to make sure your room's
dialed in and for that check out our
good friends at Pulse sensors
from humidity to temperature to par to
VPD to so much more whether you're a
single tent a single room or a
multi-state operation you need to keep
track of your grow parameters to ensure
you have the most productive Harvest one
increased yield increased resin
increased terpenes get serious get a
pulse sensor
and last but not least a huge shout out
to the patreon gang we love you so much
you're truly the lifeblood of the show
if you would like to get early access to
upcoming episodes completely unheard
interviews with the likes of Mr Mean
Gene Bob Hemphill bodies tricome jungles
so much more we're now doing genetic
giveaways every second week on the
Discord live sessions there's so many
reasons to join up guys go check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
on this episode we are incredibly
blessed to have the man to the myth the
legend the chemdog Aficionado the head
honchos behind Lucky Dog seidco as well
as Lucky Dog dispensary none other than
Mr skunk VA himself
we were lucky enough to record this one
live from Lucky Dog dispensary in
Bozeman Montana go check it out it's the
most fire cannabis you're gonna see
a little bit of noise here and there we
do our best to edit it I'm sure you'll
enjoy it nonetheless
here to catch up since our legendary
first episode all those years ago
talking about the chem dog
genetics
the future of legalization
what you can expect from him
so much more
need I say anymore guys
let's get into this one
alrighty gang we're back for another one
thank you for joining me on this episode
we have the legend behind Lucky Dog Seed
Co the chem 91 King himself skunk VA
thank you so much for joining me thanks
for having me it's good to see you it's
good to see you and what a what a great
venue to be filming this episode at we
are at the lucky dog dispensary in
Montana tell me a bit about it when did
this happen
Lucky Dog cannabis uh kind of was
conceptualized uh a long long time ago
but this particular version of it is you
know
uh we uh we started here in February of
21 uh right after coven covet actually
uh prevented us from getting a lot of
the uh licensing requirements like the
inspection and just a lot of the
paperwork that has to be done here in
Montana beautiful Montana Bozeman and uh
you know so that's that's kind of how it
is and uh I made a big move from Sonoma
County to here to kind of make this
happen
um just want to be in the legal space
the legal cannabis space
um just because I feel like in the
future it's going to be absolutely
necessary to be part of a to be part of
cannabis in the future uh to
have a licensed facility so that's what
we're doing here
that's awesome to hear I guess the first
question that jumps to mind is how would
you compare Montana to California in
terms of the scene and maybe some of the
legalities
well Montana is a reddish purplish State
and they have an interesting population
here and I fit in very well here because
freedom is Big here not just in word but
in action and I appreciate that it
motivates me and inspires me
and I'm always going to have my heart in
California of course the Bay Area is
where I kind of grew up after
you know I left Virginia and Grateful
Dead tour was over raised my family
there my daughter there so but it's
changed a lot the climate's changed
there a lot and and then cannabis has
changed a lot there because it's very
difficult for
a small operator like myself to function
there
um the regulation Loop uh hurdles the
obstacles of distribution and it just
didn't work out for me there so I how I
got here is a long story we can get into
that some other time
and uh but I'm happy to be here and so
the way it's different here is I would
say that the consumer here is more
geared at least my consumer customers
that come here are more geared towards
like older school like they're
interested in what they had in high
school
and I was surprised to find out that
even though there's only a million
people in Montana it seems like
everybody here consumes cannabis and so
I have the opportunity to you know talk
directly to my customers again something
that I'd had to let go of when I was in
my early 20s
turkey bags on beds you know suitcases
and duffel bags full of
you know Kush and Sour Diesel going far
far places so I've learned here that uh
you know I've gotten back in touch with
the consumer directly and I love it it
inspires me I love to be around the joy
that cannabis brings people
and when people are just trying to make
a hundred dollars here and there there's
no joy in that you know it's just the
way you survive but when you are able to
show a consumer 71 different options of
strains we have 44 on the in the display
case right now
I mean you can find and talk to them and
find what they want based on what
they've seen and what I've noticed is a
lot of folks young and old they kind of
go back to what they remember what they
fell in love with when it comes to
cannabis and we have plenty of options
for them you know we have the new and
the old and so yeah
um yeah that's pretty much it and as far
as the regulations go I never really did
it in California but I was close enough
to see how difficult it was there and
although I don't I don't really do well
with regulations in general I uh have
found that I can adapt to what is asking
me here so I have
it's mostly just a bunch of letting go
of you know that's [ __ ] stupid
you gotta Bend to the will of the man
right that's interesting all of that
info and I would love to dive into some
of the strains you have on offer I guess
the first thing I'd be interested in
knowing is for anyone listening to this
there's basically every clone only
you've ever drilled over in this display
case so my question is do you feel like
your customers are aware of how spoiled
they are in terms of they've got
basically like the top 41 most in-demand
client onlys at their fingertips do you
think most of them realize this they do
have a slight view of it
um when they come in I you know my
perception is just between me and my
customers between my customer and
another company a flower shop or what
have you I don't really have that
perception so what I do know is that
when folks come in they I you know I
with a few questions because I love
cannabis too I can kind of narrow down
where we're going to go and it's a lot
of fun for me because we're both
discovering new things together and I
love it you know I have customers that
come in here hang out and talk about
you know purely what they're looking at
and what what they've experienced for 20
30 minutes you know and I'll spend every
minute with them and usually they're the
ones that are trying to get away from me
because I'm leveling our mind with
cannabinoid and terpene and brain
chemistry information and you know
trying to explain to them that THC
percentages don't really matter that
much and why don't they matter and so I
love it because it's given me the
opportunity to kind of you know
re-educate a cannabis user as to what we
now know about cannabis and you know why
we all love different things and you
know why we're drawing why you know the
individuals are drawn to different
things you know so it's kind of like a
discovery for them so I would say that
it's mostly
you know the thing I've noticed about
the account my consumers that come in is
that they want to try everything it's
like a winery they want to go through
the flight of course it's going to take
you a couple weeks because we have so
much but you know we will get there
we'll go from the A to B and down to C D
E and F you know we got it all so my
favorite comment when I show someone
um and let them you know take in the
aroma is
man that smells like high school and I'm
like that's the one for you then because
I know exactly what you mean you know so
that's brilliant I like the um the
analogy of taking him on a journey and
I'd be interested to know what has
unexpectedly caught you off guard as
popular are there any strains that you
thought maybe you know they're too
strong for most people or just you
didn't think it was going to be a crowd
favor but it's turned out to be like a
really big hit well I would say that the
the the answer to that would be not
necessarily new streams but uh streams
that have been with us for a while uh
Durban Poison comes to mind that's never
really been a popular stream as you know
so to speak in all my circles in life
but up here they really do like that you
know jet fuel you know energetic
um feeling they like it you know so I've
learned a lot about what people like by
being here because you know you make
assumptions you know about what you like
and what someone else may like based on
those assumptions of what you enjoy and
I've learned that that's definitely not
the case you know I've gotten
reintroduced to that fact that it's just
not the case that you just never know
and you have to take the time with
someone and go through it with them and
so you know luckily for us even though
we have probably more strains on the
table than anyone else in this in this
uh beautiful state
um you know we've been I've been
collecting these for a long time and uh
you know the things that I held on to
that it weren't never really popular
were are very popular here and so that's
been a big surprise for me also you know
pleasant surprise you know because we
could talk him all day long but there's
so many different things you know and
those folks they try Kim and people come
in and they're very Frank with me about
why they use cannabis and it's just it's
a treasure to me I love it you know it's
rewarding again you know there you go
well look I gotta tie it in you know
this has to be one of probably the only
places you can get verified chem 91
flower uh to purchase what to you what
conditions do you feel chem 91 works
best for and have you ever had any
customers sort of do the the fabled
story of taking some home consuming it
becoming a bit uncomfortably numb it's a
little too strong or comfortably High
um honestly no I I uh I've been
surprised on the a level of consumption
well at least in my experience with
these customers I'm always Blown Away by
you know you know like their tolerance
and like how much you know they like
powerful cannabis I don't have many
people come through this door and say
hey give me you know do you have
something that's just not that strong I
mean that's a that's a thing out there
but I don't get a lot of that
um so the way I do it here and the way
we do it here
um is that like you know obviously we
all agree that you know most of us agree
that there's the Indica sativa you know
nomenclature is not really accurate it's
it's got a purpose to it and but it's
just not accurate so I try to steer
people away from that and I try to find
out you know what what when do they like
to smoke you know do they like to smoke
in the morning or do they like to smoke
in the daytime do they like to smoke
anytime do they like to smoke night time
and that helps us narrow it down to what
we're looking for you know and some some
folks come in and they're they're
clearly looking for a relief of an
ailment that's happened still it's real
and so that makes it even easier when
it's like that you know sleep
um stress you know my body hurts those
types of things so we just ask some
questions you know and we narrow it down
and you know I've noticed you know when
I first started doing this and selling
to the public
um I I kind of
um you know felt like you know I got to
be quick with these folks and I found
out that I wasn't really the case they
want me to spend the time they want us
here at Lucky Dog cannabis to spend the
time with them to help them understand
what they're going to be consuming why
that you know what the and then of
course when they come back I mean my
customers are are like my family here
they're like we talk about our lives we
pick up where we left off last week if
that's the case and I enjoy that and and
getting to know them allows me to you
know kind of pinpoint hey maybe you want
to try this you know maybe you want to
stay away from this maybe this one's
going to give you too much anxiety
possibly maybe this one's going to make
you too sleepy and that's not I know
that's not what you want you want to go
golfing with your buddies or whatever
you know so
um you know I I just I don't think that
you know if I had if it was a much
bigger company I don't think that we
would be able to have that kind of
personalized service but here we do and
I you know I really enjoy it so as far
as like the Kim 91 goes you know I
always tell folks that it's basically
good for any time anything you want to
do and then I mean you know to be honest
I say especially at four in the morning
after a long night you know with uh you
know say a Brighton vibrant psychedelic
experience and the sun's coming up
there's no better time to consume chem
91 than that
but you can get up in the morning and
smoke it and you can smoke it all day
it's medicinal you know if you're hungry
it's certainly going to help you with
that you know so you know it's it's in
any time herb here you know and I've in
the past you know I've always said that
you know maybe this is the more narcotic
more but then when I get other people's
experience and that's a key point is
that my experience is one thing I have
my brain chemistry but everyone else has
different brain chemistries and so I
always make sure to get the feedback
from them because I learned more from
them than they learn from me I don't
know if they know that but they're
different experience than mine you know
enlightens me and I appreciate that and
then that allows me to kind of reflect
on it and to share that with the next
customer
so yeah I would say the Kim 91
experience you know a lot of people come
here just to have the chem 91 or the
crossroad count they've heard about it
and this is their chance to try it you
know and this is the plate this would be
the place to get it and so you know we
have a lot of Tourism here in Montana
and we have had a lot of people come
from out of town search us out and then
come and try real chemdog 91.
that's brilliant it sounds in general
like the Montana uh clientele base or
the you know patrons of the business a
more educated and sort of interested in
finding out a bit more as you said out
of curiosity do you still find there are
still a lot of those same Trends you see
in California like I guess maybe a way
to distill it down is uh is is cookies
still pervasive in Montana for example
um I wouldn't be able to answer that
accurately because my ex my perception
is not it doesn't include that
um so
I don't really get you know and I don't
think I can't say this is this is uh uh
you know something that would be across
the board here in Montana but my
experience is you know folks don't
really come in here looking for the
strain they heard of I have some of
those strains and I've been surprised
that uh how very little I I um you know
sell to a consumer of that it surprised
me the the gelato 41 for instance you
know I think it's tremendous I love it I
love the smell I offer it to people
oftentimes and they usually don't even
want to look at it and I'm not I can't
really tell you why I sensed that
they've tried it somewhere else maybe
and that that they already had decided
that it's not for them
we don't really have any cookies streams
here as far as I know
um we do have chop Cherry you know I
don't know how these are really related
to that but they in my mind they're kind
of a part of that group
um you know of course we have the tits
this is the [ __ ] uh by D-Back genetics
um and uh grandpa I think it goes by and
it does have the ogkb in it so that's in
there
and that one's been moderately popular
maybe not as Pop it's one of my
favorites so I don't think it's quite on
that level with the consumer most of the
people come in they've heard of older
School strains that we have you know or
they've maybe heard you know uh me
talking about in the past and wanted to
try it and then we have you know lots of
colonies that everyone's heard of you
know so but we don't have a lot of that
kind of stuff and we don't get asked
about it a lot and
um you know that's kind of that's all I
got on that really it's it's a little
bit of a weird perception I got because
of what we do have you know yeah no
that's that's a good answer and you you
made me
um sort of remember one of the patreon
submitted questions we got which was
that on a recent episode we were
speaking to Tom Hill and he sort of said
that um it was a bit unexpected that he
he'd try to sample a gelato 33 and he
was pretty into it and uh one of our
patreon listeners was wondering are
there any other modern strains besides
maybe the July 41 you just mentioned
that sort of caught you off guard a bit
and you are interested in or fond of so
to speak yeah I mean we have a lot of
things that I are new to me you could
say and I don't know if anything caught
me off surprise like that
um
you know I'm kind of particular about
what I prefer I do like the skunk dog
that's kind of new to me but it's in the
same realm as everything else that I you
know love
um oh and I do have a a good cut of uh
Wedding Crasher afino that uh my partner
uh selected you know years ago and she
was kind enough to share with me and
that one's been surprising to me and I
think that would be one that I could you
know say would answer that question and
that is like it's a mellow it's very
smooth it's easy going it's any time and
I'm almost I'm 49 years old and I've you
know cannabis now that's kind of where
I'm at I like Smooth easy you know I
don't need like the big heavy whack me
in the top of the head experience
anymore with it I just want you know
something that tastes good and makes me
feel relaxed you know so I would say
that was a surprise to me that's a new
one to me
um symbiotic genetics I believe created
that one I and this Fino here is the
best I've seen and I'm glad to have it
and I I often you know take uh less
experienced smokers or older folks who
are delving into cannabis and I kind of
guide him to that and I said you know
it's got a nice grape flavor to it you
can't you know complain about the flavor
and it's not a big commitment when you
smoke which I think you know you have to
be careful you know like not everybody
wants it comes to the door wants a you
know the strongest weed you got you know
what I mean and so that that one is I
think that would be one that was a
surprise to me you know yeah great
answer I wasn't expecting to hear that
while we're on the topic what have you
been smoking on lately what's the sort
of things if I asked you at the end of
the day what are you being puffing on
what things are your go-to
um well the Wedding Crasher is a good
one for me and I'm always smoking on
tits uh I really do like the uh red
Lebanese hash plant that's my go-to at
night that's my night time let's go to
bed I'd like I have a lot of uh you know
body pains you know working my whole
life doing too much so I have some body
pain so I like to I tend to always fall
towards the indicas
um but you know I try to have a little
bit of everything I try to try a little
different things I've been pleasantly
surprised with
um let's see what are we looking at of
course I love the Durban Thai high flyer
so that would be my daytime thing but
Crossroad chem is still my favorite and
I know it sounds kind of cuckoo because
I made it but I love it I like weed
that's perfectly right down the middle I
like hybrids that are perfectly right
down the middle any timer and that one
hits that box big time it's got good
flavor you can smoke anytime it's just
gonna get you happier and more relaxed
and more you know engaged in what you're
doing it doesn't matter if you're going
to the bank if you're taking the kids to
the park if you're walking your dog it's
good for everything so it's always my
go-to and it's my most popular stream
nice one and you just mentioned the dirt
and tire high flyer I wanted to ask you
because you find that with a lot of
breeders they tend to sort of stick to
one lane like maybe they're more into
indicas and they just sort of do Indica
stuff but you do tend to with both
within your dispensary and within your
seeds offer a bit of a mix of sativa and
indica offerings what in your opinion is
your most sativa seed offering
seed offering
um
it probably would be
[Music]
um
I don't know it's kind of a toss-up I
mean the Chaska is probably the most
sativa like strain that I offer in seat
form
um
but I would say that one I would say
that but the Chaska
um you know we've done the Russell so
yeah I would I would also add the chem
flyer though what I liked about the
camouflage so I'm not really you know I
probably have less experience with pure
sativas as you say than most people you
talk to it just wasn't my Lane when I
was younger but I think as most cannabis
users who you know are as we're aging we
find out that this changes over time and
I have really fallen in love with a nice
sativa
I like the the the the the the lack of
appetite I like the energetic part of it
what I didn't like when I was younger
was the anxiety it brought on to me and
so I would say that the chem flyer the
cross I made with the Durban Thai high
flyer crossed with the Kim 91 bx3 male
it's it's got that for me it gives me
the energy it wakes me up it wants it's
great with coffee I want to go out and
do stuff but I never feel jittery I
don't feel my heart racing I don't feel
like all these things that I don't like
about that type of herb and so I really
enjoy that and I love that sharp
pineapple flavor I mean who doesn't love
that you know it's Unique you can't say
it's fruity you can't say it's gassy
it's sharp you know astringent and I
love that flavor so as long as I don't
get like caught up in too much thought
crippled with too much thought or you
know just anxiety
borderline I find that to be really
uncomfortable for me I think a lot of
people agree and so that's kind of it I
would say that Kim flyer the Russell but
the chask is definitely the most whoa
you know energetic you know for I've had
a lot of Kim Fuego Finos over the over
the course of uh testing those out they
gave me that that experience where I
felt inspired creative you know
energetic the things that I think people
describe sativa with but without the
jittery you know and I don't like the
appetite uh I don't like the
um you know the Kim dog makes me
extremely hungry you know and I don't
really care for that you know because
I'm kind of I succumb to that I can't
really fight that off you know so that's
what I like about this TV is this
sativas are new to me in a sense I would
say relatively new to me in my
perception than most folks and I'm
really enjoying it I'm glad that I'm
discovering it at this point in my life
you know
that's awesome to hear I too am just
getting more and more intensity versus
each day goes by so piggybacking on that
thought tell me a little bit about the
Russell because it uses a jackhara bx2
female and so I guess the questions that
come to mind are uh what cutting did you
use initially what mail did you pair to
it to start the process and were there
anything specifically you wanted to
improve on that Jack Herer clone I guess
well the Jack Herrera is you know a
legendary kite it's got the not just
lemon but the lime flavor to it and I
think that makes it unique I think
there's a lot of dreams that have that
lemon citrusy flavor and Aroma and I
think the Jack Herer is unique because
it it has that lime as well and so I
like that I like that
it's like a multi-layered citrus
astringent Citrus and I love that about
it like I said before when I started
working with uh with it that cut and
messing around with what's going to come
next what I noticed was that the figure
wasn't the best on that cut at least in
that moment it wasn't I've been growing
the Jack career for a while and it's
actually you know I get big yields out
of it so maybe I just didn't have it
dialed in but what I felt was that the
the production was a little on the
weaker side and I wanted to improve that
you know
so I did use the bx2 in the first
outcross and then I crossed it back and
made the bx2 the Jack herrer bx2 the
goal was to keep the Terps keep the that
lemon lime flavor keep of course keep
that you know high-powered sativa
feeling that you many of us feel when
they smoke
um but I wanted bigger yields more
bigger which is you know at the very top
of my list you know that's one of the
higher parts of you know traits that I'm
always breeding for is bigger I want the
end user to have the experience of like
look what I did over here with this
particular plant you know because I know
what it feels like and I appreciate that
and you know you know when you're a home
grower you've got a 10 or a small grow
maybe and this is changing of course but
maybe your environment's not 100 perfect
maybe it's difficult for you to do that
maybe you live in a state where it's
very difficult to create the perfect
environment just for safety reasons and
so I'm always thinking about that human
that may man or that woman and then I
want them to have the experience of like
success you know that they pulled
something off because that when you're
growing cannabis I think that's one of
the most
rewarding parts of it is that wow look
what I can do I can do this you know and
I you know why I like that is because
that I feel like that translates into
other parts of your life you know you
can Empower yourself with
all kinds of things you find out that
you've been paying other people to do
for you and now you can do this you know
I think that's what makes life better
and so I want my customers to have that
experience and I'm trying always to have
let them have that I'm trying to
facilitate that and so that's why I
decided to make the bx2 instead of the
Jack Herer just in the cross I wanted to
see if I can get more bigger I felt like
we did and we kept the Terps we kept the
the essential experience of the Jack
Herer and then we just added some punch
to it with the chem dog you know yeah
and I I might have missed it did you
mention what was the mail you used to
start the outcross the Kim dbx2 yeah oh
okay and then at that point when I
popped that first generation of F1 seeds
I saw that maybe it would be a good idea
to create our own female to work with
and it wasn't really like a big master
plan it was kind of like what we're
[ __ ] around and then we found a bx2
that was very Jack Herrera lemon lime
you know very vigorous and very and it
was like well why don't we use this
instead of the Jack Herer you know we're
allowed to do that and so that's what I
did you know yeah nice one nice and uh
in that same vein you know you did the
Chaska with the super silver haze bx2 is
that a similar story are there any
differences with that one
it is it's it is a little bit similar
but it's also a little bit different
there was a I had a cut of super so
right now I have here at Lucky Dog
cannabis I have the super silver haze as
they say 98 Cup winner cut and it's the
most I would say it's the most uh you
know Common cut that you see and uh you
know but I had a cut in the early 2000s
that was in my opinion better a super
silver haze it was
it was it grew it had more of like a the
structure was more like a cookie
structure it had like the nut the the
like tighter nugs as you go up the stick
you know it wasn't like the big Cola
that you get with the super silver haze
you know with a shorter plant and it
stretched a little bit more so I uh
actually I I kind of accidentally made
seeds of that by accident a long time
ago
um I would like to tell you what the
mail was but uh I can't really recall
because I did this in like 2006. so I
had those seeds in storage and I got the
cut of the 98 cup the one that's common
nowadays and of course they smelled
almost identical uh the smoke
uh effect was almost identical but I
just really like the way the other one
tasted better and I like the way the
plant
overall looked better you know
um it was really mold resistant you know
and like it just it just it just was my
favorite one and it had already started
the work kind of you know coincidentally
you know like so I took that and I
selected a uh
um a male and I went back to that uh to
that to that lady back then and those
seeds have been in storage for a long
time and so when I got this cut I was
hoping it was the same cut and it wasn't
and so I started popping those and I
found myself a nice female and I said
you know we could either use this cut or
we could use that seed Ling and that's
what I chose to do hoping that I would
get some of that structure
to be honest though I don't really feel
like I succeeded on that structure part
of that cross I feel like
it's you know mixed all up it doesn't
seem like it really did but it's just
what I used and the effect was the same
the flavor was the same it was just my
favorite so I just went with it you know
yeah I mean that's a great answer and
it's cool to hear that it's a bit
different from the the more available
one while we're talking about breeding
uh I think as of yet we really only see
mostly F1 hybrids being offered do you
have any interest in doing any line
breeding or do you feel like you're just
happy to be offering f1s and as a
follow-up how about Femmes
okay so I get this question a lot from
people when I when I get into deeper
conversations about what they're looking
for and I always try to remind folks
that there's a place you know for
everything you know uh for Femmes and
f1s and so on and so forth and My
Philosophy is that nature intended for
cannabis to be
to survive the species to survive in the
F1 stage that that's the diversity of
you know provides like the best chance
for survival and of course you know we
have manipulated nature and survival is
really not why no one's breeding for
survival we're rooting for genetic
preservation we're breeding for uh Vigor
we're trying to improve our favorite
traits with other favorite traits and
that's what I do so I stick with the f1s
and I if you know I've made I've made
femini seeds in the past you know and I
would say that I what we do what I do at
lucky dog is this it's really simple we
take our favorite cuts
and we cross them with our favorite male
and what he does and we have two
different males but what what they do is
they the idea was never to like
everything is going to be like Kim now
we're going to take your favorite cut
and we're going to cross our mail and
I'm gonna make it so yours is now Kim
that is a failure and a lot of my trial
and error that's what happened we kept
picking you know studs that were a
little too dominant I think most people
who breed with chem dog can agree that
chem dog is very dominant you know he
she dominates you know its partner and
so that can be problematic because
that's not what you're trying to do you
know you're just trying to add a little
extra goodness to it so what we do here
is you know the F1 generation has a lot
of variance a lot of uh genetic you know
traits that you don't see in any either
one of the parents and so that can be a
problem you know people don't want to
buy a pack of season have 13 different
phenos or six different phenos they want
to like they have an idea of what the
looking for before they even look at the
pictures they have an idea what they're
looking for as soon as they see the
cross so the trial and error over here
was that you know we we take the stud
and we've the way we selected him our
way I select at least I say we but it
says me selected him was to find him
find the one that's going to bring the
most Vigor that's top and add potency
um and add some gas flavor some fuel but
not overpower the mother you know and
furthermore to to keep it limited to say
three or four different phenos you know
not a million different things and so
the way we do that is that's where the
testing comes in we make the cross and a
lot of times it doesn't work I have a
whole dresser drawer full of seeds that
I don't feel like worked with cross's
favorite cuts
um and you know we wanted the testing
what we do is of course we're looking
for stability we're looking for the
Vigor but we're also trying to say okay
you know no matter how many we pop we
keep finding the same four females
roughly you know of course there's some
variants in that and if we do that then
we've succeeded they know what they're
looking for you know if someone wants to
buy Kim Fuego they know what headband is
they know what sour band or I'm sorry
Sour Diesel is and they know what chem
dog is so they don't want like some
Oddball you know usually and they're
probably going to get one every day once
in a while this is F1 generation but the
work's been done and you know we've
looked at it and we've said you know I
would I would smoke this I smoked this I
would buy this I would grow it again and
if those boxes get checked and we don't
have just Kim dog everything turned into
Kim dog and that would be probably at
the top of the list so that's not what
we want but that work was done when we
selected the mail you know we don't just
pick the most Kim dog male we picked the
strongest one that passes on certain
traits the potency some of the flavor
but once again you have to be careful
because the flavor get you know the
flavor in the room it can get dominated
by Kim dog you know we just want the
potency to pass on and then having a
male a a different male uh on a female
it creates the F1 and that creates the
Vigor we're looking for which gives our
customer the end user the best success
you know
we think yeah brilliant I love it
because I always say to people that 90
of the time when someone's buying seeds
of a regular strain they're usually
buying it because they want the mother
you know the mother is a clone only they
can't get their hands on it and so I
think that really complements your
philosophy in the sense that you're
allowing the mother to shine through one
of the questions we got from a lot of
our listeners is are there any focal
differences you might be able to discuss
between the two chem dog males you use
is does one bring a certain thing to the
table or is it more just about testing
and seeing Oh what happens to work
better that's exactly it you know of
course we started off you know I started
off with the bx2 and you know
um but then as I took it further I
started to see that you know of course
you think okay well if we select right
with the bx3 it's going to be more of
what we're trying to offer right that
turned out not to be the case it's more
like a key in a lock some things just
work better with others you know I don't
know I can't really explain to you why
it's all just you know my perception my
observation I don't really have like a
master plan behind any of that but I you
know was hoping to get to a point where
I had a stud that I can work with you
know and I ended up too because
um some just work better than others you
know
um and that's kind of what is reflected
in what we offer because you know we
keep the bx2 around because it just
works better you know for instance the
Dog Patch it just works better like bx3
dominated too much and I would say that
most people who've experienced chem dog
genetics can family Gen X would say you
know Kim D what we call Kim D is much
much much different than Kim dock you
know in fact I would say that you know
if you could get a Kim dmail it would
help you select a bx3 faster because
when you're making a back cross what
you're trying to do is you're finally
trying to find something that's not
related so it's much easier for you to
differentiate the um the traits you know
so if you have you know plan a and plan
B and plan a is the opposite polar
opposite of Plan B this is the best
starting point for making a back cross
because your next generation is going to
be so much easier for you to select the
traits you're actually looking for
unfortunately it's not quite that simple
and that's why I keep both around
because what I've learned is you can't
quite plan out exactly how it's all
going to go down and that we you know
it's better if you just kind of be
open-minded and think outside the box
and if the X2 works better the bx2 works
better and the Dog Patch is a great
example of that when I tried to use the
bx3 uh in hopes to replace the bx2 I
found that it was just too dominant in
the in the cross and those very
different chemd traits weren't coming
out and that was definitely not my goal
so I think that's a good example of why
because and I don't I'm not going to
tell you how I'm just because I don't
know I will just tell you what I observe
and that's what I observed so we have to
keep him because he works better with
that and then of course we found that to
be true with the Kim's sister
you know what we call the Kim sister
these days you know the Bundy cut or
whatever they call it now and so you
know those are just two good examples of
that you know
yeah great examples before we delve into
some chemd and uh folk MDS I want to ask
you I know you've done some Femmes in
the past is there any chance we might
see them in the future or even more
specifically maybe some s1s absolutely
um and you know I realized just right
now that I didn't fully answer your
question when you when you asked me
about you know f1s and s1s and feminized
and uh F1 generation and you know
um
so right now I feel from my perspective
that uh feminized seeds are really
popular you know maybe because they're a
better bang for your buck you know you
get 12 13 female plants guaranteed for
roughly the same price makes sense but I
always try to to kind of remind the
consumer customer grower you know
they're just basically two different
tools they're two different approaches
to a situation f1s were not really
preserving the genetics you know we're
not preserving mom or not preserving you
know one of the two plants in the cross
I would say that for femini seeds of
course having all females can be very
useful to some folks especially when
they live in a state that doesn't have
really you know legal cannabis and they
have to be careful with their numbers I
understand that I can't make a case
against that I would support that
um but you know if you're a home grower
if you're growing your own cannabis
which is always someone who's on my mind
when I do any kind of work is
um is that you know you want success and
you know you can have success with s1s
and feminized seeds of course you can so
you're going to have a higher rate of of
just yield you know getting a jar of
flour to smoke for you know several
months which is what you might need
with an F1 cross you know so I just try
to remind people that like you know they
have they each have their place and I
would say that you know feminized seeds
s1s you know they they're more geared in
my opinion towards if you know exactly
what you want you know you're not really
interested in any kind of variation and
you're in other words like genetic
preservation so to speak and so you know
with the with the regular seeds f1s f2s
we're making f2s now too those are going
to be that's what you're going to get if
you want genetic preservation if you
know you want this and you maybe you
want to buy a couple hundred of those
feminized seeds and kind of go through
them over the course of your few years
and find exactly what you want and so
yes we have made feminized seeds and
I've made feminized seeds in the past
and I'm getting ready to make another
round I'm going to be using the
crossroad chem and we're going to
basically cross it to all of my favorite
cuts and test them out and see how
people like them and then yes they'll be
uh you know a crossroad chem S one in
there too Ooh La La so much different
angles to go off there I guess the the
question I've been asked a few times by
some listeners is you just mentioned the
crossroad chems are you able to tell us
a little bit about that one specifically
what it's like what maybe sort of traits
it would bring to a cross and how it
differs from the chem Crush because I
think people get a bit confused because
they notice they have the same lineages
so how are they different and what do
you like about the crossroad cam right
so the crossroad Cam and the camera
Crush are both chem 91 females crossed
with the San Fernando Valley OG Kush bx2
bx2 came from a shape Bud from 707 seed
bank of top-notch breeder one of the
best out there maybe not the well most
well-known but definitely someone who's
been doing work for a long time
uh I know him because I gave him the
chem 91 and I think Circa 2006 which you
know he kind of took it up to Arcata and
gave it to all those guys up in the
Emerald Triangle
um and it was all chance you know it was
like a random moment where it was like
this guy you know we should hand I
should hand him the cut you know like
he's going to do some good things with
it and it just was one of those
inspirational things in other words this
is the plant speaking at the moment you
know and so I did and so that you know
years later we lost contact and you know
as we all do out here in the the gutters
of America and so like I ran back into
him and he had a bunch of seeds he's
been trying to give me a long time and
so I went through a few of them a lot of
them I think were kind of getting old
and you know I uh probably have a bunch
left they weren't really like great
germination rates I think because they
were old and but I did find the mail
that I used in that cross
and so when I made the cross I popped a
bunch of those seeds and I found that I
had two distinct Finos that I found that
I could not decide between and that
would be you know they're both casinos
of that and so you know the Kim crush is
more of like a chem dog Fino
whereas the uh the crossroad Kim is more
of a cushy more balanced more cottony I
don't know how to explain it and I just
couldn't decide between the two so I
went with both you know and I get that
question a lot and sometimes I'm like
geez I shouldn't have done that you know
because it's just
hard to
Tran it's hard to express it's hard to
kind of
um
heart kind of hard to like Express to
people that
um and so but that's that's basically
the difference you know they're both
standalones they're they're our sisters
you know it's just that I couldn't
decide between the two I noticed that
one was just include more Kim and the
other was distinctly more Kush and so I
said [ __ ] it let's just use them both
you know perfect
so it's been a minute since we've spoken
and in that time Lucky Dog Seed Co has
flourished and had a lot of success with
a lot of uh strains that have you know
quite quite a strong cult following so I
think we're going to have to drill into
a few of them and the first one that
comes to mind for me is the hunza valley
and I think the reason for that is
um you know it's a combination of like
the Skelly and the cam and there's not a
ton of Skelly crosses out there and
people are really interested in it why
do you think the hanza valley has got a
cult following and how would you
describe it to anyone if they're
interested in sort of hearing your
description of it
well I would say that uh why I feel like
it's been popular is the same reason I
love it I think those Terps are so
unique the burnt rubber the fresh tennis
ball can you know all the things people
describe about it and I'm big on Indica
I got body pains and I love something
that relaxes my muscle
I fell in love with the Skelly when I
obtained it and uh I couldn't wait to
make a cross with it I wanted to make
something the Skelly is notoriously
difficult to grow it's you'll won't see
it in a shop like this because it's it's
not a producer
um it's extremely you know botronous uh
resistant you know even though it's got
that wet greasy uh you know trichome not
Sandy not dry and it really it is it's
just perfect for me I love the smoke but
you know and that's that's kind of it
right there like when you find a plant a
clone only that's difficult to not only
obtain but also to produce grow
then but you love it it could be
frustrating because you want to share it
with the world you know like
um so that was the motivation behind
making the Hanzo Valley and uh you know
um I feel like the hunter Valley passes
on most of those trades so skelly's very
dominant in that cross I would say it's
not it's you won't find a lot of chem
doggy stuff in those you're gonna find
more Indica Skelly burnt rubber tennis
ball you know heavy duty Indica cro you
know fenos when you pop those seeds and
I'm really happy with it um and I'm glad
people enjoy it because it's one of my
favorites that I have for sure
um I actually hate to say it out loud
but I like the hunza valley more than
Miss Kelly the finals that I've grown
they were consistent they were stable
and they were fun to grow they had a
little bit more stretch than this Kelly
which I think is useful to
um you know for end users skelly's you
know complicated you know even though
it's pretty durable pretty you know
um it's I guess durable would be my word
it's it's it's hard to screw it up but
it's just you know the fact that it's so
short and squat it's like you have to
know how to grow it you know the hunza
valley gives you a little bit more a
little bit more flexibility a safety net
yeah it gives you a little bit more
stretch a little bit more air can get
through and so so um that's kind of it
you know I just wanted to share that cut
with the world as I discovered it and
that hunza Valley allowed me to do that
you know it just was one of those it's
one of the crosses that just really
worked out you know like instantly you
know not a lot of thought not a lot of
not a lot of testing had to go on it
just worked you know so hell yeah what a
great answer and definitely one of the
ones I've been eyeing off myself I've
got to ask you because it's been on my
mind for years
there are Whispers that some people
including myself have been partial to
the idea that maybe Skelly has got some
relation to the chem dog do you think
that and as a follow-up at the bare
minimum do you see any similarities in
the flavor
hmm
I've heard that and I've even I even
mentioned on the back of the pack that
that people have mentioned that
um I don't know if it's true I mean of
course there's no way to know I don't
know how we would figure that out
um they definitely both have crossed
Leadville Colorado
um for sure and so you know the super
skunk was there Leadville Colorado you
know I've only snowboarded there over
the years and maybe I spent the night at
someone's house on the way to see some
you know grateful deady stuff in the
Denver area but besides that you know
um I can't say I don't think I feel like
I see a direct resemblance especially
when you take into consideration the
Northern Lights the nl1 because that one
seems to be more like when you ask me
where what traits do I see outside of
Kim dog that are Kim doggy I would say
that's from my memory that would be the
one the Skelly I I can only say that
because people who are closer to that
cut the puck have mentioned it you know
I wouldn't say that's impossible you
know I would say maybe if you took Kim D
and set it next to its sister the Kim
dog and then he took Skelly and he sat
next to the Kim dog you would probably
say the Skelly had more resemblance you
know that's what I would say
um so I I don't really know you know and
I don't like to speculate on those
things because there's so much diversity
in cannabis as soon as you think you can
identify traits on different streams you
know you find out there is no resemble
there is no actual not resemblance but
no uh relation you know it can surprise
you and it does often so I don't know
you know I just know that that's what
folks from the Leadville area at that
Circa in 1989-ish you know set so yeah
well look while we're on the topic of
Leadville and the infamous Joe brand the
the chem brand has gained a lot of
popularity and I guess for a lot of
people they may I think of it as like
sort of a pure chemline in a sense is
that how you would describe it or do you
think they're actually getting a little
something different than two chem dogs
crossed together so to speak oh 100 the
JB cut as I call it and I I think that
you you would body coin that uh name for
it which is I love
um we were familiar with the JB cut
before it was called the JB cut in
Sonoma County uh in Sonoma County
honestly over most of the last couple
decades we weren't that concerned about
names we were more concerned about what
customers wanted and it was on scale
large scale and it was always OG
cushions and it was always Sour Diesel
and no matter what else came through
those were the ones that always were
getting asked about so we had this cut
and I honestly cannot tell you where it
came from but we used to call it the uh
a sour diesel most people called it The
Saturdays on my little circle and of
course it's not the sour diesel but it
was very similar to it but the
distinction was tighter nugs heavier
nugs shorter squatter plant but it had
every bit of that smell that the sour
diesel is known for and so we called it
a sour diesel or some of it's called a
sour diesel IBL and I'm not really sure
like where that originated from I'm not
sure if it's actually that that's just
what people called and so we were
growing and cropping that out at scale
um before you know I even knew who Joe
brand was you know probably even heard
of who he was to be honest you know I
didn't get a I didn't come across
chemdawg cuts the chem dog or the chemd
or any of the Kim family I didn't come I
didn't get that from any of the chem dog
family you know I got her outside of
that you know coincidentally as I've
mentioned before
okay so yeah so then you know that cut
was with us and what happened was it's
really a cute story actually so what
happened was I was uh going through a
divorce at the time I had a home in
Oakland I was working in I had a home in
sebast while I was working and actually
I had two homes in Sebastopol California
that I was working in so that's about an
hour difference Drive I was also a an
apprentice an electrical worker
Apprentice at the time and I was working
a lot and there's always a lot of
commuting and construction
my ex-wife wanted me to get a real job
at some point because cannabis wasn't a
real job I guess I mean there's always
risk with cannabis and you know she felt
that the danger was affecting
you know our families say you know
security and happiness and just kind of
our day-to-day so I succumbed and I
became a an apprentice in the electrical
industry with the ibw and so I was
working a lot and I had a partner in
Oakland that we were he was living there
and I was living there half time we had
a basement full of herb and one day he
approached me
um and said uh hey uh there's this guy
named Joe brand and he
um the guy who popped the Kim dog seed
gee asked if we wouldn't mind giving him
a cutter than chemdog 91. and I didn't
know any of the story I I so he told me
the story and I was like oh that's
that's an interesting story I'd never
actually this is 2006 mind you I'd never
actually heard about all the stuff that
happened at Deer Creek and then it's odd
it's kind of weird to think about but
it's true I wasn't really privy to that
stuff my experience with Kim dog you
know was outside of that it had nothing
to do with those folks you know that's
just the way it is you know and so you
know he explained to me and I said well
yeah of course sure you know like that's
kind of cool you know he's you know
explain to me that the guy was kind of
you know all these people of course were
out of contact with each other it was
all chance meetings and then here we are
in 2006 I think it was 2006 2005 where
we all were a lot of these folks could
get in contact together and you know I
appreciated that you know even though I
wasn't part of that I appreciated that
and so I said yeah sure you know I think
we have some cuttings in the basement
that are rooting and you know he had to
ask me for my permission or you know I
had a lock on that thought so I said
yeah sure and then I went to work in
Napa and I was working at the Napa High
School doing the lighting there you know
looked good and uh you know so I said
yeah sure well a little back story so my
roommate at the time was and I've known
him for a long time you know like we
used to be very close and we've known
each other since the Grateful Dead days
and you know that's our history there's
a lot of nostalgia yada yada so
um and he's a Kim head you know he loves
it and he gets it and he actually knew G
you know that's why they were able to
talk they actually met each other on the
East Coast they kind of grew up in the
same area in the Northeast and so
um you know I agreed and uh and I you
know I just went to sleep and woke up
went to work the next day well what had
been going on in the background is that
my roommate was selling packs of uh chem
91 that he was getting from another
grower in our area and I and I was
surprised by that because I know the guy
and he asked me for the cut and I said
no of course and uh and it appeared
according to my roommate that he had
obtained a cut somehow and I was curious
about like how is that possible
wasn't really you know didn't have a
time or energy to even really give a
damn but I was curious and every night I
would come home from work and uh and I
would see turkey bags of what he was
saying was chem 91. now as far as I'm
concerned he should know what chem 91 is
right he it's his favorite you know all
of us are like chem dog heads in my
little circle and he's certainly in that
you know and so you know that was that
and so I came home from work the next
day and I said did your buddy come over
he's like he did I said did you give him
a cut because I went down the basement I
don't see any Cuts going on anywhere he
goes well I was over at my homie's house
who I've been getting these packs of
chem 91 from and he had a root cutting
right then and there and I said hey you
know I I think I got
you know skunk va's permission but let
me just go ahead and grab one you got a
nice healthy rooted one here and he was
picking up some packs of chem 91 I think
and so that's how he got it and then he
passed it to JB and so that's that and
well I came home from work and he told
me that and I said huh and I was like
I'm still very curious about this chem
91 cut that I had you know why would
they ask me if they already got it right
and he was opening up turkey bags right
that moment and I was in the dining room
and he was in the kind of a darkened
living room
and uh
um
and he's like I said is that that Kim 91
that you've been you know kind of
rocking the last few weeks Pax he said
yeah so that's not Kim 91. he goes what
he goes you're you know in another room
how could you I said you should know
better than that look at that I can see
from here it's not Kim 91. so I walked
in the room I took the Bud from his hand
but when he was smelling I smelled it
and I threw it back in the bag I said
you should know better that's not Kim 91
and then his eyes got big as you know
headlights and he was like oh my God I
said I'm going to bed
and so I said so that's the cut you gave
that guy that you asked me about he said
he sure is and his jaw hit the floor and
you know I don't know what to say about
all that I mean you know like it's funny
like the uh Power of suggestion I think
is very strong you know with any of us
and so I think that's what a good case
of that you know and so like I said I
had already been familiar with that
particular cut we had been rocking it
for a while and we rocked it along you
know after that separate from this
partnership that I'm describing to you
and you know it just kind of like I
didn't really think much of it and then
later on
um I had uh maybe I don't remember what
happened to the one I had to cut the the
sour diesel IBL but it just kind of went
away somehow I don't remember
um and years later someone you know it
came I heard that there was a cross that
Bodhi had made of the Kim 91 but he had
started to call the mother the JB cut
the chem 91 JB cutter Joe brand cut
and I was like oh that's the same thing
and then I got the cut someone on the
East Coast uh who prefers to stay in you
know Anonymous he he sent me to cut and
it was the same [ __ ] cut it was the
same one that we used to rock in we used
to really get good yields from it and so
you know he then Bodhi had kind of
coined the phrase JB cut which I I love
that you know what I mean I think it's
great because I that happened in my bait
my house you know what I mean and I
thought that was kind of cool so I
couldn't wait to get my hands on I
always wanted to make a cross with it I
love Sour Diesel I love Kim dog it's
just a little bit stronger vigorous you
know version of Sour Diesel but it has
all that stuff in there and so you know
when I got it I couldn't wait to make a
cross with it and luckily it came out
and it's not chem dog I'm Kim dog
because it's not Kim doggone Kim dog
it's very unique it's one of my favorite
crosses that I've made to smoke to grow
out it's easy to grow easy to smoke and
it just punches you in the face it's
great you know what I mean so that's the
story on it hell yeah it's one that's
piqued my interest just hearing that and
in a question or two uh before you
mentioned the old NLS and how the chem
does remind you of that I'd be
interested to hear you know we've seen a
bit of a Resurgence of NLS both in terms
of some seed offerings but even just
other breeders talking about how they
would love to get some of those NL lines
they tried in their youth back into the
stable do you have any fond memories of
NLS have you ever wanted to explore that
realm at all oh yeah
um when I was a young man in Virginia
um I got uh as a 17 year old a minor
which is kind of a key to my life that I
was a minor I got in trouble I got in
big trouble I got in trouble for
possession and distribution of LSD and
uh you know they wanted to charge me as
an adult and uh I had to jump through a
lot of Hoops to not be charged as an
adult you know I had a good friend who
was 18 that night who got set up by the
same snitch and uh
uh and so he actually had a very
different outcome because he was 18. and
I had gotten in trouble when I was 17
probably about five months before I
turned 18 I'm thinking you know roughly
yeah and
um but they still wanted to charge me as
adult this is Heyday drug war 1990 I
think yeah and
um you know very very aggressive law
enforcement very aggressive like War on
Drugs in Virginia you know especially
and they were gonna like maybe he got 18
years suspended for 18 years to give you
uh comparison whereas I had an
opportunity to not really do any jail
time or not really do much jail time as
a minor or do maybe some hard time five
or six years is what they were saying
and you know they were talking about
putting a 17 year old in a in a cage
with grown men you know it's not I don't
I I could never imagine a crime to wear
a child even you know someone who's
about to become adult should belong in a
cage with you know adults it's just
you're guaranteeing you're you know
destroying that person's future and so
my attorney which was like a court
appointed attorney unfortunately because
we were poor ass
um you know fought hard for me to make
sure that didn't happen understanding
that that was going to negatively impact
my life forever so
um so back then we had in Virginia we
had the super skunk we had NL which
turned out to be nl1 I believe and we
had the Nigerian we called the Nigel we
had the Afghani a couple different
Afghans these were all like stuff you
would find in the seed catalogs you know
these this is stuff became the legend of
cannabis you know like we were right at
Ground Zero I don't know how but we were
um Beatrix choice of course I've talked
to you about that one before
um so those were the ones and so it had
a hierarchy you could find Nigerian
easier Nigel quicker Afghan quicker and
that's just what we called it there was
obviously more to the names than that
that's just what we called it that's all
I got
in my memory and then then the harder
ones would be and then the super skunk
and then you'd get to uh the NL and then
of course the Beatrix Choice was the
Holy Grail the hardest to find but these
are roughly the strains that we could
find and they were Primo they were the
best and this is what makes a young
you know person fall in love with
cannabis you know and so the northern
lights so I was on probation from that
charge right my guy sent me to he said
you're going to have to go to a rehab
which was pretty Vogue back in the late
80s early 90s and you're gonna have and
you know you're gonna have to you know
be you're gonna have to play the part
you were addicted to marijuana and you
were addicted to LSD you were addicted
to psilocybin that's your story you're
gonna stick to it you're gonna [ __ ]
beat it with a drum this is going to
save your life and he convinced me as a
young man so I did
and it was an interesting experience
that's where I met the man who became
and to this day as my mentor who made
the super skunk as we know it the F2 the
the number six is a lot of these uh you
know people out here call it who you
know want to know somebody and so we uh
you know he approached me at one of
these n a meetings and he uh he handed
me a Grateful Dead tape now he's an
adult and I'm in a minor in a facility
where people are coming off the street
for an n a meeting you know and uh we
were forced as the Myers to go to this
of course it's part of the program fine
and he knew that we weren't allowed to
have anything to do with Grateful Dead
The Grateful Dead music or paraphernalia
meaning like t-shirts you know
insignia's symbology it was all
considered
um
drug paraphernalia not allowed right so
as a minor in this place you're a child
you're not allowed to have a Grateful
Dead bootleg tape so I'm at this meeting
this is what I'm doing to try to save my
life according to my attorney mind you
and so I'm at it I go up you know as
anyone who's ever been to these things
know that coffee is the big thing so I'm
at the thing getting the coffee at 7 pm
at night you got people say people off
the street you got the adults who are
impatience there and they're
um they're not allowed to talk to the
miners like it can be a big problem for
them you know they can get kicked out of
the program
but then I'm at the coffee thing and a
man Taps my shoulder and he said don't
turn around so I didn't turn around and
he handed me a Grateful Dead tape
because I hear you youngins aren't
allowed to have these and I said no
we're not and he goes well here you go
and I shoved it down my pants
that turned out to be the guy who made
the F2 the super skunk my mentor it was
kind of a chance thing you know that's
how I met him but uh
um so when I was on after I got out I
was on probate I went through my case I
became on probation I had to quit
smoking
um I had to stay in town it was very
strict you know I had to have be known
where I was at all the time and so I
remember we went up to some friends of
mine and everyone was on board they were
like if you smoke you're gonna go to
prison and so don't smoke and I said
well you know what am I not going to
hang out like what are we doing here
like we're gonna help you with this I
mean it was it wasn't really stated but
it was kind of loosely stated that we're
just not going to smoke around him you
know JK that's me and we're just gonna
help him not hurt his own self so that's
what it was but however at the end of
this period of time in probation I was
you know all my friends my circles were
heading up to Boston to the Boston
Gardens to see The Grateful Dead there
in 1991 it would have been at this point
and so I convinced them to let me go
even though that was you know could have
been dangerous for me as far as my
probation goes and this is serious like
people hear probation now it was
different back then like this was just a
simple procedure to get you in prison
you know this was a way around it so it
was more serious in my opinion and so we
get up to Boston and we go to the show
and I I'm a good boy I take a little
acid but I don't smoke any weed my
friends are keeping it away from me to a
degree watching out for me doing you
know being good friends and then after
the show we all pile into a car it was
six of us and all I can do is smell the
[ __ ] bag of weed in someone's pocket
and I can't help myself I'm like can I
just look at it y'all you know show me
the bag I know that smell let's just see
is that the Northern Lights you know and
they won't say a word you know because
they know that once that Domino God's
starts to fall all of them are going to
fall well on the way the hotel from the
show some guy took a little too much too
fast and took all his clothes off as
they sometimes do at those events and
you know having a psychedelic experience
it was getting a little too intense for
the default world and so he was
surrounded by Boston's Finest you know
the the law enforcement and we all had
to wait for this whole movie to unfold
as we're trying to just get to the hotel
we're exhausted and I'm sitting in a car
for an hour and a half smelling this bag
of weed that no one will show me it's
driving me insane and so we get to the
hotel and I say listen
I'm smoking that damn joint I don't give
a damn what anyone says No One's Gonna
Stop Me I don't the consequences are
mine and mine alone and I appreciate you
it's not your fault but when you roll
that and they didn't they rolled that
eight that fifty dollar eighth of
Northern Lights that sticky icky [ __ ]
um goodness into a 50 [ __ ] joint with
a club a nice wrap and it was a
beautiful joint I can picture in my mind
right now and we smoke that [ __ ]
it was the first time I'd smoke in a
whole year and everyone passed out
almost immediately
but when you haven't smoked wheat in
that long and you're tolerance down it's
a much different effect as we all know
and I turned on that Kung Fu theater and
I laughed my [ __ ] ass off until I
practically pissed my pants tears
streaming down my eyes it was probably
the best joint I ever smoked in my life
and I had smoked it before it was the
Northern Lights as we caught it and I
asked him I was like where'd y'all get
this and they said well we got it here
in the parking lot but the parking lot
was flooded and you know whose weed this
is and we don't really know the guy's
name but we knew it was from Virginia
and they said I was like this is from
Richmond right and they said yeah sure
enough this it was everywhere they they
started opening up to me about it now
that it's too late and they told me all
about it you know and they're like it is
better than ever and you know yeah let's
smoke it so we did and so that's that's
my memory of it it'll stick with me
forever of course I had memories of it
before because we used to smoke it but
that was so significant in my life you
know because it was exciting you know I
was once again breaking the [ __ ] law
and you know rightfully so so I smoked
that joint and luckily I got off
probation within 30 days I was already
on when I got off probation I was
already on Jerry Garcia's bands uh East
Coast tour which was you know
you know amazing and so you know that
was it and I I and I never got drug
tested again I went back to my final
probation uh meeting I didn't get tested
and I was grateful for that and that was
that you know that's brilliant and so
obviously you've had these very
memorable and impactful experience with
the no one recently we hear a little
chat about the nl5 making a Resurgence
from a few different seed sources you've
got Matt and Caleb who have done theirs
you've got Todd McCormick has the nl5
ever held a similar reminiscent spot in
your mind or was it really just that nl1
it was just that inner one it was and we
just do it as NL Northern Lights you
know
um only and I'm I'm speculating when I
call it no one based on what I've seen
since then
um it's one of the Holy Grails in my
world and so like though that particular
cut you know but the ones that I've seen
that uh folks have been kind of working
with maybe since then it's a little
convoluted to me like exactly you know
where did it come from how to get these
at the same cut I don't know but the
similarity is there and it's clear and
so I I go with it you know
and uh the nl5 is not it's small it's
not my it's not quite it it might this
is my perception when you had that
Northern Lights let's just call it
normal lights because that's what we
call it back then let's be accurate when
you had that to go to the nl5 it's just
not the same you know it's got a similar
name but it's a much different Fino you
know and so like it's just not in that
Avenue of that I fell in love with just
to be truthful you know so yeah it's
more common and maybe that's exceed my
perception a little bit too because I
love like the Rarities of Some Cuts you
know like I'm drawn to the Rarity of
things you know like how did it make it
this far but ultimately the experience
when you smoke it that's what what it is
and I just can't compare the two I don't
feel like they're even in the same
ballpark that's just my opinion you know
so and I've got uh Matt was nice enough
to send me some of those seeds that
you're speaking of and I can't wait to
go through them but I haven't yet yeah
nice that'll be cool to see what comes
out of that and I mean in that same vein
we've seen some skunk one seeds pop
their head out as well as some original
Haze do either of those ones hold a spot
in your mind or you just didn't really
get exposed to them original Haze would
be out of my wheelhouse and but when it
comes to skunk that's right in my
wheelhouse and
I hate to tell y'all it's not there we
don't have it it's gone at least for my
perception everyone's got a different
opinion about it we can fight about it
if you want but I've been around a long
time and I know what skunk smells like
and I think we all do if you live in
North America you know what a skunk
smells like so if you don't smell that
when you smell the weed be careful
calling it skunk because we all know
what a skunk smells like it's not it's
not like you know uh gardenia
do you know what a gardenia smells like
sure me too but not everybody does but
everyone knows what a skunk smells like
right and so if we don't smell that
let's be honest with ourselves okay you
know so and yeah you know that sounds
horrible to say but it's true we have to
be honest and like that smell that the
super skunk had that was what they
caught we didn't call it road kill skunk
I was right in the middle of all this
stuff we didn't call it that you can
call it that now I know what you mean
yeah it's accurate but that that name
comes from Modern Times it doesn't come
from back in the late 80s early 90s
right you know skunk was it was just
skunk you know and so like you know
grower real growers in Virginia the ones
that really put it all on the line back
then the ones that really did what they
wanted to do in spite of United States
laws Virginia state laws Draconian drug
laws those are the guys that were
growing it and what were strain to grow
than Super Skunk or skunk one Basics
Gunk what would be worse for you to grow
in a place that you know there's no such
thing as a carbon filter reminds you so
what did they do they take that dead
skunk that they found on the highway
that they scooped up and put in the
garbage bag and they throw it in front
of their [ __ ] house until the someone
came and cleaned it up and then go get
another one until you know until their
house didn't smell exactly that's gone
and the reason they did that is because
that smell was so similar to that dead
skunk that you know it worked right well
we all know what skunk smells like and
like we have to be honest for ourselves
when we describe things and each other
it's just not around anymore I don't
know why but it's not around you know so
well look I guess that answered my next
question which was going to be do you
have any leads on the Super Skunk but I
guess as if we zoom out a bit there has
been a bit of discussion in the
community around the uh Super Skunk that
he's passed around and whether the mass
Super Skunk as we call it was the same
as the original one that you first had
what's your thoughts on that
my thoughts are my experience and my
experience is this
um so we you call them Staten Island but
we were very uh we were he's my mentor
my brother uh he's someone I love we've
known each other for a long time he's
responsible he's who I got the chem dog
from he's the one who taught me
everything that he knew at the moment
he's the one that I uh you know I kind
of linked up with uh some very private
growers in Virginia where they traded
Super Skunk for Kim dog and he traded a
chem dog for the Super Skunk based on
all the stories I tell them about you
know it's like the one that got away you
know like the super skunk you've got to
check it out of course he had heard of
it we hadn't seen it so when he brought
it back you know he told me that he had
passed it around some other folks in the
tricest area it didn't matter to me I'm
just a kid mind you and uh you know I
was just grateful to kind of make the
connection or be part of it or just you
know the joy like show my friends in
Virginia and him that like I care about
this stuff you know it's not just I just
don't want to smoke the joints I want to
be you know it's what I can do to help
you know like you know and it's not like
when you're that young you don't think
too much into it you just do what your
role is you know and so anyways you know
and he brought the super skunk back out
to uh Sonoma County where we were at and
was very grateful and that's where it
went but we did lose it we did lose it
and I remember the day I have so many
details my memory we did lose it and I
want to say you know 1998 I think is
when it was it was very early on you
know luckily I'd pass it up to some
people in Humboldt County you know uh
maybe two or three years before that
um in 1995-ish you know when when all
this happened for me and so uh there was
always a possibility we could go get it
again the people I passed it to didn't
have it anymore they had passed it to
another guy who was going to give it
back to me right that never actually
happened so we kind of lost it you know
we went on and that was that you know
and uh and it's one of the saddest most
regretful things that I've ever
experienced in my life is you know
losing that cut and so then you know
fast forward to 2006 when I met G you
know Kim dog
um I met him because I I think I told
you before in the previous story but so
I won't get into that but I uh when I
went out you know I was going to get the
Kim sis and I mean the real original Kim
says and and and bring him back some
chem dog cuts some healthy good Kim dog
cuts so I did and
um as I've said before and so what he
ended up giving me was the Kim d
and the super skunk as he put it to me
he got and I said the Super's gone and I
was surprised when he gave it to me
because this wasn't part of the deal and
and he said yeah the one that you guys
brought up back then you know in 1992 or
three and I was like Wow right on I
didn't know you know and so he didn't
call the mask he ain't called the MSS he
just called the super skunk you know and
so I took it back home I flew it back
home to California and grew him out and
you know I've told you about the kimdi
whatever this was you know my big hope I
was like wow what a bonus like this is
going to be great we've been missing
this because we gave up on it we let it
go we mourned over it you know what I
mean and so
um I grew it out and I've immediately
noticed the stretch wasn't there you
know the super skunk has a I've shown
pictures on my Instagram and you know I
I've documented what the super skunk was
in photo I mean as good of photos you
could take in 1995 with a with a camera
and um so you know the stretch wasn't
there alarming you know but there was a
little bit of resemblance in the
structure so I went with it and then I
just kept on waiting for that smell kept
on waiting and it just never appeared
and in 2006 like as best as I knew and I
want to say that best is we knew but
I'll say as best as I knew there was a
thing called genetic drift you know
maybe that's what happened to it but it
was such a
painful memory of something that was
gone that wasn't it that I just said you
know what I don't want this cut I'm
going to let it go I'm not interested in
it it's not it if it is it it's not the
same I'm Letting Go and that's not like
me I don't let Cuts go like that but I
did only after one car and so that was
the end of it and then you know I was
kind of like damn dude I didn't even get
the Kim says you know like
so
um then fast forward to say 2000 let's
just say 18 or 19 I can't say you know
then you know of course now we're here
about the mass super skunk and so uh
someone was kind enough on the east
coast to send me
um and I don't even it was almost
Anonymous and but he definitely had the
credentials to have the mass Super Skunk
he's in Massachusetts he knows all the
people and everything and so I grew it
out and it was the same [ __ ] cut that
I got from G in 2006. I immediately
recognized it doesn't have the skunk
Terps doesn't have all the things I love
and then you know I don't even have that
cut anymore because it's just I'm not
saying it's a standalone for some it may
but you have to understand that like it
just brings up a bad memory for me you
know it's like a disappointment no
matter how good it is on its own it's
just when you when you have the
perception I have it's just a
disappointment you know because you know
the super skunk was the Holy Grail it
was one of the best cuts that's ever you
know been on this planet and so it's
just a bad you know kind of memory so I
let it go now I do believe based on what
they've told me there that at one point
that super skunk cut from Virginia was
the cut that we're talking about I can't
say for sure I don't know you know I
wasn't around for all those decades in
their Circle you know and so who knows
you know you'd have to ask them but to
me seems like something got mixed up
because how could that be you know the
Holy Grail it it's it's just not that
great in my opinion you know yeah maybe
because of my perception but still and I
ain't I'm not trying to dog to cut don't
don't send me no hate mail just it's
just not my thing I'm a [ __ ] weirdo
you know no that's good to get some
clarification from your perspective for
sure and you know while we're on the
topic of the super skunk and you even
reference Staten Island guy himself I
get tons of people messaging me asking
me you know was that weasel was it this
guy do you think he's ever going to pop
his head out will we ever hear from
Staten Island just from my perspective
seems like he played a huge role in the
chem dog story and people are naturally
curious is it someone the community
knows or do you think he'll remain a
mystery the answer is no and yes
no is not part of the you know no he's
not someone part of you say or part of
the community and yes he seems like he's
he's not interested in all this he's
interested in the work you know
um and so you know we've had our falling
outs in the past and we've come together
as family members do and that's us and I
love him with all my heart and he's
meant the world to me you know
um
he was not supposed to do what he did
with me you know but he took a chance on
me you know and I appreciate that but
he's a you know he I don't want to say
he's private I don't really necessary
thing is he's just not interested in all
this you know he just wants to do the
work and I can't speak for him but
that's all I can tell you you know but
no he's none of those people he knows
them all but is not no there's a lot of
dudes in the weed industry well let's
just back it up I said industry there's
a lot of people who are in the Cannabis
find Cannabis who did their work in
Staten Island he's just one of them you
know there you go I love that but he
knows all the ones you're talking about
let's just say that yeah there you go
there you go and you know and
furthermore like if if if if this was
important to him he's how many
opportunities he had you know lots right
and he's never expressed to me that he
gives a [ __ ] about any of this so that's
that there you go we'll kudos to you Mr
Staten Island we're all appreciative we
sure are I forgot to ask you earlier you
mentioned when you were talking about
the strains you would get in um Virginia
that The Afghani was one in the mix is
that the Virginia Beach Afghani we see
nowadays I don't think so
um based off memory
um The Afghani was honestly a little bit
more like the chem dog than the Virginia
Beach Afghani but I would you know and
like we caught it the Afghan that's what
we caught it but as anyone knows none of
those seeds were really called Afghan
they were crosses you know in this and
that so we I and I can't say which one
it was you know I can't say but I can
tell you it came from that seed stock I
can
pretty accurately say that can't say
firsthand but I would guess hard that it
was but the Virginia Beach Afghani
um which I have I I love it actually
um and it's it's probably not exactly
the same that one had the the Afghan had
a bit more stretch the Virginia Beach
afghanis pretty squat you know typical
Afghan Highland type of strain this
particular Fino of whatever whichever
cross it actually was was a bit more
stretchy
had a bit more smell I had a bit more
punch
um but it was definitely in the same
realm definitely in the same family it's
no doubt you know yeah killer killer
well while we're on the topic of super
skunks I wanna ask you
there's been a lot of discussion about
whether or not it's possible that the
chemd is actually just chem 91 cross to
a soup skunk so the idea is that chem 91
is in fact the mother of chemd and it's
possibly just a super skunk Herman to it
something along those lines what
thoughts come to mind when you hear that
immediately wheel my first thought is
does Kim do you smell like skunk
no so you know the kimdi to me is an
anomaly like I don't know where it came
from I don't know what it is exactly I
could only take what I hear from the
people who say they know on face value
but I definitely have questions about
what I hear I mean I all I can expect
you all I can do is speculate and I
would say no you know it just doesn't
like it's just such an anomaly the kimdi
it's like outside of all of this it
seems to me you know like
course like who am I to say what's what
as far as like and I don't mean like the
stories I mean like what what is what is
possible in genetics like when you make
crosses like what what kind of recess
yet you know recessive genes can pop out
and and create something that smells
like trash you know like it just doesn't
relate to anything and I don't make any
claims I just you know I just have
questions probably more than most people
do but it just doesn't make any sense
but I would say no based on what I know
of those two cuts you know I've we've
we've worked with uh crosses of super
skunk and chem D or Kim dog I'm sorry um
and so none of them came out like the
chemd you know we had uh you know Staten
Islands you call this human uh we you
know super dog seats you know yeah it
was the first time I'd ever seen weed
come from seed you know the super dog
and it was phenomenal you know it had
that skunky Turf you know it had those
those Kim dog earthy Piney just like
dripping
goodness but nothing came out like the
chemd I'd never smelled anything like
the kimdi until I smelled the kimdi and
I could say since then the only things
that I have smelled that are like candy
or crosses with made with the candy Dog
Patch girl glue right is that that's a
chemd cross GMOs got some Kim D in it
right I think GMO is chemd I think
um I think Gorilla Glue uses a different
chem cut well I'm not really that
familiar but I can I grow the GMO here
and I can say yep that's it you know
there's no doubt you know we call them
trash chirps here you know we call them
[ __ ] disgusting trash trips and I
tell people say you're going to smell
this at first you're not gonna like it
give it a second and you're gonna love
it and that's exactly what happens and I
feel like everybody feels this way it's
repulsive yet
attractive all at the same time but it
goes in that order what the [ __ ] to man
let me smell that again you know so I we
didn't come across any of those you know
and I've I've taken down many of those
super super dog seeds uh phinos and you
know they were two or three different
types of Finos
um there wasn't anything like chemd I
never smelled anything like that in
cannabis until I actually smelled the
chemd
so and look there's a very uh rigorous
discussion around all the various
different chemd cuttings there are
without delving into you know trying to
identify them from visuals or whatever
like why do you think there are so many
different chemd cuts out there do you
think it just piggybacks off what you
said before where it's just it's Unique
people are looking for their own version
or do you think there's something extra
which goes into why we see like I think
um Matt counted them at one point and
there's something like seven different
chemd cuts that float around wow I
didn't know that um I've heard there's a
few different floating around but I
didn't know that you know
um
I only can go to what my ex I can only
based on my experience with cannabis and
what I've heard and combined the two and
I would say that most likely Cuts got
lost and s1s popped up I just don't know
I really don't know I I try to like not
speculate there's enough of that out
there they don't I don't think that my
speculation needs to be added to the Hat
I just don't and I don't find it to be
useful and I find that speculations
usually lead to
um you know nope that's not it you know
so I don't really know you know I don't
know I just took take it on face value
you know if I wasn't there then I don't
know and it's just that simple and you
know that allows you for a good night's
sleep when you live by this you know
it's the you know the internet
detectives who have it all figured out
you know their version has got you know
the the phrase I hear that it always
makes me pauses yeah that makes sense
well how does that make sense you know
does it make sense genetically like are
you talking about recessive genes are
you talking about combinations of
genetics that make a brand new like what
does it make sense to you you know like
how does it make sense so I that phrase
makes me pause you know people say it to
me all the time they'll be like they'll
ask me a question and I'll tell them my
experience I'll tell them my life I'll
tell a story about what happened that I
was there for and then they'll say that
makes sense no it doesn't none of this
makes [ __ ] sense to anyone dude you
know what I mean like how does it make
sense to you because people will have
biases they have perceptions that they
hold on to we all do it doesn't matter
what it is you know it could be about
anything in life you know but we all
hold on to that and we have to be
careful with that because we can add
a false narrative to a story that's not
even ours to tell and this happens every
day in canvas as we know and I just
don't want to do that I don't need to
add to that my experience is limited but
it's also vast I've had a lot of
experience with some of this stuff just
kind of chance kind of coincidentally
I'm okay with just sticking with that I
don't need to figure out anything else
I'll let the people the internet
detectives figure that out and I'll you
know enjoy their stories as they come
you know that's that I like it
diplomatic well look while we're on the
topic you mentioned the um the Superdog
and we're talking about strains from
sort of yesteryear are there any strains
from the Sonoma Bay Area Mendo sort of
area in that 95 to 2005 period that you
miss that aren't the super skunk maybe
strains that don't get as much of a
mention but you do remember like oh that
was a good one I kind of wish we had
that
jeez man my my answer is probably pretty
boring of that because we were so delved
into our chem dog you know like when I
got the sour diesel I was like wow look
at this you know and it had already been
around you know I didn't even get that
cut until like let's say 2002 three-ish
I think you know you know I you know my
perception is kind of you have to
understand that like I lived in a bubble
you know like I wasn't out here in the
world like hey man like we're this is
what we're doing you know we were very
private like we lived in the old school
by the old school rules like we don't
talk about this stuff there's no deal
now the the downside of that was like
maybe we didn't get introduced to a lot
of cuts but if but the answer to that
question in the Bay Area would have been
that super silver a haze cut that I
mentioned before that was a standout it
was outside of our lane outside of our
realm but it was lovely beautiful and
just amazing smoke so that would be the
first thing that pops to my mind
um
I mean of course you know like when I
discovered OG Kush I was probably a
little bit around that area era like
2003 and that may have been a little
late in the OG Kush story right so to me
in my perspective and my little bubble
like wow you know this is amazing you
know and uh and so that would fall in
that category so these answers aren't
like sexy they're not [ __ ] fun but
they are that's the answer you know like
I was just in a bubble like we were just
growing Super Skunk chem dog you know
like you know and eventually Sour Diesel
but like we were stuck in that you know
my little circle no totally
understandable if that's what you're
working with and it was sort of almost
on the Forefront in a sense but because
no one really knew how good chem was at
that time it's only now I feel like it's
really in the Zeitgeist oh yeah for sure
you know like we or I was die hard I
just grow what I like you know like I
don't pay attention to the outside noise
I never did to my own detriment and I
mentioned this before and so like I
would push like and I mean push I'd be
like check this weed this check this Kim
dog out and I would get the same
response like I don't want to look at
that I've already seen it I'm not
interested in it do you have any sour
diesel OG kush I'm like geez man you
know no I got a big [ __ ] tub full of
this you know check it out it's amazing
just look no I've already seen it and
it's because they'd already seen The
Fakes you know they've already seen the
fake cuts and it was not just one there
was mini you know and it was frustrating
it was kind of heartbreaking because my
favorite weed wasn't good enough for
everybody else anymore you know what was
well OG cushion Sour Diesel I'm like
well if you like those you're gonna like
this so that's kind of it you know like
I was in a bubble I kept myself there
for better for worse and that's just my
perspective you know no it makes sense
totally and you mentioned the sour
diesel I wanted to quickly ask you is
the diesel therapy seems like it's also
got quite a cult following it's a bit of
a Powerhouse in terms of the fan demand
what do you think it is about this cross
that seems to be grabbing people's
attention because I mean I don't know
the back end but it seems extremely
popular it is it surprised me and you
know when you make uh you know if when
you decide to make several crosses you
just never know what the what the users
are going to like you know and that one
surprised me a little bit
um but it's just I think what it is I
think Sour Diesel well I know Sour
Diesel it comes and goes in popularity
and it's very popular right now you know
like you can go across the board you can
look at all kinds of stuff that's out
there from what I can see that it's very
desired right now and it doesn't
surprise me it's I mean it's one of the
less strange it's ever you know come
across the scene and so I think that's
what it is you know I don't think it's
anything else I think that's what it is
and the East Coast Sour Diesel is a
great representation of What Sour Diesel
can be as far as like you know the way
it looks the way it smells the effect
um and the East Coast Tower diesel is a
little easier to deal with than they you
know I don't I dare to say original Sour
Diesel because that's probably not even
the right way to describe it but it's
it's a little easier to grow it's a
little shorter a little stouter a little
stockier it's a little bit less stretch
well it's a lot less stretch really and
so that was what made it a good
candidate you know of course I'm going
to be I'm always [ __ ] around with
sour diesel [ __ ] you know I love it you
know
um but if if I was like uh and I think
that Kim Fuego is going to give you all
the traits that you're going to look for
in Sour Diesel but maybe because it
doesn't have the name up front maybe
that's what it is so I think that's what
it is I think it's the name you know
people people want to you know bring
that fuel that diesel that fire you know
right back in and so there it is you
know 100 percent look we're gonna have
to drill down into some of the strains
because in the last chat we did
um these weren't really released and so
people have accumulated their questions
and I guess on the topic of
experimenting with new crosses a lot of
people are really keen on the Tropicana
Cherry cross you've been posting about
and you've also done some hybrids with
the apple fritter I guess in general you
could say that you're bringing some some
new uh genetics into the library making
some crosses with some more sort of
modern stuff what's been your take on
this and what and what uh crosses have
sort of caught your eye I'm trying to
expand and kind of get more experience
with some of the newer crosses you know
or the newer you know hybrids that are
out there like the ones you mentioned
and I like a lot of them you know
they're outside of my wheelhouse or
outside of my you know the things that I
like about candles but I'm okay with
that I'm open to it and so
um I thought I was being kind of unique
making those crosses and now it looks
like a lot of breeders have been working
with especially those two cuts but I you
know we've tested them out you know our
testing you know we move at a certain
Pace we have a flow here I have a flow
um and it might be a little more slower
than some and so we're here we've tested
it out we really like it I like it you
know so we've released them or we're
getting ready to release them and I'm
really happy with them you know and I
and I I get a little bit of pushback
from the chem dog heads out there about
it but that's okay you know
um we can't make everyone happy all the
time and but we want to like you know
kind of cross it's like an opportunity
to take the old school and cross it into
the new school and kind of show the new
school with the old school is all about
in a cross you know and how things can
be improved especially in the area of
potency and also inflate flavor I hate
to say and but we've we succeeded there
and so like that's the idea and maybe
we're always a little late to the game
we always have been
um but we do it right I do it right we
do it right and and those two are the
results of that we're going to release
them later this month you know oh that's
exciting and I mean you just referenced
the Die Hard chem heads and one of the
questions I have received a few times
over the past few years probably one you
get quite a lot is will people ever be
able to get a pure chemline from you
maybe like a bx4 a bx5 just straight 91.
well we did make a bx4 selected and I
and I've mentioned this to folks before
um it was he was doing pretty good in
the crosses and he was the one that we
were probably going to test a lot of his
progeny his brothers and sisters out and
say okay this is the chem BX that we're
going to release however
um in
[Music]
2019 in Sonoma County most of the county
and I mean literally almost all the
county got evacuated due to fire another
[ __ ] Wildfire fueled by the El Diablo
winds this is Nightmare and um during
that of course when you a have a genetic
library and you know full growing mother
State outside of tissue culture you're
going to not be able to leave your home
unless you want to lose big time so
although the Emergency Services
Sheriff's Department fire department and
others were coming through the area
where we were keeping the library I was
keeping the library
when I say we I mean with me you know
but it's a habit so
um they we were uh basically hiding from
the emergency services and not
evacuating now you know
anybody listen to this you take those
wildfires very seriously those fires can
be very fast we had a good advantage
point and I had rooted cuttings you know
in the bathroom of my RV under a
skylight just in case we had to go along
with the family photos you know and the
glassware and all the things that matter
in life that you cannot replace and so
we were ready to go but I wanted to keep
my moms going too well however we did
lose the X4 male so we have the seed
still but I've decided to kind of put
that on hold for now
um I want to do the feminized project
that we talked about and I want to um I
have some other crosses that I've made
that I'm testing out so for space I'm
just leaving that alone
I don't really feel like people are
gonna be
getting what they expect I think the
expectations of BX line released as it
is will be less because like I said I
don't I'm not trying to recreate Kim dog
I'm not trying to put it and see I'm
trying I always was trying to make a
stud that I could cross with my favorite
females that wasn't going to dominate
them but add potency to them add flavor
to them add that extra little fuel you
know chem Fuel and so if you were to
grow them out and I have like you may
you may it may you may feel like you're
not getting what you want you know I
mean because my goal was not to recreate
chem dog and Seed form
so but to answer your question yeah I
will be doing that work but I have to
kind of start from where I had started a
couple years ago and then I'm gonna have
to gear it towards that and so that's a
little bit different work than creating
the studs that I've that I've created in
order to make the seeds that I make the
F1 hybrids
um I'm gonna have to kind of backtrack a
little bit and there's more work
involved than people realize like to
take all my bx3 seeds and I have bx4
seeds too and just say this is the bx4
I don't it's accurate but it's also the
goal wasn't to get that to the market
the goal was to create a stud that
doesn't overpower every female that
comes in here and so if you were to grow
them out you'd be like wait a minute you
know so you have to back it up a little
bit and then you have to reselect for
different reasons and then you can
continue the work once you find your
selections with that goal in mind right
and so this is like this is a lot more
work you know this is basically starting
over in some ways not completely
starting over but maybe going back to
the bx3 generation and selecting for
different traits which certainly could
happen and then you know maybe taking it
in a different direction instead of
going back into back cross maybe start
to create filial Generations that are
geared towards that goal which I think
is be a better more uh like a more
um you know like what's the word like
it's it that would be a more accurate
way of doing it at this point you know
like an IBL essentially you know and so
this is years and years and years of
work you know I don't really think that
a bx3 or bx4 chem at this point is
really useful to anybody I don't think
it's going to be as great as anyone
thinks you know what I mean that's
basically what I'm saying I'd rather
select brother and sister and move
forward that way you know from one of
the generations and I haven't begun that
work yet well I backed up I have begun
to work but I haven't like narrowed it
down this is big work you know this is
important work to do what you're asking
or what you're suggesting
and so I just haven't I that's gonna
take that's a lifetime you know and we
we're not going to do her dirty we're
not going to try to make a quick Buck on
a bx3 we're not doing that you know so
that's the answer we're not going to do
that we're going to probably go a
different route we're going to select
some filial generations F1 two three
four five all the way wherever it is
that's where it'll happen we're doing
the background truthfully we're not
really focused on it right now I'm not
focused on right now sure it's a great
and a very comprehensive answer very
much related but one I got from two
different of our patreon listeners was
sort of in that same vein they wanted to
know of what's currently available what
do you think best embodies the chem dog
if someone was saying look what's just
something that's going to give me a
really good idea of what chemdog is
which strain would you recommend that's
really easy so it's going to be griller
for me you know
um not by Design but kind of by Design
it's also going to be double Crush you
know which you know the road dog like we
talked about before it's kind of close
relative very close relative that one's
kind of taken over in that realm but I
would say the double crush and certainly
the gorilla for me the gorilla for me
when someone asked me that's immediately
the answer you know you're going to find
a lot of females that are very similar
to the chem dog you know so that's what
it is you know what I meant by that is
that the bx3 is not as Kim doggy as the
gorilla fume of the best phenos you know
so that's the answer like the girl who
may I always tell people that's chem dog
in seed form you know that's as good as
it's going to get you know we could
probably do better but you know we
haven't yet you know so and look just in
the last question you're talking about
the different chem dog miles you have
them playing around with filial braiding
I think you mentioned to me that you've
been playing with a new male a Master
Kush hybrid can you tell us anything
about that
yeah so we we one of our new we have a
new release coming out Lucky Dog Seed Co
does you know sometime Christmasy maybe
depending on if we can come up with some
names
um we're not real good at that well
maybe we're good at it but it takes time
but um so we have what we have Grand
Master Kim is our new one and that's the
Master Kush cross with the chemdog vx3
male that we're all familiar with well
we happen to have made f2s of that as
well so we're not really planning on
doing any extra work with that F2 mail
the mail that we used in the F2 we do
have him around still for obvious
reasons because we want to be at we are
happy with that cross and we want to be
able to continually make it so we have
for that reason will he go to anything
else will we further work him I don't
really know that I don't really have a
sense that we will that I will we just
you know we wanted to make that F2 you
know we wanted to because we saw some
diversity but we love the diversity so
we wanted to kind of narrow it down and
the F2 generation and I think we did
that I feel like we narrowed it down
from say seven or eight phinos down to
five four three somewhere in there and
that's more what we're trying to do so
that's why we did it and we've done it
with other crosses I've made but not the
same success that we're having with that
guy in in his partner so you know that's
kind of it you know that's why we're
making that one because we
I you know it was one of the ones that
was going to go in the drawer that I
mentioned before and we fell in love
with some of the females we're like okay
what would we what do I do well let's
make an F2 you know let's see if we can
narrow down we did you know we're not
going to release dev2 yet because we
want we have to do more testing but
we're ready to release the F1 uh we got
Grand Master Kim we think it's kind of
catchy and we think people are going to
love it you know that's exciting I mean
Master Kush is one you don't hear of as
much these days so good to see that
making a comeback I've got a similar
sort of question for you in a sense to
the last one
um in terms of the recommendation of the
chem what would you recommend if you
can't know any specifics about the
grower any you don't get to find out
anything about their preferences you can
only recommend one pack so I guess in
essence what I'm saying is what pack do
you think is like broad appeal most
people are going to be into it what is
your cookie cutter that you would
recommend
did you say cookie cutter what it's
almost like you're subliminally trying
to get the answer I mean that would be
the Schism this gives them fade Schism
is the only cut the only seeds I've made
that have some of that cookie in it's
got the OG KB crossed to the Cyber band
so the the male in the in that cross the
tits is what it's called this is the
[ __ ] it is the the male to the the sour
band male using that cross is direct
progeny direct brother and sister to the
female that I used in the sour uh I'm
sorry the Kim Fuego the sour band that's
used in the Kim Fuego so they're
directly related in that sense and the
Schism
um is a cross between the tits and the
bx3 male right and so honestly it's one
of my favorites even though I'm not a
big cookies guy I just love that [ __ ]
cross every I say this with 100
confidence every single uh Schism seed
that I ever popped and grew out I would
have kept as a clone only no doubt and
that I that's me saying it I 100 now I
can't tell you why it hasn't been you
know the Kim Fuego is our most popular
the Dog Patch is up there for obvious
reasons you know sour band right but
that that Schism is just off the chain
easy to grow it's got both worlds it's
got the new and the old mixed perfectly
all phenos you know like you're gonna be
happy so that's the answer you know like
it's interesting but that's the one that
you're I love it and is one of the rare
one as one of the few people who's been
lucky enough to try the rare tits cut
it's truly a special cutting and I'm
sure that pairing is going to tick a lot
of boxes so let's do a um Let's do an
adaptation of one of the questions we
asked you last time so in our last chat
I asked you if you had a time machine
like what would you go back and get so
now I'm going to modify that question a
little bit right let's just say those El
Diablo wins had knocked out your entire
Library you lost absolutely everything
turn up and I say I've got the time
machine for you but you can only bring
back one pack of Lucky Dog seeds and
you're going to restart the company with
a male presumably from this one pack of
seeds what pack of seeds are you going
to restart the company with that's a
good question
um
male
the mail oh I mean you could do whatever
you want to read something but I presume
you're going to get a rake pack and get
a mail that's a good question I like
that I got my head going here
um I would say
man that's a tough one I don't know I
like that Schism
um
I don't know like it depends on what I
was trying to do like if I was gonna go
back to you know working with Kim dog
and trying to wrap you know put Kim dog
and Seed form it would be gorilla fume
it would be you know it's special like
that
um but you know I tend to want to answer
it a different way but that's probably
the answer
um I would want to do that because it's
chem dog you know and that's what I'm
into that's my thing you know I love it
and nothing you know messes with my
brain chemistry better you know and I
think a lot of us agree once we
experience that like it's hard to
it's always going to be compared to
everything else we as we move forward so
maybe that would be it but also like the
Bohemian Highway comes to mind which has
really literally been one of my least
sought after which has always surprised
me because it's fire and the people who
did buy it they always come back you
know
um I had a farm up in Philo California
Mendocino County who I don't know where
they got back from it wasn't for me but
they got it from a seed bank and then
they reached out to me you know they're
a farm you know they're a legal farm and
they wanted to get quite a bit of bulk
of that and then I was like finally
someone recognized you know
um what this is this cut is
um and uh so I would say that that kind
of makes me think about that one but I
can't get away from the fact that I
would want to try to get back to the
chem dog as fast as I could and then
that would be the gorilla fume you know
yeah great answer and I mean maybe
there'll be some overlap with the answer
for this one but a lot of the time
people are interested obviously
yield for some people is very important
what do you think is the most
commercially viable in the sense that
it's a good compromise of potency yield
all the different aspects that would
make it suitable for production hmm
I don't know I would I I guess I would
try to you know I would think about one
that uh has a good really solid yield
easy to grow it's not going to be
complicated it's not going to compete in
a negative way with other strains or
phenotypes you have in your garden and
it would be honestly it would be the
Schism it would be you can't you can't
beat the potency it's a unique the
mother's so unique you can't really pen
her down you can't say oh this is a
cookie strain yeah it's got that in it
but it you know oh no this is uh you
know Sour Diesel headband you know you
can't pin it down but it's got big
yields you know it's you know resistant
to pressure you know pests and otherwise
and it's really consistent and easy to
grow it's very fast to find if you know
I I was surprised by it I knew it was
going to be interesting I had no idea
that it was going to be so consistent
and stable as far as like traits that we
all love you know and in this moment in
cannabis in America or otherwise so I
would have to say that one you know
perfect great answer great answer so
you've got me wondering what's on the
horizon for Lucky Dog Seiko or more
generally for skunk VA you've gone from
seed to dispensary what do you plan to
do next
so you know and here's the deal so like
we I see like a need for good clean
you know Legacy genetics and it doesn't
have to necessarily mean it's old that's
not what I mean but like
good representations of what we all
agreed cannabis is you know and so
there's a lot of stuff out there not all
of it's gonna make it to the next day
not at all it's gonna make it to the
next phase uh there's a lot of hype
um so for me like I'm all I love doing
lab work I love working under the hood
you know I'm not a biologist I'm not a
scientist but I know how to do some of
the stuff that they do that we do and so
like we are going to be introducing
um VA labs to the community and we okay
so let me start from the beginning so
tissue culture we all know what it is
we're all familiar with why we would
want to do it we all understand the
reasons why I exist we either want to do
long-term storage of genetics we want to
clean up genetics you know Mary stem
tissue culture
um and who knows what else next you know
like there are some viruses that can be
passed on to the meristem rather easily
and so therefore that's not necessarily
going to be a cure but to me like and I
first did tissue culture in 2005.
um Staten Island as you call them gave
me a kit and he said figure this out and
tell me you know tell me why this is
useful to cannabis and I did what he
asked and what I my answer was like I
can't really tell you what it's useful
for I can say that Transportation around
the globe would be definitely at the top
of the list
um and these this is 2006. these are
things the the issues that are actually
you know being like uh dealt with with
tissue culture uh propagation they
weren't really present at the time you
know we weren't aware of some of the
viroids we weren't you know like there's
a bunch of stuff you know like we were
still in that genetic drifting and so
that's what the answer was so I've been
familiar with it on that level I've done
other work with other uh I guess you
call them plants under sterile
conditions under flow hoods you know
sterile air so like I'm familiar with
the process and so what what I'm doing
is I want to like what I did was like I
wanted to find someone who I have so
many mothers you know right now I have
70 mothers 71 71 different strains in my
library that's not a lot but it's a lot
you know and so biggest problem and it
became highlighted here at Lucky Dog
cannabis is that geez how much labor and
time and energy and resources go into
keeping all those mothers I'm all about
redundancy redundancy is how you keep
plant alive for 30 [ __ ] years that's
the secret what is redundancy redundancy
is overdoing it you know never relying
on one always relying on the redundancy
system and so you know what I've learned
here is like I it's hard to describe how
much energy goes into keeping that
ground healthy
uh vibrant productive you know there's
always at least two moms there used to
be four now we got it down to two to
give you an example it takes up a lot of
time a lot of space and a lot of
resource and I didn't discover that in
the last few years this has been a
problem I've had for a long time now and
so when tissue nodal tissue culture
came an option for long-term storage I
was very interested in this the problem
is is like who to do to work me I'm
already busy I got a lot going on so
there's a lot of outside options
um you know Outsourcing I think they
call it so I looked around and every
time I looked into a company that does
this type of work I just couldn't quite
pinpoint what their goal was and it it
it's like so when you want to store your
library and it's that vast and that
large you want to have peace of mind the
reason you want the reason you're even
thinking about is because you want to
sleep at night without worrying about
you you're wondering life again
basically you want to be able to go have
some fun with your girlfriend you know
what I mean or whatever hang out with
your family take your dog for a [ __ ]
trip you know whatever it is it becomes
a problem because you know you can't
really get that freedom it's not the
flower production it takes your time
it's really that that's what keeps you
up at night if my flower crop goes to
[ __ ] I don't lose any sleep over I just
start over well you can't do that with
your library you know you lose something
it's gone forever and whenever that
happens to you it breaks your heart in 5
000 pieces and you can't put it back
together ever again you just have to
kind of mourn it and move on I've been
through it so nodal tissue culture as we
moved into the modern era was something
that was very interesting to me very
attractive to me but every time I went
and looked at a company that could help
me with this
and I'm I tend to do things on my own so
there's that but it's just I couldn't
figure out what's going to happen next
and then you hear stories this company
did this this Scandal happened this
[ __ ] [ __ ] happened I don't want
to be part of that because like I said I
just want to sleep well at night knowing
my shit's safe you know these are my
kids these are my dogs this is my family
it has to be safe and so I just couldn't
trust the system so I was like okay if I
want to do this I have to do it myself
right not the decision I want to make
but that's the decision and so that's
where we're at and that's where VA Labs
is popping up from that's where we're
that's where it was born of so I took it
upon myself to learn the process you
know nodal tissue culture Mary stem
tissue culture yeah sure synthetic seeds
these things aren't that uh you know
useful to me they're part of the the
work you know and so you know and I'm
thinking to myself as like well you know
maybe there's other uh you know
preservationists out there that feel the
same way they can't seem to break free
of the chain around their damn neck
because of their mother's stock you know
their mother block is just taking up all
their life and time so you know maybe
maybe I can like you know learn the
process share the process and that's key
I want to teach other folks how to do
this you know I feel like that cannabis
has missed had a close call with say
like hop late and thyroid you know it
snuck into all of our Gardens and almost
ruined many you know uh people's
libraries you know in the in the silent
of the night you know it's kind of a
silent killer you know
um and so you know what I saw was
there's like a you a use for that like
you know storing people's genetics is
obviously a service that we're going to
provide and that we're happy to but we
also feel that it's going to be better
to teach people the process teach
companies the process anyone who cares
about it we can help them that and
that's what we're going to do so we're
going to be doing you know genetic
storage we're going to be cleaning up
genetics you know all the typical stuff
but also we're going to be teaching
people how to do it themselves because
we realize that that's where the um
that's the biggest need you know you're
not going to like be a company in New
York and come out to Montana or
California to get you Cuts it's just not
practical so what is practical having
your own you know your own team learning
process Master the process feel
confident and then you can store your
own genetics what does that do for
cannabis that propels cannabis that that
keeps cannabis genetic pool clean and it
allows anyone who comes across any
problems to have the proper skills to do
something about it and then you know we
uh we've been known to have pretty good
reputation and we're not going to [ __ ]
you over we don't want nothing from you
we already got what you got so if you
want a store here we can do that for you
so to be honest with Lucky Dog cannabis
what this is It's a licensed facility
it's a licensed business in the United
States
you know I believe personally that
National legalization is just a few days
away it's coming quicker than anyone
realizes and once that happens
interstate commerce when it comes to
cannabis is going to become going to
become part of the deal and what that
means is that like it doesn't matter
what state we're in we're all going to
be able to help you we're going to be
able to work with you and that's what
the goal is so and then furthermore we
want to be able to provide clean
verified clean how well we're going to
be testing it we're going to be testing
it every two weeks we're going to be
testing mother stock your mother's stock
if you choose if you're ready to come
out of tissue culture and be integrated
into you know uh standard propagation
practices we're going to make sure that
before that stuff happens whatever it is
whether it be ours or yours or whatever
it is it's going to be clean you know
we're gonna we're gonna make sure that
you know and so you know the the testing
has come a long way you know now we're
taking root uh you know we're testing
the roots in the first few inch the soil
at different locations and you know we
are investing in we have a cute PCR
machine so we are able to test for qpcr
machines are pretty readily available
for hot plate and firewood for instance
and other pathogens
as long as as well as sex testing we'll
be offering all those services and we
feel like that is a good focused focal
point for us to
further take the next step with cannabis
you know
um and of course there's other ways of
doing it there's other folks doing out
there but you know It's just tough to
find someone who really gets it you know
and understands like where we're going
with all this and we feel I feel like we
do we get it you know we've always been
about the plant we always will be about
to plan
and so you know if there's you know a
service that is worth money great but
that's not exactly why we're doing it we
just want to make sure that cannabis
makes it to its next step that's what
I've been doing the whole time and
that's what I'm going to continue doing
and when when I saw this kind of
opportunity or you know like kind of
this Vision to do it it I just couldn't
it's just passion it's like my passion
just went right to it like this is it
this is what we got to do this is the
work we've been waiting for we've been
in this law between what we've done and
what we're going to do and this is it
you know so we're doing it you know wow
that's super exciting and in all honesty
we could probably spend a whole episode
just delving into the specifics of it
all we'll have to keep our eyes open for
VA Labs that sounds super cool we're
sort of on the tail end of things and I
have a really good patreon question I
wanted to run by you before we wrap
things up which is basically along the
lines of what does Staten Island think
about the fact you've been able to make
a really successful company off the back
of chemdog does he ever talk about
wanting to do his own breeding or start
his own company
um he is uh gonna be opening a nursery
in Northern California and so where
we're at right now he's like he would
like to get lucky dog you know breeder
Cuts in in the nursery so that's kind of
where we're at you know yeah
um you know he's he we all played our
role you know none of us like did
anything we all collectively what we did
was we preserved one of the greatest you
know the the queen of contemporary
cannabis is what we've done you know we
did that and so you know
um
I think that we all are aware of the
role we played in the bigger picture and
for any one of us to take like uh you
know a [ __ ] Victory lap about what
each what an individual has done would
be kind of
that's not in the spirit of what we're
trying to do and he he gets that you
know so I think that that like we're
we're talking about
um that nursery and how to get unique
genetics and of course Lucky Dog you
know Cuts there so you know that's
that's kind of what I would say I can't
speak for other people I would say that
that's
pretty close to what you would hear you
know that's really cool to hear and
hopefully as time goes by people can get
access to some killer braided cuts
through his Nursery one of the other
patreon questions we got from a fellow
Virginian was what area of Virginia is
skunk VA from and as legalization rolls
out further would you ever consider
moving back to Virginia
absolutely
um I always dreamed to sell legal
cannabis in Virginia I'm from Richmond
the south side of Richmond on the south
side of the James River Chesterfield
County that's where I grew up but I did
I did uh spend some time in Oregon Hill
in Richmond back when it was a weird
place it's not weird now it's kind of
gentrified
um but uh south side of Richmond is what
we call it the South Side
um Chesterfield County you know
I would definitely not consider moving
back there Virginia is a beautiful place
it's one of the most beautiful places in
the United States uh George Washington
National Park is one of the most
beautiful places you could ever be and
there's so many other spots you know
um it's an interesting place it's a
diverse place in some ways and cannabis
has always been a really popular thing
in Virginia oddly enough because it's
you know you get a lot of trouble for it
over the years
um I I don't think I would ever move
back to it but I would like to uh kind
of do what your your listeners
suggesting and and kind of be part of
the you know uh evolution of cannabis
there because I'm from there I always
like uh every time I've ever been busted
I'm always thinking you [ __ ] I
might hire your kids one day you know
because I know they care about weed more
than you hate it you know and so that
that's a little bit of a motivation but
also yeah I'm from there and it's like
every thing that happened in my life
stemmed from you know growing up there
just kind of coincidentally and yeah
Virginia's I think everyone knows now
Virginia is well known for its
contribution to cannabis in the United
States due to the Dark Ages especially
so I'm so happy to see that my brothers
and my sisters there are able to you
know more freely Express themselves in
uh their love for cannabis without the
fear of what can happen the consequences
and so I would love that you know I
would love to be part of any kind of you
know thing that picks up and happens
there you know it's a slow moving
process legalization there
um just the way they're doing it but
it's happening you know and when I go
there to visit because I I have gone to
some seed events there and I go back and
I love my people back there like they're
good to me and I I just love their
passion you know I recognize their
passion I see it the same passion that I
came up with in spite of the law in
spite of what the consequences I still
see it and I so much love it you know so
yeah I would love to be part of it but I
don't think I'll ever live there so to
speak I'm not big on the humidity I
wasn't when I grew up there and I'm not
still now so that would be a big one for
me you know so so so one of our
listeners wanted to know what is the
sort of considerations that go into
making a hybrid for you and they
specifically reference that uh the pine
Soul go gog is a cut they love they were
a bit caught off guard they weren't
exactly expect you to make a hybrid with
it and they thought oh wow there's maybe
all these Cuts I wasn't necessarily
thinking he might work with it what is
it is it just you liking the flower and
going this will work well like what goes
into you picking a cut to breed with
well that's just it it's it's the I fall
in love with the mom the cut and and I
want to see what else we can do with it
so it's like a bit of experiment
experimentation at that point but it
starts with that it starts with I like
the cut sometimes
um you find a cut that you just want to
see what happens you know and that's
happened a few times but really it's the
you know like the
um the sunshine biscuits is a good
example of one where I absolutely love
the mother I love the the flavor potency
is missing it's just not that strong you
know even for me and I don't need like
overpowering cannabis but it's just not
that strong it's kind of a quick lasting
um you know High effect and the flavor
is just phenomenal you know and so that
one's an outlier because of that it's
like maybe we can improve this and we
did and I feel like the strength what
we've made is you know more in tune with
what we think it should be not the cut
but just cannabis in general
um but it maintains that flavor the
beautiful colors you know the experience
you have with Cherry AK right so that's
an outlier of that but other than that
it's like oh I love this cut does this
work with it and see what happens you
know and like I said most of the time
we're not happy with the results
and most maybe everyone maybe most
people would be but I'm not you know
like if there's too many damn funerals
it's just it's not what we're trying to
do you know if it's too dominated by Kim
dog that's also not what we're trying to
do and in that case we may try the bx2
male right and if that's not where it is
then it just goes in the drawer you know
and we'll deal with it some other day
there's plenty of types of work we can
do with those but what we're trying to
do at Lucky Dog it now that's not really
in in tune with what we're doing so it
goes in the drawer we're not trying to
sell
a guy in Texas for instance or Arkansas
or Mississippi you know let's take
Mississippi because they're they're
actually medical now but you know
Georgia and then and then like confuse
them with a bunch of phinos and it could
be disappointing you know and we don't
want that so that's what we're trying to
do now you know in the future well we
got a lot of stuff to work with and
maybe our goals will be slightly
different you know
but that's kind of it nice I I like that
it's a well thought out so our final
patreon submerged questions before we do
a few quick fire ones is can you tell us
a little bit about the Royal Apple it's
made by our buddy Jay trees and used in
The Zephyr I guess people don't really
see it anywhere else how would you
describe that mother for people that
mother
um it had the reason I uh got interested
in using that mother was so I met him at
the 2017
um Emerald cup and he gave me some seeds
you know and they were interesting you
know the Long Valley Royal we're all
familiar with that amount of rocks
working and then uh cross with the sour
apple I believe it is and so
um you know that's interesting that
sounds interesting to me so I popped it
honestly they weren't like what I hope
but there was one Fino that had this
amazing color and purple and I don't
really have a lot of beautiful I wanted
to like have visually a visually
different stimulating kind of cross you
know to kind of like give people who are
in the that an option a lucky dog and so
that was where I started it didn't have
the structure didn't have say the
potency so it was a prime candidate to
be crossed with the bx3 and so that's
what I did I worked it into a
pollination that I did and I was really
pleased with the results and I love the
color the structure everything was
improved but it had that pedigree and
also that extra fuel chem just you know
sticky icky just destroy you kind of
thing and so we went with it you know
um you know that's pretty much the story
you know it started off with I wanted
more Beauty I wanted a a visually
appealing flower you know
um just to see what comes from it
because oftentimes with deep purple
strains like that gosh they're pretty
the flavor you know potency the the
oftentimes those things are missing with
the Zephyr we nailed it we got it you
know we had those pink purple Hues but
we had this [ __ ] dripping trichome
production and just like amazing flavor
I fell in love with it you know and very
consistent you know like two phinos you
know it was really nice beautiful great
answer I'd love to hear that uh Jay
trees work made it into the library so
on to our final questions we'll we'll
juggle it up a little bit this time so
we don't repeat any from last time first
one is what's the single most memorable
cannabis experience you've had so it
doesn't necessarily have to be like the
most potent hit you ever took but just
for whatever reason it just sticks with
you is like that was just a great memory
and cannabis was involved
well I did I did share with you that
joint that I smoked in 1991 and that's
definitely at the top of the list but
I'll give you another one
um and Grateful Dead Land uh they you
would find what they call backstage bud
and backstage Bud it didn't it wasn't a
particular strain it was what they
wanted you know as they you know came
out in the parking lot and searched
around you know they got a lot of Clouts
so they're going to see things that I'm
not going to see you know even though
I'm out there every day they come out
you know for a minute you know I don't
know who Steve parish is you know you
want to see some good weed hey Steve
Parish he's the Roadie for you know I
wrote it for the Grateful Dead uh he was
Jerry Garcia's right hand man he's like
a bouncer slash guitar polisher slash
Roadie like he did it all so I don't
know if he was the one but I know he
loves weed and he would come out you'd
see him out there every now and again I
mean mostly he was working but he had a
thing called backstage butt and this is
the backstage but it wasn't the same as
yesterday it wasn't the same as the last
set of shows in the other City this is
what they're smoking tonight and there
was this one
um particular uh backstage Bud that was
I I think we were we were in Oakland
California and I believe it was December
and I believe it was in December 1992
and this weed was indoor weed from
from Minnesota I believe Minneapolis or
St Paul area
this stuff looked like someone had taken
sugar water and sprayed it on it and let
it die it looked like rock candy you
know and it was almost fake looking the
buds were kind of sparse they were
definitely like coated in this like
glassy like trichome but it was just
oozing with resin you know and the jars
were all eighths mason jars that were
sealed somehow don't know how they would
have done that you know like when you
open it your the pop you know like like
a like a canned jar and that stuff
stands out my memory don't know what it
was don't know what the strain was it
was just backstage butt and then someone
I knew my little buddy little Mike uh he
found he's rest in peace he's not with
us anymore but he had a knack for
networking that I've never seen anywhere
in my life uh to this day and he somehow
came across you know a box of these
eights and Mason jars and he you know
this is the backstage but we didn't
question that it was phenomenal and it
was amazing you know it was so good so
that always will stick out my head and
that's a long time ago that's 1992. you
know it's a lot so I would say you know
that that memory's endured you know
brilliant what a great story so next one
if I'm gonna drop you off on a desert
island and you can only take three
strains with you to grow for the rest of
Community what three are you taking
Kim dog
I think yeah Kim Dong I don't know man
Sour Diesel
and something different you make me pick
three
um tits a selection I like that I like
that
what sort of changes do you think I
needed to help keep the ogs in the
system and not being forced out
the ogs are not business people business
people and ogs as you say they're very
different animals so I would say like to
the death protect the home grow to the
deaf you know like increase the numbers
allowed like how many tomato plants am I
allowed to have endless so why would
cannabis bees different you know and
right now in the United States the
biggest problem I see right now is the
federal government is gearing up for
National legalization how are they doing
that right now what they're doing is
they're they're preemptively creating a
regulatory system that's going to affect
us all as National legalization comes oh
who did the federal government ask they
asked liquor producers they ask beer
producers we all know that we that those
uh that industry feels falsely that
they're at odds with cannabis that
cannabis is direct competition you and I
both know we discussed it last night
over dinner that that's not the case
that cannabis and say wine
beer they go to hand in hand they're
actually complement each other you know
if I'm a beer you know if I'm away into
beer which I don't drink beer anymore
but if it was you know like I the same
kind of experience I'm having with craft
beers is the same kind of experience I'm
going to have with cannabis the people
who are making the rules they get it
wrong every time and now they're getting
ready to give it really wrong the
federal government has put together a
regulatory committee or whatever you
would call it and it's based on like the
the makers of Molson uh you know
Kentucky cheap bourbon and others and
it's mostly alcohol and it's to me I
think it's important that we don't just
stand by and say yeah cannabis is like
alcohol it's not like alcohol you know
and it's not it's it intoxicates you but
that's it that's as far as it goes on on
a on a public safety standpoint
so as far as like the way we view wine
and craft beers and and flavor that is
very much
um you know relating to cannabis and how
we we perceive it and experience it you
know but how could the federal
government understand that how could any
of these people who feel like they're in
direct competition you know people have
50 bucks this week to spend on their
Vice you know the liquor and alcohol
industry says we want all 50 bucks right
so if you put them in charge of
developing a regulatory system for
cannabis they're going to make sure they
get the 50 bucks over here still
what does that mean that means they're
going to like push us out you know the
ogs as you say it's already happened in
many states like California you know and
so like that would be the focus that
would be the place that we have to stop
and we can't do it after we have to do
it before because as we all know you
can't change what they already do you
can't go back it's so difficult it could
take decades Now's the Time Now's the
Time to get involved Now's the Time to
come out of the Shadows Now's the Time
to push back now is the time for us to
say what regulation for cannabis should
and shouldn't be we don't want no
regulation we all want a safe product
but I don't want Molson to tell us what
that safety is they don't know anything
about safety they've been their their
gig has been you know like safety got
circumvented around their industry their
industry is not safe I'd like to have a
nice little drink you know we all you
like wine I like wine you know and
others I like Urban you know I
appreciate good bourbon good Kentucky
bourbon and so like you know
it just doesn't translate the the liquor
industry the alcohol industry will say
their regulation doesn't translate to
cannabis now if you talk to a politician
to them it clearly does it's two vices
that people spend money on we're gonna
tax the [ __ ] out of it and we're going
to make money on it to them it makes
sense and I understand that and this
isn't like adversarial it's just they're
uneducated they don't understand
cannabis we do so Now's the Time if
you're a big cannabis producer out there
you know you know get off your [ __ ]
ass and stop counting your [ __ ] money
in your jet and get involved you're the
ones that are going to speak for me and
so since you're going to speak for me
make sure you speak clearly and
accurately for me I am an OG and there's
many of us out here if you want to do it
right you do it right but get involved
you know take your [ __ ] millions of
dollars you made off the legacies that
many of us produce and [ __ ] put it
where it belongs put it where your mouth
is and stop bullshitting and and make
get involved and I will get involved too
but I don't have that power I don't have
that that pull so you do do it you know
what I mean don't let it [ __ ] up yeah it
may work out for you you'll figure out a
way to work out for you but what about
the plan what about the culture what
about the rest of us you know get
involved because now is the time they're
already Congress the United States
Congress has already passed a bill to
allow the regulatory system to be
developed but the people the players
that they invited in they're the wrong
people they're not the right people
they're going to take it out of your
pocket they're going to take it from you
so be careful and and furthermore
protect the home grower don't feel
threatened by the Home grower I see a
lot of these big producers are pretty
adamant against the home grow it
disgusts me it makes me sick to my
stomach you don't get it if that's your
position if you are against the
homegrowner because you want to make
your little money off the eighth you
don't get it and you need to wake up and
you need to act right and you need to
like put your money where the culture is
this is not alcohol no one makes beer no
one makes beer or liquor at home for
consumption it's a hobby it's a niche
cannabis is different and that's the
main reasons why I think that's you know
maybe your point that the home grower is
the backbone of cannabis
why because the home grower has learned
you know what you learn from growing
cannabis is one of the most important
lessons you can learn you can be
self-reliant you can be self-sufficient
you don't need everything that you can
buy you can actually produce some of the
things that you consume cannabis would
be at the top of the lesson list and
when you when you discover that you can
you know when you fall in love with
canvas it's at the top of the list of
things you love it's not like yeah I'm
okay with it you know no you're you love
it you know if you don't love it okay
but when you do love it you become
passionate about it when you grow your
own cannabis it opens up a door that you
never had open like you can be
passionate about so many things that you
consume that you can't produce yourself
you know at home for you and your family
I don't give a [ __ ] if it's San Pedro
you know I don't give a [ __ ] if it's
Tomatoes kale whatever it is you find
you discover through canvas just like I
did that you can be in control and
empowered by what you consume and
producing yourself so that should always
be the focus without that there's no
real legalization you know
so for the final question we're gonna
Jazz it up a bit here I want you to give
me a quick summary of what a day in the
life of skunk VA would be in 10 years
time if everything goes to plan do you
wake up in a in Malibu with a jacuzzi
out front like what what's a day for you
in 10 years time if everything goes well
hmm
geez I don't know man that's a long time
from now you know I'm glad you didn't
ask what my day like is today because
nobody wants to hear about that but uh I
would say you know what I talked about
like see you know pulling off some of
these goals like being like it you know
how would I say reintroducing injecting
into the Cannabis culture of the old
school you know how did this start never
letting the user the grower the big
producer forget where did all this come
from how did we get to this point
um and I think that like the clean you
know keeping dedicated to the uh further
you know furthering of the plant itself
whether it be cleaning it from pathogens
whether it be creating new practices for
people to avoid pressure from pathogens
and stuff like that I think that's good
work you know and I I'm happy with that
you know
um I would like to be
you know part of that movement you know
and I'm I am going to be part of that
movement but I would like it to be
successful like that and then of course
what I said about when the United States
goes National legalization it's one of
the biggest things that's going to
happen on Earth you know imagine
cannabis producers in the United States
exporting cannabis to China you know
imagine a stressed out Society like
China you know
feelings from relief from their
day-to-day like we do with cannabis so
to me that would be it where I'll be
Malibu I don't know about all that you
know you know I've been to Malibu I I
don't it's not for me you know but I
mean
I certainly wouldn't want to have to
work as hard as I am in 10 years from
now I'm only 50 years old next year you
know so I feel like I worked you hard a
lot and that would be you know
personally that would be something that
I would want to go for the more kind of
feel like all right you know we we
fought the Battle and like we made some
progress and let's pass it on to the
next generation and let's hang out and
chill with our dogs and [ __ ] smoke a
fatty on the beach somewhere maybe on
the top of a mountain but as far as
cannabis and the culture goes I just
would like to re I think that it's being
the you know you say oh geez has kind of
gotten it's starting to feel like a
relic it's starting to feel like the
past it starts it needs to be
re-injected it's not fast we're out here
still we're still influencing we're
still working you know so that part I
would I would say I would want to be
part of that to re-inject that back into
the culture that hey you know young man
or woman this is where this all happened
this whole where it all came from this
is what had to happen for you to enjoy
this plant you know that's awesome to
hear that uh even in 10 years time
you're still serving the plant I love
that so that brings us just about to the
end of it for this one do you have any
comments or shout outs you want to throw
in the mix
nope
perfect well as always a huge thank you
for coming on the show except for you I
appreciate you you know I really do
you're one of us you perpetuate the
culture you perpetuate the facts the
realness of it it's so easy for for the
big players to gloss over some of the
things that happen maybe they don't even
notice maybe it never occurred to them
and you keep alive and we all appreciate
you for it oh you're too kind it's super
cool anyway that brings us to the ends
of it thanks so much again thank you
appreciate you
so what do you think guys absolutely
incredible one in my opinion we're so
incredibly grateful for skunk VA taking
the time to chat to us yet again sharing
all of his insights and experiences as
he said so many times this is his life
as always we're hugely appreciative of
both you and our sponsors seats here now
best seed banks in the game all the
hottest breeders go get some lucky dog
seeds right now from seeds here now
likewise go check out Copa biological
systems get yourself some appy param or
some spider spiral trust me release
these before you have a problem and you
can avoid the tears and heartache of
pest and Predator infestation trust me
guys you've got to stay on top of this
one
likewise a huge shout out to our friends
at Pulse sensors you know them you love
them a single tent a single room a
multi-state operation they're all using
pulse sensors if you don't have one get
serious guys get a pulse increase yields
resin flavor everything you want check
them out
likewise huge shout out to the patreon
gang we love you they heard this one
hella early if you're just listening to
this live now in the general public just
know when multiple episodes in the
future they've listened to it they're
talking about it you've probably seen it
on Instagram and you're like I haven't
heard that one yet that's right gotta go
join the patreon
www.patreon.com the podcast
that'll do it for this one friends
[Music]
this is Heavy D
ude signing off from the upside down
Library
[Music]