[Music]
welcome back to another episode of the
podcast a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts as always you're joined by
your boy heavy days from the upside down
Library
we want to give a massive shout out to
all of our incredible sponsors who help
ensure the show continues to happen
seeds here now number one seed bank in
the industry all the hottest breeders
the latest drops everything you can look
for and more whether you're after indoor
outdoor feminized regular autoflow
they've got everything under the sun to
keep you loaded on all the hottest
genetics producing the most fire Bud
you've ever had I hear they've got some
incredible lines from heavy days is
still in stock if you want to go check
that out make sure to do it before it's
too
late big shout out to ctnl we appreciate
you so
much as usual a massive massive thank
you and shout out to our good friends at
copit biological if you want to harvest
the best crop to date you have to ensure
your garden is pest and pathogen free
pumping on all cylinders if you're
battling spidermite check out the
incredible spyx red likewise I know a
lot of you guys are battling apids at
the moment check out their AIP parm this
is another product I absolutely stand
behind from copit if you want to get rid
of apids get rid of spidermites check
out the apip parm check out the spidex
red big shout out to copit biological
thank you so much we appreciate your
ongoing
support the final piece of the puzzle to
ensure that your room is killing it is
our good friends at Pulse their sensors
are second to none industry-leading and
just recently they announced the pulse
Hub what more could you want an
integrated unit for all of your sensors
to ensure that your garden is automated
and tracking all of the variables you
may not be consciously aware of from VPD
to ppf Duo temperature humidity so much
more you've got to get yourself a pulse
sensor guys it has revolutionized the
way I grow flour and increased the tping
content the cannaboid content the yield
Soo so much more shout out as always to
our friends at Pulse sensors likewise if
any of you you guys have been listening
to the show you know that I am
passionate about helping people
transition to vaporized options if
they're considerate about their
respiratory health and for me dap are
the world leaders in this dap helped me
to transition from bongs to vaping and I
tell you what I've never looked back
their unit is the most potent the most
highly replicating of a bong hit I've
ever come across and through their
incredible munit I was able to
successfully get off bongs a few years
ago now truly one of of the most
Innovative and interesting Vapes on the
market using a totally different design
to others you have found check these
guys out you will not be disappointed
massive shout out to dnat thank you so
much and last but not least we want to
give a massive shout out to the
incredible patreon gang without you guys
we could not continue to make episodes
if you want to get early access to
upcoming episodes exclusive content just
on the patreon including the likes of
mean Jean Bob hmill Bodie Tricom jungle
so much more be sure to go check out our
patreon we give away genetics every
month to our supporters along with
artwork Vapes sensors so much more
please check out the patreon guys I
promise you you won't regret it you'll
get your money back in swag for helping
support us show you love thank you so
much to everyone from the
patreon yo yo yo welcome back for
another episode
you know what you came
for the extra part three we
recorded I really dig this part guys I
think you're going to absolutely love it
super upbeat and
fun big shout out to Bod for coming and
recording the part
three without further
delay let's get into
it all righty gang we're back for a
special extra third part for this
incredible episode with our good friend
bod you might notice our voices are a
little different we've fast forwarded a
little bit into the future I guess my
first question my friend to follow up on
it uh in in the first installment of the
interview you mentioned that um you know
that weekend coming you were looking to
jump back on the plant medicines uh has
that has that happened since then what
was that like if so you know what I I
would love to say yes yes but life is so
complex these days and there's so much
going on we've had these we're having
this bomb cyclone and so I've been doing
a lot of Winter Rising I also have this
these two bags of substrate that just
won't colonize so that's also kind of
putting things on the back burner um so
yeah you know I I have been I have
started smoking cannabis in small
amounts and it's been a really I can
it's like a deep old friend like hey you
know it's it's going to be okay it's
cool so I've done that but I haven't
jumped fully in so um we have a little
yurt up top that it's been kind of too
hot this summer and if I can manage to
pull up a wood stove or something I
think that's going to be like the the
kind of ceremonial uh Command Center and
so I'll haul up all my sacred items and
I already have some uh Indian rugs up
there and I think that's put in some
cool lights and I think that's going to
be the place where it all goes down but
not yet right now real world stuff like
balm Cyclones and weather is taking up
the time I think we can give you a pass
given given you have been keeping
yourself busy and Hey look it's cool to
hear you're you're dabbling in it all
yeah yeah I'm back right it's good to
have you back my friend we can uh we can
always use you on uh on our on our team
oh thanks I uh I got to give a quick
shout out I'm actually for the first
time in a very long time enjoying some
Chernobyl I was thinking of Monty today
it's um it's it's every now and again
someone will message me and they'll
remind me that like quite a few people
from our community have sort of passed
away in the past 5 years like it's it's
um it's it's easy to think we'll all be
here forever but sadly um you know
Monty's no longer with us which is a
real bummer cuz I think more and more
people are looking back and realizing he
just made such phenomenal work yeah what
a character too like he was such the he
was such a you know he's so driven he
was such a force and he could be a real
knucklehead sometimes but you had to
love the guy like just for the sheer um
output all those like you know the weed
nerd and uh he was yeah he was such a
unique and Wild guy and you you kind of
you don't really realize what you have
until you until they're gone you know
it's like yeah yeah I like subcool he
was funny and you know some of the very
first strains that
uh that I saved up money to get on uh
was it Heaven staircase and of course I
saved up $500 it took me forever and I
put a order into to Heaven staircase and
I think I was getting double PE judge I
was getting all these really cool land
races and I got a couple C Chiba strains
and it all went down about a week and a
half after I sent it in and I was just
like okay my money order sitting right
on the table so yeah I mean some of my
first strains that I bought and lost
were were his and yeah you know at breed
Bay we we shared you for a while he was
predominantly on breed Bay so we shared
space on breed Bay and we'd be
diametrically opposed sometimes on
things but I have a massive subcool
collection believe it or not because a
lot of times I wouldn't get paid I would
ask for trade so at some point I don't
really you know I've grown up some of
the older ones but I have so many so I
might get those out to the or throw
those into an auction or do something
with them because yeah they need to live
on he there was you know I mean Miss
Jill's still around and she's still a a
driving force and yeah what a what a
great story someone should do like a
mini like a documentary or
something you know some cool because
yeah he was like a sacred clown like a
hyoka like there was magic to him you
know even if sometimes he he did some
really cooky things and and you know got
uh rubbed people the wrong way but you
have to love someone that's just so
dynamic in their s and so passionate
about what they
do yeah totally and when I think back I
I might be mistaken but I'm I'm almost
certain like the weed nerd sort of
franchise you know cuz there was lots of
different parts to it uh was sort of my
introduction to cannabis so always got
to give a shout out and and definitely
he was the guy him and the Rev you know
the two dudes who sort of inspired me to
to go organic so heck even if I didn't
like his genetics which I do like him uh
you know he helped me to go organic
which gosh that's got to be one of the
biggest game changers and he kind of got
really people into the Super SL and you
know if he was around today he was like
Flavor driven and like hype driven and
way before everyone kind of caught on to
that you know there wasn't a lot of
people that were always you know back
way back it was in the old days it was
all about yield and strength and you TPS
kind of came a little bit later or you
know turps are great but he was really
the one that was pushing these Really T
forward sometimes to a deficit but
always like super flavorful and unique
kind of like especially like on the the
fruits and
tropical uh you know flavors and
stuff yeah definitely I I I've said it
before but I think that there's a good
argument to be made that space dude is
the most proven male in existence so to
speak you know there have been other
Killers throughout history I'm sure some
of the ones that Neville and Sam picked
over the years were up there but in
terms of something we still
have yeah yeah is it still it might be
still around too I know think Jill still
does she still use it and there's even
like controversy on actually what it is
yeah so interestingly Caleb's got it and
he's doing a bit of work with Miss Jill
on that cool um and when I asked sub
about that you know I said look when you
sent it to fos it said it was like a c99
back cross like space queen Cross c99 or
something like that I can't remember but
in the episode I I'm sure I had the
right
Intel but um he just said that that was
that was like someone had just sent in
like a mislabeled cutting or something
so he he sort of brushed it off but it's
interesting because I I have I have
spoke to a few people over the years who
had ran the Remake from Brothers grim
and said you know I didn't really get
anything out like space dude wow yeah it
yeah it's it's you know what a good
story always has to have a good
mysterious ending yeah well look to me I
I love space dude that that mango to
penelene sort of thing it uh it really
does it for me some people describe it
as more limey but I you know it's it's
the exact profile of the Chernobyl I'm
enjoying right now yeah and the Jack
cleaner's still around too you know I
have a lot of weird ones like you know I
have like Bubba something I have like
these old old like kind of one-off uh
subcool stuff that I've always been
interested I still have Danny boy that's
the one that I might still pop oh wow
that's meant to be like the cult one
right yeah that's the one that he always
thought was like one of his best works
so that's in the fridge for a rainy day
wow that's cool hey on that topic did
you ever do anything with any of those
old Neville
cuttings um like the A5 and the C5 or
which ones yeah any of them I know that
there was a
few yeah you know um I got a few to try
the only ones I ever really used were
the A5 and the C5 and I did
like what did I do I did like an A1 C5 I
did a lot of like kind of more like old
school crosses and not huge amounts just
like the small little bags um but you
know what I I'd a friend who got some of
Neville's last seeds that he gave out to
all of his friends before he passed and
even though there's not a lot of
information on them there's like six of
them I get a little bit here and there
it's kind of like it was like his pardon
gift I believe to his friends and I have
those so those are going to be
interesting and I still have some of
those ones that I got on breed Bay with
credit when you know when he came back
and he did like super cush and he did
stuff with contiva and he he put out
some some L you know he put out a fair
amount of lines and then he kind of went
back Into Obscurity again or just
basically I think he was working with
the Australian medical scene I don't
think he could be connected so much
anymore but there's still a lot of his
work that is kind of always it's like
that Pandora's box or the treasure box
there seems to be always more stuff
coming out you know that's interesting I
mean kind of on that topic one of the
really common questions that popped up
on the patreon and one that I wanted to
ask is on your Instagram there's been
some really nice photos of uh various
hybrids of the sort of more raw stock
that I think a lot of it came from uh
Jade necta
Farms oh yeah Jeff Farm yeah yeah
everyone was Keen can you tell us a
little bit more about sort of what you
found and and what went along with that
you know it's it's it's kind of like a
cannabis botanical garden and he's in a
a spot way up in the mountains and I
don't know how he does it he's in the
Redwoods but he manages with his whole
team all organic just to create he just
collects all kinds of seeds from all
over the world every year and he just
puts them out he has ones that he uses
specifically for his like uh his uh
olive oil um you know extracts of
cannabis which are pretty pretty amazing
but yeah just stuff that he gets and
some of it is sometimes uh I wonder if
it's pure and sometimes you're like oh
God yeah like there was a caloa this
time that I saw I think I'll probably
post a picture of that I I last time I
went this year I didn't really take
pictures because I got there kind of
late and the light was feeding but this
Calo is definitely not a hybrid like
this thing is raw like and you know with
Mexican
varieties there's a lot of cartel
influence and there's a lot of I think
at this point a lot of hybridization but
there's still these amazing plans and
like I think I said before it's like
really a lot of these incredible lines
aren't going to come from point of
origin anymore they're going to come out
of like like I said your grandpa's stash
or uh crazy old Uncle Larry or you know
or little pockets it um people that you
know maybe that have family back in
Mexico oh my grandpa used that he still
grows out in his garden you know it's
like these finding larger grows of these
ants more ants cestal or like
heirloom accessions are getting so
difficult at point of origin unless
they're places like Afghanistan or
places that have kind of a firewall of
war or Strife but really it's like some
of the best old school lines are coming
out of collections they're not coming
out of current stock you know even if
you go like me and stray and uh and doc
d we went to Waka and we did a whole
tour and we were getting I think it's
back somewhere on my Instagram but you
can see all of the different lines and
such amazing ones purple ones green ones
smoke you know very up electric but they
seem to be morphologically a little bit
too not broadleaf but hybrid that it
seems like maybe at some point they were
um worked with but you know still
there's always those ones that pop up
you know wherever you are and I think
the higher you go like maybe in the
Sierra mzka like up higher towards p
it seems like the lines are a little bit
more safe but down by the coast with all
the surfing and stuff you you know you
can get it but although actually I'm
going to have to uh eat crow and shink
my own ship when I was in mazun in
ziplite a long time ago I got some stuff
in mazun that was absolutely incredible
and it was fully just there was no way
it had any kind of hybridization it was
just Spears and the thinnest of leaves
and just the most excelsor like high
like and then you know in zipolite I got
the zip and it had it was similar but I
I don't know I mean maybe it just
climatized it was still pretty narrow
Leaf but that mazun like you could you
just saw it and you're like oh gosh this
looks like right out of a time machine
so um back to circling back around to
Jeff's Garden yeah in such an incredible
garden and like he does a a shade garden
in in hogga culture that's really cool
and it finishes out he um he's highing
up he doesn't get a lot of bugs but yeah
he has an incredible YouTube channel too
where he bu he shows them all and bio
essays them and there's some insane
plants you know Rob and Mojave show up
every year and check it out
um let's see he had this amazing
Filipino I think we called them like uh
Purple Dragon Tales which is the most
amazing Buds and like just so you could
tell there they were just straight out
of uh Jurassic Park like straight out of
um Filipino nature
Compton like you know just just a
beautiful beautiful Fox tailing and just
the most epic purple with these kind of
like I don't know like pepperish Berry
and just the most floaty like dreamy
effect almost a little bit like napali
but not but without the the
drive so yes big vote for J nectar's
amazing uh farm and he hopes to someday
kind of create a sanctuary where are
kind of like a place where people can
come and like check out the plants
growing and get to sample them and have
a whole kind of experience and I think
that's really cool I think that the
world deserves that you
know 100% it sounds like the he version
of the Tyson cannabis
Ranch yeah I'm pretty sure that's what
his original pitch was you know like
come hang out H some weed see what it's
about but it's like this is the real
deal oh my gosh I mean UCSC what I was
at they were I was they wanted to do
like a Botanical cannabis botanical
garden and they were talking about it
but it was so long ago I don't know if
it's going to really happen and you know
there are big massive um UC or like a
university system grows but they're just
field like just they just PL it's just I
don't know the terminology it's like
field sample or whatever where they just
let everything go and it'll just be all
their sections but it'll be males
females and they're just just letting it
all fly and then checking it out from
there so things are happening you know
and it seems like with Thailand too um
you're getting a lot of hype stuff and a
lot of stuff that's you know potentially
airborne and dangerous for hybridization
but there's also a lot of farmers that
are bringing their best old school stuff
and there's even um people that are
involved in it you know like there zomia
and I heard that maybe deepo is going to
help out I heard that um you know
there's like a that amazing lady what is
it her name Prem Prem she's this uh
woman that's a big Advocate and
supporter of all the like uh old school
like Backwoods farmers and bringing out
like old squirrel taals and tie sticks
and really trying to uh Champion the
heirloom Heritage of like southeast Asia
so it I think we have a a bright future
if we can just take it back roots and
everybody just um you know just find
your own personal relationship with can
and support the people that are doing
that and I mean it's the same thing with
um uh I was going to say with growing it
it's like you know everybody should be
growing it don't rely on the government
don't rely on the uh uh the dispensaries
I mean I know it's amazing and we all L
dispensaries because it's so fun it's
cool it's like a candy shop and they
definitely have a place but if you can
grow it and if you don't Maybe find
someone that does a friend or a farmer
or something maybe if we can get farmers
markets it would be so nice to have it
Go Grassroots so we can kind of support
things from the ground up and you know
there'll always be a place for a big big
egg and and and dispensaries because
it's always nice for the kids to find
the ZaZa and find the things and it's
like 31 Flavors you know it's it's its
own kind of like it's its own experience
in of itself so I don't know I just
encourage people maybe before they give
their power away to all these places
they always say the Cannabis is the
gateway drug not only to the
refrigerator but to gardening and you
know I know people that started growing
cannabis and now they grow tomatoes they
grow peppers like it just never stops
like it's once you realize you can work
with nature you know on a heart level
and especially with you know
non-hybridized heirloom stuff there's
like a a whole world it's so nourishing
it's so like it's the best antistress
oxygen rich like environment that you
can put put yourself into and you know
my hope one day too is all those little
ladies out of the gardens throw some you
know feminized autof flowers of CBD rich
like anti-inflammatory things and just
next time you Grandma makes pasta throw
it in to the big pasta bowl and just
have the
anti-inflammatory pasta party or even
like you know like um thca like who
needs to who needs to process it with
heat you know just eat it make like
chichin Chong that that was that one
movie like this is it was a restaurant
he's like any the waiter brought out
he's like a fine California bud leaf
salad you know with it's like get
creative it's like this is this is it
this is one of the coolest things you
can do on Earth and it's our Birthright
and no one can tell you what you can or
can do with it and that's why I always
you know I got get down I guess a little
bit on science but science is a tool and
cannabis is a like spiritual technology
that is inhabiting a you know a plan
body just like we're a spiritual uh
entity having a human experience like
there's a connection there and no matter
what science does finding these markers
and finding all these things and doing
all their stuff like that's beautiful
and amazing for farming molecules and
for tracking things but the real magic
is when you inhale and especially if
you're creating what you inhale or your
friends or things or the Creations that
you've done there's a special connection
that from your heart to the plant and
even epigenetics you know people don't
talk about epigenetics enough about
creating seeds and creating strains and
what the inputs are Beyond just but you
know just beyond foods and light but
also music vibration crystals you how
you feel around them like what you do
like you're processing curing you know
pyramids like there's so blue glass myON
glass you know there's so many inputs
that are Beyond just growing you know
and the true input really is yourself
and your heart into this system so yeah
I just encourage everybody I don't mean
to get down in science and people will
be like oh well skunk one was you know
that was scientific reading that's
natural science that's beautiful that's
mandelian breeding that's a person
that's so passionate and dedicated to
cannabis that they took this plant that
they found and just grew it and grew it
and grew it through the years without
doing huge field things and they came up
with something truly remarkable and
that's their legacy like and that's
that's still Natural Science that's you
know it's I worry about bringing in
anything you have to plug in like you
got to plug in your computer you got to
plug in your phone anything you plug in
I don't know if you need that in
cannabis breeding what you need to do is
plug yourself into it that that's a
that's a brilliant answer and and I I
agree for for a number of years I used
to take great joy in what I considered
to be producing relatively high quality
Harvest
with what gear that people would laugh
at me for having you know and I I sort
of took a certain sense of pride in that
and and and as you alluded to you know
that old saying the plant's best
fertilizer is the gardener Shadow it it
pays dividends to spend time with your
plants you know and I talked to my
friends about that you know whether you
feel it in like a connection sort of way
or just in a practic cool way I promise
you the more time you spend with your
plans your garden will flourish for it
and in that answer you mentioned that
you're not beating up on science and I
think everyone who knows you knows that
you're not that sort of guy anyway but
on that topic you also mentioned taking
it back to the roots take me back to
your roots with uh University you were
mentioning that earlier that it'd be
good to see um universities get involved
I want I want people to hear a bit about
your roots your experience at University
and a bit more about your backstory I I
think it'll help paint a better picture
of sort of how you came to be the Epic B
that we know
today yeah this strange and
fascinating uh creature that I am um I
don't know I mean I kind of goes all the
way back
to to when I was you know my mom and my
dad split up um they're hippies kind of
and I split up when I was one so I was
raised by my mom and grandmothers and so
I always had like this deep kind of
feminine influence and my mom was like a
really big green thumb she had so many
plants around the house so I always grew
up around plants and as I got older and
older I really got into like different I
was really into like different foods and
like just the world besides where I live
just really fascinated me we have this
place called CPL it's like this World
Market that has like stuff from all over
the world and I remember my favorite
thing to do was my mom would be like oh
we're going to go to cos plus to get
something do you want to go and I'd be
like I'd be so down she would just let
me loose in that place and I would check
out all the candies I would check out
this I would go all around that store
and that was kind of like my way to to
experience the planet and you know as I
got older and older in high school I you
know I got kind of influenced by
um like classic rock and 60s Punk and
then you know the Grateful Dead I went
to my first Grateful Dead show I think
like in ' 85 I had a bus pass so my mom
was you know back then you could get
away a lot um it wasn't as dangerous
like kid on the bus you know who was 15
or 14 13 wasn't a big deal so my mom got
me a bus pass and the things I love to
do was I would look around at the towns
near me and the bus routes and my two
big things were to do would be to find
new like libraries like college or
university libraries and also record
stores because I loved music and I would
collect music and Records so you know I
would take my bus pass and I would go
and I would look go usually would go to
like I would go to UC Irvine or I'd go
to UC Long Beach I find these places I
knew had things and I would find the
books that I always would want to read
so i' look at what rare like I was super
influenced by um you know like the world
culture and especially different
religions and uh and so-called like
primitive religions I was super into
just different ways of perceiving
reality through the lens of like of of
environment and uh and so you know I
look up books on ethnobotany and magic
and Witchcraft oh and to go back I think
the pivotal moment I probably said this
before is I think one of the pivotal
moments in who I became as a human was
my mom had a really cool groovy um
boyfriend when I was like five or six
and he had this
um amazing bookshelf with all these cool
books and he was so groovy and he
actually had a health food store with my
mom called good enough's natural food um
and and he had this kind of Encyclopedia
britanica called man myth and magic and
it was like 20 volumes of just every
imaginable cool weird thing about magic
and man and um you know the col and
Witchcraft Alchemy um plant Sciences
like everything you could ever imagine I
would just go to his house I would just
sit there and read those and I actually
a couple years ago I picked up a full
set just to have because it was such
this amazing thing and I really think
that kind of opened me up to these
extreme possibilities on Earth and so
but I'll loop back around so you know as
in high school I got really into
psychelic and especially mushrooms uh
was one of my really favorite things to
do I think going to the Grateful Dead
one of the best things for us uh besides
the music and comaraderie and you could
still Camp back then was the abundance
of plant medicines you know and I I
would always go and pick up my goodies
for the until the next tour and and uh
you know so there was that and also uh I
got really into eventually into other
kinds of plants so I had the of the
Jungle cataloges I would go I would also
have the Church of the tree of life
cataloges you know all the stuff where
you kind of underground stuff where you
could get um all these amazing plants
and I started to experience with other
plants you know and I've never really
got so much in the Cannabis I kind of
thought it was a little bit like a
peasantry in a way like I was always
finding new weird plants like vong
or like you know I search out these new
experiences and I just got so into it
and then eventually um when I got uh I
don't know if I got my car or I was
still on my bus pass but I started going
to like teren mechanic conferences and
going to different meetups and meeting
people and uh talks and then I became
the youngest member of the Albert
Hoffman Society believe it or not I
think I was still only 17 and I used to
go to all other things I don't think
they're around anymore but I got to see
a lot of people like Jonathan a and I
think I saw Christian ratch and all
these different really cool psychedelic
kind of ethnobotanist people and then as
I got older and older I'm like I was so
driven and I really wanted to be an
ethnobotanist kind of like Richard Evans
schulties or like Timothy Plowman or
like you know all these guys way Davis
Mark plin all these really cool Roots
like uh no botus but like more on a
religious tip like really trying to
figure out what plants they use to
connect to the Divine or to their
ancestors and so I got really jazzed
that me and my friend were going to move
up to Santa Cruz I was going to go to
UCSC and do uh ethnobotany and somehow
he got in and I didn't I think he got in
because he he was part Guatemalan which
was Co but and I was a bum that I didn't
get in but it actually sent me on a
whole another trajectory where I got
really involved with the underground
like music scene um you know before I
moved up I had a smart bar in in LA in
San Diego called tribal liquid where I
used I made all these herbal concoctions
and I would sell them at
Raves um back in like 89 to 91 and that
was kind of my uh thing and so I got to
do that and then when I moved up you I
went to school I just kind of sunk back
into that and he used to go to free
outdoor parties and I realized I have
this amazing record collection like and
I saw people DJing I'm like why can't I
do that you know and so that's when I
started getting into d DJing and that
was kind of back when there it was
pre-trip hop it was more like acid JZ so
what we were doing is we were taking we
were we had this group called spaceship
guia which was a three of us and we were
really pushing the genres we would get
like um hip-hop instrumentals and then
also like drum and bass records and we
pitch down the drum and bass records to
33 and then and then play like real
world like Peter Gabriel like um you
know he had this label that had all
these kind of world music so we would
drop like fullon ragas and different
stuff over really fat beats and
baselines and that was kind of like
pre-trip po we got known for that and
then we just started having our own
group and we started a magazine and then
we were doing three outdoor parties and
we I did that Forever Until I you know
and then I got started playing in San
Francisco and then I started playing in
Canada I think I played at Shambala a
couple times on almost every stage they
had there and that was kind of my life
and then you know going through that
going through that and finally I'm like
I I still want to be an noobist so I
went to Community College and they had a
thing where if you go to the local
College they'll get you right into UCSC
so I eventually got into UCSC and
realized right away that ethnobotany
really there was just too much science
like I just couldn't do it I was like an
artist I just really I had a different
mind so I got into uh religious
anthropology with an emphasis on plants
and culture and I was able in that to
have a really cool teacher who um try
lowkey Pandy and he really allowed me to
just take it wherever I wanted and for
two semesters I got to do my own
semesters abroad one I did in um in the
Himalayas and I wanted to tie in like
sacred plant use and tantric science and
that that was just too hard of a nut to
crack so I just had fun in uh in the
Himalayas and kind of started you know
introduced to Himalayan hash which was a
total Revelation to me I think that's
where I really realized how amazing
cannabis could be you know I didn't
really always put the dots together you
know the very first dot I think it was
in a previous episode you know where
were you first turned on we got some
really good gona in B and I remember I
first really got the Cannabis hit when
we smoked at these temples in Guatemala
and I realized that just opened up a
completely different portal to reality
like like I saying before like that
natur Nature's Wi-Fi like the spiritual
internet and that's where I really tuned
in but smoking Himalayan hash was truly
one of like that that if anyone gets a
chance to get up into Himalayas like
it's just there's nothing like Himalayan
handrub like it's just so incredible so
to Circle back once again I keep on
Losing Myself um yeah the second uh
study abroad um I actually decided to do
my research thesis in the Amazon jungle
um and it was going to be the my whole
thesis was on the intersection
between the jungle and the cities like
that point right where the jungles and
cities touch and um MSO based iasa thing
where how in the context of iasa and
these
incredible um ancient systems how they
converge with these modern encroaching
cities like aidos and PPA I was
primarily in Peru and where this how the
ma these magical interfaces how the iasa
would morph and how they would blend
with these kind of like City or like
City jungle shamans would interact and
even how the jungle and the city went
undera and that was kind of my I also
did a little addendum on IAS tourism I
would have never known today like that
was 25 years ago how it's bloomed like I
would have never thought it so many iasa
centers would be going and how uh how
prolific it would be and how much it it
would spread out through Consciousness
so that that's a real eye opener these
days but you know I I went into the
jungle I was there for like five or six
weeks I went in the rainy season which I
realize now was probably the dumbest
thing I yeah no one ever goes in the
rainy season so it was quite an
adventure you know I had so many
incredible Adventures on boats and ships
and ship captains and you know we'd have
to go way way way in and meeting some of
these amazing amazing deep uh plant
people and you know and doing an
apprenticeship and realizing through
iasa that you know I always thought I'd
work blance but I always thought it was
going to be something else I never knew
it was I didn't never thought I was
going to be cannabis was going to be my
thing but you know I had this this
experience in after the IAS in a dream
where it was like the spirit of iasa
said you know I know you're here I know
you're initiating but iasa isn't your
plant your plant is back at home your
plan is waiting for you and so I didn't
put it two and two together until you
know
in the future when I started to really
get involved with cannabis and you know
primarily that involvement was also
through DJing and music the entire music
scene in the Bay Area was fueled by
cannabis everybody that was a DJ or an
artist or hit rapper and everything
everybody subsidized it and all these
free parties with ganja and you know I
was the guy that was you know making
bubble has so that that was my thing and
then as I met my previous partner who we
had kids with
um she was a grower and she
really uh was dialed into that and I met
a lot of amazing people through that a
lot of people that I know today and as
she stepped out of it when uh she was
pregnant I just dived in head first and
I just went berserk like I became a
freak like I just loved everything about
it and got into the seeds and did all
that and you know I and I never stopped
so I guess the I guess that swings us up
to date you know I made it out of the
Amazon alive um I got back I graduated I
realized that you can't really do much
with a religious anthropology degree
besides teach or do demographics so I
just I pivoted into really following my
passion and following what the plants
told me was my destiny and I I guess
that's kind of my background I'm sure I
missed a lot of stuff but that's it in a
nutshell wow I uh I always love hearing
that story and even even having heard
most of that before still some bits I uh
I I hadn't heard so that's that's
beautiful to get that backstory and I
it's it's it's perfect cuz it ties into
the next question which one of the
patron users submited but it's just a
cracker of a question in general and
they sort was saying look I'd be
interested to hear bod's thoughts on
when how who uh was involved in cannabis
first entering in to the Americas
particularly narrow Leaf drug types in
South America there's obviously a few
different theories was it European
explorers was it slave trade was it pre
poost Columbus uh a lot of theories out
there but because bod's work with so
many different nlds I'd be interested to
hear his
thoughts yeah I mean
I'm going to have to say there's
definitely a lot of information that
points to certain sources but there's
also a lot of things that we don't have
the ability to know like definitely I
think you had a lot of African narrow
Leaf drug types moving with the the
slaves you know and uh bringing it with
them and all these different places
throughout Brazil you know even Gana
like everywhere seems to have these
things and it was and equatorial place
they grew well they worked well they
were a Panacea I mean there's also some
of the theories that you know early in
the Americas uh there was these kind of
uh they call them like uh what is it
snake oil medicines patent medicines all
these kind of medicines that were people
were providing the early kind of
a uh drug store concoctions and they
were using like uh kind of
a these in uh import Indian stock there
you know and I heard that it was hard to
get the Cannabis over in ships without
it molding and eventually Park Davis and
a couple other people that were starting
to use it um realized that if they
brought seeds over and planted seeds
they would have a product that you know
was a lot quicker to ship it wasn't it
wouldn't it would be more prolific it
would be a lot more uh um you know money
uh it would be a lot less money to have
it within reach and from what I
understand I'm still looking for I'm
sure maybe like snow high or someone has
the documents but I heard that Park
Davis brought a lot of different strains
into
Mexico um and that a lot of these
Mexican strains are actually uh a
climatized
Indians
and
um uh from different uh not necessarily
Himalayan but I think a predominant
amount of the stuff produced was uh kind
of near um like a poon job and kind of
these drier Aid places uh where they
would Farm it you know and before that
up in the stands you also had like
shinjan and all these like places just
over the border that were producing
tremendous amounts of hashes so I I've
heard that a lot of these strains in
especially in just Mexico itself where
there wasn't a lot of uh slaves coming
in so much
um the populations were a lot of these
are escapees of maybe par Davis's stuff
and I'm sure there you know there was
slave ships I know in uh Guatemala
there's the garuna which are a really
unique uh section of people that were a
whole I think they were Yuba or they
were it was a uh it's a whole population
of uh African Guatemalans where a slave
ship crashed or hit rocks and they all
were kind of tossed out and a bunch of
them survived and they kind of Eder
breed with the Guatemalans and they have
a rich culture and I know in that area
um I saw a lot of
uh uh really unique narrow Leaf types
that were distinct from like Colombians
or the other Mexicans you know they were
under eradication at that point they
were trying to get it because it was
kind of a stronghold for growing but you
know I would
say Park you know Park Davis I would say
definitely Columbus even captains you
know they needed to grow stuff that they
could also make sales if they had to get
their butts out of these places that
they sailed you know you sale from
Europe or Spain you come all the way
here you maybe you lose a sale or two
you're going to need to grow your hemp
back sales but I've seen books too I
think there's a mark Merin book I don't
know where there's eyewitness accounts
in the Midwest of people seeing large
stands of hemp or cannabis and then we
have to you know then if you want to go
way back there's the you know the mummy
that they did the the um drug testing on
uh it was quite a controversy for a
while but they had a mummy from Egypt
and they thought hey let's just check it
let's test it for drugs and it this is
the mummy had like
cocaine uh nicotine cannabinoids it had
all these things showing up stuff that
they didn't really have in Egypt so I
think there's
definitely a time where there was a lot
more trade than we know about and I
think Columbus was probably one of the
last people to get here you know
especially with these OMC heads there's
there's such this ancient history that
now we're kind of starting to get an
inkling of and when we're starting to
open up these new sites like gockley
tley and all these Indonesian there's
definitely a high culture that existed
before our current understanding our
current Lich or maybe pre flood I but I
believe that the whole planet was turned
on in a way that there was a lot more
things going on but I think the stuff
that we see these days is definitely uh
diasporic like it came from
people coming from their cultures and
bringing their things similar to how uh
there's a big Indian population in
Jamaica and they brought a lot of their
strengths from India into Jamaica and a
lot of Jamaican strains are actually
climatized Indians so that's kind of my
just on it uh but you know we just don't
know enough you know and and time and
environment does amazing
things 100% I agree and you know what
When in Rome we've got another great
patreon question I'd love to hear bod's
thoughts on grahe Hancock Billy Carson
ancient civilizations extraterrestrials
all that good stuff I I'm down like I I
mean how do you you
control uh you know the society by
controlling history by controlling
information I think there's so much more
that's happened that's going on that
they people that it's very restricted
you know there's I think there's some
kind of system set up to keep a
narrative um so that we are less
empowered as humans and as people if
there was this high
high time that's not a good thing to let
out the population that were like this
this dumb kind of like uh uh leftover
Society uh that came out of a higher
Society you know like they're saying
that the at one point in Egypt a lot of
the knowledge was lost the people that
were living there really didn't have so
much of a clue they were just kind of
running off of older paradigms that
there was actually a higher time in
Egypt that a lot of these uh these you
know pyramids all these different things
uh uh ge ology all the you know
terraforming all these things were being
done at a level that we no longer have
the same in you know you have in South
America with the NASA lines and all
these pyramids there's
definitely there's there was a high
culture and it's pretty obvious to
people that want to dive into it that
you know there's so much more to history
that we don't know and there's so much
more to our story and there's so much
more to us you know we we're a product
of something so so complex and
magnificent and it until we kind of
realize that until we find these Clues
to kind of awaken us out of this kind of
collectic collective Slumber of
informational um servitude in prison
it's like we're not really going to be
able
to engage with the future because we can
really create what we want by learn you
know learning from the past to create a
better future and if our past is
controlled we're we're going to just be
doing the same old thing so yeah I I'm
down I'm I think Graham Haw Hancock is
right on uh Billy Carson yeah he's a
little more trippy and I love that
there's so many of these guys you know
you know what's funny is like on YouTube
um you can go around and check out
different things and I see some wild
stuff and I have to just suspend belief
I'm like I don't know this is the
strangest Planet I've ever been on I
have no clue what's going on they have
these like soccer moms who are who are
like channeling the ashtar command or
pleadians or like and you know it's like
you know come join our pleadian mother
circle you know there's so there's so
much wild stuff going on right now that
I'm not I can't say what's wrong and
what's right or even if this is
simulation and whatever you want to do
is what you do I say be who you want to
be and just dig get into whatever you're
into and just make this an
ecstatic uh
place of like loving compassion fun and
like you know make this the place where
people come from other systems to see
how we get it done like this you know
this is Earth we may have a spotty past
but we're getting we're getting things
sorted and we're we turned this place
back into the garden you know I think it
was the Garden at one point and through
bad choices and maybe people with
Messianic complexes you know I mean look
at the Aztecs they were jamming and then
they just started to do way too many
mushrooms and way too many sacrifices
and I think they tapped into like some
kind of denic kind of energy in the
Psychedelic space it's it's like it's
kind of like downtown Kingston or
something it's like there's loads of
cool people but there's also you got to
watch yourself there's a lot of things
they're willing to take you know for
take you for your money or take you for
as in a psychedelic situation I believe
that you know you have to navigate it
you have to be kind of this war of love
when you go in because there's a lot of
things going on I think with the Aztec
you know they think I think they lost
the pot I think they were tapping
into something that needed blood and it
instead of you know with ket quaddle I
think he eventually came about and he
decided to stop human sacrifice and they
sacrificed Flowers and Butterflies so
it's like on which side of History you
want to be you know so I mean that was a
little bit of a tangent but that's the
basic kind of my philosophy on it is
yeah there's a lot that that we don't
know and there's a lot that we can do so
let's do it completely I agree you know
the the past is the key to the Future
and and and the the golden line from in
there this is the strangest Planet I've
ever been on I have to agree for sure oh
but can I interject something I just
realized if people want to really have
fun did you ever see like the the um
Ancient Aliens but the Action Bronson
versions where they all get stoned and
watch Ancient Aliens and comment on it
like if you want to get like I I love
crazy stuff like that but when you just
throw super stoned guys into the mix
like that is a classic experience I
don't know if you've ever seen that but
I thought that was one of the funniest
things ever oh my God it's on the list
now I haven't seen it yeah there's like
five or 10 episodes like they watch they
literally watch the best Ancient Aliens
in they commentary on it the whole time
or they're getting super
blazed all right I got something I can
watch in bed that's
good yeah I I love that I mean on that
theme at the end you were talking about
doing too many mushrooms if we scale it
back a bit one of the first questions I
asked you answered in saying you were
you were waiting for your medium to grow
some mushrooms I assume I wanted to ask
what are you growing cubensis anything
more exotic and what do you like doing
with the medicine I I I've actually gone
to the gym one time and it was uh it was
interesting it was fun I don't know if
I'd say do it every time yeah like when
the micro do accidentally is a macro do
you don't realize it pump and iron that
was exactly
it that's right you know I um in my past
I I grew a long long time ago mushrooms
and then you know it just when I was
doing cannabis it's like I had to you
know I there's things like I don't
really own guns I'm not like anti gun or
anything but there's certain things that
you shouldn't be doing when you're
growing a lot of ganja and that is
growing other psychedelics like back
then mushrooms was a big big no no you
know you shouldn't have firearms you
shouldn't have money counters those
things that as a peaceful plant person
you know pumping out a very sketchy crop
in an urban landscape you don't want to
do so I took a big long Hiatus until
covid and you know I was in an area
which it was sanctioned you know Santa
Cruz County you could mushrooms so you I
I had some friends in high places we
just did you
know I hadn't been exposed to some of
the mutants at that point so we were
getting into just like some of the newer
stuff like the albinos and some of the
mutants and now I think this next round
is just going to be I'm trying out kind
of like I did when I was young and
growing cannabis I'm trying out some of
the hot new strains you know I'm doing
like an albino Bluey Vuitton I'm doing
these like Snape like star
um uh what is it star night Apes like uh
some of the uh
shockd and couple of the like more
whatever land racy ones you know because
I used to also collect uh sport prints
you know I collect sport prints in the
terai of Nepal down in the jungles uh
you know in the late 80s early 90s we
did a whole um me and my uh friend Mike
did this whole Adventure where we
followed the foot steps of like our Gard
wasan we went up into the Sierra maitech
and looked for Salvia and we got to meet
the Sabinas and we did a lot of mushroom
work up there with different things like
I'm super into I love mushrooms I love
medicinal mushrooms I love everything
about them so you know I I don't know if
it's too cold up here or I'm just maybe
I got some
bad uh or just really slow culture but
yeah I'm waiting for my my spawn or
substrate to colonize so that I can
fruit it and it's been quite a while so
if if this doesn't work out I might just
re re uh colonized but what's going
right now I think that I'm waiting on is
I'm doing some albino tidal waves and
just some regular old stuff like some
Classics from the last year or two and
let's see what was the other one oh
albino Bluey
Vuitton wow that sounds a really cool
and also uh exotic I like it you got the
Zaza of mushrooms by the sounds of it
yeah it's not even so exotic it's like
we're not going into the Super Mutant
Zone which is what what FAS Fates me and
which kind of seems to be driving a lot
of the uh mushroom culture right now you
know how you know like there's like a
some amazing people that are doing this
like AP King Kong and all the people
like that are also kind of connected
into our community um so many people are
just really pushing this and you know
even the breeding there scientific
breeding and then there's people that
just mashing up stuff in test tubes
they're just praying they're getting a
new thing and then with uh fenos
selection is primarily driven you know
on output and potency and and uh um even
canopy and perfect fruits but there's a
whole genre that people just searching
for mutants and just the most amazing
thing things that look like lettuce
string cheese swiss cheese like brains
like that have incredible potency and
then you know and with that I think
there's a whole realm of uh of uh you
know people concentrate on psilocybon
and psilon and bosy and all these you
know General tryptamines but there's a I
think there's a lot of other tryptamines
in some of these varieties that they
haven't really measured for and that
gives them their kind of individual
effects and so it's just such a
fascinating fascinating world you know
I've also been getting
really back into Cactus I've always
really been into Cactus but now I never
really popped Cactus seeds because they
take forever so it's fun to Cactus but
it's like you got to start the year
before you know but you sprout so many
and then the next year you've got like
little
12 inch cactuses so I mean I just love
planting seeds have everything and yeah
I flip out when that Baker Creek Seed
Company catalog comes out you know with
all the hybrid strains and like I
especially like the ones they're getting
up from like they'll have a little
section with new African accessions like
Basils from Africa or I love when I was
in Santa Cruz I love the Japanese stuff
because all the little Japanese islands
are kind of like the same general
environment as Santa Cruz kind of hot in
the summer but kind of balm and a little
bit too humid but Coastal environment
with trees and getting all the weird
greens and eggplants like I just go nuts
I just love plants and I love seeds and
I just I don't even care if they finish
I just like to check them out like so
mushrooms spores same thing spores are
great they can they're one of the only
things that can can um go through space
travel like I learned that like you know
how cool is that that spores survive
space travel so you know I I had a whole
weird trip where I was like oh my gosh
what
if uh mushroom spores are terraforming
Technologies from The Source they're
just like blown out through uh SpaceTime
hitting you inhabitable planets and
seeding those planets because with you
know because they're these little mini
like starships that have the DNA of
fungus and then fungus is one of the
very first terraformers of these planets
I love I love your theory yeah I mean
I'm sure it's not my theory I'm sure
there many Trippers have done that I'm
sure Paul Stam are all these people it
it it it's pretty self-explanatory like
why would spores uh be able to move
through space flight and also you know
why not have something that quickens the
monkey mind you know and the whole
Terence McKenna the stoned ape like I
totally believe plants are the reason
why we are who we are and you know and
and and definitely
communication like I think the spirit
plants are what kind of taught us to
communicate and I even heard something
really crazy recently I don't know if
it's true but I heard that every before
this one famous Alchemist uh everybody
read books in their uh out loud no one
read books in their mind like everybody
who would read to would always read to
themselves so whether it was in their
room or to other people and it really
tripped us out I think it was like maybe
five or 6 hundred years ago there was a
certain Alchemist who could read in his
M like basically how we all do it just
read to ourselves and it really threw
everybody for a loop because they're
like What's this guy doing how does he
remember all this stuff and it was just
because he was reading his mine total
tangent but I just that popped in my
head because I thought it was so cool
and then people started to be like oh
wow you don't have to read with your
mouth you can read inside your head and
that set off a you know whole another
level P guy to do rooms yeah maybe he
did or maybe you know they used to do a
lot of uh hashish was a commodity that
moved through time and space a lot more
lucratively than we ever you know ever
thought like it had a it had a
trajectory of its own I think it you
know you of course we all know about the
silk route and how things traveled along
that but there was hashish getting into
Europe to The Alchemist and stuff and
actually all over you know the
Mediterranean everywhere quite early on
it was a coveted substance along with
you know opium and I'm sure many other
things that we just don't have a
historical record
of yeah totally I I mean all of that
stuff is so interesting like especially
all the the history of the Silk Road and
as you said the stuff we don't have the
history of is probably the most
interesting of it all but while we're on
the topic what are your thoughts on like
modern hash and and I guess like the
Rosen scene the the BHO and all the
variants where do you where do you feel
we're at with
that um I mean I think it's just coming
into its own it's incredible like with
this they even have like the Pella now
there's all these natural Technologies I
love rosing and them you know fresh
frozen and pressing out like people are
finding like it is it's a modernday
alchemical revolution you know in the
processing temperature like it's
basically people just getting to tweak
out as hard as they can to create the
most
you know the the most fabulous item like
the most you know everybody I think it's
like what a noble pursuit to create the
most fabulous like representation of the
plant it's Tricom head like its gift is
its head you know it's it's like here it
is here's here and people doing
everything they can I mean BHO was our
like kind of like a MacGyver level just
getting to know that hey we can do this
and then moving into like bubble has and
then and then two Frenchie bringing back
you know his whole bringing back the old
school ways you know and then there's so
much to learn from the old school if we
just apply it you know people are now
like you know a lot of cultures would
Harvest and hang into the winter so that
when they did their processing it was
super cold out they preserve heads you
know burying things like some of the
Afghan they would bury it in you know
like the stomach of a sheep or sheep
Skinner do these different processing
techniques and hand hand rubbing is a
big thing on its own and having kids
hand rub because they're such you know
delicate there's so many unique ways
that we're taking to this future but
this new current like uh Machinery meets
you know like pressing meets cing meets
you all these instraction Technologies
and then everybody getting so into it
and like you know things like the ego
clash and it's it's kind of funny that
it's always the same strain like
Skittles winning you think would be a
they people would be pushing it in uh
new directions with flavors but I think
it's kind of like everybody wants to win
and Skittles is always winning so why
you who wants to deviate from the winner
like you know it's like if you have a
winning hamster breed you don't want to
be breeding like a hairless hamster or
something thinking it's super cool do
that makes no sense but you know what
I'm saying is I think this new hash
Revolution Is Awesome same as the the
pipc con same as yeah just all these new
avenues that people are really finding
and finding their their path in it too I
say I say yeah Kudos gho you guys get
it yeah no totally totally I uh I'm all
aboard and I I'm interested to see what
it'll look like and so as a as a more
general question like where do you see
the Cannabis culture going in like 5 to
10 years what do you think the landscape
will look like will we will we still be
consuming
flour I mean if you it I think we'll
always be consuming flour
because there's a lot of people that are
just doing what they can to get by and
use cannabis just to make their end of
their day better to you know help with
those aches and pains to stay up and
stay anti- depressed and to uh to get
more into their music their Hobbies
their video games I think there's always
going to be flower because it's easy to
grow and you know people love flowers is
that um isn't
that uh Luther one of Luther birth Banks
like quote like nature laughs in flowers
like it's just this it's a special thing
and I think in 5 years I don't know I
guess it depends on legislation too or
how things open up and how creative
people can be I mean there's it can be
very dystopian with just fake TPS and
and U distillate and people mixing into
creepy carts and getting them out as
every flavor underground I mean there's
always going to be that it's easy it's
cheap I know kids like that you when we
were talking that's about the spray pack
that's I think what I would like to see
is just total freedom people can do is
people get into how they want to do it
and just come up with every imaginable
really cool thing and you know the best
toys always rise to the top you know
it's like people are going to make more
and more unique things and the more
novelty and uniqueness the more uh the
Public's going to want it and the more
it's going to bolster it and the more
it's going to kind of encourage that so
I I want to see a dystopian future I
want to see like a future that has like
infinite cannabis potentials and enough
potentials so that everybody has a way
to um provide for themselves but also
nourish themselves if they want to get
into cannabis and plants and stuff that
they can support themselves and their
family and find their Niche and find
their passion and create something
unique and new whether it's just making
really good bubble has from a really
special strain that maybe their family
has only had to some kind of wizard
level like Ros and Pella like um uh you
know 31 flavor swirl unit like just just
getting so uniquely amazing you know
static Tech
superhero I don't even know just people
going for it and that's what I really
want to see so I'm hoping not to see
pharmaceutical companies and big
growups uh just gross mids uh you know
massive company grow offs and People
Brewing up just to LIT um funky carts
that's not what I want to see I want to
see people following their heart and
Bliss and making this a really unique
thing and if that takes people like
giving the middle finger to government
big business and maybe deciding that
flower shouldn't be illegal and breaking
some laws then maybe it's time to break
some laws especially laws that are dumb
and have only been around since you know
the prohibition days it's like
this is really yeah it this is where I
just like especially like putting people
people in cages for growing or selling
flowers like where where did that like
who is involved in that that probably
one of the most insane myopic and dumb
things I've ever like can wrap my brain
around so no I want people to just
do do the impossible and do it from
their
heart yeah to totally totally I I agree
and it's interesting you mention that
because I I can't remember who it was I
think it was Ed Rosenthal um I I spoke
to him and I sort of said look you know
people have criticized some of the
things you've advocated for um L
legalization and he sort of said you
know look at the end of the day though
like the ultimate metric is like people
kept out of jail for cannabis and as
much as it's not great like you know you
it it's got to be the ultimate metric
and it's like yeah it is that is true
and on that topic you know I got two two
questions for you the first one is you
know you you spoke about moving forward
some of the listeners had taken a look
at some of the new lavender lemonade
lines or hybrids you you'd made and they
wanted to know firstly are there any
you're particularly excited for but as a
quick followup one of the listener says
look there's some cool looking new mums
in the mix that I hadn't really heard of
you know like chai and Frozen and lemons
and dessert lime can you tell us a
little bit about some of those mums and
are there any you're really Keen
about yeah like a lot of those ones are
ones that I got from um from Haze of
Valley like ones that they really liked
and really and they really dug and you
know and when I uh and when I didn't
have a grow and I was uh you know I made
and I needed help making seeds they you
know it's a long story but they were
made in a place that
well I won't get into it but they helped
um make a ra a round of seeds and like
uh they had so many unique cultivars to
choose from that I threw in some of
theirs as well as mine um because you
know I got to experience some of flower
and I like wow these are really neat
like I always love to see what people
are doing and what all the new neat
things because people are awesome and
cannabis is awesome and cool stuff gets
made and it's easy to like especially
when you're kind of hermetic like me to
really get a chance to see all these
things so I I threw in some of the ones
I liked you know and there's also a lot
of ones that were just stuff that I
never released like chai is actually a
um ass F3 that I just push the ass more
and more towards the kind of like
um the I think it was the Hell's Angels
and it uh you know there's a little bit
of Hell's Angels in the ass and I I like
to take a lot of my lines and push them
in different directions and kind of use
them as tools or have them for a rainy
day like I don't usually release them
because you know when you're doing uh
you're pushing lines and you're doing FG
you're usually kind of just doing them
for yourself and you're maybe you're
just pollinating a small plant or you're
pollinating a branch so um yeah the chai
is is part of that mandarin orange spice
uh line that was leased it's a lavender
lemonade and that is a a almost a plant
that was reminded me of kind of like the
white it was really creamy and just the
tiniest bit spicy but mostly just kind
of very very frosty and monotone but I
knew in a hybrid if you searched hard
enough that skunk stuff might come back
out because it's only like a cross away
from just you know popping its head back
in and I know in the mandin orang spice
you'll find once in a while you get a
really gross kind of like ass throwback
so you usually get kind of like this
hoppy orange peo te really beautiful
flowers really good producer really
thick um but once in a while you get a
stinker so that that's something to look
for and those yeah and then I I mean
that's the gist I'm trying to think of
some of the other ones I threw in and I
threw in some of my other like you know
I used to test out a lot of things at
home and so I would always find cool
stuff and maybe I didn't have any seeds
so much to release but I would keep them
around and you know I'd throw them in
and I thought that was kind of fun
because it wasn't a traditional breeding
uh kind of event where I would take a
you know a a medium size room and put in
all my favorites and just let one of my
St standards kind of just do its thing
like the ad3 or W or Appalachia snow
Lotus any of those bigger populations
there a lot of these new things are
either special things from other people
or they're kind of special things that I
collected over
time beautiful I I love that and look on
the topic of special things you've
collected over time one of our listeners
says that they were lucky enough to
score themselves a pack of the akapo
gold freebies and they uh they just
wanted to know a little bit backstory on
these ones yeah like I'm really bad um
I'm pretty positive um I always get
everybody especially back in the old
days everybody's handles and stuff I'm
almost positive that it was that was
from liquid kid sorry if it was from
some otherone and those came from his
mentor um what was his mentor's name
like Blackwolf or Dire Wolf it had a
really cool like old schoolers name I
I'm such I wish I wrote I'm somewhere I
have this all down but my memory is just
not what the way it used to be even a
year ago and it was his mentors that he
got in a Poco a long time ago and he'd
save for so long and then um I got him
from liquid and there was so cool that
um that I decided oh this is an awesome
line I'm going to do a Repro and try and
save this and it was actually a
gentleman that I knew that was such a
good guy he actually did I sent him to
him because he's like oh I've always
wanted an AAP old you know he saw that I
was growing him and and what is his name
oh my God he was a great guy and I sorry
everybody um but you're living on
through the strains here there's a story
to every strain and it's beautiful that
maybe I'll post it somewhere when I can
get all the information back but he
always wanted to go on aaok gold and I
was like you know I only have a few
seeds but if you if you do an open
pollination and you give me back a bunch
for the N project um you're welcome to
have these so he grew out a bunch bunch
and he did a great job he had he grew
him around his pool like in Southern
California and he did he had a I think a
couple males and he had about eight
females and he kept a bunch for himself
and he sent that me the rest and you
know one of the lines was slightly
hermaphroditic I still have those seeds
didn't put those into the mix and put
them into packs and gave out tons I
think and Nara I think sold some through
Nara um the Nara project but mostly just
gave them out and then yeah it's
beautiful to see people getting back
into him I know like Mass medical he did
he did a a Repro um and I think a few
other people so I mean that's that's
where I think a lot of these cool people
want these old school standards is find
the old Growers find the old people that
have had these lines forever because you
know it's a snapshot in time in time and
space environment that we don't really
have the opportunity to uh have anymore
you know it's like these these are
beautiful it's like a Polaroid of your
uh uh you know your an old family member
in OKO you know get to see them in their
teenage years all these things it's like
it's these are
amazing snapshots like these time
machines like and they're interactive
too it's like this is not only a seed
this is an interactive time machine for
uh a special time in history a special
geographic location history and
everything that came before like if you
dig if you go deep enough into these
strains like really open up to them and
just especially if you just get a Mega
Blaze going on and deep dive you can
follow these strains back into almost to
the back to their very origin and to you
know and you'll get these little
sometimes imprints of people and
cultures and maybe it's just tripping
out and having fun with your mind but
it's just as real as anything so yeah I
another once again I'm going Tangy on
just that but big UPS to all these
people that have brought these old seeds
into my life and especially AR World
cool cool strain so yeah that's the
backstory that's epic I hadn't heard any
of that so there you go that's uh dir
wolf okay never mind I'll shut up but it
it's not it's
something something like that but you
get the gist I get the gist I I I like
that story that's that's really cool and
and talking about older seeds you know
um another good question we got was in
your opinion you know do you think
cannabis was really that different in
the early '90s or is it you know a bit
of Nostalgia about all
varieties um I think it was both you
know I think we're getting a lot of
import back then and anything grown
point of origin that has the right Arc
of the Sun the right soil composition
the right all these parameters you know
these
strains kind of grew in these locations
and were tended by humans in these areas
for quite a long time and especially the
ones that were picking for drug types
you know a drug type selected over a 100
your Span in a certain location with
everything it needs to express itself to
its highest and that's getting imported
you know and a lot of these narrow Leafs
do better when they have time to age or
oppressed and they're coming into the
states and you're getting tie stick or
you're getting these different things
hell yeah it's a a totally different and
amazing experience it would be the same
thing as maybe going to Thailand now and
trying some kind of you know tie stick
or something at their point of origin I
really think there's something to
experiencing these heirloom and
so-called like land race Springs at
their point of origin because that's
where they truly shine we can try and
climatize them here and we get or we can
try and replicate indoor environments
that are like it and we can get pretty
close but we never really get the true
true like it's like you know in its
native um element you know and that's
why I think hybrids are so cool is these
are kind of like these futuristic
Creations that have
um um a little bit of everything that
unation like you know I talked to like I
saying Jeff from J Nector he smoked my
um uh space nectar which is like a blue
dream wook and he's used to smoking
heirlooms all you know all the time all
these different things from all over and
he was like wow this is really cool
really got really introspective was F
with friends it had all these qualities
and I was like you know this is welcome
to the world of hybrids you know it's
like you sometimes it's just like people
that never smoke heirloom or land race
that has a very specific kind of
morphology and canabo spectrum and
Turpin if you've never smoked those you
never really have get to experience the
specialness of kind of other plants so I
think he it was kind of an aha moment at
least for me and probably for him too
that wow hybrids also have this really
special magic it is really this unique
blending so
um that was kind I don't know if I got
too off talk but that yeah that's that's
how I feel about um yeah these these I
think there was a big difference back
then and I you know and maybe it wasn't
as potent or maybe we didn't have the
same amount of variety and Spectrum but
we had these really distinct and unique
cultivars that were shaped over long
periods of time with the hands of you
know many I would say many green hands
like many hands shape these many nights
many days many full moons many rains and
they have like a really they have a
personality whereas the new hybrids are
like crazy groovy like hyped up kids
that kind of can you know especially in
this day and age with the internet we
have influences from all over the world
you know you have kids in uh in the
highest towns of like Bolivia making
super dope crazy like electrocumbia or
like mumon or like they have trans baton
like they have all these new like
combinations of music because people can
with their old PC can download these
programs on like you know dark web or
whatever someplace get it for free or
from a friend or and make a crazy unque
amazing things that that are really true
to their generation and to their because
we're kind of like you know as a culture
and as a society we're not these like
sure we you could say oh you're Indian
you're African you're this we're really
like a global you know if you strip down
the melanin you strip down uh you know
body hair whatever else that makes
people different races or cultures we're
really a like
Global human and I think in cannabis
it's kind of what we're experiencing now
and as well as with everything else that
we can be creative with so to answer the
question yeah I think it was special and
different and unique and I the good
thing is now we have this new thing and
if we're smart and if we really look to
our elders and we really try not to lose
these things and also keep these places
that still hold these things clean and
and well um nourished I think we could
have the best of the Both
Worlds The Best of Both Worlds sounds
like exactly what we want really yeahuh
that's that's brilliant and I I guess as
as a followup to that you know talking
about memorable cannabis a really good
question was what's a plant that has
just really held a spot in your mind
over the years and what was it that made
it so
memorable let me think I mean I've
always liked Stevie Wonder mostly just
because it was a snapshot of all of the
like hypest things of like what is it 20
years ago or something you know was like
like a it was a sensey star um was a
blueberry Bubba cush Sensei star train
wreck like it was just the ultimate Mash
was one of my earliest kind of creations
and it's still like like the only clone
I hold from when I very first started so
that's cool but some of the old ones we
had one called Kiba which was like a it
came out of my deep Funk line that used
a long time ago was called biodiesel
before um it kind of dropped uh before I
just switched it back to deep Funk and
it was it was this it was a res Sour
Diesel IBL deep chunk cross and it had
the most insane F1 Vigor you'd ever seen
a plant it was just insane like I guess
because deep chunk is so in Brad you
know Rez did a good job of really
pushing those SD lines way down the line
so and it it was the coolest plant it
was just jet black with this beautiful
milky white tricomes and it was just
huge and amazing and it just it made
these big cushy nugs and it smelled just
like Cohiba cigars it was like uncanny
and weird and so earthy and it just had
a really kind of like I just felt like
cha or something smoking it you know it
just really had this vibe to it and we
you know I think we lost that one maybe
six years ago I still have some seeds to
kind of go through that was always a
cool I'm trying to think and like this
kind of goes back to when asked before
like what are my favorite strains like I
was a little dumbstruck when you asked
me because I was like I realized oh my
God I probably have
500 release strains or something and you
know maybe five times that just in the
fridge unreleased I don't even know and
I was coming to terms now and I'm like I
should have said like there's ones that
I really love like I didn't even say
mother's milk which I think is such an
amazing strain just the turps and just
the feeling like it's just such a warm
hug like everything's going to be okay
like hi you know Temple was one that I
just so loved like that was one of my
kind of very first successful kind of
narrow Leaf style like sativa highs like
and it was so joyous and laughy and fun
and it grew so cool and it was like that
perfect Williams Wonder Super Silver
Haze kind of combo um you know when I
was thinking back all those stashes I
made Boba stash um Lando stash all of
like the Bounty Hunter um series with
all the old La Kush cuts um uh you know
and the good medicine I love so much
because that was just I started that
just when they were learning how to test
CBD and that was when I kind of that was
where I got a little scientific that um
I was really trying to create a CBD
breeding mail back when you know that
was I don't even know that was when uh
SC Labs first open and so I was actually
testing my Mals and I think that was my
kind of my first introduction to science
to make that line um wow and there's
been so many plants too that just kind
of come up in my garden there's one that
we call graus Madre that still comes up
to this day
um uh and that's just the volunteer
tears and I had this most amazing last
time that it happened a few years ago we
had one called grus mudre and it was
this I think it was like a la A1 or
something but it literally was like
spoton that China Church incense in the
air smell like just classic kind of when
people think of that piffy kind of L
lights Haze and it was I love it and I
lost it I'm hoping still that radio
Ridge has it but you know they're super
diligent on the Hop PL and so they test
everything and if it even anything's hot
they instantly smoke it which is good so
hopefully it's still alive and it didn't
reach that fate um I don't know there's
so you know what was one that was really
cool that I don't really talk about it
was uh this one I made really early on
when I was still selling seeds like on
seed Bay was that we called it the PK
bks SD it was a um Sour Diesel Bubba
Kush cross to Purple Kush it was kind of
this San Francisco Super mesh up and I
gave that to a friend who moved back to
Israel before um legalization and it he
started that one of the first companies
there and it became the most um smoked
grown and U medical cannabis in all of
Israel for a while for like years it was
the number one seller and it was we just
call it PK bksd because it was purple
kush Bubba Kush Sour Diesel so that kind
of took on that's one of the strains
that kind of took a life of its own and
who knows what's going on now I'm sure
they still have it but so those are kind
of some of the ones that that got away
or that that I really you know that I
have a deep connection to that I kind of
forget you know and even some I love to
do like remixes like switch the mothers
and fathers and sometimes the remixes
are better than the releases so there's
been some really cool releases I think
that even some of the Girl Scout cookies
remixes where I use the ogkb instead of
the know Thin Man or cookies cut those
came out sometimes way better than the
cookies ones because they were so unique
so that's kind of my take on that
question I love it and uh shout out to
tranquil elephantizer remix I uh oh yeah
I love that bad boy that was one of the
first trains I grew beautiful stuff oh
you know what that just reminds me I was
thinking people always ask me like
what's a good air if I want to start out
on something that's like an heirloom or
a land race or what you know whatever
you want to call it there's like there's
a few strains I think if anyone want
just wants to start easy grow you super
unique beautiful really great highs and
just special like you know the Pakistani
chitrol Kush it's you know I think
everybody's pretty much released it like
Ace and Charlie and CBG and uh what is
that the other one in Spain like it came
through Spain they used to have green
fenos too I still have some of those
that's a phenomenal line so easy to grow
it's so beautiful it's a really great
introduction another one that's made its
way out is that be frog Kashmir aad that
I use in a lot of those probe series you
know the Kashmere it's an amazing plant
like it's such a cool combination of
like lowland and Highland like coming
together like you know it has some of
the traits of that you know kind of like
Himalayan style it's not in the
Himalayas I think that's a caroom in the
it's in the Pakistani kind of Kashmir uh
area such amazing like you can tell it's
kind of like it has a little bit of Low
Land kind of that kind of cushy quick
uh special magical like kind of
harvestable and this kind of high
Himalayan like narrow Leaf Space Age
like Beauty realm and so anybody ask me
those are two great ones to kind of
start in on if you want more narrow Leaf
you know if you want Broad Leaf there's
infinite unique ones to kind of try
these days um but yeah sorry for going
off on that I just want to throw that in
there before I forgot I want you to
throw it in before you forget so it
works out perfectly did exactly what I
wanted yeah see we're we're
telepathically connected through the
zoom that's exactly it that's exactly it
I should have asked this earlier but
this one's from a good buddy of mine so
I got to make sure I I do him Justice he
says he's actually uh going to be doing
a trek in Nepal next year and he said
he'd heard you'd been to the I'm going
to butcher the pronunciation but I'll
try um maniso and the sum Valley is that
right okay yeah those are areas that's
kind of in between like um langang and
anap Perna like that's a little more
West I've never been in that area so
like that's probably a really cool place
like you know there's places where a lot
of the tracks kind of focus in on and
it's like I think that and you know
Everest before bank before base camp a
lot of people fly into base camp they
don't really do the whole Everest track
like that's really cool and then farther
west near sakee is I mean sorry farther
east so sake's really cool and then
farther west west um where um kind of
where the uh Communists the maist were
for a while is a really cool areas but
yeah that Mano area I I think that's
right that's kind of in between langang
and and aera I think that would be a
really killer place to kind of check out
because it's even more off the Beaten
Track you
know yeah definitely look it it sounds
cool I'm jealous and he had a quick
follow-up question which was um are you
able to elaborate on your LA or napole
Adventures I know you've done so in the
past so um feel free to just say refer
to that but any specific sort of
locations in Nepal you think are like a
must for people who go there well I know
there's I mean if people want a little
Insider tip like if you want to go like
where there's like the super like
wizardy like uh ganja guy that you can
pick up stuff on the trail hopefully the
authorities and npole aren't listening
to this chitry um which is on the Anapa
circuit if you're going down towards the
um I believe it's towards the hot
springs on your left there's a it just
looks like a groovy house maybe ask
people there's a guy that literally has
like the best buds from all over the
area and kind of knows everything chitri
is kind of special like I found a lot of
really cool things just growing out of
the blue like you know some towns you're
just groovier than others and I think
it's because this guy kind of had an
influence but there's a dude in chit
tree that has great stuff I I think the
antier circuit is cool you know it's a
little bit
uh overrun these days and now I think
theyve ran and now they have a bus line
that goes all the way through which is a
total shame um langang is still a bit
wild it's a little jungly they have
there I think the the Far West might
have some stuff and you know there's a
lot of commercial areas and you know
what's really cool is like get down into
the lowlands too like the terai like Bia
and then uh chitwan those are like on
the jungly and that's jungly areas that
have the rhinos and the the um you know
the elephants and all the crazy tall
grasses they have some really cool
narrow Leaf stuff um that's a really
cool place to look but you know even
just cat men do meet people try a lot of
different head rubs try a lot of
different places look for you know the
heads there's you know even I think up
near doshin Ki which is a famous Kali
Temple I think there's a lot of really
kind of tucked back ganja growing back
in there but you sometimes you'll meet
cool people that are just kind of exp
Patriots or people that live in Nepal
and really pick their brain take him out
for some tea or just take him out for a
Sizzler they call him like it's this
kind of like a it's like Nepali fajitas
you know make friends and like really
check out where these places are coming
from you know what if you're on the
trail I'm not saying child labor is cool
but these are ancient cultures like kids
are usually rub just to make extra money
kids are rubbing up a storm up and just
hitting the trail like so many times I'd
be walking along and this little kid
would kind of roll up and like hey and I
I knew I'm like okay this kid just rubb
some hash she wants to sell it to me to
get some candy or something so sometimes
you'll get a really good kid hand rub I
mean it's just out there I mean Nepal's
a great direct from The Source yeah it's
so friendly it's so and you could go
with your family I
mean yeah I would say that you know Sim
is another kind of like it's in India
but it's right near Nepal it's a little
less uh off you know it's more off the
Beaten Track I think they have a lot of
really cool stuff and then you know
that's a great great area the Himalayas
are just so amazing so yeah just get out
there talk to people find some cool
spots but if you see the guy in chitry
that looks a little bit Stony you give
him you know talk to
him that's amazing everyone needs to
stash that away in a part of their brain
and and use it I uh I was thinking about
it all of like the top five most
psychedelic plants I've ever tried were
from you with you I want to know what's
the most psychedelic plant you've ever
ever had or at least in your memory that
jumps to
mind yeah I don't I mean it has to be
kind of like point of origin I I I don't
know what when I was in Waka when we
were up in the mountains with the Saina
family and working up there and with the
c cmir the other big mushroom family
there was this guy who went who uh kind
of was a heron addict and he moved to
Mexico to kind of get away from it and
he became I don't know if I told a story
before but he became like he was a
beekeeper he came down and they didn't
really have the whole beekeeping Vibe
going up in those mountains they didn't
really know about it and he kind of
became this teacher of the bee and he
would follow all around and he would
teach beeping and it really turned
people a lot of these tribal people
there maitech um onto beekeeping so
everyone loved him and he used to have
like this he had the best stash ever and
I got to try some of his Hawk and gold
and that stuff it was like i' never
experienced anything like that was
probably one of the most psychedelic
kind of like true psychedelic it was a
really good W Hawking you know I've
never been to Colombia I've only been
Peru and Biv Stu I've never got to try
like real Santa Marta I mean I've tried
Colombians here and and I've tried
hybrids and they're it's such an amazing
you can really tell the difference in
the
effect um and you know I'm trying to
think where else oh my God yes long time
ago I was on kopang Gan you know place
where they have the big full moon
parties and I was staying in the old
osou Comming that they turned into
Bungalows and I befriended a guy and I
got he got me a bud I think that was
though that was probably 25 years ago
this most this butt I didn't even know
what I thought it was like a it was like
a piece of lint that got stuck in
marshmallows or something it was this it
like stuck to the bag I like had to peel
the bag off it was like in some like
plastic wrap it was the most insanely
sticky thing I ever got and I smoked
that and I remember going out under the
moon in front of my Bungalow and just
floating in the water and just having
the most like epic just like you know
when you sometimes you smoke and it's it
was almost like a deprivation chamber
with the moon above me it like I got to
download you know when you just it's
like oh it's something in creation or
sometime in your life where the source
is just like all right it's time to
download those codes get ready you know
it's like you know here's your next
assignment or whatever it is like I
remember getting like a super download
from this that I don't know where he got
it on the island or what it was but it
was like and that's when I think people
talk about like I never really had super
tie experiences even in Thailand we
would always get the best stuff but that
was like where I was like oh cool I know
what real Thai when people talk about
like taii like that was what it was like
it was
incredible wow that's so cool I'm so
glad to hear that you had that
experience you know I'm I'm sure it was
just as epic as you said and and
hopefully everyone else out there can
relate in their own way you know as you
saying that I was sort of thinking to
myself of a similar different but
similar um I love it I love it one of
the things I wanted us to do before we
wrap up was uh touch back on our book
club theme I want to hear what do you
have for recommendations oh yeah so yeah
this is great this is great you asked me
because I yeah same time I was a little
bit like I got a little bit stumped
because you know when my my mind I don't
know if I'm on the Spectrum or what but
when someone asks me something my mind
goes like into every
imaginable like scenario and it doesn't
always have the best it's like it shoots
my Consciousness into every possible
thing not but that doesn't mean my
Consciousness has enough really to grasp
it back it's just like this thing where
I kind of go in and and and it and I
kind of get into everything and then I
try and bring it back so I got a little
bit uh bam like uh what do they got B
dazzled so I kind of this time I'm going
to be like I kind of I'm going to go
back what I kind of feel like are some
really good resources for people you
know uh so like I'm always super like
these are kind of like more breeding
plant stuff like my Bible in high school
was plants of the Gods like that is like
anybody that wants a cool book like I
know it's dated it's old it's uh Albert
Hoffman and Richard Evan Schult like
that is like that is like pretty much
one of my favorite books of all time as
a like a guide you know anything Terence
McKenna Terence McKenna interviews
there's so many there's so much amazing
information those he was one of smartest
most amazing most eloquent humans has
ever kind of walked the Earth you know
Luther Burbank such such an amazing
breeder such a cool guy like really um
Rudolph Steiner these you know these two
guys are this is like the Pinnacle of
like Natural Science like people that
are they're SC they're scientific in
their methodology but they're working
from their heart and they're working
kind of with nature not they're not try
it's not a control of nature it's like a
connection and working with nature uh
you know any of like the Psychedelic
guys anobot inist you know like like I
said Jonathan a and Christian ratch and
Plowman way Davis Mark CL and like
Richard M Schult like these guys are
just these are kind of my like who I
look up to you know and then for like
religion you know I'm really influenced
by like a
Barefoot doctor style dosm and like
super ancient even even kind of modern
stuff like mon Chia and just that kind
of watching being part of nature to find
you know they always say like in Terence
McKenna is like who's the greatest
teacher like just nature just go out on
a walk and just be attentive and aware
but you know I'm also really influenced
by uh uh Buddhism and Hinduism
especially some of the more ancient
forms like kind of in the it was call
like Odana it's kind of in that kind of
I guess a lot of it came from this kind
of Tigress Euphrates kind of area
there's an area that kind of spawned a
lot of the things that I like like
Kashmir shiism and zoen and you know you
know some of the authors I think are
super cool like for Buddhism I like uh I
like Keith dman I like n namai noru uh
love that chman trunka like you know um
for Kashmir shiism I super dig like
Swami lanu he's just just down to earth
and super good I love like Paul Mueller
TGA and I like Christopher Wallace he's
a really cool new guy that kind of that
really kind of breaks down like some of
a b AG gupta's teachings which he was
like one of my kind of like I really
like what his as the Saints and these
old philosophers kind of like he's like
you know kind of like people a ploh um
I'm I love gorano who was kind of like a
an ancient
Yogi um you know who else is cool like
markety he does a lot with Kashmir shym
Robert saada he did like the agori books
he's an aric doctor um you know I super
dick like even old sites like irw you
know shumer de T Nexus like if you can
get yourself a hold on like some of the
old Shaman drums magazines those are
super cool they have all kinds of great
stuff I mean that's kind of it you know
and just podcasts um so you know there's
so much going on I love YouTube now but
there's a lot of like I think I'll be
watching something cool and then they
get it all wrong like it it you know
back when we researched like we didn't
have the internet we had to get like we
had to find books we had to go look you
know for these things on ourselves like
it was like really finding some of this
information when I was like like a
teenager and even a young man it was a
treasure hunt and it was amazing it's
like almost cut the wheat from the shaft
like because you would if you met
someone and you guys could talk about
things on the same level you know that
person really did their work whether
they had parents that were into it or
they were had you were you know they
were super into it they went to
libraries they collected books like they
were in places points of origin like you
really had to do your due diligence to
get this information you know when we
were originally in the sztech looking
for Salvia dorm that was before they
realized it was um it was bual it was
only active well primarily active
besides smoking uh by mucus membrane you
know so we were drinking Shamrock Shakes
we didn't know what we were doing we
just drinking it right down because you
know we were told you it's a very
feminine and beautiful plant who didn't
like fire it was a very ancient
magical uh moisture feminine being that
it really when people smoke it it kind
of turns on them
so you know we never knew that so I went
through my whole first Salvia phas not
even really understanding how to utilize
it so back then same with records you
know before cdjs and laptops we had to
find these records and they were like
magical spells and they would get beat
up and we couldn't just redownload them
or we couldn't go to Spotify like it was
such a treasure hunt back then and I
kind of miss that these days and that's
what was so I think what made me so
stoked on on seed hunting it's so analog
like getting these seeds like no you
know I was like sure as I as a DJ
everything turned to memory sticks and
first it was CJs then memory sticks I
even thought a long time ago record
compilations were kind of cheating and
now it's all just pretty much
computerized like it with seeds you're
never it's never I mean maybe someday
it'll be computerized with these new
embryo seeds and all this but really
it's one of the most epic treasure
hunting tweak out trading card like
natural like I can imagine you know
100,000 years ago like full on Chaka
from Land of the Lost like hooking up
and trading seeds with his buddies a
couple valleys over like it's ancient
and it's so cool um like you know what I
mean it's like seeds are I know it's
kind of a pivot but I love to treasure
on and I think seeds are an amazing way
to make friends and trade and dork out
and have a hobby so
sorry that's a long one but that's what
I
mean I couldn't agree more with
everything you said and on the reading
list I got to give a shout out to you
one of my biggest recommendations I give
to everyone all the time still hooked on
it 10 out of 10 anything from ramas but
walking each other Home big one oh yeah
always a big one for me ramas is a good
one oh you know what too I I haven't got
to read so much of the new science
fiction I super dig fantasy and science
fiction you know always like you know
tolken and Herbert and all those but you
know what's really cool I trim people on
to it it's an author that not a lot of
people people know about is he's Liv
he's kind of like obscure is AA atanasio
like such a cool like he does fantasy
and um science fiction he did like a
whole trilogy that people kind of know
him for it was based on Aran Legends
those are really good but his super dope
one is called wyvern like and it like
the book wyvern is like one of my
favorite books you know I also like kind
line you know stranger and Strang I like
some of the' 60s kind of sci-fi too like
that kind of 70s groovy freaky sci-fi
but AA alasio if anyone ever read like
wering that's a really cool
book wow I'm gonna have to put on the
list I haven't I have not heard of that
one to be honest yeah it's pretty
rad that's incredible well look that
just about brings us to the end of it
for this one as always I wanted to ask
anything we've left out
I don't think I mean no I mean I think I
I always want to revise my my if I had a
time machine like where would I go well
why don't we do it let's say I've got a
time machine for you you can go anywhere
any place anytime presumably to collect
some seeds where you going to go what
are you going to get okay I I I really
thought about this and I think I got
really stoned I was like where the hell
do I want to go like like if I had a
time machine because you know what
cannabis is a time machine especially if
you know where you want to go if you
want to go Afghanistan get yourself a
heirloom Afghani get super bit and just
get into it so um I was thinking about
it before you know I did the usual Silk
Road kind of Heyday what you know
whatever 7 1600 1700 I was thinking I
would like to go back to the whole kind
of Eurasia area especially the
Mediterranean about 400 BC like around
kind of around like Plato era and I
would like to be like this super Elite
uh sax Slinger for all of the
Mediterranean all those islands all
those like really cool places and like
have a little Entourage and collect and
we all grew like the most crazy stuff
are picked it up in our traps from the
seeds that you know from the seeds that
we got all over we traded with like you
know the Mongolian Empire and we went to
Egypt and we hooked them up like we were
Travelers and Seed collectors as young
ones and As We Grew Older we had all
these lines and we grew them in little
farms and then we just rolled through
like we took like a maybe like six
months eight months we started kind of
maybe in turkey or maybe like even like
Paris or something I I don't Paris
didn't exist so actually that was kind
of I think that was back in the Mythic
age or with Mythos and all these
different so okay let's start in the
Mediterranean we would start our role in
the Mediterranean and all the menow and
all this Creed and all those places and
roll all all the way through to Egypt
and then into Asia just like with the
just a whole crew with just the most
epic plant like just Buds and hash and
all the kings and queens and everybody
would always invite us into their courts
and offer the you know finest foods and
cortison and entertainment and it would
be like the Highlight for every main
city like when we rolled through you
know like our Squad so like there would
be like songs sang and and you know all
these and people would write these books
and Praises that yes the squad comes
through and brings the most epic
mindboggling seeds and strains and
concentrates and and just a good time we
would have like I think and eventually
it would be kind of like a traveling
Road Show I think we would get like bars
and musicians from all the places like
the best musicians from all the
different cultures we went to and form
like this super crazy like like Muppet
like Electric Mayhem band with like
people with instruments from China that
were like their class and people from
like you know and just make this crazy
metal band or like so just and just have
the most ultimate like traveling Road
show of plant medicine and ganja and
music and delight and marryt and just
bring the just keeping the vibe alive
just just getting just just going for it
like just having so much
fun that that's that's got to be up
there for maybe the most epic answer
we've ever had I love that
just it sounds like a good life yeah
like just love and life just making
people happy and just living your best
life oh that's that's brilliant and uh
so fitting that that is that is your
answer I I absolutely love
that again massive thank you a Titan of
the breeding world the breeder's breeder
prolific in his output both from the
wide variety of land race to hyp Beast
one of the most respected out there big
thanks to Bod for taking the time to
join us thank you so much and yeah have
a beautiful beautiful 2025 let's bring
alive and there you have it my friends
what did you think I absolutely loved it
of course that's 100% due to our good
buddy bod thank you so much for taking
the time to come and join us sharing the
love sharing the knowledge sharing the
passion I hope you're all invigorated
and excited to spread the magic spread
the love for our plant and as you said
let's make 2025
[Music]
great if you love this episode please
consider supporting both the patreon as
well as the websites of our incredible
sponsors if you're looking to transition
from combustion to vaping check out our
good friends at dap you will not be
disappointed cheap affordable and
Incredibly efficient units likewise
check out our friends at Pulse sensors
if you want to make sure that your
garden is dialed in and you are tracking
all of the variables that are going to
ensure your next Harvest is the best to
date you got to get yourself a pulse
guys it's a
no-brainer in order to ensure that your
garden is pest and pathogen free please
check out our friends at copit they are
the number one in bior predatory
technology copit thank you so so so much
for your
support likewise a big shout out to our
friends at Organics alive for all the
most incredible powdered organic
products usable in all systems both
organic and hybrid a huge thank you to
Organics alive we recommend them highly
please check them out if you want to
take your organic game to the next
level finally massive shout out to our
good friends at seeds here now they got
heavy days beans go check them out guys
I promise you will not be disappointed
they got all the latest drops the
hottest breeders fem Auto photo period
CBD whatever you need they're here to
help you out massive thank you to our
friends at seeds here
now and big love to the patreon gang we
love you so much thank you for
supporting the show they got Early
Access to this episode over a month ago
if you want to get extra content please
consider supporting the show you'll
score yourself genetics a whole bunch of
swag from our sponsors and so much
more so that just about brings us to the
end of it for this
one big thank you to you for getting to
the end yet again and for the support
big love as always from your boy heavy
days signing
off see you
[Music]