[Music]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts in this episode
we're joined by Jeremy from build a soil
to chat all things organic growing so
buckle in for some awesome organic
knowledge from the man himself so first
of all this is the only time I ever do
this I wanted to say this episode is
actually dedicated to someone it's
dedicated to all of the growers out
there who are thinking about maybe
switching over but maybe you use bottled
nutrients at the moment and maybe it's a
part of your income or you just scared
things will fall apart trust me and I
listen to us and the world won't come
grinding to a halt I promise so before
we get started
Jeremy what's your favorite straiten
well I don't know I've been one of those
types of growers that's been a seed
hoarder and always looking to collect
something I get easily excited about
crosses that I wasn't able to get become
available or a buddy that I respect
their work made across and so my garden
has really been I guess complemented by
organics because I can run many
different cultivars never having grown
them before and a lot of times they're
all able to run on the same regimen and
that was attractive to me so it's hard
for me to pick a favorite I grow a
different flavor almost every time but
one of those clone only elites there's
several of them that are running around
out there and it seems like the glue has
been one of those very consistent even
if somebody doesn't do a great job
growing it comes out smelling very
similar and looking good it has a ton of
oil on it when you're going to press it
or if you're gonna make a concentrate
from it and so that's one that I keep
going back to right now in my garden
there's one that it's very unique came
from Canada and it was a freebie and it
was a gene jinguk
crossed with a
Marrakesh and the jean-guy was a really
sought after clone only white widows
something you know I don't know the
background on it but this one in
particular really purple hair and the
odor is just unmistakably candy-like and
it's really really stinky so I'm hoping
that it translates to taste it I guess
we'll find out awesome
so I think the first big question is why
should people be growing organically
over say bottled nutrients it's a good
question for me it was about congruence
in the beginning before I knew a lot and
so I was already eating organic I was
already trying to remove processed foods
and I was being at least starting to be
conscious about the carbon footprint
involved in my lifestyle and I'm a
hypocrite in a lot of those areas
because I'm not perfect but I choose to
make decisions in areas where I can
easily make an impact so started growing
and had some success but when I went to
the grow shop there was no organic
options
I mentioned being congruent I was
already living a lifestyle that was more
that that method and so when I started
growing and really got a little more
serious about in 2009 there was a number
of options available that were organic
for the first time like different
bottled nutrients and then there was the
super soil which was by TGA and there
was I'm not sure if that had come out
yet it was about to come out but the
revs true living organics and so I was
like wow look at all these different
options and so when I started
researching more I found out that there
was actual whole world where people were
concerned about our soil and how it's
gonna affect our society in the future
how it affects the nutrient density of
the food that we eat and the disease
that we can get and so it started
becoming you know more of just a
translation of that healthy lifestyle
and then I found out how easy it was to
grow organic how it suited me my ability
to take weekends off and do things where
I wasn't you know completely revolved
around my grow and then I also found out
that yields could be good and then
significantly different to my experience
with hydroponics was that I could get
the taste and the smell out of those
genetics the first time I grew up
instead of really trying to figure them
out if that meant
since and so for me it was just natural
to wanna grow organic and it seems like
most of our customers also want to grow
organic and then we can get into all the
benefits behind that but there's there's
too many to talk about depending on the
angle do you have any more specific
questions I guess about that well I mean
the first thing that comes to mind is
starting build a soil was that just kind
of a natural extension of that passion
or was it more of like you saw there was
a niche that needed filling it was a
little bit of both I'd been reading and
dabbling a little bit and internet
businesses I'd run a couple of
businesses on my own in the past that
were more brick-and-mortar and I was
disenchanted with the nine-to-five job
routine and where I was at in life I had
a breakup of a relationship I had some
things happen in my life where I was
kind of refocused on growing and then my
father passed away and so when that
happened I took a look at my life and I
was like well geez I'm gonna wake up in
30 years at the same job I might as well
you know pursue some of these dreams
what am I waiting for
and so build the soil happened because I
was having to source these ingredients
that I was reading about on IIC mag and
other organic grow forms and I was
having a source them from all over the
country and all over the world and it
was really hard to get him sometimes I
went without or waited awhile or I'd get
a low-grade product and so all the money
I spent finding out all this information
started to make an impact on some of my
local friends and they'd buy some of the
products and so that was kind of a way
for me to buy more for myself and then I
thought well I'm gonna try this I built
build a soil and I posted a couple
craigslist ads and I had some initial
interest and then from there we did do
any advertising we just did
word-of-mouth and it went like crazy so
I'd say it was a passion for organics
but more than that it was because like I
mentioned before I went to the hydro
store and there was no options that were
really organic it was just these kind of
predatory wannabe organic companies with
really high profit margins that were
selling you products that were very
similar to the current paradigm and it
fit their model of keeping you back in
the store all the time and so when I
started build a soil it was just a way
to share what everybody knew in the
organic forms but it took them years to
find out hoping to speed that process up
and also hoping to make some money which
is it's working out and I'm really happy
about that
yeah nice so I guess moving on to the
big question which I'm always trying to
answer to people why is bottled
nutrients or for this interview I'm
gonna call it synthetic why is synthetic
cannabis different to organic like what
are the fundamental factors which cuz
people always say organics better than
synthetic well let's explain to people
what is it that makes the organic better
that's a good question it it crosses
over a lot of different lines worth or
whether we're talking about setting up
the grow and making it easy to do versus
check in pH and all that stuff it can
definitely have his advantages but I
think most of us that get really
passionate about this there's some a
certain genesis of gwah about the
finished product that has more romance
to it it has a depth of flavor and taste
and it's it's hard to explain because
for instance I kind of I kind of like to
think of it calling it early so if we
were going to compare it to food or to
cooking most of what people are
experiencing grown synthetically is akin
to buying a Campbell's soup well or
maybe like a wolfgang puck or something
a little higher end but it's still a
processed synthetic it can chelated
versions so to speak and so it's it's
ready to use it provides value to the
market it certainly works the same every
time but if you would ask a chef who
spent his life visiting farms tasting
ingredients from regions traveling the
world growing in seasons and putting
that in their flavor it's like it's not
enough and so ultimately in organics if
we can now grow some of our own inputs
make our own compost build our own soil
or have somebody that we trust to do
that for us we start to connect all of
the dots and then you get those flavors
and you get those nutrient profiles and
one of the things that's neat is just
like wine you find that there's a term
called terroir and it relates to the
region in which the wine was grown the
temperature the soil and even with
tobacco you know if you're gonna buy a
cigar the soil is absolutely the most
important part of that and that's why
people seek out Cuban cigars so taking
all that in perspective looking at soil
as a bigger picture it's like well geez
how is synthetics gonna add
because it's all it's trying to do is
duplicate soil and then from there it's
trying to take out any of the potential
problems when you're mono cropping on
scale indoors which could be bacterial
pathogens yada yada so it's kind of like
using hand sanitizer as opposed to just
getting in the dirt and being healthy so
all in all you organics just fits all of
those different similarities in my life
and makes a lot more sense to me so so
people often try to say essentially that
organics is harder than synthetics what
is your general thought on this idea do
you think there's any truth to that or
maybe people have got it a bit confused
I think it's a lot easier but it is that
is missed on a lot of people because if
you go to research organics you're gonna
get a variety of different information
that can seem confusing what's great is
a lot of these people that you find with
million different methods they're all
having success in organics and so I
think the difference is in perception if
I go to the gross store they're gonna
give me a neat little print out with a
couple lines on it to say add these
ingredients on this day at this time and
for a beginner that's really nice to
have a recipe it's just like opening up
a cookbook and measuring every single
item to put it in the bowl but once you
get a little better at this you don't
need the cookbook it's significantly
easier you know ratios you throw things
together and they work that can be very
scary for someone who's new to this who
has no mentor who has nobody to hold
their hand and so I think that it's just
kind of a misconception organics is so
much easier that it's hard to give a
precise recipe where that's very easy
and synthetic so you just tell people
exactly what to do the thing is is when
people get down the line in synthetics
and they're grown a lot of plants they
realize that it's not that simple most
of the manufacturers miss label you have
to cut the dosages in half you have to
make certain changes to make things work
and so I don't think organics any
different it's just to where you're
gonna invest your time and kind of like
switching from scheme to snowboarding or
surfing to bodyboarding it's just
different skills and so if you're an
advanced expert in one area it's gonna
make you feel kind of like a beginner to
try organics but I feel like the
learning curve is a lot easier and
certainly the ability to lose a crop in
hydro can happen overnight where in
organics I think even a beginner isn't
going to get to harvest so yeah so I
mean kind of touched on something he
said earlier
in relation to organic food its there's
a little debate you know everyone would
prefer organic food if they had the
choice so why is it that people go to
hydro over organic as say their first
choice you know like it would seem to me
like it would be the thing people would
first want to do but a lot of people
don't you know it often you hear people
saying oh I did hydro first and now I'm
organic yeah I don't know why that is I
think that it's a system of the
marketing machine that existed you know
you have a lot of the magazines that
target a core demographic of teenagers
to early 20s you go to the store that's
fueled by repetitive sales with high
margins that are on the same products
and so when you're not allowed to ask
for help ask anybody things are illegal
all you can listen to is the people that
are selling you the products not only
that but it's coupled by a few different
things when you look at the history of
cannabis you can read a few different
posts but DJ's short has a great one and
it's talking about how in the 90s there
is this perfect storm of hydroponic
nutrients and lights that were available
at stores and coupled by the fact that
people figured out how to grow hybrid
plants that grew shorter and had higher
yield and worked indoors and that was
all a consequence of the war on drugs
going indoors and forcing people to do
that at a larger scale so when you have
that happening you just have a lot of
things that are changed in that process
and are forced to have happen so I think
that's kind of a key difference there if
that makes sense yeah so here's kind of
a bit of a nuts and bolts question can
organic ever yield more or equal to
synthetic you know this is the major
argument presented by everybody in the
hydroponic industry do you think there's
any proof behind this or do you think
we've moved past those days where it's
just commonly accepted that hydro will
always out yield organic and sorry sorry
sorry as I follow-up if hydro does yield
organic do you think the cost reduction
because often hydroponic we don't go for
as much as organic do you think the cost
reduction in selling price is worth the
cost savings or any potential savings in
say you increase yes so it's so strange
cuz there's there's not enough data on a
real large scale we're talking five year
data by real companies there is when
we're talking farming so
we're looking at agriculture there's a
lot of data when we're looking at
horticulture specifically cannabis there
isn't as much data and I know a lot of
my friends can claim some pretty
significant yields using the hydroponic
techniques the thing is is we also want
to look at yields 24/7 365 including
problem gardens crops that are failures
we also want to look at energy usage we
want to look at the profit margin not
just the yield that's produced and so I
think that when we start to consider
that I'm finding my greenhouse customers
that are using the sunlight and
supplemental lighting are drastically
increasing their profit margin by
keeping the same soil around and
learning to soil test top dress and
amend and what we're all learning right
now even you know me I'm learning every
day about how to improve these soil
mixes so the it's crazy because some
people will get hydro that will actually
go for a higher dollar amount based on
the bag appeal just like how you can go
to a shop store and get a tomato that
looks perfect but tastes like nothing
hydroponics can make a beautiful product
no doubt about that it's it's the punch
behind that the power the lasting
effects the taste the flavor all those
secondary effects that organics
typically has from the nutrient density
now some of these hydroponic guys are
getting a little better by incorporating
organics into their synthetics and
starting to bring some of that back and
so when we're looking at indoor
duplicating a grow and having someone
who's never grown before hydroponics
hag's has a few legs up on systematizing
but once you get growers that are really
good at their craft and good at organics
we're finding a higher sellable profit
product like you're finding because it
smells better and looks better and then
we're finding that the profit margins
there and so one of the reports that I'd
encourage people to look at is going to
the 30 to 35 year I believe now Rodale
organic farms trial study and what
you'll find is that when they compare
synthetic verses or conventional versus
organic when they compare also no-till
conventional versus no-till organic
versus some of these other hybrid
methods organic just wins across the
board every single time you know when it
comes to bumper crop years where the
weather is great they both are
neck-and-neck when it comes to drought
years organic just crushes it when it
comes to bushels per acre organics is
winning when it comes
to the price per actual profit margin
there's less cost and inputs in the
organics and then actually already not
do like you said demand a higher price
at the market so they're widening the
profit margin both of the front and the
back and that's really appealing because
that's a 30-plus year study on an
agricultural level which is where we
should be heading as the laws change I
don't think we're gonna be forced to be
indoors at least we'll be in greenhouses
as things loosen up a little bit more
and we can get those profit margins
there and get more medicine produced if
that makes sense yeah so I mean maybe
this is a bit of a no-brainer but um in
the ideal world would everyone be
growing organic in your you know in your
ideal world yeah of course in my ideal
world but I think that I think that
there's always like for instance how do
you know how good it feels to be healthy
unless you've been sick there's always
this yin and yang and so if I just saw
that the mainstream majority understood
that organic wasn't witchcraft and there
wasn't you know something that will
never work I think I'd be really happy
with that and people can make their own
intelligent decisions but you know
certainly having 5000 percent markup on
little bottles with liquid in them I
think that that's gonna end pretty
quickly as consumers get more educated
so that will be phased out next is gonna
be you know looking at actual scale like
for instance the hip farms that we visit
out here it's different you know we're
not gonna recommend a 30% compost they
can't spend you know 400 truckloads
across an acre to do that and so we've
got to start to consider different
methods that are going to create new
opportunities for business and new
challenges for growers because right now
on scale that's the really big challenge
is how do we do organics on a farm that
has been synthetic for a long time and
do that conversion and successfully
train people to convert learn the new
skills spend the money that it takes to
ramp up and that's essentially what it's
like for most every single grow because
every grow grower that I work with
unless it's a brand new facility is
switching from hydro to organic when
they're brand new and they have our an
organic grower I see a higher success
rate it's a lot harder to change over
for you know keeping the same grow or
the same same mindset yeah so let's talk
about that process of rejuvenating soil
so if you have had soil that's been you
used for synthetic nutrients for an
extended period of time it's obviously
gonna have a large amount of salt
buildup and virtually no microbes in it
what would be your you know kind of
first guess as to how to rejuvenate it
would you be looking at using you know
adding houmous through some means and
then trying to get some microbes back in
there or is it a much more complex
process because this kind of crosses
over into you know like how would people
you know reuse some of that cocoa to
make their new soil mix if they're going
organic yeah yeah there's a few
different ways and it really depends on
your time frame so in farming they call
it leaching instead of flushing and you
could certainly do a flushing if it's
just a small amount of cocoa medium and
get the salts out they sell products
that are gonna doing that and they sell
enzyme products that eat the salts on
the agricultural scale people have been
using the product by tear organics the
em1 it's a probiotic it's kind of one of
the originals that has purple non sulfur
bacteria lactobacillus and yeast and you
can make something that's a part of that
at home on your own and some of these
have been proven to remediate toxic
soils and help with salts so I would do
specific research based on my area what
type of salts I'm dealing with but but
definitely there what ways to do it
I really recommend when people are
considering doing that if they've got
just a small investment in some
synthetic medium may be using that out
outside in the garden or something and
starting from the from scratch to start
their organic process and it's not that
I think that it's a hundred percent
necessary but when you're trying to
troubleshoot later on I hate that
there's a variable there I'm wondering
is it really some leftover salts or
something that I messed up from trying
to recycle this soil that I probably
shouldn't have and so to make it just
really clear-cut keep your variables to
a minimum I think starting from the base
recipes is advisable otherwise flush it
with just water you could add some
sulfur it's how they do it on the
agricultural level and that leeches some
of the potential excess cations and we
can talk about that you could also use
some gypsum and that would replace any
of the ones that it's flushing out with
calcium so I guess it's a case-by-case
yeah okay
so kind of full
in that same vein what is the best way
to increase the general human content of
your soil because a lot of the times
when I see people and they tell me you
know this this soil is depleted there's
nothing you know often what rings in my
head is like no you've just got no human
content in that soil so do you think
that I guess this question it kind of
the underlying of is like no-till versus
general recycling should you be looking
to continually just topdressing your
soil with things like compost and you
know eventually the human content will
kind of leech back in or should you be
looking to full-on pull your soil our
composter with some rich human
ingredients for a few months and then
bring it back in so to speak you know I
don't think that we should ever be
recycling and dumping and reinventing
and all that at least from an idealist
perspective if we were to scale it up
it's got to be scalable and dumping
reinventing is certainly a lot of labour
when you start looking at acreage and
greenhouses and anything bigger than it
you know your own closet now at home if
you I guess the reason why people do it
as far as starting from scratch each
time and throwing all of their stuff
away would be because it's a reset and I
can guarantee the starting point and so
then from there we started recycling and
it worked from there we can also do soil
testing recycling and that works but
when we started to learn or when I
started to learn more about how planets
and nature work the biomimicry portion
you start to look at all of the compost
that comes from the leaves and from all
the stuff on top it's never mixed in
unless it's brought down by animals and
so the no-till crowd uses worms and over
time you continually can lessen your
inputs because there's a nutrient
cycling that starts to happen but at the
beginning I would prefer to top dress it
and so I've got a story out back in my
at my property I have some really bad
soil it's very clay out here really high
and cal stress and alkaline and so it's
very simple you want to add a lot of
organic matter to start to get it to
work properly and so I was considering
tailing down and doing a ton of work and
I decided to get a very affordable
truckload of compost that wasn't even
finished yet more like woodchips brought
it in and dumped it down and I
raise the soil up about six inches using
that and then in the areas I wanted to
plant plants I just put a little potting
soil and dug out a couple gallon hole
and put the plant and that first year
everything was successful but the second
year it almost completely turned into
soil and built the soil up instead of
digging it down so I think I saved a lot
of money and saved a lot of effort doing
it that way living indoors when you're
growing or when you're growing in beds
adding the worms in the container can
certainly help so you don't have to add
so much that it adds to the volume of
your bed but all the biomass that we are
taking out should be added back in and
there should be a little extra and so
whether that's adding a cup of this a
cup of that as far as dry bed mints or
adding compost back I think those are
them I think those are the easiest way
to go meaning when you add it to the top
there's a lot less risk of it being out
of balance and in hurting the plant but
when you start to mix it in you better
be balanced and so that's why we make a
potting soil that tries to follow the
major cations in balance and we're now
working on all of the micronutrients but
from there after a cycle or two without
doing a soil test it seems to be a lot
easier just to top dress and keep it
just so it has a bigger savings account
than it needs and things go really well
yep so would your general philosophy on
how to get the most out of your soil be
that essentially you try to maximize the
cation exchange capacity or not
specifically yes you want to have a good
balance between cation exchange capacity
and the organic matter content and if
they go kind of in opposite directions
the more clay you get the the more
cation exchange you can have the more
actual you know exchange sites there are
and then when you go the opposite
direction and add a lot more organic
matter sometimes you lower that a little
bit and you complex a lot of the
nutrients it's a little bit harder to
read so to get the most out of the soil
we want a generous amount of organic
matter it's gonna hold moisture and it's
gonna have all of those complex organic
nutrients in it but we also want to have
the cation exchange and a decent level
and what I found recently is that our
lining agents can actually artificially
increase the cation exchange and what
that means is there's calcium that's
free floating around it has
been adsorbed into the cation exchange
sites yet and the soil tests falsely
read that as a higher cation exchange
and we just did a soil test recently in
fact I got it here in front of me and we
did a man look three soil tests through
Logan labs and it came in at thirty two
point five two cation exchange capacity
or the total exchange capacity and
that's pretty good
we'd like to see something you know the
20s or 30s that's really high certainly
we don't want to be able below ten
that's more like a field soil when we
did the ammonium acetate point two
alkaline type test on it dissolved out a
lot of that excess calcium and showed us
where our exchange capacity was actually
an eighteen point seven one that makes
sense because our organic matter is at
forty three percent on this recipe which
is really high and so to get that
exchange capacity higher you could have
a little less organic matter maybe add
some more clays and things like that but
in any case here's what happens if you
have a really low exchange capacity
you're gonna have to supplement your
full season plant with a lot of input
nutrients and so if your soil is not
quite as balanced that might actually
benefit you because you'll exhaust
through things faster and you can
control it by using teas I don't like to
use a ton of teas and so I want to have
a lot higher exchange capacity and
really properly balance these nutrients
that way you have to basically just add
water and so to get the most out of your
soil the higher CEC will hold more
nutrients but I think that at that point
the balance of those nutrients is gonna
be a little more important yeah so that
question for me it kind of relates to
like super soil versus coots mix you
know like on the one hand when I look at
the super sore yeah it's like that that
organic heavy and the the exchange
capacity is not as good whereas kootz is
the opposite you know I using what is
there more efficiently do you think that
that shall be our general approach to
all organic so let's use less amendments
and get more out of them yeah I think so
especially when it comes to economies of
scale we're gonna have to learn how to
work with the microorganisms that are
able to break these down for instance
phosphorus is very immobilize been a
problems for farmer and consequently
always been a problem for groundwater
too and it's gonna bind and lock up and
it's not going to be available where in
organics nature finds a way even
you know ph's that should be available
they're able to exchange differently
pick up nutrients in different fashions
and so when I look at a super soil a lot
of times there's the margin for error
was where you'd hit a hot pocket not be
able to undo it so my opinion is that
starting with a really good balance you
can always add more to it in the areas
in which your environment or genetics or
whatever might require that but if you
start off just tripling and doubling all
the nutrients to try and power it and
just really push them hard you could end
up finding cultivars that don't like
that or imbalance within the input
recipes that made that batch each time
and then from there it's very hard to
recycle a really hot soil like that even
if you did nail at the first round very
hard to get it right the second round
without throwing a win starting over so
having a balanced soil with a known
recipe that people can duplicate allows
us to create this and then if we have to
like I said add to it by topdressing
and to me that just seems like there's
more power and man there's more control
in that and if we're trying to get more
people to grow organically they're gonna
have more success doing it that way yeah
so if people were growing with super
soil and they're of the opinion that
they've now depleted it do you think
it's the case that there probably is
still a fair amount of nutrients in
there and you say they amended it with
maybe some peat or some cocoa that might
kind of change the exchange capacity a
bit to uh you know you know to make some
of those nutrients more available or do
you think no yes you probably just start
over okay totally work I've seen people
take it and one of the benefits is a lot
of these guys are flushing really hard
and it does strip out a lot of their
nutrients and so it's not as bad as you
think in fact we're worried about sodium
excess but when I test soils that are
you know super soils and have been
flushed at the end because that's their
protocol I'm not seeing sodium build-up
because they're not using liquid
nutrients and so that's fine what I
typically see is that their phosphorous
and potassium is still just in excess
more so than they think
and then the calcium and magnesium is
not quite supporting which should be you
know the more major cations and so it's
hard to tell exactly what's going on
when they plant back into it and then
they're adding more of the wrong things
so I wouldn't know if we took super soil
did a soil test we can look at it
balanced
pretty easily if I was just gonna shoot
from the hip I would say cut it in half
with some peat and some compost and
aeration to make sure that the textures
right plant into it then you could top
dress from there and have that you'd
work perfectly it'll have it'll have
excess P&amp;K and probably a little low
calcium and nitrogen and so when you cut
it in half it'll cut that PK where it
needs to be and then the top dressing is
where you'll fix the rest so if you're a
good grower you could certainly cut it
and then judge on the plant if this is
your first time you had a good luck with
super soil and you're hoping to use it
you might want to send off for a soil
sample and see where you're at if that's
easy where I live it's 25 bucks and you
get a really good report there's also I
can go down to the local college
Extension Office and actually get a free
soil test so if you have those resources
I totally use them where you're at
another great person to talk to would be
Steve Solomon not sure if he's available
for consulting but I know that his book
the ideal soil I'm sorry that's funny I
mix the two up I'm also thinking of
Michael a sterile I deal soil and then
Steve Solomon is the intelligent
gardener those two really talk about
soil mineral balancing and so that would
be worth looking into maybe grabbing a
copy of those yeah for sure so I'm just
gonna say I have to admit I actually use
blood and bone in my soil mixtures and
it's only been recently that I've been
reading more and more about how the the
salt levels can start to really build up
how detrimental do you think it is to
use blood and bone and the salt that's
in a verse say another amendment that
would say replace blood and bone do you
think it's because I see that more and
more people were kind of urging us to
move away from it and I'm all fine with
that but I was just wondering is it
actually that detrimental or is it more
of like people don't agree with the
methods in which button Boehner's
presumable sorting methods I think it's
I don't think it's that bad as far as
the actual salt you could certainly get
some back to they're a little saltier
but I mean we're talking fish bone meal
and kelp we get sodium with those as
well and if we make a proper soil a lot
of times we could use a little sodium
and I don't think that's really going to
be detrimental I have seen soils where
that's hot where I focus on this is like
in the kitchen if I'm going to use an
ingredient I'd like it to be a
multitasker
like I don't need to get a watermelon
cutting knife I've got a great knife
that'll cut anything and so if I'm gonna
buy a soil amendment I'd like it to be
just like in nature very well balanced
so seed meals and kelp has every mineral
you know things that have a good NPK
where you look at but then a blood meal
it's just basically in and then use take
a step further from that and you realize
that it's basically corn or feeding the
cattle corn in which we shouldn't be
they're features of eating grass
Monsanto GMO roundup sprayed crops going
through the process it's one of the
worst industries there is I know there's
only a few meat packers out there and so
we're getting all the blood from those
sources and minutes stamped organic
which most people I think if you asked
them and they bought organic blood meal
they would expect that to come from an
organic cow and that's just not the case
and so in an effort to not support that
I've not sold any of those products and
will will continue to not offer them and
then from the perspective of let's say
they were actually good it was your cow
I had a great diet and you got the blood
from it I'd be all for using it and I
don't really see a downside so I think
it's more about the methods and then
from there it is a little one-sided it's
just the end or it is just the P and so
that is good sometimes when you're
reading a soil test and you only need
one ingredient sometimes the challenge
with organics there's a lot of your
ingredients comes with multiple
variables and so when you read a soil
test you have to see how each variable
has changed like for instance if I need
calcium but my sulphur is too high I
can't use gypsum because that brings a
lot of sulfur so there is a place for
these unit asking ingredients but once
you get there it becomes about the
source and who is supporting etc etc so
yeah so when we deal with this I call it
the minefield of organics because you've
got all these products which may be a
labeled organic but under the hood maybe
aren't so I think the best example is a
lot of the bottled nutrients which are
stamped with organic yet I have to
explain they're not how do you you know
how do you straddle this kind of
dichotomy of where the chemistry
nomenclature already exists saying that
anything with a carbon backbone is
organic and therefore some people will
claim that certain synthetics are
organic
on that viewpoint well in the gardening
we'll you know the time organic Ole Miss
has a completely different meaning you
know I had how do you deal with this you
have to deal with it by getting educated
and setting some core values for
yourself and keeping that as your focus
point and what I mean by that is even in
the organic world some people would say
that gypsum is not organic because it's
not a carbonate it is calcium and sulfur
it's a mined mineral but that to me if
it's dug out of the ground that's great
I like it it's natural is that it's out
there it helps grow plants and so
there's always this duality that exists
on both sides of the fence where a very
intelligent hydroponic growers can
explain that
organic nutrients are broken down to
these chemistry nutrients at the end of
the process anyway so why not just cut
the chase and so to me it always ends up
coming around where I think that if you
don't use it you lose it and we're
certainly losing our soil and we haven't
been using it it's like if you were to
take a person put them in an IV diet
that was supposedly the perfect
nutrition I guarantee you they'd lose
their teeth their stomach all the stuff
that was not processing the nutrients
and it would be very strange but equally
hard to get that perfect diet when
you're just feeding them food but I
think we'd all agree growing your own
food and eating holistically would
probably be the best way to live a long
life so it's just it's strange these
organic minefield like you say you have
to get educated start asking questions
just like when you go to the store and
you start instead of looking for
calories and fat you start to look as
this real food or is it fake food and so
in the organic industry you just got to
do the same thing and I think when you
apply that logic it becomes easy you
know you're like huh where's blood meal
come from I wonder if it's organic cows
you google it you find out it's not with
guano it's a little more interesting you
have a lot of organic grower still using
guano and I can't really hold them
accountable to some you know perfect
ideal because my reasons are different I
don't want my crew to breathe it in and
I think it's expensive for what it
brings to the table and historically
organically when Kawano was the only
nutrient we over mined it and it did
cause a lot of problems so there's gonna
be a different reason for a lot of these
organic
and I don't want people to kind of lose
sleep over it you just have to kind of
pick your area of comfort and go for
that meaning I know a lot of people that
compost non-organic produce and some
people would just think that's insane
but I trust composting and I know how
it's able to rip molecules down to their
basicness you know building blocks so
each person is gonna have a different
answer for this yeah of course
and finally enough you kind of hit one
of my lighter questions on the head I am
I use a lot of gypsum in my soil mix and
cut out a chunk of oyster shell flour
and I get it some people give me a bit
of flack for that and I try to explain
to them that like even though the gypsum
isn't organic as you mentioned they
bring up it's not organic and you know
yeah yada yada I guess in the end what
I'm saying is do you think that it's
really do you think it's really
worthwhile for people to go and look
into those elements a bit higher so that
they can as you said you know make that
distinction between well you sure do
person's not organic but I can use it
and you know sure epsom salts are not
organic but foliar feeding with it isn't
gonna you know I kill my plants
overnight I think it's important for us
to all go through these things on our
own and a lot of times in organic
gardening it's important to learn these
lessons one by one and going through
that in our garden and answering them
for ourselves because that's
unfortunately one of the only ways to do
this but what's great is if you have a
vegetable garden in a cannabis garden
you can try a lot of different different
experience experiments but like you said
with gypsum I just don't have any
problem with that
some people will and there's no way you
can convince them otherwise but to me I
mean there's a town in from Colorado
called gypsum it's laying out there in
the ground and so okay that's just okay
to me but here's the thing let's say we
scale up big-time
how much gypsum is there so one of the
things people think about or they
purchase is perlite what a lot of people
don't know is that perlite is an
obsidian rock and there's not an endless
supply of it and it takes a ton of
energy to transform it from this black
rock into a like a puffed up piece of
popcorn that turns white and is really
fluffy and is it is great material for
gardening that's why we don't use it but
when you start to look into organics and
you get to deeper levels it not only
becomes is it or
will it work but how sustainable is that
like cocoa core the argument is is more
sustainable than peat moss but the
pima's society would argue that we've
only used a very small percentage and
they're replanting in yada yada yada
whereas people against coconut will say
well they're planting plantations of
coconut trees they're using synthetic
nutrients so now you have to find out is
it organic or is it synthetic is it near
the ocean where it's salty are they
shipping it over on an oil tanker
it just becomes insane and so the only
answer if you're a purist is to get back
to permaculture close of the loop and
have it all coming from your property
but to ramp up you still have to bring
in outside sources cover crop organic
material animals and then from there you
can start to close that loop so you have
to ask yourself do I want to make all my
own inputs close my loop have my own
animals make my own compost or am i okay
digging in the ground on someone else's
property to get a few of my resources
and I think that if it came down to
actually producing food for us to eat or
you'd all be okay using some gypsum when
it comes down to three plants in a
closet we can afford to have some really
high ideals and I'm ok with that but
applying those to everybody isn't I
found in the beginning when you're first
learning you want to hold everybody you
know kind of there's this organic
elitist thought and people kind of get
in this trap where they I have to
justify their process by kind of being
condescending and I think once you start
to learn a lot more about it there's
that goes away and you just kind of
focus on your own garden and teaching
those that are willing to learn yeah so
I mean just touching on that point about
the cocoa in Australia for example cocoa
is readily abundant because you know
we're close to lots of small islands
that produce a lot of coconuts however
however peat moss is very very expensive
it's it's you know five six times the
price it's no sense to use peat moss
where that right yeah that was going to
be the question whose are they are they
pretty interchangeable they're not
really I want to say yes but I think
that they're not 100% interchangeable in
the idea that if both of those were
available to you at the same price and
they had no environmental impact and
they were just perfect to use we'd still
be able to divide that line up
a little bit and some peat moss
typically when we get it fresh from the
bog is gonna have fulvic and humic acids
it's going to have some indigenous
bacteria it's not gonna have to be
washed and rinsed and sat out for a
couple of years and it's going to be a
higher cation exchange capacity it'll
hold more nutrients I mean there's a
reason why Pete Moss is so widely used
and why garden like greenhouses that
have you know millions on the line still
use it even in the presence of coconut
coir being viable and rice hulls being
viable and all these other options so I
think that peat moss has a little bit of
a leg up but if I was forced to I
certainly think I could grow with
coconut coir in our soil recipe and if I
was forced to going out both I think I
could by making a compost that was not
quite as nutrient dense and cutting that
with maybe 50% aeration and then from
there adding my starting materials you
could use aged manure that was fairly
devoid of nutrients that's been rinsed
out rained on and that would be kind of
like peat moss so ultimately if I didn't
have a mic I could do it and for you
being out there I probably would avoid
even starting to learn about peat moss
as my soil recipe because it sounds like
it's cost prohibitive and it's
definitely gonna have a big
environmental impact so yeah that was
actually the other thing I was gonna
bring up is that um yeah we don't
produce a lot of thing here so that was
one of the reasons I had heard while I
was so expensive there I'd be doing it
in a side-by-side just to satisfy my
curiosity and I'd import some peat moss
and I would attempt to get my local
recipe to match and miR that and then
exceed that because my natural curiosity
even if I made the best recipe ever I
would probably say dang but I wonder
what if and so if you could get over
that I think that you'll be fine but if
you really have to try it do it other
than that I would say locally just you
know try and work with it now if you
start reading a coconut core you'll find
a little bit of difference one of the
things I found we sent a recipe off that
was half peat moss half coconut coir as
the portion of the base we used that for
and the soil test came back very similar
a little lower CEC a little bit
different a couple numbers but it was
almost a interchangeable so I would say
with confidence that as long as you can
balance the calcium and
potassium and all that stuff and have a
little bit of thought to the salt that
might be in that coconut core and really
wash it I don't think you'll have any
issues fantastic
so to someone who's currently running
synthetics and wants to switch over to a
Yank what would you suggest is the best
way to convert so maybe not necessarily
talking about like soil mix is quite yet
but if they wanted to convert would you
say look you know just just go all out
just you know switch all hydro all
organic all you say no let's just do
like maybe a few buckets organic and get
the hang of it and then slowly switch
over or how would you recommend they
they switch from one to the other
there's a tough question from it a
large-scale agricultural perspective and
from business perspective it's always
advisable to just do a small test and
then go from there but I'm always at the
thought that when used to stand on the
fence and you're in the middle you get
shot from both sides and it's really
advisable sometimes to burn your brayer
put all your efforts double down and
know that's what you're going to do no
matter what a lot of people that are
going to organics that's their mentality
they're not going to retreat they're not
gonna do hydro that's not their mindset
that's all they want to do but for
people who really don't have a emotional
investment in this you just say hey
whatever better I don't care if it's
hydro
it's synthetic and as chemicals or if
it's organic I just want to grow what
fits my lifestyle and works for me I
think that the easiest setup for someone
like that is going to be looking at what
they're comparing it to and I know a lot
of the hydro guys can get just crazy
with the number of nutrients they get
into so then their personality's gonna
come into play some guys find organics
so easy a dredge and crazy they're
always looking for extra things to do
yeah I guess circling back around to
your question about what's the easiest
way to start we have two methods that we
share it build a soil and one of them
for a beginner if they have an earth box
which is basically a sub irrigated
planter it's a plastic growing container
that has the water that's held
underneath the soil and it's held up by
a tray and above that's just soil the
plant grows in it like normal but once
it hits the bottom instead of just
hitting the fabric pot it digs into a
reservoir of waat of water and this
eliminates the watering factor which a
lot of times somebody moving over to
organics is going to underwater
over water and that's gonna be their
steepest learning curve and so that's a
great way to mitigate that now prior to
me using earth boxes I would have said
earth boxes are stupid and I never use
it I only used the fabric grow pots or
plastic grill pots and the fabric or my
favorite and as long as you use a little
bit of mulch on top and you start to
sometimes people like in a 15-gallon
will put a tray underneath and you can
water from the top and also pour a
little water in the tray to help it wick
up and water from the bottom there's a
few ways you can take that with a pretty
easy learning curve we have a moisture
meter that'll allow you to probe into
the soil and find out if it's dry or wet
and that'll help a first-time grower to
determine if they're over under watering
but certainly what we hear about all the
time when they're going to a big bed of
soil to make it easier to get a large
yield we find the first thing to have a
problem with is how much water to add
and the rule of thumb on large scale has
always been what I've always heard from
people is said hey if you have a hundred
gallon pot you're gonna add 10 gallons
it's a 10 percent rule if you have a 10
gallon pot you'll water a gallon every
time but that doesn't always translate
in organics because it's gonna be
dependent upon your humidity you know
and a lot of other factors so I guess
the easiest way is either a fabric grow
container or that earth box and then my
favorite is a large large grow bed but
most people that are willing to just try
out organics don't want to put a couple
hundred gallons of soil in their bedroom
and not have the ability to move it
around on a whim so yeah so funnily
enough I got a friend who was in a
similar situation so he's just switched
over to organics and now he's in I
suspect he's over watered a bit and he's
now got a lot of bugs as a result what
would be your recommendations for
someone who's just switched over I've
actually got a few friends in this
position and they've just which do
organic and because they've been using
some of those hydroponic principles you
know like obviously Coco absorbs a lot
more water than soil so people naturally
overwater I find what would be your
advice to them in terms of getting rid
of the bugs because I've got a lot of
friends who are kind of acquits and
trying to deal with these bugs and they
that's kind of the biggest downside they
find coming from synthetics
interesting to me because when you get
bugs in synthetics it's game over in
organics you know there's a lot that can
happen before it really takes your crop
down and so it's depending on how you
look at it of course somebody that's
used to visioning a white lab coat in a
sterile room is gonna have a hard time
looking at soil that has bugs moving
around minute but most of the bugs we
find in the soil are beneficial and if
they're a fast-moving mite usually it's
a soil mite and they're assisting in
that whole ecosystem and so a lot of
times it's just a false thought hey is
the plant growing great yes it is don't
worry about it of course if you got
fungus gnats if you've got actual spider
mites or Russert mites or you know all
these problems we hear about those are
specific problems that you're gonna need
to address fungus gnat seems to come up
as the really common pest that doesn't
seem to do a lot of damage but it's
really annoying what would be your
recommendation for getting rid of it
it's really coming up as a problem with
a lot of our customers as well it can
become a problem in hydroponics and it
can really be detrimental because they
eat the organic matter so if you're
growing in rock wool on slabs and you
get fungus gnats they can decimate your
grill in organics it's more of an
annoyance and it can be very very
annoying and of course it can get into
your flowers and stick there and it
could you know hit you in the face when
you open the tent or go to look in your
grow and so a few things we can do one
of the least expensive portions of our
grows the mulch layer and a lot of guys
are having a really thick mulch layer
with a lot of decaying organic matter
that fungus gnats love and so until this
soil in a no-till system ramps up to a
full ecosystem where there are Rove
beetles and there are predator mites and
there's all these things happening that
balance that you'll notice things come
in in booms and so a huge fungus in that
population you could just leave it on
its own and probably in the next six
months to a year maybe a few months it's
gonna go away something else is gonna
come in and eat it and of all balance
out but we can't just sit around and
wait it ruins crops it has problems so
we can remove our complete mulch layer
throw out the trash remove it from the
room that will remove a lot of the
larvae and then from there you can
sprinkle some neem cake down if you
don't have access to neem you can use
some insect
if you don't have access to that you
don't have to use any of these
ingredients you can create a barrier
with the next step and that's to put I
like to use a premium compost or
vermicompost and put about an inch layer
up to two inches as a barrier covering
all of the soil that would have
previously been infested and something
about the beneficial the probiotics the
organisms that are in that compost or in
that worm castings the vermicompost it's
Smothers amount and it really wipes out
a big majority of them so you're back
down into maintenance mode instead of
you know a huge eradication effort and
then from there don't water immediately
keep it dry so that the adults can't
immediately lay eggs on the top and you
can put some sticky traps start to kill
then while you're smothering the you
know larvae below and that works really
really well what I'd like to do is do
all of that but the exact same time once
I remove the multi layer to get the soil
really wet so that I can avoid watering
the top for a day or two I like to get
nematodes predator nematodes I'm not
sure if they're available in Australia
but we have a number of insector ease
out here and I use our becau organics
and we have a couple others but I order
one that's specifically for fungus gnats
and you water it into the soil and they
eat all the larvae and they really not
come down within the first week and then
you can also get hypo abscess miles
predator mites and those would be you
know coming already in your worm
castings if you're getting them fresh
but you can certainly buy them and add
them to your soil and they should do the
one-two punch when you have the
nematodes and the mites and you've
removed a lot of the larvae the multi
layer and you got the sticky traps it
should be pretty much eradicated at that
point I haven't had a ton of luck with
diatomaceous earth in organics because
we keep the multi layer so moist and
diatomaceous earth is not helpful when
it's wet and that's also why the fungus
not like it because it's wet up there in
that mulch layer so you may want to do
some bottom watering and get the top a
little bit drier but there's also if you
do some research there's a product
called BT I bacillus thuringiensis ray
leus and they're in a product called
mosquito dunks and it's a common
bacteria that they use and it definitely
helps destroy the larvae and stuff
that process so using one or all of
these techniques can really help I also
hear about people doing some soil
drenches so I would ask around and talk
to other organic farmers and maybe look
at other products that exist in your
market but those are all the steps that
we take that seem to have the biggest
effect you have fantastic and for anyone
listening in Australia every one of
those things is available and I've used
most of them they work pretty well so
just creating a barrier is a good way so
you'll even notice that Nick's as a
product it's like a recycled glass it
looks like perlite you just put it on
top of your soil I think you could
probably just use perlite but no well I
would prefer like I said it's compost
and all that and so cool great
recommendation so I'm in a previous
episode we had a guest recommend that we
all check out insect frass as you
mentioned earlier now insect frass I
believe it's available in Australia
should be available in most everywhere
but it's pretty new to a lot of people
give us a bit of a rundown on the
benefits of insect frass well when you
look at the manufacturers and what
they're advertising a lot of them will
key back to a chitin and chitin is a
material that is in crustacean in the
shells that's in the insects and their
exoskeleton it's also in the cell walls
of fungus and so what what we've learned
is that the enzyme that digests chitin
is really helpful and it stimulates the
plant's SAR or systemic required
resistance and kind of like a booster
shot gets them on the defense and
besides that the kite maize can help if
it's perpetuated and there's a lot of
chitin is it can help be a deterrent to
certain pests and so when we use insect
frass it comes from insects and not only
does it have a kind of like a worm
casting like effect as far as
fertilization it's an it's the poop of
insects the benefit here is the insects
are all eating plant material and so
it's a really organic process and
usually it's pretty I guess I wouldn't
say really affordable but as things
start to scale up where we're getting it
is from
mealworm farms and bug farms that are
usually meant for feeding reptiles and
things like that and so just like worm
farming had this by-product called worm
castings that become popular in
gardening the bug farms are having a
byproduct and it's called insect frass
and that is turning out to have you know
multiple different benefits and I think
what we're seeing is in any ecosystem
bugs are gonna be there they're gonna be
eating they're gonna be pooping we're
gonna have worms underneath we're gonna
have compost from all the leaves we're
now finally mimicking that putting all
of it into our organic soil and it's
like wow the whole thing is right here
now and so I think that's where that
real extra effect is coming from but
I've heard a lot about frost recently
too a lot of people are starting to use
it
awesome yeah I've heard it too it's a
good sustainable amendment sustainable
so just kind of going back to a point
you made a little while ago about the
kind of um the elite ivities that exists
around organics how do you think we get
around this because like for me
personally like I try to be as non
elitist about it as I can at times but
sometimes it's even just like it's hard
to get around it like I've got some
friends who grow synthetically and like
I just don't want to smoke synthetic
weed like that it's nothing against them
it's that's just my kind of personal
stance how do you you know how do you
say to someone hey man I don't want to
smoke your weed because it's synthetic
without coming across as super elitist
or just in general you know what I mean
I don't think there's a great way to do
that I mean if you go to a buddy's house
and he's gonna you know microwave some
some canned soup and cook you up a
frozen burger patty and look at you as
if it's the best thing that they've ever
made before you're not gonna want to
look at it and say [__] I'm sorry man I
want to eat this it's [__] but at the
same time if you're somebody who has a
very specific diet it cares about what
you eat you know all the chemicals that
are in that you know what went into the
process you know it doesn't taste as
good and you're thinking the [__] can't
you see what I'm saying the McDonald's
burger might sell a lot of burgers but
it's not the best burger I can make a
better one especially if I had my own
cap knew what a ate processed it myself
built the fire and cooked it myself and
so I think the difference just becomes
really when they don't care at all down
to personality and it's just better not
to try and
Venson better not to have that friction
in your relationship and just appreciate
them for who they are and if they start
to open up at some point maybe you can
share it I find the number one way to
open them up is to share some of your
herb with them and they're gonna go what
like how does that happen
and that might be enough but beyond that
I feel like it's just a losing argument
yeah okay cool so a lot of people like
to talk a lot of trash about woodchips
in soil mixes like whenever I see a
photo and I can visibly see woodchips I
just know there's gonna be some comment
somewhere about like oh you go woodchips
in your soil
what's your thoughts on woodchips are
they really the worst thing ever the
only thing I really read about them is
that they can kind of dive the pH a
little know I know what chips are
fantastic and from Leica if I was to
improve a property putting a multi layer
down on truckloads of wood chips that
were from potentially you know downed
trees that had to be fallen for certain
reasons like beetle infestation or they
had to they were old and rotting and
removed from other people's property
chipped up instead of making compost
they went to my property phenomenal
results I mean so highly fungal really
helps build soil fast and that high
lignin turns into good humic and fulvic
as a compost so I don't think it's a bad
thing here's where the fear comes from
there's a I'm gonna say it wrong but
there's a process called allelopathy
where trees will not want to have other
trees competing in their inner territory
and so they exude and excrete these
chemicals that will not it will make it
harder for things to grow there and so
the fear has always been that if you use
these particular woodchips especially
from a green waste yard that has all the
different types of trees blended up
you're going to get some early low
Pathak wood and it's going to ruin your
soil I've only found that to be an issue
when it's mixed into the soil in a high
ratio as opposed to compost at first or
just top dressed when it's top dressed I
don't see any issue it's a perfectly
fine mulch and when it's composted it's
a great material addition to compost
that helps provide a low-cost
sustainable source of compost of course
not deforesting but using trees that may
have been pulled for various reasons
other than that
I I guess I haven't heard as much about
the wood in your soil or anything I know
that certain places have talked about
bad about municipal compost facilities
that are shredding pallets and then
composting that I'm calling your compost
then I could see kind of the concern
there for the chemicals in the wood and
you know all the nails and stuff like
that but all in all if I had to chop a
tree down my property I think I'd be
really excited to use that in fact users
should list the listeners should look up
a process called Hugo culture it's a
permaculture principle and it's based on
burying rotting wood trunks and stalks
underground to eliminate watering and to
build an ecosystem and it really really
has some power yeah fantastic
so um it seems like there within the
organic movement there there's a little
bit of an appeal to nature fallacy and
this this question is going to be a bit
extended but essentially the whole
movement around indigenous microbes now
in Australia for example we've got a
very specific environment where we have
extremely low phosphorus in the soil and
the microbes have adapted over time and
as a result the native plants really
don't actually like to have a lot of
phosphorous in the soil and so
essentially whenever I see people going
and trying to you know populate these
indigenous microbes I just think to
myself well you're gonna be adding them
to a medium which is high phosphorus and
I know that those microbes can't handle
high phosphorus so they're just gonna
get wiped out by the treaty almost
instantly and if I thought about it do
you do you think that this you know
indigenous microbes thing is a bit of an
appeal to nature fallacy or there is
maybe some truth to it and just it works
out in Australia's case that it's not
going to work too well for you I don't
know I think the time will tell you know
we don't know enough at all to tell that
and I think that a lot of people are
wanting to use purchased microbes or
indigenous microbes and the research is
showing that those aren't around months
later but what they are doing is kind of
like a team of soldiers going in and
training the locals how to do their job
and so you get some of them to have
immediately some of them stay and
persist and nature always has this
ability to have all that diversity and
that's where its benefit is where we
come and slaughter that
by using synthetics is where we start to
have to add back and guess but like you
said indoors with a soil recipe two
totally different high phosphorus I
don't I don't really know the answer if
you're indoors the indigenous microbes
may not be of any benefit other than the
fact that you could cultivate them for
free
and if they were really good at actually
saw you buy zhing phosphorus because of
what they did for the local plants you
might find benefit in lowering your
phosphorus in put your soil recipe it's
so knowing that would be beneficial and
might have some effect we're just
throwing into a high phosphorus recipe
like you said that might actually hurt
it may just be a waste of your time and
so more education more testing is gonna
need to be done to say definitively but
I've heard from a number of growers that
are using these phosphorus all you buy
zhing products on a super soil with high
phosphorus they're having a ton of
issues where growers that are using a
balanced you know low phosphorus all
recipe are experiencing really great
effects from it so that's all anecdotal
is just stuff I'm hearing from people
but it just shows how much more research
means to be honest every one of these
questions is great questions and I know
that nature finds a way so when I use
the micro eyes I when I try just create
a balanced phosphorus instead of an
excess I have great results I know like
Michael astera recommends a lot more
phosphorus in our soil and certain
growers will want that but I haven't
necessarily found the need and I find
that it shuffles that I've balanced
around to other areas so ask me again in
a year and I might have a very different
answer we'll see yeah no worries
so another one which kind of seems like
maybe it's I don't know I'm not going to
say a fad but it kind of seems like
splitting hairs to me when we look at
the Korean natural farming or the
no-till movements in certain regards
like it seems like there's all these
names and all these kind of ways to
individualize your specific style of
farming we're in the end I think we
could just use like this broad term of
natural organic or something like that
do you agree with that that we should
stop trying to you know split organic
into these subdivisions or you think oh
it's just semantics it doesn't really
matter
I don't know I think that from just
learning about it at all and teaching it
we should you know not really categorize
it that
you know which one's better but learning
about these nuances has been helpful for
me
you know I think that where it becomes a
problem was whether ego gets inserted so
if it's kind of like oh I knew about you
know Fukuoka before you did
I knew about Cho before you did and ha I
make my own nutrients and you don't
therefore I'm better that can go but the
different segments to me are like
specialization with an educational field
and so when you go to school you can
specialize deeper and Neri or narrower
within a niche and I feel like as long
as they're all working we can maybe mine
some valuable information from that and
what I mean by that is for instance the
Korean natural farming's latest
extension is you Dom natural farming
chose Sun I believe and so we start to
look at that and the difference between
show Cho is Cho uses a lot of molasses
which is imported not grown there and is
expensive whereas udam uses leaf bolt
harvested within digital microorganisms
and is going to be fermented on the site
where the plants are grown at that
temperature and so to them it's like why
would we do this different you're gonna
import a lot of stuff but from the
outside in their favorite thing to make
that's very important to a lot of these
recipes and foliar is called a digital
wetting agent which involves bringing in
potassium hydroxide from without in the
farm and making your own soap at a low
cost and so for me I'm like well yucca
is easier for me to get a great wetting
agent is not zapping it is a great
fungicide I'm gonna use that because
it's just as cheap and I don't want to
wait and make my own wedding agent so if
we can't and instead of learn about I
guess embrace our differences and learn
why they're there and then each person
individually figure out whether that
should be applied to them or not it's
probably the best way but because we
don't all have done limited time to
research all the methods we end up just
kind of asking and that's where I think
a lot of us get it shut down is you know
you'll Alaska is this way better of
course it is I've been doing this for 10
years it's all I think about this is the
only way but most people that are honest
will say that they all work no matter of
where you live what region where in the
world what you're trying to do and we're
gonna have a different answer for a lot
of these situations yeah so um I guess
kind of another one that might be a
little bit of semantics but how do you
feel
about exotic ingredients you know
recently we've seen the rise of herb I
say right the shilajit now how do you
feel about these types of ingredients
you think on the most part there's
probably something that you can do its
job reasonably cheaper or do you think
some of these kind of exotic ingredients
do have a spot in the garden yes because
a lot of us are one an experiment at the
highest level with all these things
we're gonna be reading about all these
things that work for human health
like shilajit and you're gonna be
reading about Ormus and different things
that you can make but without a doubt
I've never found anything that just
doubles my yield or just makes
everything so incredibly different a few
of them like you know good compost some
kelp meal compost tea certainly was one
of those wow that really worked and so
there's a few things that just make a
huge difference but some of these things
I'm just not sure are worth the cost
and so just purely looking at them are
they do they do something but versus
their return on investment a lot of
times don't pan out you know you don't
see essential oils used on big farms
because it's just you'd have to grow
billion acres of plants just to make the
essential oils to turn around and put it
on all our crops but for an indoor
gardener essential oils can work really
good so I guess I guess there's value
but everybody's gonna have to ask you
know that on their own and the most
value comes when you're really
researching this I find if somebody just
gives me something and I try it for some
reason it's not the same as me reading
romance and learning about every effect
it's going to have and then seeing if I
see that so you do something about that
law of attraction the power of thought
you know there's some products that'll
definitely have that fake effect that
placebo effect and so weeding that out I
think is important and a number of
products will come back on the market
there's just a cycle that happens and
you know full vyx a lot of times get
popular and then they go out because so
many fake foot companies come on the
market people realize it doesn't work
and then they go by the wayside and then
the real companies stick around and
people start using it again it gets
popular then it goes away and so it's
always going to depend on the
all of these inputs as well a lot of
snake oil salesman wolf they keen on the
latest keyword and sell you stuff so
just just do your research if you want
to try one of these newer products yeah
so just touching on how you said that um
one ingredient you had noticed a big
improvement from was like quality
compost a you of the opinion that really
high quality worm castings in a fermi
compost is the best compost or do you
feel that there's another compost which
maybe is a bit better
they're good for different purposes worm
castings will have the most nutrient
density typically and then here's that
here's the difference a thermophilic
compost will go to temperature to make
it so that it's viable for use and if
it's done over a really long period of
time it'll have really good balance of
nutrients and pH and all that compost
isn't gonna have a lot of minerals it's
all organic matter and so mineralizing
that compost is always going to be
important and if you mineralize compost
feed it to worms add extras like kelp
meal and things like that
it's not gonna go to temperature again
the worms will work it through bacterial
action and fungal action and it's gonna
keep a lot of secondary benefits that
might be available in these plants so
for people that are looking for the
hormones the metabolize the second berry
you know properties of compost worm
castings is where it's at and so that's
why everybody uses both but what we're
learning from a scalability perspective
is that following these recipes is not
affordable and then it would make more
sense to make your own castings and use
those for side dressing top dressing and
teas and then focus on your main soil to
be built on other materials like compost
okay interesting yet because I was
actually gonna ask what would you
recommend yeah doing the opposite of
what you said well I may be using a
slightly reduced quality compost in the
bucket but top dressing with a high
quality compost is something I'd always
heard was that a huge benefit of top
dressing with say vermi compost was you
know the the leaching of the microbes
down into the root ball and so that
could kind of improve the compost down
there if it wasn't quite as good and you
say you didn't have the money to buy a
lot of worm castings yep and worms
always do it right people don't and so
if you go to a local spot they may not
have the carbon to nitrogen ratio proper
which means that the off gassing of
methane and nitrogen gases will be high
it's not gonna happen
nutrients where when I test castings
it's like really high in nitrogen really
high in potassium really high in
phosphorus and that's why we're seeing
those effects even if the microbes
aren't fully intact and it's a little
older so worm castings are significantly
more potent and that's why their money
is is that's why it's more expensive but
contrary to that they can also be a
little too potent and so if you base it
on a lot of our recipes at 30% compost
and you get a really potent vermicompost
you might have some problems of excess
nitrogen excess potassium excess
phosphorus and we ran into that the
reason why is about 90 percent of the
comp of the worm castings on the market
the United States just thrown a number
out there it's got to be upwards of that
percentage are made by unco and they're
a processor that basically makes a
product that's devoid of nutrient and so
you can grow in a hundred percent unco
worm castings you can't do that with
homemade and I think that's a big
difference so one of the reasons why is
if you start feeding a said Reed peat in
a bucket with a little bit of grain to a
worm that process the weight of input
material is the weight of castings they
get out with our castings when we have a
regular farm doing it they put about 8
pounds of feed in to get 2 pounds of
castings out those other six pounds are
for the worms and it's just a big
difference in nutrient density and so
you have to use a lot of times around
that 10 to 15% mark to hit that sweet
spot yeah and so um I guess the question
would then be is if you are gonna make
your own worm castings what would you
recommend is the best way to do it I've
read some stuff which says you know you
should use if you want to go for those
really nutrient-dense costumes as you
spoke about maybe use a lot of manure as
your base instead of cocoa you know what
are your recommendations yeah so if you
wanted to make a material that would
that when composted was very low cec
very you know not nutrient rich that
actually might serve a purpose as a base
kind of like peat moss and it would
certainly be high in bacterial and it
would be a good material to work with
but when you start thinking about making
a really nutrient dense top dressing and
T quality vermicompost we're gonna you
know relate that to the quality of our
inputs and so the best would be to start
with a thermal
what compost is the starting point it
would remove all those seeds and all the
problems that happen from just just
recycling waste like throwing your
Tomatoes right in there you might have
some tomato seeds pop up because it's
not gonna be you know fully composted so
you make a thermophilic compost and you
get the carbons and nitrogens and greens
and then from there to make it even
better a lot of people will focus on
using really nutrient-rich plants to
make their compost like metal and
comfrey and all of the plants that are
already revered at gardening because
they are able to draw nutrients from
deep within the soil and you use those
along with uh some straw or whatever
Browns you find that are good and you
make a compost that by itself would be
phenomenal and then you feed that to
worms with a few extra benefits like
kelp and things after the compost has
gone to temperature and cooled back down
that to me makes the most nutrient dense
compost or vermicompost and the compost
the word the worm castings we're
currently using are from a facility that
does use manure and they are incredibly
nutrient dense so I would agree with you
on that okay awesome
and so just touching on some cover crops
like you just mentioned there with the
nettle in the comfrey do you think that
having a cover crop like those or
something like clove or each - any of
these nitrogen depositing companion
plants do you think that they outweigh
the benefits of say having a nice big
top dressing layer of compost and you
know like if you had to pick one or the
other which one would you choose
essentially well from indoor perspective
probably just top dressing but there's a
number of benefits we have a facility
that's multiple tens of thousands of
square feet indoors and instead of doing
big beds they ended up doing I think 20
or 30 gallon containers on rolling
tables and so for them a little bit of
clover that they're growing in their
acts as a binder to the soil and keeps
the entire soil mass intact so when
they're hand watering it doesn't shift
the soil and so for them that was really
imperative that they had that process
and they feel like it also is feeding
those eggs Yoon's to the soil and
keeping the soil alive and a lot of
people will tell you that that's just
totally imperative and I agree but
picking one or the other I think that
you had a little more nutrient power
command on the spot by just top dressing
personally all rather the top
mulching and I'll just top dress right
over the top and smother it so you get a
little bit of both yeah and then in the
field when we have time is our benefit
we can harvest we can sow cover crop
after harvest let that grow up and then
we can smother that through winter and
then we can tell it back under or top
dress over it get all of the benefits
from the free nitrogen that's taken out
of the air as well as the top dress
where the way most people are using
cover crop indoors it's not really
fixing nitrogen and nodules and and
putting it deep into the soil it's more
once that cover crop dies and returns to
the soil that is adding its benefit so
so if people could grow one plant may be
outside or around that's gonna help out
with the growth of cannabis what would
be the one plant you recommend they grow
alongside it so to speak like so for me
it's a leviair because i it's got a lot
of good purposes in my opinion yep LM
very probably the one I recommend
because most the plants that grow have
to have some benefit whether it's
beautiful or whether it produces food or
you know an aloe vera just has a ton of
them if you look it up it has all the
amino acids it has the you know
salicylic acid for rooting it has
benefits as far as happening and wetting
agent you can use it for burns and it's
a great plant to grow it's very easy to
grow is the other key point you you know
you almost can't mess it up if you get
the right type of aloe and if it's got a
lot of Sun you can water in lots of
nutrients in the winter you can just
almost not water it it'll stay alive if
you practically kill it you can bring it
back to life beside that comfrey is
another really popular one
the problem is comfrey can be invasive
and take over so you've you know they
found that the Bocking for Bocking 14 or
a very popular cutting of comfrey that
doesn't develop seeds it's sterile and
that one in particular has a good carbon
to nitrogen ratio so when you cut the
leaves off and top dress with them or
make compost they turn to compost very
very quickly and they have some
secondary benefits that are good to have
on the farm too like that they can come
in the nickname for it is knit bone it
helps heal broken bones and you can make
a poultice with it and in the soil it
has a lot of potassium and it'll have
you know a good rounding of other
nutrients so those two the aloe or the
comforter would be great to grow and
very easy to grow so yeah fantastic
so
for me when I found Koontz Mix and
admittedly it was through your site it
was a pretty big game-changer for me in
terms of the results I was getting it
was phenomenal
however as you've kind of alluded to a
few times when I went to upscale this
the worm castings became a bit cost
prohibitive do you find that there is
fairly similar results from using
because I find that you can get pretty
high quality general compost and and
it's pretty good do you think that from
using say a good quality compost as
opposed to the Carson's you can get a
fairly comparable result yep I think so
as long as it's good compost and we've
actually switched our recipes to exclude
the vermicompost it was really keeping
us to the point where we had no profit
margin we couldn't you know get it to a
sort of resell it because they couldn't
afford to ship it and all that and the
castings was the problem I mean 15 to 20
grand just for a truckload of castings
and we start burning through them it can
cause a really big problem for cash flow
and then inconsistencies that would come
from having to source that much when you
know people just don't make that much
where compost they can and there's a
really good reason for composting and
people are already doing it at scale and
they understand it better so when you
find compost facilities that have really
good compost tests and you can learn to
interpret those find the pH look at the
carbon to nitrogen ratio look at the
salt levels you can pretty easily make a
great soil and then from there make your
own dang castings for free put worms
right in your soil they will turn that
compost into castings for you while
you're planting rose it's like it's
brilliant and then on top of that you
can take that worm castings out of your
bin and top dress you get all the
benefits without all the expense or if
you really are just starting you can buy
a small amount of local castings and use
those for teas and really stretch it so
all in all I'm starting to get off the
high horse of castings or bust and start
to say that a good compost is probably a
lot more important and making your own
castings will be the big price
difference so yeah so if you were gonna
recommend to like say a good friend a
sow mix and they're just starting out
would you give them coop thanks or would
you give them maybe something else like
what would your recommendation
someone who's just looking to get into
organics yup just coots mix or for
instance if those ingredients might be
hard to find and it would keep them from
taking action I would say just mix up a
recipe of three parts one part you know
peat moss or coconut coir or whatever
that type of medium that you have
available make sure it's good and rinsed
and it's a good quality peat moss over
you know we're not gonna rinse it with
cocoa that's why I say that the next
part would be your aeration perlite
pumice lava rock something to have some
air holding capacity in there and then
the third component would be the compost
and from there you pretty much have a
good soil but when you're using peat
moss it's a little acidic and the
numbers aren't quite right so we add a
little bit more calcium to it via waste
your shell flour gypsum so I would still
recommend those normal numbers and then
from there if you didn't have like the
crustacean me on the neem and the kelp
that as part of the coots mix I would
say go grab a tomato fertilizer that's
organic you like follow the recipe put
it in your soil and use that as your
first grill I think you'll crush it from
there you'll experience some benefits by
getting some really high-quality
amendments and starting to learn about
each of them individually but tomatoes
are similar fast-growing annual or
biennial plant kind of treated as an
annual so similar nutrient requirements
and I think most people are aware of
that so out here there's a number of
tomato fertilizers you can buy problem
for me was I pick up that box and I'd
read cottonseed meal and realize oh
that's GMO number one pesticide sprayed
the the next one is there's feather meal
big chicken farms all GMO corn fed and
you know hormones and so it you find
right away that all of the fertilizers
are usually just someone's waste sold at
a huge profit margin and that's why we
ended up going to these specific recipes
but certainly if you're already doing
synthetic going down the street by the
tomato fertilizer mixing the three parts
together I think you'll have good
success great and just specifically I
found it almost impossible to find
crustacean meal in Australia just for
that one amendment what would you
recommend is like a good interchangeable
we're mainly after the calcium carbonate
there and so it's just a natural source
of calcium if you have a waster shell
flour great you're done you don't need
the crustacean
the one thing that it does bring to the
table though is a little bit of meat
that might have been in there so a
little nitrogen and I might also bring
to the table the chitin which you know
we talked about previously that's
available in insect frass and so even
then if you didn't have it I don't think
it's totally imperative and so you could
just get away by using a lime which is
calcium carbonate and if you have an
agricultural lime it's gonna be mostly
calcium and about four percent magnesium
if you have a dolomite it's gonna be
higher magnesium but here's the kicker
and then museums not the water soluble
part the calcium is and so you're mostly
giving a calcium from that anyways until
a few years down the road so I wouldn't
worry terribly about the crustacean you
know that's one of those that's a little
more easily replaceable I would use
insect frass as a direct replacement if
that's available so yeah and so for
people like the Rev he often advocates
that um you know dolomite limes quite
good in your soil mixes and I remember
the first post I ever read on Builder
soil was essentially a link and it was
dissecting through the super soil recipe
and I was really impressed with it and
the biggest thing I always remember
about that article was that you were
fairly adamant that you don't really
need dolomite in your soil mix and it
just forms like these little anaerobic
pockets and it's not even really doing
what a lot of people think it's doing
would you mind maybe explaining this a
little better and do you still stand by
that philosophy of don't really need
dolomite so I don't think it's as
detrimental as I maybe previously
thought when I was getting educated in
the subject I know people that use it
it's not ruining their soil by any means
but you know most those people aren't
keeping it around for years at a time
and it may not be hardening up but the
wicking and the moisture holding
capacity may not be as good and it's
certainly been proven on an agricultural
scale so what I started to do is instead
of making up my own opinion and just
going by what I saw 100% I started
researching and you know across the
board at the forefront of soil
remineralisation and soil testing
application they're not using double
mine anymore and it is very cheap you
can buy all over the place but the
calcium to magnesium ratio that we're
looking for is not present in dolomite
it's a little bit off and so over time
it will affect itself now
you're just lining peat-moss it's very
cheap it's available and it works we're
keeping our soil and so in an effort to
avoid that I still hold true that you
don't need dolomite I would rather see
magnesium added separately calcium added
separately and have more control over
that I would rather see waster shell
flour which is more natural there's a
reason why it's fed to every chicken it
has a premium source of calcium and then
on top of that it also rather see maybe
gypsum that brings the sulphur with it
that's so much more beneficial so if
that's all you have you know looking
back on my previous posts I don't think
that I would maybe beat it up as much
but certainly at the if you're gonna be
the one teaching everybody about
building soil right now that's not the
go-to and I still believe that using an
agate and AG lime using that oyster
shell using chips something a lot of the
others it's gonna be better yeah so
we've got some people like the Rev who
advocating some of these really
long-term amendments like green sand and
as you mentioned just that dolomite the
magnesium can take years to become
available do you think they're
advocating the use of such long-lasting
or slow release pavements is a good
thing just because from my experience as
much as we all try to reuse our soil
things often happen and I can't really
guarantee that everyone would have the
same soil in three years from now such
they're really getting all the uses out
of those long-term amendments do you
feel the same way or do you think that's
the you should just hang onto your soil
well I think you should I go to your
soil and if you're one that can planted
that far ahead that's great but I don't
think any of us really can that
accurately I've had a number of people
that grew up in Jersey tell me man I
wouldn't buy anything from there it's
probably dirty but that being said it's
mined other places and so you know there
there was a big kick and it was a fad
and there was a huge market that was
talking about potassium it's important
and green sanehat it and it you should
use it and I'm a big believer that some
of these things that might be a long
term breakdown in a very very active
microbial living soil might actually
break down faster so who knows maybe
we're gonna learn more about that in the
future and double back on that but I
don't like to get a rock dust that's
just potassium or just one direction and
like you said is proven to take a number
of years to break down
you like that the bad use of the space
in that container
I would rather add an ingredient that's
gonna have more power and so that's just
kind of how I looked at it I would
rather use basalt it's got the
paramagnetic energy it's got all of the
micronutrients and there's a number of
other ways to get potassium for instance
from compost and I don't think that we
need such a slow release form so I
definitely don't believe in green sand
but there's never a number of other
ingredients that I'm surprised like
there's a local buddy of mine that got
basalt and instead of getting in rock
dust he got gravel of basalt a larger
chunk of it he said after two years it
was dawn anything a lot of microbes in
his soil and so I'm just I'm thinking
you know maybe it's not about just the
minerals but maybe the coenzyme factor
the energy effect of just having those
minerals there and the ability for the
microbes to play off that energy I know
if there's a Discovery Channel show you
can watch that's about the formulation
of the earth and it talks about basalt
and how the first organic substances
were created at really high temperatures
and it was something to do with the
energy of the rock and all the minerals
there and there was this amino black
substance organic life like created for
the first time and you know I don't
obviously that's not something they're
teaching in school and it's not like
exactly this they're just talking
generally but it still exists it's
exciting enough to consider that you so
maybe there's a possibility Green's hand
has some of that benefit but I feel like
more more of it was a marketing ploy
based on the fact that at that time
people do potassium was important and
they had a mindful of it and so we've
moved away from that and I don't see it
as popular anymore yeah so just staying
on that topic of basalt it's actually
one that's a little more tricky to find
in Australia as well as like things like
glacial rock dust what would be your
recommendation for alternatives to these
ones is regular rock dust a good
replacement to glacial rock dust yeah
well we've got rock dust I've found
basalt is a little harder to find and
I've never seen glacial rock dust
I just think rock dust would be fine
it's weird you know you look at rock
dust and all of a sudden you start to
see like aluminum and you think oh my
god I got to stay away from it but a lot
of these alumina silicon a little bit of
iron silicates they're just locked
this complex where most of the
micronutrients are the coenzymes that's
actually having effect and if you read a
book that's free it's available on the
internet called bread from stones they
started with granite and have really
good effect and I feel like in the
United States if you're towards the East
Coast probably go granite if you're in
the West Coast probably a volcanic or
glacial and so here in Colorado we're
blessed with the where I live down the
street there's a Mesa it's called the
Grand Mesa
we're the largest flat top mountains in
the United States maybe even the world
a few hundred lakes are on top of it and
it's completely encapsulated by a basalt
so for me it's just a no-brainer we just
go right there we get basalt it's got
all the benefits it's being talked about
right now it's got all the energy that
being said if I didn't have it and
granite was right there I'd probably use
it so I would look at what's locally
available a lot of times you can go down
to a gravel production area and just get
some rock dust for free as their waste
product it's the 400 mesh it's like the
powder they just can't do anything with
and you can use that as a rock dust if
you really wanted to you can send it off
to a lab and get it test it and see if
there's anything toxic in it but for the
most part if you go to remineralize org
they really just talked about using
whatever rock dust is locally available
in it having a remineralization effect
on the soil and so I'm still trying to
learn about that but for a while we used
the glacial rock dust and now I'm really
sticking with basalt and it makes a
great texture in our soil so that's
that's where I'm at right now yep and so
when you're looking at just a general
soil or maybe more specifically a
compost do you think that like black is
better like that's the aim for a really
nice humic rich soil you should be
looking to get it nice and dark or not
necessarily I don't know it always
depends you know rock dust a lot of
times we go there as we look at the
Earth's ability to remineralize itself
and in volcanic regions where that's
happened through lava we see a really
increase in the nutrient density of
crops and so if we look at that and from
the lava flow to a high canopy
rainforest we find that there's a lot of
microbes involved in the beginning
processes and so when we look at compost
now we're not looking at minerals we're
looking at an organic matter and so to
get the humic sinful vyx a lot of
premium compost like are all amount
fish compost is broken down with
hardwood and stuff that takes years to
make and it does turn dark black that
being said if you took a manure compost
that it was dark black I'd think that it
was made in a few months I'm guessing it
got way too hot and it was full of way
too many thermophiles
and it just turned black and if you were
to take a hundred percent grass
clippings from your front yard and
cotton from your front yard it'll turn
death black and smell nasty and that
black is not a premium compost but it
certainly turned black so it depends I
would always be asking you how it was
made
yep okay so how do you feel about using
Bokashi as a soil amendment because I've
seen it come up a lot lately but to me
it kind of was initially ringing some
alarm bells like the idea of like
because Bo Kashi obviously wants an
anaerobic environment but in your soil
you want an aerobic environment so how
does that kind of work are they not
working against each other in a way oh
no I used to think that they were
working against each other I was scared
of it then I saw people growing
completely in aerobic Li with great
success and I thought [__] this nature
has more than one way to do things it's
pretty crazy I mean you look at jus daun
farming American tenant is that if it
smells it doesn't matter you know we
need to get over that we used to throat
[__] and blood and sticky stuff all over
our farms and it worked great you know
when you look at other cultures too like
some of the Asian cultures farming for
10,000 plus years without having any
issues and all of a sudden they adopt
Western philosophies and they got major
problems so yeah well I mean have you
ever heard anyone who had looked into a
toyed with the idea of creating cannabis
from humanure
yeah I haven't people have done it I've
even talked to a couple people that are
in the outback there and they live and
they've had composting toilets and
they're more comfortable with the
process and their diet is good and
they've been growing their own in it
having that as a day-to-day conversation
with customers and talking about peeing
for fertilizer and diluting with water
and most of our diets aren't there I'm
not totally comfortable with it from a
permaculture perspective it makes sense
to close the loop and I think you could
successfully do it I think that the only
way I would do that was making a product
that was been used and turned into
compost and maybe grew another crop and
the back crop was used to make the
post that I actually used I would have a
couple layers between being that yeah
but when you're looking at Bokashi
there's a couple different methods so
for instance we talked about boss
gassing that happens when composting if
it's done properly there really
shouldn't be a lot but it does take time
so we're finding in tests that people
can Bokashi compost significantly faster
so for me I try not to say one's better
than the other if I'd Bokashi composting
it could be a tool where in my kitchen
when I used to do it more often it was
because it was winter it's snowing out I
don't have a thermo compost pile going
and I have some food scraps I want to
recycle so I open the bucket I put the
Bokashi and I'll use it but most people
aren't using the Bokashi compost or the
Bokashi product as the actual fertilizer
I mean that could go get buried in your
yard or processed through the worms or
fed to the compost we're talking about
using the actual Bokashi as a fertilizer
and it does have a pretty good NPK so it
can acts as a fertilizer the digitus
microbes that are the microbes that are
on it like the lactobacillus and things
they're actually Faculty of anaerobes so
they don't have to have anaerobic
environment to work and you know the
lactic acid is certainly being a good
decomposer so adding that in depending
on who you're talking to if they might
be making a soil from scratch and you
want to out-compete a lot of times
mixing it into a soil could be a good
idea and I've not seen a a problem from
doing it when it's in the proper
proportion
I personally don't mix it into my soil
though I would use it only as a top
dressing or I would use it for my
Bokashi compost other people are using
it for teas and so if anything what's
exciting is that people are finding
benefit to it and it's working even in
the face of the fact that a few years
ago I would have said anaerobic is gonna
kill it all you just can't do that
that's so I'm just a neighbor that it's
like the complete opposite of what we
said actually still works and so I'm
just trying to learn from that right now
and what I found is that fermenting some
of your own and fertilizers works pretty
well and look how she has a place but
it's not like a make-or-break must-have
item in my book I think that the
relationships that I've created with
people that like Bokashi keep me talking
about it a lot but other than that if I
absolutely had to have a few things it
would just be some soil you know it's
some compost I don't think the cost you
number one item on there yeah so if
someone was looking to get their own
compost pile started whether it be
through Bokashi or other means would you
recommend that will not recommend but do
you think that you could use both Kashi
to kind of kickstart a compost pile like
my friends got this big compost pile and
it's not that thermophilic but it is
quite anaerobic and I tell him like you
should consider throwing some Bokashi in
the middle of that and it might really
kickstart things you think that's the
case or probably not I think you
probably would but you know I don't know
if it's just gonna be from if you were
to just throw some grain in the pile it
might be enough you know extra kick and
nitrogen or whatever is required from
the scenes to kick-start that you know
if you look if you go buy a product at
the store called compost starter you'll
flip up on the back and realize it's
alfalfa meal crustacean meal it's just
some you know some nitrogen having
materials in it that helps kick start
the process sometimes they'll have a
little bacteria in it and what's neat is
that there is the bacteria in it and
that's a lot of times what's considered
a starter so I think it'd be a great
place to start and here's the great
thing if it doesn't work it's not gonna
hurt anything
that being said most of the people that
are doing thermophilic compost they're
not including Bokashi now they're
keeping them separate on my property
I'll dump the Bokashi right on my thermo
compost but I still considered a thermo
compost I'm not Bokashi in the process
they're separate from each other yeah
and so if someone did want to say start
their own compost pile whether it be you
know quite cooking their soil and just
for anyone who's not aware I appreciate
Ronnie's but you know whenever like
someone like sub cool says cooking soil
like they really just mean composting so
if someone was to start their own
compost pile and make either the Cootes
mix or the supersoul how long would you
recommend composting at four and would
you recommend turning it regularly I mix
it and plant directly into it I mean
we're putting very small amounts of
inputs premium compost where most of our
initial nutrients are coming from peat
moss and aeration there's no reason to
cook it when you make a super soil and
you add tons of nutrients out of
proportion that need to be kind of
homogenized he's the word I like to use
into the mix it makes a ton of sense to
moisten it and to let it sit to turn it
and the reason why is the inside of the
pile is gonna get hot and the outside is
going to stay cool so when you turn it
it puts the cool part back into the
inside and make sure that it
all homogenized evenly and once it cools
back down you know that it's not going
to go thermal and burn your plants and
if there wasn't excess and some
nutrients that needed to be released by
the bacteria that process has now
happened when we get above 200 gallons
per container even in a kootz mix I want
to let it sit at least a week or two and
see what the temperatures look like
because even a basic recipe can go
thermal if it's in enough volume that's
why making your own compost at home is
typically a minimum three by three by
three pile another reason why Bokashi is
popular is because most people don't
have enough waste to make a three by
three by three pile and so they end up
doing cold composting that takes years
or a tumbler and it's not as good as
thermal compost and so then they have
them seed sprouting and have flies in it
and larva and bugs and so everybody's
gonna determine what's most important
from him you're just growing vegetables
on the field if you're throwing it on
the lawn it could be called compost it
could be Prakash e2b anything if it's
going in your prized plant that's actual
medicine for a disease you're trying to
fight in your one indoor grow that
you're paying electricity for you might
get a lot more specific about what's
going in there so so on a question
that's maybe a little left of field have
you ever heard from maybe a customer or
just friends that using certain
amendments is able to really alter the
properties of the cannabis and I mean
more so than just say like if it was
deficient then then you give it a
suitable environment obviously it's
gonna come out different but like the
specific example I've been told of is I
know someone and they grow these really
skunky strains and they said that when
they use more sulfur amendments in their
soil it can really make those skunky
smells come out because they're
typically characterized by those thiols
sulfur groups do you think there's any
truth in this or maybe it's just a bit
anecdotal no I think it's totally true
and what we need to look at is the
building blocks and when we're talking
terpenes terpenoids that have our
flavors we're talking carbon and
hydrogen or carbon hydrogen and oxygen
and you look at what goes into the
building blocks of that and you start to
find that sulfur is actually a big part
of that creation process and so you
don't know well that makes sense okay
it's not just that sulfur is aromatic
but it actually might be a key part in
the process of these secondary
components that actually provide that
smell and what I've noticed is that
that's that taste
smell translation - and there's two
components complex organics Burnette and
the sulfur brings that and having both I
think gives them both so for a while in
hydro if you had a little guano that's
where that smell came from but either
the best just the organic part when you
add the sulfur the organics and all of
it you get that taste to smell
translation and I'm a big believer in
sulfur as a part of that in fact our
soil has about twice the recommended
sulfur amount for two reasons one it
keeps the nutrients inflow and the other
one is is really because of that flavor
aspect fantastic so another one which is
kind of like soulful where like maybe
some people use it some people don't
how do you feel about biochar you know
I've got a friend who swears by it but
I've got a lot of other friends we don't
even know what it is what do you think
about it it's an all our soil at five
percent I found enough benefit through
researching Terra Preta and biochar and
all that to find a benefit and it's
really interesting I've got our worm
casting producer they just got a new
facility they've got massive indoor
space and they go do a really good job
but one of the things they notice is
that they were doing a lot of farm
trials and they had a number of studies
one of them in particular was a growing
elephant grass and it was like 11 foot
tall grass and I think it the seeds are
something created like biofuel and it
was popular for a while to use organic
feeds our fermented feeds and stuff like
that and create biofuel and you get
grants for it whatever so they hired the
worm casting producer to come out there
and talk to him about increasing
production and one of the things they
were looking at was nodules on the root
zone and each one could be removed and
grow another plant and no matter what
they did the best they could come up
with with all the synthetic fertilizers
and nitrates were about four to five
nodules per plant and they invited our
worm casting guy out he put 50% worm
castings that he made in 50% biochar
about the size of a rice whole that kind
of texture fifty-fifty and he put a cup
next to each little planting site and
they were getting 50 to 60 nodules on
those plants it's significant multiple
hundred thousand percent increase with
corn they did the same thing a little
biochar little castings and they were
able to get that third or fourth year
corn that really increased a 33%
increase
yield across that sweet corn that was
taken to market at a high dollar price
so the biochar for some reasons seemed
to be a key link and adding that organic
matter that couldn't be instantly added
to the field that sequestered carbon
they've been behind nitrogen worm
castings next to it balance the two out
and when it was done at planting it had
altered the trajectory enough whereby by
the time it was yielding there was a big
difference here's the problem we're
facing our soils are already built how
the castings have the compost the cec
all the nutrients and now we're gonna
add biochar and so we won't notice as
significant as an impact in a situation
like that because it can't impart as
much with luxury on the such a special
soil we're in a native soil devoid of
everything it acts as a little sponge
slow real slowly releasing the benefits
to the plant next to it so I believe in
biochar but like squeezing a sponge if
you were to put that in your soil look
and soak up some of the goodies people
are pre charging their biochar with
bacteria and with nitrogen and things
and for the cost of it and the fact it
has all that carbon I see no reason not
to do it I really like using it but I
didn't notice it double my yield or
anything silly like that it will hold
five times its weight in water so be
careful if you want to use biochar as a
aeration of it but it can't act as one
but it can also hold a lot of water yeah
so um so I guess maybe what you the rule
of thumb is that like the the better the
soil the the less effect it has yeah but
here's the other thing too we're looking
at water filtering and we're looking at
heavy metals we're looking at all these
different properties that a soil might
take any consideration and alternate
uses for these products like pumice is
used in beauty products as used in water
filters so as biochar so adding these
things to our filter that could
potentially filter out heavy metals or
be a part of that complex of increased
cation exchange this is always a benefit
and so if you're going to add a little
bit of clay and a little bit of biochar
I feel like your soil is going to have a
higher CEC we talked about the beginning
of this that having that CEC higher
means you can hold more nutrients which
means you can go longer without having
additional inputs which means that a
smaller container of soil should perform
better yeah so
so instantly we've seen a bit of a
movement to replace perlite with some
alternative aeration amendments as we've
been talking about do you think that the
the buckwheat hole is a good suitable
replacement for that I don't know and I
only say that because I bought buckwheat
hole they were available locally as a
natural alternative to stuffing pillows
with and so that's what they're used for
I bought some I mixed it in a soil and I
had the worst nitrogen robbing I've ever
experienced everything was yellow
couldn't get nitrogen to save my life
and so I I don't know if that was just
my batch I just never went back to it I
didn't give it a fair shot and I think
that if it was maybe compost at first it
could have an effect but I'm using rice
hulls and those have been sterilized and
they work fantastic the problem that the
rice whole industry faced was that on
greenhouse and large scale in very small
containers the rice whole company had
too high of a percentage of viable rice
seed they germinated fermented and
caused anaerobic conditions and killed
entire greenhouses and so they had to
put conditions in place to make sure
they knew that how much seed was viable
in it you know if it was clean if it had
chemicals on it and so now a lot of
testings done we can get great rice
holes where the other holes we were
talking about the buckwheat I don't know
if they're gonna Rob nitrogen and I
don't know how they're grown and all
that enough to tell you if that's you
know really gonna be the next go-to so I
would just research and see on
small-scale mix it up and see how it
works for you yeah I'd be adding
nitrogen for sure
so in general do you want to move away
from the perlite I do I've never used
the perlite since I've started build a
soil
we use pumice which looks similar but
it's actually just mined as is and
doesn't have to have energy required
into expanding it to look that way
pumice will actually float in water but
it's a lot heavier than perlite and if
you're on a farm you can buy some
comments make a water filter that would
be you know at least a little bit better
than not so it has a lot of benefits it
works really good in our soil so I like
using pumice we use a mixture of pumice
and the rice hulls the rice hulls are
really high in silica so they take a
while to break down I think the
buckwheat holes would probably break
down a lot faster that's why we use the
rice
they also do have the celica so if
you've got those available and look at
it other than that I know people who use
peat gravel so I'm sure you can replace
it with something but in a one gallon
container perlite has some very unique
properties that will really be dialed in
so it may not be a one-to-one
replacement you may not have to relearn
how to water your soil on how to work
with it if you find something that isn't
as ideal as pumice or rice hulls yeah so
it can't be done yeah cool so how do you
feel about um people who I keep bringing
him up I'm the Rev you know and the
reason why I bring the Rev up Pilates is
because he was actually one of the
people who initially got me into
organics thank you very much for that
the Rev but you are really cool and so
one of the things he advocates really
strongly is that you use AA road water
now for me I found this to be like a bit
of a long term annoyance because you
have to then supplement with your
calcium sometimes but I found that my
tap water is like it's got like just the
perfect amount of calcium in it and but
he would say you know we know the
chlorine in the world is gonna be
detrimental to the micro life but I've
always thought well you know if I use a
little bit of micronutrient to boost
those numbers of my microbes its kind of
countering it out and it's just really
easy to just use tap water are you of
the same mindset or do you think no it's
really got to be ro because I mean you
know God bless the Rebbe he's very
strict on this you know he said that you
know if you can't get RO water don't
bother and I thought that was a bit of a
you know maybe there's not so much truth
to that yeah we'd never use RO water I
grew up using our old water it was in my
house and long story short I ended up
getting involved in this company through
a few friends that was a short period of
my life and I really just used the
product but that a sales opportunity and
they sold a product that made alkaline
water and so it caused you to do a ton
of research on the properties of water
and all this different stuff and it was
called a kangen and magic water machine
it was like 9.5 pH water you can push a
button make 5.5 pH water and it used
electricity and some other things to do
that if I was really cool and turns out
there's some health benefits to the
actual antioxidant property of some of
that water but
when I looked into it that company
called ro water dead water they said the
Japanese referred to his dead water
completely mineral devoid you put it in
your body it's actually gonna suck stuff
out into it instead of the other way
around and it's not found in nature that
way and so I started thinking about it a
night
since haven't been using oral water and
the same thing is true in a garden you
find that people have to supplement
sometimes with it it can potentially
leach I think if you already were paying
for all water and it's the only thing
you could use I would consider using it
other than that I would never pay for it
because it's a waste you know there's no
RO system that doesn't waste water and
if you're using all of your waste water
and filtering it back again you're gonna
go through those expensive filters
fairly quickly and so how our water
works is it takes all the bad stuff it
puts it in you know waste in the waste
water and you throw that away the other
water is the good water so it's kind of
splitting the good from the bad I'd
rather just filter it and keep the
contaminant and even above that if you
don't have a great filter just like you
found chlorines never hurt my grow I
used the hose on tons of grows and not
caused the detriment using the mulch
layer having the organic matter in that
top that actually hits that chlorine and
turns it and breaks it apart and off
gases it you can bubble the water to get
the chlorine out if it has chloramine
it's been proven to bind to organic
matter so some people use like vitamin C
or use a little worm castings or
whatever they have that's affordable to
actually bind to that chlorine and get
rid of it so I wouldn't go waste money
on a big RO water thing I prefer to just
use tap water if your water is good and
if it's got a ton of chlorine in it for
some reason you're worried about it you
could put some organic matter in that or
bubble it for a day and then use it and
I think you'll have a great results yeah
so have you ever looked seriously in
actually aquaponic cannabis and is it
something you'd want to pursue more no I
haven't looked seriously in it enough to
really talk intelligently about it and I
probably should do some more research
but I'm just turned off initially by the
fact that I need electricity and pumps
and containers and I'm gonna raise fish
in this little pond and it seems to me
like it's more of an idea of how to have
more profit on a smaller square foot by
raising protein at the same time as
plants to me that's not my ideal my deal
is to have the best plant regardless of
what happens secondarily to that and so
that's not my main motive also speaking
with like the local college they'll come
down and
worked with the college in Gunnison with
their agricultural department doing some
education with some of their students
and they had an aquaponic setup and I
said what's your favorite part about it
they said well the kids love it
other than that I didn't have a huge
answer for why it was so important and
so some growers haven't really found
great ways to even cultivate cannabis in
that method as far as aquaponic but I've
not seen it done properly usually the
nutrients that the cannabis needs are
too intense for the fish and you have to
have bio filters and plants growing and
all these other things to make it work
so to me is the ultimate complication of
what could be simple I can go fish in
the lake I can grow my food in the
ground and I can go spend the rest of my
time having fun of tinkering with a
hybrid combination of the both of them
but I know that there's gonna be a
couple people that'll do some amazing
things with aquaponics and areas where
the land is awful there's no fish to
fish and there's going to be a purpose
for it and it'll have a place to be it's
not the ideal like we don't live on the
moon yet and I don't need to do it that
way so yeah so this is gonna be the one
question that's gonna be a little bit
biased towards synthetics but here we go
what's the one thing or maybe even a few
things you would give to synthetics that
they have over organics or if if maybe
you don't want to concede that was the
one thing about organics you would
change what you know from a permaculture
perspective one of the things that's
unique is well come up with like um
there's one I forget the MIT Linder I
forget the guys name there's a method
where you just bring the minerals to
your garden and you can produce
phenomenal results and their argument is
that if you know in times hit a few of
these small bags of mine you know
synthetic minerals so to speak or
minerals without the carbon in it they
could be your fastest way to produce on
the farm and so they've kind of got that
beat rather than having a constantly you
know work the farm have it always there
and working so that if [__] hits the fan
you can go produce some food and so they
have that a little bit of like startup
right first year I can just go throw out
some hydroponics be growing and
harvesting mediately but if I need to
turn an acre of clay soil into good soil
it might take me a while the ultimate
benefit is though that the soils going
to be there for you forever and give
back and be a lot better investment and
so then when you look at permaculture
and you start talking about these guys
that can dial in nutrition and use
minerals and it's so much better you
start to look at how permaculture can
actually create whether it's just
there's a question of whether the rain
came first or the trees came first and I
believe the trees came first then I
started to attract the clouds through
their atmosphere that they create and
Matt creates the rain that creates more
plants and more of an ecosystem and so
ultimately from permaculture organics is
going to be the ultimate and will create
ecosystems but in between there we're
going to have to use all these other
systems to help get there and well from
managing resources it's going to be
important to move resources from one
area to another to start these farms and
that's where some of these synthetic
processes can have an advantage but when
you look at the 35-year farm trials the
data is there that organic is gonna be
the best and so I think that in the long
term organics will always win these
synthetics have these short-term
advantages where I feel like we really
got duped but if we're aware that they
are just short-term and have other plans
in place there might be some leverage
their leverage I'm not really willing to
play with but I feel like a lot of
people will interestingly enough on that
thirty five-year farm report that Rodale
does the least performing corn crop was
actually on the conventional no-till so
incorporating both the synthetic and the
non was the worst kind of kind of
interesting
mmm yeah so I mean staying on that idea
of like how you've got to put the time
and the kind of your time investment
into organics how do you feel about the
statements like would you agree with
organic gardening requires forethought
and preparation however is multitudes of
factor easier cheaper and yields a
better product yep yep and that's the
thing it's the key pieces it tends to
attract an audience that's a little bit
more mature because they're considering
you know planning pre-planning thinking
ahead how it impacts other things in
their lives and there hasn't been a very
profitable system to enable a brand new
person to start organically and so it's
just faster so you know I agree with
that
organics better but it just has a little
bit more of forethought pre-planning and
then you know the other thing that I
find a bit of fallacy is that a lot of
times people would say
only that but if he mess up in organics
there's no way you're in a correct it in
time it's gonna take months to turn it
around I found that if your soil is
built right you have an issue usually a
compost tea or a top dress can turn it
around pretty quickly so long as you've
been training that plant properly yeah
so that's actually one of the questions
I was going to bring up is people often
the one of the I call it one of the
hydro mindsets when you're growing
organically is that you see a problem
and you want to fix it straight away as
you said you can fix them fairly quickly
but it's not like like hydro or
synthetics where it's just you know like
overnight fixed do that fix
yeah do you think that this is you know
kind of a fallacy for people to use this
as a negative of organics when really
maybe they just need to change their
mindset a little to not want this kind
of instant gratification of change you
know their nitrogen deficiency or
whatever yeah and I think it's also fear
of the unknown you know you have so much
control the steering wheels in your hand
the problem is is that we don't require
that control remove the ego the plants
are more intelligent at this they can
tell what they need and how do they need
it so our job is to provide all of that
in the necessary proportions and given
the right environment and so a lot of
times we're banging our head against the
wall and it's not a nitrogen issue in
the soil it's that your humidity is too
low the plants have been dried and now
you're trying to add nitrogen to it well
in hydro the humidity didn't matter
they're sitting in a bed full of water
and changing it out might actually fix
that so there's some false benefits
there and they can become your worst
enemy in hydro because you do the wrong
thing didn't fix it killed it
organics it's not gonna happen and so
once you realize that you don't need to
change anything as long as you build it
right you're never going to have to
interrupt one of these problems and by
doing a little topdressing you can get
weeks ahead of any potential issues and
by using large volumes of soil you
eliminate the problem already just
flower a plant that's too small offer
for its container and it's never gonna
run out it's when we're pushing the
boundaries growing the maximum yield and
the smallest amount of medium that we're
always going to run into problems
organics is no different the thing is
though is that
there's a few tricks that we could use
once you get into organics where that
whether it be an amino acid or like a
compost tea a fish fertilizer or a top
dress that typically can turn it around
instead of maybe a couple hours it might
take two or three days but the detriment
of that negative effect won't be so bad
and so I think that we can still pull
through pretty well yeah so how
prevalent do you think the propaganda of
the hydroponic industry is in our kind
of community I guess when I look at it
you know the thing that I think of is
every every breeder that we've ever
spoken to they've expressed a preference
for organic cannabis over hydroponic so
we're in this situation where like kind
of the tops of our industry or you know
I shouldn't say industry our field
promote and endorse organic cannabis and
yet the tops of the industry the
hydroponic industry you know obviously
do not how do you think we've gotten to
this point where we've got you know the
leaders saying one thing and the masses
doing the opposite because we're trying
to appeal to the masses so if you were
to set a demand for a product that
doesn't exist you can't fulfill the need
and so you know talking about organics
being the best and not having a new
organic to share if anybody does anybody
nobody good so the money being spent on
marketing is gonna be for what they can
sell and that's gonna be for the
hydroponics the synthetics and all that
but I've got a number of synthetic
customers that call me that run
unbelievable warehouses with phenomenal
results that are duplicatable that are
crushing it that are at the peak of
their game they're implementing organics
into their hydro recipes to get that
best of both worlds and still even then
they're saying it's not a hundred
percent on point and they still would
prefer for their ads - organic soil to
be that's like a really big compliment
because these are people that have seen
all of it seeing the big yields the
small yields they know all the [__]
they know what to lie what's not they've
grown all the different genetics and
like you're seeing at the pinnacle of it
they're still saying there's some sort
of Janus a quoi some preference that is
there and they don't know exactly why
and I think that the mainstream is
starting to understand that and hear
about it and for the first time I'm
hearing in hip hop and in music growing
it organic and it better be that organic
as opposed to that hydro and I'm like
yes this is pretty cool it's starting to
happen and as we get that tipping point
where for instance when I was in college
it was just weed and I had no clue you
could spray stuff on it get chemicals
involved in it and have powdery mildew
and bugs and I probably smoked more some
pesticides and all that when I was
growing up and I care to admit but I'm
now burdened with that new knowledge and
I realize holy [__] you really can't
take just a plant that I thought was a
plant that was called weed and really
ruin it and not only that but now
there's a million flavors and cultivars
and genetics and so it just gets more
and more exciting yeah so um how long
will it be till we see build a soil oje
being wrapped about I have no idea it's
so funny you mention that um I've got a
friend that is in the hip hop industry
he's done some stock done a song with
some big names like Snoop Dogg and he's
got a charity and a lot of his friends
were lost to overdoses and drugs and
just living that fast lifestyle and he's
since come to appreciate everybody and
has it's just a huge heart a lot of love
and he gives away CBD oil these grows
for the medicinal aspects of it and so
we donate to him and we also sent a
whole bunch of soil to him and we've
also got nicotine famous hash maker out
here and in the hip hop world we just
sent a pallet of soil to him so who
knows maybe there will be some sudden
hip hop joke about it at some point but
that's certainly not the goal our goal
is to get more people learning about
organics experiencing the benefits from
it and realizing they don't have to
spend a lot of money or time to get
their own grow and if they want to spend
a lot of money in time they can
certainly geek out on it just as hard as
hydro so yeah and so have you ever
considered maybe doing something like an
online web series kind of you know
showing people how to do all the things
we're talking about I have and it just
runs into time and problems and I've got
one going right now I posted the first
post maybe two months ago and I'm about
to update it with all that's happened
since then and training the plants and
taking sex in the seedlings and doing
the transplanting and that'll be finally
documented last year I tried to do that
my house got burglarized and the plants
ripped few weeks into flower because I
had some plan
outdoor and so these are problems that
are real that happened to growers and I
thought it couldn't happen to be a
little the middle of nowhere so my doors
are unlocked half the time didn't have
any security system and now everything's
different in my life and so I got really
scared and I didn't want to post the
rest of the videos for some of those
grows the few months after that and so
now I'm kind of doubling down circling
back around and just like build a soil
has been from the beginning it's been
hey I know you're scared to talk about
this with everybody in your family I
know you don't want to just go be public
about it so we'll do that and we'll bare
some of that burden it helps that it can
help us all learn a little bit and so it
would be very rewarding to have those
videos and so we'll be working on it and
if you guys do something like that I'd
be cool too I hope more people share
their methods yeah for sure
so I'm something that's kind of come up
as a new craze is the whole fermented
plant juice do you think that these
products I mean obviously the fermented
plant juice to me seems like a really
cheap alternative to some other products
and you can you can just make it at home
really easily but on the actual benefit
level put a slide cost do you think it
outweighs say using some coconut water
and Bokashi like I'm a firm believer
that coconut water is the bee's knees
what do you think yes I actually think
there's some benefit there greater than
I thought when I initially got into it
you know fermentation you use in very
smart small parts-per-million
botanical teas you can use a hundred
percent it's mostly water so for
instance you know bubbling some kelp and
alfalfa you could just use it if you
were to ferment you're gonna use you
know a couple of drops per gallon it's
very different and one of the things
that we're finding benefit from now this
is anecdotal I don't have the evidence
in front of me but I tend to trust these
resources because one of the unique
positions I get put it and build the
soil is to talk to a lot of people that
are on the ground doing this every day
they're not online they're not sharing
with anybody they're just doing it and
they're sharing with me some of their
results and I've found that people that
have access to massive amounts of
testing because they are at a dispensary
or whatever and they're getting
everything tested even for terpenoids
we're finding increases by using some of
these fermented plant juices of the
fruits like papaya mango and some of
that stuff and they're actually finding
some Bennett
and taste translation to that and that's
exciting to me so I I don't know I know
that there's not a downside from it
unless you overdo it and it is pretty
cheap I haven't seen that effect though
where I see a grower use just peat moss
or pearl mix it may make their own
nutrient line from fermented extracts
actually have success it just seems to
me that it's not balanced enough and
it's more of an addition to a balanced
system for some extra added effect that
it would be to completely be your
nutritional source yeah
another thing there is the sugars you
know I'm not a huge believer I'm like
adding sugar to the soil but coconut
water is a sugar source molasses is a
mineral source that has sugar with it
too and you know in the right amounts
we're finding that there is some benefit
to taste and flavor to having some of
these complex sugars that realistically
the plant should be shouldn't be able to
update so doing something else there and
obviously it's not like putting kool-aid
in the soil you know you get that joke
purple kool-aid in my hydro and it
tastes but it's like that's not how
freakin works okay but something about
that sugar something about the carbs
that are there a little bit of microbe
food and so maybe that's what the
fermented plant extract is also bringing
to the table but in cho when he talks
about in korean natural farming he says
like a pregnant woman starts to crave
fermented foods that are high in
phosphorus and go that direction when
we're starting to flour some of these
fermented plant extracts might be able
to hit the nail on the head with what we
need it in that transitional period
because we're not in this big bed of
soil that has everything to it then we
are limited by being indoors with lights
and so I don't know what the benefit is
but what I'm hearing is that there is
some sort of even on testing data
they're finding increased chirping
terpene counts by using some of these F
PJ's or FP es as you'll call yeah so
time will tell but I think there's gonna
be some benefit there for sure okay
awesome
so what do you think is one of the
current you know techniques or methods
or products that people are using that
you don't think it's gonna stand the
test of time you know maybe five years
from now we won't really see a lot of it
being used
huh you're gonna see a million probiotic
companies kind of go selling some new
blend of microbes that's gonna be the
latest and greatest and I feel like
there'll be a few at the top that are
working with major major agriculture
that are really doing research and
finding benefit purple non sulfur
bacteria was that magical one that you
see come around and it's still important
but it's like everybody was talking
about it like every other word for a
while and now you just kind of hear the
background isn't as normal knowledge but
it's weird when you first start talking
to growers that are brand new they all
start using the super thrived for some
reason those vitamin B ones and some of
those fads that kind of happen that come
and go I feel like they're gonna revisit
us from time to time so I don't know I
guess I don't have really good answer
for that one yeah no worries so on the
Builder soil site you've got a little
kit to kind of revitalize your soil so
my question is if someone says to me my
soil is depleted do you think that most
of the time they need that kit or
there's just something they need to fix
and then they'll realize it's all
actually still there they've just made
because some lock out or something like
that it depends you know if they know
they've grown in the soil a lot watered
a lot it's possibly gotten leached I
think that kit would probably do really
good but the kit derived from me not
having a succinct enough answer for my
customers they kept on saying you just
have something I could buy and put it in
there I'm like [__] if I only worked
that easy right so I'll do my best
right and my my best was looking at a
lot of soil tests where there were
smaller containers and it did grow a lot
now this is not looking at really
no-till in particular I feel like
no-till should baby be some less inputs
and some worms and a little compost
maybe not exactly the kit because that's
more for remitting and dumping and
tilling and all that but what we found
is that nitrogen was a little low
calcium was a little low PK were mostly
fine though so our ream indicate was
adding the gypsum that brought that
calcium with the sulfur that would help
shuffle the nutrients it added back the
crustacean Needham kelp because normally
in a no-till you're advised to put a
half cup or a cup of those materials
back in anyway since we're harvesting a
plant and most the time the grain size
of the nutrients we're using or like for
instance the kelp meal that's pretty
common
number fourteen grind and it lasts like
five to six months in soil it's really
microbial active it might go a little
faster so what about we just add back
kind of guessing but what we can't guess
at what we benefit from soil tests that
I'm hoping to start to add to our
customers and our soil is boron iron
manganese copper or zinc things that may
not show themselves is important I mean
they are but may not be as drastically
important in an indoor grow when you
plant a full season 10-pound plant
outdoors we're starting to see some of
the weaknesses and our soil recipes for
the first time where boron it's just too
little copper is so low that we're
getting powdery mildew in some areas and
so as I learn about this I want to teach
others or maybe just buying that repin
kits not enough you should do a soil
test we should add back all of those
things so we have the best chance of
success but most often just added a
Riemann kit top dressing with compost is
more than enough for an immuno almost
every grower unless they're really
pushing the extremes yeah so how would
you characterize the difference between
say hybrid soil versus say like the
coots mix would you just say that the
hybrid switch has been around for quite
a while is more comparable to say a
super soil mixture or you think maybe
it's somewhere in between the two of
super soil and coots that is hydric soil
are you regarding to that you know
gardening philosophy of Brix testing and
growing from yeah yeah yeah yeah I just
make everyone talking about a brand you
know high Brix methodology is typically
going to be lower in potassium lower in
phosphorus and more on the trace mineral
balancing and not really heavily reliant
on compost they find that compost brings
way too much potassium and that and
causes an imbalance and they're just
adamant that you can't high high Brix
while involving that and I just don't
find that to be the case with these
fast-growing annual plants I've not
found Brix testing to be something that
was super informative as far as you know
making decisions in the garden but I'm
fully willing to change my opinion on
that as I do more research certainly
higher Brix a lot of times it does
correlate to a you know more nutritional
product when it comes to like apples
on a higher Brix Apple or whatever we're
talking about the sugar content when it
comes around to high Brix garden
practices though I feel like the compost
is so important it's really hard for me
to to focus on that so what I want to
look at is not only having the compost
but also having a mineral balancing and
so I think bringing the best of both
worlds is going to be important and I've
found with premium compost it doesn't
have to be so imbalanced that the
potassium is out of whack so like we're
finding there's little jewels and each
one of these different methodologies but
I find when you get to the extremist
crowd of any of these groups I have a
little rub you know yeah so what's the
most wasteful thing that you see organic
growers do that you would like them to
improve don't know that's a good
question you know it said is it in
particular I guess it depends on the
crowd a lot of times throwing all their
soil away starting from scratch is
pretty wasteful using you know I don't
know do you have any suggestions on what
you think might be a wasteful practice I
can't think of anything organics is
typically about not being wasteful well
I've got a friend and he's of the belief
that because cannabis is like a top
feeder that the top soil gets much more
depleted than the bottom so he always
throws out the top bit where all the
feeder roots have been you know like by
the end of the grow it's kind of all
locked with roots he gets rid of that
and recycles the bottom our container is
all topsoil you know I mean we're not in
nature where you have that different sub
level layers of minerals and clays and
then finally the organic matter on the
top we have all high organic matter our
whole potting soil is the topsoil and
it's all feeder roots in there we don't
have a deep taproot so I would argue
that if you were to test the top and
bottom going to be pretty much identical
except for in my soil where I'm top
dressing a lot it would be richer on top
so I certainly won't want to throw that
portion away yeah so in general we kind
of advise top dressing overusing juice
like ferments because you know you can
improve that both the humic and the
nutritional content of the soil through
the top dressing long term
yeah yeah and you also get the benefit
where you're giving additional material
for the roots to dig into and I find
that roots at their tip where they're
sloughing off and where they're getting
that actual absorption and exchanging
cations that tip is where the magic
happens and so when you top dress you
get fresh new feeder roots digging into
that adding an explosion of growth along
with the nutritional benefits of that
top dress and then the bottom stays
whereas a more balanced not so due to
rich and a kid get water and moisture
and it can have those two zones just
like in nature and so when you do that
you're constantly trading these feeder
roots where if you're a guy that does
know mulch no top dress and all of a
sudden you notice the deficiency and you
go I got a top dress you might as well
as grab a tea but if you've been top
dressing and mulching the whole time the
second you put that top dress down
there's feeder roots just dig it into it
the next day or two yeah it really has a
much faster effect and so yeah I think
that's kind of a difference there
awesome so for this next little pot
we'll just go through some nutrients and
maybe you could just fire off some
answers as to where people might be able
to source them from okay so obvious ones
nitrogen coffee hits and one a lot of us
drink I think that ad greed material any
fast Graham weed on your property you
can drop down and harvest will have some
nitrogen you could top dress with it you
could feed it to the warm beds get
nitrogen that way
I think nitrogen will be pretty easy
it's the number one limiting factor so
any any any country that's farming is
gonna have access to some sort of organ
you know nitrogen source you mentioned
you use the blood meal that was what was
there if that's the only source you
might want to consider you know
continuing to use it but unfortunately
for me I don't know really what your
resources out there are so I'm gonna you
know need some guidance from you on that
but nitrogen should be easy yeah I mean
there's a lot of nitrogen options to be
honest phosphorus this is an interesting
one for Australia because I mentioned
earlier we don't um we don't have a lot
of phosphorus something I didn't mention
is that the Australian government has
actually limited the amount of
phosphorus you can have in certain
products so I think it was about a year
ago now Kanna had to redesign their
whole leak
would product because it was deemed to
have too high of a phosphorous level and
so that kind of caused a bit of issue is
because a lot of people will have to
change their whole feeding regiments and
whatnot but um I guess at the heart of
the question is yeah we don't have a lot
of available sources of phosphorus and
even guano as much as your against it is
not readily available so what would be
kind of the lesser known ways to get it
well you know we use fish bone meal
which is a 4:20 zero and BK kind of
thing which means that the nitrogen has
a lot of phosphorus though so the bone
is what's you know congruent you know
the bone meal that you're using may not
it's probably bovine but either way if
you can get some bones that would be a
good source of phosphorus yep and help
them you may have some more grass fed
cattle sources you may have other ways
of getting that that's better than what
I'm currently get it and so that might
be a great way for you to get your
phosphorus other than that chicken
manure okay good for phosphorus alfalfa
Brewers out here number one limiting
factor is phosphorus then I'll use
chicken manure and it's excellent for
that the problem is it can be a little
hot so if you compost that chicken
manure may be a really really good
source of phosphorus that's at least in
a proportion that probably wouldn't be
illegal since it's all natural and then
the other thing to consider is using
phosphorus all you baizen microbes and
here's what we got that talked about
indigenous microbes I'm guessing they're
really good at soluble phosphorus in a
low phosphorus soil where you're having
trouble buying those amendments these
indigenous microbes might be perfect and
so looking at you know guild Karen bangs
website the unconventional farmer or
looking at doctor you know looking at
chose natural farming using some of
those the rice boxes to culture your
microbes might be a worthwhile venture
there yeah okay cool so as phosphorus is
pretty immobilize I croak microbial
based micro rise I is gonna be another
great addition yeah so that'll really
kind of allow it to get moved into the
plant you reckon yep yep I think so
awesome so what about the other big on
potassium grow comfrey plant you'll have
plenty of potassium I think you guys
have comfrey available yeah so that'll
be potassium kelp would be good for
potassium
I think you'll find potassium sources
and so this is what I want to impart
more than just talking about the
ingredients if someone can have enough
comfort researching amendments based on
what plants contain it's fine I mean for
instance the guy read about making
world-record Tomatoes thousands of
pounds of tomatoes on one plant growing
in a cage system vertically where he
asked to get on huge ladders to harvest
it he did so making his own compost and
his compost source for nitrogen was the
kudzu vine which was a very fast-growing
vine that grew there that was almost
like taking over it grow across a road
and then it was like it was a it was a
problem well he chopped it up and use it
for his compost and so if you guys can
locally find products would just be
comfortable using them for the nitrogen
potassium or phosphorus I think you'll
be fine it doesn't have to be comfrey as
long as you find a fast growing weed
that's on your property that's no dab
potassium that'd be great yeah well I
mean do you feel like in some ways we're
going through a bit of a renaissance in
that you know go back five years there
weren't that many people who knew that
comfrey was a good potassium and
nitrogen source do you think that as we
learn more about these kind of ways to
get the the nutrients from just the
plants around us that will slowly fades
out things like bone meal and eventually
one day you'll be making your soil mix
from just a mixture of plants yes for
sure I'd love to do that it's always
gonna be economies of scale it's always
going to be that invisible guiding hand
of profit and when you look at people
that are telling me hey man I got you
know 300 yards of soil I got a mix and
the only thing my I'm gonna afford as
bone meal you're still gonna have that
and so until it becomes more affordable
and so the ways this happened is for
instance I was thinking about this the
other day computers it's like it's got
to be a so expensive to buy the first
computer ever right and that market
price but it was those early adopters
willing to invest money and tinkering
with stuff that wasn't very easy to use
that just for some reason they got it it
added value to their life they were
willing to spend all the money to do it
well now decades later all of us who
just wanna you know watch Netflix are
benefiting from all of their struggle to
spend the money on all this stuff and
bring it down to a level where was
produced at a low cost and so the
biomass that country can produce on a
property is so unbelievable
we're finally finding people that are
starting to grow it for us and I'm
buying it for way too high of a price
and selling it for way too high of a
price so it's not really ready but once
we get you know multiple acreage plots
and hundreds of acres and people are
harvesting lots of biomass and we can
get the cost down certainly it'll be a
very good it'll it'll really give a run
for bone meal but right now a lot of
these products we're buying as
fertilizer you better remember they're a
waste product they're trash how can you
beat free they already have a business
that is slaughtering cattle and they're
just making extra money selling us the
blood and so to go create a business who
asked a profit by selling the country
and growing it and buying the land and
all that they're going to be up against
it
competing with trash so yeah so they're
up against the big companies yep so some
of the the nutrients that I've found her
a little more harder to find in organic
you micronutrients are you trace
elements and things maybe that aren't
trace elements like silica are often
hard to come across in the organic
setting for a lot of people
well you recommend people get their
trace minerals from zoar things like
silica well silica covers most of
Earth's and even though it's not a you
know via necessary nutrient for plant
growth as far as they say it's in almost
all the plants they find a way to get it
even though we shouldn't be able to so I
think that just rock dust will be fine
beyond that you know there's other
products there that are out there like
the potassium silicates but those are
only approved for organic used as a
foliar spray and so I've been moving
away from those other products will have
silica like the rice hulls and so you
can start to find out what in your area
might have a silica content and then
ferment that or feed it to the soil so
when it breaks down at add silica and
when it comes to trace minerals anything
from the oceans gonna have all of it so
adding that's why I added fish to the
old pile with the corn and the beans in
the in you know the Native American
principles it works and adding kelp meal
works it has all the trace minerals
organically chelated ready to go and it
can even you know kelp grows in a high
salt environment so it doesn't take salt
into itself it's not super super salty
it will have some to it
but it works other than that rock dust
I'll have all your trace minerals too
and so it need be that it's you know too
hard to find what was probably hard to
find is a specific like manganese
sulfate or copper sulfate the map being
said a lot of your organic gardeners
aren't really using those right now
they're still scared by that good so I'm
having to it I'm wanting to create a
soil that has some of those in it that's
fully been really balanced for our
larger scale customers I'll probably
still keep two soils one with those in
it one without you know yeah so you just
kind of spurred on this question often
whenever someone looks up a kind of a
deficiency diagnostic chart there will
be all these different photos of you
know this is a boron deficiency this is
how iron deficiency I have for the life
of me never seen any of those
deficiencies in an organic grow do you
think that getting something like you
know a zinc deficiency is fairly
exclusive to a hydroponic grow and that
organic growing tends to just work those
kind of fine a nutrient see out
themselves I thought so but you know
when we're seeing fall season plants
grown ten fifteen pounds people are
experiencing some of these similar
results and so we're really pushing the
boundaries and at at an agricultural
scale micronutrient balancing is very
important and they're aware of the
downfalls I guess the way I look at it
is yeah you can build a house with wood
and you need a ton of wood to do it but
those little tiny nails hold it all
together and so those would be the boron
and so if if you're a building block and
a boron is necessary to make something
you don't have it it's going to be a
problem now nature can diversify doesn't
put all its eggs in one basket it has
more than one way of doing things but
you're certainly gonna put stress on
this system once you get past that once
you get to that limiting factor and so I
mentioned earlier one over some of our
growers in fact there's a thread on IC
mag that I'm involved in right now and
the advancing eco agriculture thread
where I just posted some of our soil
test results under my moniker Mile High
guy I've not used it in a long time the
reason why is something that people grow
in full season we're having problems
with our soil and other people are
having really good success with our soil
and so we're trying to improve we're
trying to find out what's going on and
it looks like the boron it looks like
the copper and some of these things are
becoming really really important when it
comes
two full season plants and balancing the
soil because if the calcium is there but
the water has tons of carbonate sand
it's locking some of the calcium out and
Boren might help that or whatever the
case is you know I'm just kind of
talking out of my ass now I know it
can't be important and I really feel
like every detail will be important when
we get to that level so we're looking
into all of that but certainly
hydroponics has you in control where you
have to add all of these at exact
proportions and I don't think we're
intelligent enough to know that so as
long as we get it to the point where
it's into soil and it's above the
limiting factor I feel like organics is
not going to have those issues it's
going to sort it out on its own it's
gonna do significantly better but in
hydro it's very clear you don't have
boron it's not there it's not gonna get
it you'll have a boron deficiency
somehow a nature we're able to overcome
that there's some more on there and it's
going to do a little bit but it's much
more apparent hydro that's what those
photos come from so yeah so let's talk
about some of mistakes that um you know
converted growers make when they're
transitioning to organics you know maybe
we'll talk about some some likely
reasons yeah some likely reasons as to
why they're running into problems so I
just give you some topics and you can
just let us know what you think so yeah
if someone's got bugs and they've just
converted to organic we're talking you
know fungus gnats
you know annoying bugs not spider mites
what do you think their problem is oh
that's tough to say the ecosystems not
fully developed and so in a no-till
system that's been going on a long time
you'll pull back the mulch and you'll
find so much diversity it's ridiculous
and so what what's more challenging in
that system is for any one thing to get
out of proportion and scale and when we
have a fresh soil that's a really wet on
top we're trying to keep the mulch and
top dress and do all these fantastic
things we learn about we're breeding the
perfect habitat for fungus gnats and if
they're implemented and you know the
ecosystem isn't so developed and things
that eat fungus gnats because they
haven't been there we're gonna have that
problem and so like I said outdoors and
it may not be an issue though fungus
gnats indoors in a tent it's a big
problem they get in your fan and your
light they get in the buds and so now
all of a sudden we can't wait for these
predators to come in
we have to sort of create that ecosystem
on our own and so I think a brand new
grower number one mistake they're making
is potentially maybe a little over
watering maybe there's just up against
it maybe they had fungus not larva in
there there's nothing they can do and so
from there having a big nurse oil having
a fuller ecosystem having the predator
mites having all of those different
variables is really it helped that but
it's tough to say exactly what they're
doing wrong yeah and so let's just say
someone did have some fungus gnats what
would be and they're the new convert to
organic what would be your
recommendations for how they handle the
pest management you know like their IPM
because this is something I get asked a
lot because I'm always trying to convert
people over and they usually get fungus
gnats and then my usual answer is get
some neem or some predator and nematodes
what would be your recommendation as
like a first port of call yep that would
be my recommendation and if they've
noticed it's because the top is wet and
they are mulching and maybe over watered
Allah as I previously mentioned just
scraping that entire mulch layer off put
it in a trash bag getting it out of the
house going in sprinkling down you know
the frass or the neem cake or whatever
you've got that's gonna help as a
preventative and then covering that with
a premium barrier like a compost or a
vermicompost that's not you know
infested with larvae and I feel like
that should almost wipe it out because
it removes most of the larvae and it
covers it with a drier layer of a
material that has a lot of bacteria and
benefits and it should be good but
here's where it adds insult to injury I
tell somebody that may take compost full
of fungus gnat larvae and pile it on and
it probably just getting worse now I've
had people that have gotten all the
nematodes all the mites and everything
had still had a problem and it's only
one of their areas and one of their own
rooms and I cannot figure it out and so
if one thing is proven for sure it's
that farmers are never gonna have it a
hundred percent Easy Street we're gonna
have to earn a little bit of this and in
nature when we have you know hundred
acres there's a certain percentage of
crop loss it's just a given it doors
with two plants we're not gonna allow
for any of that and so it's one of those
things where we're not gonna win every
single battle and sometimes having to
start over and scrap it build new soil
maybe what has to happen to artificially
create this mono crop indoors
you know lights but still be organic
there it's kind of hypocritical and so
we're gonna have some of these issues
that are a byproduct of our own creation
like Masanobu Fukuoka says as soon as
you prune the first branch on the tree
well you're in control of it for from
now on out as soon as we put the
container indoors and throw the light up
well we're gonna have some of these
issues to deal with and so it becomes
more in building your confidence and how
little it might affect you or how able
you are to get rid of it and I think
that you know that's really the main
difference maker
I had powdery mildew on an outdoor plant
this year and all in one area none of
the others had it well I tested a
treatment which is the product we carry
with peppermint bora-bora and some
enzymes it's totally harmless but I was
worried it would taste like peppermint
on the buds and talk to the manufacturer
they didn't feel like it was a high
enough percentage to do that it would be
too volatile and went off gas so I
sprayed the whole plant down three times
and the pattern is completely gone and
so I was willing to gamble a little bit
to learn that lesson and if I have a
problem again next year I guarantee well
what about that same thing it'll work
but preventatively we talked about hydro
versus organic before and a lot of times
the differences like Western medicine
treats symptoms by covering them up a
lot of times hydro methods will do the
same organically we're trying to get
back to what's causing that problem and
fix it and that would be like I said
maybe the copper was why that plant got
powdery mildew whatever but I don't know
that I don't pretend to I just know that
I'm learning more about it that you know
everyday yeah so what would be your
advice to the new convert on how to
approach troubleshooting because this is
something I find is the biggest issue is
the way they try to solve problems if
you start to think about the soil you
say okay the soil was recently made I
follow a proven recipe most likely it's
not a lack of nutrients but more a lock
out in there what I'm gonna look at is
the over water did i under water and how
do I verify that well keeping track of
the weight of the container and how
heavy it feels at its ultimate moisture
content should tell you if it's heavier
than that you've over watered if it's
much lighter you're under watering then
from there what affects the moisture
uptake is going to be the root movement
so one of the things that a lot of
growers don't look at which can be very
important with energy-efficient lights
in organics
oil is the VPD or vapor pressure deficit
which is the relationship with humidity
and temperature in the grow room and so
if you've gotten way too high of a
humidity it creates this pressure where
the plants can't drink and then just
slow down and they're not growing even
the like bacon and even though the
nutrients are there and then you have
the opposite where you have a 40% grow
room humidity and it's at 80 degrees
because you're not wanting mold but
certain cultivars are not going to be
able to transpire they will shut down
three three hours into that grow all the
nutrients are there but they're not
gonna take it up because they're not
photosynthesizing in photosynthesis is
so important that's what we have to look
at if the nutrients are in there we know
we made the soil Dennis look in an
environment looking at watering them and
if you go through those every time oh my
god I got a problem well [__] this is
really old soil it might actually be a
lack of nutrients well then I want you
to consider that look at topdressing
your failure if you go oh my god what's
gone I got a deficiency it's yellowing
well then you just start to think is it
new soil yes it shouldn't be nutrients
then okay how's my environment oh [__]
my environments off problem solved
oh my environments dull my soils fresh
and that's dialed what could this
possibly be well I'm gonna look at
moisture is it too heavy is it over
water is it under water if I'm positive
then across the board perfect the water
is right the environments right I know I
made the soil and I followed all the
protocol well if it's every single plant
a grow room I'm gonna go Ollie [__]
maybe that compost wasn't as good as I
thought it was or look at some of those
variable inputs if it's only one or two
plants I'm gonna say okay is this a
different genetic or if it's not a
different genetic is it potentially in
the corner of the grow room where the
fan is hitting it is it right under the
light in the hottest area it's after
I've ruled out all of those basic
variables I'm gonna get a friend
involved and you're like what the hell
am I not seeing that you might you know
be able to see here it's kind of like
proofreading your own report in school
let's just sometimes you just skim over
the same exact mistakes over and over
again and it could be really simple
shoot maybe it's your first time
experiencing a really bad Russert my
problem and you think it's a nutrient
uptake issue so adding a professional
help at some point even if it's just a
friend can be a big time help but the
main things environment muttering how
old how do the soil is you know when -
the last time I Teeter talk press
you answer all those honestly you'll
know if it's a lockout or a deficiency
and you know how to go forward so yeah
and I think that's kind of funny that
you mentioned that resset might thing
because anyone who watches a really cool
grower on YouTube or MIDI cropper he
were he had a very similar thing
happened to him and it it took like
months before he realized what happened
but I mean it was really really like new
lights and he thought it was the lights
and it turns out it wasn't bad yeah he
thought it was the nutrients at first
and then he thought it was the lights
and they thought it was blower blah but
yeah and he couldn't he was just
visually looking for the Russert mites
and he couldn't see them and obviously
they're a lot smaller than spider mites
that point everything that was a problem
you could see and so this is the first
time you have to scope every week as a
part of your IPM to look for things you
can't even see as a potential problem
yeah that's very become a lot door that
get you know wilt some sort of fungus or
Foose Aryan problem that is just
horrific and so then we look at
micronutrients as potentially the cause
of that excess phosphorus not enough
micronutrients causing these little
festering problems that can become you
know really good home just for pathogens
and so I think that's probably why
Australia is monitoring the phosphorus
and how it affects the water how it
affects the plants and all these things
is there aware the larger ecosystem
impact that we're starting to learn
about where we you know grow in these
methods yeah I mean I would love to
think the government has that kind of
forethought but based on other issues
I'm not quite so sure but anyway so last
one for this section reusing soil what
would be your advice to the new so
someone just finish their first organic
grow and they've been hearing about
reusing their soil how should they
actually do it for their first time I
take the plant and I would let's say I
just harvested and I brought it out of
the rib now I'm left with one container
it's got a stock sticking out of it and
I'm ready to go for ease we'll just
pretend this is a 15 gallon because
that's kind of what we recommend as a
minimum size for started yeah and you'll
take that you'll you'll cut the plant
down and from there there's a couple
different questions in a no-till in a
big bed one might just plant a clone a
foot to the right of that
well the 15 gallon
foot to the right I mean you're not in
the container anymore so you're probably
gonna dig out that stock in that root
ball and put your clone right back in
that hole and when I do that I'm gonna
sprinkle my coryza in the hole but the
cloning once it's in there I will
sprinkle back some nutrients that I know
are never gonna hurt but could be
lacking and that could be whatever I
have kelp crustacean neem anything
well-rounded the blend of all three if I
just had neem I would do that - pretty
good NPK well well-rounded and I would
top dress that and then cover that with
a little compost that's all you have to
do if you really wanted to you could
like put some gypsum in and a few other
things and really start thinking about
it but for the most part if that plant
when harvested wasn't completely just
your brain it wasn't like ten times the
size that it should have been in that
little container and it wasn't just
completely flushed meaning it was just a
nice transition good sized plant
probably still had some more nutrients
in there I would just harvest it
immediately plants another one in there
sprinkle some nutrients on top cover it
with compost and I'm ready to go and I
do that all the time if you know we have
a real big
but if they've got their own organic
nutrients at home a lot of times when
was talk of in and doing that and so for
a 15 gallon container we know that
that's about two cubic feet and normally
our recommendation would building soil
is about one and a half to three cups of
nutrients at the very most per cubic
foot so in a top dress I would probably
never put more than three cups of
nutrients on top you could probably
realize I do six without hurting
anything but I would just put a cup of
this cup of that up to three cups cover
it with compost and that's how you go
and you'll experience some really good
results doing them if you really want to
take it to the next level you can send
some of that soil off for a sample at
the soil lab get a report back and
analyze it and I guarantee you're gonna
be surprised at how little that report
is gonna have you add back the only
caveat there's if you grew a really big
plant and you really did water a lot it
might be really low in nitrogen and
calcium and stuff once you're done but
certainly even those few cups of
amendments and compost would probably be
enough to get you going on that next
cycle and before a flower you could
judge again if you wanted a top dress
again so on that same note like the the
nutrients potentially needing
replacement if they've been leached out
do you find that it's necessary /
advisable for people to water until
there is that 10 percent runoff like
what people advised in hydroponics or
not necessarily no I didn't know runoff
and the reason why is we don't have
salts that we need to exchange and get
out and we're not replacing what
nutrients are in there with a new
balance the water is more of just the
carrying medium it's just keeping it
moist so I don't do any runoff if
anything I will notice a little runoff
and I'll stop so I'm not like I'm
worried about it but I like in Cocoa you
have to have an exchange you have to
push all the old out get all the new in
and you need a large amount of runoff to
do that properly which is wasteful and
so the main problem we have is probably
the opposite when you're not getting
runoff and you're in a big container
making sure that you don't get that
bottom of the container just totally
soaking wet all the time yeah okay well
I will alternate between little light
water and on top to a deeper watering
but but definitely not to run off yeah
well I mean have you ever run wicking
style grow system and how did it go if
you have yeah well I guess so I mean the
earth boxes that I currently use and
recommend a lot of newer growers to use
has a wicking system in it it's a sub
irrigated planter holds about a cubic
foot and a half of soil on a tray and
below there is two and a half gallons of
water the corners of the plastic
rectangular grow box are impressed down
into the water and you pack that soil
tight and that acts as a sponge that
wicks the water up to the rest of the
soil unbelievable results with it I put
a clone in there put the soil in and
then maybe the benefit is you're not top
watering so you can actually mound
compost and nutrients well above the
size of the container and put the
plastic cover back on the top and that
keeps the moisture all inside the
container constantly wicking and I found
that you can take that earth box that's
only about you know 10 gallons of soil
and it'll mimic very closely what a 20
30 gallon container of soil can do in a
geo pot no didn't from there outdoors
I found it better just use the ground or
large volumes of soil not to build a
swimming pool to do a sub irrigated
planter unit and so I'm finding that
there's you know each one of these is a
tool to be used in a certain
and I'm also seeing permaculture people
doing these big wicking beds and
sub-irrigation was a big part of nature
with underground currents and water and
underground aquifers and so I I don't
know I know that there's definitely
benefit to both like humor culture also
uses some sub irrigation in that in the
rotting wood so yep okay so for this
final part of the interview we're just
gonna go over some questions we had sent
in by our listeners the very first one
this is the only one I'm gonna read in
the terminology they sent it in why you
know more ship to Canada haha man
you mad bro it's funny because it's been
a big challenge and we were flying under
the radar we are actively working on
switching our Canadian shipping so that
we could be back and we had to turn it
off the other day because we started
just losing hundreds of dollars the
reason why is that a number of our
orders were just sliding through the
radar no problem but in order to avoid
the taxes and tariffs and fees that come
with importing to Canada the best way is
to use the USPS and the reason why is
they have a standing reciprocating
agreement between the United States to
work with each other where FedEx and UPS
is going to charge us a lot of money and
charge you a lot of money without
telling us how much so we have to
involve like a specialist and we have to
guess at the fees so you're not
surprised so the only way is USPS well
we don't have international tariff codes
on all of our items because we
manufacture them and don't know what the
hell an international tariff code even
is and so all of a sudden in customs
this product that should be charged no
taxes is just held up and said hey you
don't have international terror and
we're holding it and so our customers
would order items they needed and then
get turned around held in customs they
wouldn't get their money back for 30 to
45 days we'd ship them more product than
an extremely high expense and then it
would just fail and we would just be
left apologizing to the customer holding
the bag and so right now we're going
through with a team but getting every
single international tariff code and if
you're in Canada and you want to order
right now email the order to support
that bill to soil tell us the items you
want we'll look up the tariff codes and
we'll use your order as a test and
probably even give you a discount to do
so so let me know we're working on it
right now
great so the
be very happy so next question on your
IPM mixture on the site we've got a
listener who wants to use it in light
flower but they were wondering does this
render the parts of the plants
specifically the leaves unusable so for
example if they wanted to say use it a
few weeks before harvest and then maybe
juice those leaves after harvest
are they still good to go or you think
those leaves probably no longer edible I
think they're probably totally fine
but the only caveat to that is just like
produce I'd have to wash the leaves and
all that stuff yes so if I had it was
totally natural sprayed on there and I
could actually put it in a salad spinner
and so come and wash them and yeah great
juice oh it's not a big deal but you
know the flowers are where the oil comes
in and so that's where becomes a little
bit more of a sticky situation and
people are really scared about it and
the other reason is you know juicing we
have our liver we have our stomach we
have our kidneys all these things that
help us process when we light it on fire
it's going right into the blood it's
bypassing all of that and so it becomes
very important and so in considering
some of that the products that I've felt
the most safe with are the big time
exterminator and the treatment and those
are both enzyme based I've also got the
owner of Terry Ganic cm-1 says that you
could spray e-m1 mixed with yucca
extract up until you know the last week
of harvest or whatever and then wash
after and not have any problems and it's
a great fungicide and a great way to
out-compete powdery mildew and things
like that so I'm not sure what your
exact problem is the only answer I can
give you that's the number one
recommended is never ever spray your
flowers with anything from personal
experience that's not always the case
then if it's for personal use and you're
willing to test it out I tried that
tweetment product I'm guessing you might
be able to get it international I don't
I don't know but it's an enzyme based
cleaning product that's got really
nothing in it but enzymes water the
peppermint oil and the borax and the
boric and it works phenomenal and I
haven't had any issues also the big-time
exterminator we've had a number of
people do testing and enter contests and
never fail due to anything that's in
there but the nature of these tests is
they only test for what they're looking
for and so the purist will said that
spraying on your flowers could
potentially lead to something that's a
health and we just don't know and so the
only guaranteed way is don't spray that
being said I think there's a number of
things that you can do yeah including
essential oils in a small amount I think
we'll volatilize it not be part of the
final product yeah okay so annex
listener says I don't live in the USA
but I wanted to make my own fish compost
after seeing your video however I'm
scared of composting meat is there any
tips you know I don't know I've never
done fish compost and the guys that do
the fish compost have a pretty good
process for it they've got huge piles
that put the whole fish in and got
hardwood and all this other stuff to me
it sounds pretty straightforward just
put the fish in there have at it but you
know I both know that certain issues can
arise that you didn't expect to plan for
and so I maybe look at making your own
fish hydrolysate and you can make your
own lactobacillus and grind the fish up
blend it and by the time it's has no
odor and is back to a stable pH you have
your own fish fertilizer has no
stabilizing agent in it and it shouldn't
work really really well other than that
I mean people have buried whole fish
right in their planting hole for corn
and stuff so I gotta imagine making
compost with it wouldn't be too
different just put in the pile
I would Google and I would look up maybe
some loose percentages on what percent
of fish to add but other than that it's
gonna be a part of your carbon to
nitrogen ratio so worst case if there's
no help I would look up the nitrogen
content of average fish per pound and I
would balance that against the standard
carbon to nitrogen ratio of compost and
I bet you work just fine okay awesome
and just as a bit of a side question
I've read a lot of stuff lately saying
that um you should opt for just in
general I know that you just said it and
I'm gonna pronounce it wrong but hydro
so lights over emotions do you think
that that's true yeah yeah what a
percent an emulsion is a chemical
extraction and and hydrolyze say it is
blended in water and so a lot of times
the hydrolyzed state is still gonna have
a stabilizing agent and the reason why
is these fish hydrolyzed states the
product that we're currently purchasing
they're fishing a very deep water fish
that's very fatty and bony and so it's
low and heavy metal and it's very well
tested and the reason why they buy it is
they're making a
Glucosamine Chondroitin product for the
health market and so if you need a bony
fish well a bony fatty fish is also
great for fertilizer and so they have a
good secondary market for it but they
use citric I'm sorry to use phosphoric
acid and it's kinda kinda it like makes
soda pop like coca-cola has phosphoric
acid they use that kind and it stabilize
it get a number of growers are like hey
phosphoric acid what the hell that's not
organic I don't want it my soil well the
amount they use is very small and as
soon as you diluted it becomes a
non-issue kind of like how honey is
antibacterial but if you dilute honey it
immediately grows mold it's a non-issue
once it's diluted the thing is those
it's not the best and so it the reason
they use it is it makes the pee number
on their NPK label a lot higher using
phosphoric acid and it is a peace horse
but the company we're working with they
have a market that once a year gets a
citric acid stabilized version and we're
gonna try and get that and the next
batch and beyond that I'm hoping one day
in the future they make a lactobacillus
version known so then hydrolyze that
would be great it's a waste product we
need to do something with it and either
composting it or turning it into
fertilizer makes a lot of sense that
being said there's a subset of people
that will say any fertilizer like that
liquid is feeding the plant not feeding
the soil and on an agricultural level
they'll say it actually does feed the
soil and they can prove it by measuring
how much nitrogen is left over after
these feedings even after the crops are
harvested and it seems to be true but
the main source we see for selling right
now is the Ingham crowd and a lot of the
compost tea brewers that are using fish
hydrolysate as a food source for the
microbes and they're using such a small
amount but by the time the tea is brewed
there's no fish hydrolyze I didn't even
left it just fed the microbes yeah so um
just just to clarify when you say I'm
potentially adding some lactobacillus
that's the same stuff that's in kombucha
right did the drink yeah I know kombucha
would be a whole bunch of other
different consortium there the kombucha
the material that makes it is called a
Scobie or a sin biotic colony of
bacteria and yeast and you know there's
a lot of research on what specifics
some people do use kombucha cuz it's got
a very low pH and they can use that for
powdery mildew but
the lactobacillus is actually a lot of
people would be lactose intolerant
that's a sugar that's a milk and so the
lactobacillus is the cerements made from
taking a rice wash water high in
carbohydrate and getting all of the
indigenous lactobacillus that's any air
in there and then putting that milk to
stifle all the other bacteria and just
feed the lactobacillus it turned way and
curd the curd is the cheese the way is
the clear liquid that is the
lactobacillus serum it's basically a
whey protein powder the liquid version
while it's still alive
it's high in amino acids high in protein
and in the farming world feeding animals
with high protein turning over to
agriculture means a high nitrogen and so
when you use that lactobacillus it's a
great decomposer for some reason it can
break down that fish remove the odor and
keep it stable and lower that pH down to
about 3.5 so you don't have to add the
phosphoric acid it's pretty cool yeah
that is actually really interesting you
mention that because anyone if they want
to check out my Instagram page they'll
see that I'm a bit of an avid cheese
maker fan and and so yeah I didn't
realize until right now I've actually
got lactobacillus hanging around all the
time when I separate my weight off the
top of the curds
an indigenous cheese making a lot of
times for instance um everybody's heard
of San Francisco sourdough bread well
it's called that because the San
Francisco bacteria that's in the area is
only native to that region it imparts a
certain flavor you can send me your
culinary chef prepared sourdough starter
from from San Francisco but if I make it
at my house by about the second time
it's totally different and so that's
where the indigenous microorganisms come
to play and that's where when we're
talking about lactobacillus it's crazy
but all the protein powders on the
market here in the United States
fat free became a huge thing and that's
what cheese became popular because fat
free milk was being sold they had to
take all the fat off and all of a sudden
you had grated cheese cheese slices
government cheese and then from there
you have the next waste product all of
the way from the cheese making that they
end up using for the protein powders and
so we find the premium protein companies
use grass-fed cattle and all that so at
home if you've got your own goats or if
you've got you know some raw all natural
milk that would be the best
but certainly any milk I think would
work
yeah and that's like kind of an
interesting I we're probably going down
a bit of a rabbit hole here but that's a
bit of an interesting one um the quality
of protein because yeah I read some
studies and they say that you know the
cheaper the quality of protein you find
the higher the glycine content in it is
a glycine is kind of the least useful of
all the amino acids so it's interesting
that it does translate the way it does
especially when you mentioned the the
grass-fed cattle and then how that
translates into protein powder being
better quality yep yeah there's so many
crossovers I always tell people cannabis
is a gateway gateway to a healthier
lifestyle and realizing you know that
there's a lot more going on than I knew
before so yeah awesome so our next
question it's a little bit extended
what's the cheapest way to start an
organic cannabis grow so this person has
said is it possible for me to veg a plan
in a bag of potting mix just some
regular potting mix and then transplant
it into a big pot the bottom half is
compost the top half is just the same
potting mix would that work essentially
with just water only so I guess what the
question is is can you grow a nice plan
with just a bag of compost and a bag of
potting soil hundred percent in fact
I've been challenged before people said
oh you love nature so much why don't
just throw a seed outside see what
happens well [__] I did that it was one
of the best girls I've ever had of
course each soil is gonna be different
and then happened to be an old chicken
coop and the soil was pretty good in
there the challenge I would have to have
is the opposite that put the compost on
top of the potting soil underneath
that's how nature works the compost
isn't you know just underneath that's
where all the minerals are and so I
would do the opposite and that's why I
had a challenge with the super soil the
hot part was on the bottom then I get it
because the roots are eventually gonna
hit that but wait you don't what they
don't talk about is that the first thing
a plant does is search for the walls of
its container within the first couple of
days it's ending roots everywhere so
putting it up top would be more where it
can balance what to do with those and
certainly just growing with some compost
than everything the number one limiting
factor meeting if your compost is
imbalanced it would be better to have a
lot of it so that I could just eat the
portion that it needs as opposed to
reaching that imbalance sooner so what
we lack in quality we can make up for
at least a little bit in organics in the
beginning and that's how cheap it can be
from there the cheapest way as far as
following all these recipes would be to
get the cocoa core get your own compost
get some sort of aeration mix it
together in plant that's gonna be the
cheapest way but I've I've even seen
people make 50/50 their own homemade
compost they just use that in aeration
and I plant into it their plants do
great fantastic final question for this
interview I think we've already kind of
answered it but uh obviously the person
didn't know that submitting it
beforehand can organic growing
consistently yield as much as a hydro on
a small commercial scale with the same
or less amount of input so I'm assuming
this person they're from the states I'm
assuming that they're wanting to switch
over their little home grow that they
probably sell for a living yeah do you
think it can consistently yield as much
with the same or less effort / input
yeah and here's the question though um
I'll always have hydro growers that are
gonna tell me they can do better and
I'll always have organic growers that
can tell me they can do better and what
I pay attention to in particular is the
growers that have done boast at the
pinnacle and they always say that
there's always room for improvement
there's ways to get better but certainly
I think one of the benefits is you could
probably could force a little more yield
out of hydro it's just going to be the
case and the factor is is at that point
where you push it beyond almost like
steroid usage isn't really healthy is it
taste is good or we push it beyond the
balance and so I would say that with a
quality and perspective yes you can hit
those yields every time and when we look
at that actual farm trial of Agriculture
not horticulture but you know large
scale for sure if you go look at the
Rodale farm study you're gonna see that
every year you're in you're out and over
the whole 30 years organics not only did
just as good but one and so that is
definitely interesting I feel like kind
of like I've mentioned steroids before
you're gonna see a dramatic result in
the beginning but down the road if
you're not keeping every else everything
else perfect you're gonna see that it's
artificial it doesn't translate to as
much real strength and then it could be
detrimental to your health same same
thing with using synthetic a number of
countries that adopted synthetic
practices or worse often there were
before
they're having super weeds and all sorts
of problems and they're doubling down
and going back to their old practices
and the government's right there behind
themself indoors on a facility and main
limiting factor is going to be that
grower and that goes for hydro that goes
for you know organics but here's the
other thing to consider the Phantom
yield is what I call it if I could get
10 pounds hydro or 10 pounds organic
there's apples to apples but what if I
only get 8 and organic and 10 in the
hydro but I made twice as much money off
the 8 than I did the 10 that phantom
yields are gonna be more important to me
and that's what real investors are
looking at and the way that's done and
let's say commercial real estate is it's
called the cap rate yeah it might be a
billion dollar building but if you only
make a thousand bucks a month why would
you spend so much money contrary to an
area where you could buy a cheaper
building and make a lot more money per
month so when we're looking at growing
organic versus hydro keeping quality and
perspective the profits can be there or
better and to me that's what we're
talking about when we're talking to
yield otherwise I can go spend a whole
bunch of money and get a lot of yield it
doesn't mean it was efficient yeah for
sure
and I like to use the again the Reds
analogy of synthetics being like you
know your force feeding it like sure you
can get it bigger than it wants to be
but is it the right thing yep is it the
right thing yeah and I guess you know
you can get a strawberry in the store
that's the size of us no golf bigger you
know maybe the size of a tennis ball
it's not gonna have as much flavors that
one you find on the forest floor that's
the size of a quarter well we're hoping
to do is find the limit at which we can
get between there and keep all of the
flavor I mean can you imagine the
translation if we were able to really do
this on scale and then take maybe let's
say a product like wine
that has to historically have a drought
to have any flavor and actually be able
to produce at a higher quantity and keep
the flavor we're not gonna be pretty
cool but there's that limiting factor
yield versus that relationship of that
flavor and taste and there's no way to
have all of it at the very top because
the biggest producing genetics a lot of
times aren't even the ones that you want
so now taking the same genetic with all
the flavor and getting the most yield
out of that I think is really the
question so yeah awesome
and so I guess my personal final quite
News do you believe personally that with
the cannabis plant it is kind of that
invisible seesaw of you know like the
yield on the one end or the flavor and
potency on the other or do you think
like no you can find a happy medium so
certainly you can find a happy medium
and what's crazy is when you get too
narrow in any niche like yield and
specific plants there's gonna be people
wanting more yield no matter what and so
at a certain point you have to ask is
there enough flavor as my yield good and
that's gonna be a genetic base but like
for instance squash right now you know
if you grow one squash plant you can
feed five families off the damn thing
you'll have a hundred of them every year
and so you go talk to the squash
breeders and what are they trying to do
get more freakin yield it's like I don't
need more yield I want a better tasting
one oh and so that's where we start
looking at heirloom seeds and stuff
that's whole focus wasn't yield but
flavor and color and beauty and reasons
why individual home gardeners kept these
things and that's why we're seeing
certain cultivars they don't produce
very well being popular in the market
and they command a better price because
those flavors tastes and appearance of
that so we'll find a happy medium but
that's gonna be based on genetics and
grow room environment and really just
getting better every year
awesome well I think that brings us to
the end of it was there any comments or
shoutouts you wanted to make no J guess
just keep an open mind like you
mentioned get out of that minefield of
being on the high horse of organics and
even learn from all the synthetics and I
think that you'll be a well more well
rounded grower but but I really do want
to leave people that are on the fence
considering organics it can be easy you
don't have to have all these potential
problems and you can get yields you can
get flavor and I think that if you're
going down to the shop and the only
opportunity you have is hydro it maybe
start that way but reach out follow the
podcast find some of these resources
that are be going to be becoming more
available in Australia and look at what
we're doing over here and take a little
time to duplicate it I think it'll be
well worth your time and you're going to
be really excited to share the results
with your friends that's what it's all
about
I
maybe I look what I did look at how
amazing this is and I think that that's
you know like you mentioned asking your
friends how to convert its there's
nothing you can say it you just gotta
show them yeah I couldn't agree more
so I'm thanks so much to Jeremy from
build a so taking the time to sit down
with us
huge thank you to Jeremy from build us
up go check out business or comedy
[Music]
thanks again for 20 Australia
you