foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
welcome to the next episode of the
podcast a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts
[Music]
as usual a huge shout out to our
sponsors seeds here now you know I'm in
love them all the hottest breeders and
the latest drops of the best prices
offering a guarantee on satisfaction not
just germination why would you shop
anywhere else guys if you get it from
them and you're not happy at the end of
it all hit them up they'll sort you out
see it's here now thank you so much
likewise a huge shout out to our friends
at corporate biological systems
you know I'm in love them they've got
the industry leading predator and
predation technology you can see the
bugs working in front of you as they go
red that's if you grab the spidex vital
those bad boys get rid of any spider
mites you got and trust me there's
nothing better than getting on top of a
problem before it begins
check it out spidex vital incredible
product thank you so much
[Music]
huge shout out to our friends at simply
souvenirs who have got our friends in
the UK Stockton sorted
if you're after hand selected Boutique
breeders as well as some big names to
satisfy all your needs check out Simply
souvenirs they've got a range of smoking
accessories dabbing tools a whole bunch
of extra things to keep you covered all
with the best customer service in the
game check them out big shout out to our
friends at simply souvenirs
[Music]
and a big thank you to our friends at
Pulse grow sensors you surely are aware
of pulse you probably already got them
if you don't you need to get one guys
because the reality is a lot of
variables in the garden you can't see or
feel VPD like you don't know what that
is most the time get a pulse sensor in
your garden it'll increase your quality
increase your yield it'll help you get
your grow room pumping on all cylinders
check it out guys thank you to pulse for
supporting the show
and last but not least check out the
patreon guys if you want unheard
episodes additional content we're giving
away genetics all the time for free
check it out guys
www.patreon.com the podcast huge shout
out to the patreon crew
on this episode we've got a much
anticipated and awaited interview with
the man himself Gypsy Nirvana
you know MC Boutique I see mags so many
other things
here to talk about a very illustrious
history some cool stories
so much more
let's get into it
[Music]
alrighty friends we are back for another
big one and on this episode we have one
of the most prolific seed distributors
in cannabis history The Man Behind I see
mag and Seed Boutique and the guy who
gave countless breeders their start a
big warm welcome to Gypsy Nirvana thanks
so much for joining us today
hello how how do you do
I do well my friend how you doing this
morning and I'm doing fine I'm I'm
sitting on this lovely balcony as it's
Dawning in the UK looking out over blue
sky but let's see it
uh things are green and uh
happy to be here I guess
um kind of uh flattered that somebody
would want to ask me some questions
about my illustrious and and many
faceted life
you nodded on the head many faceted is
to sort of not even do it justice but a
question we love to start off most
interviews with is what have you been
smoking on lately uh
Moroccan hash is kind of what I started
with when I first started smoking
cannabis way back in uh
the Stone Age
1975 something like that I think I was
15 and my brother had some Moroccan hash
and we rolled it up in a spliff with a
bit of tobacco and we smoked it and uh
it seems that you kind of revert back
maybe I'm going through a second
childhood because
after all this this heavy uh indicas and
and uh you know soaring high sativas
to come to some sort of regular daily
constant and keeper kind of a level head
as much as you can
I come down to what I started with which
is a Moroccan hash so yeah uh I actually
I got a little bit I can show you a
little bit
oh beautiful and how does that one
compared to the stuff you have in your
childhood do you think it's similar or
quite different yeah it's it's not too
strong and it's not too mild we used to
have much milder stuff called slate
Moroccan back then that was the cheapest
stuff and that was harder this is uh
kind of soft you can just break it off
and crumble it up like that
very simple
but uh yeah you know I've been a
consummate cannabis Stoner user whatever
you want to call me uh most all of my
life and I find that finding something
that
is consistent on a daily basis it
doesn't knock me out too high or put me
down too though
keeps me on a kind of level that I can
cope with is the best for me is when I
mix them up then I have the problem uh
particularly a couple of weeks ago I was
over in Amsterdam interviewing a few uh
quite well-respected breeders and people
in the seed industry over there Soma
being one of them and he knocked me out
with some of his Soma salad bubble hash
so you know you can really overdo it on
cannabis you know the the amount of THC
you consume uh everybody's got
you know the tolerance levels and uh for
me
um I try to keep them not too high not
too low
but as soon as you you try something
extra strong
you're gone you know I literally I was
out cold for about a minute came around
again
but in that day I tried all these other
varieties too of weed and Nash so kind
of
knocks you out eventually it doesn't
matter how how strong you think you are
or how much you can combat the THC
everybody has imitations
that's brilliant and I guess as a
follower in general would you say you're
more of like a flower guy or you're more
into your concentrates
that depends you know I'll take what I
can get
you know if there's nothing going you
know a lot of the times uh the users
don't get to choose they just uh they
just take whatever the guy has that has
some you know whether it's a dealer or a
friend or
whoever that passes you some weed or you
grow it yourself
um
that's what you cope with at the time
it's not as if we have the choice of
selection of some areas of say the
United States to with all their
dispensaries and what have you
so generally I don't know I find hashes
more compact so it's much easier to um
to deal with weed is generally smellier
and
and uh and more bulky so it depends if
you're traveling or not generally for
traveling hash is the best
and uh it's nice to have a bit of both
if you're at home you know to have as
much Choice as possible
certainly I can appreciate that I would
be interested to hear though what's your
thoughts on the current UK scene you
know these days it feels like by all
accounts it seems to be really
flourishing and um the law enforcement
is taking a bit more of a relaxed
approach to it how do you feel about the
UK scene at the moment
well I don't know I'm not really with
the In Crowd or if there is an in-ground
I live with quite a quiet life these
days after the Mad Shenanigans of the
past decade
um kind of settled down with uh my wife
and two kids
I don't get too involved I go to bed at
nine o'clock at night you know and I'm
up early in the morning like now
so I'm not so sure which way they're
going I'm not really involved with any
organizations I never have been never
been a member of any organization as far
as I can remember no unions
no political parties
[Music]
no
maybe a book club once
so I mean take me back then what was
your childhood like what was the
progression like for you to get into
cannabis more seriously
well try and encapsulate it in a in a
short space of time as possible I was
born Down the River from here where I am
in Kingston now in chertsey in a field
in a caravan in a rainstorm and I grew
up kind of on the fringes Society I went
to a state sink school after being
thrown out of a boarding school
um
yeah and
they said I was maladjusted they when I
was in my early teens they took me to
for psychological evaluation or whatever
and then they gave me these pills I
think it was how the periodontal or
something like that and it made me go a
bit kind of veggie and a bit Bonkers and
I didn't like it
um yeah sure it calmed me down but it
turned me into a vegetable so I didn't
like that it didn't take them for very
long and about that same time my brother
was experimenting with Moroccan hash and
that seemed to work uh it calmed me down
I don't know when you go through your
teens you you get a big release I think
it was testosterone or whatever makes
you um you know more prone to explosive
episodes or whatever it is and so they
took that as being some sort of
way to say that I was not correct
psychologically so it gave me the pills
and it didn't work and I found cannabis
and it did work
so it's helped me
mentally during that period and later on
when I've had injuries and what have you
and other things I wouldn't say it was a
great painkiller but it kind of takes
your mind off it makes you a bit sillier
so it kind of Cheers you up
you can laugh at yourself easier
it's good to be able to do that most
certainly
so as far as it being a benefit to me
yeah I'd say it has been it's not killed
me it's got me into a lot of trouble
well look I'd be interested to delve
into all of that but I remember when I
read this uh Guardian article about you
it said at one point you're a roadie for
The Clash was that when you were younger
and sort of before you got heavily
involved in the seed scene
well I grew up kind of 19 years we were
in the 70s and I'm a Londoner so I was
very close to the whole Punk scene when
that came about
and uh I used to hang around the back of
the hundred club and other venues at the
Nashville in London various other hubs
where bands were playing and you know
this whole this whole Punk thing seemed
like a new wave it was guys around my
age who were a little bit older who were
um
yeah dressing in Old clothing
were rebelling against society and
during the 70s we had a big depression
then particularly amongst them working
classes
and uh there wasn't much else to do
but go to gigs and jump up and down and
act full you know
we had a lot of fun and some of these
bands I started helping them with their
equipment and they're doing a bit of
roadie work it's just really donkey work
pumping uh big Marshall Stacks around
and various other
items for for the public address system
they wanted to set up in whatever
you know hall or University or Pub all
over the UK so it kind of worked as a
roadie for
a couple of bands the adverts I work for
for a while and then I work for uh
a couple of gigs with the pistols and
then when I went to the states in 1977 I
moved to the USA and The Clash came over
in 1980 and found me in San Francisco
over one of their gigs and then they
asked me to work for them on the U.S
tour because I was just about to join
the U.S Marine Corps and they talked me
out of it
so I did it did a few gigs with them
across the states and then I ended up
going down to New Orleans because early
Dorsey who was supporting The Clash on
that tour it invited me down there
because he had an auto shop
and they gave me a job spraying cars
which I wasn't very good at that kind of
mucked along and then got a job in Old
Man Rivers or some Honky Tonk down there
there's a security at the door
did that for a while it was a New
Orleans invention and came back to New
York and worked for a band called
rockabilly band called Levi and the
Rockettes you know they played cbgbs
Maxis Kansas City Lone Star Cafe
this is going back please
anyway I was kind of mixed up in the
music industry from a perspective of
somebody who worked security were
backstage security for The Clash
um and from stage two to stop people
climbing on the stage
when the band was on the stage
you know there's some really crazy
events not least one at the Santa Monica
Civic uh where um I saw this guy getting
paled on the one of the four by twos on
the buttress the wooden buttress at the
front of the stage and it kind of turned
me off the whole thing I I didn't like
crowds anymore
get away from that
ended up coming back to the UK
eventually and stayed here for a while
worked in a
uh a British wine Factory of all places
for nine months and then decided to take
off to Asia once again bought a car on
drove from Europe
ended up in Crete and I got a job as a
minor for America for an American
Property developer and ended up in him
in his uh misses took me over to Bangkok
and uh yeah one signaled to another God
the guy was crazy
and uh
I ended up in Hong Kong for a while back
in 1980 early 1980s
and traveled all over Asia doing various
smuggling runs
and uh worked for a while in the
entertainment's industry in Hong Kong
I used to use in the martial arts kind
of actionability area it was in Blood
Sport I did bionic ninja and all these
kind of b or C-Class movies
some of them are just hilarious go on to
YouTube and Google bionic Ninja
and you'll see me back in 1980
is it five or six jumping around in
Caroline park or in some container Port
out near the new territories in Hong
Kong it was a crazy crazy days
back in Asia but all the time I was
traveling I was always looking for the
best hash or the best weed
and sometimes it came with seed so I
always thought it was a good way
to
get cannabis around the world was to be
able to be at the layer of seed somebody
that could find something that was
different you know somebody was trying
to make something new they might use it
in the mix
that's so fascinating to hear that you
know the whole while you're always
looking for the best harsh and the best
seeds were you collecting seeds that you
would later sell or was it more like
you're collecting the experience that
would allow you to later sell the seeds
I think what really opened the door was
the internet with weed base
you know which came up was it was a
cyberb where Growers could communicate
breeders from around the world it was
just pretty overgrown
um guys from that side set up over broke
around 2000 I think it was 22 years ago
and uh didn't enable people you know
with a like mindset to uh communicate
internationally
I'm going to go back inside
bloody shivering out here I don't know
it's dropped to about 12 centigrade man
oh wow that is chilly isn't it so I
guess then I would be interested in
asking what was it that stimulated you
to think you know what I'm going to
start selling seeds myself
well I
it wasn't until I think 1985.
um
when I got into some trouble over a bit
of hash
I was I had a fiance who was in Holland
and I regularly visit her
and of course I go to a coffee shop
and I'd pick up a piece hash and I'd
bring it back to the UK
with me you know after the visit and I
think it was about the eighth trip
this Springer Spaniel
stood in front of me and then sat down
and gave me this really stoned look from
this Customs agent at Harwich you know
because I was on the boat from the hook
Van Hollen to Harwich and they ate a
customs check and they found Smash in
the jacket pocket as always
I would carry a bit but not enough to
assume that I was intending to supply
anybody it was just kind of personal so
that ended me up in jail because I
refused to pay a fine or do any
community service
anyway it was a terrible jail experience
and I thought I've got to do something
about these stupid laws
so what do you do
get a Kalashnikov and a bomb and run
around acting like a terrorist no I
don't think that's going to work you
know
you know you become a Target very easily
so
I just thought that cannabis is a
beautiful plant most people have only
heard bad news about it it's been
portrayed as being some sort of evil
um let's get it growing in in thousands
of gardens worldwide
hundreds of thousands maybe even
millions of gardens
so how do you do that if you get it
growing and then people see the benefit
of the plan
they use it maybe they use they eat the
seeds you know or maybe they use the
flax maybe they they uh
you know make a medicine out of it maybe
they get high on it it benefits the
society in some way or another but
Society isn't going to know that unless
they see the plant growing or they have
the access and the ability to be able to
grow that plant
so what do you do you have to give
people that so you have to have the
seeds the ability to distribute them
and you also it helps to have the
education and the know-how and how to
cultivate plant
as well as you can
so what do you need you need a website
to explain that so people can interact
so we did that with icmag and uh
the seeds you need a seed site and
a lot of our policy well my policy from
the start
was the main idea was to get people
growing wasn't to make lots of money
from people
you know so the impetus was from the
start to give people a good deal on the
seeds make sure that they're not crazily
priced if possible unless the Breeders
first of all pricing them so high you
know then obviously you've got to make a
cut on top of that
but uh and then giving away
kilos of free seeds along
with the orders on condition that people
would share them
with others and this is what happened
so for every order that went out it
wasn't just for that person to grow it
was intended for somebody else as well
so instead of one grower you get maybe
two
people kept to you know their pledge of
spreading the seeds
so it seemed to work and over many years
now I think the Cannabis industry has
grown
exponentially it's it's huge now in
comparison to what it was
back in the 70s and 80s
when I started out
getting involved with it in one way or
another
that's brilliant and did you ever have
like a conscious thought so to speak
that like
hey this journey I'm on I may not be the
grower to change the world but I could
play another role and help change things
or was it did it never occur to you that
the ripples would spread that wide and
you just sort of thought you were doing
your own little thing and it wouldn't
cause the effects it did
well yeah I always enjoyed growing I
mean it's a wonderful thing you know I
love having plants around me
but to do it well and to be a breeder
you've got to really you're kind of tied
to one place
you know generally well
would be you'd have to unless you're one
of these Jet Set breeders who can do
everything over the internet you can
even feed your plants every day you know
but no I haven't seen so many successful
situations uh with people that try to
automate their whole systems generally
you have to be in one place all the time
and even if you go on holiday you're
worried sick that when you come back all
your plants are going to be dead
so I know you know the the mentality of
a grower and a breeder
so I you know I do grow a bit but but
not really to the extent that you would
need to grow to be a breeder I mean
people like Sam skunkman think you need
to grow out
ten thousand plants for selections
um to be in any sort of uh respected
considered respected breeder in the
first place and who has the facility to
do that right I think more people do
today than they did
10 or 20 years ago because of the the uh
decriminalization and legalization in
some parts of the world now
but you know still most of the world is
is growing uh
in a illegal light to a certain extent
and you have to take this into account
you can't just think that oh it's it's
legal in the United States so you know
you can be really lackadaisical with
your own security it's not a good idea
sometimes maybe I am because I've only
got three plants so
that's kind of tempting fate but
somehow you've got to work you've got to
do something against it but yeah people
are growing more today than ever they
did and hopefully I you know I was
instrumental in in aiding that somewhat
in the past
wasn't just me there's there's been a
lot of a lot of other people who've been
Distributing seeds
and have a similar mindset and it's a
way of getting back at the authorities
because now we have seen legislation
um hit home you know in favor of
cannabis legalization
uh
you know decriminalization worldwide and
hopefully that will continue throughout
all the Western Nations and then the
rest of the world
accordingly it's it's a very slow
progression I must say over my whole
lifetime
and I've seen it go from bad to worse to
better and it's getting better
now in the UK now I I really don't think
this
concerned as long as you're not causing
a problem with it you know or you're
making a huge business out of it
we've got 250 Stoners knocking on your
door within a 24-hour period
I mean on that topic in a sense do you
feel like you really paved the way for
people like say the attitude seed bank
who are now arguably the biggest seed
bank in the world
yeah well
I think in some respects
um I've I've kind of been
the the head of the industry and been
the one that's had his head banged
against the door a few times uh
I kind of feel knocked out or I did it
it was quite a shock in 2013
I was in a
I had a house in Subic in the
Philippines
and then I got told by my sister's
brother who was kind of our caretaker of
the house
that there was several guys with long
guns surrounding the house yeah
long guns I mean rifles you know so I'm
like oh what's the weather what's going
on so we waited for the knock on the
door there was a knock on the door and
they wanted to take me to Manila it was
um the Bureau of immigration
and I I had no clue what this was all
about I've been living in the
Philippines since about
2006 seven
and uh
had a family there had children there
had my life there everything
and suddenly they wanted to put me in
this uh Detention Jail so they drove me
for a couple of hours into Manila and
dump me in this
really awful dump
dumped me in a dump that smelled like a
dump
and um
yeah there I lived for two and a half
years
um after 10 days of being there they
tried to kidnap me and do what's called
a extra judicial rendition
uh by um
trying to force me onto a plane to Los
Angeles
from Manila Nino Aquino International
Airport I think it was terminal
terminal one yeah
and of course I lucky enough I was
informed what they were attempting to do
by one of the other prisoners there
um
he said that yeah they'll try and do
this to you you need to resist and and
you know don't need to get violent but
you need to try and stop them from
Shipping you over to the States because
it's totally illegal
and can only be done with your consent
because being British I'm not an
American subject
so I shouldn't be subjected to American
law
the long arm of the law overseas
their Homeland Security that seemed to
operate outside their Homeland
so how did you manage to foil this plan
what happened
oh it was
it was a comedy of
it was just a comedy
you say The Comedy of Errors I don't
really know but uh they took me there
and then before I went there uh I mean I
had back then I had my back problem was
a lot worse I've got this
from doing some weight training back in
the 90s and overdoing our talks and
muscles and graded some bone and L1 and
L2 vertebrae or something with my back
so um
I had this enormous
back problem when they put me into this
jail
and so I was taking quite strong
medication for it
and so when they were kind of trying to
cart me off to
the airport I took a double dose
and then I went to the airport and so I
felt no pain at all and I had the
attitude I didn't care and I was very
stoned and I just said to them
you know this is illegal
um you can do treat me as a punch bag or
whatever you like but uh I'm not going
to put those handcuffs on I put my hands
above my head and then they stood on a
chair to try and reach because they're
quite short the guys said
and then I moved along and they couldn't
reach and we had this argument about
them trying to put the cuffs on
but eventually I said look I just want
my lawyer and it's obvious to me that
this is not being done right judicially
and I managed to talk them out of it
without too much wrangling or any
wrestling or anything
so it kind of worked out but then they
took me back to this Detention Jail uh
camp bagong niwa in bicutan
which is kind of like a huge uh police
camp
2000 plus police surrounding you uh all
living in barracks
so so it's not easy to get out of that
place unless you've got some sort of
SWAT team and a couple of helicopters
so I think I read in the guardian
article that you ended up spending like
about two and a half years there or so I
was interested in asking like what was
that experience like how would you
compare it to other jails you'd been in
and as a follow-up did it change your
outlook at all
well it's not as if I've done a world
tour of jails you know think about only
been in two in my life that was one in
Norwich for a month in 1985 in England
and uh then the two and a half years in
the Philippines in bickerton but yeah
that was uh that place was something
else I mean it wasn't a traditional
Filipino jail because the majority of
the people in there were actually
foreigners it was a foreigners jail
so you have people from all over the
world in there in all different types of
conditions physically and mentally
uh you had a mixture of guys that were
thrown in there for various types of
alleged crimes you know
from as small as their girlfriend making
a complaint that that he called her a
bad name you know to some guys that are
involved in you know Kitty Fiddlers and
nonsense and people like that you know
and then murderous between that uh con
artists rapists you name it came through
that place
it was uh it was a human criminal
Menagerie
yeah to put it bluntly and I spent most
of my time in my bunk reading every book
in English so that I could lay my hands
on that was about it because I didn't
really want to mix and Associate too
much
with the other prisoners I kind of kept
away as much as I could
it was kind of it was open in in some
respects because the guards weren't
interfering all the time
they pretty much left the prisoners up
to controlling themselves
so the guys just uh
we're checking the gates that you
weren't allowed to go through or you
were allowed to go through a different
time they weren't too intrusive uh only
had one guard that tried to be a little
bit aggressive towards me at one time
so it could have been a lot worse
and what was it like in terms of when
you finished your sentence what happened
then did you go back and live with your
family in the Philippines or did you go
straight home to the UK
well I never had a sentence you see
I never went it I I never went to court
was found guilty of anything
all that happened was the United States
put out an indictment in their state of
Maine
saying that they wanted me in connection
with uh International
uh trade in cannabis well it was only
the seeds actually you see but in the
United States the seeds are the same as
any part of the plant
they can say you know they can say
you're an international traffic uh
illegal trafficker in Narcotics even if
you are a seed salesman and this is all
I was doing was I was buying seeds from
Americans and selling seeds to Americans
and I was doing it from the UK which is
perfectly legal place to do it from
because in the UK there there is no laws
against buying and selling of cannabis
seeds
so what happened eventually I mean I
didn't want to leave my family over
there I tried to be able to stay in the
Philippines because I thought if I went
back to the UK I would automatically be
uh transported to the United States or
that there would be
you know this this uh
extradition hearing uh or there would be
a trial and uh so it did happen
eventually when I did return there was
the United States came after me after I
was back for eight months in the UK
and they took me to court and after a
year or so the court said no they can't
help me because there's no dual criminal
criminality the law is different here in
the UK on seats as it is in the in the
US
so they can't extradite me for something
legal in the UK
to somewhere where what I've done is
illegal which is in the USA But since I
don't live in the USA since I'm not an
American
uh
you know it stands in British law that
they can only extradite you to another
country if you've broken a similar law
in your own country you know if it's
it's within law that
you are operating illegally in some way
or another
which I wasn't yeah in fact I was just
kind of living in the Philippines I
would say semi-retired
and you know my breeding project then
was was making more kids and just having
a family life and I had I've still got a
few hectares down on the silhou sea
there full of coconut trees and just
trying to live a more basic life of what
you call in the mega City Madness of the
rest of the world but then the rest of
the world has the long arms of the law
that can reach around and grab hold of
you and screw your life up for the next
five or six years and that's what they
did
I had a lot of loss of family
life
I miss my kids for many years although
they could come visit me when I was in
jail but then I left the Philippines I
finally
[Music]
um
they allowed me to come back to the UK
and I think going back there and talking
about other people within the Cannabis
industry
um I was locked up for about two years
in that jail and then the British
Embassy came to see me
uh the Consular attache and he came
along with his quite poorly man who was
uh who had flown in from Bangkok who was
part of the consulate cache group over
in Bangkok
and the first thing he said to me is you
know Howard marks don't you in her sense
yeah so
when he winked at me you know did you
know Howard Marx and I thought
yes or well that's good what's that got
to do with things and after that guy
left over the next six months the
British Embassy couldn't do more to help
me they actually got this one guy on my
case he was half Filipino half English
this young young fella to push my case
forward so that I could finally
[Music]
um
go back to the UK
and to do that I had to drop two cases
in the Supreme Court I had against uh
the Bureau of immigration over there
because I wrote cases against them
and they said that they won't they're
not going to let me leave the
Philippines unless I dropped these cases
in the Supreme Court
so that took about six months to do
before finally they dropped the cases
and then they allowed me to deport
because had a good case against them but
I would have been there forever waiting
for it to come up in the Supreme Court
so what's the point
they got out of there I'm still on a
blacklist so I can't go back there
unless they clear it with the Philippine
Embassy here in London and with the
would they want me back and if I go back
they think I'm some sort of cannabis
Kingpin yeah
this is what was said the uh the
Filipino DEA
um consider me
to be some sort of Kingpin
well I mean you got to admit if you know
how it marks not hard for them to
confuse that while we're on the topic
did you have any cool or interesting
stories of spending time with Howard at
all
I think I met Howard the first time was
I was very young it was out out in Asia
in Hong Kong back in the 80s
um but then he became quite
visible on on the whole weed scene with
Mr Nice
stuff that came out and the association
with Ben dronkers
and uh
of course Shanti Baba or Scott
yeah so I've known all those guys on and
off
for quite a few years we'll kind of
revolve into similar circles on the
internet within the industry or did and
occasionally we get together and party
on the rare occasion that we did it was
uh
you can't I can't remember half of it
because it was so intense you know
that was the way it was uh it was it was
sad because I think Howard went the year
I finally made it back to the UK
and I was not in good shape that's it I
mean the last couple of a year a year
and a half I've really been
concentrating on my own health and get
back in shape because you know sitting
in a prison in Bangkok
to to getting on for three years isn't
isn't doing your body much
I even tried to work out and slipped in
the catch [__] and uh injured myself
so that kind of turned me up
yeah
um occasionally
I might have a chat with one or two and
I've been thinking lately it might be
more interesting to just go and
interview them
so that's what we've been doing uh
putting together
some sort of uh travelogue
a video
Podcast chat thing or whatever you want
to call it going to interview these
different breeders in different parts of
the world
so it seems like I might be doing more
of that coming along
and I haven't done this type of work in
20 years I did I put out a couple of
DVDs I think it was back in
2003 2004
one was uh the kiss from the Riff which
is about the hash trade in Morocco and
another one was
with bubble man over in Jamaica
making bubble hash
that must be nearly 20 years ago
so yeah it's it's kind of an old
profession that I'm trying to pick up
again and
and see if I can be an interesting
interviewer basically doing what you're
doing so that that might be interesting
for me I've always admired um
certain people uh who do that as a job
and I thought that would be a really
really cool job
to be able to do to be able to travel
and experience various cultures meet
different people
and just keep talking about stuff that
interests people you know the the
viewers is is entranced by what you're
saying isn't bored to tears you know
trying to make it interesting
that's fantastic you you fully answered
one of the questions I was going to ask
you which I was gonna say can we expect
any more of those videos but that's
great to hear and you mentioned bubble
man I'd love to quickly ask you I feel
like there's been a notable decline in
the amount of people who are interested
in bubble especially in the Advent of
like BHO and all these other types of
concentrates how do you think we can
help educate people that like really
high quality bubble is still some of the
best concentrate you can get
all right
I don't know I mean you've got to kind
of look at this
not as a cannabis connoisseur you've got
to pull back and kind of look at it as
the General Public
and then make a comparison I mean a lot
of people do always to the alcohol
industry and so if you could try to
compare say bubble to the alcohol
industry what sort of booze would you
have you'd have very fine expensive
single malt or something like that
and out of all the people the alcohol
how many of them actually are really
into super expensive fine single malts
you know it's a very small percentage so
yeah there's it's interesting bubble you
know for me has always been something
nice but on an everyday basis I fear
that I would just be knocked out
so I stick to my kind of mild the
Moroccan hash and it keeps me going
that's brilliant we've had other guests
in the past talk about uh many years ago
you know say the 90s when concentrates
weren't as widely distributed as they
are now people talk fondly about smoking
with Sam the skunk man and he would have
like you know some of the only full
Mount bubble did you ever get access to
that do you ever have any Recollections
of uh events like that some memorable
half smoking with people
Sam's always been that way
you know
when you when you see him or your first
meet him or you see him on a regular
basis he'll always have usually has this
uh very fine dry Sith that he makes him
sell
he's very particular he won't
take anything from anybody else I've
never seen him smoking anybody else's
gear
and he uses that he was the first guy
that I came across I don't know how many
years ago it was that told me about CBD
he said now smoke this and you're not
going to get high off it but you might
feel a bit better
I won
it's an interesting concept isn't it so
it was just like non-alcohol beer this
is stuff is like non-alcohol beer salmon
he's like no no no it's uh it's just
CBDs in there it's not uh he's got all
these numbers and names for all these
different terpenes and God knows what
you know just blinds Me With Science
sometimes the guy is so knowledgeable
um
but yeah he knows what he's talking
about and sure enough another 10 years
later it's all over the place people
were
it's it's it's a Panacea it's a
therapeutic thing it's in all sorts it's
even in shampoo you know
that's brilliant to hear I mean while
we're on the topic of Sam who was some
of the first people once you you know
you started I see mag you thought let's
get the seeds out there who are the
first um breeders whose seeds you were
Distributing was it like Sam's stuff or
was it other people
uh I think
one of the first associations I had was
with Mel from Nirvana seeds
and uh because we share a name
it was kind of interesting I like the
guy he's kind of all over the place he's
not he's very different to say Hank from
Dutch Passion or or Ben dronkers is the
guy from the streets
uh interesting guy his mouth so yeah I
made an association with Mel first and
started uh vending the first breeders I
took on was him with his seats
that must have been I don't know
uh late 90s I think from Holland yeah
the first time I started doing it and I
put a website up I think it was called
seedsdirect.to based in Tonga
yeah and uh then I had a one-page ad in
High Times
and it started snowing through the
mailbox there's so many people were
ordering it was hard to keep up with the
orders just off the off to get go
because it turns out that I was one of
the only
people in the world I mean there was a
couple of other
seed Distributors online I think Mark
Emery was doing it in Canada
and Heaven's stairway in Canada also
a place called Laughing Moon
uh that that was about it
so I've I've kind of tapped into
a niche market uh that of cannabis seeds
that people were really trying to get
hold of you know all these new varieties
that were coming out and older ones
that they couldn't get locally and they
could only get internationally
so yeah it started snowing orders and
trying to keep the administration
together and the work the workers
uh you know to micromanage all that
stuff
was quite an accomplishment for me to be
able to get hold of you know it took a
while
I don't know maybe it's going to take
forever but I find it much easier
without having employees these days
uh just minimize minimalizing my life
making things smaller instead of bigger
taking less on instead of more on
being a [__]
that sounds like a good approach given
the uh you know how busy you've been in
the past what was it like as the
business grew you know were you do you
remember were you just picking up a lot
of sort of European Dutch breeders and
and if if so do you remember when
America First sort of came on the map in
your mind as like hey I could I could
get a lot of USA breeders too and who
were the first
yeah well I I looked at it from a global
perspective because I know that this
plant grows just about everywhere you
know
um
what it can do has the potential to
if you give it the right environment of
course and people were creating
wonderful indoor grow environments
tropical or otherwise I mean I I live
about
I think about seven eight miles away
from Kew Gardens
that I could just go there and walk
around the tropical house and
imagine it was full of cannabis you know
so I know that it you can create
environments like that they're my grow
history I kind of
a bit rubbed off from my grandfather who
is one of the top guys in The Royal
Horticultural Society and he used to
grow wonderful chrysanthemums and breed
them
and win all sorts of trophies and medals
and plaques for it you see the silver on
his mantelpiece it was all from
chrysanthemums
yeah I live in an area where there's a
lot of Gardens and there's a lot of
stuff growing it's very green area of
London right near Bushy Park in Richmond
Park
so it always is a child I was always
interested in plants and how they grow
and
then it led to me being thrown in jail
and me wanting to get back at it and uh
so I thought I'd be a seed distributor
and it was a fun job too you know and
running around the world looking for
rare land race varieties or anything
somebody was making in a different neck
of the woods
basically you didn't you you try and
have a look at how this person was
making seeds whether or not they were a
closet breeder or whether or not they
were doing it properly
so I'd have fun traveling all over the
world to go and visit these people often
before I bought their seats I want to
see how they actually made them and God
knows they might just buy them from
someone else and sell them to you
it might just be a middleman
I got interested then and all the
different varieties and seeing how
people would grow them
in different environments
and being able to share this knowledge
because these people obviously they're
living in a very secure environment they
don't have many associations with other
people because they're doing something
that needs to be kept secret
so a lot of them they're only outlet has
been through the internet
and being able to communicate with other
like-minded people anonymously is
important for that and they've been able
to do that
now for how many years have we had icmag
going I think
not 18 19 years something like I think
we've been going since 2003 2004.
so they're able to do that through the
site
and it's a good way
for people to mingle
to uh
make friends
there's a lot of people a lot of friends
that have been made through the internet
and a lot of those people who never have
met each other in real life and perhaps
never will but they've still got a
friend online
yeah that's a brilliant point you make
and I guess I would be interested to
know was there ever a point where you
realized how big I see mag was getting
and the influence it was having like
when you're going around checking these
different breeders could you feel that
this was getting a lot of momentum or
was it still just sort of relatively
seeming like it was controlled
uh
I don't really know
um like I say I'm not
educated particularly that far
academically or you know I haven't
haven't been through a college or
university
so maybe that's my excuse to say that uh
yeah I saw things moving forward but I
just wanted to do what I always did
which was travel and meet new breeders
and Growers and either get new seeds
made or buy seeds that were already made
by these breeders and then bring them
back and then the whole distribution
outfit would take care of the
distribution I wouldn't have to do all
the emails
I wouldn't have to do all the work
setting up websites anything like that I
just go around the world and meet people
buy seeds trade seeds grow plants
whatever it takes that's all I was
interested in
um so it was reliable upon
you know a core of people back in the UK
to keep the whole distribution up and of
course when I get into trouble
like I did in 2013
and the people that were working for me
and with me
got the heebie-jeebies naturally because
they'll think it's like Domino's you
know I'm gonna be next
so obviously uh
work kind of slacks off or you're not
there to monitor it you're stuck in some
stinking jail in
in 40 degrees celsius under a tin roof
in the Philippines
so
you're not functioning the best that you
can either
um
with your brain
while we're on that topic do you think
that when you read people online who
maybe you know have some gripe with you
maybe with some seeds they bought or
whatever do you think that like that
essentially was the circumstances in
which that happened like maybe it
happened while you're in jail and like
it was out of your control sort of thing
or what's your thoughts on that
ah yeah I mean
the whole mail order seed industry is
it's it's full of pitfalls and and
difficulties uh many levels from the
buyer's perspective and also from the
seller's perspective
because
you know for years I went through
working within that industry and
you know with with the way that the male
is uh having P.O boxes that certain
postmen figure out
there's there's money going to those
boxes so so orders disappear you send
orders out and they come back to you six
months later
uh after you've resent the order twice
you know it's it's a
crazy world that whole mail order world
and nothing is perfect nothing works
you know like clockwork it's uh
yeah we've we had all sorts of problems
and then of course you got Staffing
problems because you're in a cannabis
industry most of the people working with
you are stoned anyway and occasionally
people make big mistakes because this
don't or they forget things I mean I've
done it myself before
so it's not very accurate sometimes
because of the nature of business I I
guess you could put it that way
yeah certainly I guess just to you know
put it to rest to anyone out there
Whoever has had any issues you know sort
of accusing of like any sort of issues
with seeds or like replacing seeds or
anything are you saying there's
absolutely no truth to that you know
it's just the the general inherent
issues of the system
I don't know yet there's all sorts of
this industrial Espionage as well in
there there's other seed companies that
will try and build themselves up by
putting you down uh you get fake uh
customers sometimes who demand that they
ordered and yet they didn't or that they
didn't receive their order and yet they
did you should have seen back in the
Heyday of it and some of the chargebacks
uh we used to get were horrendous you
know looking at five grand a month or
something people that receive the seeds
or whatever it is that you're sending
them and uh
didn't say that they didn't because you
don't end up with a signature because
you're sending it through regular posts
and there's no actual proof that the
person received it when perhaps they did
or perhaps they didn't you you never
know
uh this is the whole thing with the
International Post it's so unpredictable
it can work nine times out of ten or it
can only work one time out of the ten it
depends where you live and what happens
on the way
yeah certainly certainly so I mean if we
loop back to what we're talking about
before you're going around to different
breeders houses sort of trading seeds
getting a feel for the land well is
there anyone's grow or Bud who like it
really stood out in your mind is like
memorable where you were just really
Blown Away
uh yeah there's a lot of different
breeders a lot of different characters
and it's difficult to
you know to put them
in a list who you think's better or
worse but um who stands out
I guess breed of Steve more than
anything a Canadian uh breeder he had a
company called spice of life
seeds
very interesting guy
very smart
and uh yeah I used to go I used to drive
to Switzerland he he got himself set up
with a Factory in Switzerland for a
while and I used to drive out there
and see what he was growing you know he
was really into making this variety
called sweet tooth
and uh several others a lot of them were
canada-based varieties or USA based
varieties that he be coming to contact
with and made seeds from
but yeah there was one of the more
interesting readers I'd say
would be breeder Steve and of course Sam
Skunk Man as well you could sit there
and he could ramble on for hours just
interesting stuff if you can understand
it you know because it's quite technical
a lot of the time
but yeah if if you want to look at
people like him
yeah it's uh somebody that's been
eclipsed by this plant all of their life
and had something to do with it in one
form or another has made a living out of
it so is part of the industry
yeah definitely definitely I mean I was
also going to say we're lucky enough to
have um had breeder Steve on the show
he's definitely uh a very smart guy
interesting character and I remember I
think he actually told her a story about
being on an Autobahn with you in a fancy
car or something going very fast
yeah yeah obviously we have some funny
experiences sometimes
yeah I used to have this very fast car
and used to drive it over to Switzerland
and commute to Amsterdam in it and there
was quite a few Adventures associated
with its travels
suitcases full of seeds and
getting pulled over by the uh
who was it by the Belgian police wasn't
it no just before I went into France
from Belgium
and then them finding a couple of
Samsonite suitcases for the the seeds
that I just bought in Amsterdam because
I used to go on a a couple of times a
month I go through all the breeders in
Amsterdam and just buy a whole bunch of
seeds and then drive them back to the UK
rather than risk sending them through
the post
and of course I'd have to travel through
Belgium and France to get to the channel
port to get to uh
Calais before I could take the channel
tunnel over to the UK
and yeah they nabbed me once in Belgium
and it in the diff it ended up with them
taking all the seeds that I had in the
back of the car
they did same me for I think about four
hours and just let me go
after searching the car
quite well I think they were looking for
class A drugs they were surprised to
find seeds you know
and the funny thing was as I drove away
I'd before I'd stashed half of spliff in
the sunglasses
capsule just above your head if you're
driving that car
and I popped that down and they hadn't
even looked in there so I had half a
split was driving away from the Belgium
to Lisa just taking I don't know about
50 grams worth of seeds off me
and there's me smoking a spliff thinking
I'm lucky to get away with that
and I said to them when they took the
seeds away what I do they said I'll get
an attorney thinking geez the attorney's
going to cost more than the seeds did
that's brilliant you know there's
there's all these pitfalls I mean if
you're
if you're a businessman and you're
you're trying to distribute cannabis
seeds around the world it's a lot more
difficult than than if you were into
doing Distributing shoes or plates or
there's a lot more pitfalls particularly
legally just driving through a country
with something that's legal in the
country you bought it from in the
country you're going to that's what
happens
yeah look that's interesting sounds
sounds stressful did you find it
stressful or is all pretty laid back
all right I'm quite used to
you know the Customs organizations
around the world and the thought of
being detained and all that so you kind
of preempt these things you might do a
trip 10 to 20 times and think oh yeah
that's fine but you know in the back of
your mind
that there is a potential that you could
come unstuck but you kind of you work
that into the risk factor
and you either take the chance or you
don't
and if it happens at least you prepared
yourself psychologically uh for the
event
that you're kind of like oh yeah I
thought about this before this this was
going to happen sooner or later so you
can kind of eat that
and not get too freaked out about it as
if it's a big surprise
yeah sure sure
I'm always interested to know
I got I have this like theory in life
where it's like any job you can think of
like some of the biggest challenges like
it's not the things you would think
about it's other stuff so I want to know
when when you were doing the seed
Boutique and I see mag was sort of at
its peak what were some of the
challenges that like the general public
was probably not even aware of that you
were dealing with and you're like you
know it's calling causing you
frustration you're like oh people knew
it would be like make my life so much
easier like what made the job
challenging
I think it's drama
you know if you let too much drama into
your life
if the people that
you're in regular contact with daily
have ulterior motives if they are
pretending to be something they're not
and you were actually fooled by it
and you've taken people into your
confidence perhaps you shouldn't have
and then it can all fall apart uh
quite quickly if you don't feel that you
have the security within your own
business that you thought you did have
before
and this happened uh
because it's not only the business but
the people that run it they have their
own personal relationships of course and
uh their interactions with other people
and it's the success of the business is
to a greater degree I think based upon
them being in harmony than anything else
because if you don't have the chemistry
of the people that work for the business
correct then the business isn't going to
do well it'll pull itself apart
and this started to happen because uh I
broke up with my partner Nikki
and we we had a partnership in the
business
both of us equal partnership and then
the manager that I had at the time this
Roger Thomas Clark otherwise known as
plural of mongoose
was kind of the manager of the mail
order and they
became an item they became a couple and
they moved in to a house with each other
and then they tried to take the business
off me to skirt to scare all the people
that were involved all the other
employees
uh with me with threats veiled threats
and otherwise
and it became nasty as if you know this
business that I created with Nikki as
hell of course uh suddenly it wasn't the
beautiful business that I thought it was
that somebody else is becoming bold and
it turned kind of nasty and
we had to certain events
violence certain events of extreme
emotional distress amongst the people
involved and
yeah it
it was like a
it turned into a bit of a beast
I didn't enjoy it so much
is this the uh the context around that
Infamous video of I'll eat your mind
yeah well that was
kind of made as a gag
um I think if you see in the beginning
of it
or at the end
I'm saying cut because I asked the guy
to film it and I told them that yeah I'm
going to chastise uh Teflon in front of
the camera because he was in cahoots
with the mongoose
and to film it because it might be
interesting people might want to look at
it
so it was kind of I was had my mind set
in The Long Good Friday that there's
some movie some scene in a movie and I
was very stoned at the time but okay
let's give a Teflon some grief but not
to the point of chucking him out the
window I never had that intention
it was just kind of a bit of drama that
we played out
that was all that was
and then Mongoose okay Mongoose got hold
of it and then used it thought he he was
using it as something really bad to
throw at me and put online
so and he entertained a bunch more other
people I suppose
yeah interesting we had a few listeners
who asked about sort of just your
general Reflections on having work with
Mongoose I guess by sort of what you've
said here you sort of like I don't know
would you say you regret it or it's just
one of those things where you like
learned her lesson
sometimes you've got to look at yourself
in the mirror and say that you've been
naive you know that uh you've let people
into your life that haven't been
beneficial to it
you know I haven't even been neutral
that have been bad uh your association
with those people
has not ended up well put it that way so
yeah you can have regrets that what's
the point it's in the past now
um as far as whatever Mongoose has done
I think now he's um
be sitting in a I don't know is it a
nursing home or a jail in New York
still waiting on his sentencing
and he plea bargained down to I think
just being charged with one case
and he's uh he's looking at 240 months I
think it is
in jail that would be minus whatever is
served
well
reading through the papers because as
the trial goes on or a case goes on in
the USA you can actually follow it and
one of my ex-employees has been
following the case of the Mongoose at
the moment
and of course he's accused of being
instrumentally involved with the Silk
Road website that would sell
every type of drug imaginable there was
a few kids that ordered with their mum's
credit cards and died of heroin
overdoses or something through that
website
so he was involved with something that I
would never touch
[Music]
um
and now it's you know he's trying I
think he's trying to delay his sentence
in as much as he can because
he's had a fall from his bunk in jail
he's uh complaining constantly about not
having a pen and other things and that
only been reading through the case
lately
what's going on with him
and they're trying to get him sentenced
I don't know
good
anybody in the prison system you know I
have a kind of a little
feeling for because it's no fun
maybe it's something to do with Karma
with him
because I see I've seen him do so many
other people wrong
maybe it's coming back on him now
we'll find out I think he's sentenced to
supposed to be some sometime around the
end of September
coming up there you go we'll have to
follow that one to see what happens
I think at this point you know you've
been talking about negative associations
everyone is waiting to hear us talk
about res you know he's a focal and
polarizing figure in the Cannabis
community and especially in history what
was your relationship with him like and
reflecting back on it how do you view it
now and I guess you know whether you
want to answer now or later we'll we'll
go into the the whole incident with
Dutch grown and whatnot
yeah uh res
well
as you read through you spend hours
looking at a forum site and you read
through it some members stick out more
than others for whatever reasons maybe
they use language that
is outrageous or maybe they've got some
sort of humor
that you can
you can jive with
uh there's always seemed kind of
interesting
to me and
he he had a kind of a following of
people that either they loved him or
they hated him
you know he had this he got a reaction
out of people
I think because it was always very
abusive to everybody maybe that was it
whatever it was he has some sort of
pizzazz you know
um and uh
he seemed to know a bit about breeding
and he was making seeds eventually and
he wanted an outlet for them so I
suggested hey you know I've got an
outlet why not
so like any other breeders I started
bending seats that came from him over
the years
and
generally they were quite popular you
know he had his detractors
and he would voice citrusly attack them
too on the boards of overgrow or icy
make sometimes I think I had to ban him
I even had the banner is at one point
and for a short period of time
yeah he seemed like before I even met
him he seemed
quite uh
an open and interesting character
or maybe it was just a Persona he'd
created
for use on the internet I wasn't to know
until I met him of course
and what was that like
when I did meet him
he's a very slender
um and a Haggard looking dude
like he'd uh
he'd worn life on his face a few times
and
yeah he he was interesting he was he was
conversationally quite lucid and we
talked a lot about different things
um over the years build up a
relationship as a vendor and him the
producer of various seats and we he
would allow him to go and build up his
release or whatever it was and then we'd
do a pre-release on seed Bay and
get some seeds out there people would
grow them and then if they turned out
well then others would want to buy more
oh he had this ongoing
kind of business deal with him
he would it was very difficult to pay
him you know so you could only pay him
in cash and uh
you know you couldn't just send it like
we with the other breeders or whatever
it was most of them you could just pay
them bank to bank or whatever it was
they didn't want to play portrayal uh
yeah and I think one time he was on his
way back and he got caught with some
cash or some seeds got caught he was
sending coming this way and the cops
wrote him in
little did I know about it at the time
um that he he'd already had I think two
strikes he lived down in Florida and
he'd had a some sort of cocaine uh
charge some
yet some federal charge against him
anyway it was back in the times I think
when there's like three three strikes
and you're out it's this whole thing so
if he got busted for something else then
they could throw him away for a for a
very long time in jail
this is what I think led to him turning
informant and grassing up a lot of
people over there like chemdog and
Dutch grown and a bunch of other people
that the police pulled in and then
squeezed them as they do
and so it goes and I was one of the ones
that got turned over
The Better or For Worse I mean they
probably I heard that they'd gone to
um
after they took res down and then turned
him into an informant
he told him about Dutch grown and they'd
gone over there and they'd seen my name
on seed packets what I wanted to know is
this Gypsy Nevada
and of course they'd handed me over as a
the UK distributor
and at that time I was out in the
Philippines I was living there I was
resting
and so that's where they they I was not
as if I was hiding
uh I was being quite open I didn't think
I had anything to worry about really but
uh
obviously I I did and it ended up
with me
being detained
excuse me I've got the burps
no problem you strike me as someone
who's sort of
um I get the vibe you sort of made your
peace with it all do you still hold him
quiet personally accountable for it all
and as a follow-up like do you have any
thoughts on the fact he's like back and
active on Instagram
yeah
you know I could be bitter
than I could feed off some sort of hate
and
uh want to
you know get some sort of Revenge or
whatever it is but I I can't muster up
the energy to bother it just seems like
a not a very productive endeavor
to go after that I'm not really into
tearing people down
if he's come through it all and can
manage to
keep a living out of life
I think he's got more to worry about the
people he grasped up in the states than
me
I'm a long way away
you know we all have to pay for our sins
at some point I guess
and uh
you know I always like Ransom I thought
it was a bit of a crazy guy he was
always popping pills too as always on
these Pharmaceuticals whatever it was
but uh he visited me a couple of times
when I was in the Philippines and I got
along fairly well with him so I didn't
have you know I didn't hate the guy or I
don't really get into heat anyway so
and okay well I'm I'm gonna say that
this guy has to go to jail indeed do 20
30 years for me
I mean who's going to do that honestly
you're going to go to jail for me
they came after me anyway and then in
the deaf they couldn't get me
um I've got a clear Clean Slate now
they've dropped the charges in the court
in Maine and they've got the proofs
they've got the original uh court
documents saying that there's no charge
against me and it's been dropped
but it really screwed my life up for a
long time cost me an arm and a leg yeah
led to a more simple life which which
I'm quite enjoying to tell you the truth
that's interesting to hear it's come
full circle I like that I like that did
out of curiosity a lot of people say
that um res did a lot of his work out of
a few tents which people try to
criticize but I always thought isn't
that more like impressive because he's
regarded as having some pretty pretty
bloody good work have you heard anything
about that did you see anything like
that when you were with him
no actually I never saw anything where
is it ever grown because I've never
really visited
New York much at all since the 1980s I
was in New York in the 80s but no I I
never went to see any of his girls but I
did know some people that did and they
said they weren't really a large concern
to say the least
um
but you know it's stayed with breeders
again you know some of very few of them
hardly any of them
do it what's considered the right way by
growing out for selection
tens of thousands of plants you know at
least a thousand they cannot they only
can do it within the space that they
have so if they've got a closet they
could still make seeds
like you can still make children in a
council house and you can make them in a
mansion you know
yeah a fair point a fair point
interestingly you were one of the first
people to pick up bog what was your
friendship with bog like
a book was always entertaining wasn't he
in a kind of risque body brought it on
kinky way the way he would describe how
he would play with his female plants or
whatever it was I just like this is this
broad sense of humor because I know that
humor is a good way to teach people you
if once people are laughing they're more
likely to hang on every word you say
so book had the uh kind of skill
to write down stuff that would make you
laugh and wince and kind of cringe or
whatever it was it was an interesting
character just in the way he wrote
so good afternoon that way and then of
course I said to him at one point I used
to send him three seeds because he would
always grow them out
and make some glowing reports sometimes
and I said why don't you make seeds from
the seeds I send you so he decided to
become a breeder and that's how he
started boxes and
the rest is history well he's not with
us anymore I think he died last year or
the year before not too long ago and I
hope he's resting in peace
and he's got plenty of bulk bubble with
him
certainly Victor he came over to
Amsterdam a couple of times as well
he used to be a paramedic so he'd have
quite quite a bit of life experience I'd
say anybody who works in that profession
would do
um and he did some things with me like
we drove through the German order barns
at speed it's in a fast jaguar and I let
him drive and then I drove we went over
the mountains and yeah it was It was
kind of idyllic he had a good laugh
together
it's a good character sounds brilliant
and that's what it's about personalities
and characters you know that's what I
enjoy most uh getting around to meet
these people and of course the the
lovely plants that they're involved with
generally as well
that's an interest too but uh I've been
able to travel and meet people
why not you can always stay at home and
grow but that's the options you have
generally I choose to be on the road
but if you're raising your own kids at
home with your missus you don't want to
be absent too often
so at this stage in my life I'm spending
more time around the house I suppose
yeah certainly and uh yeah I didn't
mention before you know rest in peace
bog another character who have to give a
rest in peace to who you have a history
with sub cool who passed about a year
before bog did what was your
relationship with sub cool like I mean
there's obviously that notable story him
on the forums when you got arrested how
do you reflect on the relationship you
guys had
subcool is another guy that in was out
of the early overgrow days they give us
some weed base even before that what was
that variety he was connected with
Jack's cleaner that was it
was all into the Jack's cleaner thing
and uh
I got to know him a bit online and then
I think at one point he got into quite a
bit of trouble
and I said uh to him well why don't you
come over to Europe you know maybe if it
works out if you're the right person for
it I can give you some work
and uh
I'll let you stay in a place there when
you come over
so he did eventually he came over and at
that time it was around about
it was the first Cannabis Cup that I had
a stall in
and I was advertised in the stash boxes
and of course the seed company
and
I kind of got him to help out is that
um
trying to set it up
and
after you've been over for a short while
he brought another friend of his over
blunt blunt I think his name was
I don't know his his real name that he
called him blunt
and
he also asked if he could stay at this
place I I was renting this house at 43
zadike
um it used to be owned by Morris de
hernand who is a famous hash Smuggler
and it was a crazy place with a lot of
different bedrooms and different levels
and what have you and at that time I was
given because I was riding the weed
World magazine they gave me this big
plastic bucket full of uh various types
of hash and weed I think there's 30 odd
types of weed and maybe the same again
different types of hash and sub coolant
blunt sat down with me and we were
trying to judge and so I was giving them
a smoke of one variety and something
else
and these guys were always talking about
harder drugs as well they were always
talking about and
Pharmaceuticals
um
yeah
I forget the names of them
pretty strong opiates or
synthetic opiates that they were into
like Percocets or something
yeah
is it vicod Vicodin yeah Vicodin yep
that's a strong one I could then and
some others
um I I can't recollect there's nothing
I've really been into
those sort of things of serious pain
relief
and these guys didn't look like they
were in serious pain
anyway uh suffice to say that after I
think a few varieties I tried and I just
it's knocking me out so I had to go to
bed and I woke up the next morning and
soccer was running around saying there
was his friend had died during the night
what the hell
is going on
okay so sure enough
this blunt guy
had passed on in the night for whatever
reason I mean
I'm not sure but you know I could I
could have my guesses
so this was the the notable incident
with uh Danny Boy
oh Danny that was his name yet Danny Boy
oh blunties to call maybe that was his
own name on online name was blunt
but uh I mean in the house at the time
we were starting from my company in the
UK
and it was about three different ladies
and they're all freaking out
and it's not every day you wake up
and there's a big guy in the house
and you don't even know the guy
you know so I don't know if you've seen
some of their movies
where what's the name of that movie I
saw once where they had a party and then
they woke up the next morning there's a
dead guy in the house it was just like
that
and it kind of freaked everybody out
knocked him off whack a bit
and uh
sub cool was just really losing it
and I was trying to help him out and
calm him down and realized that he was
agitating the women as well uh the
ladies there who are very emotionally
upset so I thought
best if if we get in the hotel so we go
so I've called 400 bucks and said I
didn't go get a hotel because we can't
deal with this right now you know we're
busy as a company trying to do this
Cannabis Cup Thing
and this emotionally is upset in the
whole house so it's better if you if you
get a hotel and
he was uh you know I'm not there as a
psychologist because his buddy died you
know for me it was it was I was trying
to deal with a the whole business thing
is of keeping the store open the
Cannabis Cup and doing what we intended
to do while we were over there from
England
[Music]
uh yeah it was it was difficult let's
put it that way maybe I was a bit brash
maybe he was a bit too emotive about it
I don't know how long he'd known the guy
but it was as if he'd lost a brother it
wasn't good
yeah I think you know reflecting back on
the chat I had with sub I think he did
largely view Danny as a brother
um that's interesting to hear your
perspective yeah because I think when he
said it he sort of viewed it as being
kicked out of the house but of course
you know we didn't really know about the
effect he was having on the other
housemates which is obviously a
consideration
yeah so to me morale was important and
we were trying to do something there
that we worked out months before
and to get it done you know we couldn't
be mourning this guy and be walking
around moping because this guy died in
the house we didn't even know the guy
anyway
so it was kind of removed it was sad but
it was kind of removed for the fact that
this guy was nothing to any of us it was
just somebody that showed up the day
before
literally
some of the girls didn't even know that
he was in the house in the first place
certainly a very unforeseen event for
sure how did and then how did that all
pan out after that the event finished
and you just ended up going home did you
have any like follow-up investigation or
they just accepted it as an accident
well it was me also a bit concerned
because I had this huge cachet of
samples for the Cannabis Cup inside
the house and I don't know what the
other people there were what type of
recreational drugs they might have had
for their own use so no idea
um and there was quite a compliment of
people in the house itself
so
yeah there was a concern for that but it
turned out that there was no
investigation or anything like that and
they said that he had some sort of heart
attack uh something to do with his heart
and that was all I ever heard about it
and then the next thing I do is sub call
a bad mouth in me saying that I'd acted
in a bad way or whatever I don't know
uh basically telling some lies as well
maybe he felt hard done by by my
reaction to the whole thing
it's sad but that's the way it is
sometimes [__] happens and maybe you
don't act the coolest on the block with
it the way life goes
yeah look certainly sounds like a very
complex situation I imagine that there
would have been a lot of competing
interests at mind I mean you know
obviously a rest in peace Danny Boy and
sub and bog while we're on that topic
you know I guess around that time we're
sort of around the time when we had the
original incarnation of Brothers Grimm
and I feel like you don't really hear
much about Sly Mr Soul's still around
and doing his thing but do you have any
Recollections about slide or did you
ever deal with The Brothers Grimm
yeah I was I think I was this the second
vendor ever to offer their seeds for
sale after having stairway Richard
Calrissian
um
he was their initial vendor and then
they wanted somebody in Europe
so I think it must have been 2001 or
something
21 years ago I became a vendor of
Brothers Grim seats they were very
interesting in fact they're very
interesting to a lot of Dutch breeders
um who taken them since then they made
their own varieties or crosses
female seeds and various others
taken Cindy 99 and various other
varieties that brother scrimmer put out
and created new hybrids with them
so yeah it became with me you know again
transatlantic not just going one way
sending seeds to the states it became
receiving seeds from USA breeders and
then showing them to European breeders
uh
that's interesting and did you ever have
any specific Communications with Sly and
I guess the reason why I ask is I've
heard some people describe Brothers
grimmer's Soul was you know really good
at the marketing and Sly I was doing
more of the breeding did you have any
info on that or not really
um I never met Sly but I did meet Mr
Soul he came over to the UK you know
maybe 20 years ago nearly
and uh I gave him a road over with me to
Belgium
in the car because I was doing my
regular commute to the Amsterdam shop
and he came with me on one occasion he
seemed like a nice fella
I can't remember the actual conversation
at the time
that uh yeah I I did ask him at the time
if it's okay to make f2s or whatever you
call it out of uh Cindy 99 because we
had so many people asking for stock and
we didn't have any more Brothers Grim
stock and it didn't look like he was
going to have any because I think he was
working in the engineering field and he
had a job in Europe
and so he couldn't concentrate on
growing back in the States like he had
done before
with the sly
um I've since learned that sires passed
away in recent years
so
Mr soul is the only representative now
I've got brother scrim out there
and good luck to him he seemed like a a
nice chat I didn't really know him for
that long you know it was just a car
Journey more than anything this is the
thing with the internet you you might
know people for years online
but uh when they sit next year in a car
and you're on a four or five hour
Journey or whatever it is you get to
know them much better that way I prefer
the personal meeting with people that's
why I've always made an effort to get
around the world to meet various
breeders
different times not just to buy stock
just to see
see how they make their seeds you know
yeah brilliant brilliant something I
wanted to ask you a little bit unrelated
I heard that you were friends with
kangativa and when you got out of jail a
few years ago he went to the UK is that
true can you give us an update on him if
you know anything
who is kangativa
I guess that answers the question you're
not sure no he's the um the Australian
grower who's like associated with
mullumbimby Madness
um he was working with Neville on the
Grail Haze a little bit he's
yeah known a few horses over the years
I think they don't go by their online
names so I might have known him as
somebody else
yeah there you go maybe maybe I'm just
trying to think of how else you might
know him do you remember Wally duck at
all or not ringing any bells uh yeah
yeah Wally duck or Donald Mallard as we
know him yeah that's the one
yeah he's a mate that I see yeah from
back from the early overgrow days again
um and obviously a bush grower
I think he's up in Queensland or
somewhere
up there in the table mountains
yeah yeah he's a good mate he's out and
dealing with all the wildlife and this
that and the other and it was quite
descriptive and then we got chatting and
of course we shared seeds and he'd send
some seeds over uh that they got over
there and I would send her some more
from over here over there
and he would grow them out and make more
seeds and then send them back this is
what happened with many breeders around
the world
you share the seeds with them and they
want to share what seeds they make with
you if you could sell them or if you
could give them away at least they're
being distributed and plants growing
from them
so that was their mindset which is mine
too if you've got seeds that are just
going to waste away
they just give them away they try and
get somebody to grow them
definitely definitely definitely
I I wanted to ask you who in your mind
is like one of the unsung heroes of the
scene be it a breeder or just a
Community member who you think like just
doesn't really get as much attention as
maybe they Merit
I think there's a lot of up and coming
breeders
that
will come to the fore in the future as
the old school sort of die away
and we we can see that happening already
Within
the Cannabis subculture or industry or
what you might call it that's been in
prohibition mostly over
the last 80 or 90 years
you know there's some have come to
prominence and
others not but I think there's a whole
new batch of people making seeds now
there's there's new breeders up and
coming
um I could throw some names around but I
don't think
that's really the point because these
these guys are the product of what we've
created in the online communities
many times
you've got people that have grown up
were in the early teenage years with the
overgrow and then they come on to say I
see mag
and they've become readers in their own
right and now they're
got their own Instagram accounts and
this and the other their own legitimacy
companies
and it's it's kind of helping spawn the
industry has always been
uh one of the things I feel
most proud of if there's anything to be
proud of within this industry
[Music]
um
helping others and having something
there where they can communicate with
like-minded people
whether it's on a social level or a
business level
or a matter of interest in the plant
it seems to work
you can even go in there and have a chat
you can go in there now I don't know the
latest software
and now we've upgraded um
from the old V bulletin software to the
new stuff
it's a much better site to navigate
I find it interesting but we don't get
the um
we don't get the traffic that we used to
get
because there's so many options now out
there people seem to like
Instagram and Facebook
I'll try to keep the site going as long
as I can
seems to pay the bills at the moment
yeah people talk like they're very fond
about
um the forums but Instagram still seems
to dominate in terms of the numbers do
you think that there there might be some
sort of paradigm shift because Instagram
seems to be increasingly Banning
cannabis accounts it's hard to advertise
do you think there might come a time
where the forums rise back up and become
like the main point of communication
uh I don't know I I don't go to these
sites
uh there are people called Gypsy Nirvana
on these sites but they're all
doppelgangers or fakes or whatever
somebody's even coined gypsynavana.com I
thought I had control of that domain but
I must have lost it through non-payment
of something or other
and um
so there's somebody out there with with
the domain name in my name selling seeds
that's got nothing to do with me so the
internet can be good and it can also be
a bloody crazy place when people Nick
your identity and go around making money
with it
yes certainly and you just answered one
of the questions I was going to ask
which is that yeah the current website
looks pretty unanimously like they're
scamming people but I had a suspicion
that you weren't involved in it
well I guess it's kind of flattering in
a in a kind of perverse way isn't it
when you think of it
yeah certainly certainly we had um some
interesting fans a bit of questions I I
would love to know the answer someone
wanted to know the backstory behind
getting the genetics of the citrile or
the Bubblicious do you remember either
of those two specifically
oh geez I'm only running a 486 kilobyte
hard drive in this brain you know so
I've got to pull up that information
somehow I've got to go back to the 1980s
there's one of these weird modems I use
to connect and it makes all these odd
noises these clicks
so it was citrail
yeah and
Bubblicious Bubblicious
hmm
wasn't Bubblicious something that
now put out
yeah I think I think they were both from
Nirvana yeah as a form of bubble gum
yeah because the the Dutch breeders uh
or seed makers we're all into knocking
each other off big time you know
I think Mao had this uh particularly
potent
um skunk mail
that he got from Sam
and took most all of the popular clones
or anything that won a title or a
Cannabis Cup or whatever and pollinated
them with this particularly uh strong
resinous male
and seem to produce seeds that in many
cases were even better than the
originals as far as uh potency or even
yield was concerned
so just by making these hybrids
you know shaking around the pollen from
this this very good male enabled him to
start a whole Seed Company
out of it
a lot of the Dutch breeders worked it
that way you know and I mean I've I've
heard in the past there's ongoing
court cases and and uh
all sorts of consternation between
various companies using the names of
seeds of somebody else that's created
them like Simon from Syria seeds and the
AK-47
Mel started selling something that was
called AK-47 as well
and of course Simon didn't like it so
they brought a court case or they get
involved in it it almost gets Criminal
uh almost to the point of violence
amongst these people
um
and eventually I think Mao changed it to
ak-48
yeah so it started selling it as ak-48
so yeah amongst a lot of these Dutch
breeders uh or seed makers
um it's not that they all produce their
own special varieties there's
some very good varieties that go around
and they make hybrids uh off of all of
them to a lesser or greater extent
brilliant brilliant and another question
we got asked by a listener is do you
specifically have any recollection
around when Nirvana did their remakes of
some of the classics like the northern
lights and the white widow were like two
notable ones yeah
well I know I know Mel he he would go
for
um what is the correct genetic material
to create something
um he started out with Bernard at
positronics
so he knows the value of producing
something that the public will like
the growing public will like and I'm
sure he would have put together
something that
was popular
you know there's been a few
I think in the past there's been a few
releases of seeds that have not
come up to expectations uh
because they haven't been tested or
whatever but I think Mao always tried to
get tested and looked at me as a good
outlet for testing when I I got the
website together
so we would do you know test grows if I
would get a batch of seeds something
coming up new I put them out to Growers
on the website they grow them out we'll
be able to see them
in live action uh you know how they
would grow out they put pictures up and
then other people would buy on that
whether or not they'd be all different
types of phenotypes and some stunted and
there's some mutant plants
then people wouldn't be so keen on
buying them would they
okay
that's interesting I mean one of the
questions we got asked by a few
different people was like a lot of
people in general have this sort of fond
memory of some of the African lines you
sold and I guess I'm wondering who did
those come from and uh do you have any
seed stock in general laying around or
it's all sort of gone throughout the
years
yeah
most most theater's gone because I've
moved around a lot I've been in places
that I didn't plan on being for for a
long amount of time and uh I haven't
been able to concentrate on securing and
keeping the seed stock that I've had in
good repair so to speak
like when I was away in in the
Philippines in jail uh
my seed stock wasn't kept refrigerated
and it it was just left in an office
with employees that were kind of
lackluster and a bit worried about
themselves getting in trouble for
operating this business
so
obviously germination ratios dropped off
and
yeah uh eventually
you know I came back and I had you know
loads and loads of seed stuff but the
majority of it wasn't worth or it
couldn't really be sold as anything
other than badly germinating seeds so
yeah I lost a whole fortune in in the
stock that I'd accumulated over many
years because of my incarceration
yeah wow that's uh that's a bummer to
hear I I can only imagine all the
beautiful things that would have been
there otherwise one of the listeners
wanted to know they asked a little bit
about if you could tell it I'm actually
not 100 familiar with this so it's like
maybe you know about it maybe you don't
they said can he tell us a little bit
about the haze drama I think maybe
they're talking about the amazing Haze
you gave out is there some sort of story
behind that or not really
now there's been so many Hayes hybrids
and
hazes over the years that I've come into
contact with
um I can't even remember half of them to
tell you the truth because Hayes seems
to have got
into so many different uh cultivars and
and crosses and hybrids whatever you
want to call them
that it's difficult to quantify uh
what do you think of when I say Haze
well I know the roots of it supposedly
it was something that came from the
Hayes Brothers it was mostly made out of
a Colombian of some sort some South
American origin
and
it was passed on to Sam Sam brought it
over to Europe and grew it out
and it didn't always grow true
apparently it's got a lot of different
Thanos and you have to search for the
good one and
you know it's a bit variable I've heard
people say that occasionally it had
intersex traits so
maybe you know it depends on how
somebody grows something out
as well that can affect all of that so
it's difficult to work out exactly
what the haze is or what it was it's
kind of in folklore now almost and
there's people in contention about it
and will forever argue about it you know
about Neville's Haze and about Sam and
we've had ongoing discussions
that go through hundreds and hundreds of
pages on I see mag about the mysterious
Haze
that's interesting yeah it um it's still
just so much discussion around it that's
interesting to hear it's the effect of
the plant I think that more than
anything
is uh most cannabis people smoke I think
these days or consume and be
you know however they take cannabis most
of it is more of uh something that
relaxes you that makes you lower in
Consciousness perhaps
whereas the haze has kind of the
opposite effect and it is very
extreme I think to most cannabis users
because the majority never even tried it
so that's the interest you know it's
kind of uh
what was that it's like the absence of
can of cannabis
that's a good way to put it I like it
there's an Allure about it for sure well
if you could only pick one strain to
smoke for the rest of your life what
strain would you pick
oh well whatever I say people will
disagree with me because they prefer
their own but as far as hazes are
concerned
um sometimes I think it's a it's a
little bit
too much on the edge I wouldn't pick a
haze but I'd pick something that was
a nice hybrid like Cinderella 99 that
would suit me
something that's fast grows indoors very
fruity
wonderful kind of dank kind of
fruitiness pineapple papaya fruitiness
that Cinderella 99 has it's almost
um
ah it's almost like a candy
I remember the first time I ever tried
any uh sent one of those old film cases
for
by Mr soul I think it was
and uh
yeah ever since then I've been a Cindy
freak
that does me I could survive on
incinerator at 99 for the rest of my
days
yeah it's brilliant isn't it really
functional lovely stuff so I got another
question sort of similar to the last one
and this one was submitted by one of our
listeners they wanted to know if you had
to start growing today and you had to
buy seeds off one of the Breeders that
currently is around what seeds would you
buy if you could only get one pack oh
geez
God that's a tricky one isn't it
because there's so much variety and
there's so much good out there it's like
uh say a kid that really likes chocolate
and you say all right what have all
these chocolate bars do you like
well they're all chocolate
yeah
oh that's a that's a hard one very hard
one
uh
first of all I'd I'd look at the
Breeders that
are kind of admire and would stand
behind their product
um and they are not just something
that's made
conveniently from another breed of seeds
and relabeled and called something else
and look to be growing something that
was
Maybe original maybe getting nostalgic
looking back growing one of the
Mainstays of uh that's the current
industry maybe just grown out of skunk
one or growing out in Northern Lights
or
something
kind of not too fancy doesn't have a a
name that incorporates all sorts of
weird gizmos
that's brilliant another question we got
was um what was your recollection of Tom
Hill and his lines you saw them for a
while do you have any fond memories any
specific memories
the roller coaster of a person really uh
great guy but then I mean there's a lot
of people wouldn't say that uh
yeah it's kind of a a bit of an enigma
and then tends to come on my site
sometimes in one mood and then gets
along with most people then comes on in
another mood and pisses off a load of
people and ends up get getting the
moderators to ban him or he gets himself
banned through breaking the terms of use
of willing
but
yeah I don't know many years ago I got a
package in the mail and it was all these
seeds from somebody called Tom Hill and
I didn't know where they're coming from
particularly and then he kind of hooked
up with me on the website and said yeah
I sent all these seeds over and you can
just give them away or sell them
whatever you want you know so we sold
some we gave some away and
and people seem to like them and then he
became more vocal on the forums and
I don't know a lot of people liked his
style but
yeah he used to I think his his thing
was rum and coke
and maybe when people drink a lot uh
they tend to get a bit sloppy online and
yeah
he was uh kind of
informative interesting but at the same
time insulted to a lot of people and put
it across in
he didn't he didn't coat it with any
sugar
straight to the point that that's uh
kind of people like that if if somebody
comes across sometimes a bit crude
and makes their point with passion
so Tom was very passionate like that and
I think I met him
invited him to come out to the
Philippines years ago and he came out
we went out and had a couple of nights
out on the town together for absolutely
Blotto
had some good times seemed like a nice
guy really interesting
I think he grows up in the mountains so
he's been he's kind of like a mountain
man you know
foothills of the Rockies or something
we've got a few stories together and um
yeah interesting chat now there again
it's about personalities you see
you've got some wild men of cannabis and
I guess Tom is one of them
I love it I love it I wanted to ask were
there any particular standout Cannabis
Cup experiences I'm sure you've been to
a number of them anything kooky or wild
that we haven't spoke about
yeah there was one year I think it was
the second year I had anything to do
with him
and maybe the last uh was uh
I wanted to enter Cinderella 99 in the
Cannabis Cup so this was a big deal for
me the first time I ever made an injury
I cleared it I think we missed the solar
system we went into
this into the Cannabis Cup where you
please yes no problem
so
we were waiting
for the authorization and they needed to
come and pick weed up and the guy came
over from the Cannabis Cup and you know
in a roundabout way they told me that if
I wanted it to place I would have to pay
a certain amount of money so
[Music]
I thought that was kind of corrupt and
that led on to us wanting to you know
every year do the The Growers and
Breeders Cup we wanted to do our own
kind of mini Cannabis Cup just amongst
the Growers and the breeders of the
plant so we started this 420 grows and
Breeders Cup so
the 20th of April every year
um
we put a show on some years
we employed a tribute band so we had an
AC DC tribute band one year and big
venue and I used to Fork out a lot of a
lot of dough to try and get this thing
happening
but I'm not very
very together with organization and
stuff like that
so some years it didn't really work out
but there was still a lot of entries and
a lot of people showed up for it
so
it just financially was a bit of a dream
eventually it just became
um maybe 50 or 60 Growers and breeders
would show up and then they judge each
other's weed that was the last time I
think we had it just pre-covered
we haven't had one since
there are plans to put one on for next
year
and yeah we started it in a way
because I thought the Cannabis Cup was
corrupt
and we thought it might be more
interesting
particularly the The Growers and the
Breeders on on International canographic
to
have some sort of event every year where
they could get together and meet each
other
and I think we've done it in Amsterdam
mostly and for a couple of years we did
it in Barcelona
so hopefully we can get it on for next
year again and I can go along
and pass out on all the different
varieties
I love it I've got to ask and follow up
which Canada's Cup was that the one you
want to send to the Cindy in
oh geez High Times yeah
ah
there you go there you go we had one of
our listeners ask about the Gypsy
Nirvana collection of seeds can you tell
us anything about that
well yeah ever since the get-go
um I've had
some favorite varieties that I would put
into my collection yeah I either they'd
be rare land race stuff that I'd found
on my travels
or they'd be from different breeders
that had certain seed lots that I
thought were particularly good and so
I'd put them in the collection
so there's been several varieties that
have gone through the collection over
the years and I don't think I have any
of them left in this unless there's uh
ones that are still up on seed Bay or
seed Boutique and they would more likely
be newer seeds because I've told them
we don't want to try and sell the older
seats anymore because they're just not
good
the older varieties obviously stock
Runs Out
so we don't have them all the time and
so we have to introduce new varieties
occasionally I'm looking around for
something good to put into the Gypsy
Nirvana collection
and currently
I can't think of anything
that's interesting great someone wanted
to know specifically did you know
anything about the G13 in Cross or is
that like a bit too specific
um
I know this G13 plant it was supposedly
from some American government
institution in in Mississippi you know
this folklore going on about it
and
what has been presumed to be the G13 or
whatever I think Ben did most with it
initially I think he crossed it with the
hash plant
the G13 hash plant it's ncc's
yeah very famous nowadays isn't it yeah
and that became
known as the Mr Nice wasn't it Mr Nice
cross
after Howard monarchs
G13 background how would be an
instrumental in me getting released
from uh Philippine authorities
in the Philippines back in 2016.
Howard was an Oxford Don and he met many
people who are now heads of government
and Industry today yeah he probably sold
them hash back in the 70s or the 60s or
whatever
and he pulled some strings with the
British Diplomatic Corps to get send one
of the top dogs to meet me in the
Philippines and then after he met me the
British Embassy couldn't do enough to
help me get out of there
so
I got out the year Howard died and I
didn't get a chance to actually go and
thank him but I think he talked to the
right person or pulled some strings to
get me out of that that hell hole in the
Philippines that ex Marcos era death
camp that I was
in sconed within and couldn't find a way
out of for two and a half years so bless
Howard Marx
bless Howard marks having a brilliant
effect I think that just about brings us
to our quick fire questions so I wanted
to ask you first one what are you most
proud of out of your career thus far
I'm a proud father uh I'm proud to draw
seven kids into this world I've been
able to support them
um
I guess that's breeding
well as far as cannabis is concerned I'm
I'm glad that I've introduced a lot of
people to it and it's helped them in
many ways maybe there's one or two that
have fallen by the wayside but
I don't know it's the same with anything
you do in life there's always a risk
concerned with it and it's up to you
to quantify that risk and whether or not
to take it or not
and I've taken a few risks that weren't
really in my favor and become a Cropper
in the past
but if you don't keep going forward and
pushing for what you believe is right
if you're looking for change or if
you're looking for a living
the Cannabis industry has offered me all
that over the years I don't regret
anything I've done really
you almost got me there I was about to
ask that so I will phrase it differently
although you don't regret anything is
there anything you wish you could have
done differently
uh yeah well there was this guy is this
online entity called John Lee pettitmore
jlp
and we had this plan to aerially bombard
various parts of the globe with cannabis
seeds
with balloons you know and we were very
into working out the whole science and
you know the weather and this that and
the other how we could like invade
various nations with plants that would
grow from the get-go in the right season
at the right time you see and just force
cannabis on the rest of the world
bit of a pipe dream I must say but yeah
I'm kind of sad that we didn't explore
that a little bit more
that's brilliant that's brilliant okay
so next one is what is the single best
flower you've ever had
um
it might have been the most recent one
that I experienced over in Amsterdam a
couple of weeks ago
Simon from serious seeds offered me a
very beautiful Mimosa but it's this
variety that he has called mimosa
which was an offering and a gift and of
course
it looked beautiful and it was cured
properly and it smoked like a dream and
that was the same day that I'd passed
out on Soma's bubble hash Soma salad
so I have some weird dreams of that day
being in and out of Consciousness
whether or not the Mimosa contributed to
it or not and can't really say I'm not
that okay with my own blood chemistry
perhaps
that's brilliant sounds like a fun time
either way but on the other end of the
spectrum what's some bud wear everyone
around you is hyping it up you're really
looking forward to trying it and then
when you finally did you're just like oh
is that it
I don't know because all various
varieties of cannabis have some sort of
attribute merely by being cannabis
itself you know it's something
um and whether or not it's got one
percent THC or it's got 35 THC on it
seems to be a common denominator whereby
people will judge how good or bad it is
but not from my experience you know I've
got just as high in some respects or
even higher on cannabis that has a lower
THC level than I have done on stuff
that's not neither six you know and is
it really all about becoming comatose no
no you want to try and Plateau out
before you become comatose and enjoy a
high you don't want to just pass out
or do you you know some people's some
people's lives are so Grim that just
being under a chemical Koch is a relief
so
I guess it's horses for courses as my
mother would say
depends what your what works with you in
your own metabolism and what particular
time you take it and what company you
take it with
that's it right Different Strokes for
different folks so we're on a boat and
I'm going to drop you off on a desert
island you can take three strains with
you for the rest of time what three
would you take
first of all the island would have to
have a good water source and the soil
would have to be decent uh surprisingly
it's got everything got lots of coconuts
yeah oh yeah yeah lots of fan leaves
that shade you and take the basic
building blocks of what we've mostly got
today I'd take a very good Haze
I'd take uh a really good skunk one and
uh maybe a Northern Lights five and you
can make a lot of things from that
I'll come back in 10 years and you've
rebuilt cookies from scratch
you know
okay so this I thought is it's a
different one to what we normally ask
people and uh I wanted you to I wanted
to hear your perspective on it looking
back what do you think were some of the
best seeds you ever had available
commercially
yeah I've I've I've got I had an
interest in giving away uh
certain varieties of seeds in the past
because I thought that the one that you
give away are the most important ones
because they're more than likely the
first seed somebody might grow
so you've got to start it with a bang
I remember
I had this seed lot made once called
because who who's your Daddy yeah
and basically what I did I think it took
a whole bunch of power plant
and the Clones you know top commercial
clone at the time in Holland and I I
situated a whole bunch of different
males around the room that matured and
spread their pollen all over these
different Power Plant clones
and
yeah it would call it who's your daddy
because we didn't know who the daddy was
but we knew it was power plant
and it made a whole bunch of seeds a
couple of kilos of seeds out of that I
think and just gave them away for eons
and just about everybody that grew them
out was happy that they got a wonderful
plant that you know flowered fairly fast
it was a good yield and had nice
terpenes to it so yeah those are some of
the more fun things that we've done in
the past giving away batches of seeds
that I know are great and you could
probably sell them for a lot of money
but knowing they're the first seeds a
lot of people will grow and to make sure
that they grow something that they would
really enjoy
that's brilliant I love it not the
answer I was expecting but the answer we
deserved so final question we asked
people if I could give you a time
machine and you could go back anywhere
any point in history presumably to get
either clones or seeds where are you
going to go and what are you going to
collect
oh goodness graciously I feel like um
Philly is fog Around the World in 80
Days who's going to be my past part two
now and do the collecting
if I was to go back in history
[Music]
well you know
um
the enormous Indian hemp trade that
there was
amongst I think it was the East India
Company
particularly in the UK and throughout
the world India
was one of the Prime Growers of of
cannabis going back to the 17 1800s
and to be able to go back to a time like
that
and peruse through thousands of plants
in the fields and make selections and be
able to bring genetic material from that
stop
back into the present
yeah it could be a kind of Time Tunnel
episode at the very least
[Music]
that would be incredible a brilliant
pool to select from and a great answer
in general so I think that just about
brings us to the end of it for this one
are there any comments or shout outs
you'd like to make
uh no just wish that any viewers out
there have an enjoyable experience with
the Cannabis that they grow to in their
life
and for the ones that I've been
instrumental with helping in the past in
the present there may be in the future
grow on
brilliant sentiment so again one of the
most prolific seed distributors in
history The Man Behind I see mag seed
Boutique countless others having given
countless breeders their start a huge
thank you again Gypsy Nirvana for coming
on the show
oh thank you for having me something
nice to do this morning
huge shout out to Gypsy Nirvana
and a huge shout out to you guys for
making it this far join us for the whole
episode as always I hope you enjoyed it
as much as I did
and I hope you go check out our sponsors
who helped make this show happen seeds
here now you know them you love them
number one all the hottest breeders the
latest drops at the best price check
them out seeds here now
likewise corporate biological systems
you want to keep your garden happy
healthy Pest and pathogen free spidex
vital appip param you know two killer
products get your garden healthy and
clean huge shout out to Copic number one
in the industry thanks for supporting
the show we appreciate you so much just
like we appreciate our friends simply
souvenir holding down the fort in the EU
if you're anywhere in the EU and you
need some killer genetics some killer
smoking accessories check out Simply
souvenirs they got you covered guys best
customer service in the game hand
selected Boutique lineup of both local
and international breeders you're not
going to regret it guys simply souvenirs
huge shout out and thank you
that's about it guys
make sure to go check out the patreon if
you're interested in supporting the show
huge love from the upside down Library
this is heavy days checking out
we'll see you