[Applause]
[Music]
alright alright right welcome back guys
part two of our erasing interview i hope
you guys are ready as always it's your
boy heavy days here at the podcast the
cannabis podcast for funny enthusiasts
as always big shout out to seeds here
now amazing sponsors guarantee on
germination and satisfaction what more
could you ask for well you might need to
keep that garden running when you're
popping those seeds so hit up our
amazing new sponsors profit biological
systems
all of the beneficial predators you need
all of the beneficial microbial products
you need and even some artificial feeds
to help boost the numbers of your
beneficial army while the cycle's
running
as always huge thank you to the patreon
gang lifeblood of the show early access
to episodes additional content
interviews with body interviews with me
and jean interviews with bob hamphill
the list goes on check it out
patreon.com
the podcast
hope you guys are ready for part two
we're going to be jumping straight into
it with your boy erasing lock in for
another two hours
let's get into it
so yeah what a fantastic explanation of
all the different areas if we kind of
just keep on that same topic i noticed
in one of your posts you're in one of
the valleys looking at one of the
different farms in the kaiba pass around
the pakistani area and you mentioned how
some of the farmers like to import the
high altitude varieties and they'd
hybridize it with their stock and it
would give a kind of quicker flowering
more squat more resinous plant
this was like
you mentioned this as though it was done
very intentionally and methodically do
you feel like this type of breeding has
always occurred because i think people
often talk about land race breeding as
though
there wasn't a ton of
kind of shall we say intelligent
breeding done but this very much points
to the opposite
exactly that's a very good point by the
way i mean
the way you
[Music]
intend to like put it across
so i mean there are a few different
things happening of course here like
everywhere else so first of all we have
to understand you know the cultural
basis of that practice now this is not
something that has been happening for
the longest period of time like this has
not definitely not been happening for
thousands of years
in pakistan okay
now
some of the regions
of pakistan i i mean even before we get
to that i mean let me just uh build a
little more you know cultural context
here because see pakistan is
predominantly it's a muslim country that
people over there at least 95 percent of
the people are muslim
by religion and the country that is next
to them is afghanistan and that is also
uh predominantly you know muslim family
i'm sorry a muslim country i'm so sorry
about that it's a muslim country right
so now
uh you you tend to have a great deal of
interaction between these two countries
because of this common theme which is
the islamic religion right so
now what is happening is
there are certain areas of pakistan
where this happens and those areas are
situated around thira valley that is
like 32
31 and 33 degree north okay now those
regions while they are significantly
higher
are still not you know high enough on
latitude that they would induce
a quintessential
uh expression that people you know
usually refer to as of ghanica okay
so
what happened was that some of the
people from pakistan must have been
traveling to you know afghanistan and
they must be seeing these varieties over
there that
tend to have
you know better resin content better
effects and just they're just better
overall i mean
in in terms of production i mean that's
one of the reasons why you know
everybody wants to breed with them
so it was a very natural progression for
them to only get those seeds in pakistan
but here is the interesting part now
they're not intelligently thinking at
this point in history
okay we're gonna get these seeds to our
country and then we're gonna mix them
with our uh you know indigenous
varieties or you know the regional
varieties that we have they're not
thinking in those terms that is
something that is going to happen as a
result of they getting those seats into
their country because they think that
you know of course these these are so
much better i mean the highest if not
better i mean it's so much different so
i mean such is
you know
our
human species i mean you know that our
nature is just we're curious and we want
to have everything and we want to have
things which are different we want to
know why they're different
so they must have you know gotten those
varieties and started cultivating them
not not knowing that
uh eventually they will get
cross-pollinated to your regional
varieties
so
in the end uh you know what you re what
you really end up with uh in in a way
that
people are not selecting
after you know after they're getting
cross-pollinated because they're not
really thinking about that they're just
then picking up seeds and they're
growing them and eventually what you see
is you see an intermediate type of plant
emerge from this interaction
because of course there are going to be
still very short plants like afghani
varieties which would still stay intact
and you would always see them pop up in
larger populations you would also see on
the other hand you know
the thinly variety the regional
varieties from pakistan within the
larger populations of that mixed crop
they will pop up but what you would see
in maturities majority you would see
a plant you know which is a perfect
amalgamation of both of those words
and which also seem to have certain you
know qualities which not only make it
better uh in terms of effects or in
terms of production that is yield it
also you know
uh makes it better in survival and you
know in mitigating the environmental
risk so for example i'll i'll just go
this small example and that would really
uh you know
make things more comprehensive
in afghanistan uh if you go to uh
bulk if you go to bulk province it's
really dry arid
there is hardly any rain uh you know
year-round
and most people rely on the glacial
waters so the varieties which are
growing there i mean they're not
accustomed to you know rain falling on
them especially not during the flowering
time even if a little bit does fall in
the spring
so when you take those varieties to a
place like thira valley where you have
an n1 anvil rainfall of close to 900 mm
ah
right so then you're
what you're really doing is that you're
really pushing that variety
uh you know in a way
that the phenotypes or let's say the
genotypes you know which are uh
what you should say which is resistance
to mold mildew or you know mitigating
these
uh you know moisture related risk would
then you know excel and eventually
what's going to happen is that the
plants which are not able to mitigate
those moisture related risk would die
out because
they will not be able to you know they
will have bud rot and because of that
their seeds
uh will be less viable
or viable in less numbers of what i mean
to say and eventually every year their
population would decrease because of
that
and you know we we understand i mean how
population works and you know
natural settings and eventually what
you're going to see is that only a
marginal amount of you know the original
variety that was brought from
afghanistan survives intact
of course with a little bit of change
and then a little bit of you know
pakistani would remain but
what would really overtake and what
would really become of
you know the whole process or what would
really emerge as the one champion in
that you know
a whole
breeding thing is the intermediate plan
that is not only better than both
parents it also has the capabilities to
mitigate all the risk and still bring
all the properties from the afghani
varieties
which
which is why they actually you know in
the first place got those seats to
pakistan so most of the farmers tend to
work with those and
the interesting part is now there are
some farmers which have gone a step
beyond
who have understood that you know what i
could actually separate these two
varieties and i could not only grow them
separately i could have them interact or
cross pollinate at my will
so that i choose you know which plants
get to make the seeds and then i would
have like a test field kind of a thing
which which in modern world we call you
know testing for
uh the seeds that we make and they would
grow them and
then they would select plants you know
which seem to show the best uh you know
the best features what they're looking
for regionally whatever makes their hash
sell more
so it could be yield it could be resin
content so each one to their own but yes
there are people who are now
meticulously looking into these little
aspects and you know
uh it just became becoming
apparent to these people that you know
if they go on selecting for better plans
they they eventually end up at you know
better places yield wise production wise
and quality wise
yeah of course
do you think that the modern breeders so
to speak
could learn anything from the older
school farmers have you ever stumbled
upon a little patch and kind of been
impressed by a little trick or something
you've seen by the farmer and i guess as
a follow-up as these more traditional
farmers learn the more modern breeding
techniques do you think there's a risk
of us maybe losing a little something
about their maybe slightly more
primitive methods but maybe there's
something to it which might be lost
um i mean if if
i mean if some somebody's do i mean
answer this question in a very emotional
political way then of course he's going
to say yes there are a lot of things i
mean you go back to roots and blah blah
blah but if we just break it down in a
very practical manner and look at it
objectively then what do you understand
is that
there's not much that can be uh adopted
by the modern people because
see the
it's not modern people it's not like
modern people is a different species
it's just that
we what we are is that we have at our
disposal
the collective consciousness the
collective intelligence of the entire
community and that includes even those
people who have no idea that you know
what they have been doing has been
incorporated
into the larger understanding of how to
grow plants but what we have understood
that you know there are better ways to
do that
you know at the same time i mean
there are communities in india you know
which have been using you know
lactobacillus bacteria and many other
forms for
you know growing the plants and even for
they spray like 50 50 solution of water
and milk to for the best
so it's not like these things have been
uh invented or like uh you know brought
by the modern cultivators
these were all like simple indigenous uh
techniques but at the same time they had
refined them to a level and not only
refine them i think the what modern
society or rather the modern
community of the breeders have done or
the cultivators have done that they have
uh you know
they have scratched the surface beyond
indigenous communities are capable of
and that is on the scientific grounds
because a lot of cultivator and breeders
nowadays are like scientists basically
so they can they not only breed with
those varieties grow those varieties
they they tend to i mean you know
scratch the surface that
uh you know what makes a certain
technique work or what makes a certain
technique not work like there's a lot of
debate that goes around no-till and
tilling the soil i mean
i know there are a lot of people who get
really you know edgy about this kind of
discussions
and
it is just a amazing thing that you
don't see in indigenous communities you
don't see this kind of discussions
usually they know something you know
that has been told to them
by their families by their elders and
they just
blind you blindly kind of follow that
i'm not trying to say those are wrong
things but what i'm trying to say here
is that because we're not having
continued informed discussion the thing
is only getting passed down it's not
evolving any further it's not evolving
into
something better every year but
that is what has happened in the modern
society when we take up those concepts
we don't just sit on them you know we
we kind of expand them and we scratch
the surface and
you know try to understand why this
works in this way and why not in that
way and because we have the tools and
resources
and you know the scientific
understanding of uh you know the
cannabis has increased so much in the
last few years thanks to you know all of
these countries investing in
uh you know the information of
dissemination of information of cannabis
i'm really grateful but at the same time
i mean there's a big problem because you
know even in if you look at times like
70s 80s 90s in the modern society i mean
there wasn't much of that happening okay
that only started happening like
after 2000 i would say and
because during 70s and 80s the people
who were growing cannabis were not
scientists and the people who were
scientists they would not have grown
cannabis at that point in time so that
really kept cannabis away from you know
scientific exposure for a very long time
but uh as we know later on people like
you know rob clark and a lot of other
people you know got into it and they
started really you know fixing a few
things explaining a few things and i i
think they have what they have done is
that they've really paved the path for
other people you know
uh to like not think about the stigma
related to this plan but just go ahead
and use your scientific expertise and
you know help the community you know
bring out more and more information
and in 2020 the situation is that you
could go on google and there are just
endless array of you know scholarly
articles you can go through about
cannabis
and it's almost like you know it was
never illegal
yeah exactly right and we certainly all
stand on the shoulders of giants like
rob clark and people who did early
contributions and it makes me wonder
were there any people in india who you
looked up to as a bit of a role model or
who was doing work kind of when you were
in your kind of more junior stages of
things
um
i would say in the early life
there were some but it was not related
to cannabis especially
specifically
so uh
my mother belongs to the chamoli
district and chamoli district is
actually the place where the chipko
movement started now i'm going to talk a
little about chipko movement what is
chipko movement was
uh it was like a
environment and feminism kind of a mix
kind of a movement
so they were cutting down trees in
northwestern himalayas so all of these
tribes and that includes uh you know the
one my mother hails from they would go
and they would stick to the
trees they would hug them now chipko
means to like stick to something or to
hug something okay in hindi so that was
the chipko movement so they would go and
they would stick to the trees and hug
them and like ultimately that would you
know enable
make it you know impossible for the
people to cut it down
so i mean i've heard i mean i was not
around in 70s but i definitely heard
great stories of you know
our ancestors you know helping in that
moment on the other hand from my
father's side you know one of my uncles
and you know he's he's pretty famous and
he has been you know presented aboard by
the government as well for his work
around the environment his name is jagat
singh jangli
jangli basically means the guy who comes
from the jungle guy right in hindi so he
has been given this uh
salutation in a way jungli his name was
jagat singh and you know we call him
jungli that because this guy
alone himself planted an entire forest
one day after the other by bringing
plants one
uh he would sometimes take ten plants
sometimes take 20 plants and in a barren
place he was able to make a full-fledged
forest which is now inhabited by a
variety of you know
animal and you know birds and inspect
insect species and you know he was
ultimately awarded a great honor for
doing such work around the environment
and preserving these plant varieties
which grew there so that has always
been you know a driving force for me
that has kept me around the plant it it
always told something inside always told
me that if
it is something around
related to the plan that is you know
that that's going to be what i'm going
to do so
i think that has been a great great
motivation i mean not that i want to
like you know bring that up to you know
really legitimize anything but i mean
that just something that is attached to
my history and you know i'm proud of it
yeah totally understandable that's
that's a really amazing story and you
bring up a really relevant point about
the the destruction kind of of the
natural habitats of these cultivars do
you think people are really paying
enough attention to this and are aware
of the repercussions of that
in america i mean certainly i think uh
almost everybody understands and when i
say america because the community that
i'm in by and large i mean there are
people from america and canada so
basically i just considered that all
americans and even south americans right
and some europeans so uh i think in
europe it's even larger i'm sorry i
think because of the greenhouse seed
company and you know some of the work
they have done around the land race
um the awareness has been a little more
on the european side
but because uh you know all the uh you
know indian and you know the pakistani
and the afghani people who are now you
know coming on to these platforms
uh with their land race varieties they
they are more connected i feel with the
the american part of the community
so i think the larger wave of
understanding is coming from the
american side of the community but
i think for the longest time the
information has
uh been been residing in the european
community and people people have been
aware that you know this is something
i mean this preservation work is
important and it needs to be done the
only thing that sort of bothers me about
that is that there are some people are
not going to really name anyone here
because that really doesn't serve any
purpose but some people you know who
have been to india and you know they
have collected seeds and all they have
ever done is they just sold those
varieties you know to people and made
money they've never sent anything back
to these people they've never spoken
about them they've never spoken about
their problems
and they never even came back or are
even in contact with these people apart
from when they really need the seeds so
although these people have been around
and you know sometimes these people even
you know feel the need uh to assert the
fact that you know they've been around
for much longer but you know then
but i don't
i i feel that you know just being around
is not enough i mean you have to do
something i mean you know you have to do
something that makes a difference even
if even if you've been doing for a month
i don't care if you're if you've done
more if you contributed more then you
deserve
uh you know to be at the forefront of
the movement and you know especially the
people who are whose intentions are
inclined
in in the right way because you know
this thing is this thing is very
delicate you know it can go wrong in so
many ways i mean it's just not very hard
to imagine
right
so
uh you know we're very very of the
people you know we connect with them and
there were instances you know i i got in
contact with some people you know
we're not exactly the kind of people i
would have worked with but well that
happens i mean you know you you really
understand you know the human factor is
going to play out you know sooner or
later
so
eventually we're trying to figure out
more ways to you know keep our rigor
around preservation of the varieties so
not only that we have been you know able
to sending these varieties out to people
we're also preserving them ourselves
which i feel that at least the people
who are you know
uh you know selling them or what they're
doing whatever they're sharing them they
should they have a responsibility that
if you're in a situation in a place
where you can grow it you should grow it
or if you can't then you can at least
you know collaborate with someone
outside you know who is in a legal state
and is able to grow them and have them
grow it
because keeping them shows that either
you want to uh really hoard it and you
know
create some kind of pressure in the
market or some weird thing or maybe
you're just not bothered you you just
say preservation and you don't really
understand you know that the
preservation just like the charity
begins from home
yeah of course and i can understand why
you would be concerned about that
i guess it raises an interesting
question and we had a few of our viewers
ask you know varying forms of the same
question where they wanted to basically
know
as someone let's just say for example in
the western world you know kind of the
countries you mentioned canadia usa
europe stuff like that
someone who's living in those places
what can they do to help kind of
preserve these regional strains is the
best thing they can do
try to get some seeds and do a
reproduction and just make sure they're
around or should they try to caretake
for australian should they try to get
over to a village and actually
physically help the village out like
what you mentioned would be a nice thing
if you went there initially like what's
your thoughts
yeah there are a few things i would like
to
talk here i mean
the first thing is that i really want to
i mean take this opportunity because you
reminded me and want to thank
the global community especially from
australia new zealand
europe and very specifically from
america because they have been nothing
but supportive for last five years i
mean if it were not for the community i
mean the global community you know has
helped and supported
uh you know we can't even like imagine
doing one person of what we're doing now
uh what people can do there are so many
things people can do i mean you know you
could just take a plan you could grow it
and you know if you could show it to 10
people even if you don't reproduce it
let's say you don't want to keep a male
because you have your og and cookies
going at the same time so you want to
make sure it's safe so even if you grow
a landry is female and you show it to 10
people then you might show it to someone
you know who may be a little more
interested and then he would go on to
get those seeds and you know
grow a male and a female and preserve it
so
the point being is not what you have to
do the uh the point being that you
uh you have you have to feel that it
that it's
it's priority that you have to first of
all understand that there is an urgency
this is uh this is not uh you know
uh like women are getting oppressed
which has been happening for like
thousands of years and would go on for a
thousand more i mean this is
something which is happening now and
it's gonna end very soon and then there
will be no more of it so we have to
understand the urgency around this the
preservation effort has to be a little
more than what it is right now but i
think we're on the right track the
attitude
is uh absolutely fantastic in you know
global community for about preservation
people just have no second thoughts they
understand this is important but what
people are missing on is just just
talking about it just going making
comments and you know liking pictures
and saying oh this is the best thing
that's not really helping anything what
you have to do is that you have to get
hold of something gets get hold of
something not trying to say that buy it
from me or like from some of my friends
get it from anywhere you can get it from
grow it preserve it in a way get a male
and female you know this is i'm talking
about the very basic what you could do
and you know you could preserve it make
some notes you know
when when it grow what what was it like
you know how much time did you take in
what it smells like and all the other
aspects
and that information becomes part of our
collective consciousness our collective
knowledge about the land race and
heirloom varieties which to be honest is
very scarce right now okay there we
don't know anything about land risks and
heirloom varieties i mean most of the
questions we have to say i don't
understand and you know i'm not trying
to say that that is because we don't
really understand the whole thing in a
very comprehensive manner as we do most
of the other things
so uh first of all we have to ensure we
have to take every part possible to add
to the collective understanding of the
land race and heirloom varieties and
that could be as simple as growing one
plant in your house making all the notes
about it and you know disseminating that
information among at least with 10
people
the second would be to motivate other
people you know
if you are you know smart enough if
you're that intelligent guy who
understands you know the importance
around the uh preservation then it's
your responsibility to go out to 10
other people and you know let them know
about it at least make an attempt to you
know
um put things into perspective and you
show them why this is really important
and why this is not just uh
you know another
heated agenda on the horizon
well and then there are other people you
know who are more capable who have
bigger farms they have more resources so
those people should definitely be
supporting these groups and you know
support anyone you know i don't care i
mean like it's me or anyone
but
support these guys i mean because you
know uh that's the only way i mean you
can make sure that they stick around
otherwise uh you know it can be hard for
a lot of people i can say that
and you know because you guys have the
resources and i'm now i'm talking about
these people who have big farms and
resources to put behind the plants they
should be growing more of it they should
be the ones who would be you should be
selecting these and they should become
these new people i mean you know how
there is this
uh variety that goes around in uh
usa i might be wrong it's called
i don't know i don't remember the name
of some kind of oj kosher i think maybe
let's just say some og or some something
which is very good which was selected by
oh i'm sorry yeah it's like called 78
og fe i don't know something like that
so
somebody that that tells me at least it
is telling me somebody in 1978 got some
of ghani seeds and he was
you know intelligent enough and
resourceful enough to grow a lot of them
and then select a really nice plant that
has made it down you know 30 years down
you know down the pipe and now everybody
can enjoy that
but
won't we want to have more of that won't
we want won't we wish there were like so
many other more people
when that was everything would have been
you know preserved i mean isn't this the
most uh you know regretted thing ever by
people that i wish people had you know
saved the haze i wish people had saved
the skunk or like whatever else you know
isn't this
the biggest regret in the community
right now and if
if you look at the nature of that
concern the nature of the concern is
that you know we weren't vigilant enough
to preserve the things that we thought
are good
we knew these things were good we still
did not preserve it so if anything you
know if if anything's gonna wake us up
then it's only going to be our own
history which may be as short as like 30
30 40 years i'm talking about the
communist cannabis community but there
are so many lessons to be learned that
the things we lost why we lost them and
how can we make sure that whatever is
present now is not lost so again for the
people who think that these things will
not be lost well consider this i mean
even in america where you know things uh
you know are so much more stable and
everything they were varieties which
were really good and then they got lost
so
you know i mean there is a very good
possibility
this this thing is not going to exist in
like five to seven years
i mean i i could tell you right now i
mean some of them will but most of them
would be gone and if not gone in a way
that they eradicated then those
varieties would not be the same because
like you mentioned earlier in the
podcast
that you know it's only a matter of time
that some people do get those seeds and
they get mixed up
it's all done for so
let's do what we can do now when instead
of you know telling our kids
stories about these varieties let's give
them the seeds let's give them the
actual plants
yeah perfect what a what a brilliant
answer for what people can do to get on
board and help out i think this would
actually be a fantastic time for you to
maybe just explain for maybe the few
people who aren't aware who's a part of
the indian land race exchange and like
where they could get your seeds from and
just some stuff like that if they want
to help out okay um so indian landry's
exchange is a collective uh that really
looks after a few different uh you know
collectors
and you know if they need some kind of
uh health that is related to seeds uh
you know because that also helps them in
a way that financially
uh just let me just elaborate a little
more like i went to manipur this
december and i was alone and i went
there and i got
you know a few hundred thousand seats
from there
so i don't need that many seats so what
i do is i pass along some of those seats
to my friends and they have different
pages on instagram and they can you know
sell some of those seats and whatever
uh you know money resource they get in
turn they can then use it
for their next year tours or for you
know
growing the plant that they're growing
in india
and you know just continue the whole
thing right so
we work i i basically work in that way
and what i have is i have two immediate
uh people who work with me one is
archaic serpent
he's on instagram as archaic serpent rap
realms i think
and he's the guy who's from kashmir and
you know he he does all the stuff from
kashmir basically for me
and then i have another guy that's named
red giant he's on
instagram his red giant 92
he's uh he's the grower he pretty much
grows everything for me
i mean and he's a brilliant grower he
grows a lot of hybrids as well you know
he sells that he does a lot of stuff
so
this is the immediate team and then we
have further extension like indian hair
uh indian heirloom seed company who's a
great friend of mine and who lives in
bombay and you know
he uh
he has these uh unique varieties as well
and you know we collaborate sometime i
give them some of the varieties i have
and you know he moves them
uh so that you know it helps the
community as a whole so we can lift
everyone
and
yeah
and that's pretty much it i mean like
then there are other accounts uh like i
can name in uh there's my
friends from malana the
land race mafia i'm sorry because i
can't really uh you know remember them
land race mafia so these are uh like
young kids and one other kid actually
was on the cover of dope magazine along
with me
uh you know because uh these guys have a
great relationship with you know
villagers in milan so you know they have
they have uh helped us a lot you know
get access to the malana village in the
milan region so
later on you know i thought you know
they were talented enough that they
should be you know
leading their own project and i you know
really motivated them that you should be
try to put out some of the varieties
uh from your friends from malana and
they're just doing just that and they're
also trying to get to these uh different
places you know and trying to get hold
of the other seats
and of course you know the uh afghani
guy baba eight seven nine i mean you
know he's nothing short of an icon of
course and it was really interesting you
know that in 2018 i i met with him over
instagram and you know i tried to get
seeds from him him and the scenes got
seized in the mail
because we had no idea that they will
get seized and what i had to do was i
had to actually flew him over to india
along with the seeds
and that's really was the first time how
i got the got hold of the afghani seeds
which were released in april 2018 to the
community and then since then he has
been able to expand his work beautifully
and you know he now has access to a lot
of uh you know european and you know
american seed banks as well who sell his
uh you know seats so that's fantastic in
the way that things have evolved in the
past few years for everyone
so this is basically the small team that
we have i mean i'm sure there are a lot
of people from america that i want to
name but if i start naming them i mean
you know we would need like for five
more hours to complete that but i'm just
gonna speak about like maybe two or
three people who have played um
important role
uh of course uh you know i've
been motivated a lot by mr body you know
because he even came to india you know
for the fair for the kum mela and you
know we hung out together for a couple
of days i mean he's just amazing guy
uh you know tells you all these crazy
stories from south america about dmt and
all that
so it was it was really cool and you
know he gave me so many seeds i mean uh
right now i'm working with some of the
varieties
uh some of the varieties that i could
not get like pakistani chitral question
you know the kandahar black
so he got it to me and they're like
amazingly inbred as well so like most of
the work is done
so yeah he's been a great help and then
you know i have another friend i don't
know if you know him he's known as
biovortex jesse dodd
yeah yeah yeah i met jesse
yeah he's he's probably one of my best
friends from america i mean he's he's
one of the best guys he's had me so much
i mean you know we're almost speaking on
a weekly basis and we're doing this
conference and we're discussing you know
sometimes that i'm writing you know some
of these articles and papers i have to
share with him and you know
so that he can do some you know critique
on that
so uh it's really great i mean because
see
the most needed thing here is the
motivation
the only thing you need to make sure
that people keep doing what they're
doing
is by making sure they're motivated and
you know these are the people that i'm
naming right now they're motivating me
and i have another friend
his name is he's by dr grinsky i think
on the
instagram that's how he pronounces it
and you know he helps me a lot for like
sending money to country like pakistan
and afghanistan because see we can't
send money to pakistan because we have a
very difficult relationship with them
okay politically and i'm sure you know
that like everybody knows that so
sending money there is like if you want
to get arrested you do that
so i have to yeah i have to route that
money through them and just imagine it
you can't find people in america who's
going to risk their ass you know and
send money to pakistan because it's just
pretty similar for them as well right
and i'm not trying to say that someone
is bad or you know some country is bad
or good by that i'm just saying how
things politically are right now okay
so
he helps me he went he goes out of his
way and he makes sure that he's sending
big amounts of money to pakistan which
is perhaps risky even for him to do that
but he does that because he want to make
sure that this
thing is you know done the whole circle
is completed and he also was receiving
seats for me because if i try to get
seats from pakistan they get busted so i
have to get them to america and then i
have to get it i have to get those seats
from america to india
so
i mean he's been helping me and he's
yeah he's a busy guy i mean you know
it's not like he's not a busy person
he's a very busy person he has several
projects of his own and you know so much
work but he makes sure that he takes out
some time so like i said the
preservation or the helping doesn't
necessarily needs to come in the form of
you buying seed or you're growing them
it can be so many things that you could
enable other people to do or put them in
a situation where they could do more for
themselves and ultimately you know
contribute to the larger community
and these are people and one more person
i want to name is would be i don't know
his name might never ask to
i think he's mass medical strain so i
don't know his real name but he's a
fantastic guy you know absolutely
amazing we have lovely conversations
around the plant very spiritual kind of
conversations and very philosophical as
well and you know we agreed that uh i
had a plant you know
uh uh you know that i feel was really
special and you know i didn't have
enough seeds to release to everyone
because then some people really get
angry because there are very few seats
and i can't get them to everyone so what
i did was i uh just reproduced like a
bunch of seeds about like 150 and then i
gave the f1 seeds to you know mass
medical and i told him like hey you know
you could grow them and you're going to
find like the sativa ones and like the
indigo ones like the you know tall ones
and the short ones as
you want to classify them
and you can either segregate them into
different your tangents and breathe them
separately or you could just amalgamate
everything and just make a very
homogeneous mix of everything and you
know just distribute it to people and
put it into people's hand and you know
he's
uh he's a great grower and you know he
makes uh you know a lot of seats
available to a lot of people through a
lot of you know american seed bank and
menus
so i thought i should give it over to
him and he would be the more responsible
and better person to work with it
and you know he's doing it and he's
again that's just another unique way how
you know he's contributing to the big
effort i'm really thankful there are
some people who are helping me in the
library project as well there are some
people from aficionado estate
uh and
i can't remember the name
she's she's a woman and you know she's
helping tori gates
and she's he's helping me a lot with the
library project as well we are going to
make
a cannabis library in himalayas
in where in my hometown and you know
we're going to put together a lot of
agriculture related books and cannabis
related books and she's been helping me
collect all these book donations and you
know
uh
just helping overall with the morale and
motivation you know so
yeah lots of help and like i said
there's so many other people i want to
talk about but you know it's just not
practical to do that but these are the
people i can think of
really who are involved in the movement
movement with us in a larger way and are
making a difference
yeah what a really comprehensive answer
and i mean you brought up a favorite of
the show body everyone loves bodhi
that's a bit of a common sentiment um
and yeah you know it's so funny you
mentioned that i was only talking to
mass medical strains just yesterday
about just general stuff and he brought
up that collab you were doing and so i
wanted to know
what can you tell me about the swabi
line you sent him it looks really cool
and do you hope to do more collabs going
forward
um yes swabi line is a really special
one and for a few different reasons
so uh if i talk about my father's side
of the family
they were not necessarily
from india in 1947
india and pakistan became two different
countries
and at that point in time my my father's
family you know they moved from pakistan
and they used to live in swabi they
moved to rajasthan and then from
rajasthan they moved to uttarakhand
where they found the you know
environment was pretty much similar to
where they had come from and they kind
of
settled there
and after a couple of generations you
know everybody was speaking the language
and they had completely you know become
a part of the larger you know gerwali or
the uttarakhand culture that there is
so
i was able to make a friend in 2000 i
think it was around end of 2016
in pakistan and you know he sent me some
seats from swabi and that was really
special for me i kept those seeds in
refrigerator for a very long time
and in 2019
i brought them outside when i had the
resource and i was sure that if i grow
them i can you know like make sure that
you know i flower them and i make the
seeds and do everything that is required
to reproduce and preserve it so i grew
few of those and what i did basically
was
i excluded all the longer flowering you
know females which were present in the
population and i just only selected the
ones which are flowering faster and had
copious resin production
i used two different meals one male had
an amazing vigor
the other male didn't have great vigor
but it had visible uh you know
trichomes on it
so
i mean that was a plus so i wanted to
use it and see if that really translates
into something else but it surely does
because
uh when i grew the f1s here uh last uh
last year and i saw that you know most
of the f1 that came up they were just
way more resonance than what i had
originally selected that population out
of
so uh for that reason it's a very
interesting population but now
the question is why there are some short
flowering and why there are some longer
flowering varieties within that one
population especially if it is
domesticated in place like pakistan well
the answer is that swabi is a place
which is like really the edge of
khyber pakhtunkhwa near like mardan in
punjab so while you're just
it's sort of a place while you're like
getting down from the mountains
and you know you're going towards more
hotter more temperate climates uh which
are also flatland territories okay
so
you have the wilder varieties which are
growing out there are pretty much
similar to the indian varieties which
are thin leaved and you know they flower
like 14-15 weeks and you know they
seem to have a very unpredictable way of
producing thc cbd or whatever
so
uh what people did in swabi was just
like everyone else in pakistan you know
they got their seeds from afghanistan or
some place like pakistan where they can
get the seeds uh which you know grow
plants that flower very short and you
know have all those desirable effects
that we know of
from the short flowering varieties but
the problem was what they did not
account for was once again the wilder
population growing around it and because
there's no one stopping that they keep
interacting with with each other
however if you see
on an overall basis the flowering still
remains short and you know
the resin production is pretty much
there because uh because you know the
domesticated population after all is
being taken care of even though it is
getting pollinated uh
with the one
which is wild and of course the wild
variety
is the farthest thing from a true
breeding variety while you're
domesticated one isn't either
attributing
variety exactly but it still is a little
more homogeneous than the other ones so
it tends to dominate overall but you
still see a lot of i mean you know
longer flowering plants not to the
extent that 14 15 weeks but yeah about
like 11 12 weeks you see them and you
see they have a significantly more
stretch
and as a matter of fact i would say even
the ones that you would consider uh you
know short flowering or indigo away
even they have significantly more
stretch compared to a pure guy variety
or a pure variety brought from a place
like uzbekistan
so a lot of diversity going in there and
the smells are just amazing because
you'll be getting a lot of spices i mean
that's the thing about pakistan a lot of
varieties that come from pakistan have
this spicy
flavor and it's just delectable i mean
you just fall in love with it absolutely
so the spice is gonna be there in an
overwhelming fashion and it's gonna be
coupled with like raw mango and even
mass medical told me that you know he
was getting some rubbery tones and
something like onion
um so well that really let's see you
know how it really develops and you know
because he's really growing and growing
them out big and
yeah we'll really see and i'm
really excited to
see how they test and what kind of
phytochemical composition comes up
you know number wise
if there's some cbd present or even some
other rare you know cannabinoids present
in that plant so that all remains to be
seen but uh so far the developments are
good and
mass medical has
also gone ahead and you know taken the
opportunity to pollinate
uh some of his you know stable varieties
with swabi and you know eventually work
on those lines and see if he can release
some of them
so it's gonna be it's gonna be great for
people well i'm always open for you know
collaboration
uh but like i said you know there's this
big factor human factor you know that we
have to be careful about so we have to
be careful you know who we're working
with and that our intentions are in tune
and then we both have the same goal in
mind and not that you know one person is
thinking something and the other person
is thinking something else
there are so many varieties that i have
you know which i cannot release because
that's not uh you know good numbers but
eventually i'll find people you know
good people who will uh who would be
responsible enough to take them and
reproduce preserve and then distribute
them uh to the community so that
everybody can enjoy them
yeah that's that's really exciting and i
think likewise we're gonna wait and
see all the awesome stuff to come from
that collab i'm interested to know do
you have a certain type of breeding
style you like and by that i mean do you
like to cross different land races
together do you prefer to just reproduce
them and just kind of hunt within the
one line what's your preferred kind of
way of doing it
well because see i mean i'm not a
trained leader or i mean because i've
been only doing it for a few years but i
mean i've had a background in science
and you know i also studied uh you know
cognitive psychology i mean i have a
master's degree in that so we've done a
lot of you know you know research and we
understand how the recent methodology
you know works so that pretty much
remains the same wherever you go even
though you know plant breeding is quite
a different thing when you compare it to
uh you know other things like psychology
but uh if you are curious and you
understand
you know how to perform experiments to
reach and at different conclusions how
to form hypotheses and you know how to
prove and disprove them yourself
is eventually going to help the help you
uh you know get at positions where you
know more than
uh you know somebody who's just looking
at the plant in a much simplistic manner
now
uh there are a few different things that
i like to do uh first of all i'm a
really fan of like pedigree breeding but
that's more for like the monuis
varieties you know which has male and
female on the same plant so it pertains
more to that because you could
self-pollinate those
in a way you know
which is not really conducive for
varieties like cannabis i mean to say so
even in cannabis you could do that so
basically what that means is you're
going to trace the pedigree so all the
characteristics that you see in a hybrid
okay let me just start over i mean if
you have
uh let's say two plants that you cross
together you have two land races let's
say i have kandahar black and i have pck
and i cross them
so what is going to happen is that uh
i'm gonna see the progeny and the
progeny will have a few different things
okay
what's what it's going to have is some
of the progeny is going to look like the
male some of them going to look like
female and some of them will have a
co-dominant expression which will be an
amalgamation of both of the parents in
varying manners
but when you're working
with varieties which are highly inbred
which have been homogenized
uh for certain traits like i'm going to
talk about pakistani chitral krishna
pakistani chitrakesh has
is so in bread i mean that it's so
homogenous for that trait or i mean the
way it grows and everything that no
matter what you cross it with it's
completely takes it over
it is it just knocks off the other you
know alleles and just
just takes over completely and
i don't know about the kandara black but
i grew only about like five to seven
plants and i could see
that almost every plant was identical in
the way they would acquire you know
colors and you know way they would
uh you know grow in a lot of things so
that made me understand i mean again
this is also a very
inbred variety and pretty homogeneous
for the trade black leaf if not anything
else
so i just thought you know you just
cross these two varieties and the
predictability is going to be really
high so for someone who's working in
small spaces like me i mean i don't have
like [__] farms here like i'm growing
plants at but i have enough space to you
know do my breeding work in a meticulous
and in an honest manner
so
i have to readily choose plants or the
parents
uh when i will be able to greatly
predict the outcome because i don't have
really have the space to see what's
happening every time by growing 200
plants
so
when i run into varieties like hindu
kush let's just say when i was growing
hindukush and the first thing that i saw
was again there are these three
different you know expressions there the
first is a narrow leaf that corresponds
to the primordial state of that plant
because they were all narrow leaf before
they got domesticated and everything
and then you have the domesticated
variety which is of course of course the
broadleaf variety you know the perfect
structure and everything that we
recognize as the cannabis plant and then
there is intermediate variety which is
just between both of them it has
you know certain features from both of
those varieties in varying manners
so as soon as i saw that i will i
thought if i'm if i want the narrow leaf
trade to carry on into my projects then
i can't just take this very plant and
you know start you know crossing it to
everything else because this is a part
of a very uh you know
uh
a very
heterogeneous you know population i mean
it's just not something you know which
is consistent it's not dominant in the
population if it were dominant then i
would see it pop up a lot more often
like the broad leaf
so
then the only option you have then it's
not really a matter of what you like to
do the only option you have is to take
that plant you know and find another
plant you know its counterpart which is
as closely related to it physically in
other aspects smell and all as you can
and then you start in breeding them
selectively and you do that until you
reach a
you know situation where
almost every plant comes out like that
it happens in four generation five
generation who knows depends on the
variety depends on you know how well
you're selecting it
and a lot of the things so once you do
get to that point then you have once
again reached the situation of that pck
into gandhar kind of a situation because
now you have a hindu variety that is
going to act as a true breeding variety
because it has been you know how much
noise for all of those traits in it over
generations by selectively including it
with closely related individuals
now if i take that hindu question i
cross it with something else
then i can be sure that these traits
will show up in a overwhelming
proportion and at least in the f1
generation and then the selection work
is going to be you know really easy or
you could just you know cross pollinate
the f1 generation get to the f2 you know
and then select from an even more
diverse population but then again there
is no fixed rule there are no rights and
wrongs you can cross land races to land
races you can cross land raise to
hybrids you can do whatever you want
right you will end up making seeds some
plants will come out of those seeds
but if you
want to work in a way you know that is
predictable and
that
kind of creates like a feedback loop
that your own work has to give you
certain feedback that what you were
expecting yes you're able to see that
like for example again if the kandahar
black and pck
cross does not show in f1 population you
know what i'm expecting to see then that
tells me that something went wrong in
the parental generation then i can go
back and you know i can figure it out
what it is although i'm pretty sure
that's not going to happen
but uh what i'm trying to say here is
that it really depends on where you're
trying to reach so if you want to reach
somewhere
where you want to be confident in giving
out your seeds and letting people know
what they would be like then well that's
the way of working that you have to
either find true breeding varieties or
you have to find varieties and you know
make them breed true for you know traits
by reading them and just a lot of work i
know but
you know
it has to be done and i understand i
mean the market situation is completely
different for people in u.s and europe
because they're constantly you know
competing with so many other people and
you know
so the actions are pretty much
predicated by you know
uh what's market what market is doing
what what's good in the market more than
what they want to do
and it's kind of sad at the same time
but you know people have to put food on
their table so i mean i'm not going to
go ahead and blame someone for like
uh not doing the work that way should be
done but at the same time there are
there are no rights or wrongs i mean
you do what you you can do and then you
try to reach at a place where people can
appreciate it
yeah of course understandably people
have got to provide for themselves and
their family
just to
kind of
tie up two little things i was wondering
about your breeding process do you given
what you just said do you tend to like
to select just one male to pollinate
females or do you like to use a few and
then as a follow-up do you keep any
cuttings at all either male or female
i i like to select a few males uh always
i mean at least uh three four or five
depending on the population as well if
i mean it again it really depends what
you're trying to do so let's let's say
if i'm working with lola valley that i
and my friend archive serpent were
so we saw there is a staggering amount
of variability present within the larger
population so we had no option but we
had to select five different males
they looked completely different and
then we had to narrow it down to one
which took around like three months or
just stressing those males and just
trying to see if there's any you know
latent intersex
trade that might pop up later
so all of those things so it really
depends what i'm trying to do but if i'm
working with let's say pck
then i don't really need to have like 20
different males really i mean
it it
it doesn't really make a lot of sense
but i'm sure you could uh you know
increase the probability of your results
in in a better way if you have more
males and i do understand that but
uh
i think a more
i i think a more uh i should say
uh
a more in tune way with your process or
i would say a way that would you know
take you towards your goal has to be
taken by people rather than what would
appeal to people as you're doing good
because i see that some people would go
and do things because they feel that you
know this would uh drive people's
opinion in us uh you know
in a certain way and it would make them
feel that i'm doing the right things
but i think you always and always have
to choose
over
uh you know you have to choose what you
want to do over
what would drive other people's you know
uh opinions and then you could
i mean it's very hard to explain in
words for me i mean english not being my
first language i guess
but um what i'm trying to say here is
this that
uh you know that the breed
the male selections
i mean
it's difficult i mean you know because
most people you know who are growing
like selecting 20 males they never tell
you like what they're selecting for and
how they're selecting
because i see some people say that you
know if your male you know drops the
pollen late and that's a good male or
you have to find a male that has a big
cluster on it
all valid and you know they make sense
you know all of them but
uh i don't see people like you know
when they're working with the population
that taking notes of the females you
know the females you like if let's say
you like four females you know in a
population then you have to take notes
from the beginning that what is the you
know difference between their internodes
you know their life
their leaf surface area and all of those
things and then you will be finding
males that's exact thing is going to
help you that data is going to help you
determine which are those males which
will be perfect which will be synonymous
to the females that you have selected
instead of just relying on something
like a bigger you know cluster on the
male or you know it has a dance stem rub
or something of that sort which is great
i mean you should do that
but i mean if you're maintaining data
from your female selections then you can
just take that physical data apply it to
the male and see which males have that
exact structure in every all those
traits and you know these plants are the
closest to the females you've selected
and you could do that so i think
more than in numbers
uh it is about how to select the male
then
that that is more important because you
could have 10 000 males and yet not have
a clue how to select the right one
yeah very astute point to make and i
mean you know while we only just talked
about bodhi just a minute ago i want to
use him as a good little segue into my
next question which is when you kind of
travel around and you go and visit
different places do you predominantly
trek between them or and is that like a
style of travel that you enjoy because i
just i just remember boat he's so fond
of it
yeah we have to track i mean most of
these places are not accessible by um
by roads
so uh
most of the places you have to track so
himachal pradesh is fairly easy because
um you get if you want to go to the
malana you get to uh to the last point
with your car and then it's only about
two kilometers to the village
and two kilometers to
you know waichin valley and about
another kilometer to magic valley
uh whaling valley is a little farther
it's about like eight to nine kilometers
and
everybody's not even welcome there so i
mean like most people don't go but apart
from that i mean it's pretty much easy
but you go to places like uttarakhan or
you know northern kashmir then there's a
whole lot more you know walking involved
because the roads are just not paved
those places are not getting the kind of
revenue and tourism
pradesh is getting and
you know
the development is uh i mean pretty much
uh you know in sync with that i mean as
much the revenue the state's going to
have i mean they will only be able to
spend that
and sometimes not even that so kashmir
and uttarakhand it's going to be really
taxing i mean if you're not the kind of
person who likes to walk then you're
going to have a very hard time and
because of the altitude i mean it's
really difficult and you know i have
met some people who
come from like america i mean i had this
guy in 2018 he's a good friend of mine
and uh he came from america and we took
him to you know uttarakhand and you know
i took him to kashmir and i took him to
you know
uh
pradesh as well in malana and you know
you had a great time but
again it got really taxing and tiring
for that person because you know he was
just not
you know used to walking a lot
on a daily basis so
and another thing is when you're doing
this you have a very short window like
you have to spin too of 15 september to
sort of like 30th october because most
of the harvest is gonna happen between
that and you have to make it out to all
of these places
at least to the three himalayan states
and have to be present there you know
while it's going down so it's it's
important to you know plan very
meticulously how you're going to go
about your
you know
hunts every year so every year we make a
calendar at least four months prior at
least five months prior and we know that
you know what places we're going to go
to this year and what exactly are we
going to cover and uh you know if you're
going to make some kind of video like we
did one in kashmir you know we covered
how they make cash traditionally by
cooking it so we we write a storyboard
for that and we make sure that you know
we know exactly what to do at that point
in time because it's all happening live
and if you miss it then you miss it so
you just have to be prepared and the
presence of mind is of the essence uh
while conducting this kind of work
but
hiking and walking is is basically a
very integral part as well and if you're
not up for that are you probably going
to have a very hard time
understandable of course and
when i think back to bodhi talking about
the trekking he often speaks about it as
though there's like a spiritual aspect
to it and a lot of the cannabis and
hashish you sample along the way is
really special
is that kind of the way you think about
it or is it more just like a means to an
end to get the seeds for you
no absolutely there is a deep spiritual
aspect uh attached to it and i just want
to be clear and this has nothing to do
with the religion or the god here when
we when i'm saying spirituality i i just
mean to say a higher understanding and
higher awareness
of you and your surroundings and i think
there are two very important things that
happen when you go out on these tracks
especially if you're alone
first is that
you are in a serene environment that is
very hard to come by and you know a
chaotic life in in places like india
so now you are actually physically in a
place or in a situation where you can
reflect back to things in your life
reflect back to
things that you see in nature and you
can connect with them because there's
nobody around you to you know judge you
or to call you crazy or any of that
sort of thing that we you know we seem
to be really worried and preoccupied
about
and the other aspect of it is the
awareness of the surrounding i mean
without going out in the nature and you
could call it data collection in a way
in a very crude manner and you could
also call it increasing the awareness of
your surroundings so both are correct
and
you know that can only happen when
you're venturing to these places where
there are no roads because see if there
is a road somewhere let's understand
this that place has already been
ventured and you can probably find that
information somewhere on google
right
but if you go to places where you don't
have a road and you're hiking into these
mountains to these valleys
well surely enough you're going to run
into places and you're going to run into
cultures and people and resin and you
know alcohols and honey and you know
sometimes they make you know butter
from indigenous milk and all that and
all of those experiences you know you
will always be devoid of that if you are
not attempting to go there
so if some person especially somebody
who lives in america or lives in a
country where you know these kind of
experiences are scarce to come by
and they do make a journey like that
i mean what possibility do you think
there is that
it does not have a spiritual deep
spiritual impact on that person i mean
you you basically have to be like you
know a non-human entity you mean not to
be moved
by the beauty of the nature that is
present in himalayas i'm not sure if
you've been here but it's absolutely
breathtaking i mean i've only lived all
my life here and every time i go
i'm just dumb stuck you know looking at
the nature around me so like you said i
mean you know bodhi really i mean you
know puts it in a very local manner that
i might not be able to put it across in
that way but
the gist of the story is
he he's just as interested in hiking and
in the journey as much as he's
interested in getting to the destination
and then doing the thing
which is incredible and that is the
attitude that we need to have
and not because that it's something
spiritual at the same time this is the
same thing that is going to help you
with your data collection if you're
aware and sensitive all the time if
you're receptive of your surroundings
when you're and you're hiking you're not
going by a motor car or by a bus you
know you're walking slowly and you're
taking information as our senses are
evolved to you know at medium speeds at
medium
uh sizes then we will be taking a lot
more in we will be imbibing all this in
raw data from nature
and because there are no roads so we
might be getting in you know more
or newer information
which you could then process in your own
way use your intelligence what you make
of it and present it to the community
you know who
uh
are not geographically blessed enough to
be in those places so frequently and you
know that's really what
what it's all about so i think he puts
it in a very beautifully and a very sim
sim puts it very simply but there's a
deep deep meaning to that i think
yeah most certainly and i mean bodhi
actually gave me two questions to ask
you so we may as well roll into him
saying as we're here and he wants to
know first off what's the most
psychoactive indian heirloom strain
you've been able to try
okay the most uh
so
most i mean this is this is a this is a
tricky question but i'm going to say
manipuri the one that comes from
northeast of india manipur and
especially the one that
we recently got from uh eastern manipur
burma border
and i i don't understand the reasons why
because you know again the domestication
is pretty much you know
uh of the same standard as it is in rest
of the north india but the varieties
that seem to come from
these
places northeast of india
seem to have a really uh you know
intense high if
if not more and i have a little theory
and this might be wrong but i'll just
tell you what i think about this what i
think about this is
uh the eastern part of india is where uh
which is like quite close to the equator
near south and the east part the
southeast part where orissa is and
andhra is
and those places are very close to
northeast india and northeast india is
also close to the
northwestern you know himalayan regions
so it in a way is a sandwich between
these two places so it's
i mean it could be that you know people
from you know different places like east
and north
went out there migrated and they may
have contributed somehow you know
in what makes up the natural population
out there today
but we also understand this as a matter
of fact that you know the mao tribes uh
you know of
you know the the tank holes and they
have descended uh from the burmese
people
and specifically the burmese people
of uh the tibetan descent tibetan
chinese descent so that's the migration
pattern that has
uh
that has been traced and they have been
able to trace it because of the language
because the way
uh you know the languages they speak and
these are different dialects so they can
understand that this dialect evolved
properly from this one so that really
paints the picture of the migration for
northeast of india so those people have
come through the ways of china so i
don't know if they bring varieties from
china or tibet along with them and then
it gets mixed along with the general
population which is just entirely
different because
of being in a very wet tropical like
climate but it it seemed to have an
amazing an unparalleled high at least if
you uh you know compare it to any other
variety in india
and kashmiris can be quite strong but um
they're not psychoactive in a way i mean
i wouldn't call them like they don't
have that psychedelic kind of
uh edge to them and they're more like a
they're different kind of high i mean
which which could more be associated to
like broad leaf plants
but yeah northeast india varieties
manipur eastern manipur burman
specifically i think would be the most
or the best in terms of high
yeah a really solid answer and so the
second question he asked was
do you think that the high elevation
himalayan cannabis
differ in effect from the tropical more
sea level specimens
and
do you think that it's because of maybe
the uv that it creates a little
something special and the reason why he
asked is because he said he knows of
some barbers
who just want to try to find cannabis
from like the highest elevation possible
okay
um i i think we did bring this up in
conversation somewhere previously that
you know about the uv radiation when i
was speaking about the highland
varieties which also grow in the high
lot high latitude regions so they seem
to be getting a lot more exposure of you
know uv rays than any other place
in the world
so
[Music]
is that
is that something that makes the plant
behave in a different way
phytochemically i mean i i can't say yes
or no to that because i don't have any
tests to you know fall back on or any
kind of study
but what i can tell you for sure is that
the varieties that tend to grow at
higher altitudes or you know high
latitudes especially
they seem to uh you know they seem to
produce like we said before
and in a competitively dense coverage of
resin
and you know the resin gland gland
glands seem to be bigger and you know it
just seems to be more potent in the way
you know overall in the way they uh make
you feel and and this would you know
encompass india in the way and i'm
talking that when i say highland high
latitude that would include everything
from central to southeast asia but
in india itself as well if you go to
places like northern kashmir you know
it's at 34 degrees north and then you
have altitude of like 3000 plus meters
just more than ten thousand feet
and you definitely see that there are
certain plants
uh there
you know which are just insane to simply
say the least so i think because those
babas that bodhis
is referring to they have been to all of
these places because these babas are
just about getting you know getting to
all the places to highs of the mountains
to the
lowest of the cities you know so so they
they know they know the higher up the
out there is
are the plant populations which seem to
have you know
bigger trichomes and you know larger
density of trichome so if you're rubbing
the plants you can probably get the same
thing done within
10 minutes instead of doing it an hour
if you're working with those varieties
if you're working with varieties in low
land in places like punjab you may have
to spend like three to four hours before
you can
get anything at all in your hands so i
think they tend to have that
understanding maybe not in a way that we
would like to think about it but uh you
know as always
indigenous cultures and uh these
primitive cultures
they knew so much because they didn't
have these distractions of you know all
the societies and the markets and these
phones and laptops and whatnot so they
could rely they used to rely on their
natal their innate senses so much more
often than we do
i mean you know we were just not able to
you know
think in in those ways so i think it's
always a great idea to take advice from
your elders and especially those elders
happens to be some uh you know chilean
smoking baba i mean
you know
uh yeah and you know bodhi knows i mean
what's up i mean he's been here uh you
know so many times in india so he pretty
much understands india very well because
when he was here
i mean
you know he's not asking me that you
know how to get around so he pretty much
knows everywhere and in fact when i was
in the mela he was able to show me some
of the
things um you know that i would would
have missed i think
wow yeah i mean what a testament to the
guy so just to kind of wrap up this
section on kind of the little trekking
stuff what's one of the most memorable
smokes you've had while doing the
trekking around and as a follow-up do
you have any kind of crazy stories from
while you're tracking
yeah i'm just gonna answer that all in
one and this has happened now last year
so uh last year around the month of uh
end of july or beginning of august
um india
made a huge change in the way you know
the things are in jammu and kashmir we
kind of took hold of kashmir entirely
our government i'm not gonna go into
whether that's right or wrong i mean
that's their thing
so there was a lot of tension there a
lot of people it was locked up for the
longest time and i was there before that
happened so it was like really hard for
me to get out but i got out somehow on
the 6th of the august and i was home
and i was really you know thankful i was
able to come back but see what happens
is uh three months down the line things
got a little eased up on 10th of october
they said okay we're going to open it
for the tourists once again so you guys
can come
and nobody's going to be i mean of
course nobody wants to die
and my friend is like hey so you guys
are like coming over or what and i said
you know i want to come but i'm in the
situation i mean aren't you watching the
news and everything and he's like these
news guys are crazy man there's nothing
happening here just come over they
officially open for the tourism should
be okay i got the flight i went there we
did the srinagar thing it was fantastic
smooth sailing we went to dachigan
national park smooth sailing got all the
samples pictures everything
then we moved to northern kashmir and uh
i'm really happy i'm going to the lola
valley and i'm going to go to those
spots where you know my friend got the
seats last year and i will get to see
those in person
as well now you have to uh first of all
let me put things in perspective a
little bit lola valley is just like
three to four hills away from pakistan
okay and not only that it's at the
border that's a de facto water what that
means is that there is no actual border
it's just assumed that there is
somewhere a border in between and you
just don't cross so
very often what happens is that you
wouldn't realize and you would just
cross over and
well that would be you know a very bad
story to tell in the end if you survived
too
but
we were there and you know we were
rubbing hash we were actually 12 people
because we had an entire team from lola
i had like seven guys from srinagar and
some from the lab locals and we were
there we were rubbing hash
and you know i was collecting samples i
made several videos and even posted that
then we were almost done and we were
coming down
the there's an indian army post there
all right so they were uh they were wire
i mean somebody did a wireless to them
that there are like about 10 to 12
people they can see on the top of the
hill and they're like coming down and as
we were descending down in the first
meadow that came there were these two
guys from sog that is special operation
group and let me tell you something
about special operation group i mean
they're just asked to shoot people if
they think that they should be shot and
no questions asked
so they had their guns and you know they
they made us sit there
and you know they everybody just went
around telling them that how they are
just from you know this local place and
even the guys from srinagar had some
relatives living in this place so they
were like almost all off the hook i mean
it was natural for them okay so you guys
are not coming from the pakistan or you
know something fishy
then when they got to me and they asked
me where i'm from and i told them that
i've come from punjab and these guys
were absolutely they just absolutely
lost their mind they were like
oh man like are you not watching the
news or like do you not live in this
world of what like
you
first of all you don't come to kashmir
in time like this and if you do come to
kashmir you stick to the lake or to the
srinagar to the southern part you don't
freaking come to the northern kashmir
and even if you come to northern kashmir
and this is exactly how he said i mean
not in english but
even if you come to northern kashmir
then you don't climb up the mountain and
you don't
uh try to you know get close to the
border region and like how dare you and
he's like that i've been here for 10
years
you know serving an army within just the
kashmir and i've never got my family
here to show them around i've never had
the courage to got my family here to
show them around and look at you like
what are you even doing here
and then we just kind of told him like
what exactly i was doing there and you
know i had to tell him because you know
i wasn't doing something that i wasn't
proud of
and the good thing there is like they're
not the kind of they're not like police
so they're not worried about hash or
feed that's like
none of their concern their only concern
is the security that
who are you where are you coming from
and why are you here when you're not
supposed to be on top of these mountains
so that thing went on for about
i don't know two two and a half hours
and you know they scared uh the [__] out
of me you know
but i think at some point i had like
kind of understood that they will
eventually let me go because most of the
guys that we were there with not only
that they were local but their fathers
are in army you know in certain
different regiments so
that helps them you know build on the
confidence that okay these people are
not you know anti-social elements or
someone who's here to do something bad
they're just young guys who want to
smoke and
uh you know that was one incident i mean
one hell of an incident i mean you
you're just sitting there and they took
our pictures they took our ids and they
had this machine where they could scan
our ids and they figure out you know
they could
check that number with the
data government database whether or not
these are like fake or these are like
the real ids so they did everything that
they could and they took our phone
numbers our addresses and it was only
after that that they let us go the first
thing i got down at the lola valley
floor i got into the car with my friend
and we left and we only stopped at i
mean srinagar not before that's about
120 30 kilometers
uh although there were a lot of
stoppages in between so this is like a
very usual thing for kashmir that you
travel like 10 kilometers then you stop
for the army and then just happens like
that everywhere but that was that would
be one incident that i'm never going to
forget and definitely something to be
spoken about
yeah well i think i would have been in
the same boat as you quite worried
so i'm only just in this moment
realizing that i haven't asked you at
all
do you in general tend to prefer like
more kind of uplifting highs or more
kind of sedating
i i like i i like more sedative eyes
uh something you know that helps you
relax because
uh i don't smoke much during the daytime
i i usually you know begin my morning
and then i try to refrain from smoking
till you know six or seven in the
evening
and then i just gradually you know
start hitting some bongs but
when i really feel an urge
where i really feel a nourish to smoke
is when i'm you know going to sleep
because i have some you know issues
relating sleep
and
uh you know so so i'm always just
looking for varieties you know that can
you know help me accomplish or help me
you know
just mitigate those uh issues that i
have
around the sleep so i'm always inclined
towards finding varieties which are more
sedative in nature and you know would
make you
feel sleepy
uh which is also one of the reasons why
i
tend to you know get
some of my resin or cherries in bulk and
you know try to cure it for the longer
durations because then even if you know
the plants naturally are not
or plant predominantly do not produce
you know a narcotic effect we can
actually cure the hash in a way and you
know get it to a point where it would
induce that sort of sleepy effect
yeah i think i can certainly relate to
many aspects of that answer something i
wanted to ask you a little about a
little bit about was
kind of the general smoking culture in
india and i guess specifically
is tobacco normally mixed with cannabis
and as a follow-up are there other
things besides tobacco whichever get
mixed with cannabis and smoked
yeah so tobacco is big big big in india
i mean there is no uh you know hash
smoking or even wheat smoking in india
without tobacco
so
yeah i mean everybody spoke tobacco it's
not a matter of who or where i mean you
could go to himachal pradesh you could
go to kashmir and
sure the brand of the cigarette is going
to change or the brand of the tobacco is
going to change but they all want
tobacco i mean it's it's the bread you
know that we are going to spread the
jelly on basically
so
uh yeah tobacco is a very integral part
of our smoking culture everywhere but
there are few other things that actually
get mixed along with it and opium would
be you know one of the things
that do because we have a lot of
ayurvedic
[Music]
opium you know preparations here in
india
so just to be sure not to confuse this
with heroin in any way i mean opium
preparations as in like uh they're
ayurvedic they're mixed with some spices
and then it becomes a medicine actually
and it's
it's really beneficial so
we have uh those getting mixed a lot
with uh you know cannabis often but then
again the can uh the tobacco has to be
there i mean you know without tobacco
you just cannot imagine i mean at least
i can ottoman
so if i smoke without tobacco and i've
tried you know because sometimes some
people would give me that what do you
call that dab
and it just feels incomplete you know
if you're not smoking with tobacco and i
understand the underlying reason for
that i mean you know part of that is
that you
eventually get addicted to the you know
substances in
tobacco
but i mean if we were just to talk about
the experience and the very typical
indian experience of smoking then it
just can not be imagined without tobacco
in any any place no matter where you go
in india
yeah that's that's understandable and
i'd certainly heard that so
how do people tend to smoke do they use
chilums do they use bongs so they use
joints what would you say is the most
common
usually people begin with cigarettes and
when they empty cigarettes and then fill
them back up
you know with the mix and then usually
people graduate to smoking in joints
that is they start buying you know
rolling paper
and
as people uh you know tend to grow a
little more older and i'm of course not
talking about everyone but i'm just
going to talk about the typical smoker
uh you know middle class like a working
class kind of a society that works in
the ideos and relate software related
jobs so those people then after a while
they tend to lean more to gravitate more
towards bond smoking because it's just
more convenient and it's not that time
consuming you know you could just smoke
get a good high and get on with your
curriculum so
i think that
contributes a lot uh in people you know
gravitating more towards smoking in
bongs
the chilum
is more like a
it's more like a pseudo connoisseur uh
environment in india
related to chileam so while you have a
lot of people you know who smoke in
chilam and they have very expensive
children as well
but
um more than often and i'm not talking
about everyone of course more than often
i see people they are using us smoking a
childhood only because they would want
the other person to see that they're
smoking into them and you know that
that is supposed to you know give you a
high ground in their opinion i mean
amongst other smokers i don't
necessarily feel that way but i can
certainly see that you know
you know in people
so
while i mean uh you know
uh chilling smoking is morally
culturally confined within the babas
but the new generation that smokes in
chilemi i think they smoke arachila more
that has to do more with
um either
you know
either trying to you know experience
if what baba's experience in a way you
know
or just to uh
be in a place where you have a
you know
moral high ground or just a high ground
over everyone that you smoke in chile
man other people smoking bomb
it's it's weird but that's how it is i
mean this is a thing in india basically
so if you have like an italian chilem
you know that costs like 200
and you're smoking in it so you
automatically become a connoisseur i
mean you may not know anything about
cannabis but if you have a chillum then
whoa man
yeah look out for this guy and you know
if
i'm just smoking uh a joint then you
know i'm i'm
then you're just like everybody else
so
immediately children will give you a
status hike amongst the smokers in the
circle
but
does it does it have an intrinsic you
know property to it uh
then i mean i'm not really able to see
that to an extent that i can explain it
and i don't much prefer to smoke into
them a lot but when i go to himachal
pradesh they have some absolutely lovely
chilums
and i indulge in that fully till my
throat is
you know sacrificed but yeah i enjoy it
i love that what a great answer so i
guess just as a really quick follow-up
is there that same kind of hype culture
maybe more particularly in the younger
people like what we see in america where
like you know they want to try to use it
as a status thing so it's like you know
i'm smoking cookies in my chillum look
how cool i am
yes exactly so
but there uh but in a much different way
i would say
so uh
yeah yeah okay
okay the way this works in india would
be maybe that if you go to malana like i
said if i go to malana and i'm always
like you know trying to smoke in
different chilums and i'm not really
trying to
find a joint or just bong just forget
about it
so
why why what that happens is because
when when you're at a place you know uh
where it's a common practice then then
as a human nature you know we want to
gel in we want to fit in
and we we don't want to be you know
going around the village holding a bomb
and you know look different some people
certainly like to do that
but most people would like to gel in so
uh it has that aspect to it uh the the
children smoking
and
the high ground really or or the
superiority that that is imparted by
owning a chilum or smoking in a
childhood really comes from
one that it cost a lot if it's an
original italian children everybody
knows that
and second is that
it is
it is almost
as if assumed or you know presumed that
if you have very nice children then you
must have very nice hash too which is
not necessarily correct again because
you know why
and
i mean those are just really the things
uh you know why people tend to have
chilums because of course you go in
circle there are girls as well and you
know you wanna you wanna look good right
you wanna
make sure that girls are like totally
stoked on you so
i mean there are just so many reasons
but i just don't see it for the cultural
reason so much
so among the youngsters with that said
there are certainly some
youngsters who are you know very
dedicated and they would follow all the
rituals you know pass it to the right
and you know pray before you know
smoking it they take care of everything
and i absolutely love to be with those
people sometime in smoke
but
as you move out of those circles i mean
most of the people you see are just the
rich people you know can afford to spend
a lot of money and get hold of these
things but they don't
uh actually appreciate them in a way
that you know a baba would do or another
youngster is doing who is following all
the rituals
yeah of course and i guess
understandable there's a natural kind of
distribution there
so one of the other things i noticed on
your instagram that i wanted to follow
up on which seems like it's kind of more
of a local thing is that you posted a
photo of what you said was a traditional
kashmiri corn wrapped and baked hash
please tell me a little bit more about
this i've never even heard of that
yeah so that's a really special one in
2018 first of all let's talk about i
mean how that came to be i mean like how
we were able to document it so in 2018
i invited my friend from usa to come and
you know let's go to kashmir and see if
we can come back live right so we went
there and once we were there um
the guy that was supposed to take us
around and my friend archaic serpent
they said you know what we can actually
arrange because we have material we can
arrange for making hash right now and if
you want you have mobile phones you
could like you know capture it and then
it could be made into documentaries so
when i was in college because
uh you know along with psychology i also
was part of you know mass you know mass
communication team so i know a little
bit of editing and software's like you
know final cut pro and sony vegas pro
so i thought yeah that's a great idea i
could just take that footage and i could
make it into a small you know
documentary or a short film kind of
thing and show it to other people
because
um i mean showing is always you know
better than telling so we we covered
that and
you know i myself didn't really know a
lot about it even though because i live
in i live near kashmir you know so we
often get
uh get that here i mean we we get that
kind of hash here but we never tried to
redeem and you know reconcile
what this is and why would this hash be
like this and you know there's so many
other things that could be thought of
so when i was there it was happening in
front of me and i was able to see the
entire process i was even like asking
them the things that i could not uh you
know readily understand
so what this process is it's very
interesting it's a mix of you know a few
cultural phenomena
a few techniques which are apparently
not from kashmir has been brought you
know from other countries like
afghanistan and then you have
a few things happening which are really
really local to that place
so
how people usually go about it so
this is happening mostly in srinagar in
the southern kashmir region okay so
northern kashmir they're not doing it so
much because it's really wet out there
in sudden kashmir what they do is they
don't have a farm population of cannabis
out there so
they would just go during the season and
as soon as they find a good plant they
break it they break it and they leave it
there they break it they leave it there
and they mark the plants they remember
where i broke the plants and i have to
go back to those places
after a few days uh or a few weeks they
would go back with a big polythene and
they would you know then collect all of
the material that's on those plants and
just bring it back to a place where
they're going to you know go about the
rest of the process and
the first thing that is done is they
just spread it out in the sun let it dry
let the material dry completely in case
there is some water
uh you know some moisture in it once
it's completely dried um they just
simply go about how people usually or
traditionally dry safe they take a
uh they take a cloth and you tie it over
a plastic
sort of like what do you call that
plastic sort of tub
and then they just you know see the dry
material over that
you know pile after pile and the resin
is collected
in the tub so that process is pretty
much i mean
similar to what you see in places like
afghanistan and pakistan and i'm pretty
sure this process has come from there
but the interesting part and the part
that is not seen or heard anywhere else
is what happens after that i mean they
don't actually stop there so what they
usually do is they they take that dry
seed resin and they will make it into a
ball i mean they of course just press it
into a you know ball like thing inside a
plastic and they would let it sit and
you know cure a little bit so that
those lipids and you know
cannabinoids can be you know separated
and would be easy for it to you know
process it later i mean not that they're
thinking in those ways but it's usually
what happens when you're curing it
now after a few months if you're doing
it properly then you would do it after a
few months if you're like um you know a
youngster from srinagar who's just
trying to you know make some hash they
usually do it the same day
so on that particular day they did it
the same way they took the hat and
you need uh corn wraps
you know the corn husk
and they need to be dried and they need
to be cleaned
uh before you're going to put resin
inside them so what they do is they take
the dry seed resin and they completely
you know smuff them just fill them up
and tie it very tightly you know bound
it in a way around it with a thread
then they would put a cloth over it
which is a little wet or rather wet and
then they would wound it again
uh with you know some kind of thread and
they would light a fire and they are
thrown into the fire like directly to
the fire now this fire is not being
controlled you have no idea what
temperature what temperature it is on
you have no idea what temperature your
hash is going to go up and down to
and it's just all
a matter of experience from that point
onwards i mean once you throw that uh
you know little thingy into the fire
then you just have to know when to take
it out and just beat it into a
snake-like shape
which they do later on and if you're
late then it'll be all burnt and if you
do it early then it's just gonna be a
really messed up thing which is not uh
you know properly homogenous but if you
do it just right and you let everything
just go to a lick
to a liquefied form but at the same time
you bring it out and not let those
cannabinoids and terpenes degrade to a
level that it won't even make you high
then you can do a perfect job because
once it cools down it comes out of the
fire
it is perfectly homogenized because you
break it open and you look at the layers
i mean that tells the story i mean
pretty much that how well it's done
so it's a very unique process but what i
really felt uh i mean because somebody
asked me a question that why would they
do it what would make them
uh do such a thing why could they just
not cure it like they would do in
pakistan and afghanistan would they just
like you know pack it and store it and
you know leave it for months on end
well there's a good answer for that
because you know
you are in kashmir i mean this is not
pakistan or afghanistan and uh you know
things and the culture has been so much
different and you know smoking hash is
not seen something you know particularly
good
so
these people have a pressure to not only
harvest these plants but at the same
time process them and process them fast
in a way or get get it to a form where
it does not smell a lot but it still
gets you high and it's ready to go
from the day one you make it and i i
think because the decarboxylation
process is happening you know while
you're heating it
and you're just speeding up you know
that curing process although it's very
rough and you shouldn't be doing it i
mean because
you're just gonna end up you know
burning a lot of
cannabinoids and especially terpenes but
that's the only way these people know
and when they do it actually well it
comes out beautiful and it's like
nothing else that you've ever had and as
a matter of fact when i met bodhi in
allahabad uh you know in 2019 january
i was able to bring some of the ash from
kashmir which was in the powder form
and
some hash which was then made into this
you know this cornhurst cache big dash
and then i also
got some which my friend you know
archaic serpent had pressed in the
modern ways with some heat and you know
pressure
so
yeah i mean
it's a good question you asked but um we
don't really understand i mean what
drives the whole thing why they do it
this way or not any other way but there
certainly seems to be a cultural
pressure and the way things have been
evolving in that place that they have an
urgency to process everything quickly
and just
get it to a condensed state which is
easy to hide
and everything
yeah of course makes sense you know
different historical situation they're
going to do things a bit differently so
kind of in that same vein of historical
things i noticed in one of your posts
you were talking about how sugarcane and
cannabis have a very intertwined history
and you go on to talk about how it was
kind of transported by a lot of slaves
that were a part of the european
colonialist kind of settlements would
you be able to just talk a little bit
about that that's a really interesting
point i think
yeah of course i mean uh i mean if you
look at all the varieties which are
going in west indies i mean when i say
west indies so let me just make this
clear i'm speaking of caribbean islands
so in india we usually do not say
caribbean or caribbean islands we refer
to them as west indies
or western these islands
so when you look at the west indies
islands and you know and i'm just going
to speak about those places there are so
many other places that could also share
the same history
but we're just not sure of them so i'm
only going to speak about them
the cannabis varieties which are growing
there and i'm not aware of the many
which are
uh they seem to be
uh you know a product
of
uh you know history you know what
happened in history because
when we had uh you know the colonial
colonial rule from you know the
britishers
so of course you know they had just
figured out that hey you know what the
sugar that is so expensive back in
europe and it's almost like a luxury
like every goddamn person is eating here
i mean the
guy who doesn't have anything on him can
still have some sugar
so they thought uh you know what they
need to do is they need to
produce it a lot more so then they could
make it abundantly you know available in
their country in their region as well so
everyone can enjoy it and
rightly so so they started uh i mean of
course doing the surveys and they
understood this is a crop that would
grow in tropical regions or sub-tropical
regions
and they started looking for those
places and it just so happens at the
same time they i mean they had colonies
uh the west indian islands and they
thought wow this is this is a perfect
place and these are islands you know we
could just bring slave from you know
these places and put them here and make
them grow
sugar cane and you know just
yeah i mean things really went in
history you know
so what they did was they got some
people from africa and some people from
india which both were their con
colonies at that point in time and you
know they put them there in west indian
island and said hey you know what go
ahead and just you know do our thing
here the farms they already had the farm
set up and they started working there
but just imagine this these people are
being taken on the ship so it was only
uh
you know it only made sense to these
people that you know we're not coming
back so we have to take everything with
us that you know we like to do on a
daily basis and cannabis seems to be one
of those things
and this is a fact because we know that
because if you go back into the
you know the british commission report
that they did on hemp and drugs i i i
don't remember the name exactly but
there's a report that was published by
the britishers about the indian about
the use of
cannabis in india and the cultural
effects and the
physical effects as well
so
that tells us that uh you know even
before that uh
there was a widespread use of cannabis
in india so we know that these people
took these seeds along with them to the
west indian islands and they started
growing it
and
you know uh those seeds are in those
varieties readily acclimatized to those
region because
why
the whole reason they were brought to
west indian islands was because
the temperature and the climate was
pretty similar to that of where they
were living in south india so most of
these uh you know um slaves were taken
taken from southern india and uh very
rarely from northern india
so uh the cannabis varieties that they
brought with them just readily took off
and over time i'm sure they must have
adapted in few different ways i've never
been there so i don't know what they
look like or
any idea anyway so uh that's the
connection between them and you know
even you could just see the same thing
happening in the people as well because
they got people from africa and india so
you had
people in africa
uh you know who were like turned into
christians
okay earlier when they were in africa
and then you had indians who were just
hindus so now you have people in west
indies right now who have
a lot of people they have very weird
names which are half english and of
hindi like shiv narayan chandra paul
they have a ball in their name they have
shiva they have chandra and or
there's just so many examples you know
so
you just see the cultural amalgamation
and you know the way history played out
in in in people and in their names and
in their languages and you know the
plant that they grow there
so yeah they have they sure can and
cannabis go back a very very long time
in fact
wow okay and so do you think that this
is kind of a bit of a two-parter but do
you think that
given many people consider some of these
um
islands to have their own kind of native
land race do you think that that's proof
that it only takes you know a couple
hundred years for a land race to
readjust and become a whole new land
race
uh yeah because see land race is a very
uh broad term again i mean it could
cover it could basically cover a lot of
uh things right so if you go just by the
word definition it says that any uh
domestic uh any traditionally
domesticated variety
at a certain you know geographical
locale right but
at the same time there are plants which
were not domesticated which were there
even before we have we were there and we
know that for a fact this the plans have
been before us like way before us when
we came here
so how do we account for those varieties
so
those are the primordial land races but
yes if you if you're saying about if
you're talking about the regional land
race varieties which which i think would
be a more appropriate term to use here
uh
yes that happens in as uh in as small of
a time as 200 to 100 years you can see
these plant varieties evolve and just
become completely different varieties
because of the selective environmental
pressure and of course human beings are
just all around this plant all the time
so
you really have to track all the
activities and understand their culture
for you to really uh you know paint a
picture that what could have happened
with this plant for it to become like
this today
and once you understand their culture
and you understand the environment and
the history
i mean you can just paint a very
comprehensive picture that how things
came to be and that just that might just
also give you a theme
or an uh insight into you know how
a cannabis plant basically adapts to
different terroirs
and i mean we just need a lot more data
and a lot more studying from a lot more
people but
i mean uh this is not something that you
know cannot be done
yeah certainly so
i mean this is a bit of a weird idea
i've had but i'd love to hear your
thoughts on it but basically i'm
wondering if you've ever noticed that in
areas where historically cannabis was
grown with other crops like maybe say
maize or sugarcane like they were kind
of grown in the same general area maybe
even the same field have you ever
noticed that maybe those plants have
increased ipm because what i kind of
wonder is like
where these two crops be at corn maze
and cannabis were they ever grown side
by side because maybe they benefited
each other in an ipm sense or have you
never really seen much like that sorry
um as far as the ipm is concerned i
think it's it might be the other way
around because uh even if you look at
the plants which are of the same family
like the canopy family
uh you look at sticking nettle i mean
nettles are of the same family as
cannabis
so you you do see that those both of
those plants are you know getting
affected by similar pests
and uh but but that really uh
i mean but
that's not a thing like because cannabis
plant was there that's why the pest must
have gotten onto the nettle plant or
because the nettle plant was there
they made it the vector to ultimately
reach you know the cannabis plant but i
i think the way it really works uh for a
lot of other crops that grows along with
it like maize and you know you could say
wheat or even potatoes
that they may have certain benefit in
terms of like you know fixing nitrogen
or something of that sort
but as far as ibm is concerned they do
not because you know cannabis as we know
is one of the plant that produces
aromatic compounds
and some of the plants that we're
talking about are like
potato maize and all that they just do
not produce aromatic compounds like
cannabis so
they they just do not have the kind of
uh you know
protection against the pests and
you know other
uh insects as cannabis as a plant has so
maybe cannabis provides them security
from the past but again i don't know
i've never looked into that never
thought of it but definitely a great
thought i'm going to make a note of it
right now
and you know next this year when i go
out i will try to look for that i will
try to look for some uh some conclusive
data that could uh you know show clearly
what what's happening uh whether you
know cannabis is helping the other
plants you know
uh
not get a lot of pests or actually
they're using it as a vector to get on
to the other plant so
i'll try to collect data and definitely
get back to you this year
yeah awesome thanks so thanks so much
for that um
now let's move on to
some viewers from our questions that we
had submitted just a couple hours ago
and we got some good ones and so the
first one i think it's going to be a
little hard but um first question is do
you think there will be a time in the
near future where americans will be able
to travel through the farms of pakistan
and afghanistan
i mean they're doing right now so
i mean i i don't really understand that
question uh basically because people are
doing right now it's only a matter of
finances
and it's only a matter of courage
because see
nobody's going to stop an american from
getting a visa for pakistan or
afghanistan i mean if anything it's the
other way around it's hard to get a get
an american or a european or australian
visa for people who are in asian
countries especially india pakistan
afghanistan right so i think it's only a
matter of
courage and resources i guess you can go
there and you can roam around i mean
i've certainly seen a couple of french
guys you know who were there they took
some pictures got some seed for some of
the european seed banks recently
so
but if you're maybe referring to it in a
way that when things would legalize then
i'm not sure if things are going to
legalize very very soon but
we don't know what's going to happen in
future and all we can do is just stay
hopeful that it does happen and you know
everybody could be out in the open and
you know flaunt their read on instagram
without having to fear about you know
getting abjected or you know
taken into custody
yeah of course
uh so the next question is have you ever
found any land races that kind of have a
strawberry smell to them and
specifically any pakistanis with the
strawberry smell
i have
smelled a few plants in
highland regions which is around
uttarakhand and himachal pradesh they
had a distinct smell of strawberry but
they were just one odd plant
which were growing in a very variable
population so i didn't really think of
you know getting those seeds and didn't
really think that it's going to help me
you know get to that terpene profile
uh
but if you talk about pakistani i'm
gonna say no because most of that stuff
is like really uh accurate and you know
um spicy and like dalwin like smell like
phenol like smell do you you guys use do
you guys use like a disinfectant it's
called itol
and it has that phenol yeah it has that
phenols phenol smell in it and you you
get that a lot and always smell that
comes from the whitener you know the
correction whitener people even you know
use it to get high sometimes
and so those uh
those uh smells
are pretty uh you know pretty often
found in pakistani varieties but i think
there was one balochistani variety which
came from our balochistani friend that
he claims has apples and strawberry like
smell now i haven't started growing them
yet so i'm not gonna go ahead
and say if yes or no but we'll see but i
have complete faith because uh we're not
talking about a cross-pollinated
uh you know uh population here these are
the plants which
have been you know
selectively inbred by
by the fam by the family itself and they
keep it within the family
so i mean if he's specifically pointing
towards you know strawberry and
apple and they seem to have a very good
understanding towards the flavors
because they're eating so many different
fruits over there
so i think i'll trust him and we'll see
if uh you know it does come out exactly
like strawberry i mean that would be
amazing because i've never had anything
uh that is like even close to the
strawberry
and and that's kind of i wanted to ask
in fact i wanted to ask you a question
and i asked that question to everyone
that i speak of from you know
from the western society that
it's it's the smells that people talk
about i mean often people talking about
like smells like banana and people are
talking about smell like rubber
and i've never smelled those
uh things on plants i mean never smelled
a plant that was exactly like a banana
or like exactly like
rubber so could you maybe tell me i'm
sorry i'm but i'm just curious i want to
know i mean are there plants that really
actually smell straight up like that
yeah that's a really good question so in
terms of the banana one i've smelled the
popular clone only banana oh g and stuff
like that in the states it smells like a
candy banana not like a real banana so i
can understand why you would say i've
never smelled anything like banana
because i think the reality is no one's
really smelled anything that smells like
an actual banana but people have smelled
things that smells like a candy banana
which is just probably like
two or three of the main terpenes that
come out of a banana but obviously not a
full spectrum picture of what it
actually is
and then in terms of the rubber one
i hear people say that all the time but
i myself have never smelt anything that
smells like rubber i think maybe it's
just a general term people use to
describe a more accurate
maybe kind of
um
yeah like offensive smell but yeah i
would agree with you if we're going to
be very strict about it i've never
smelled anything that smells like a real
banana or like real burnt rubber
okay because i was really curious about
that i had a word with
um again i don't know his name and i'm
really bad with this i don't ask
people's name um pip sweet you must know
him he must be your friend
yeah yeah yeah i like peeps
he's an amazing guy i mean i've been
speaking to him for
uh you know some time now and you know
i was really interested because he had
this uh variety that's called rubber
city and i just you know asked him does
that really actually smells like rubber
and i think what he said was really
interesting because i think he said uh
pretty much similar to what you said
that
well it's not exactly
you know closing your eyes and you know
that you would be able to imagine rubber
like smell but it's more like an oniony
offensive smell that
could you know at times be
uh you know felt like it is coming off
as a bunt rubber so you know i had to
get a pack from him and you know i'm
just going to grow and see
you know what exactly it's like i'm
really curious so i really want to see
yeah yeah that's that's an interesting
one i mean i've got a little follow-up
question for that do you have any issues
getting seeds in from like america or
the eu
seeds uh i mean like getting seeds from
america to india yeah yeah like if
people send you stuff do you ever really
have any issues with it or it usually
always makes it
no no issues at all i mean india is very
very cool i mean especially if it's
coming from america or europe australia
new zealand i mean these great countries
i mean we just don't really bother about
that yeah if i'm getting seats from
pakistan afghanistan that's when we
really tend to have issues
yeah understandable okay well uh the
next question i think is a really good
one and the person says what is one of
the land races that you that you've
experienced i guess we should say
regional cultivars if we're going to be
correct um
that you've found that you would
recommend for like kind of a home grower
who's just looking to start out with a
land race they don't want anything
that's going to get too unruly or really
out of control like just to help them
get their feet wet what would you
recommend
that's an amazing question because we i
think about it all the time because i
mean as much as i want to you know
motivate other people and talk about
preservation the ground reality is is
that
people have responsibilities and people
have to feed their families and they
have to you know manage their space and
do other work as well right and that's
what life is all about so
in order to strike balance uh there has
to be some varieties you know who
would let you preserve a land race
variety or an heirloom variety or like a
regional variety but at the same time it
will not bother you
a lot that it would interfere with you
know your work let's just for an example
let's say you're you only have 110 which
is 4x4
and you're going some og cushion there
and you have kerala gold
it's it's going to grow really wide and
tall and eventually you would be forced
to lift your lights up but your og kush
may not grow that tall and then it would
have to be you know lifted up or you
would have to do some kind of makeshift
arrangement so it will be a constant
improvising you know which is not really
a big problem though but everybody's not
does not have the kind of schedule to be
in their
you know grow room all the time and do
these adjustments
so i think uh as we discussed earlier
the pakistani varieties are perfect i
mean they bring you know both uh the
best of the both were you know the
narrow slim leaf and you know the
broadleaf varieties in a way that is
just unparalleled and
again they they
the the variety and the variation is
still there nobody has selected it for
anything specifically so you can pretty
much you know turn your magic on them so
swabi would be one of those things one
of those varieties i mean it has an
amazing high amazing height for a
variety you know that
that people have not heard of so much
and it's very easy to grow i'm going to
say that and you know it's not going to
get uh you know all unruly and it's not
going to become like a swamp monster
inside your tent you'll be able to
control it
uh
so i think just you know keep an eye out
for that swabby lines that's gonna come
out he's uh mass medical is gonna you
know
release them pure in the long flowering
and the short flowering version and i'm
sure he'll be working on some hybrids
that's like his thing but
yeah those would be really good options
to pounce on to if people just want to
get into and not really get into very
deep waters straight away this is this
is a great way to get a taste of it and
not get into trouble
yeah what a great answer
so the next question we have from our
viewer is
how do you know babaco
okay that uh that's very interesting
story because uh initially i i met him
over the instagram i came across uh his
account and but i never really did send
him any message because
that's usually how we were not working i
mean we were we had like stopped sending
messages to random people and you know
getting random seeds from them so we
were kind of like traveling out to
places more working more like that
so um
at the same time uh
i had a
you know i had a friend in delhi
you know who's basically a south indian
but he was in delhi at that point in
time and he was also
following him
uh somehow i don't know what the
connection was basically
but uh baba he came to india because uh
you know
i'm not gonna go into the details of his
affair because he was there for some
kind of hospital related thing
uh you know that they have to come
because they don't have that kind of
services in afghanistan and you know
india just seemed to have
a a little better when it comes to you
know medical services doctors and all so
he was here for that and you know he
wanted to smoke so uh he basically
called uh you know the guys uh you know
who live in delhi
guys who are usually doing the balance
stuff and you know they offered to give
him some hash but i think because it was
very costly so you know he was not sure
whether or not he would get it
so then uh subsequently he contacted me
and he told me you know hey you know
what this guy is from afghanistan and
he's in delhi and you know this be great
opportunity you guys can connect and see
you know if
you can guys can get some kind of trade
going for seats and i was like sure sure
give me the phone number and he gave me
the phone num phone number i sent him a
whatsapp message and i was like hey how
are you doing i follow you and i've seen
some pictures you know cannabis you're
from afghanistan and whatnot and i told
him hey you know what like you're
welcome to india and i would like to
make sure you're taken care of just call
my friends in delhi and you know told
them to get some hash to him asap free
of cost of course and make sure he's
taken care of
so that happened and you know he said
i'm going to remember that he went back
and he did and you know he said okay
uh you know if you want seed i could
send you seeds and i told him that you
know this is what we do we actually take
seeds from indigenous communities or
farmers directly you know we you know
give them out to other people who need
it and the best and you know they kind
of pay for it
and you know that uh
money could be distributed amongst you
know people who are collecting it and
people you know who are connected to the
operation in many different ways as they
deserve
now he was he was really gay for that
because you know of course everybody
would need some financial help at the
end of the day and you know i i set up
uh
you know i spoke to these people at full
power selection and told them basically
you know we're gonna do this and we're
gonna do a pre-order and seeds were on
its way
and next thing you know the seeds get
busted so seeds didn't make it to india
and this is around this is happening
like beginning of april 2018 okay
i got really nervous i was like i have
to get these seats and again you know
baba told me that hey man i'm game for
this i mean i will do anything you just
tell me what i have to do and i will get
this thing to you i mean
i
absolutely have no problem it's just the
way government you know works
and what we uh you know realize at that
point in time the only way around it was
to actually get the guy you know
actually fly the guy over to india and
you know ask him to simply just get the
seeds because they're not gonna you know
take it out on the airport because
basically to possess seeds is legal in
india
because of the you know religious
uh you know things attached to it
so that's exactly what he did he flew
along with so many different varieties
and you know we picked him
we picked them up and came to delhi and
from delhi we got him to you know our
headquarters just somewhere near you
know punjab shivalik and you know we sat
we spoke i tried to understand the
culture as much as i could because uh
you know
language is a little bit of problem not
much of a problem because he does
understand hindi you know which is our
language
and
but i don't seem to really understand
you know the arabic language or the
farsi language that much
so he speaks english
you know as well not as much but you
know as much as you could he could make
you understand what he's trying to say
so that was great we we sat there for
about a week and you know we went out to
a few places you know roamed around
punjab had a good time he gave me the
seas and then you know we we sent him
back with all due respect and you know
that's where we really started to work
with those seats and i think i i i did
get to you know send him like a couple
more times there were a few different
varieties i went ahead and documented
those varieties for him you know so that
you know that
so not just seeds but information could
also become you know available to people
so that when they're growing it and if
they see something peculiar they can
fall back to that cultural historical
geographical data and see if that has
any relevance to it i mean that's
basically how the findings are made
and uh yeah that went on for about a
year but uh then you know of course we
are a small collective and uh we gotta
understand them in you know full power
selection even they're just like couple
of my friends so we can send out like a
lot of orders so we we have to we can
only do a limited amount of work but you
know
uh you know he had a massive amount of
seeds and you know he had so much more
coming in so you know it was only the
best that you know he
[Music]
got in contact with you know bigger seat
banks who have the ability to take more
orders and the ability to you know uh
send out more orders readily and you
know that's exactly what he's doing
which is fabulous and i'm really happy
you know that he's been able to do so
much for himself and you know all the
credit is to him i mean like you know
it's it's all been him he collected
those varieties he understood they need
to preserve he took immense amount of
risk getting those varieties out to
these different places so you know i i
have a great amount of respect for
for him and you know he has
really been a central figure in this
whole movement
and i think i'm i was pretty lucky to
have met him at a certain point in my
life
yeah awesome what a great little recount
on that introduction so the next
question we had was
what's the single most surprising smell
you've come across from a regional
cultivar
the single most uh you know
weird or i was a weird smell was there
was this one plant that was growing in
baling valley and it has a smell which
is straight like ammonia like like
hydrogen you know
uh
should i say
uh i mean you in india they use a cheap
uh you know derivative that is uh you
know used to color the hair you know to
bleach your hair as basically uh
hydrogen i think if i'm not wrong and it
it has that stringent ammonia-like smell
to it
uh right and you know the same smell
that comes from urine as well
because there's ammonia in it so i i
could smell exactly the straight ammonia
smell from a plant it was a really ugly
plant i have i took a picture of that
and i made a post about that and back in
2017 if you go down my
uh you know feed you can actually find
that post from 2017 and you can also
look at the plant it looks weird it does
not look at all like any of the plants
which were growing there
and you know the smell was something i
mean
it was just
awful i mean
awful in a very good way straight
ammonia
yeah it sounds like you found like the
uh the regional cultivar equivalent of
the roadkill skunk but there you go
we'll have to look more for it so the
next question we had was do you have any
tips or tricks for people who are trying
to grow high altitude cultivars at sea
level
i i don't really think i mean i mean
given that you know
cannabis as adaptive as adaptive as a
plant that it is and rightly so it's
called the weed you know for that reason
um you you never what i've experienced
from my growing and i don't have a lot
of experience but this is what i'm going
to tell you from my experience whatever
i have
that cannabis does not require like very
special things you don't have to make it
so hard on you and you know you grow
and
if you keep it simple i i pretty much
believe every plant
does pretty much good as long as you're
growing it in in a 22 degrees to a 26 27
degree celsius range temperature range
and you know relative humidity is
somewhere around like 50 55 60 and you
know you're you have a decent soil
medium you don't really have to you know
worry about
things at all but on the other hand if
you are growing an equatorial variety
and you happen to be living in a place
which happens to be higher up in the
latitude that means you can have a
shorter season
uh for flowering so then you have to uh
you know then you have to ensure that
uh you know either you're working with a
variety that's not going to flower you
know past november or you just have to
grow it indoors
and you know put it into flowering
straight away instead of giving it veg
time because even if you grow those
equatorials or highland narrow leaf
varieties
you know straight away under 12 to 12
which is basically what induces a
flowering in them they still have go on
to grow pretty much like four or five
six feet and if you wet them then i mean
it's really gonna be a problem if you're
not expecting
yeah right they just get out of hand all
of a sudden um
cool okay so the final question from our
viewers that they've submitted is have
you ever made your way over towards kind
of thailand and down that way
um i have been to burma i mean i have to
uh you know
you can actually go to burma you know
without a visa and without a passport so
i've been to burma but i'm planning to
go down thailand this year and you know
i have a great friend there
they have a beautiful collective you
know they're preserving thai and you
know other land races from you know
different regions
so i really want to go there meet them i
do have friends in laws as well i have
friends in cambodia as well
and you know i'm really meaning to meet
them because i did get seeds from them
last year and i was able to help them i
was able to you know give back to them
and they were really happy you know that
i told them something and i came through
and you know they kind of trust me with
it so i'm just going to go and meet them
in person and you know establish a
deeper relationship and try to collect
some data as well firsthand
wow that sounds really cool
so
now on to our last little quick fire
questions before we wrap things up so
the first one i had for you was
in your opinion what kind of little
pocket or region of the world has really
fantastic cannabis but just doesn't
often get recognized for it
cold as it regions
which are basically in the trance
himalayan ranges i don't think i think
they're completely unheard of nobody
talks about them yet they seem to have
plants you know which would
uh rival
most of the you know modern varieties
only in terms of you know resin
production not in terms of high or the
structure
but in terms of the amount of resin that
they can produce they can pretty much be
at par with some of the
you know modern varieties
well yeah you bang on right i hadn't
heard of those at all really so the next
question is what's what's the one type
of cannabis that you've always been
looking for but you've never really
found you know is it like a certain
smell or a certain look like what are
you still chasing
i mean i'm pretty much not
i'm not trying to chase like a specific
flavor or a specific kind of plant or
what i'm rather trying to chase is
uh as many places as i can you know
so that i have a rather complete picture
of the evolution of this plant or at
least i can you know forward this data
to people who are competent enough or
have the scientific abilities
to put a bigger picture together of you
know how this plant evolved into these
different types because although we can
you know classify them and we can do all
the labeling we want but that doesn't
really tell us you know what actually
happened how they evolved into these
different and branched off into these
different plants
so what i'm really after is you know if
i can just somehow get
get to all of these places physically
within this lifetime and then you know
concise that data in one like a book
kind of thing or i mean not necessarily
but in one place and then you know
other people can take that data and then
they can you know develop it further as
we advance and you know as more
scientific people
will be you know coming into the
industry because it's no longer a
stigmatized industry so what we're
seeing if you're seeing a surge of you
know scientists and you know engineers
and even you know one of my friend is a
software engineer so
they want to do it they don't feel like
it's wrong anymore so this is the time
when we are going to
really see a very steep curve of you
know the advancement in the
understanding of cannabis all across the
world uh but you know what is really
going to be of the prime importance here
is going to be that data and i mean if
you don't have that if you don't really
have the data and those things are gone
and it's going to be really really hard
to really reconcile the complete picture
yeah very valid answer right there so
what is your favorite cannabis that
you've ever had be it flower hash what's
the single one that stands out the most
in your memory is the best ever
that's ever the best ever for me would
have to be lola valium in
the low lab valley
is
i mean i don't have words and i'm not
even going to attempt to explain it in
words i'm just going to say this is the
best kind of effect if i'm only speaking
in terms of effects and nothing else the
way it makes you feel the
the place it takes you as a person when
you get high on this
so i like that place a lot and you know
other cannabis also takes me to these
different places and i like them
but you know lola valley northern
kashmiri varieties take me to a place
that
is just unparalleled and you know
i i just love it i mean you you just get
some some seeds from me if you want and
grow them and smoke them and you'll
you'll know what i'm talking about
oh music to me is my friend i'll have to
take you up on that but i want to give
you a good little remix question so
often we hear people talk about oh you
know i got to try this landry strain it
wasn't really that good or something to
that effect you know like standard
western person so here's the remix for
you have you ever tried a more modern
strain maybe like a cali import or
something and you were like a bit
disappointed
um i i was but i think uh that was
primarily because
it was not grown by me it was grown by
someone else and i felt that you know
had it been grown properly i mean it
would have certainly lived up to the
expectations because see like i said in
the beginning in india i mean hybrid uh
weed cells for any
anywhere between 800 to 1500 or 1200 at
least for an ounce and the biggest
reason behind that is is the boat i'm
sorry is the potency that you cannot
find in the regional varieties here
you just cannot i mean uh the high is
unparalleled in the
uh hybrid repertoire that you guys have
over there so uh it's very hard to be
disappointed i mean i mean i i don't
really understand i mean um you know how
can somebody be disappointed but then at
the same time i can understand if all
you have is all of this good weed then
you tend to have a relative scale you
know which is mapped against some of the
best varieties like cam dog or og kush
so then people tend to
or headband like things then people tend
to like you know compare everything to
that and
by the virtue of that comparison you
know some of the people who are
regularly you know experiencing these
things could say that you know that this
thing is uh not gonna get you that high
or it's not that enjoyable or if this is
crap if somebody chooses to talk that
way then
but for us it's really hard to say a
hybrid sucks because i mean
we're like smoking varieties mostly you
know which are not that potent okay so
uh you know it's hard for somebody from
india to just look hybrid and say that
it is not good especially if it's coming
from
usa because i see a lot of good work
happening in usa and there are so many
people doing it i mean
i mean i think the
plant is in very good hands in america
yeah hard to argue that they're not
progressing things forward in a lot of
ways so final question of the interview
this brings us to it and this is the one
i wanted to ask you the most
if you could go anywhere and select
seeds from any area any point in time in
history where would you go and what
seeds would you want to get
okay
if i could go back in history and i
could collect wow that's a good question
i'll have to think about it because i've
never thought about it before so just
give me a second
take as long as you need my friend
okay who would i want to go
then that's uh
yeah uh okay i think i know what i would
like to do is uh i
okay and you could only go to one place
yeah just one
place oh man sorry
okay then
i would like to go to that uh near that
cave at exactly the same point in time
you know in tibbat
where they just found this evidence for
you know
some cannabis which was used by you know
some people some hundred thousand years
ago so i would want to be at that point
in time and get some of those grab some
of those seeds
while those primitive gentlemen are you
know smoking on their cannabis i just
take my time machine and come back
hell yeah i just get that primordial
stuff
yeah
for that
what a brilliant answer well
that just about brings us to the end of
it did you have any comments or shout
outs you wanted to make
oh no not not really uh i think i think
you were really able to i mean just walk
over i mean all these things and then
you ask some things which i hadn't even
thought about so really um
i'm just all empty here man like unless
you have a question
no no that's awesome my friend well i
mean thank you so much for joining us on
the show erasing and you know dropping
all the knowledge about the land races
and the local cultivation i think people
are going to really love this one
thank you so much i really want to
appreciate you from the bottom of my
heart because you know i'm a big fan and
let me tell you before we go i mean 2017
i think was the year that i heard your
podcast for the first time and you know
so i've known about this thing for such
a long time and you know it is an
absolute privilege to be here today and
be able to speak to you and share my
thoughts through your reputed platform
thank you so much
oh man the pleasure's all mine
[Music]
and there we have it guys a four hour
block of pure information download
straight to your brain from your boy
erasing
[Applause]
[Music]
so appreciative
so much i didn't know about indian stuff
i hope you guys have learned a lot and
like me i hope you're excited to go to
india do your own land race hunt down
as always huge shout out to coppit
biological systems best predator mike's
microbial products and artificial feeds
in the game huge shout out to ct now
guarantee on satisfaction not just
germination and as always big love to
the patreon gang you guys are the best
dragonfly earth medicine we love you
guys long time
i'll see you for the next one guys
[Music]
let's see
foreign
[Music]
you