hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding Enthusiast as always you're
joined here by your boy heavy days here
from the upside down library and as
usual we want to give a massive shout
out to our incredible sponsors who help
make the show happen I know you love
seeds here now but guess what they're
taking it up yet another level they've
got a whole bunch of amazing
celebrations and promos coming up over
the month of February celebrating
Groundhog Day Valentine's Day
presidential day and to kick it all off
for the whole month of February they're
celebrating pineapple that's right a
range of different pineapple flavored
strains across the site 20% off be sure
to get in on the fun at seeds here now
all the hottest breeders the latest
drops shout out seeds here now we
appreciate your support so much in order
to get your garden producing the best
crop to date you got to make sure your
rooms dialed in to do that check out our
friends at Pulse sensors Number One
sensors and integrated hubs in the game
measuring all of the variables PPD VPD
temperature humidity Duo all the extra
variables you don't consciously track to
help ensure your next crop is the best
to date whether you're running a single
tent a single room or a multi-state
operation pulse sensors are the number
one in the game and they've just
recently released the pulse Hub a
central unit to integrate all of their
monitors to make sure that your rooms
are the best they can possibly be
massive thank you to pulse sensors we
appreciate you so
much likewise you got to keep your
garden pests and pathogen free and to do
that you got to check out our friends at
copit these guys are the world leaders
in Sustainable biocontrol Solutions for
pests and disease if you're battling
spidermites check out their new spidex
vital plus sachet these are new pillis
breeding sachet that release predator
mites into your crop consistently over a
period of several weeks providing you
with sustained spidermite control now
you don't have to spread carrier
material through your garden just to
introduce predator mites just hang the
sachet on your crop let the person
Millis walk out and do the work for you
trust me guys you don't want to have to
go up against a spiderm infestation
without spidi tool plus these are truly
the best predators in the game I promise
once you use it you'll see the quality
you'll never go back massive shout out
to copit likewise you got to check out
our friends at Organics alive if you're
growing
organic and want to use high quality
powdered organic fertilizers you simply
cannot go past Organics alive these guys
truly walk the walk and talk to talk
they have been picking up cups left
right and center with Growers all around
the country sweeping categories using
their products that is the ultimate
Testament in my opinion if homeg Growers
are winning competitions using their
products the proof is in the pudding
guys no matter what stage of the plant
cycle you're at veg transition flower in
need of micronutrients or a very
specific sort of boost in late flower
they've got it you got to check out
Organics alive guys truly one of the
best in the industry we're super stoked
to be working with them because we know
how amazing their products are using
heaps of breeder Gardens that we have on
the show again check them out Organics
alive massive thank you massive shout
out for supporting the
show finally a massive shout out to the
entire crew at dap these guys make some
of the best vaporizers on the game I'm
really pass about this one because they
help me to get off combustion and
smoking bongs if you have any concerns
about your respiratory health or Heck if
you just want to try a different mode of
ingestion maybe try to get a better
flavor hit you got to check out the dino
that these guys units are cheap they're
incredibly welld designed and most
importantly they're very customizable
you can take your Vape game to the next
level getting insane turps all while
retaining the potency you'd expect of a
combustion or a bong truly I was smoking
bongs for over 10 years I'm now Vape
only massive shout out to DAP they're
one of the best in the industry and we
owe them a massive thank you shout out
again dout massive thanks for supporting
the
show finally a quick little mention to
Our patreon Gang truly the life blood of
the show if you want to get early access
to episodes unheard and unreleased
interviews as well as going in the
running to get amazing genetics each
month and fortnite come on check out the
patreon at www.patreon.com
/the podcast we do live smoke with heavy
sessions every fortnite and give away
heaps of Swag every month come check it
out we love you the patreon gang thank
you so much we are so
appreciative today we're here for part
two of our interview with Kevin
ji talking all things
breeding
growing
history his recent trip to Pakistan and
so much more so without further
delay let's get into it you know you
just spoke about how different latitudes
produce sort of different effects based
on the original land races and I think a
lot of people listening are waiting for
us to delve into it obviously if
anyone's been paying attention to your
Instagram you've had what looks like a
really epic recent trip over to Pakistan
I'd love to talk a bit about this what
what stimulated this how did all the
ball get
rolling oh man that was an epic
adventure I I I can't say enough about
the Pakistan the team I was with and the
people of Pakistan they were just lovely
so so friendly um what started it was
there was a group on you know yeah we're
all online but I had I had done some
work with um the Indian Land race group
where they had reached out to me and
said hey we're trying to do some
promotion to get people to be more aware
of genetic preservation and that even
though you know when you take the genes
from one nation in small population and
move them you're not really doing an
official preservation but the idea that
some of the genes stay alive and get
shared and and hopefully bring back some
value to the farmer was what they
desired and so I I say hey I'm down that
sounds like a great project I said I'll
I'll participate and what I did is I I
took some of the genes and I created a
population but I cleaned them up a
little bit and got the intersex traits
out because I knew that most people were
going to grow them indoors
and I gave them out at conferences all
over the world right I shared them
everywhere and so what it did is it and
all I asked was for people to give
credit to the farmers in the region of
gazy
Afghanistan so this way what we're doing
is we're showing the this relevancy of
others that at the end of the day all
small cultivators are connected around
the world by virtue of our
craft and so that it was successful
where it brought a of attention to that
that project and it was something I was
really into and so it it caught the it
caught the eye of you know two groups
land race
genetics and let's be friends Pakistan
so let's let's be friend Pakistan is a
tourism group and land race genetics is
a genetics collection group and so they
reach out to me and said hey you know um
we just want to be your friend online
and just chat with you once in a while
so I said sure and so we become friends
and we chat once in a while over the
years and they say we have this idea
that we've been working on and we want
to know if you'd be interested in coming
out to Pakistan and experiencing our
country and traveling the silk route and
doing a collection with land race
genetics and if it's something that's
positive for you to let the public know
that this was a good place and that our
people are good kind
people and it it sounds so simple you
know and it's just that Pakistan had
such a horrific reputation I mean I got
a text when I was ready to fly out about
chopping my head off and I mean the
people people believe that we were going
to go there and be murdered and and I
didn't believe that at all I had been
man I had a fantasy of going to Pakistan
since I was a kid I always wanted to see
these regions and I was just bummed that
I couldn't because of the wars in
Afghanistan and so when I got invited
out by these two groups I'd spent enough
time talking to them online I knew they
didn't want to cut off my head what they
wanted was they wanted to they they're
they're young they're 30s and 40s you
know I'm almost 60 what they wanted was
they wanted to be able to bring
attention in a positive
way and it was such a I want to say like
lack of a better word noble Endeavor
that I was like man I'm down I'm
supported and so I fly out to Pakistan
and I'm with uh green walrus Danny
and uh his team and I'm with a a a two
dudes from from England one of them
that's a breeder and another one that's
working with an operation in Australia
from
relaf so Neil from relief was with us
and so we're called the Internationals
and there was one other cat too uh Imran
from uh Canada who is a a premium
extractor and he was interested as hell
too because he's a really talented like
street dancer and so every cool place
he's been on the earth he goes and
dances with the people and does some
cool [ __ ] and Pakistan was live because
the backgrounds were Wicked and he would
throw on some on some music and just
tear it up like this kid can move so it
was really uh this interesting trip that
they had gathered some of us knew each
other some of us didn't but it was just
people that let's be friends Pakistan
and land race genetics had connected to
you know over the last year or
two and realized that hey you you you
all make a pretty good diverse group we
think that if you all travel together
with us it would be really a good
Adventure so they put this idea together
to travel the ancient silk route the
route that connected the world really
and we were going to travel the silk
route and then go explore the Cannabis
regions do some
collecting and enjoy you know the time
together and it was the single most
insane trip I've ever been on in my life
because when you're traveling the silk
route you are literally traveling the
Korum Highway which is like the
deadliest Road in the world and I mean
you got landslides going down it it's so
rugged it it let me understand like the
first time I've had the concept of
verticality where you know you're at
like I think the highest we went when we
went over past was like
14,000 but the mountains around it were
14,000 feet higher than that so like you
have this up and down that your neck
gets tired from trying to look at the
base and to the top of something because
it's beyond comprehension and it's the
there's four ranges that come together
but the kurur the Himalayas and the
Hindu Kush all Collide there and through
those glaciers that feed at 7,000
glaciers up through Nepal and Pakistan
it creates the indis river and the indis
river is feeding you know onethird the
Earth's population with fresh water so
it's a river that's twice as big as the
Nile and it's one of the birth places of
humankind and so this if this these
areas to me were just like mythical
because I had studied them as a kid and
I'm in love with herbs so I'm fascinated
by the regions that really developed all
the varieties that we use so much in
North America so the ability to go and
and visit this place was just surreal
and the teams were awesome the the Les
be friends Pakistan put a trip on that
couldn't have been any more
comprehensive it was like every day you
were
247 experiencing Pakistan by the time
you left you're almost a
native and for me to go and get to do
some collection work with the land race
crew was awesome because they'd spent
the last seven years practicing
collecting and so they knew the regions
and they knew the profiles and they knew
what profiles were coming from what type
of gardens what type of companion plants
like they had a really
intuitive technically developed view of
the job so it made it awesome for me
because you know hanging out with a
bunch of weed freaks is never bad and
hunting herb in the mountains with
people that are able to help you
understand with the patterns that they
see and so you're just there to
participate with them I wasn't there to
teach them anything I was there just to
work with them as a friend so it was
just totally cool it was it was like
total camaraderie and when we arrived
the group said hey we know you guys
smoke a lot so we got you uh six quarter
pounds of indoor grown in Pakistan which
was fire and 500 grams half a kilo hash
so we had and there was probably like
seven kinds of hash but it made up a
total of 500 grams all kill a hash from
Tia so you know it's going to be a good
time when you show up and there a pound
and a half of herb and and half a keia
hash to smoke and so we basically smoked
our way through
the the trails and explored the
mountains and the people of Pakistan and
got to check out some stun in cannabis
varieties with patterns and profiles
that I really can't describe because I
don't have the ability to describe them
it just blew my mind it was it was so
interesting to find the true
outliers wow that's that's absolutely
incredible I'm sure everyone's you know
very jealous what a what a warm welcome
you know a pound and a half and half
kilo of hash beautiful beautiful man
knows how to welcome people I guess the
first question I'd love to ask is um you
know what what were some of the standout
sort of profiles or plants you came
across on that Journey
you know there there's the the one that
resonated more than any
was I want to say it was the only way
you could describe it would be some form
of like lacquer thinner combined with
every ingredient in an exotic Spice Shop
and then swirl that [ __ ] together and
then turn the volume up to 10 where this
thing screamed the smell that emanated
off that plant just ripped through a
field when when when I didn't find that
one Jamie found it and so he finds it
and he yells whoa and and he shakes it
and I can hear him you know shaking
something and the odor led us to it and
I mean you're to feel the weed and it
was so volatile that just him moving it
pulsed it through the entire
crop just incredible there was a another
profile I I really loved but I was I
would say it's like a classic Kush
and that we would say what is classic
Kush that dirty earthy tobacco cigar box
but now take all that [ __ ] and clean it
up clean it up and refine each one of
those flavors so that they're clear and
crisp and defined and then weave them
all together so that you're just having
this this this
explosion in your nose of of those
things you you think you're in some type
of habiter like a clothing store where
there's fine fine epicurian tobacco and
the the the smell of the wood and the
the fabric and the material just leather
unbelievable I just loved it there was
plants that were so wet with essential
oil that when you rubbed against them it
wet your arm and I had to look up and I
laughed too because I did it multiple
times I go oh it must have rained and it
because there was they were literally
wet they were just dumping liquid and
then you found plants that were the
polar opposite where they bone dry but
they had the most granular grainy gritty
ryzen heads just and so what we did is
we basically looked for everything that
had good morphology where the plant had
a decent frame on it and that was
interesting too because the mineral
levels are so high from the glacier
that that the plants are just absolutely
leathered when when you try to rip a
branch off I mean it almost cut your
hands trying to pull the the bark
through your fingers it was it was you
had to tear them off and putting your
feet on the ground you look at a lot of
plants today you can peel them off with
your hands this [ __ ] was cemented and
when you cut it with a knife it was so
lignified it wasn't like a cannabis
stalk it was almost like a semi
hardwood just so minerally dense the
food was like that too super high
mineral levels in the
food so you just notice some very
differences than what we're used to but
what what we did is we just looked for
outliers that caught our eye and so you
would just go and go through hundreds of
plants just going plant to plant to
plant and there was what seven of us
eight of us together looking and so we
would look through you know a shitload
of plants and anybody who found
something they thought was an outlier
would yell we'd come over and look at it
I had a journal we would then identify
is it is it something unique yes then we
write why was it unique Cod it and then
then bag it and double tag it so that we
had the plant to sift later and every
time we found something similar we would
go to the journal and say okay this is
something similar do we think this plant
is better or worse than the one we
collected and if it was better then we
would collect it and put it into the
journal so at the end of the day it gave
us like 60 plants that we had collected
out of you know eight different
collection
sites and then that that allowed us now
to be able to to break those into
categories where I was able to say okay
these are these are our Earth categories
these are the ones that have um some of
these fruit profiles these are the ones
that are colored in this direction these
are these are all purple almost black
these are these are a matrix so it let
me start to create kind of divisions of
what we were looking at and why we were
grabbing it and how to kind of explain
it to the
public and then what we did is we took
that that truckload of plants plants and
trash bags fill the truck and then as
soon as we got to the hotel at night we
would break the plants down and start to
separate the buds from the bodies of the
plant and then because it's so dry there
we would leave them out at night and
they would slowly dry then in the
morning we would seal everything up and
then move to the next site and as we did
but every night we would open every one
of the bags either on the roof of the
building or on the on the porches and
everything was organized and we would
work as a team constantly allowing the
plants to dry enough to deed so that at
the end of the at the end of the trip
what we had was a case of product versus
a pickup truck of product then once we
got back to lore we're able to go
through and do a final sift and
cleansing and get rid of all the Chafe
seed get rid of all the undeveloped and
there should be a picture on my Ig of a
tabletop filled with bags of seeds and
each one of those reflect the ones we
kept and the only one we really got rid
of was we selected it but when we broke
into it we realized it was a bug Factory
where that that we didn't see any real
pest problems on any plant I mean it was
incredible resistance but one plant had
every if there was a bug in Pakistan it
was on that plant and so we laughed and
said well however nice this smell this
is exactly the last plant one wants to
bring into their grow world because it's
a it's it's a trap and so having trap
plants is great but um also not great
wow that that's awesome to hear the the
process behind it all and how you were
able to get so many cool different
samples one of our fans submitted
questions was if you had to pick just
one of the lines that you were able to
secure which one are you most excited to
dig
through oh [ __ ] that first one I talked
about I want to say it's uh
4D so each one of the each one of the
sites was was numbered with a you know a
number and then each selection was given
so we had eight sites so we had one
through eight and then each each
location had a variable amount of
selections made some one two some 10
just depend on it was really all quality
based but that first one that first one
was so
noxious and
ferocious and and crazy that I'm like I
want to go there first and I second I
would go into those cushies that I chose
because I really love
that tobacco coffee chocolate you know
that old world type profile you know the
the like a true Bubba cush even like
gorilla glues a similar that chy flavor
um done right you know to me that's just
an epic profile and so those are the
ones I'd go into second but that that
first one and the beauty of it too was
that it was an absolute dumper and
dumper means that that it had an
incredible collection of seed that were
fully ripe on the plant which some of
the plants did not and so if I don't
see seed that's developed that lets me
know that the plant's going to have a
longer flowering period and that doesn't
work well for most people definitely not
outside and so the way the pakistanis
work it is they don't they don't sift
females what they do is they sift
males so it's their male selection that
they work with they don't they don't do
like a a true open population they do a
selected pollination and they choose the
males both on purple and green so you
get both
colors purple is more for frost
resistance from their opinion that it's
a little bit more resistant to issues
but they think the green has a more
interesting chemotype but they make sure
that there's both males in the field all
the time and then they choose the ones
that have the best Vigor you know best
uh display of uh flower formation best
odor just the qualities that someone
would seek in a in a pollinating mail
and they have a diversity of them but
they Rogue out most of them and so you
can you can kind of see the consistency
in pollination because they've cull out
all the males early they didn't want
present so that way it lets you at least
be able to compare the plants to each
other if it's a true open pollination
it's a nightmare you don't know if the
plant was it the male that triggered
quick and pollinated or was the female
early what happened but if it's all the
same males and then the females are
different we can say okay this one has a
reasonable finish time and so the one
that I lik the most was the seeds were
phenomenal so what we saw too was
incredible diversity in seed size from
you know huge like you know pinky tip to
microscopic and when you looked at at it
under a loop they were completely
developed complete perfect but just R
yeah and it's the same deal because you
got to remember that for the pakistanis
and and afghanis
cannabis was first a food source before
it was a drug and it still is so they
used the seed to survive the winners and
they roast it with wheat and that way
they're getting all the fats and the
omegas and it gives them great health
they use the byproduct as a tea and then
they also bang out some hash for hash
places like Tia which are which is the
primary hash region of the country their
you know primary function is Hash all
the other products second and third
whereas most of Pakistan seed primary so
and and they don't breed for big seeds
either because what they want is
diversity so they're they're intelligent
in a way that only someone who's been
touching a plant for 18800 years 1500
years can
be that's beautiful definitely some
wisdom in a lot of the different
practices you just uh mentioned them
doing there I'd love to ask you know on
the other end of the spectrum did you
see any population contam mintion while
over there any European or American
genetics and there's a quick followup
what was sort of the farmers perspective
were they aware of like American and
sort of more Western genetics at
all yeah they they are because the one
thing I noticed in the world no matter
what elevation altitude location
everybody's got a cell phone and so you
know the whole world is on IG and so
they're fully aware but they they
they're kind of protected in a way that
different than Morocco Lebanon where
tourism is is still you know pretty
prevalent to a degree Pakistan has been
on a you know 20-year Hiatus where
people really haven't been there since
911 so I mean I only saw one white
person the entire time I was there and
that was a German tourist and German
tourists are notorious for going where
no one will go and so you know if
there's if there's if there's a single
white person anywhere up in the side of
a mountain I would say it's probably a
German tourist because they they
absolutely ferocious on
exploring but that's it we were the only
white people we saw and so when I spoke
to all the different farmers and all the
different groups you know the questions
I was asking were you know do you hold
your lines individually and they said no
we all share we all share the lines we
choose uh best stock if we have great
crops we share the seeds with others and
they didn't have any infiltration from
any American or Dutch genes because
nobody had been over there
and it was a it was awesome to see that
that it was still this protected
population and yes they are curious
about the the the in you know about the
the the new genes but where you see
those develop they're not in the outdoor
fields that is in the new indoor
industry of Pakistan and so Pakistan and
the upper middle class uh high class
Financial level people um the kids of
that World they want Western type [ __ ]
and so they want to smoke gelato they
want indoor
runs and so when we got there and they
broke out this weed I looked at it and
it was dank and I just said this is some
really good grass and I said this [ __ ]
is not outdoor and they were like no
it's indoor and I'm like how'd you ship
it in and they said we didn't one of our
friends uh grew it they imported all
their grow equipment from another
country and they have an indoor sparked
up at their house or at a location and
they producing this good indoor and I
was cracking up because you know it was
like lemon sorbet and you know [ __ ] that
you see in the California Market but in
Pakistan and done correctly it was
really well done like Well Done well-
grown weed so the indoor is what the the
the trendy want they don't want outdoor
and so you only see the jeans coming in
on the indoor end and I think that you
know as time went on I I I it was
awesome having Imran there because Imran
a really talented extractor too so it
was neat to see him and the the the
native extractors hanging out you know
talking shop because they they work off
of a dry sift
static but you know when we're talking
they working off a dryft static that
means that s that we were rolling with
he's got a 4 acre patch himself and so
he's hand sifting four acres of cannons
wow so like you know and and and his
first memory is like I asked him I said
you know what what what was it like
being a kid you know like in the world
of cannabis here and he goes oh man my
first memories of helping my dad when I
was
three and now I'm in my late 30s so I
mean I spent my whole life basically
making hash with my family and now I'm
the the senior hash
maker and they just had a familiarity
and comfort with the product that was
refreshing because what we've done is
we've become so obsessed with this
Perfection that it to me it's bougie
where you know every detail has to be
just right or it can't cross your lips
and you know and majority smoked in
Pakistan is being smoked in
tobacco wrapped around a cigarette or
inside a cigarette and people will like
oh God they need an education and a
lesson I'm like no that's that's how
they consume it it's their world and
it's not right or wrong it's just our
perspective but I would love to have had
you know someone like s come back to the
US and go to a hash operation and watch
them make cash in this in this new world
and then have all those hash makers go
back to Pakistan and work dryft Tech
with them because they're having to do
it with far less resources and so the
the art is greater than the science
where in our world the science is
becoming greater than the art
and you have to meld both of them for
incredible
they they a great scientist is an artist
and a great artist is a scientist it
it's just that where the focus lie but
you can't separate the two of them
completely art by itself has no end and
Science by itself has no Direction so
when you could put them together you
form like some incredible stuff that's
that's Da Vinci Da Vinci was Art and
Science
merged so to me you know when you when
you look at it from that perspective
it's always it's always a a neat way to
look at things because you don't get
comparative with like our product's
better our product their product was
incredible because they could do dry
sift that was shelf stable that was
absolutely
aromatic and Rich full flavors they off
gas it in the cold for months before
they make the hash so they get rid of
the profiles that we love most In
America which is gas they don't like it
because they think that it gives you a
hangover the next day and make Su grogi
so they off gas the gas and it Reveals
All these subtle fruits and florals that
I hadn't experienced in dry sift hash it
was really
interesting but it it fits their world
they don't want to be too [ __ ] up
because you're walking on the side of a
mountain yeah fair point until you're
until you're in Pakistan you realize
you're not on a lot of flat ground some
of that [ __ ] was I mean we were climbing
up these things I was like oh you got to
be kidding me and then these kids come
running by us like goats and it made me
feel like I was 90 instead of 60 because
the kids are laughing just skipping down
and it just helps you understand well
what they want is they want the benefits
of the Cannabis they consume but they
want to be able to control it in a way
that fits their reality and it was
beautiful to see because man you have
you know you got 500 grams a Kil aash to
smoke and then every village we went we
got hook up with somebody that hash
Friends of the team would meet us at
certain locations and they would show up
with hash we got to hang out with a dude
that was a minor he owned a mineral
company and he had just got back from
Morocco and so he brought a brick of
Moroccan hash with him that he just hand
carried over so we're grinding up
Moroccan hash and filling joints and
we're wrapping them with snakes of trra
valy Pakistan hash it was like a hash
morgage boy I I mean I smoked a lot of
hash in my life but I don't know if I
was ever consciously trying to smoke
myself through you know 500 grams over a
3 we period because that's a lot of
smoke undeniably that's a lot of smoke
that's that's incredibly impressive and
and you know a beautiful
Story the next question I wanted to ask
you was what sort of plants do you think
would cross well with some of the seeds
you got on the Pakistani trip you know
like do you think like just as a general
thing like OG cross to some of the
plants might be a cool combination or
does anything jump to mind in that
respect
you know it's interesting I did I I
started messing around with the Afghan
work that I got from gazy and they're
they're they're not similar Gene pools
but similar
regions and I started messing around
with the males that I was pulling out
and I laid them into everything I had
just so I could see the influence on it
and some of them lined up better than
others it was funny but the the the
disgusting sulfur that I was working
with
they didn't bring that same heat to the
ogs and I went through a bunch of
different plants but the Cherry Pie took
the took the profile
incredibly so it was kind of shocking
because I didn't expect
that sulfur to be minimized by the gas
of the ogs and the sour and the chems
and I mean I I went through a plethora
of them but it was the Cherry Pie that
turned out to be the most disgusting
powerful rosin i've smoked in the last
couple years I mean it was almost scary
high like you know
sometimes it's funny but sometimes the
shit's just uncomfortable where you just
like whoa you want to come down because
you are just fired up
so I think that's truthfully that's
where I would start I would take
that that plant and I would go into the
Cherry Pie and I would also look for the
same male that I chose in that to go
into the select red Leb Puck because if
I could add more complexity to that it'd
be
unbelievable and so and both of those
are similar like red lab Puck I mean I'm
fascinated by it because it has a
profile that everyone in my house had to
listen to me to talk about this [ __ ] for
a year but when they got to smoke it
they were like whoa I got you I can see
why you're so obsessed with it
and it has a really similar like cherry
pie type bite cherry pie is mouthy it it
cherry pie Done Right is incredible and
it makes a superior hash the flavor
profile is just ridiculous and I just
happened I get the old original cut and
so the cut that I have Jackson he has an
S1 of it he found a seed in a bag that
he uses in all of his work that's all
his Cherry work that's louder than the
Cherry Pie mother but I like the base
cherry pie it it's it's just such a
perfect plant for where I live and my
family loves to smoke and I just love
the flavor and for whatever reason it
takes male pollen and does some
interesting [ __ ] with it I can see why
it's woven into so many other plants I
can see why cherry pie is you know
that's your you're
into billions and billions and billions
of dollars of herb is sold every year
that have cherry pie in its
lineage so I would go there first and
and and mostly because I'm not looking
like if I wanted to do something cool I
could go into that's polar opposite and
say okay I'm on the 34 latitude and I'm
in a I'm in a heavy chemical let me go
down to like the you know the zero
latitude let me go into heavy floral
which would put me into like an African
or it's a shame Australia doesn't have
any true land race because your your
latitudes in the zeros too but um that
sent me into Africa that sent me into uh
if I go up a little bit higher like 13
I'm in the the the bottom of Mexico that
puts us into like Thailand any of those
things would cross really well which is
really the original hybrids that took
over North America was they were taking
things that were distinctly unrelated
and putting them together and doing big
population work to find the parents so
you know there's nothing original about
that it's you you and and that's not a a
derogatory comment you don't need to
reinvent the wheel every time you wake
up in the morning sometimes it's nice to
say okay they took that and that and put
it together and came out with some
incredible [ __ ] maybe I do that but what
I wanted to see more than that was I
wanted to see it in a chassis that was
workable for my area so that I was
already bringing
the the the chances of success into a
tighter realm of possible and if I was
to want to mess around with something at
today I would take that Oreo cut that's
basically bulletproof moldproof grows
like a weed I mean couldn't be a better
chassis as a plant and throw that
profile on it but you know I'd have to
go through enough of them to find it but
if you could put two together being A+
just like the Cherry Pie only only
problem with the Cherry Pie is it's got
a little bit of mold prone it doesn't
like the moisture at the end of the
cycle it's a it's a per perss don't like
moisture at the end of the cycle either
so if I had to say there was one thing I
didn't like about the plan is that it uh
and I'm glad it finishes early because
if it went late you wouldn't have it
yeah what a comprehensive answer I love
it that cherry pie hybrid sounds
incredible and I myself big massive fan
of the Cherry Pie I think it's one of
the best strains out there so that's
awesome to hear that it lined up like
that and as an extension of the last
question you know I wanted to ask you
when when when we talk about land race
genetics in general everyone generally
speaking except like afghanis and ties
like there's some real fire in there but
I wanted to ask you what are some of the
other land race or Old World genetics
that you think are really under
represented that might have something to
offer and the reason why I bring this up
is cu I noticed you'd put a post up
about doing a Cambodian after too and it
sort of got my brain juices
stimulated that's a killer one too you
you know was was was cool was like what
made it good for me was that growing up
as a kid I got to see a lot of herb
coming in from around the world and then
when I left the Rhode Island and went in
the military I lived in Hawaii in the
mid 80s and Hawaii was just a hot bed of
the nastiest weed and then we were
raiding all kinds of boats out at Sea so
I got to see all the herb coming in from
Asia too but all all like original Jean
stock so it it just left this incredible
print in my mind of profiles and impacts
and it's my it's my
foundation and so I I spent years after
that you know chasing different
directions and so when I started hanging
out with the Mexican cats I'm like hey
bring me seeds from the grows you guys
are doing in Mexico because I was moving
the weed let me get some of the good
seed you're screwing with and then I
would grow them indoor so that would be
able to experience what it was like to
grow these profiles and then as time
goes on I get to travel the world and
look at
stuff and what what really helped me
most more than anything recently was I
got to go to Jamaica and I went out
there with the the the piff crew which
was uh Joe the hard way and white boy
Kev out in New York they're like the
original piff Hayes guys and so we were
we were going to do this project in in
Massachusetts with the group Community
Gardens and I came up with the idea that
we ought to go to Jamaica to go take a
look at a project that's going on out
there which was this preservation
project of this guy's lifetime of
collecting land race jeans and since it
was in Jamaica you get to see like a
true representation of it in an
equatorial
climate and where he is in Spanish Town
is the driest part of the Caribbean so
it gives you a really interesting
ability to do fuel like varieties in
addition so I got to see some crazy
hybrids from jeans I had provided him
that he got to weave in with some of his
work so me Kev and Joe fly out to Scott
family farms in
Jamaica and we spend the next week out
there really looking at the the breeding
projects and looking at the varieties
and it was just epic because it let me
take a look at the Colombian collections
it let me take a look at the Mexican
collections the the green apple um aapo
Golds where like two puffs into it it
literally lit up like a green sour apple
candy in your mouth the zakataka purples
that are just Ultra perfumey and pungent
and I had really never played the zakat
takus and I hadn't had aapos that had
fruit flavors either really so it was
like directions I hadn't
explored we got into the he had the the
mullby madness which is really a
tie and so some of the tie lines were
epic he had a beautiful collection of
Lous work and Kim Cambodian work that he
acquired while he was in Cambodian LA
and I had already gone through a
population of his Cambodian three line
crossed into a C5 and actually I have
some hanging in my garage right now it
just came down a little while ago
because it could make it through the
rain and so I have probably a couple
pounds of that that I'm gonna trim up
and then have some really killer C5
Hayes Cambodian 3 for the rest of the
season oh yeah it's nasty man I I was
able to break a little Branch off maybe
like two weeks early so that I could
just dry it and have it to smoke so I
could just like let me because I grew it
before but I just let me let me let me
puff on this [ __ ] and man it was such a
searing clear clean High just beautiful
if you like a good beautiful like
electric High that's not racy or edgy
but just total Clarity and energy in a
in a controlled way that stuff is money
I really liked the Lae hybrids too they
brought some really interesting lemon
profiles and the high was ripping
um I I messed around with some zamal
when I was younger but they were always
hybrids and they they were kind of
always hybridized with things that took
the zamal edge
off and I got to mess around with some
real zamal that he had that was same
thing we call him carrot weed when I was
young so had that carrot flavor but holy
[ __ ] that that high was cracking he was
able to
take some of the I want to say he took
like some of the LA or some of the Cambo
and then went into a black lime Reserve
so I had some of the original black lime
Reserve seeds put away in the original
box and I sent them to him you know a
year or so to back to play with and I
got to see some of that woven in so you
started to see some of the fuel and the
limes brought in with some of the
Tropicals he had a a bunch of different
Congo work that he had done so the red
Congos and so you got to experience some
of that bitey
sharp conal work he had done um a
collection called skunk by scratch where
he went to the three different locations
where skunk is supposed to come from
which was
Afghanistan
Mexico and Colombia and in those regions
brought back the genes from those
regions and he recreated his own skunk
one but from his own source collection
and that was really interesting too
because what he had gathered was choice
and you got to see some different edges
to the profile because it wasn't in your
typical skunk Jean Pool just from same
regions so at the end of the day man
what you got to do is you got to go
through as much herb as you can find and
kind of find what you like and what
works for you and you know and for me
what I always try to find is is things
that that I'll do a couple runs indoor
personally for Smoke on [ __ ] that
doesn't like being outside like my La
cush if we have a wet fall it doesn't
like it so if I'm in a drier hotter clim
it kills it or the year happens to be
coincidentally D than normal but
otherwise I run it indoor I run it bio
indoor and I I I get that product that I
want but from that method but everything
else I sift for myself for personal use
is is sifted for my yard I sifted for my
my personal growth and that's why I know
some of the things that are sorted
that's why I like the Mexican work
better and I think that the Mexican
lines are completely un uncredited I
think that I think the Mexicans in
General get [ __ ] they it's almost like
they they didn't contribute to the
industry and really I mean they were
absolutely flood in America for years
and the quality of the products coming
out mishan and ohaw and the zakat takus
and aapos and just stunning stunning
work and it works in our environment and
so I think in a perfect world you know
you'd see a lot more of the Mexican work
being moved into the system for
California
cultivation and you'd see you know the
the the Colombians the stuff coming out
of zamal uh the ties being grown in
glass houses down in like Central and
Southern California where they could
have that bomb your environment because
our cold gets too cold and the plants
don't like it so they don't like the
cold they can handle they can handle the
moisture they can't handle the cold
so I think that you know is is you you
define where you want to grow and then
you go chase those Gene pools that work
for you in that regard
wow what an awesome answer you uh you
you read my mind and touched on the the
Jamaican trip I was going to ask you
about because I noticed you were as you
mentioned the Scott family farms AKA
reefa man what a what a blast from the
past to to see him pop up down there
what's what's the end goal of the the
project he's doing there is it to to be
able to offer some seed stock or is he
growing
herb no he was he was down there you
know Charles in the same situation
everybody's in man you're you're you're
working in cannabis for your whole
career and you get involved in any large
operation it turns into a freak Show and
I think that um he had some bad
circumstances and he settled there and
what he was trying to do was use this
incredible location that Spanish Town
location was phenomenal you it's funny
Kingston is like the that's the irony of
the world Kingston is considered like a
really rough area and Spanish Town is
considered the roughest area of Kingston
and it was still was safer and cleaner
than San Francisco so everybody always
laugh I'm like I'm from California you
know I don't think you understand
California's a mess um but the climate
was
ideal and it allowed him to be able to
work a tremendous amount of work and
what he was trying to do is basically
you know do his
2023 release and start to hand over the
business to his
kids and he and I knew each other I've
never met Charles in person till that
day I showed up we just knew each other
on line because we're both in the genan
game and we had chatted a bunch of times
and when I was talking to the team at
Community Gardens Stephen Doug and we
were talking about working together on a
project I said hey if we got the haze
guys with us it would be incredible to
just jump to Jamaica and go spend a week
with Charles and go look at all the
foundations of the things that really
created the plant that they worked with
solely for 20
years and it would and it's for me I
like I love working with other people
and getting to see their experiences and
understand how they view a thing and so
I said hey I don't and I didn't know
them either we were all we all just met
on a zoom for a business conference call
but I I was talking to Charles I knew
the project was going on I'm on the the
computer screen with the two lamarina
boys and I'm like whoa wait a minute I
know this is going to sound crazy but
the three of us should go to Jamaica and
go look at the products and get
ourselves
educated on the diversity of all these
lines at the same time next to each
other that was the thing is that I've
seen these plants over the course of my
life never in the same room at the same
time all growing side by side it was
like what you what I think made me
understand OG well is that I probably
had 15 different ogs and I used to run
them all side by side so there was no
question they were not the same but
everyone was an OG and it allowed me to
say why is this OG better than this one
or or why is this one sold for more
money than this one or why is this one
more popular with this group why is this
one so successful here because I had
them all and I ran them all next to each
other when you're running them
independently you only see that thing
but when you put them all in the same
room at the same
time and you're segregating the
population so you can pay attention and
then you're recording it you can really
make some pretty
good opinions
and so to go see all this plant material
that he had collected his whole life
from around the world and get to hang
with them and listen to him tell you why
he had collected it why he had worked it
and where he got to this point it let
all of us
see a part of the industry that we're
not involved in and also for him to see
parts of the industry he's not involved
in and it allowed for the California and
the New York group to you know I mean
I'm from New England I'm a RH Islander
but I spent you know [ __ ] 30 35 years in
California so basically California is
where I've spent majority of my life
that's where I know the industry best so
that background in California lets me
talk to New York and New York since
they've been there their whole lives
they could say the same thing and we can
really start to understand what are the
differences and the similarities in
consumptive patterns desires cultivation
like all the little details that just
you need to understand so that you're
able to Pivot intelligently when you
need to there you go over the years you
know a lot of people do find reeferman
to be a bit of a polarizing guy and some
people have said that oh he never [ __ ]
my seeds things like that I'm I'm sure
you heard from some people they might
not have been stoked about your recent
trip what would you say to someone who
was critical of you know the trip to
visit the
farm you know
the I I only knew Charles online
and he and I met online and neither one
of us actually knew who the other one
was like he I didn't realize I was
talking to reefa man he didn't realize
that who I was and so we we meet through
a a friend talking about jeans and when
we realized who each other was It was
kind of fun because it allowed him to
have somebody that uh was a weed freak
that he could kind of share his weed
freak [ __ ] with so I get to enjoy him as
a as a as a person in that regard and
then I start to find out you know all
this backstory of um you know I'm say
want to say like white supremacy and so
I was like holy [ __ ] man you got a
wicked backstory
but the whole time I'm speaking to him
online everything was good and never
once did I get any kind of feel that he
was uh that kind of dude and when I when
I see the problems with business I
realize that people have issues and the
issue with cannabis is that the whole
industry is so [ __ ] up that I don't
see a single company that doesn't have
about 50 different I hate you because
something unhappy so I didn't really
know how to take it and so when we went
out there and hung
out he explained he goes hey I was from
like a white supremist background I was
raised rightwing as a kid and he goes I
you know I got into Buddhism I'm trying
to be a better guy and what made me
believe it was that I spent that week
with his family right his kids and his
two daughters were the two nicest girls
he could have been around I mean like
balanced he got three daughters but the
two of them I met two of them and they
couldn't have been any nicer and and U
genuine and one of them had a a Jamaican
boyfriend so if if living in the house
so if you're a white supremist you're
you're definitely not allowing your
daughter to have a a Jamaican living in
your home and the way they all got
along was really pretty beautiful and I
just realized that you know as nutty as
you background may be and as crazy as
life may be you can't have two daughters
that nice that are still sticking with
you for
years if you're if you're that [ __ ] up
and so it just let me see a piece of
them that was solid and that's the piece
I focused on because there's there's you
know Decades of people saying great
things about Charles and then there's
decades once I started digging in I said
holy [ __ ] you polarize people incredibly
but the end of the day it's it's a a
tossup between I love you and I hate you
so the only thing I can do in that kind
of circumstance and I try to do in
general is just what are we there for
we're there to be explore your crop
you're being gracious enough to let us
explore it and in the
process I'll be able to talk about the
trip and get some attention onto the
lamarina boys so their story gets
covered and the story about them
exploring the the the the the the work
and it brings attention to
community and it seemed like a win-win
for all and I would say that some of the
blowback on it was like you know do you
know who he is he [ __ ] me on some
seeds or he has a past history but you
know I'd say probably 80% of the
comments were really pretty positive
maybe even 85 out of a 100 and in
general Chet had a good run but you're
in cannabis long enough and you try to
go legal the minute you get into legal
cannabis abis you lose control over what
you're doing and people are so erratic
in legal cannabis that holy [ __ ] if your
name's connected to it man you better be
careful so Charles was nice to us while
we were there and he absolutely is a
weed freak beyond belief man he
absolutely loves breeding dope there's
no question about that and his memory of
the work was phenomenal so it allowed us
to go toward the past with them
and so I don't have any bad memories of
the trip and I don't have a bad vibe
from him you know we haven't spoken in a
minute he was having some health issues
and so once people start to struggle and
stuff I just give you some
space and he was he was having some
health issues of you know just personal
[ __ ] but all in all man Charles was
gracious and his daughters were really
friendly and the trip was good it was
just a really positive trip you know and
so I same thing with Pakistan everyone's
like well what about the Afghan refugee
what about the women and I'm like okay I
live in California what about our
refugees what about our homeless what
about our violence I saidan what am I
supposed to do tell everybody else how
to live when we can't get our own [ __ ]
straight so like how am I supposed
to fix these problems and people like
well you know you're not addressing it
I'm like how am I supposed to address it
I'm being brought in to look at jeans I
got brought into the Middle East to look
at a project everyone's like but what
did you do when you're there for the
peace and I'm like what the [ __ ] would
you like me to do that that's not my
expertise you know how I do peace I I
try not to cause anybody any problems
that I don't hit you in the head with a
[ __ ] Hammer when I'm angry at
you so there's there's only so much you
can do right and the the main thing is
you try to be as decent as you can and
if people are totally out of [ __ ]
control then you can't be around them so
like there's projects that I have to
turn down because I'm like
yo you you you burned too many people
and I know it so I can't work with you
man you just you get a bad history bro
it's just like you're nice to me we get
along good everything's great but like
my man you lit everybody around you on
fire I can't play with you but in this
case you know I wasn't doing business
with Charles we were really wanting to
explore these Gene worlds that he was
digging into so that we were able to
come back into the New England area and
bring that flavor with us courtesy of
the Larina boys because they're mythical
New York figures in the haze in the haze
crowd yeah it's great great to hear your
answer there you know I definitely can
resonate with love me hate me got to
pick one and choosing love seems like
better option to me so I can certainly
appreciate that and it's good to hear
you're able to you know give a bit of
props to the lamarina boys so you know
some positive can come out of it I
wanted to to Pivot for a moment and ask
you about something different which was
I wanted to talk about autos for a
second because uh when we when we had
Sean from flying line research on the
show a little a little while back you
dropped a comment talking about how you
know Sean had given you some seeds when
you saw him at one of the conventions
recently I was wondering what's your
thoughts on Autos you know do you think
they're going to play a role in the
future what's your experiences being
growing them
out Autos are definitely going to play a
role in the future because they they
allow they allow you a couple things it
seems like um Autos are tougher the the
issue with Autos is that they're
sensitive root system so if your soil
temperature isn't at at par they they
halt so you have to have warm enough
soil which is you know so most people
aren't measuring their soil temp right
so they're not putting a thermometer
into the soil of the of the garden
saying what is my Surface Temp and if
that's not right you can't
plant and if you transplant and you
shock them you screw it up too but if
you see an auto put in correctly oh it's
an incredible plant because the the the
Vigor genes have been basically stroked
so what they have is this explosive
growth profile in a very rapid period
and they'll fill the world with the the
products you need for like lower qual at
some point I'm sure they're going to
nail an auto that can compete with
anything smoke wise but to me Autos are
the things you use to fill your your
edible markets anything that you're
going to use as a concentrate that
doesn't require epicurian traits I would
get it from my autos and I know that if
you're doing fields of Autos correctly
they're very cost effective and it
allows you to get your good b-grade
products to the market at a good fair
price so remember most people are buying
everybody wants a Ferrari most people
are buying a Toyota or Honda right and
there's no shame in that I mean they
make great cars it's just that your
budget dictates it I have this View and
people you know they get angry about it
but it's there's only two customers to
me two I don't nothing else matters
except this one thing if it's if it's a
customer if it's someone if it's a
patient million different variations
customer that they're coming to buy
something that's the definition right
there's only two that exist those that
buy what they want and those that buy
what they can
afford so those that buy what they want
the conversation is radically different
than those that buy what they can afford
and I make sure that I try to service
both of them but 85 90% of the effort is
going to go towards those that body what
they can afford because that's 80 to 90%
of the
population the other 15 10 to 15% is
they buy what they want that's your
epicurian upper scale group and so
everybody wants to serve them only
because they believe that's where all
the success in life is but the problem
is they're not always buying a lot of
weed cocaine champagne [ __ ] like that
they're on but when it comes to Herb
they're not herb is a bluecollar drug
more than anything
and when you when you talk about about
this stuff you have to make sure to me
you always have to have that customer in
mind that at the end of the day what we
want what who cares what what matters is
what does the customer want the customer
would like to have cheaper pot and if
they could grow it using technology that
allows them to get it that's excellent
because at the end of the day that's a
fair market if if we're talking a market
economy the the things that are required
are you can enter and exit it will and
you're there to serve your own best
interest so as soon as we start to put
limits on that by saying oh no no that's
not fair to us the small farmer we need
to create this special situation where
they don't get to do
that that's not a that's not a fair
market and so you're asking for
concessions and considerations there's
no difference than if I said I wanted to
be a monopoly because that's also not a
fair market so to me what we have to
address is where does the majority of
people get weed they're going to get it
from easy to grow commercial sources and
where does that leave the small operator
to work on epicurian Lane but what I
know from the you know the auto work is
that it's only a couple genes that
control it and so you're going to able
you're going to be able to see
incredible profiles being brought out
and they even have ways to create
semi-autos where they're just
accelerated in their flowering cycle and
there's something to do with the Vigor
Gene that seems to dra along with it and
I'm not a geneticist so sometimes when I
talk about this I get geneticists
jumping up and down screaming at me
online but I'm not a geneticist I just
work with the geneticist I just help
them choose the traits that sell I help
them say these are the things I want as
a grower and I never want
that and then they're able to say okay
then I ask them so what do we do and
they go oh what we have is U multiple
Gene interactions that make this happen
and if we're able to trigger these
things and and and and place them within
other plants then what we have is an
ability to make any plant do this and so
what I know is that our future will be
extremely technologically advanced in
how we grow
cannabis and I just know that it's
inevitability that there there there is
that it will happen and it's it's when
it takes place you know through the
entire state of Nebraska it's when you
are cultivating you know 10,000 Hector
in
Australia it's when you're doing you
know six million acre in in Colombia
because you're providing 40% of the
Earth with its extract which is what is
going to
happen that's that's where it's all
going to take place and that's how it's
going to
happen but it's it's it's just the
inevitability you what happens right now
is everybody's lumped in the same group
it's just pot you have to have
commercial or you can't have craft their
comparative terms their opposite sides
of the same piece of paper so so without
one you can't have the other you can't
have one side of paper because paper has
two sides so we have to have commercial
in order for people to say you know what
I want craft and for people who smoke
craft they're like hey I love smoking
craft but I got to go to a party and I'm
G to go smoke with a bunch of people
that don't appreciate it let me just go
let me go back grab some Auto pre-rolls
because it's the same with liquor after
the first two drinks the best thing you
can do is drink drink cheap boo because
you're not going to know the difference
so you drinking $200 whiskey and now you
drinking $20
whiskey yeah no hugely you know I was
thinking about that the other night
myself just with uh some wine I was
going to take with me you know you're
100% right soon enough there'll be
fields of gelato 41 autos and you you'll
barely be able to tell the difference
and you know could be a good thing for a
lot of
reasons I just wanted to quickly loop
back you'd mentioned some um uh zamal
strains a little earlier in the answer I
saw on your Instagram you posted some
photos of some Reunion Island Seeds did
you end up growing those out was there
anything cool in there no I didn't I
just stashed them because uh those were
from like 24 week open
populations and I just I I received them
and then I just banked them because I
was just do I really like I went through
this phase where I I went on this Haze
phase Right Where I Was Haze obsessed
and you know I spent a lot of time and a
lot of space digging through deep cycle
populations and you really really have
to want to do that [ __ ] I mean you it's
it's not casual like you really you
can't [ __ ] up at all you you're
basically you're you're dealing with it
they they they don't like any nutrition
so they they work off of the bare
minimum and if you if you mess up at all
you'll curl these things
up and if you're not able to like really
bring the light down heavily over time
and maintain the intensity they don't
finish so it's really hard to control a
plant that wants to be 20 foot indoor so
you're chopping it back and I mean try
do this with a building right so I mean
I went on this I did I dove I went into
it and I was looking for the for the
Holy Grail of the hazes because I'd
smoked so much Colombian growing up that
I was like I know Colombian and I was
looking for all these and and really you
know that that's the thing is is hay
Thai or hay Colombian depends who you
talk to but no matter what
they require an incredible amount of
effort
indoor if they haven't been like a
worked population and what you find is
that a lot of the stuff that we consume
coming from the you know the seed
banks the parental selection is poor and
so you're having to go through you know
I went through we're talking like you
know year and a half of digging through
populations which is 140 days so I can
get you know
basically two two and a quarter run runs
in so in a two-year period you get five
runs
in brutal right so five versus 12 is a
radically different uh amount but I had
my home garage sparked up and I and it
was tall so I was able to do it all in
the garage and work it but I went
through population after population I
wasn't really that impressed with a lot
of it because what it let me understand
was the parental selection had been done
poorly and when I was talking to Charles
me and him were rapping about it and he
said the same thing that when he did his
initial selection he
said it had got so spread out that he
had to go through almost at the time he
had you know huge resources spatially he
said he had to go through over 700 to
find the parental stock that he wanted
and then what it did is allowed him to
get selection down to like 10 to 15 so
now you could go through 10 to 15 seeds
and find something that was epic but for
me I noticed the same thing I had amass
this collection of these equatorial from
all these different companies and I went
on this crusade to find the fire and
what I found was okay and okay doesn't
justify 140 days and so the thing with
the zamal was it was a great gift from
someone who went to
zamal and I wish I had got those seeds
before I went on that Colombian or that
tie dig because I would be
braver but once you realize it's going
to be you know 24 weeks you're looking
at you know 160 days of
flowering and even if you bring it down
to like you know know 1014 you're still
in the
120s you really and what am I
getting and so sometimes you know I just
like I as I get older I said okay how
about we don't hunt them here how about
we hunt those in Colombia how about we
go hunt these
varieties in their land of origin where
they just grow and then we select the
phenotype from that population versus
let me do it in Doran California
because it was just it's just
impractical 90 days is reasonable 90
days is good you know
like and a lot of plants really that we
pick at nine should really go into that
that 11 12 week period but 90s good if
you can get something to finish in the
90 range that's Stellar that's
reasonable but once we get past that
there's got to be some exceptional
reason why not just because it's
different different different's
different but exceptional that's
something where like it's wor you just
straight up know it's worth your time to
do
it most certainly and while we're on the
topic of exceptional I'm sure you've had
a plethora of memorable weed come across
the desk at the nursery over the years
can you recall one or two that jumped to
mind is extremely unique or
memorable over the last 20 years what we
did is we destroyed the gene population
and we just basically went you know we
went right into per then we go right
into Kush then we went right into cookie
then we went right into candy gas and
they were all interesting in their own
regard but
like they they didn't stand out what
stood out was like a a Mexican that I
grew that was identical to smoking a
Newport cigarette where if you if you
mess around with Menthol it was menthol
cigarette it was
insane I had I had some seeds that I got
from an old dude in in soam when I got
here like in the
90s and there was and I man I missed
that plant but one of them
was when it when it burned in the joint
it burned so oily it looked like you had
lit a tire up and when you smoked it it
was so devastatingly strong it knocked
me out and put me on the couch and I
woke up and my my my girlfriend was
wiping my face with the wet rag because
she thought I was Ill or something she
goes oh you're moaning and you're
shaking I'm ing your face I was crack I
said no I'm just really high like this
stuff was Next Level power and so that
like it just stood out because nothing
had that type of nail you to the- wall
potency just to a degree that was
frightening the rosin that I made off of
that Afghan cherry pie was absolutely
unique I took it to a breeders meeting
with a lot of really well-known people
and turn them yellow I mean they they
were just shaken from the potency of it
and the flavor was excellent it had that
really disgusting cheese likee aroma so
high in methyl butc acid and heavy heavy
sulfur so the mouth was really
interesting but the potency was
crippling um I had a skunk that kind of
reminded me of a sour diesel in the way
it
stacked but it was the most noxious piss
skunk in the world and I got it from a
friend of mine Brian and his buddy his
his buddy's dad was the head of the drug
task force in the
triangle and the dad brought home a
plant to the son and said out of all the
years we've been raiding weed this is
the best weed I've ever seen and I stole
a plant for you and gave it to his son
and then the son shares it with Brian
and then Brian shares it with me and
that [ __ ] was Supernatural and it that's
the one plant that I lost in a raid that
I of all plants I've ever lost in raids
or boss or any of that [ __ ] that's the
one I miss the most because
it was so exceptional in the mouth the
nose the weight the resistance every
single part of the plant looked like a
marble but connected in a tightly dense
cluster so you almost had no leaves on
it whatsoever and when you broke it
apart each piece got beautiful Sun so
the coloration was consistent throughout
and it it had an odor that was so loud
that when I opened up the car door at
the football game I was at the Oakland
Raiders the door opened up the smell
blew out it blew through the parking lot
hundreds of yards two cops turned their
heads and ran at the car and arrested me
and I mean they were like out of view
when I opened the door I mean I'm
talking like hund like football field
away that there was nothing that was
more volatile than that
[ __ ] so you know and the the one that I
saw in in Pakistan was exceptional I
think the the zakat takus uh work that
Charles had
in Jamaica was exceptional what an
incredible odor like just absolutely
pungent stunning
unique so I think that you know when
you're talking about really exceptional
standouts
they they don't fit into any category of
today and I don't mean like categories
of perception that I I lay them out as
but they
don't they're
they're they're just not present we're
not working with those extreme ends of
the gene pool right now we're working
with really more consistent
populations safe and distribution
doesn't like Risk so distribution
doesn't favor plants that are outliers
they want things that this is what the
market wants and so it it it discourages
in Ingenuity and discovers Innovation
and it
inhibits your your creativity so you
don't explore the weird edges and
uh what else is some sexy [ __ ] I I
really like the the Pam Anderson work
from Tyler family trees some of his pam
pam Anderson is this this line that he
picked up in La you know decades ago and
he named it after Pam Anderson the the
actress but that stuff is some sweat and
Deuce and cheese everything's like a
dirty sock and a funky bag of cheese but
it puts a mouth on it that's just
absolutely stupendous with a ripping
high so I love all the the the the Pam
work that he's done and he shared it
with Nick risden risden um opened up
those
populations and put into a bunch of
stuff so to me that's pretty
unique
um what else is really really unique
that just stands out that doesn't taste
like anything
else there was a cheese out of uh
Michigan um I'm trying I don't remember
the Paisley Farms did it but it was a
rosin I can't remember who bred it but
it was so indistinguishable from like um
parmesan cheese that I I had my girl
close her eyes and I held the parmesan
cheese up and the rosin and I went back
and forth and she couldn't tell the
difference
wow yeah like I mean it was that level
so I mean that really stood
out what really caught me recently too
um [ __ ] that's really all the weird
standouts you know like you always
remember the first time you smoke OG you
know I I I love La pure Kush that cut I
have I think that that can stand next to
any
herb like period it's got such a mouth
on it such a it's such a a complete
flavor all the way to the
roach and there's no everybody I shared
the plant with like the crew I roll with
everyone that got a got a cut of it like
that's their go-to smoke because no
matter what they're going to get that
effect they want from it and so I still
get little text messages and messages
saying man I love you bro for giving me
that plant I gave it to him [ __ ] for
evero they just let I'm laughing I'm
like oh you high as [ __ ] right
now and so you know like it's stuff like
that that there's just these little
things that just differentiate it from
the norm and it doesn't have to be a lot
it just has to be a point or two
different but different enough to where
it just sticks in your
mind yeah 100% I I could definitely
relate there certain ones that just
leave such a lasting memory for you we
normally ask this question sort of at
the start of the episode but we're going
to switch it up today we're going to ask
it basically at the end what was your
first experience with
cannabis oh
[ __ ] that's a good one my my
neighborhood was a crime zone right and
my my one of my buddies dad was a
crooked cop and so he was always robbing
all the people he was arresting and so
when you went to his house and you went
into his dad's room when he was at work
there was all kinds of stolen goods on
his bureau and guns and knives and [ __ ]
he was collecting from people and drugs
and so my buddy Kenny had access to to
the herb the old man was jacking from
people and so this would have been
between the summer of uh sixth grade and
seventh grade so I was 12 and so I'm
seeing some of my older friends that
tell me man I've been smoking weed I'm
like oh I want to try some weed and so
Kenny's like man I'm gonna go to my
dad's room and score some weed so he
scores some weed and he scores a pipe
too one of these big old like Sherlocks
but all made out of metal Parts all like
you Plumbing fixtures and [ __ ] right the
old school pipes from the 70s because
this would have been
78 and we went up on the roof of my
house and we were chilling and we light
it up and as I'm puffing it a seed
explodes and takes off in the air just
as this cop car drives by my home and we
were all sitting there laughing like did
he see it did he see it but no no he's
gonna see a a a a seed pop but you were
so
self-conscious that you were smoking
weed and that there was police nearby
and I got a little bit of a buzz from it
but the next maybe a day or two later he
came by again and this time we took my
garage I had a big garage and we hung a
strobe light up on the ceiling of it and
we all got our bicycles in there and
turn the lights off and turn the strobes
on and we smoked and we were doing kind
of like cage of death riding you know
zooming by each other and I'll never
forget that [ __ ] because that's when I
was high and so I was just like
whoa and it it just kind of went from
there there was so much herb around
because all the people that I was around
were all involved in crime so there was
never a shortage of
grass and soon you know you get into the
game a little bit and you start meeting
the people that are trafficking it and
they're helping you kind of get an
education on what you're looking at
where they're like not just selling you
weed they're like you're getting to
touch the bail and they're helping you
understand yeah this Colombia is pretty
good but we usually get something in
later in the season that's better and
I'm like no way and they're like yeah
when that comes in I'll buy your house
and grab you so make sure you stash some
money so that when it comes time you can
score the really good weed and so these
dealers would help me understand batch
quality and when really good [ __ ] popped
out they would combine and grab me and
then I'd get to see what like they
considered premium Thai or premium
Colombian or premium Lebanese hash or
premium iraan hash or premium Afghani
hash and I just got this killer
education and that was all you know
prior to 83 83 is when I caught my first
you know case so from 78 to 83 that
5year period was this incredible
education so from 12 to you know
basically like 12 to
17 I was I was getting a a fantastic
education in the diversity herb and
still getting really high too you know
when you're a kid then man you're just
getting
lit oh my God so jealous that sounds
like an awesome introductory into a
lifelong passion how did it sort of
evolved from there to say when you had
your first grow um I I started growing
in 80 so we started smoking 78 we get
into a little bit I have a neighbor I
was a brown thumb so that's why I always
tell people that you can you can you can
learn to be a good cultivator when you
learn to listen to the
plants and I didn't have a background in
in listening to the plants and my friend
was just more intuitive so my buddy
bounce uh took on the growing end of it
and I had a location in my grandmother's
yard that we could grow in and they
didn't know it but in the backyard there
was there was a spot where no one knew
that I and I could hide plants and so we
used to stash the plants there and grow
them in my grandmother's
yard and it was just awesome because
everything I touched I was killing but I
could help Gary and Gary was uh gentle
with the plants and so I started to
develop a a micro skill and I said well
[ __ ] I might as well spark up big and so
I filled the whole yard o of my my real
house in 83 and got caught by the cops
and got dragged out of high school in
handcuffs and so I don't grow again
until 89 when I get out of the military
and so the day I get out of the service
in in the in uniform using the
government vehicle I picked up all my
grow lights in Berkeley and sparked up
in 89 I lived in Oakland but the grow
star was in Berkeley Berkeley and
Gardens and I sparked up and I never
stopped so you know the first
cultivation you know was 80 uh three
years of growing and then two years of
not
growing and then into the military where
I was around weed constantly and smoked
and we were [ __ ] I was in the Coast
Guard we were raiding drugs everywhere
so I was looking at as much herb as
anybody on planet Earth and living in
Hawaii exposed me and you know it's
funny you go in the service trying to be
you know like I'm gonna be good I'm not
gonna get in trouble soon as I get to
the island I hook up with cats that are
smoking fire and next thing I know I'm
smoking with them and I'm like holy [ __ ]
I can't stop and I was loving it because
the Hawai was just phenomenal and then I
moved to San Francisco in you know in in
the late 80s and I'm in the Bay Area and
it's a it's a schoras board of weed too
and so like no matter where I go I'm
swimming in weed and there was a story
that really prompted me to go back into
it professionally but bottom line was it
just was always around me and I just
seemed to feel comfortable with it
and I wanted I wanted to explore that
world
I was just so curious I just felt so
uneducated and I just knew that herb was
so massive and big and I knew I only
knew so little and I was like man if I
could just apply myself maybe one day
you know I'll understand this complex
thing it was a hidden
secret you know what I mean like there
was no real info then like it was it was
you know the underground now it's it's
radically different and I think it's
better in that regard because regular
people shouldn't have to go through that
many Hoops to get an education in in
Canabis use and
cultivation but it was almost cultish at
that
point like you know you were you were
cautious it was criminal you wasn't no
Outlaw [ __ ] you were when you at to
Criminal Court when I got dragged out of
high school in handcuffs I didn't go to
to Outlaw Court I went to Criminal Court
you know what I
mean certainly certainly and and a lot
of Prior guests have commented on that
you know it really hard to find info and
people very tight-knit about who they
disclose that they're a grower to and
sharing information even the next level
of trust up I guess I'm curious though
um you know I'm sure you grew for some
time and then eventually you decided to
start Wonderland Nursery where where did
the idea first come from to start
that well I was already doing Nursery
work for years before I did Wonderland I
I Wonderland uh is after I worked at
humble patient resource center and
before I worked at humble patient
Resource Center I was doing commercial
Nursery work for the community meaning
that like large scale Growers were
accessing jeans what what I had done is
I had I I was a good operation
Builder and years earlier I had so many
operations running myself that I was
able to do using the I had to go to
Adult Ed to learn how to use a
spreadsheet this was in the the you know
mid90s kind of thing and I was able to
kind of crack the code on yield I was
able to figure out the variables that
you had tojust to make the plant produce
like what do you like it's really modern
day crop steering but I it was it was
even more profound because you were
having to actually steer an
operation so there's no data there's
nobody to copy and follow and the
standards were a pound of
light and so I said I just think that
that's just so under producing so I
started to really figure out what it was
that allows you to get higher yields and
maintain quality and when I cracked it I
went from pound of light into two and
then I went up to almost like you 214
213s but two and a half all the time so
off the 2000s I was getting five pounds
that's in the
90s so it instantly made me attractive
to work with for other cultivators that
wanted to do things because they were
like whoa off of a single table you you
know two tables you're pulling 10 pounds
so four lights is coming out to like you
know 40 Grand they're like how the [ __ ]
are you doing like you're making 40,000
out of a bedroom that's insane and so I
said' well I pay me to build you a room
so I would build him a room but in order
for the room to work I had to put in my
system and my genes so that I could
repeat the process for you and what I
started finding was that people didn't
like to do cloning or do mothers because
it was too problematic it was a lot
easier just to run a cycle and so after
I built the operation they said hey you
know would you provide the clones and
I'm like sure so I started doing clonal
work and the next thing you know I mean
I'm just pumping clones out like
crazy so I was doing way more clonal
production than I ever was Cannabis
production at that that stage of my
career you know into the 2000s because I
was just skilled at it and I and I was
willing to take the risk on the plant
counts and I was able to generate you
know an ungodly sum of money from doing
plant material and the people you deal
with are different than buyers you're
only dealing with
Growers so and they're they're they're
coming in to buy the product they need
to make their money so where you insert
yourself into the supply chain changes
the
relationship so when I got into the the
operation in
Arcada when I took over cultivation
director of that operation I said hey um
I let all the people know that were my
prior clients that if you went and got a
215 you could drive down to Arcade
and legally buy plants from me and
return with them with the script and
they would be protected up to a certain
number and it it it
exploded that company I mean it
absolutely financially changed the
direction of that business
forever and the owner and I ended up
having conflict over Direction and it's
a bummer too because I was happy there
but some people just want to stay in one
situation their entire
existence and and to me what I know is
that time can't be held still that no
matter what you're doing you can't hold
it this way forever you have to adjust
and change with the changes around you
or eventually you become a dinosaur and
you're you become
extinct and so she and I had different
views and I I left the company and I lit
up Wonderland and and Wonderland was
funny because everyone was like there's
no way you're going to be able to do
this there's no one who's ever done a
year round Nursery at scale it's never
been done before but I knew that if I
mined the whole state of California it
certainly could be done and so I light
this place up and we go after the
population of California where I'm I'm
whooping through neighborhoods all over
Southern Cal Central Cal Northern Cal
Eastern Cal I didn't care if it was in
California I'm coming at it and it
allowed us to be able to just absolutely
step up really quickly
and what we were trying to do was put
really really good genes into the system
and good genes mean genes that when you
grew them
out you could sell the
product but at the same time what we had
issues with was we would we were also
same thing as I understood that the
world was changing and I said listen we
didn't use any toxic [ __ ] at at at the
hprc and I said I don't want to use any
toxic [ __ ] here so we're going to have
to start learning really how to do
organic pest control how like because
the future I knew was not going to allow
you to use pesticides and and fungicides
that are aren't allowed for human
consumption so as I'm doing my homework
on potential problems we will face down
the road and I had done all this
research [ __ ] decades ago I'm like we
got a problem with the tools we use and
so it was a learning process too and
that's why when I see people like
someone gets some [ __ ] for doing
something wrong I'm like you know if
you're first you're going to make
mistakes
and at the end of the day are youed
still here if you're still here you had
to have figured out what you did wrong
and so Wonderland for me it it allowed
me to
understand biological Pest Control in a
way that is critical for today's world
so it it lets me work with my own crops
at the farm in a radically different
manner so I'm grateful for the
experiences and I love the fact that we
took so much incredible material I had
collected over decades and just
basically flooded the system with it so
that these genes made people's lives
better
financially and it funded all the
charity programs we were able to do at
Wonderland so it was this it was a
really magic moment where in life it's
rare that you get to do philanthropical
work at the same time you're doing work
and medical Canabis kind of was that
where I got to be part of medical
cannabis where the people who were ill
and having problems we just covered your
[ __ ] for free and people who are making
money we were making money with you so
I'm making sure that the markets that
you're approaching I'm giving you the
right plants for those markets see I
would do all the market research I would
figure out what was hot in every major
city across the
USU and then when then I would acquire
the plants that needed to fill those
holes so when you came into me and you
told me hey I moved weed to Atlanta I
would know what was hot in Atlanta and
that's what I would set you up with so
what it did is it allowed you to
instantly be able to hit your target
markets at speed and instantly you
recovering your money and coming back
quicker and it allowed me to be able to
work with all these farmers and develop
so the more they bought the bigger I got
the better I did my homework the more
money they
made and so Wonderland was really almost
like a Brain Trust more than it was a
nursery it was people didn't really come
in to buy clones they came in to ask me
what should I do and then I would sell
them the Clone that would fit the
need so it it it made it this really
interesting proactive
relationship and I also did stuff that
other people wouldn't do where I I I
lived in Oakland for years and so most
of my partners that I rolled with
weren't white and so I didn't have an
issue of going down to Oakland and
dealing with people that weren't white
all my partners that I rot with up in
Humble were basically Samo and tonging
so for me being around people that were
poly was fine I had done work with
Mexicans for years right so I was able
to go work with the Mexicans and when
the bulgarians and the ukrainians and
all the Russian groups started coming
into the area I understood what they
were seeking which was quality product
that would work and I approached them so
instead of just kind of focusing only on
the the typical cannabis cultivator I
went after the ones that I had spent my
life around people that have to
cultivate because that's where the
money's coming from
and what I would do is I would create my
menus in different languages Mong you
know like liosan um
Spanish um and U Ukrainian and I would
have them translated and then I would
have I I would have my partner um Kemo
he would go to all I would identify
where all the supermarkets and ethnic
food stores in each one of the areas
were and I would have them go there and
talk to those people and say hey is said
okay if we put this up in your store and
so what I did is I went after the target
populations where they lived around
California and I gave them the menus in
their own language and I put it in
places where they would see it and it it
just allowed me to get a reach that was
just Wicked and when the the Cannabis
industry turned upside down I got really
fortunate because when they started
changing all the zoning they changed the
zoning of my oper
a so Wonderland no longer had an ability
to cultivate at that location but some
uh people said hey we would love to have
you come over and work with us and be
partners on an operation here and so
that's how I got into the One Log and
then cookies approached us to do the
nursery and then step by step we ended
up becoming their entire you know
research and development facility for
that entity so all the work I did in
Wonderland it just put me into a
position where people realized that you
were seeing something others weren't
because you were moving plants at a pace
no one was with with really no staff to
do
sales it was just that I was doing all
this work on my own because I understood
that if I just I just learned this as a
kid if I make you money we should make
money together if I'm if I'm filling
your pockets with
cash it's rare that you don't come back
and deal with me yeah business is
business
yeah powerful stuff and what a what a
really unique and organic sort of
progression you just described there to
ultimately have the the various
facilities you Opera in today that's
really inspiring the development I've
got uh I've got a few of our patreon
fans submitted questions before we get
into the final five questions first one
I just going to quickly run by you um
our first listener says uh can you ask
Kev has he done any work with any CBD
CBG or any of the alternative varieties
and if so what does he find to be the
most
medicinal man that's a good question we
did we were it's funny but like some of
the first CBD work ever done in the
United States came out of my original
shop and I didn't do the breeding of the
development on it I just was I was the
one who who listened to the person talk
about what was potentially possible and
said okay I'll dedicate floor space and
people to the op and that's where ACDC
came out so
ACDC and it was from Courtney there was
Wade louder who did Harley Quinn and
then there was Ringo who did Ringo's
gift and that was all simultaneously at
the same time that would have been like
around you know
208 209 and so all that work resulted in
this massive development of CBD and what
I had done was I open sourced it I
started flooding the market with all
these CBD Cuts because what we realized
was non psychoactive cannabis would
transform the public perception of
cannabis
because if you're no longer feeling pain
from your arthritis in your hands from a
rub cream then maybe you'll have some
compassion for someone who needs to
smoke cannabis because they're
depressed and so my theory was if we
shared the genes in this way it would
absolutely infiltrate the public and it
did so like I was known for years for
just releasing [ __ ] millions of dollars
of free clones I did it for free so I
mean we release hundreds and hundreds of
thousands of plants to groups all over
the world of CBD genes and what I think
is that if you're if you're working with
CBD I think some of the the mix ratios
like one to ones two to ones are ideal
because when we it depends on the
individual but say you're say you're a
normal cannabis consumer if you have
some CBD woven in it it balances out the
high so like when you really look at
land raise populations they're not all
pure THC definitely mixed cannabinoids
because they're not steering towards a
singular singular molecule and because
of it what you have is a better
Synergy and so I think that the the best
thing you could do is you know go into
some of these modern hemp varieties and
use them as a platform to bring in more
THC so you can get to a 122 13 15
something in that range and what you'll
have is you'll have the best effects of
both
and on a lot of these other canabo
that's a tough one because really I
don't I don't I don't try to chase
canabo dour because really that's a a
molecular basket hunt that means you
have to be really using labs to do so
much of the driving and the work towards
it and it's
expensive and that's not me I mean like
I I can work with you on a project to do
it by helping you choose plants but what
I want is I want cannabis that I like to
consume for the reasons I do and so when
I'm chasing
something I have to kind of have a
desire to touch it and play with
it and so THC molecule is one I really
seem to like and I like it woven in with
some CBD but I I don't I didn't go after
the cbc's the
cbgs um I have a plant that's got some
thcp in it at at you know detectable
levels which is very rare and I'm
fascinated by that I don't know there's
enough there to be able to actually
steer towards the direction but thcp is
a a molecule
that is like 30 times stronger than
THC and so it it to me it's one of the
things that affect longevity of high and
U just the overall how much you need in
titration to get high I'm pretty
fascinated by that I think some of the
the thcv work that's being done right
now is fascinating and I got to consume
some thcv
herb grown by a brand
called pure beauty out of LA and so it's
a woman-owned living soil indoor op and
I've never met any of the team but I
they sent me some of the products so
that I could uh do an essay on it and I
was astounded man they just straight
crushed it so the pure beauty girls are
throwing down some straight heat and
that thcv was fascinating because you
got this unbelievably effective
uplifting high and when you came down
you didn't crash and it had a really
interesting side effect where you
weren't hungry afterwards you didn't go
through the Munch cycle but like you it
wasn't that you weren't hungry you could
eat dinner but you didn't eat dinner
twice you know where to me if I'm
smoking BHO I have to be careful because
I'm gonna not just eat the pizza on my
plate but I'm gonna eat the pizza in the
Box thcv didn't do that so I think the
mix I think the the novel can abono are
fascinating but I think for the average
individual a one to one a two to one is
just something wonderful to
have yeah I've certainly found a oneto
one is sort of that sweet spot for
myself so I can hugely relate to what
you just said there we got another good
one from one of the listeners who says I
saw that photo of the huge ball of the
Roberts Creek Congo hash on his
Instagram I'd love to hear any hash
making tips for making hash from like
low yielding but special
plants you know the the the process of
hash is is is pretty well laid out what
you what you have to do when you work
with plants that just don't produce is
recognize that so you you it's not for
commercial purposes when I made that
ball at at Roberts Creek Congo hash I
laughed and I said I guarantee there's
no bigger ball of this [ __ ] in the
country at this point right now because
nobody would wait waste that much weed
to make that much hash but I I got some
right here I still got a piece of a
left I still I still have a piece of it
left right there yeah a little little
tiny nugget that's yeah yeah two years
old now I was smoking it the other night
I got destroyed um you just have to be
able to like make those decisions and
the the the situation is it's really
difficult if you're doing it indoor and
you're paying electricity on that [ __ ]
so for me you know it's different that I
I could do the Roberts Creek outside and
I could get a plant that could throw me
three pounds so that I could basically
get a golf ball of hash off of it
because you know you talking yields that
are just non-existent in the wash and I
knew that when I went into it but I just
wanted to try it I wanted to say hey
what happens when you don't care about
return what you care about is the
quality of the return and the Roberts
Creek Congo hash was excellent and
I still love smoking I only got that
little piece left you know I probably
got like what maybe two three grams left
but man it was
just grabbed you and and it and it
didn't lift it it when it was fresh the
high was way more like
heady as it started to mature and and
really polymerize the effect became way
more pronounced and profound where you
felt it in your body too so two-year-old
Congo has is still unbelievable and it's
two years it was two years ago that I
did that easy so I think you just have
to be able to make it you know work for
you and don't be afraid you know if you
have an outdoor patch next year same
thing I want to do I want I got I got
one of my one of my red Leb plants is is
low yielding but the the profile is so
attractive and I know that it'll break
off well that it'll be worth me doing my
whole medical Garden of just that to
wash and then grow my six plants for my
flower so I just think that at the end
of the day if you're not looking at
commercial constraints and you're a
consumer who gives a
[ __ ] totally got to follow the passion
and the quality I love that a question
we end up asking most guests on the show
if you had to take a guess what do you
think is the genetics behind the
legendary chem dog
91 oh that's a good question you know
the the the chem lines I remember I was
out there in ponia I was out there in in
Crested bu area of Colorado where all
that comes from initially I was there
around 92
93 and my partner was out there and and
it was funny because he was like heav he
goes I smoked some weed here that that
destroyed any other pot I ever smoked in
my entire life he said this area is the
hot bed of Colorado for Killa
weed and there was um I just talked to
somebody that it was they were trying to
chase down what was the parental stock
of it and at the end of the day we just
know basically where it came from we
know it came out of the that area but I
do not know the lineage you know we
could say it's it's got to be a hybrid
so it has to have some form of of
something Broad Leaf and something
narrow because of the growth
characteristics right so like on a
morphological level you can see traits
that are explosive in growth on the 91
which only really apply to plants that
have to outgrow everything around it in
the surrounding vegetation but it has a
profile that is
distinctly Afghani
Pakistan yeah I'm not sure we'll ever
really know the the true Origins maybe
genetic testing will get a little more
info at some point but might just need
to accept that we'll never fully know I
have another good one from one of the
listeners who said I got a pack of seeds
from the 2020 Durand Line of the GNE
what sort of Expressions did you get
from your hunt what can they um hope to
find
themselves I found two really distinct
profiles both male and female and it was
kind of neat because it it made it
pretty easy to make your choices but
what I found was you know green and
purple and purple was more open
branching kind of umbrella shaped
pomegranate nut
paste floral sweet and then the green
was more more pole like chunky with just
a a ferociously noxious
sulfur and so when I did all my
hybridization work I went with the
sulfur because everybody was going fruit
and sweet and I was kind of sick of it
and what I wanted was some you know
really funky nasty deep penetrating
odors Aromas and highs and that's where
when I did that that project I took the
mail I chose that I made those plants
with or one of them there was multiple
males in that in that release but the
one that I kept for myself that's the
one that I went into all the fuels and
the Cherry Pie and pulled out that
cherry pie plant that was absolutely A+
and I had my son's friend come by and
fresh freeze it and then process it and
then rosin it for me so that I'd have
because I don't do Ros it I don't press
it and so I I wanted someone that could
go through the process and give me a
dabbable product that I could take to
this event so that this is the product I
wanted to show people that was possible
when we take some of these lines and it
was so attractive that the lead breeder
a raw Adam got excited by it and I ended
up giving him some seeds so that he
could go play with it and they they did
a huge uh selection of it this year to
see how it worked out for them at their
operation because he had never smelled a
profile like that in person it was just
super
attractive and at the end of the day all
I really wanted to have people do was be
able to say hey this reflects uh seed
stock from gny
and it was uh you know Indian Land race
that put it out so all I did was clean
up the population to get rid of the
intersects for on an indoor sip so I ran
it outdoor took the ones from the out
put them in the ones that went
intersects I called and that's what we
used as the population to make that
F2 and you have two directions really it
broke up really really clearly and and I
would love to go back and I think I will
when I get a chance I'll go back and
I'll do the purple pomegranate with the
nut paste because that was super exotic
too it's just that I was bored with all
you know you got to go back I probably
did that like through three four years
ago right and I was just bored with all
the candy gas [ __ ] and so I said look I
want some I want some really deep Funk
and then I went and deep funked it for a
while and like maybe I wouldn't mind
going back into some of the florals and
fruits but not from the typical Jean
pools so go play and if they do a
preservation make sure you put the males
and the females together to get the
assortment you want to be able to keep a
good cluster of the genes pure and then
choose males that you can play with to
find out their impact on the females you
want to use so you're able to do
hybridization bring the qualities
forward the qualities that got brought
forward too I noticed was
incredible um change in water
consumption the plants decreased water
consumption dramatically which was one
of the reasons really why I wanted to
mess around with some of that work
because because we were in the middle of
this horrific drought in California and
I was like man if I could just put some
better water efficiency on some of these
plants it would just be a lot easier for
us so we're not having to go through so
much water and in the trials I just
noticed that all of those hybrids I did
all watered at you
know I would say twice as you know T
like you know double the infrequency but
probably like 0 6 so extremely water
effective
that's awesome to hear some really cool
observations there and you know
hopefully our listener can find some
cool stuff in there I've got one last
fan submitted one before our final five
it's a cool one one we've never asked
Our Guest before I'm I'm Keen to see
what you think on it the question is
what's the hardest part about being
cannabis famous do you get stopped a lot
do you find people respect your time
generally speaking I do I do I get I do
get stopped a lot and it's weird because
I never expected to be you know famous a
thing and it wasn't really the desire as
much as I was Desiring to be recognized
for the work I had done and I ended up
just becoming featured on media enough
times that all of a sudden you kind of
become comfortable with it and you you
because you're not Desiring that
position you understand that they're the
people that are listen are not really
there to listen to me as much as they're
listen to what's coming out of my mouth
in terms of of
information so what what I know is that
I try to provide information to the
public that has
value and I try to be
approachable and the hard part is that
in real
life it's hard to you know be able to
give that much time to that many people
and so what you have to do is you got to
kind of create like parameters where
people reach out to you and they're
reaching out to you seven times a day
and you're like look I don't talk to my
own kid this often um could you just
maybe not hit me up every 15 minutes and
we'll we'll probably be able to have a
better long-term friendship so what I do
is I I try to create some separation of
barriers but not remove you from the
picture and if you approach me and you
polite man I'm always down to sit down
if you want if you want to lay out your
whole business plan to me and I have to
go spend six hours of like trying to
sort through your [ __ ] I'm like that's
business
but if you're asking me a question and
you just want to bounce an idea for
somebody and you're able to like be
polite in the way you approach me it's
rare that I won't sit down and try to
take the time because at the end of the
day my desire in real life was to do
well and to see people around me do well
I I wasn't trying to do well
alone and I just think that when you
behave that way you end up having a
better life period Your Life is Richer
because you're around people trying to
do positive [ __ ] and just because you're
being nice doesn't mean you're stupid or
you're a sucker because you know the
difference and so for me it's it's about
the approach where you don't have to
give me I call it a verbal [ __ ] I
don't need a verbal [ __ ] I just need
you to to treat me like anybody else you
meet and just be polite and and approach
me in a way that's
approachable and if you can do that then
we can begin a conversation
and so for me that's why I make myself
so available at all the conferences I
attend all the different events I go to
because what I know is that I get to see
so much of the Cannabis
world that if I can provide little
tidbits of info to people that are
trying to figure something out and find
a world for
them it maybe it changes how they
approach people in their future maybe if
we behave this way then you'll behave
this way you know it's like the same
thing with me giving the jeans out I
helped all these people that it was
funny because when I was doing it
everybody was like you're a heretic
you're helping out nobody's but I'm like
yeah but they're nobody to you but
they're decent people to me they don't
have to have any value to me I I'm not
seeing as that they're just good people
and if I give them this cut and they
they use their own skills and effort to
take it further and it it really well
could change their life it'll change it
financially for sure and so what happens
is I didn't realize that I was
developing a future of
people and you go 15 years into the
future and you got people hitting you up
and they were like hey you know when I
was 16 17 you helped me you change my
life I'm in my mid-30s and I'm running a
monstrous operation in another country
and I just wanted to reach out to you to
let you know that if it wasn't for you I
wouldn't be here and I never got to
thank you but now that you know I could
find you public I can say thank you for
being good to me when no one else was
and it's it's emotional
because you you're not thinking about it
like that you're just trying to be
decent it it was like the Louis the 13th
cut right I get the Louis the 13th cut
because some old lady had a bad time and
I helped her out and and she knows what
I do and she and she she uh comes to my
office and she brings the phone and says
here my family wants to talk to you and
it was her Armenian in-laws that own the
the Louis the 13th cut down there in LA
that were making all the money on it
that cut was hotter than a firecracker
and they drove all the way from LA to
Humble to bring me five
clones to say here these are the most
valuable OG clones and the connection
right now like this is the number one
cut in the game here's five cuts for you
for helping our our
mother-in-law and I had no idea that
mother-in-law was connected to these
these Hustlers from LA but it was just a
good deed for an old lady that needed
some help and so I think that you know
for me in my and it's almost like an
innocent world but like I came from a
different background man it was
rough a a nicer life is never bad and so
when you when you when you decent to
people it allows you a radically
different
existence and being well known in
something is never bad as long as when
people meet you you're the same person
that they they
and so for some people it's not good
because they're like well you smart ass
in real life and on the net but for most
it's good because I'm pretty predictable
and at the end of the day what I want to
see is I want to see cultivators around
the
world in in a in a in a cohesive
collaborative cluster that lets us help
shape the future that we'll all have to
deal with when we're old and like I I've
been saying for decades I'm just the
tiny Link in a chain that's G on forever
and I just want to be a good link and so
if you want to link up with me you can
and if you don't you can let go it's all
good but being being exposed is a gift
because it allows you to really be able
to do some incredible things you can't
do if you're
not yeah that's an awesome take I really
like that and it sounds like you you
know make yourself available to people
which is really generous of you with you
know your time I'm sure it's limited on
to our final five quickfire questions
the first one I want to ask okay what is
the single most memorable experience
you've had with cannabis so this doesn't
have to be like the strongest nug or the
most insane dab just whatever is the
most memorable for whatever reason I got
it man I got I got the story I smoked
some weed from pipe I was working out in
Micronesia I smoked some weed and I got
so high that I couldn't navigate the
offramp on the freeway and so I just
drove around on the island for hours
until I came down because every time I
got to the onramp it was too technically
difficult for me to navigate and so I
just did another loop around the island
and I was just praying that I didn't run
out of gas because there was no way that
I could navigate this offramp until I
came
down that is brilliant I really like
that that's one of the best ones I think
um so on the other end of the spectrum
what's a strain where everyone around
you really hyped about it everyone's
telling you it's going to be the best
thing ever you finally try yourself and
you're sort of like H is this it oh [ __ ]
that would have been purple punch
recently when purple punch first came
out everybody was hyping the living hell
out of it and then we smoked it and we
were like
huh
what I think that was the most hype
strain I've seen in a minute that just
really gorgeous top 10 visual who won
the
flavor totally that's that's one of the
top contenders with we do here on the
show you know so there you go next one
is I'm going to drop you off on a desert
island you got infinite resources and
you can take three strains or packs of
seeds with you what three things are you
going to take oh damn I'd have to take
I'd have to take uh three packs of seeds
because if I'm on a desert island I
probably don't have a nursery and so I
would I would want to work with um
something in that lap PK range because I
I I need that type of profile
I would love to have something that was
in
the the the Mexican groups like that
zakat takus or the aapo just because the
high is um just so interesting and the
flavor is so rich and I love uh like a
killer
tie I love that that super cerebral high
and that that really back in the day man
taies change flavor but like for me all
the tie we consumed you know in the 80s
when people chocolate tie I it's color
or not but like the flavor was sure
chocolatey I mean it was amazing and the
high was absolutely riveting so I would
do that I'd go like a a good Mexican
collection something out of Asia Thai
Flavor I think Thai flavors are better
than La I think the cambodians the
Vietnamese are a little stronger but I
think the ti is more balanced and then
the the a self lpk but I want a self I
would need to have m female populations
all three so that I could play with it
for a while so I didn't feel like um if
anything happened I'd be
screwed I like that really balanced it's
a good little spread there so similar
but different question I'm forcing you
to start a seed company tomorrow and you
can only start it with one pack of seeds
what pack of seeds would you
use oo that's a good
question for me myself or for the public
for yourself and for the public like as
in you can give two answers one for each
yeah I guess if I I mean because I'm so
obsessed with that red Leb puck right
now it have to be that because that's
what I did is I took those seeds and I
chased it down and I'm throwing out you
know lines for public sale so that would
be for me for the general
public I would say gas is returning
so you know you're seeing like the the
hunger come back and I would go
into something from like like I would
say you know Gabe Ruth's work is pretty
good Josh from um regen has got some
good work risen's got some good
work Tyler family trees's got some good
good fuel work where he does some dog
walker sfvs that are just
ferocious I'd say if you went into any
of those groups right there you know
there's always Jean is Jean always got
some really killer [ __ ] but there's some
guys that have some really nice work
that AR is known and I think their their
uh direction is good and because it's
Fuel and these guys have been doing a
lot of fuel-based work for a while I
think there stuff's really
interesting yeah great answer you know
Jean stuff is incredible and all those
dudes you mentioned I'm I'm familiar
with them you know shout out to Josh and
um you know all the stuff there is
awesome so that's cool to hear final
question for this one is I've got a time
machine for you you can go back anywhere
any point in time presumably to collect
some genetics could be seeds could be
cuting could be whatever where are you
gonna go and what are you g to
get wow that's a good question
I I think I would go all the way and
it's funny because it would it would be
the least commercially
valuable because until you see feral
populations you just realize there's
very little on them but I would like to
go back to where we map cannabis merge
with humans which would be Nepal like
you know Plains of the
Himalayas um you know 14,000 years ago I
would I would like to see the plants
from then I would like to see the plant
that really drove people's Obsession to
move it so heavily on the silk route and
down into these
regions that's what I'd like to
experience what what what is it in its
unadulterated
form the true P1 right there yeah I want
to know what and I mean we we know that
cannabis is a million years old but we
can only go back 14,000 with any kind of
recorded history but that'd be enough if
I could go back 14,000 years and and
experience the planes of Mongolia and
get to see how they use the plant and
eat the seeds and drink the tea and and
then throw bales of it in the fire in
the cave and have rituals and [ __ ]
because you know that's what they were
doing they weren't smoking that [ __ ]
they were using it as firewood but they
would get ripped so that's what I love
to experience I think because otherwise
I'm really been happy I've been able to
touch and
smoke and see and experience so much
that it would it would just be awesome
to go back and and and see our
Roots that's what Pakistan did for me it
was this was beautiful I mean I it was
it was different than any other place
I'd been to because the people had been
in the valley you know for 15 100 years
each family was like we've always been
here you know 15 centuries herb has been
here before us this is what we've always
done we've always eaten it we've always
drank it we've always smoked it and it
it just lets you understand the holistic
complete relationship with a plant that
I only really knew in skewed form it
wasn't until I got into medical cannabis
that I really started to understand
medical applications then we we get into
the discovery of CBD
and you get to really see how many
applications and then I I get into doing
all the green juice work so you start to
see it in its acid form unconverted and
you're like my gosh if we had mixed
canabo we would have these impacts if we
had acid form we would have these
impacts and so my my career just
kept turning the the facet it kept
turning the stone so I get to see more
and more facets and I got to see so much
that I'm just grateful that I got to see
it it's just been this NeverEnding
turning of a stone that's Unlimited in
depth no matter how far I go the deeper
I dive the clo the farther from the
bottom I find myself that's beautiful
you know a student of Life by the sounds
of it I love that so sounds like that's
just about the end of it for this one
any comments or shoutouts you'd like to
make yeah I just want to say thank you
for having me on the show
it's um it's always a pleasure to to be
able to sit down and and talk with
friends and I always want to thank the
listener for taking the time to listen
to me you know go off on my tangents
because at the end of the day they have
a choice to not hear it so thank you for
uh the support and um be nice cannabis
cannabis is a beautiful drug it seems to
bring out some really lovely attributes
and
people 100% And we are all indebted for
you taking the time to share your
knowledge today so again a big thank you
to one of the most well-known faces in
NorCal and meno a local Legend The Man
Behind Wonderland Nursery a career
Hustler and true cannabis connoisseur a
big thank you to Kevin JRE for coming on
the show today beautiful thank you that
was wonderful
[Music]
and there you have it gang thanks for
joining us to the end and a massive
shout out to Kevin JRE coming on the
episode sharing some knowledge and
teaching us a whole bunch and a massive
shout out to you guys for getting to the
end we appreciate you so much just like
we appreciate our incredible sponsors if
you want to help support the show
support our
sponsors massive shout out to seeds here
now don't forget guys it's pineapple
time check out the pineapple strains
online 20% off massive sales month of
February check it out massive shout out
to CTN now we love your support thank
you so much likewise a massive shout out
to our friends at Pulse sensors all the
best and latest sensors in the game
including their New Pulse Hub which
integrates all of their units together
to ensure that your operation is on
point producing bigger yields better
turps higher potency whether you're
running a single tent a single room or a
multi-state operation pulse are here to
help you guys get serious get a pulse
further shout out to coper the number
one leaders in Sustainable biocontrol
Solutions for pests and disease if
you're battling spidermites please check
out the spidex vital sachet I can't tell
you how annoying it is to have to spread
carrier material in your garden just to
get the Predators out these new sachet
circumvent that just hang the sachet in
your crop let the person millist walk
out do the work for you trust me guys
you won't look back if you give it one
go you will see the quality you will be
converted a massive shout out to copit
we appreciate your support so much these
guys are industry leaders check them
out huge shout out to our friends at
Organics alive number one for powdered
organic fertilizers if you're thinking
about giving Organics a go get on board
their products make it so easy whether
you're in veg transition or Bloom
they've got products that make it easy
to dip your toes in the water likewise
if you're a season veteran of Organics I
promise their products will help take
your next crop to a whole new level
massive shout out to Organics alive they
have some of the best products on the
market really fast release because
they're small particle size you will not
go wrong with Organics alive hit them up
massive shout out and thank
you finally a big shout out to our
friends at dap just a week or two ago
they came out with some new models the
titanium M Series in two different
colors you can get yourself the nebul or
the quantium I've been rocking the nebul
I love it guys please give it a go if
you've ever tried a vape and felt like a
didn't hit the way you were looking for
it these ones will truly a game changer
based out of the US owned in the US dap
truly one of the best vape companies on
the market I really really love their
products and we are super appreciative
of their support massive shout out to
DAP last but not least massive shout out
to the patreon gang thank you so much
for your support if you want to help
ensure the show continues to happen
please consider checking out
patreon.com theep podcast you will get
early access to upcoming episodes
unheard exclusive interviews and you go
in the running to win a whole range of
Swag each month we give away genetics
cannabis artwork a whole range of
awesome products all while ensuring the
show continues to happen again a massive
shout out to the patreon gang we love
you so so so much thank you thank you
thank
you and I think with
that I'll see you for the next
one I'll see you