[Music]
[Applause]
what
[Music]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast
a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts
[Music]
this episode as always was brought to
you by our amazing sponsors
seeds here now best in the business
guarantee not just on germination but
satisfaction as well check them out i
don't know why you would suss anything
else
as well as radio ridge nursery if you're
looking for the best clones in the game
clean ready to go breeder cuts
exclusives do i need to say any more
really i mean come on all the best
breeders work with these guys why aren't
you
and finally a shout out to our friends
at dragonfly earth medicine and organic
gardening solutions you guys are amazing
we love you lots and lots and lots also
a quick shout out to our patreon gang as
always lifeblood of the show we
appreciate you guys more than we can
ever say
[Music]
on this episode we're joined by mr wonka
himself james bean of seeds here now
to talk all things seeds
industry
and predictions for the future
[Music]
so without further ado
let's get into it
alrighty it's that time again my friends
a big thank you and a big welcome to the
one and only
true mr wonka thank you so very much
james bean for joining us today
how you doing
i'm doing good my friend how you doing
i'm doing good i'm doing good uh it's
good to be alive and good to be in the
industry so
amen to that let's start off with our
normal first question these days what
are you currently smoking on
well uh earlier i was smoking i'll admit
it i was smoking some of the kaka kush
the brown frown as it were i found some
brown frown but i ran myself out of out
of cannabis and so i've been smoking on
some some dry sift i got from exotic the
strawberries and cream f2 dry sift
wow and you just dabbing that one or
putting it on top of a cone
oh no i don't have anything i ran myself
out i was i did put so i didn't want to
put it on the cocker kush because i
wouldn't even help it but uh i just been
dabbing it haha yeah okay so you can't
even elevate the trash with the gold
i don't think so i think it tarnishes
the gold
yeah right why would you want to ruin it
yeah so
cool that i've seen that one pop up a
fair bit what's it what's it taste like
what's the high like
what is strawberries and cream or kaka
kush oh god
you say baka kush gives you a [ __ ]
headache
you know you miss a seed or something uh
strawberry strawberries and cream
strawberries and cream uh it's really
nice it's it is tasty like you can
definitely taste the sweetness of the
strawberries in it which is pretty odd
but uh exotic's been working on it for a
minute so
i know he's real proud of it and he's
been he's just been bonkers over it so
um i was nice enough he gifted me a
couple of sips that's nice thing about
mike is that uh before his line will
drop
he will mike from exotic genetics but he
will give like when i when i meet up
with him a month beforehand or whatever
i'll get like flowers i don't get dry
sift
of the product that he drops in a month
which means to me that she tells me
right off the bat boom this guy's
already already grown all this out he's
already happy with it he's already seen
it at all flour and this is you know
he's giving me the flour as he's
releasing the seeds
and so um you know that's that's a
credit to his part he definitely tests
all this stuff for regression
yeah of course and mike's also one of
those guys i've noticed who
is always continually pushing forward
with projects and that's something i
like a lot you know like he doesn't let
things get stagnant and start to just
sit there and redo the same releases
again and again
no he he goes he's always moving now
he's moving a couple ahead
wait a minute all right
check pause
definitely leaving this in
sorry i love that no that's good so i
was just saying yeah like mike's always
moving forward um do you feel like
that's a trait like a lot of successful
breeders in body or is it possible to
just kind of make your releases a bit
more slow and spaced out
i just i it really depends on the
breeder to be honest because i mean
we're
you could
there's there's mike who definitely
works on this stuff for a while and um
the nice thing is i was part of the
interlude was 360 when i was in
washington and i would get their their
tests and i would
chilly everybody was running um and i'd
be like man why are you running a citrus
thing you know and six months later it
comes out with satrik but he was just
sitting in samples trying to get you
know terps and profiles and whatnot so
he was on top of it but
um but then at the same time there's
there's like uh there's od diesel from
homegrown natural wonders who doesn't
have a lot of releases but when he does
it's it's tried and true like odie will
walk around with 10 jars with him trying
to figure out which one is his best is
his best one and he'll sample it with
everybody that he knows and then we've
you know he figured out which one he
likes boom that's the keeper and then
that's the one release but
um so i think that's a credit to both of
their those those guys when i talk to
people that work with mike or work with
mike in the past and always one thing
that comes up with him is he he's he's
got the eye like he can in a room full
of full of room full of [ __ ] and a
room full of girls uh he can pick out
the fiery one
so
yeah that is a skill in itself right
either that or or in a room full of
dicks you can figure out the best one
too so either way
another very admirable breeder trait
so
just in general what's new in the world
of james bean
uh a lot and not a lot uh just getting
ready to go to portland tomorrow while
we're doing the uh indo expo
so it's always a fun show uh dunn is
broadcasting from there tonight
um tomorrow we'll be on the floor
hitting the floor i fly out tomorrow
morning that'll be a cool weekend show
and i'm going back to medford to uh run
down my office and then i'll come back
to san diego area so
um and then of course we've got uh
upcoming shows we've got the miami show
coming up the big uh the big industry
show uh september 23rd down in miami so
that'll be pretty awesome it's a big
retail show
yeah what what's the florida scene like
oh canada and back back when they had a
couple years ago when they were then
passed laws in florida just because
cannabis didn't pass because it has this
this crazy percentage that it needs in
order to pass i think it's two-thirds
majority
but just because canada didn't pass cbd
did pass and so they've been growing it
but they their first restrictions were
very weird like you had to
the place that your facility had to have
been in operation for like 40 years and
it had to have shown that it would you
know it could produce at least 400 000
plants or something and they had to have
been owned by the same person for the
past 40 years
and so that that kind of you know
that's the bias and horrible movement is
i mean that gives a certain amount of
people a certain shot at it
yeah it seems very limiting i mean yeah
do you feel like there will be a more
full scale roll out of legalization
eventually down there
i think there has to be like that that
that weird law is just too weird and too
selective of a very short minority of
people and so it's not it's it's not
right um so there has to be that when
you go down to like key west uh two
years ago i went from coast to coast i
drove from coast to coast i started in
key west but when you go down there
there's there's pot t-shirts everywhere
and all the on all the vendors or
selling you know get high get this there
was one smoke shop
but uh but just t-shirts everywhere and
the culture was there so
i don't think i don't see why not they
have the also the tourism boom in
florida and everybody that gets it on
and off those cruise ships
uh it's a customer suicide
yeah of course
and i mean on that same train of thought
what state do you think will be the next
to fall and to kind of open the
floodgates for it all
uh i i don't really know there's so many
that are just that are there um and now
that the sessions are out they're not
really um they're not really passing
anything but i
because you know i think um a couple
months ago one state just went and did
their own bill and acted their own stuff
and got got with the times and so i'm
not really sure i know it's not going to
be idaho
so
sadly no
i think idaho has some of the best
climate to grow that uh our canada
cannabis end but
just
just not the right people
not the right people at all like they
made a law against ever making a law
positive about cannabis
yeah right that's how backwards they are
we are surrounded by legal states so
okay
i mean
when utah passes ahead of them
yeah that's a bit weird isn't it but i
mean
they do their own thing so just to kind
of jump back on track
let's dig back into the past for a
minute i'm not sure i asked you this in
our first interview so i want to bring
it up now what was your first experience
with cannabis
yeah i thought i thought we did um
so i was basically uh
hustling qps a shake
and the joints they bring this uh maybe
the a place of education
daily so i would just sell them off and
i was actually hustling them off before
i even started smoking i didn't smoke
until like my senior year high school
so but it was just uh with some friends
i'm sure in the back of a blazer
didn't have any bong water she used iced
tea you know that kind of thing
well it was fun we did it at lunch time
and we got we got really stoned of
course we were we had beasters which i
come to now know as m39
but to that back then it was beasters
all smelled like hay i was like oh they
must grow this in a hay field
as i got educated i was like oh no
that's just mold you're smelling
and what was the experience like did you
get high on your first time
uh
you shaved they say
they say the short term memory goes and
so i don't really remember
there you go
must have been pretty good right now
yeah yeah i i continued down the path so
that was good
very good very good and so what was the
progression next from just you know
getting some stuff to some mates at
school how did you then progress to
become the giant of the seed world we
know you to be now
and so let's let's let's pause on that
on that note pause but but keep rolling
if you will uh who is james bean so um i
am
uh a nobody if you will like i i'm
flattered that that you even uh you had
me on your show twice now i'm a sponsor
so i guess that helps but uh to have me
on your show that and care of my
opinions are and things i think that's
awesome um i was lucky enough to get to
find you early uh the questions i
thought you asked are on point uh i was
like the way i explained people i was
like he either doesn't know things or
he's [ __ ] got huge balls but he just
he asks questions that you shouldn't ask
and so you know and so i appreciate that
about you because you were getting you
know let's get to the bottom of [ __ ]
here um when you were concise about it
but um
uh i lost my train of thought we were
going with that oh who am i who am i so
i'm a nobody man i'm i'm a broker i mean
it's nice to have uh to hear all this
and see all this but um i think what
people sometimes
misinterpret is that i have anything to
do with the seed production i don't i
don't at all i'm i'm a broker who helps
uh breeders get there get their genetics
out
i've got great customer service i've got
a great work ethic ethic i've got great
um
ethical tendencies i guess you want to
say morals uh and so if i if with our
satisfaction guarantee if you ever buy
anything you're unhappy with it for
whatever reason you know if king kong
comes out of the sky and breaks your
[ __ ] plants you think it's my fault
uh you know call us up we'll talk to you
about it we'll send you free five pack
like we want everybody to be satisfied
the the the
we have uh sixteen hundred uh five star
reviews on our website at least we've
got like i said outstanding customer
service but i never want anybody to go
to facebook and start ratting or say
anything or say that this we did them
wrong or i never want anybody to have
the ability to say that i didn't i
didn't do them right or i didn't take
care of them so and then on behalf of
the breeders it's always it's never it's
never
a good question to ask a customer you
know how did you how did you germinate
those
and as it is um we sell souvenir packs
and so we don't speak to germination
anyways so if you're unsatisfied with
your packs get a hold of us we'll make
sure you're happy
yeah really really solid sentiment and i
mean who on earth would go to facebook
and start trashing you before they
contact you
it never ceases to exist it's like they
think they're going to get more that way
or if they think their squeaky wheel and
i don't i'm sure where they what they
think but um they shouldn't know by now
i mean
i think any company you don't just
when you're pissed off at sears and
roebuck or you go buy a bow system if
it's sears and it doesn't work you bring
it back you don't go start trashing
sears you know what i mean yeah
but in this industry it's a little
different uh
yeah
tell them that i i i sold impacts they
heard me down they're upset about it
it's like no no i i didn't i didn't make
[ __ ] of those i said i'll fix it i'll
replace it make sure you're happy maybe
put you in with a different breeder but
it's not my fault i don't i mean you can
yell at me all you want you can yell my
customer service but we didn't we didn't
breed them we're simply gonna just stand
by them
yeah solid ethos solid ethos so i mean
to jump back to that question what was
the progression from uh mr wonka to
where you are now
oh yeah so they go back back on back on
course so i was a dj for 15 years 95
through 2010. um i played records and
final kind of back in the day when it
was cool it was kind of an underground
thing
and i was known for notorious for for
for weed and so when i flew around i
always had to have like you know a
quarter and eighth waiting for me at the
where i was flying or whoever picked me
up from the airport i needed to make
sure there was trap with weed when i got
there
um
i just came you know i'd smoke on stage
a real world wrecker uh so that was all
fun and dandy um in 2010
i uh
the scene kind of changed and it went to
mr rags if you will um
you could buy your little rave gear in
the stores you could you know the thing
that was underground and kind of cool
kind of got blown out of proportion and
everybody in their [ __ ] brother was
in it now
and so it wasn't cool anymore um one of
my friends that i had gone had you know
started djing with back in boise idaho
he was now uh he whenever he'd come
through portland he'd always you know
i'd stop and talk with him and he'd been
sending me facebook stuff about how he's
in breeder uh for your diaries and he
was doing all this and that of course i
had an ego i was like you know this guy
doesn't know more than me sure you do
sure you do um i met up with him at a
show
that i played here and he busted out
some cannabis and it was [ __ ]
phenomenal got me super stoned it was
you know
he dropped the knowledge and schooled me
and i was like damn that's that's
amazing what can i do to you know
dj scene's killing it for me what can i
do to get in the green scene he's like
well i won't breed her you could you
could sell a [ __ ] for me i said well
that works
so i you know with a napkin i bought
washington's the right to washington
state
from him um started watch wac bank
out of my
uh just doing trade shows uh hemp fest
and whatnot was my first show
and then that progressed to my friend
hoffa uh pushing me to get a website
and we'd have a web platform
to a shopify site to
my original manager rebuilding a
wordpress site to
another site to another site which
brings us to our latest site so
i've learned that with websites
uh it's best to have a team
uh to do these things that way when you
call
somebody's not at their cousin's
birthday this weekend or doesn't have
family in town or you know when you when
the website goes down which you know i
want to thank all of our customers for
that that stuck with us um
the website shit's been a pain in the
ass i'll be honest with you guys i
appreciate you sticking around we're
doing a killer sale right now or so just
kind of a way to say thanks for sticking
us
in there with us because these last four
months we've gone through four different
websites being shut down targeted
so i went with the firm
forked over a lot of dough
the new website will
uh i'm not gonna jinx myself but by
september 1st should be up and
functioning
since the last time i talked to you i
might have mentioned a forum well that
that little dream of mine came true yes
uh i got my form up
and so it's got uh it's got chat room on
the top where you guys can chat back and
forth on the bottom it's got
uh breeder pages where you can go into
each breeder's page each reader is to
add their own facts section their own
strain section their own uh general
section where they can announce their
their giveaways
so you can go in there ask a breeder get
one-on-one contact with them uh it's
also you know set up on our servers so
it'll never go down they'll never be
you know
taken out or
subpoenaed so
there you go and i mean you guys have
gone through an unfortunate amount of
kind of attacks on the site why do you
think that is you know why do you think
you because i don't hear other c banks
complaining about their websites being
taken down and stuff like that do you
think it's just like uh you're an easy
target because you guys are so far the
biggest
i don't know you know i never wanted to
be the big guy um kind of just you know
with uh i don't know dope go pure
terminology or thinking he kind of you
know you never want to be the bright
shiny guy on the corner he kind of just
keeps yourself and don't show you guys a
lot of [ __ ] and then you won't be having
a problem um and so when people's
reference s is one of the biggest it
kind of still shocks me and you know
wonders me but i'm not sure all i know
is that uh we've been attacked a couple
times and
this you know one time on 420 we got 17
000 comments per hour or something
that said [ __ ] you 420 [ __ ] you i told
you i'd [ __ ] with me [ __ ] you told you
to [ __ ] with me like and code like just
17 000 times
and so
uh you know that two years ago we were
we were ready we were prepared for the
420 attack this time and we had people
on standby we had 420 cyber on standby
to watch everything and we got attacked
again they're attacking us from of
course russian sites
using tor
an onion and so there's not you know i'm
told there's nothing you can do besides
defend against it yada yada
but it's been a pain in the ass
yeah wow do you think that this type of
practice is going to become more and
more
i common know because i don't know
that's the thing i don't know who's
doing it
our customers you know obviously don't
have an issue to be uh upset with me if
you have an issue let me know i'll take
care of it um some ex-breeders i don't
know if they have an issue with it i'm
not i'm not sure once again i'm i'm just
uh
i'm just the face if you will of a much
bigger company i have a team that works
for me there's 13 people that work
full-time that i employ
um along with 40 breeders that i
represent and so it's uh
when people attack my website because
they just like me it's like hey you know
yeah you're also [ __ ] with 40 dudes
webs you know incomes and 13 families so
uh if you've got an issue with me just
take it up with me but
i'm not really sure like i said what it
is or or why i um
i wish i wish i knew
yeah understandably frustrating well why
don't we move on to some more kind of
brighter pastures
let's chat about the newest breeder on
the block i've seen about two days ago a
very big name brand joined the seeds
here in our roster you want to tell us a
little bit more about that
yeah yeah my guy jackson zentner aka
meme gene aka freeborn selections
the guy is uh
as uh i think i've said in the past pops
more beans i think anybody else does i
think he probably pops a five gallon
bucket full of beans looking for finos
um
he really works as plants his lines i've
been working with him for about two and
a half three years now trying to get him
on board i remember him calling me and
asking we talked about an hour about his
real his launch his release and i've
been wanting his root beer for about two
years
uh
but yeah we got sky cutler kush and we
got pina colada
so we're happy to start with those two
um of course we'll get more as time goes
but yeah jackson was a big pickup he's a
really solid guy i like i really like
working with those type of people so
i'm definitely a guy who knows about the
plant loves the plant
hundred percent you know he's one of
those names that frequently gets
mentioned alongside the likes of duke
diamond and many other in that tier one
category
i guess my first question is how quickly
do you expect that drop to sell out
because i can only imagine you've got
what seconds when it goes live
yeah it uh should hopefully go pretty
fast uh we're in the middle of summer
and so a lot of people have already got
their their strains in the ground or
whatnot
that we only had a two day two day
advertisement on it but it should go it
should go pretty quick i should i could
pull up the numbers on it but
yeah should go like i said jackson's an
outstanding guy we're just we're happy
to work with him
of course of course so do you want to
maybe let a little cat get out of the
bag and tell us maybe some new breeders
you're considering adding to the roster
yeah
ah
yeah i mean we've already talked to them
all so it's not it's no secret on their
behalf but uh of course until until we
have anything uh solid it's all it's all
just fictitious and then my my making
[ __ ] up in case anything goes south but
um we're happy to add umuerta is coming
up
uh it's a really nice guy out of canada
uh super super nice guy um has some
really nice plants um
i i met up with with uh cannabis i
believe you you had did you interview
him true uh yeah we're looking to get
him on the show in the near future a lot
of people have had really good things to
say about him especially leo
yep uh yeah that guy uh so cornbread
ricky from swamp boys uh i did a post
about a month ago asking for you know
maybe uh there's banks i was sleeping on
or people they had ed wanted to add and
so cornbread ricky uh
posted up uh when kenneth was a lot a
lot of people wanted canvas probably got
the most tags out of it um and then
corey ricky underneath it posted up
saying you know grab this guy and so
that was that was enough for me to go
you know okay who's this dude and so i
called him up talked to him he's in
spain but awesome guy has some serious
[ __ ] history
um knows a lot about
uh sacred sea bank about neville about
the grateful heads
about uh
uh oh what's his name
oh
controversy 80 uh 2007
starts in r rez res yes
some great stories with about
connoisseur
and so yeah uh
i'm uh we're excited to get true on he's
a really good dude and uh you know the
guys the guy's cool yeah he's got
something i think he'd be great for your
show but
yeah
definitely he's he's got a lot of
history doesn't he because he he
messaged me just having a chat about res
one day and as you kind of reference i
was very surprised by how i think he
even mentioned he used to work with res
so like i mean how's that for inside
knowledge
right now he's uh we're just to work
with him knows him very very well he
used to work for connoisseur he used to
be connoisseur that guy you know i'll
let him tell the stories but you know
yeah he's he got he got busted once for
uh exporting marijuana because he was
going to a high times cup
and so he just thinks that he thinks the
people that he asked how to smuggle it
out with ratted on him so his entry got
flagged and so he he did jail time for
i was like damn
wow
yeah
but uh but cool very cool guy i'm
excited to get him on
yeah there you go that's something cool
to look forward to i guess we should
maybe do something a little
controversial so on the opposite end of
the new breeders you're considering
who's a breeder who you think's fallen
off
what the hell kind of question is that
you can choose to deny i don't mind uh
all the banks that i no longer carry
uh no
[Laughter]
um i don't know
yeah
just cause i can't i can't take shots
fired shots fired brothers grim you know
um oh that's a hot one i love that
victor's nice it was nice enough did us
all a favor and said you know
i will have new packaging so all the old
packaging is stuff that uh
uh is older stock and all the new
packaging is the newer stock and i said
oh thanks rick so all the older [ __ ]
tommy made and all the newer [ __ ] you
made
yeah it's been interesting to see the uh
the slow down in the number of offerings
from brothers grim since duke's
departure
dude duke was the the heart and soul
that oh oh damn shots fired again the
heart is still that thing but but duke's
just a [ __ ] yeah
but duke's an animal dude i mean that
guy's just uh
i'm really glad to call that i can call
him a friend and uh he's mentioned
before if he's having an earthquake out
here he's gonna
get his truck and come out here and save
us all
so
and i believe that he'd [ __ ] try
so he's just he's a good dude just him
and that massive uh swiss army knife
just comes and saves everything
that i can't i can't tell stories but uh
yeah uh don't ever play paintball with
him put it that way don't ever play
paintball with a [ __ ] [ __ ] because
yeah he will he will clear the field of
like 10 people to get the guys out
outstanding
yeah i can imagine right that's
brilliant
it was a shock i was like what the [ __ ]
well i mean you know just continuing on
from that topic how we were just kind of
discussing brothers grimm how how do you
think a breeder can continue to stay
relevant in what is essentially an
ever-changing market
i think
maybe on this one the swamp boys get
undervalued or get get uh
when i say number number one or or do it
a lot but they just like chrome said
they just do what the [ __ ] they're doing
like they don't care anybody else is
doing they don't want to do what anybody
else is doing like leave them alone
stay away from my [ __ ] and so they just
do they just do their own [ __ ] thing
and they just care about their own [ __ ]
and the lie i mean of this year i've
seen that lemon royale man
that thing really killed it for me last
year in boston um and just about every
other
every other time i've seen it or had the
chance to to be around it it's it's
something phenomenal it's it's massive
and stinky
um but i really like those guys those
guys are back in florida now uh
um i think they you know they they say
the best in order for you to stay
current you just have to you have to do
what you do like don't try to copy
people because by the time you time you
get to where they're at it's gone and
they're already the next thing
yeah right i've actually noticed that
about them they're they're very much you
know like the uh the silent grinders
just every so often you see a new
release and the genetics are always like
you know make your pupils dilate like
whoa like
and uh yeah sometimes they don't get
enough credit but thankfully they do
have a you know really really passionate
fan base behind them yep for sure
well i mean let's talk about it because
what's interesting is when you mention
the lemon royale the first thing that
jumped to mind was i had seen um
our buddy at tk origins posting about
who he was growing it out and he was
very impressed by it
tk origins so so i guess i could get
some knowledge here from you so we
decided that's the guy who did the the
cushions because i s
in my instagram swipings i had seen
somebody asked on a josh d og pick what
who did the real thing and josh did it
and first of all i'd seen josh post
no at tk origins did or something like
that to that effect
which surprised me because i've never
seen that from josh before
um but i know josh and so
have have they come back to decide
that's that's the guy
yeah like from what from what i can
gather the the central people in the
story seem to be reasonably happy that
it's probably the case everyone has
expressed a small amount of like well
you know it's hard to say a hundred
percent for sure type thing
but on the whole it seems as though like
the main players are able to trace the
connections back and from what i've been
told
he grew the weed and you know the seeds
were formed in his room but he wasn't
really aware of them as far as i know
and just the pounds went out got sold
people found the seeds
and he was really none the
wiser and you have this on a show that
can go back and listen to it on or is
this just from your basic knowledge
um i think uh we briefly touched on it
in the matt ride episode and i'm hoping
to have cornbread on next episode in
fact so i'm hoping to be able to iron it
out but i did talk to josh in real life
at the emerald cup and and he just
basically said everything i said
awesome so uh is this guy is that the
dreadlock guy or no no relation
see that's what i'm trying to figure out
i i don't think the tk origins guy is
the dreadlock guy but he is like a super
surfy dude from florida but i feel like
maybe they someone got sold the bud from
the dreadlock guy maybe
right
yep that's that's the story
um and on that uh one of the guys we've
added in the last two years is katsu
bluebird
ooh
okay
so catchy bluebird is known for
uh his um
the of the of the katsu bubba cut if you
will
which um so he he bought it and as as as
you get on the show he can tell stories
better than i do but he bought it in
2001 where he said he had more dollars
than he had since
and so he bought it off the off the
forums from some guy green crack man or
something
and uh he paid you know a couple hundred
bucks for it and got it it was like a
half a half a tree he said he got a real
healthy thing and then like the day
later the guy called him and said hey oh
by the way
you can't sell it you can't you can't uh
give it away
don't do anything with it
and catch you is like that's kind of
[ __ ] up here and tell me that part of
it when i spent the money
and so he was like you know what [ __ ]
this guy and so he just started he was
like made his duty just to send that
bubba cut out to anybody and everybody
like if you hit him up on the forms he'd
send you that [ __ ] cut so if you're
some guy in like nebraska
who's growing like your [ __ ]
ditchweed
seeds because that's what you had and
you can meet the guy and you're looking
for information on the forms and you're
surfing you come across as katsu guy
who's handled he agrees to send you this
cut and the only restriction is you have
to give it to five other people
well you're now the [ __ ] king of
nebraska you know like you've got the
best [ __ ] chronic in there you've
even if you're a shitty grower you start
with good genetics you're going to have
a good output and so you're now growing
the best thing in town everybody's
calling you you're making money all
because this guy you've been on the
forums has just sent you this cut
and since then
all these people that he sent cuts to
have returned the favor and sent cuts
back to him
and so he has this reverse genetic
library that's
quite extensive um east coast saradiso
the chacos that came from him
um
he's uh he you can tell the story on the
bubbles but uh it was the same cut and
and i believe that the whole pre-98
story was that's the only one that
oregon kid knew that he could that for
sure was before 98 that he had the
longest
um and the other ones were most likely
but that that that one cat was the most
likely the one he's had since 90 they
knew he had longer than 98
um but that's what that's what cats who
got it was fun to when i got a tattoo on
the phone i said i said can i get bubba
on the phone let's let's talk that's
three-way the [ __ ] he's like yeah he's
like that'd be awesome so i got bubba on
the phone and that was you know the [ __ ]
coffee book coffee book tables are made
out of but
they were just talking to each other on
how you know
cats really liked the plant and he was
explaining it to it and he wondered what
the cross of it was and you know bubba
came out he was like oh before you you
know before bubba even said uh
uh cats you would guess she was like i
think it's the northern lights and
bubbles like yeah i was looking like
stuff
but
yeah very interesting and and that guy's
uh
a head so he's got like band-aid haze
he's got a bunch of old uh a bunch of
bunch of really old great cuts he's
going to start releasing in s once
um his his scrum he just crossed with
the bubba um he's got above his sister
across with bubble cross kim sis
and so
a lot of really good stuff coming out he
came to me from matt riot as well
so
there you go i guess matt matt coming
out with a good pick
yeah yeah matt you know and i definitely
respect what matt i was just saying uh
when you interviewed him i thought he
had a great interview i called him up
and i was like dude great [ __ ] show
you came across like an [ __ ] but a
guy that i like and the guy that you
know we work with but um you know
sometimes your point of views are a
little [ __ ] dickish on how you say
him but
but he's uh he's a he's a purveyor of
the plant you know and he wants the
truth and
i think one of the best things he said
was you know people tell lies plants
don't
yeah that's some wise words i was like
oh snap
yeah i love it having just discussed at
katsu bluebird and how they're now part
of the catalogue it it begs the question
have you ever considered having cookie
fam on the ct net catalogue i'm just
kidding but seriously
so i had the opportunity to have cookie
fam last year uh
fortune oh yeah oh yeah i turned them i
i turned them down i i dodged i dodged
three bullets last year
so cookie fan was one of them
um and that offer might have came
through
uh bz or those guys that bg could have
come up with them but they had a really
weird setup they were there you know
they they wanted a
they had a really weird setup they
wanted to charge 400 and sell it for 500
and let everybody steal them off you and
auction off for 800.
they were like a 30-something pack and
my deal was that i couldn't you know
just tell me you didn't do cookies
because i know you didn't
and just tell me who's doing this
because if you did it i don't want it
but tell me who's doing the k don't stop
the candy rain
because people are crying and they're
crying and they're upset so yeah i
dodged that bullet but no i can't uh
uh and so and so i'll eat my words but
um
cookie fam as i know it has gone out and
done good things as far as i know uh
maybe public maybe not but jbz is gonna
start breeding for him um he'll there uh
it'll be a collab as far as uh sharing
of the company goes jbz gets you know uh
he gets to bring his collection out and
start working on projects for them um
they get to push their media and use
their you know their social plug-ins if
you will to push the strains
but um i think beezy's a [ __ ]
excellent breeder
uh i think that guy is really cool like
he went through he went through and took
care of all the candy rainbow [ __ ] just
because he didn't want people to get
feel like they got ripped off so he paid
his assistant to like go through their
dms and get everybody's [ __ ] names
and numbers and mailed everybody like
replacement backs of his [ __ ]
just uh so they weren't upset
because i guess it all came down i guess
[ __ ]
he was not to be found
yeah okay that that's interesting
because i hadn't heard that part about
uh jbz making it right by people so
that's that's quite nice to hear
yeah like i asked bj i said i said you
at least stick a stick a sticker in
there and say hey you know just if you
weren't happy with those my name is b
you know i'm busy this is my gear he was
like nah man i just i just put the seats
in the pack and just cut him out you
know
i was like damn i would at least [ __ ]
advertise myself on it you know
i just he's like that wasn't the point i
just want to make it right with people
so these are really uh
really really see i say they're really
good guys but they are to me like
they're nice guys when i talk to them of
course somebody they're gonna be nice
because i [ __ ] pay them i mean i get
that part but bg's a really nice guy
like he's he's a family dude and when i
call him he's cool i've been his dad uh
we haven't played ping pong yet but
we're going to i'm going to take that
old man out
uh
he's
a really cool guy
and so there's you know there was
yeah there's just dramas oh everybody's
everybody's got their egos in the [ __ ]
that's the problem there's drama with
everything and it's hard to stay it's
hard to stay [ __ ] sweden you know
yeah it's so it's so interesting you
phrase it like that because what i've
noticed is that everyone i know who has
interacted with jb's he says he's lovely
and yet he does seem to get quite a bit
of hype and the only reason i can kind
of attribute it to is because he is
quite quiet you know what i mean like he
doesn't he doesn't like project a lot of
stuff out there just kind of does his
thing and i think because there isn't
exactly this huge vocal presence around
him people are just happy to hate on him
in a way
and that could be but he's you know he's
gonna be um of of the guys i know like
i don't know i think i think beezy would
be like the most gangsterous
[ __ ] that would stab me in a
parking lot
like so he's not he's not gonna go out
there and shoot his own [ __ ] horn and
be like hey look at me da
like he can post pictures all day and if
you [ __ ] talk to the [ __ ] he might
just block it because he doesn't give a
[ __ ] but he's just kind of like a
gangster he doesn't you know you don't
you never met a gangster that told you
they were a gangster
and so he's just quiet he doesn't need
to you know say look at me do my [ __ ]
he's let his work speak for him and how
he got started going is uh he was
picking up packs from from those from
his guys there in l.a and they were they
were charging him more like taking a
percentage of all of his packs and he
was like that's [ __ ] up they couldn't
get they wouldn't sell him any cuts and
so he got pissed off and flew to
amsterdam get back some beans
uh started growing his own stuff breed
his own stuff and he started he reversed
it he started charging his homeboys
started taking a tax on their [ __ ]
started selling it to them wouldn't sell
them cuts
and so uh that's how he came out but
he's been in the he's been breeding for
a minute since let's see 2003.
well he's been in it longer than i'd
given him credit for and a catalog you
know he's a he's a super east la gas
type dude so he's got the gassy
nastiness
um but people are into the the cushman's
and stuff right now but yeah nice guy
and you've got his wedding cake force
coming on the line and
yeah
i think what's interesting about his
work is i've always noticed that he was
working on that high octane cube in the
background and no one ever really seemed
to pay too much attention to it and now
that he's got it all solid and i think
it's at the bx3 or maybe even further
and he's now using that male in other
strains and that's really like you said
adding that gassiness to now the cush
mints and the various other crosses
yeah no but and it goes and it goes back
to be like i said
keep your secret secret or circle small
you know uh he's not that guy that
caught you know get caught in any drama
or talking that bad about anybody like
he's like i said he's not the guy to
talk bad or talk do anything he's he's
he's about it you know so
um but he's gotta you know work have it
the numbers that some of these guys are
now able to run you know if you if if
these guys were talented if they were
you know say they were if they were
smaller they were using you know back in
the day when they started they're using
a tent or that garage or something
now the ability for them to run female
hunts of the thousands is [ __ ]
phenomenal
like just just that that sheer ability
and then to be able to go and select
through them seeing the true structure
of the planet like to be able to go walk
through a room like walk through
exotic's room and like see when he's
running out because he see pops
everything so
to run through the phoenix and see it
all you know being of the same or alike
is is pretty quite cool
but back in the day you know these guys
with limited numbers they didn't have
that ability to run so many strains and
kill so many strains you know like it
just didn't happen
yeah and i that's really up in the
floodgates hasn't it
and yeah and i think it's made the guys
that are really good even better because
you know if they were good like i said
that's what i was getting if they were
good with one tent [ __ ] give them a
whole room and now look at what they
look what they can do
and so and and it goes back to you know
mike having that eye like we talked
about earlier you know all the guys that
work with exotic he could pick a [ __ ]
out of a room
um or a
party but uh
but uh that that that ability is just to
notice those traits i think is uh
is really quite phenomenal and then you
know on the large scale
it makes it better and
because they can i mean they can test
their gear more like exotics say you
know he pops i think two packs or three
packs of each of his gear uh to run it
before he sells it make sure it's good
but just to be able to walk through
those rooms and see them and to know
that they're all solid is pretty cool
and back in the day you just said now
that ability
yeah
well i mean while we're on the topic of
cookies peripherally let's quickly wrap
this one up because i love always asking
this what do you think will be the new
cookie cross you know like i mean what's
going to be the new big hype strain
poster child thing
gelato is is this year's thing i believe
that's what everybody's crossing
everything with now is gelato
you know
it's it's weird um
i know things uh
it just depends sorry i was gonna say
you talking about runs in your life up
no narrow runs runs in your life what's
that i've heard this runs
thing dude it's like the shittest meme
ever i love it
it's just about how like runts is like a
gelato crossover gelato s1 and it's just
like all the the [ __ ] boys are on it
they they love it man they want that
runs yeah yeah yeah that's gelato that's
that's this year's [ __ ]
cross to sell if you've got a gelato
then it's going to sell out and be the
[ __ ]
uh whether or not they [ __ ] grow it
or not you know i don't know but
you know it's it also does it all
depends on the breeders like i know duke
you know he's giving me some [ __ ] that
whenever that guy wants to release it
he's going to own it but he doesn't you
know he's sitting on it doesn't want to
release it and like
like some of the stuff he's got is
phenomenal um
his is uh uh uh schmucker's is quite
phenomenal
when are we gonna see more schmuckers
you know because sometimes you you do
see it pop its head up here and there
and i just think maybe the problem is
people don't know what they're missing
out on
yeah i don't know um whenever people
want to be out in the market i don't
know i i know like i said duke's got it
to me a couple times and he's got
something else called sally's beauty
salon
which he tries to just make me guess the
strain he'll just [ __ ] send me street
but
uh
he's definitely sitting on some [ __ ] but
i think you know there's some people
that are they're sitting on stuff too
you know like not everybody believes
that this is a cool and fair market so
they're not not everybody's coming off
their [ __ ] so to say i know that people
have stuff that i've tested and tried
it's like oh when's that gonna see the
light of day and they're like it's not
i'm not i'm not giving this [ __ ] out
but you know i still uh the thing that
was that's that sits in my nose the most
is probably from indo expo this year
denver
uh denver
and uh right at the end of the show this
guy came up and he had [ __ ] uh
like he was two giant it was two people
away from me as soon as he popped the
jar it was [ __ ] maple syrup
like all day long like pancakes and
[ __ ] maple syrup no question and like
and so
brooks was there jason brooks would see
i was like jason i popped the lid he's
like dude pancakes i was like yes
and so his maple syrup all day long and
that that guy had some really really
nice thing of that so if that ever sees
you know you could i was like dude you
could make an entire line around this
thing
wow and uh do you know what strainer was
nope
just something he made
yep i know how to get a hold of him but
it wasn't even something he made he was
popping beans for a guy
wow
so it was just it was so uniquely
[ __ ] [ __ ] dead on maple syrup that
was you know
i was like okay don't lose that plant so
yeah
okay well i mean you've just spurred a
thought in my mind i've been seeing our
friend obsolete post a lot about this
pretzels thing can you give us the
inside scoop
uh yes i can uh hashtag pretzelfam
that's what i'm saying
that's what i got
that's all covered in indian [ __ ] i
can't uh i can't do that
i will say that
i just had some new hats printed up with
his logos on him so we got that done i'm
glad to see him come back out in the
game and uh get back on the on the dm's
or get back on instagram um hopefully
he's not answering his [ __ ] dm so
guys don't dm
but
you know that's what i see a lot of my
breeders a lot of my breeders like the
they're there for their public but at
the same time
sometimes the public can drive them
[ __ ] crazy
like i know duke told me that he was he
spins you know duke will answer every
[ __ ] dm he gets and sometimes he says
it takes three hours
and sometimes people just ask the same
thing over and over again
and so
uh you know maybe just a food for
thought if you're talking to breeders
and they get short chambered with you do
you know
read maybe sometimes but i know that's
what that's what drove obsolete into
being obsolete was two years ago he was
just like academy's like [ __ ] [ __ ]
facebook [ __ ] instagram i'm done
spending six hours my dm and dms mower
and he just got off of it
uh and
unfortunately his sales declined he
became you know uh obsolete if you will
and so which was which was which is
weird to see it was weird for him to be
like the
the tester if you will but yeah he was
he's guaranteed from solid gold to just
being stagnant because there wasn't
anything it was anything pushing it
people don't see pictures it wasn't out
there in the current runs and people
were using this stuff
like uh
um
i don't know i want to believe that part
of the mac is
there's an obsolete in there maybe his
orange congolese
or his orange cookies
yeah
so
interesting it's not the first time
we've heard that sentiment and it's it's
even more fitting that you bring up the
orange cookies because i have noticed
and i'm sure many others have that our
buddies over at jungle boys are gonna
start to be breeding soon is that
something you've been keeping an eye on
no not at all no way that's not that's
not see uh i don't know buyer beware
just
oh
you want to explain
uh i
you sell weed so just because you sell
weed and all of a sudden you're a
breeder like you know what
what to look for and you know how to
breed you know about recessive [ __ ] in
your mind i mean i don't know i like i
like people to stay in their own lanes
and i i think that uh like like i've
always told my guys if they ever see me
[ __ ] making seeds or become a breeder
take your [ __ ] and run like i should i
think that just adds cd to a cd business
um and some of these guys that are
starting to breed that used to run seed
banks i think is [ __ ] i'm like i
can't make this [ __ ] up you guys are
perfect thank you you're just driving
traffic to me because i think it's just
shady when people make their own you
know their seed bank and they make seeds
but
uh
for them to be
so that's facts are facts they got
famous off through other people's weed
colorado's we threw obsolete tweed
through other people's [ __ ] and so
they should just keep getting famous off
other people's weed
uh try to take all the credit like
there's enough food on the table for
everybody to eat
why can't we all just drive the same
[ __ ] cars how we used to
yeah
understandable understandable
and it's kind of like it's kind of like
you know cookie fam like all the people
that bought into the candy range [ __ ]
sorry but if you didn't know that they
didn't make the cookies then you haven't
been doing your research they can claim
it but they didn't do it because if you
did it you can do it again or more so
you have a male
and that's not that's not to say that
that [ __ ]
love childs are bad because you know six
of the top ten were loved childs they
were never meant to be they were
accidents that happened
but for you to claim it or start a
company behind that rep when it was just
mother nature [ __ ] taking care of the
job
um is something you shouldn't do like
you shouldn't you should leave that up
to breeders who go for things for a
reason
so like i always say you know what what
proves it in my eyes or at least for my
bank is that um when people claim
strains is if you did it you can do it
again you have the pieces to make it or
you have the mail
and if you don't then it was a luck
yeah
i can i can get down with that idea
so our so our so that's like of of the
45 or 50 banks i now represent on on the
site there um not one of them uses the
same mail
all different males
yeah right because they used to be a
common thing in the amsterdam days right
like they'd share mails between each
other
right and that's and that's the thing we
all share [ __ ] we all share our
clones around unfortunately sadly as it
may sound as harsh as it may be you know
we all pass the girls around but nobody
shows dick
and so nobody wants to hold on to your
mail for you in case it might go into
flower and [ __ ] up his room just because
you want to have your backup mail
somewhere that's why you always hear
people losing their mails
but uh
yeah that's that's the only way for me
to separate it because nobody passes
around there's not people passing around
males it's people that pass around that
you know the past around clone only or
female plants or they're using female
plants and that's fine but it's the
males that are unique to me
and so like if you take we've been using
exotic a lot just because he's got you
know he just just cleaned up at one of
the last cups he got four cups there are
six cups and four of them he didn't even
go for but
um he could come to me and use one of
his males like i'm not gonna want to
represent that because that would be
taking
you know a selection of his library or
food off his plate you know so i
wouldn't want to represent that that
that stock if he came to me and he took
exotics mail and crossed it with uh with
crockett's tangy and he came up with you
know exotic tangy then that's something
different because now you've done
homework and you've you've you know done
some work um you found a male that was
uniquely yours and now you want to breed
with it and so
that i can support and i will rap
but uh stuff that you know you didn't do
or using other people's stock basically
his stuff and his stuff just to breed
and make something
right now we're not we're not uh
i'm not representing and that's not to
say that those people that are doing
that are bad you know like if you start
with good and cross it with good you're
going to come out with pretty good i
mean
me and x were talking to one of the
shows and um about how you know people
will come up to his booth and they have
better phenos or have found better
phenos than what he currently has
and as we discussed i was like that's
that's part of the game
like if you or you're breeding to
enhance the strength to
make it better and so you don't want
people to come up to you there you know
saying that they can't get your [ __ ] or
make it you know that you're your
strain's the best or your fino is the
best because that means you're just
[ __ ] putting the string out the same
if you're if you're making the strain
better if you're strengthening
it then you're sending out better
genetics than what you started with and
that's what you want people to come back
with this [ __ ] that you have that's
better than what you have
so that's just a testament to you know
breeders when people come up their booth
and bringing [ __ ] that they grew is
better than they started with
yeah of course right me to exceed the
parents a bit of a common idea we hear
but i would love to quickly ask just to
wrap up our last point about the cookies
in the jungle boys quickly
do do you have a little guilty pleasure
strain that comes from one of those
crews i have a feeling everyone does
um
no i can't juggle like i said jungle
boys didn't really they haven't done
anything they they grow good flour
that's nice but the genetics still
belong to the individual breeders that
they used and so i don't know that they
put out anything that i like um cookies
who doesn't you know who hasn't liked
cookies when it first came out i made i
made a ton of money selling [ __ ]
cookie clones
and i think i even had fookies i didn't
have the real cookies i had the cookies
i got funkied
the fortune the fortune cookie the fake
cookie
but uh that's nice i started with a
bunch of those but um everybody likes
that but that's worn out so i don't
i don't know i've always uh i can't say
that i do
i've always just i've always just been a
hater on him because i couldn't i can't
get past the part that you know i think
that st george did it and so
yeah that dog don't hunt
and when when's he gonna pop his head
out
i don't know man um
he's one of those like we're talking
about earlier there's stuff that's out
there that's real that people are i
think they're sit on because they're
still
you know they don't they don't believe
in the legal market or believe that you
know they want to see what plays out and
how people you know let's say that
philos does get away with what they're
doing or let's say that philos comes out
next week and has this crazy breeding
project where they are able to you know
a plant replicator gun pearl powell
well well now they're [ __ ] they're
putting out your [ __ ] that you had just
because other people you know submitted
it so if it never got submitted in the
first place then they would never know
about it they would never be able to
[ __ ] point the plant ray gun
and so there's people out there that are
sitting on things that never want them
in the plant ray gun that way they're
never able to
uh have pieces to remake it or put it
back together again if you will
yeah
okay so
the next thing i wanted to chat about is
kind of something i've been thinking
about myself
when will seeds here now be shipping to
australia and or other ban countries if
at all
where you gotta go there dog like [ __ ]
we may have attempted your wonderful
country and they may have stopped it in
customs couple times send it back
um i'm not sure where we were with our
last
uh
our last game that we played we'll have
to talk and see off the air over that
that went with but
it's really frustrating and this can get
us into a different a whole another path
of
of talks but it's really [ __ ]
frustrating right now with that with the
fact that the farm bill passed in 12 of
which came out and said that you know
anything any any material any matter
anything anything
with less than point three percent ghc
as
as hemp anything above
is cannabis
ghc and so
banking should be [ __ ] legal
um
to australia so the fact that it's so
there's nothing illegal with shipping
seeds if i was to smash up a hundred or
school [ __ ] smash up a thousand but
let's say they were to you know as far
as shipping goes there's they won't come
back and test i believe at the thc mark
these are still you know ungerminated
items and so i don't know why when the
governments are all going to snap up to
it or get through with it and decide
that this is a
miracle plan and and furthermore i mean
i can't just get in my soap box here and
build it
i'll come back down off of here in a
minute but uh furthermore i think that
the [ __ ] citizens of the united
states should be pissed off like i want
to start seeing some like aren't we
upset they're the government that
they're just now allowing this [ __ ] to
be legalized and we're [ __ ] thankful
for them to legalize again [ __ ] you like
you guys have known this [ __ ] since 37
you guys have done this you [ __ ] you
may have had the cure for cancer you may
have had the cure for autism or at least
made life
more pleasurable or enjoyable for those
with those ailments through the use of
this product but you [ __ ] banned it
in 37 and [ __ ] you get out get out of
there
and i don't know why you know i i wish
the
people the states would be because
because we pushed that on everybody
else's [ __ ] like we were the ones
that drove the drove the warhammer
hardest the hardest as far as we will as
far as the other nations that it goes um
and and banned what is now coming to
fruition to be a very helpful plant
um that a lot of us you know grew up
with got shunned for or
you know got familiar dramatized or
[ __ ] over with because we were you
know smoking or self-medicating with
with our uh alternative medicine it's
like no no [ __ ] you like this is the
original that's the alternative your
little chemical pill [ __ ] is alternative
alternative like this is the this is the
original medicine
and so i think that you know people the
states here you know are getting pissed
off they're just now allowing us to to
use this stuff but
it's it's funny that that's
that's what i've seen too is i started
to see i start to see him spinning it as
far as cbd is now coming from hemp
um and media and so it's not like oh
this is this is weed pot marijuana no
this cbd comes from hemp
it's like no [ __ ] it's the same thing
like it's not yeah you don't nobody went
back and [ __ ] told mother nature that
we decided in 37 one was hemp and one
was cbd
and one was cannabis like we did we
didn't tell mother nature the [ __ ]
terms were planned it comes back as
cannabis sativa elf i'm on if i'm not
mistaken
yeah
and so
uh
it's but i start to see the media like
trying to cover their [ __ ] asses by
saying that this is you know from
derived from hemp plants and only from
implants you know or
uh and not giving not getting the full
plant the full attentions do so
yeah no i i agree and i often wonder for
example if people will look back in the
future and think this was like a
almost a hundred year version of like
alcohol prohibition where like looking
back they're like what like why did they
ban it that's such a stupid move like
yeah i think for sure like i said it was
so you know america the only country
that [ __ ] banned the cure for cancer
so you know
uh and i definitely think we'll look
back and especially when i mean we're
still just at the at the forefront of
this [ __ ] we talk about medical uh
medical ailments and different uh the
ability to use isolates distillates and
separate things and put things together
and you know dial in exact combos for
people um which i think will all
fortunately and unfortunately be part of
the future
like in the future like i've seen it
happen too in some of these places now i
don't think i feel very good about it
but
they'll they'll have uh pens they're
just like relaxed
and calm
sleep i think we've all seen those focus
like [ __ ] you you can't i mean like i
get it or put them all together but i
don't know i want this
[ __ ] i want alien orange cookies like
give me that i want shirtless give me
that
so
yeah okay well i mean on to a bit of a
different topic but one i did wanted to
bring up with you again we spoke which
we did speak about in our first
conversation do you think you might ever
get around to i know there's a lot of
other things going on but do you think
you ever might get around to working on
that breeder catalog or is logistically
it's just a bit hard
um i was looking at uh some print on
demand services the other day uh because
i wasn't going back to listen to our
last show but
yeah i think i think i would like to
because i can at least do it with the
brands that we have that are solid and
have the you know the basic the building
blocks and that's what i think a lot of
the breeders have been doing is they
they get the
basic building blocks the strains that
they're notorious for and then they kind
of build off those
um
and so we could definitely do a probably
a catalog uh
okay maybe i always want to do like a
calendar like a
one-year calendar with different strains
of the month as of the pictures
and it's just all cookies right
oh cookies cookie fam and uh
jungle boys yeah just just
doing like a slab squat on like 10 of
the 12 months
yo yo yo yo
[Laughter]
the last two months we'll get our mendo
dope in
drive-by drive-by oh yeah no those guys
oh well you've heard you i'm sure you've
oh so that's another ad addition so we
had uh also voted miss jill since last
time we talked yeah tell me about it
well the same reason that i wouldn't
take other people i was like when she
came to me i was like no no no
uh and she came in in an odd fashion so
let's say that like odie and sonny chiba
were first like hey you should have jill
i was like from youtube like
you guys would be the first ones to
[ __ ] hate her like you guys you know
i've heard very many things come out of
your mouth about her but as they tell it
she's a much different person she's
different than she was when she was
recepcal
and so but i said i told her i said well
that still doesn't change the fact that
you probably learned everything from
subcool and i don't you know i don't
know that i want that kind of breeding
practices i want to support that
and so and she let me know that you know
one of the things about her strengths
her releases is that they're not being
bred by her she's uh she's in collab
with a breeder uh forgetting his name
off top of my head i think it's moses
miles right but uh
he's taking so it's not her it's during
the breeding and she's you know quick to
say that but it's her strains that
you're you know picking them and what
not working through and so i think
that's so that's why i was i said okay
you know that that i can represent
because i don't want to play off the you
know you're this breeder now because
that's not what's going on and if you
are i don't want to represent it because
you'd suck at it because you learned
from from suck sucker and suck and say
no
uh but she said you know she's working
with another guy i was like well cool
that that i think is that i can work
with
so yeah we added her and she's got a
whole jelly line she's coming up with
chili jelly beans and
whatnot oranges and
flavors
yeah i'm glad things worked out for her
and you know and i know people are quick
to hate on sub but i i think it's kind
of sad to see what's happened to him you
know like i think
subs in a bit of a bad place at the
moment
yeah um
i think that
we put ourselves in certain positions by
our certain actions and whatnot but
uh
i hear 7-7 is different from what i'm
told now you know i've never been a fan
of the guy uh who will put back on
exotic again but if somebody watched the
way he talked to people [ __ ] exotic
would have been breeding for him
like that's you exotic well those are
the videos that that guy that he watched
and for as much as i dislike subcool for
you know
i
i get what he's saying but he tries to
take
he tries to do what i don't want to do
like
take
credit for their strengths or for them
being
in positions to win things or to get
notoriety because he was the broker for
everything he wants credit for
doing it and i i get it from being from
broker side where we're distribution and
we we we push certain strains we can you
know we can do these and do those
um
but
the credit still lies in the breeder
like i don't i don't have nothing to do
with it besides
you know get into the customer or making
a suggestion to the customer relaying
the information you give me to them
but and that's where me and some you
know differ on thoughts opinions he
wants he wants credit for distribution
and
you know i think that that it is it's
not a hard pill to swallow but i think
our credit comes from when i get paid
like that's my i'm a broker i move i
move gear um if i don't have uh i don't
have feminized trains whether i like
them or not my customers want them um if
i need them i'll find them and i'll find
breeders there that have them and again
good ones
um
if i want autos i'm not a fan autos but
if you need autos because of where
you're at you're [ __ ] in washington
and so you're going to get an outdoor
crop
that are here and i mean excuse me here
in alaska and that's the only way to get
an outdoor crop and who might just say
that that you know i don't want you in
my competition and buying shitty seats
so let me see let me sign and find some
good ones and see who we could go with
and
uh i i called it two years ago as far as
my festo goes
those guys [ __ ] continue to hit out
of the park they've had some situations
as of late i was talking to mitch
recently
but uh their gear is still that's still
top of my charts i don't know that have
you found many other auto autofilm guys
that are working lines like they did or
they do
i don't want to sell anyone short but
not they're in a league of their own
mephisto
yeah
so
just wish they could scale but yeah
they're
yeah they put in the work right yeah
lots of they do lots of works on those
things that's the thing you don't just
take a plant and flip it over overnight
and make it an autofilm
like
there's some breeding and some some [ __ ]
that's got to go on with inbreeding of
photos and non-photos in your breeding
habits like four times three times each
way
so yeah they
when they realized how much work they do
as opposed to other people don't do they
were a little perturbed
yeah
yeah i can imagine right so it's been a
minute since we last spoke and we
haven't i haven't really touched on it
much on the show because a lot of other
people such as sun grown meds have done
a really good job about it but um
the filos controversy you know like i
wanted to ask how can anyone feel
confident about getting any form of
genetic mapping done nowadays like do
you just have to accept if you want to
get some genetic mapping done if that
shit's going to get sold one day
i think that's what that's where people
have come you know
uh
we we called it a long time ago uh
we
um we were with them for uh for a minute
until they couldn't explain their their
business model to me or talked to ralph
the guys today you know uh
you don't have this this uh
facility these machines these
technicians for [ __ ] seven dollars a
test like that's that's not gonna meet
your overhead what's like what's the
endgame what are you doing with the rest
of that [ __ ]
of that uh
that sequence
um and they and they didn't have an
answer and so
uh
they came out and told leblanc during
the block on his show that they would
never do breeding nishan came out and
said that jerry has it has it on tape
you know nisha and said they'd never do
breeding
so that's kind of it's just
it's really bad it's what everybody
thought was going on was going on like
we all thought that that was the the the
ability or you know at least to give
them a further heads up and start on a
project and
kind of that's what happened um
dunn had him on the day after that or
two days after that story broke
done had him on the show so they could
uh damage control
damage control and it was [ __ ] worse
like i don't know if you listen or not
but they didn't do themselves any favors
like if i was a pr guy out there i'd be
calling finalists right now i'd be like
hey you guys need a pr guy
because they were like he was just
lighting himself up left and right he
was like we never never you know planned
to be breeders but we're just like
we kind of had to be
like oh no
and then they just kept saying like
we'll never sell you information we'll
never sell it and i just thought like
we'll never will but we never will but
the company we sell our ass to [ __ ]
jewel you know like yeah they won't tell
you information but whatever they sell
out to they will and i've heard and i
don't know if it's true or not but i've
heard that
they've uh they've been offered money or
they've tried to sell but they only have
the short code read they didn't do the
long code that's why they can't tell the
difference between cookies and okay gb
yeah that's an interesting one how
things that are clearly different
sometimes show up as the exact same
thing and of course you could argue
there's some close relation but that
does seem like a short sighting in the
technology right
right that's just and i believe that
comes from reading just the short code
on the sequence if they pulled the long
code which is more expensive and more
extensive process when they were doing
these tests then they would have had
valuable data so say because that's what
it all comes down to is data
um and they don't have that or the data
they have is incomplete so they can't
tell the difference right now between
you know on the filos chart as far as
you know cookies and okgb because
they're so the short code shows you know
same same same
but the long code would read them
different
so
well i don't know what truth like i said
there is that that's just what i've
heard
of course everything i say no it's true
on here i'm just a [ __ ] liar and you
know just it's all hearsay yeah this is
all just
for entertainment purposes yeah always
always
so the next thing i wanted to bring up
much more lighthearted point than the
past little bit of discussion but what
is with breeders and their obsession
with breeding pit bulls we've got you
elena bob hemphill and jj that that's
just off the top of my head you know
there's a trend here what's going on
uh i don't know and and jj's pit bulls
this and i'm not a breeder uh i've i
just recently got a mail that uh elena
has bread from green fire
um
and he's just a little awesome stud boy
and he's just already set for a couple
shows but uh i i think it's so so so but
nonetheless uh elena's still a breeder
of dogs jj still with with with with
pitts um micotech also does dogs um
but i think it's just breeders and
breeding
so uh i hate to bring up zonic again
because he's kind of like [ __ ] i
don't know just [ __ ] be his biggest
fan boy this time but i talked to him i
know him he's my guy uh he's breeding
chickens
okay so
okay he's got he's got [ __ ] he wants
black chickens that like green eggs
all right now for if we think about
exotic and the extents he goes to and is
in his cannabis breeding well what does
that mean he's going to what extents is
he going to and his chicken breeding
well that means he's [ __ ] sourcing
eggs from canada
bringing him through customs hatching
them incubating them and then so he has
different [ __ ] ones because they're
because chickens like [ __ ] cannabis
are all gonna be different and so he
hatches them from [ __ ] eggs they get
different ones and then when everyone's
don't make the cut he stitch he's saying
he says oh
because there's one that was like oh
dude that's the winner for sure he was
like nope that one's ended up in the
[ __ ] frying pan i was like no
so but he he made like the [ __ ] w of
chicken huts uh if you look on his
instagram it's like these chicken hats
are all [ __ ] piped and plumbed and
all [ __ ] marbled i'm like god damn
like it was it was a there's a tangent
he went off on but i think it's just
breeders breeding i mean we looked at
archive he was started with orchids
um so my guy amuerta who i'm bringing on
he [ __ ] does pythons
huh
so can i do one
yeah it's a very unusual one and big
pythons and he's [ __ ] smart about it
too
um
but the same uh the same things or
characteristics for color he you can use
it and as same as canvas but once you
gotta let him explain all that because
it was it blew my mind but i don't like
snakes they are [ __ ] nonetheless big
ones that want to [ __ ] squeeze you to
death
but uh i mean i like i don't even like
hugs
[Laughter]
but yeah uh yeah snakes man uh but he
just breeds snakes now he's in the he's
doing cannabis
there you go what a crossover and you
brought up a good little talking point
microtech just released that gg4 ibl
tell me a little bit about that
so my pr uh
i'm not allowed to mention that strain
by its name
oh oh yeah because of that lawsuit
[ __ ]
i don't know but we just try to
avoid the drama but yeah somebody else
put one out now who
i guess you know it wasn't necessarily
josie just she approved but uh
did his own [ __ ] work and he's smart
and got it back to an ibl and has you
know documentation of the [ __ ] thing
and so jose he's even said josie pack
but he's cool with it so yeah michael
tech put it out they flew they who were
gone day one um glad to have tech back
that guy is uh
once again a breeders breeder if you
follow him online you see
he controls the penis envy if you will
um
and uh he's all-around good guy i i i
i like him um and it's rough that gets
us into a different subject but uh
in my mind but um
i i like him god i'm glad we got him
back we're working together again um he
is a really good breeder it's
just this the whole politics of [ __ ]
seeds is [ __ ] you know it's just
[ __ ]
speaking of which i need to come and
visit you i need to come down i need to
come down under
oh mate mate we got a prawn on the
shrimp in fact
you got me shrimp on the bobby
yeah man
hey all right that's not a knife
this is a knife
you'll lose track of how many times
people call you a [ __ ] in an endearing
way
all right i'll come back calling people
cuts
dude yeah you i when i come to the
states i have to like watch myself
because people just use it as like a
substitute for friend
oh yeah that's not what they call here
like girls don't see i don't know most
women do not appreciate the c word
[Laughter]
no i got it i got a female friend and we
probably call each other that word every
day
oh well yeah i've just come to know that
no not a lot of females enjoy that word
if you want you want slapping time
that's when you bring out that word
yeah right that's the difference we
traded we traded guns for the use of the
word [ __ ]
yeah legally well fair enough yeah you
know it wasn't all right trade you know
retrospectively
um
anyway
let's let's get back into this yeah
i thought we're ready though back in
this [ __ ]
oh yeah we would i'll cut that bit out
we're good
so yeah just i mean going on that last
point right it seems like there's a lot
of people in the community who really
kind of only see things in black and
white no shades of grey type thing and
as a businessman you seem well aware
that you can't allow yourself to fall
into this pit for yourself and we can
see the proof of that by virtue of the
fact that there are breeders who you
yourself admit you didn't once get along
with are now part of the seats here in
our lineup so what would your advice be
to people
out there who have these long-standing
grudges and like won't go near a certain
person because of like something which
may even not be related to them like
maybe it happened to a friend or
whatever and it just happened ages ago
what would be your advice you know like
do you feel like people need to take a
step back and trust people a bit more so
you [ __ ] i see you wrote that one
sitting on the toilet huh that was a
good one look at that one good lordy
uh
i think
i think everybody does in general like
a lot of people just because our general
mentality i think some of us have maybe
seen this as a
as a as a green rush unfortunately and
it looked short-term and been like hey
you know let's let's get what i can get
while i'm getting it and that because
that's good enough no you're missing out
on the picture like look at the long
term of this this is an actual industry
in a business now and you can't
you can't treat [ __ ] like you used to be
able to like if you
for instance you had a situation with
somebody in the past you didn't like
somebody you could relatively meet them
at the airport and duke it out and then
one person would win and one person
would get their ass kicked and no matter
whose side were one uh it would be over
and it wouldn't continue to [ __ ]
haunt the channels of facebook or
instagram or any of that [ __ ] it'll be
over and two guys would [ __ ] figure
it out
but now with everybody in everybody's
business
um
[ __ ] just gets it's overblown and
quickly
and
uh i think before we overblow things you
know um
try to reach out that person and
ask themselves and i i don't know i
think i think i was
of course i think i was on the right
side of things because i
judge myself well but
um
recently
somebody posted that
they had a difference with our company
they didn't like they didn't like my
company
and somebody else posted another content
down there
and went back to the original two people
i said hey i said before i say anything
online or before i ask you about
anything about youtube um is there
something i didn't do or wrong or
something in a certain way that i
[ __ ] wronged you for you to say this
thing
because you know those screenshots
showed me with it like hey do you know
about this so i reached out to them and
direct messages instead of just about
putting them up a blast
but the one guy came back to me and said
he said he said i don't know i said i
didn't post that he said my web guy went
through this stuff he doesn't post he's
like i can't get into my instagram
account i can't give him this other
thing but he's like i'm sorry i didn't
post that
i said well it's
not a lot of the [ __ ] adds up you know
it's kind of hard to believe that [ __ ]
but if you're telling me you didn't post
it everything i know about you is that
we don't have a [ __ ] issue then yeah
just do me a favor say something that
you didn't mean to post it or you just
take it down and say you didn't post it
we're cool but
you know even you know
each breeder has their say 10 fanboys
and they'll [ __ ] take a bullet for
them if you will you know what i mean
and so you know their opinion matters
and when
they say something negative about me or
the company
not only does it hurt the rest of
breeders but it's it's it's not good and
those guys are going to take us to heart
their fans
and so i asked him to just trust you
know do a favorite from attraction he
was like he said cool no problem and he
took care of that and that was said and
done with um which i thought was you
know was kind of the way it
could have should have been um but
that's that's weird you know if you look
at that more in depth because then
which i seem to do but
like so that means somebody had to hack
his account
to say [ __ ] about me
to make it look like i was mad at him
and that'll make them too [ __ ] pissed
off each other
like what kind of weird [ __ ] is that
in this world like that
like there's a guy who hacks somebody
else's account just to talk [ __ ] about
me to make me
not happy with that guy
yeah well why
but that in fact is what allegedly
happened because i have no reason not to
believe this other guy
but so i didn't you know i didn't let it
blow out to me i just said reach out to
the guy i said hey do you ever take it
down and say you didn't say it and we're
cool and he did it and it was awesome
and you know i was a nice guy i didn't
have an issue with him to start with him
i haven't issued him now
but um
yeah it's it's uh it's a weird it's a
weird gray area because we're not like i
said we're not in the time of day we
could just
kick somebody's door in or don't meet
with the airport and and we're not still
at
a day where
where we can file contracts and [ __ ]
sue people yet because then you know
that's still frowned upon because it's
legal whatsoever how can you sue
somebody for violating a contract well
it's either that or kick in their
[ __ ] front door and i can't do that
because you guys are calling me an
[ __ ] my lawyer says i'd never win
that case
and so it's a real conundrum of
of what to do and and
and
i don't know that kicking in anybody's
[ __ ] front door is the right answer
to anything you know if we could sit
down and smoke a bowl with them um and
finish it out it'd probably be a lot a
lot better world but that'd be too
[ __ ] easy and that would be drama and
we need drama to sell [ __ ] and so
let's stir the pot a little bit
um
i don't know how that got me on to
thinking about this but one of the
coolest moments i had this past year was
uh
being able to go see the grateful dead
with kim dog
at
um foxborough the same place that he saw
his first show
i i went and saw i've never seen
grateful dead before i've never i never
got it
i was there one of the dead heads didn't
really knew their acid knew their
parking lot knew of course the kim's
story but
um mickey hart one of the drummers
for grateful dead i'd say one of the
drummers if you're not familiar with the
grapefruit bed if you are as a band like
i was cool well here's the thing about
them they're real estates i didn't know
they have two [ __ ] drum kits up there
there's two guys playing the drums
and they're each as i put it to kim dog
and he said i said it correctly he said
he's like yeah that's how you think of
it but
one drummer will finish the other
drummer's sentence
like when they're like if they're like
if they were there to be speech or the
drums are really talking like one
gentleman would finish the other guy
since but the other guy would do other
things in the middle of the other guy's
sentence
and so it's pretty [ __ ] cool to see
both guys going off on all the songs
just playing together
i just know bands that have one drum kit
or one drummer so you see a pair of them
was pretty awesome
um
so he so we met with mickey heart mickey
hearts won the genre she's like 73. the
guy's a [ __ ] animal uh he played
something called the beam which was
super cool we talked in his rv they had
like uh
uh
10 or 12 provists rvs out there which
are like the half million dollar ones
but they're just starting their tour and
mickey and kim dog had done a strain
together or done a collab a release
together
mickey has a brand of moves called
mindful mindset
that's managed by his wonderful daughter
rhea like the greatest sunshine
uh
but they got together and uh
um
the guy who runs the
la store kimbong's friend hooked him up
icy collective
hooked up uh mickey with the 90 the kim
91 and they put that in uh joints that
were three tenths of a gram you got ten
three tenths of a gram joints
right
well yeah so if you think about three
tenths of a gram
it's not a loss
it's like a [ __ ] pinner right it's
like a little joint i'm like oh man
and it comes this cute little tin and
it's cool looks like this little pinner
and look he's like yeah we're looking
about getting the big ones i was like oh
geez but you know you gotta think in
today's market you know some guy that's
smoking the first time which obviously
mickey is not that [ __ ] guy i'll tell
you a story about that [ __ ] but for
somebody who may be smoking the first
time a tenth of a gram might give or a
three tenths of a gram i might get them
high but
yeah they were little pin joints but
you need to get mickey on and interview
him just as far as music goes if you
could ever score that one but so he he
told me he's yeah like basically the
[ __ ] he gave me his history of weed
which is [ __ ] phenomenal um and i'll
relay it to you as much as best as i can
but
the you know he says in 64 65 66 like
they'd have the bricks so they would you
know they call them bricks because they
came to these little bricks you know
they were hard and square you know like
bricks we'd throw the money down and
they'd throw the weed up and you know
we'd keep smoking you know lots of seeds
and stems you know lots of seeds
incentives to say
and then he's like and then i remember
i remember the the other stuff coming
around the 70s that had less less seeds
and stems
so that was good then he was like i can
remember like i think it was
73 maybe
first time we experienced the indica
it was like these guys came up and said
that man we got some way that will
really knock you on your ass and he said
oh we're the [ __ ] dead man what do
you think you got
as you said he's like so we smoked this
stuff and
like an hour later he's like we're just
looking at each other on the couch like
hey you want to play he's like no you
want to go play he's like no we didn't
want to get up man we just didn't want
to play
and the people he's like they're yelling
out there they get all pissed off at us
because we don't want to [ __ ] move
he's like and that's that was that was
the first time we experienced the indica
you know and then and then he went
through how he was growing stuff and you
know how he was had some couple crows
that were unsuccessful but he tried and
you know just like the the history of
cannabis and that band have definitely
got a [ __ ] tie together but it was
really cool just to see him and
kim dog kind of talk about the the
history of themselves together
but even even mickey where he's at
mickey didn't realize that there was
more than one c91 he's like there's i
was like you know you can do different
releases of different brands because you
know me the marketing guy like you know
you can do it kim says you can do a
[ __ ] you know uh kim d and he's like
what do you mean i was like there's
different phenos like what do you mean
i'm like okay
yeah wow
that's incredible story yeah i remember
you posted that up and i was a bit uh
intrigued as to what actually went down
but cool never never would i have
thought he had such interesting stories
but i mean i guess also it should be
expected
yeah and and and definitely [ __ ]
bucket list type of [ __ ] like i couldn't
be more humble that that kim dog asked
me to go um that he's you know i i
consider that guy a friend um he blew me
up a wonka pipe that he made for me um
the guy is really really nice i i like
those guys a lot and him and him and
kim's wife are some good people um
uh
yeah certainly i can attest to that i
mean you know i've met his wife once and
she was lovely bro
yeah she's great so for them to ask me
and and then to have like not just the
experience of it like four tickets but
uh mickey heart to his credit his his
[ __ ] uh production manager was
the most [ __ ] on the ball guy [ __ ]
man ever like this guy had [ __ ]
15 irons to the fire and he's just fired
in all directions boom boom boom boom
boom it's as nice as he could [ __ ] be
just a really excellent road guy but he
was in his mickey's personal answer but
the guy was [ __ ] on the on the ball
but he uh he got us hooked up with a
sweet
and so it was stocked it wasn't you know
it wasn't it was stock of popcorn and
water drinks and stuff and then he
hooked us up with uh backstage tickets
so we got uh we got backstage and we're
like you know pretty much like the only
pair that we're back there
while mickey i'm a free family with a
show but i guess they call it drums in
space that's like a break for the for
the for the band and then mickey and uh
the other drummer and the almond brother
come up and they do
like this [ __ ] awesome thing of drums
and bells and [ __ ]
and it was really just really cool to
see it from firsthand because i'm used
to you know making music production on
the dance music side which is you know
if you want a [ __ ] symbol or if you
want a hi-hat you just add a new bar and
just cut and paste a little hi-hat right
there and then you're cool um in the 60s
if you needed a [ __ ] cowbell every 12
beats well you need a guy to [ __ ] hit
the cowbell every 12 minutes you know
what i mean like you couldn't just
[ __ ] cut and paste that guy in you
needed to do to over there just be you
know knock on this other you know this
opposite
rhythm that you're doing and hitting the
cowbell weirdly and so uh just to
witness that [ __ ] then he played like i
said this beam thing which
earlier he had talked to us about man
just
oh
i don't know yeah
sitting sonically sending images through
your mind to you by the use of of of
scanning
through drones
like suddenly sending your drones into
your mind and getting you to like
remember a [ __ ] feeling about a
product
and and you think it's it's crazy but
then i wouldn't do it i look him up and
like do my research on the guy and
mickey heart is like he's not just a
[ __ ] grateful dead drawer right but
he's like this accomplished [ __ ]
world musician like he's got all these
[ __ ] uh uh scholars and credits for
you know world beat doing this you know
south africa [ __ ] doing this european
[ __ ] it's like wow this guy is
seriously into the sound of percussion
of bass and [ __ ] beats and
what if that's true
like as smart as this [ __ ] guy is
like what if he can sonically send me
[ __ ] in my mind like images that make me
recall a [ __ ] flavor
like [ __ ]
so when he was playing it like i got him
on camera he's looking at me i'm like
dude you're beaming people on here he's
like i asked him i said you're gonna
play the beam tonight you gotta send
some drones she's like we'll take it out
for a spin
oh [ __ ]
that's interesting you're like like so
talented in so many different ways for
just one particular really weird kook
yeah but
i don't know i i don't
i don't think it's parkour i think it's
you might be able to send people sonic
messages through the [ __ ] sound waves
and make them recall a strain
like that's basically what it was is
that i can by scanning your barcode i
can send you sound drones that make you
trigger that thought
yeah it's pretty wild stuff well
yeah
it's it's out there but as accomplished
as he is you know you look at all this
[ __ ] cratchit like well
maybe he's onto something here you know
it's weird it's weird until it's [ __ ]
not you know
yeah
well
maybe we should depart back to the realm
of regular cannabis all right sorry
i took it i took it down detour that was
that was a good little detour let's um
something i i didn't ask you when i
should have um how do you feel about
last year's emerald cup you know it was
a little different wasn't it
oh
man
so last year in world cup was uh there's
a few situations that we uh
had to overcome that made the show a
little more difficult than average than
usual
we played by the book um i i thought
this is a little early for california
have seen the sale but we played by the
book anyways
um
and uh
paid out an enormous amount of taxes
28.13
which uh made me
take a huge loss on [ __ ] because i only
we didn't do the math right and so
yeah we paid a total dollars 28.13 taxes
to
uh all of the this the city's taxes in
the state taxes
so that was a chunk
of money um
they just it didn't it didn't go as
smoothly last year as we would have
liked at all we appreciate
all the customers that did wait in line
but you know after i heard what had
happened on saturday i was little it was
a little rough and we weren't
we weren't able to basically that he was
almost so mobbed with people and i'd
even come to him
the night before the day you know two
days before i said okay so what kind of
um you know i'm thinking like you know
aircraft aircraft lines like the zigzag
zs kind of stack people in like what do
you have planned for crowd control and
you know
she had i had found out earlier that
week that we were right next to [ __ ]
calculator and mike in exotic
and i'm like you know we're [ __ ] like
i've got 10 banks here in my five booths
and those guys overflow weren't [ __ ]
um and sure enough uh we were [ __ ]
so it was a big [ __ ] show uh the lines
didn't get made properly people were
getting in line just to get in line i
was told
um
so
uh
once again i didn't see any of the music
none of the bands i didn't get to talk
to other people it was it wasn't this it
wasn't as good as it was to be
recreation recreational [ __ ] it up and
i'll always say that i'm not i'm not a
fan of recreational people say oh my god
how can you not be a fan of
recreationally the devil no i'm a fan of
of decriminalization
not recreation because that recreation
allows [ __ ] big farmer man
decriminalization would have kept it
[ __ ] mama pop
but
too late now [ __ ]
[Laughter]
oregon's sitting on six years of [ __ ]
weed right now like
we haven't even [ __ ] come to crop yet
and they're sitting on six years supply
what do you do with a six year supply
because you don't leave it on the
[ __ ] shelves that's for sure you
gotta blast that [ __ ] in oil
because six years from now that weed's
gonna be brown frowned
oh man it'll make some uh very top shelf
cuts i'm sure
yeah
exactly and then that's right you know
and and to that you know kooky oregon
but they also passed legislation to try
to export weed
and what did it pass
no they've written they're trying okay
so it says they can export to different
states
well
that's what the brokers are
they're probably bad for them so yeah do
that
yeah because because oregon is you know
they have the demand of of 300 000 in
the supply for 3 million like la has the
supply for 300 000 the demand of 3
million
and so logistics are reversed
jesus yeah it sounds like if you knew
what you were doing and you set up an op
in la like it you know like why would it
not work
pretty much what i've come to see here
what i've come to hear is that uh it
seems to you know
it's just anywhere you can buy wheat
easiest is pretty much where it's where
it's been i don't know like the
california market came and went very
[ __ ] quick like it just
you knew it would i think um i think
it'd go this quick but it it came and
went and i i avoided it like the [ __ ]
plague so
cool
it's it's a it's a mess like a lot of
you know it saddens me because a lot a
lot of good people are gonna lose good
money because they're going to get
[ __ ] swallowed or because the price
is going to get too too low or they
can't afford like it just doesn't make
money
to
continue to produce at like
600 a pound you know [ __ ] they can't
do that you know about 50 grams and i
could be able to take that [ __ ] off the
ground
so
uh so a lot a lot a lot of good people
are gonna lose money on farms because i
think that you know because the guys are
doing it big are doing 100 million style
you know you're talking 10 greenhouses
all [ __ ] online with custom controls
and virtual integration and they're just
going to be able to slaughter through
weed to where mom and pop who thought
they had the money to do it they're
going to try their [ __ ] dampest but
the price gets too low to produce it
you're not
yeah
that's a bummer
definitely definitely
i'm a [ __ ] bummer today damn it no no
no it's all interesting and i mean it
kind of plays into the next question in
the way that like you know the mum and
pops are being forced out in a sense but
like recently we saw and you almost
referenced it earlier like seth rogen
has brought out that whole houseplant
line and it kind of seems inevitable
that more and more celebrities will
embrace cannabis and try to carve their
own little spot in the industry do you
think there'll come a time when they
kind of get it right or do you feel like
kind of like a lot of parts of the
cannabis community you've got to kind of
have paid your dues before you can do
that type of thing
well i'd never think they'll get it
right unless they're doing it for the
right reasons at least i've never i
never hope people get it right unless
you're doing it for the right reasons
but i don't think that
you know joe blow off the street who's
been not to say joe blow because his
name is joe rogan um not to say that
that the guy doesn't know is cannabis
but um he may not be as as schooled in
the knowledge of [ __ ] cannabis as
somebody else's who's been in the
industry a little bit longer you know as
i'm sure that person's not as [ __ ]
schooled as schooled in in
uh
fight technique or as and and talking
about stuff or and interviewing people
um
and so once again stay in your own
[ __ ] lane
i think if you want to get behind a
product and brand it
or you know uh do something for that
then you know you got to pay the person
to play the game but
if it's if you're just going to get into
something just make money off of it then
you kind of i don't know i don't
you want to yes things have to be made
for a profit but
people did this [ __ ] when it wasn't
profitable and that's what we have to
remember
is that there will come a time when the
shit's so low we kind of forget
what people went through to [ __ ] get
us where we are today
and that goes to kind of i don't know
talking about people you don't want to
make sure customers buy that you know so
with the new website launch we're going
to put up a lot of photos which include
me and all the breeders something that
stands out between me and just about
every other bank is that i personally
know every single breeder on my bank
i've talked with them i have their cell
phone numbers i can call them on sunday
they'd [ __ ] answer the phone um they
called me on sunday i'd answer the phone
um i have a good relationship with all
my guys that's [ __ ] hard to do when
you look at you say all of them i see
yeah
all of them i've met
all my guys
uh i have to and i have to look and
reset that statement since i've added um
where if i haven't met him yet and i
haven't met pioneer valley
but other than that i've met just all my
guys which um
gets me the back to the none of my 40
guys use the same mail and so it's
important to support
and and fund the guys who did it when
they shouldn't have been doing it if you
know what i mean like who took the risks
and who risked [ __ ] jail time and
their families and their you know their
freedom basically to you know yes to
profit but as well to [ __ ] you know
to push the plan and to breed and
continue doing it
yeah of course you know you need to
reward the people who took the risk in
the old days
but a lot of it's easy though right now
like you can just go and buy anybody's
crosstalk thing and i think you know
especially you know hopefully all the
breeders will pick up licensing deals
and they'll be with branded cannabis but
you know i with all the states coming
off weird if you don't you're going to
go to you know missouri and you're going
to get cookies and cream off the shelf
and it's not going to be the same that
it tasted like in [ __ ] washington or
it's not going to be the same as it
tasted like in california and that's
unfortunate but they're going to be able
to to say it's curious and cream because
they got a tent back and they popped it
but it's not really the true
representation of what you know exotic
may want them to [ __ ] you know
use as cookies and creamer or say that
is this is cookies and cream because by
giving something bad a good name doesn't
change the fact that it's bad you know
this just means more people are going to
say yeah i had that it was bad
so
uh
uh that's that's that's rough that's the
features talk kind of stuff but um you
know i see that being a thing like when
you want to go to a different state you
want to have the same thing that you
smoke or that you're you're used to
you're not you're not smoking is
something that this goes back to crap
kings which i'll just beat on him some
more like we did last year or last time
but uh when you buy [ __ ] blueberry
you want to be dj shorts blueberry like
i i just i'm gonna i'm not a mind reader
but once people ask me for blueberry i'm
nine tenths out of the
time pretty sure that they don't want
[ __ ] crap kings blueberry they want
the blueberry that came from dj short
that tastes like blueberries
not just the one that comes in a
different package that says blueberry on
it
yeah so
so it's it's
kind of marketing you know like
all of our stuff generally
what says on the package is what it is
like that's you know you can't can't
thank the funk as was told to me once
so i think it's important that people
when they buy their and they buy product
or buy flower that they support you know
breeders and brands and licensing deals
yep 100
something i wanted to
run by you though we've seen it happen
you know sporadically but do you think
that we will see pollen being sold going
forward and
how do you think that'll change the
landscape of things if it happens
um i so like uh i still do a guy now
james kerr who's in canada and he does
pollen already
he sends out pollen crosses stuff
and
you know i for the
your your interview with breeder steve
was really good i like i like breeder
steve that i love his his premise we're
just says you know just [ __ ] plant a
seed just as long as it's a c just
[ __ ] plant it i don't care where you
got it just plant it in the ground get
it wet [ __ ] make it explode like get
a seed
and so i think that that is is really
good and so um so for the home breeder
who wants to do stuff great you know buy
some pollen and [ __ ] breed with it
but um you know you get your own male
make your own [ __ ] pollen i mean it's
not that big of a deal as far as
people selling their pollen like
i know that
when collabs certain columns have
happened that there's the amount of
pollen that has been given is is very is
weighed you know it's very
scrutinized because with pollen you can
do anything with it
so when people are giving it up their
pollen
to make a collab
let's you know like there's not a lot
going there and because the breeder
doesn't because once again the only
thing that separates all 40 guys is
they're males so if you have my pollen
then you can you can do what i did
you don't need my [ __ ] anymore if you
got my mail
so
so i don't know i don't think i don't
see the breeders giving out pauline to
their [ __ ]
i know dj shorts talked about it
i know dunn's talked about put him in
different packages
but
as as
as highly guarded as the males are that
i mean as as that's the only thing that
makes people unique because we all start
with the same gorilla glue four cut the
cut you have is most likely the cut i
have if they're legit cuts because it's
all just a branch of a branch of a
branch
they always have a [ __ ] unique seed
or different pheno it's the same [ __ ]
thing
just cloned
and and so what makes it different is
the male that we use with it and even
though i may have the same male that's
the same strain it's genetically not the
same male
like if my wife and me had a kid and i
died i got hit by a bus my wife and my
brother couldn't make another kid that
was as good looking as my current kids
you know what i mean
like it's just it's just genetically not
possible it's you'll get close to kind
of like most likely of
but it's not genetically possible to
duplicate without this the same male and
so
well that was what makes people
different
um i
don't see it happening on at least by
you know
breeders
i'm not i'm not telling you the thing
that i'm doing because then you can
[ __ ] do it yourself you don't need me
i think you just take it across with
everything
no
yeah
well just to jump back to a point you
spoke about earlier in regards to the
forums you've got going we've seen a few
forums pop up recently calculator having
copied my [ __ ] yeah i have the idea they
[ __ ] copy it within a day that's it
so like why do you think we're seeing
these forums pop up what do you think it
is about the forum that people are
missing and why don't you see it taking
off more quickly
i think the forums will probably back up
because mark zuckerberg [ __ ] hates
cannabis
and uh we're going through the genocide
right now of cannabis and so if
instagram and
facebook can delete all these videos and
take down all these pictures and
accounts then we'll basically delete the
history of
the people who did it to get where we
are today and in 10 years from now
you're going to google a chrome video or
you won't be able to find out any of
this information because youtube [ __ ]
took down the channel or blocked the
account or erased all the [ __ ] because
mine most of us don't print out our
pictures on instagram we don't have
[ __ ] copies
and so when instagram deletes the
account that's that's everybody's
history and on it goes
but uh and so i think that they're just
because we've been shut down 17 times
jesus all right our instagram sucks
right now i mean
shout out twice it's my instagram guy
love everybody but uh it sucks because
we have [ __ ] handcuffs on us like we
can't do nothing we get told if
there's a price anywhere in the picture
we get [ __ ] we'll get flagged if we
do any type of video we get flagged like
i put up videos now and they're [ __ ]
seriously flagged within like five
seconds
it's up and it's it's automatically boom
through the community standards
like how did you even already so my
accountants must be being watched
but yeah our current instagram account
has like six items on it because we
don't keep anything on it that way they
can't go back for history and shut us
down
and so you know there's no way to like
document your online presence if you're
not using like an instagram account to
[ __ ] save your history
and so i think that on the forums that
people like
myself from cap have that you know
i own the hard the servers that they're
on i have the servers backed up and so
where i always have that history i'm not
going to delete accounts
yeah
okay so it's it's like a
like a preservation thing so you don't
just lose everything
kind of i think that's what people are
looking at you know um kind of get back
to the forums and the days where they
can they could grow you know and also
maybe the novelty of you know yeah yeah
i can it's california i can grow weed
now but i don't know how to [ __ ] grow
weed
you know
like how do i grow lead and so
um i think people are also looking to
reach out and find that and not get the
trolls that are on instagram or the
drama that's on instagram but still seek
the knowledge of how do i grow this out
and and
from a grower's perspective and from
british perspective how do i put my
information out there and make sure that
it's not going to get taken down or make
sure that it's not you know all these
conversations and all these grow tips
i've been giving people aren't just
going to be [ __ ] deleted one day
because somebody was pissed off at me
yeah well i mean
i think we're going to see more of the
forum rise anyway because it's you can't
track a story on instagram over a long
period of time
like that's that's what a thread does
perfectly on a forum yeah i think we
just have to get them so you know it's
gonna have a good web app and i think
forums could definitely work but people
have to be able to scroll from their
phone
yeah it has to be more accessible
because forums were so cumbersome on a
phone
yeah
yeah interesting okay well
have you
or have you yet to see something that's
truly kind of unique and just truly
coming out of left to field you know
like what's what have we got to get
excited about that's not recycled
um
well everything that my new guys have
they're putting out it's all new and
[ __ ] exciting
what kind of questions that killing me
here uh
everybody's new releases are all going
to be new and not recycled and [ __ ]
great um
[Laughter]
before and while before on that note i
would just like to say that you know i'm
james b and i'm a broker for the
following brands aficionado archive west
coast big island bog seeds
cannerado coastal sieve crockett family
dirty water organics dj short seeds
dominion seed exotic genetics free worm
selections crampon buns siege green fire
genetics green light genetics green team
genetics green skull seeds homegrown
natural wonders humboldt seed company
iron genetics karma genetics catsuit
seeds the final labs loud seeds like a
dog see man pharma genetics massive
seeds mephisto micro tech misjill
obsolete pacific northwest roots
relentless riot sagemaster selects
second generation genetics sea junkie
serious seeds snow high soul fire swamp
boys swamp donkey gh seeds the seed
company thug pug thunder fudge top dog
and last but not least utopia farms
there
and thank you very much and uh please
don't blow up my phone she didn't
mention you on the phone on the show
so you're so popular like if i don't if
i miss you on the show a lot of my guys
you give me a [ __ ] last year they were
like oh you didn't say anything about me
i was like i was thinking about you
so yeah so now i set them all so look
this is the equivalent of like mom
saying i love all my children equally
follow my children equally because i do
that's the thing about us when you go to
another breeder at his booth he's gonna
want to sell you his stuff if he's any
good you know he can't blame that's what
he's there to do you gotta pay for his
[ __ ] booth he's gonna sell you his
seats if you come to me at a booth and i
don't have all my guns because i don't
sell like
so one of my things is if i i won't sell
c to the same show that my breeders do
and so if my brother's taking money out
of his pocket he's there at a booth i'll
pull his genetics off my table and refer
people to him
and so like at the emerald cup if you
come up to me and say you want the best
land race [ __ ] sativa that i have
well i know that i'd love to say
something that i have on the table but
actually if i if i point out to you to
go to walk down the snow high's [ __ ]
uh booth and tell him that you want a
jamaican
you want the jamaican
uh you got 17 weeks
weeks to waste then you know there you
go uh
and and so i'm not biased on any
particular one like clear
see situ now is here to make sure you
find the strain that works for you like
i'm not here to push one brand or the
other um if you want that's that's nice
thing about it if you want something
gassy i got [ __ ] 40 brands to pick
from let's find the gassy thing i'm not
just we're not just focused on one
one specific goal or one one type of
thought thinking you know
like
the nice thing about all these all these
breeders is y'all they'll breed for
different reasons they're all breeders
because they're [ __ ] crazy but they
all look for different things when they
breed you know maybe it's maybe it's
short as a flower or maybe it's you know
trypton production or maybe it's [ __ ]
squash sauce you know who the [ __ ] knows
but they'll breed for different reasons
that's what makes it all unique
um
and and and
especially in their own unique way
so
that's that's really cool uh
got a [ __ ] stone together i forgot
what we were talking about but yeah
uh all the all the different brands are
cool and it's and i think it's fun to
you know i used to get orders and i'd
see like a pack of exotic and then a
pack of snow hi
i'm like man that's
that's different like the guy who's
buying an exotic which is
pretty much you know
dense snugs frosty [ __ ] you know
sunshine uh order and and grabs a pack
of snow high which will be like a land
race alchemical gold
i'm like man that's that's different
like
that's you know very opposites opposite
into the spectrum but at the same time
there was that alcohol gold is fun to
run
like some bodies gear some of that stuff
it may not be good on a
giant scale or on a on a big scale but
if you like growing plants and are
excited just to see different things and
what mother nature can do and just love
the [ __ ] plant
different breeders
have different plants and so you know if
you use land races those grow distinctly
different than something that's been
seriously worked and by growing them out
you'd be like oh yeah i can see where
that would need to be worked like that's
why you cross it with that because it's
a [ __ ] that's i don't like it by itself
you know you'd want to cross it to make
this or i see why that person bred with
it because he wanted to make it you know
this
and so i think it's fun to grow if you
like genetics you just like growing grow
different people's seeds like don't get
just stuck on one breeder
yeah i 100 agree that's a great great
message
i think that we are basically onto the
tail end of things now so we're going to
start to do some of our more quick fire
answers before we get to the last final
but
how can a new breeder go about trying to
get your attention what are some of the
things they should be doing to be
ticking the boxes
um they should be
uh and and
for first of all foremost once again i'm
a nobody i just run a bank and i had an
idea like in 2010 where i could help my
friend and have taken
certain steps and certain risks and
rewards and they've done certain things
to to
be a broker for certain cannabis
breeders and so i do nothing more than
i'm just a broker but uh so
um
i do try to keep things in line though
so
to add the to our phone to our our seed
bank of course first and foremost
generally we need it's nice if you have
good customer service if you're a dick
then people won't like you that's that's
that's you know we don't want to bring
on those customers that said
some guys you may have had on the show
are a dick and they're not the best
customer service guys but we still
support them so but you want to
generally you want your customer base to
like you because that's who that's you
at the end of the day buys your packs
these guys that you work with
you want to be using your own mail
like even if so-and-so gave you
permission to use his [ __ ]
well now you're just giving credit to
two different guys and if they wanted to
make that cross in my eyes they could
have made that cross
but they didn't want to
and if they do then let them make money
off of it so find your own mail as as as
minimal or as weird as it may seem
that's at least showed the industry the
people that are buying that you have
something that's unique to you and that
you've done something on the on the
breeding side of it you've looked into
it some somewhat
um
so that's that's first and foremost uh
and you know i don't think it's good to
copy other people's [ __ ] i don't think
it's cool to you know
copy this with that and just call it
this you know i think you should have
the genetic thing and have a
as as as well as much as you know
at the time
that this was real that you agreed with
it and make it make it so but i think to
mislead people is wrong
yeah
definitely
so so pretty much that you just gotta be
uh you know most likely i don't know if
you're trying to get my attention it's
too late
no um but i i i i'm not really i mean
but that being said when i when i went
looking for new banks i got you know
five that were suggested to us that were
you know really good guys that i'd just
been sleeping on so i don't i don't know
everybody and it's not it's not the
it's not the golden ticket to be on the
bank you know i mean you still all my
guys in the bank still promote their
gear you still have to have to promote
your seat your stuff and build your
clientele base and interact with your
clients i mean that's
that's a big thing i think if you know
people buy gear they want to interact
with the breeder they want to talk to
the guy who did the thing or get his
his insight onto it um and i think if
breeders would interact with their
clientele base more they'd uh maybe have
more sales and be
you know more successful in certain
areas
yeah definitely definitely a bit of good
uh
pr doesn't doesn't hurt at all so i
think now we're on to our super quick
last one so
let's bang out these ones yeah what's
the most memorable strain you've ever
smoked
so you say that one again sherballs
oh what's that
sherbet and fruity pebbles
oh is that
yeah yeah
yep there's a green pheno there's a
purple pheno
and it's still alive and yeah it was
[ __ ] amazing it really was because
like the first two people like one of
them was the guy at the gas store i
didn't even know his name you know i
mean he was just the guy at the gas
store
but he would he he'd always hit me up
for herb um so i just like popped the
case on it and dude was like
cereal like what's that cereal fruity
pebbles and i was like oh [ __ ] and the
second guy did the same thing i was like
oh man you know you really know you got
something when you tell when they tell
you what it's what it's called before
you even have to tell them
like fruity pebbles are like yep that's
[ __ ] it so
lovely so on the opposite end of the
spectrum what is the worst strain you've
ever smoked
since we're on a [ __ ] hate project
candy rain
oh
you smoked it we got some in
massachusetts some people brought some
to mike's booth
and it was it was like i took photos of
it next to everything else it was just
sad
and it was i don't think it was you know
it wasn't the grower because grower had
brought other things in with him as well
but it was just
sad
yeah obama all right sorry
i was like dude i'm even impressed you
got one to go like i heard there's two
out of 35 so
yeah the numbers don't lie so if you're
on a desert island and you can only take
three strains with you what three
uh
three strains
we've played this game before i think i
have to be all witty and i should have
said like you know i'm a breeder so i'm
supposed to be like uh i'm not i'm a
broker guys so it's supposed to be like
land race and [ __ ] like northern lights
and haze
and because i can make everything else
from it but i can't because i'm not a
breeder so like i'd say that i'd say the
witty thing the way i could make
everything else from it but i don't know
the witty thing uh i'd probably take
shirls with me i'd probably say uh
uh
morning
steve sativa star
the uh star plant um
i probably do
i don't know
uh i know for a third one
thin mint
no no never never never never
never probably probably can be just
because uh it's it's very potent
she does hit the spot
knocks me the [ __ ] out yeah all right
all alrighty now i know that you used to
be a grower as you revealed in our last
discussion so i want to know what is the
one clone that you used to grow out and
you just miss not having that weed
around anymore
so miss um
i'm just not having my my weed around
anymore period
like while you when you're growing you
[ __ ] like when trim trim gel happens
and you guys do trimming and you hate
life you're like god why
but and you say like i'll never miss
this but like
there's times i miss trim jail and i
miss just going out in the plants just
sitting out there with the fans on and
with the tables going and just sitting
out there and just thinking like i
missed i really really do miss that
people people probably take that for
granted like oh yeah i'll [ __ ] want
my plants but i think there's really
something between
you know plants and humans i think every
kid like in school i think they should
[ __ ] grow plants just to get that
responsibility and that knowledge that
if you don't come home and it's not if
you don't water this thing it's gonna
[ __ ] die
and so um i think there's that that kind
of synopsis is really cool between
plants and humans but so i missed that
uh clone would be
probably the romulan i had a raw million
way back when um when i was djing i had
it and deep water culture and then i
flew out to do a gig over new year's
and i had to put chains on to get out of
tahoe when i came back the tree had
fallen over my front yard and shut the
power off of course if you're in deep
water culture even [ __ ] tahoe and the
tree fell over because it was covered in
snow
while all your [ __ ] water froze
so all those plants died cold cold death
um i was able to salvage nothing pumps
turned off plants died it was ugly
that's when i decided okay you're gonna
be a dj are you gonna be a [ __ ] weed
grower or what are you doing
and i was gonna go to seattle and open
up at uh a weed uh or a uh
grow store
a garden center as i was supposed to be
called
yeah
there you go you made the right choice
by the looks
yeah yeah yeah dj scene was getting
played out it was it's all fake and not
cool kind of like cannabis right now
it's getting played out [ __ ] people
are killing me here
but no it's uh
me and duke now me and duke have alluded
to this it's just a little extra juicy
gossip at the end but we have
a strain that we're going to release
next year mj bizcon
now this yeah
it's the pre-37
dust bowl
okay this shit's [ __ ] drought
resistant
mold milder resistant
uh like you have to [ __ ] water this
[ __ ] it was so strong in 32 that's why
they made it illegal in 37.
and that shit's been gone like off the
face of the map now all we have is this
new watered down [ __ ]
but like if you get that pre-32 with it
before they made it illegal oh man and
duke's got a line on it so we're going
to sell this [ __ ]
next year mj biscott put on some suits
some shiny shoes and sell it
so i know people have talked have heard
me talk in the past about the
32 dust bowl so
that's how that's out of the wagon now
god i think that might be the perfect
note to end it on
thanks dodgers [ __ ] really right
with that being said do you have any
shout out to comments you'd like to make
oh yeah of course i got let's go through
all my breeders again okay uh
this is our that's where you cut and
paste insert that part i'd like to thank
all them for working with us and
trusting with us please know and trust
that if your breeders [ __ ] with us
then they trust us they know that we're
selling their gear i work with all these
guys you can ask them about us um they
wouldn't be working with me if it wasn't
if it wasn't good for them it wasn't
good for me and so i wouldn't be a good
guy if i didn't have other trust and i
do so um that i'd like to shout out my
office team
um everyone from my mom works customer
service lines to bear to rebel to dusty
of course to heather to rob my sales
guys my trade show team
um all those guys that go to work every
day and uh manage the office and get all
the boxes out where they need to be
like think on my legal team for [ __ ]
with the [ __ ] keeping people off my
ass keeping the haters away with the
haterade
uh
i'd like to
thank trump for [ __ ] up the world
uh non-political though of course
i'd like to thank you for uh having me
on because really i'm just like i said
just
people give me more credit than i have
and maybe i just need to give myself
more credit but uh i just started this
to help a buddy in 2010 and just
proceeded to do it and i was thinking
about it earlier this morning too
as much as i dislike this other person i
started for and and i will not
give him any name mentioned therefore
not giving him anything but
i learned things from him that i
continue to use this day as far as
what i think is good and bad and where
last time i was on the show me and matt
ryan weren't
friends so to say
now i you see he's on my bank and he
talks good about me and i talk good
about matt ryan um the guy is passionate
about what he does doesn't mean
everybody [ __ ] agrees with him
doesn't mean everybody likes him but is
he passionate about what he feels and is
he you know putting out work yes sir so
my my original breeder so the guy who i
first started with for three years four
years so i don't want to give his name
any credit uh i did i did like i said
learn things i used to this day that um
that helped me and my my ethics as far
as business goes as far as
you know
can't use other people's stuff and you
can't rename things there's not you know
he taught me a lot of those things that
i still use that i still you know
consider holy if you will although he
turned out to be unholy and a dick um
his
his methods
once again like all breeders his methods
and trying to relay his message were not
the greatest
but is he meant right
and
so you know he can take something from
any from everybody even people you don't
like and people you years down the road
that you hate but you can still learn
something from everybody
most definitely i agree wholeheartedly
well with that we might wrap it up so
thank you so much again for taking some
time out of your busy schedule to come
chat with us mr bean
no problem thank you very much and i
appreciate you and your time and like i
said you do you had a heck of a job and
appreciate you being diligent and always
having to show up and i'm sure that your
followers and fans do as well so thank
you and nice job last year thermal
company nice job
[Music]
[Applause]
so a big big big thank you to mr bean
for taking the time to join us today
as well as dropping all the knowledge
bombs and inside scoops
a big shout out as always to the patreon
gang
if you guys are looking for more content
go check it out we've got extra
interviews on there
and finally a big shout out to our
sponsors as always seeds here now best
in the business
radio ridge nursery need i say any more
you looking for that nookies cut from
swamp boy
or maybe even a special body keep a cut
get him up
[Music]
and as always organic gardening
solutions dragonfly earth medicine we
love you guys
i will see everyone
and
next episode
thanks so much for hanging around
[Music]
i'll see you
so
[Music]
yes
so
[Music]