[Applause]
[Music]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts
this episode we are incredibly lucky to
have jesse of biovortex to come on the
show today chatting all things black dog
his breeding plants regenerative farming
and so much more
as always we're incredibly grateful for
our fantastic sponsors seeds here now
number one in the game guarantee on
satisfaction not just germination check
them out all the latest drops the
hottest breeders if you want it they've
probably got it i recommend them
big big shout out to our friends at
copper biological they've got everything
you need to keep your garden pumping
happy and healthy be it beneficial
predators beneficial feeds to keep those
guys alive or microbial solutions check
them out to keep your garden happy and
healthy producing top quality
likewise a huge shout out to our friends
at the patreon gang they're truly the
lifeblood of the show and we're
incredibly grateful for their support if
you want access to early content
additional episodes or heck even a few
little bonus goodies go check it out
patreon forward slash the podcast
i hope you're ready for a good one let's
strap in
and let's get into it
alrighty so a big big big thank you and
welcome to the regenerative farming
warrior an exceptionally talented
breeder jesse of biovortex thanks so
much for joining us today oh great to be
here thank you so much i've enjoyed your
show so much over the years oh man
you're too kind and i appreciate the
kind words you gave me at emerald cup
last year i was in the audience i didn't
expect that so that was really nice of
you
oh it felt really good to have you in
the audience too it was like cool you
know just i've listened to the way
i've got a lot from hearing breeders get
to go into
their thought process and just the way
that you create this format um i feel
that you get a real stream of
consciousness that i've gained so much
from and you've had a lot of my friends
on here too that i've worked with over
the years and you know like we've talked
a lot and i get to even gain a lot from
listening to them on your show even
after years of experience so i really
appreciate that format and to have you
in the audience at the emerald cup when
we did the regenerative cannabis uh
breeding uh
panel and also we did another uh
california just humble breeders panel uh
that had just an amazing group and yeah
i was happy to have you in the audience
to get to hear it and
yeah yeah thank you no you're too kind
my friend so the first question we like
to ask our guests what have you been
smoking on recently
well today it's mostly been a
black dog with
a mixture of
banana dog
rosin from garden of greece and not
rosin actually straight ice water hash
it just was pressed out a little bit and
then um
also some
uh
24k from um resin ranch uh it was just
exceptional
flavored great great citrus
um and
um yes some cherry lime dog flowers too
which is just kind of one of my
favorites that combination between
um
i mean jeans cherry lime pop and the
black dog uh and been playing with that
for the last several years and uh some
of my favorite aromas and flavors have
come out of that so that's a pretty
constant one but that's what i've been
smoking on today
wow what a lovely little selection there
what a lovely selection there's a few
things i'd love to chat about i mean
we're definitely going to chat cherry
lime dog because that's of huge interest
to me but just to quickly backtrack you
said the 24k that's an interesting one
because the citrus turps have been
dominant for a while
and
now they're kind of like almost making a
comeback but in like a
sort of a changed form like with other
stuff brought into it what's your
thoughts on citrus do you think we've
reached the peak do you think we've
passed where do you predict it
i think there's a lot of a lot of
different types of citrus um there's
certain citrus that
you know works more or less with other
people you have those hazy
citrus you have the piney hit citrus you
have sometimes it's more on the lime
some more lemon so you get straight
mandarin you have you know full lemon
like a lemon tree or something or
mandarin like mandarin or nectarine or
you have uh
there's a lot of different ways citrus
expresses itself and what i like about
the 24k is it's
um i feel like it's the like
it's kind of the juice and gas it's like
the the sweet
orange citrus
with a bit of that that gas and earth
that
i
i really enjoy that a little bit more
than maybe some of the super spiky hazy
citrus which i also enjoy too but i i
for all the time um i kind of like that
a little bit more gas with that citrus
and i think like the mandarin and that
24k seem to deliver that really well and
they they yield pretty well in ice water
hash too
yeah lovely what a bang on description
and i mean while we're talking about it
what's your thoughts on like the kosher
and the jew gold you know they're kind
of the two gassy og things which i don't
feel get as much of a mention as some of
the other og cuts how do you find them
do you like them
oh sure um
yeah and i mean it's it's difficult too
to know like if we're talking about the
same thing all the time too whether it's
a certain cut that was the basis for
something or whether it's the feminist
seeds that were put out in europe and
and what what is your definition of that
variety but um i mean yeah i i enjoy
those those gas flavors there's a it's
coming from a long
line of very similar og cuts and it's
just different versions of the of a
similar thing um that i've enjoyed since
i was um you know since the late well i
guess yeah late 90s early 2000s or so so
um yeah i've always enjoyed those
flavors and stuck with them
lovely well we'll have to get into that
but just as one last quick question on
this subject what's your favorite og if
you had to pick one
um
i mean
it was good from the beginning uh just
the standard kind of
the first og cut that guy
that we saw like
really in circulation around probably
two thousand
two i mean and it's very similar to the
sfv very similar to
tahoe and trinidad
uh
um lost coast og
yeah they all had that that same kind of
thing and sometimes it's like is it just
being grown in a different spot or not
it's it's hard for me to to fully know
and we don't have i don't have all of
them
saved or the records to know like what's
what but um
i don't have a
favorite because they were all so
similar um
it's really if how it was grown at the
time too like is this a real living soil
uh
expression um is it just perfectly done
organic indoor is it a really nice light
depth um
but
yeah and then just having that addictive
banging kind of gas flavor at the end
it's it's interesting what og did with
our area it actually
it created an appellation of its own in
like a very
uh free market kind of way the fact that
there was this variety that had this
addictive flavor that um we were growing
out in the hills in in light depth and
getting um incredibly beautiful flowers
that
were better looking than indoor and
better
you know especially anyone who messed up
their indoor which is most people so
like
um
people could come from all over
and just make a ton of money on selling
this stuff at top shelf indoor flowers
because it blew away their indoor
flowers and it created an really an
appellation because it was a flavor and
a standard of this area that happened
with light depth and og
and it really made a a lot of
a lot of history and a lot of economic
um
strangeness
yeah
yeah i mean it's it's so true and it
makes me wonder let's say you had to
make a you know a bit of a pie in the
sky i guess but let's say like you know
25 years from now most countries around
the world are legalized do you think
america would look into really pushing
that appalachia sort of thing a bit
harder with specific strains in the way
we see like wines and stuff or do you
think people are still going to just
pick different genetics each year and do
their thing
um well it's definitely happening
and there's really smart amazing
excellent farm
and breeders and advocates that are
working towards that and luckily these
are uh
a lot of the people who who very much
support the regenerative cannabis
farming movement and these ideals and um
they're putting and also real science
and so
um you know there is an appellation
project in humboldt that's um going into
place right now um dr holly hall is
helping
um head a lot of the research and uh the
fundraising for
the
getting
nine different weather stations that
will be put in different legacy farms
with good practices and we can start get
recording all of the environmental data
from high quality weather stations that
will be properly monitored
um and then janine coleman has been
leading this amazing appalachian project
from mendo and in humble and has been
doing just this
incredibly difficult work because it's
such a complex issue and like we're
dealing with you know cannabis is so
complex to begin with and then
appellations and then we're dealing with
everyone's different perspectives and
everyone's different cultures and
everyone's different spot and what's
special about their place and what's
special about their genetic and what's
special about their terroir and also
like who do you include and what doesn't
get included and like is a plant grown
in a pot in a greenhouse or in indoor in
that location qualifies as an
appellation when we're talking about
environmental expression so you know
things like do the roots need to be in
the ground is it okay if there was other
added potting soil or amendments is it
okay if there's some environmental
controls and so you know there's a lot
of things to kind of hash out i'm on the
the side of like
as long as those roots are tapped into
that soil and that it is part of that
environment and it's not environmental
control and you don't have artificial
lights then then that's qualifying for
an appellation the second you go indoor
or an environmentally controlled
um
greenhouse or the second that you have a
pot that does not allow the roots to go
into the ground then i think that those
suspend the idea of an appellation
because you're taking out the
environmental aspect of it which is such
an important part of it of course the
culture part of it the breeding the art
you know like all of that is a huge part
of an appellation too it's like
how do you grow a cultivar like which
what are you breeding for and then what
are you doing with that that's that's
that all is part of it too but i do
think that the environment has to be a
part of that as well
um so i'm really excited about all the
amazing people that are are working on
this and amazing farmers too like moon
made farms tina gordon um just so many
are are doing a lot of work and actually
the women have been spearheading this
pretty hard like um just a powerful
group of incredibly intelligent uh
powerful people that are are doing the
the work that i'd want to see done so
you know there's so many ways to get
these things wrong and i'm really
concerned about things that could
restrict
freedoms you know i don't want people
growing only one kind of cultivar in a
place because that goes to monoculture
that goes to
all these different issues or restrict a
farmer from breeding in their own
environment like the whole point is to
establish these things that are
a part of the culture a part of the
farmers a part of the breeders a part of
making something that makes sense for
that area and i think biodiversity goes
with that so it's like
you don't just be like oh this place is
known for this
variety this cultivar because
that same farm should be able to grow a
type 1 a type 2 type 3 type 4 they
should be able to like you know cbd thc
they should be able to have things that
are harvested early things that are
harvested late that are of different
sizes that make sense uh in their
environment so
and that's a very dynamic landscape if
you think of like a green source gardens
like um you think of all of the the
breeding that they're doing and then all
the different growing that they're doing
and they that's
to me like very much what an appellation
is but they are working on so many
different cultivars at the same time and
having a full polyculture mixed in with
there like many of the other
regenerative farms like moon gazer farms
um
they're just great examples of that and
it's kind of hard for bureaucracy to
understand that kind of like freedom and
polyculture and um but i'm hopeful that
maybe this is the place where we can do
it
yeah wow what a really knowledgeable
little burst of info there i think
people have to redo that
i'm interested to know
because i got two questions from two
fans and one of them was related to they
were kind of interested in trying to do
what you're talking about in their own
little setup and they were saying do you
think it would be beneficial to get that
whole process going to kind of do your
own imo and try to like um culture your
own indigenous microbes from your area
as opposed to say using like maybe an
em1 or like like a good microbial source
but it's external would you recommend
that like that could be a viable way to
get some microbial activity going that's
related to your terroir or do you think
it's a bit more complex than that
so this is a
cultivator that's um
asking about living soil cultivation um
yeah is this indoor outdoor what kind of
situation are we talking about i think
that they recently moved to a new
property and they're looking to grow
outdoor and they were kind of wondering
like the first time you grow something
is there terroir there immediately or
does it have to develop over time and do
i need to use imos and things like that
well the terroir is there
but
yeah i mean
like any
gardening and the whole idea of
regenerative farming is the fact that
you make something thrive more every
year so
you do the things that build nutrition
that build that that generate uh more
life just by going through um
you know the cycles of things and so
by
cover cropping um
in the in the fall so after you've grown
your crop you immediately start your
cover crop um before the rains come
and that grows over the winter and
all the nitrogen fixing bacteria that
work with the
the root nodules in something like fava
beans or something like peas or bell
beans or veg those are pulling nitrogen
from the air and they are fixing it into
the ground just
through the process of photosynthesis
and through the process of having a
mutualistic relationship with
bacteria that they they literally
create these nodules to house the
bacteria like they grow these big things
and they they put out resources to make
sure that they are
housing and taking care of these
bacteria that can
process the the nitrogen from the air
which literally is prob is one of the
most difficult things uh to break apart
is a triple bond that's the hardest bond
to break apart and um n2 in the air is
is two nitrogens together in a triple
bond the only thing that has enough
energy to break that apart is is a
lightning bolt and so like when
lightning hits like
some of that nitrogen in the air becomes
free and it can attach to water and
oxygen and different things in the air
and then rain down as actual usable
nitrates for plants so you actually get
some nitrogen um
in your your rains when there's
thunderstorms
but the bacteria have the enzymes that
can start working on those triple bonds
and they can they can take them apart so
the how the plant houses basically a
laboratory that allows these enzymes to
work
and uh
so
just by planting these seeds all of a
sudden you're able to pull
the most difficult thing you know that's
the the nutrient that
that everything
needs to build proteins
that's locked up in our air and should
be too by the way the nitrogen cycle
it's really important to keep it the way
it is and we've really messed it up by
artificially producing nitrogen through
the harbor bosch process where we're
actually
using pressures in a catalyst and uh
hydrocarbons to fuel it all to make
to make nitrogen
and what we do is we we we've literally
put more than twice the amount of
nitrogen into
the system that should be there and so
you see a lot of issues with rivers with
water quality with die-offs with blooms
of algae with uh toxic blooms and with
full-on die-off because all the oxygen
is robbed of from the water so it's a
really big deal that we think about
nitrogen in a way that is regenerative
that
is the way that the planet has always
done it because it's always kept it in
the balance and it's it's allocated
those resources in an amazing way so
much of it's locked up in the sky the
bacteria can release the release the the
right amount for plants to be able to
use lightning you know releases the
right amount um and then we've just
completely changed that just like we
have with so many other things and co2
in the air
and that's the other thing that you're
doing when you're cover cropping is
you're actually taking carbon from the
air and you are storing it in these
plant cells and in the roots and they're
growing and they're taking more carbon
from the air that's what photosynthesis
is it's it's taking carbon from the air
and it's building
plant matter with it you get organic
material from that you know and that's
also like with cannabis that's where we
get all our phytochemicals all our
medicine it's literally coming from
pulling carbon from the air and growing
from that through
relationships with roots and with
microorganisms and
doing that imbalance
is
is just what we need to do with
everything in life
and so
just the simple process of putting out a
cover crop
seed at the right time you pull in
carbon you build it into the soil that
that carbon is stored in the soil it
feeds more microbiology uh and
while you're pulling that carbon the
microbiology in the root nodules are
pulling in the nitrogen and making that
a nutrient-rich soil and all you have to
do is mulch that back in in the in the
spring and plant and you've just built
soil you've built fertility
while doing a positive thing for the
earth and then those plants get to grow
with all of the nutrition and the
organic matter that you just grew out of
thin air in a way
what a fantastic explanation of nitrogen
fixation i i definitely think people
need to listen to that one again i
really enjoyed that so i guess there's
maybe just a follow-on in relation to
our listeners question
let's say you did exactly what you said
you'd done some nice cover crop and
you've plowed it in and you're looking
to go again this season well it doesn't
have to be plow plow makes a lot of
sense certainly in dry farming uh
plowing is is is the way that it is done
for well in certain places like river
banks and stuff you plow it in
it gets eaten quickly and then you
actually disturb the soil in a way that
works for the dry farming process
i prefer in certain locations mulching
in so you can figure out what you have
on a property that would work to mulch
something in whether it's a bunch of
cardboard or maybe wood chips old depth
covers for a moment although the plastic
you want to be careful about because you
only want to do a certain certain amount
of time and make sure that the oxygen
and that you aren't harming but you are
just returning organic matter to the
earth but you know worms will come up as
soon as something's covered and start
eating it you get all the millipedes you
get all kinds of um diversity of
creatures that get all this food that
they get to eat and then you just you
know you talk about like frass or like
um you know or compost teas like what's
happening on the top of this surface is
just
everything you could never even buy in
the store it's every positive thing you
could imagine and it's just piles of it
that just happen you know overnight
constantly they just come up and they
eat and they poop and they give
everything that the plants want as this
this layer of organic material goes back
so um yeah i'm a big fan of mulching
sometimes the tilling makes sense for
and there's certain farmers that really
know what they're doing and they know
how to maximize production and
you know really reduce resource use
in other cases maybe that's not the
place the thing to do for that because
you want to encourage a different type
of
soil life and
you know whether that's
using rotational grazing or whether it's
fully mulching and
developing more perennials there's lots
of different strategies um
but yeah i would
encourage mulching as well as as
not just healing
yeah of course and uh my my bad using
the wrong wording there were definitely
no you didn't no no because both both
are very are are needed and viable and
make sense in their applicable um uh
scenarios
yeah so before we get too in depth
because we're definitely going to go
further down the organics rabbit hole
take me back what was your first
experience with cannabis
um
kind of as early as my memories are just
watering beautiful plants
as a as a baby
and then next would be monday night
football there was a roommate who uh
old
peace activist and he actually had a
radio show too on kpfa and uh it was
about social justice and
but every every monday night
everyone would go in to his room and
watch monday night football and i
remember really enjoying when you know
people talk like this as they
passed the joint and held it in it was
like man everyone's super nice when they
talk like that and
you know just
fun watching you know a football game
with a bunch of happy adults that are
you know very carefree and enjoying each
other um so and the smell was wonderful
you know just this wonderful lingering
smell in the air and just positive
memories uh positive memories
um
and then
you know as a teenager just starting to
smoke with friends and um
also just being interested in the seeds
too and watching the plants grow like i
kind of you know both started around the
same time pretty early for me too um i
think 13 14 is when
you yeah it was about the right age for
me to
start perking my interest back into
something that i'd seen although where i
grew up
there was no more growing it was only
early when i was a kid and then they
made a decision that just with legal
um
uh impli you know issues that they they
were not going to risk the property i
actually grew up um
the property i grew up on was joan
baez's old place uh it's a place that is
uh was named by her struggle mountain
and it's uh
connected to
the
non-violent movements and and uh
the the movement against the vietnam war
and
multiple social justice movements as
well as being connected to this thing
called the land which was um
a area up there that uh basically
intentional communities were built on
land that was accessible at that time
and uh so they they built
all kinds of cool houses they had
irrigation there's spring systems
there's a um
a a long haul for for meetings and for
dances and um
and there was back to landers and there
was front landers that were more
political back the landers were more
about living off the land and the
gardens and
um
yeah so
yeah there's a rich history there um and
uh
they like cannabis and stuff but decided
that you know the the properties and
stuff of that area wasn't it just wasn't
worth uh
the legal risk during the time you know
and
i grew up during the reagan era and the
the war on drugs which always seemed
like just a horrible crime against uh
human rights and humanity and i can't
wait to see
that as as something
so far in the past and and just as
something is
i mean it's just a disgusting horrible
thing that destroyed so many lives and i
i can't wait till it's over
yeah certainly certainly
so what were some of the earliest
strains you can remember when you first
were getting into cannabis or was it at
a time when it was still like the kind
and it wasn't really named
yeah you know it was a little bit in
between um it wasn't so much about the
names um
as
it was it was interesting things so like
we had the monday it was a certain
variety it was super good that like my
friend would get every monday you know
like uh we had the crackhead and it was
just so strong and so stimulating that
it was just like crack you know and it
smelled so good and that's actually one
i super long for i i i would love to
find that profile again because it was
it was actually very addictive too
um yeah
uh you know other things uh
it
yeah a lot of things just weren't they
were just really good you know you just
call something like well it's a golden
indica you know it's beautiful
and that was the flavor profile and the
way that it grew um i remember coming up
the humble like so i grew up with like
santa cruz um
mountains and
also the indoor and um
it was a relatively it was extremely
wealthy area in palo alto um as far as
kids i we didn't have any money or
anything but like all the the the kids
around me were tremendously wealthy in
general um in that area is the booming
of silicon valley
and uh
so actually the weed was incredibly good
because there's the economic driver for
it to be uh i remember like we didn't
like we just didn't see uh sweat you
know mexican or brick or
or even like bee
letter like for
ever like honestly we just had like you
know cause you're buying eights and
twumps and then stuff like at least the
kids are in like
um
and it had to be really good i mean the
quality standards were super high so
honestly we started with like the best
and uh they remember i remember like
somebody like coming with like brickweed
and just like everyone's like it was a
novelty for a second and everyone had a
headache and by the next day like i
don't think you could sell it for any
price but you could sell a gram for 20
bucks the next day you know um but
yeah it's just yeah interesting times um
and coming up here well i remember the
first time coming up and humbled still
in high school and stuff and we got some
honeydew
uh
which at the time was like is that the
name of the variety or the place that it
came
and it was so good it had that kind of
pre-98 bubba
look and and structure but it was just
extra gooing it had kind of a honeydew
smell you know that made you even think
like is it called honeydew because of
that but i know it came from it had to
come from honeydew
and it was probably light depth too that
was you know looked better than um you
know a lot of the android people are
used to as well
um so you know if you paid the right
price freaking you got [__] fire back
then um so
yeah we grew up an insanely good herb
and i loved putting away like the really
nice seeds i always just wanted to grow
all the time and and it was just really
interested in seeds and really
interested in and putting different
things together so i just always saved
in categories and like any nug that it
came from i'd like save the nug and save
the seed with it and write down
information about it and so when i
had you know like started uh doing my
first programs i had all this
information just literally from the the
flowers you know it wasn't like oh i
bought it from here and i know that it's
this or that i just
just from my own observations and the
nugs that it came from
wow and back at that time was did people
talk about seeds you found in bud as
though it was like oh you know you
shouldn't grow those or was it more
accepted that you could get some nice
stuff out of seed you found in bud
i mean if the flower is super nice and
it's a treasure you know like i think
you might as well look what's what why
not um
and also there wasn't so much uh
information or misinformation going on
where people didn't necessarily have uh
you know set ideas of what is a good
thing or a bad thing or not um
and god i mean if you pull the seed out
of a flower that was just like the best
flavor and best effect like that's a
freaking treasure put it away and see
what happens
and so
as you accumulated your kind of little
treasure trove of i called it the vault
it was the vault
i love it the vault i think everyone
needs to get the vault going um and was
this kind of what spurred you to get
growing initially and were those seeds
some of the first ones you planted how
did that go
yeah absolutely yeah um
yeah so you know doing cool gorilla
grows and
with springs and and you know nice
forest soil and um
and growing some of those varieties and
then doing
oh god probably
yeah night i was 98 doing um indoors
up in arcade actually moving up here at
that time um in humble and uh running
through the vault and what i did was i
just named all kinds of different things
um
mostly i was pretty into greek mythology
and so i'd name them different greek
names and
one of the ones that stood out was
athena and
um
that's a cultivar that's still with me
today
wow as far as like through the breeding
there's like
yeah
25 years of different projects with her
wow that's that's really impressive i
mean it makes me wonder um what do you
have any specific end direction or it's
just more of like a blank canvas and you
just see where it takes you
oh she's taking me a lot of places um
yeah it's it's a canvas it's it's
honestly it's not an interaction it's
it's um the plant teaches me
yeah what a brilliant sentiment so
the question i love to ask breeders when
you made your first cross was it an
accident or was it intentional and what
happened
um
well the first cross that i'd call
across um that went to
something else as far as making a clone
selection and then other people
growing that clone selection out was
actually just the bubba selection that
uh made up here with a friend back um
about 2001
crossing that onto and that became
actually the bubba that was pretty much
grown up here and became the main bubba
and mixing that with the athena that i
was talking about um
that selection and that was athena kush
um and that actually was growing up
quite a lot up here
it was just an amazing
hybrid between them um just insane
giant trichomes amazing resin production
um
really great division between
flowers just tons of beauty
and it couldn't get powdery mildew which
a lot of people really like so it ended
up getting grown quite a bit in that
that clone variety form
um and yeah so all throughout the early
2000s that was a pretty pretty popular
variety
um in the humble area
hell yeah and so do you feel like that
was kind of what really lit the passion
to start breeding for you seeing that
success people were having or was it was
already there it was just you know nice
to see people enjoying it
i've always been interested in plants um
and putting things together
um but yeah that i mean that that that
success of that was you know that was
definitely a
great spark
to continue to see
all the different
cool things you can put together and
what can come out of that and and also
being able to see how those come out on
all these different farms
because i you know way back then i i was
already doing this where i got to go see
something you worked on grown
in all these different places and seeing
the different expressions and
um it's just
massively interesting to me and it's
never stopped being it's like what i do
every year it's just i go to all the
farms and see everyone growing all the
seeds and and try to take in as much
information as much
art photography
much as much understanding of their
practices and and then hopefully knowing
everything about the flowers and the
products that get made from it
afterwards because it all is just
amazing information for the next
generation
great answer and you know what it segues
really brilliantly into something i
think we both wanted to touch on a
little bit which is kind of you're
talking about how
there's all these different facets that
you like to approach cannabis from you
know not just growing a photography the
information the research documentation
and i think that it raises the overall
question kind of
what is biovortex to you because i've
seen you post online and i'm assuming
that maybe not everyone has seen it but
it was a great post so i'd love for you
to be able to tell the listeners you
know what is biovortex is it just a name
is it something a lot more than that how
would you pitch it
yeah it's a it's been a thing of
confusion a lot uh
because it's like oh is this a
you know is it just a genetics company
are you selling vortex brewers or are
you a living soil consultant or you know
i mean i do all these things i guess
like i make seeds and i make
uh
you know and i i've made vortex brewers
and i've made living soil and and
consulted on that and helped all that
but um
really at the base of it and also just
the whole um
you know the regenerative farm award and
all of all of that kind of education
towards that that at the base of
biovortex it is a conceptual art piece
that's what it it was from the beginning
and continues to be
and the concept of it is to influence
the cannabis industry towards a more
ecological
um
future one that's uh thoughtful about
plant genetics that is thoughtful about
social justice that is thoughtful about
the soil about the earth about how we
cultivate about the end users
that putting all of this thought into
how we do something and um what i
thought was really powerful and
about connecting these concepts with
cannabis is
how much attention is cannabis has right
now and how much
um
economic attention and medical attention
um that it has that if we can really
show these types of
farming practices about these kinds of
community
ethical practices in the way that we
produce a healing product that we can
really
drive and change the way we look at
marketing the way that we look at
medicine the way that we look at
agriculture
and and you know forge a better future
through that understanding and so i just
but the trojan horse of of all the
enthusiasm of cannabis i want to put
these these concepts into it and um
and what's amazing is cannabis is a a
consciousness
um uplifting um plant that
allows for these ideas to to soar and so
many different people that have been
inspired by some of these concepts have
done so many amazing things or have
already been doing the work before but
there's a mutualism and a synergy
between all the people that are working
towards these goals that i think is
incredibly beautiful and and really
that's what i want to cultivate and
encourage and um so it's it's a it's a
conceptual art piece that wants to build
community and awareness of ecology and
all of the amazing things that this
plant can do for
our
mental awakening for our society and for
social justice
yeah what an incredibly detailed and and
really kind of altruistic kind of body
of work you've got going on there
a question we commonly hear from our
listeners is that they struggle to
conceptually see how the small farm can
progress going forward as things get
harder to operate do you think operating
under these sort of ideals and um
guidance is a way in which smaller
people can still make things possible to
operate and maybe you know earn a living
from
well i think like all things it's just
like things diversify it there's so many
different things that cannabis produces
so um no i don't know if like small
farms makes sense for large biomass for
phytochemical companies i don't know if
it makes sense for you know large
biomass for um fiber but it maybe it
does it depends on your end product your
your marketing and then like who you're
working with and uh i know that there'd
be amazing people doing that but
hopefully you know we can that the
practices are good regardless of the
scale and that as a
a community that
buys these products that we are aware of
these things and that we um hold people
responsible for how they are producing
things um and and really think about the
environmental impacts in in certain
large scale and and monoculture and what
we want to see from that as far as the
small farm
um
staying
viable uh i think actually as far as
the more um
i hate the word recreational because i
think it's all
uh medical but like the craft and the
you know and connoisseur market um
that that it's only gonna be small farms
because uh i think
that it only goes one direction as far
as
understanding of quality um you don't
you don't experience true quality and go
backwards you don't experience the
quality of an amazing dry farm peach you
know from an amazing farm like and the
quality of that that flavor like it
can't be
reproduced you can't just buy it and
have it shipped somewhere
um you can't
you know
recreate a michelin star restaurant that
has a relationship with a small farmer
near them um so i think we already
understand that quality
but we have a lot of work to do as far
as education for the consumers
through in just even in california but
throughout the world california might
have a very sophisticated market in
general but there's a lot of work to do
there
um in in understanding practices and and
so that's part of like the regenerative
cannabis farm award is like not just
about products not just about flowers
which is of course king and you know
it's like we need to know what
everyone loved smoking on the most but
let's talk about the practices and you
know some of these farms do quite well
in the contest as well with the insane
products that they're they're coming to
the table with um
and so we get to actually look at the
practices of these farms like how are
they growing how are they um
how are they using water how are they
interacting with their community what
medicines are they making and this is
how we actually we created a matrix to
judge these different farms and we go
out on
a site visit and we will
get the whole tour go through everything
ask the questions and then later we we
run it through this this matrix of all
these different um
aspects of of what regenerative
can mean um and a lot of it is
ecological but there's also like the
community and medical and social justice
aspects of that as well
um
and
dan maher of high tide permaculture has
done an amazing job um developing that
with me with an amazing
permaculture and um
you know science mind
ecology like that is put into it is is
it's very thoughtful and
we we get to kind of understand
something about these farms so having
these awards so people can see
uh a little bit more about these farms
and making movies about them and so
people can see the practices and and
know that they
want a flower grown like that they want
a flower that's grown with love that
helps the environment they want a flower
that
comes from a farm that that is a part of
cannabis community that is a part of uh
you know their watershed and their
environment their forests
um that are true stewards as well as
growing just insanely fire herb
100 and do you think that we can get to
a point one day where the average
consumer could take all of these factors
into mind and truly appreciate the
quality of a product that comes from one
of these farms
and view that as the best or do you
think that it's hard for consumers to
understand all of the inner workings and
why this regenerative farmed product is
so superior
it's hard
but it gets easier every year and it
takes a lot of cooperation
um
and it's i think it's i'd like to see
more on the dispensary ends there's some
that are really cool um you know soulful
from a very early
um
point in sebastopol california had had
been excited about these regenerative
farms and wanting to convey all the
information they could about them and
have done an outstanding job with that
and then now we're really lucky to have
um our dear friend
uh crystal who has opened up the um
humble urban market in arcata and
i think like like no other dispensary
it's gonna really be able to tell that
farm story because she is such a deep
part of canada's community important
part of you know
uh so much of the policy developing
appellations and um
but the and just working with all the
farms and just being she's just a
positive pillar in the community so i'm
just so happy to have someone like that
um being able to
help educate the public to the um
the amazing farming practices that are
happening on some of these farms the
quality differences and just
giving them access to really quality
medicine medicine
yeah certainly
so let's go back
give me the rundown how did the creation
of black dog go down i think a lot of
people are interested in what the
genesis story was how would you describe
it
um well it starts with um
my dear friend ryan with humbled seed
organization and projects that we were
doing together
uh from an early
point you know back in even
a little ways into like the athena kush
days like i got to meet him through um
my neighbor and we
you know instantly were we're
close friends and um you know he was
very ahead of the game understanding
where you know what was happening with
seeds and you know saw the work that i
was doing and saw
um
the potential and um
and all of the things that were
happening here and did an amazing job
bringing that to um really the whole
world
um and so with projects that yeah we
were working on together uh a uh just a
regular blackberry um you know mother
with a um
the
emerald headband it was which is a uh
a california sour diesel with a lemon og
and that
um
yeah it was kind of the genesis of the
black dog and working with that in 2012
i made a selection that was like
just exactly what i wanted and i was i
actually originally called it like
trimmer's delight because it was it
literally took less than two hours to
trim a pound so like
you know it's just like okay that's way
too much money
but it was it was it was a dessert you
know it's like okay cool you know but
you know when you finished a hard job
like okay here's dessert like
you get to make a bunch real fast
but uh and then of course i you know i
like to just trim it myself too but
um
so anyway that clone got saved and then
i just continued working with that and
that kind of became the canon for
what i was doing with it and then um
really i mean black dog's still being
made you know like uh that was 2012 and
every year i've done multiple different
um variations of back crosses or um you
know continuing sibling generations um
as well as probably at this point maybe
crossed it on to 250 maybe different
things or more um and then multiple
generations from multiple different
crosses from that so i ca it's kind of
this fun flagship project where it's
just like i'm gonna do everything you
could possibly do with this plant like
you know just
unbelievable like
uh stored potential
in one plan so like yeah just from [__]
all over the world you know all the
different things like i've probably put
it on black target at some point
um
so yeah i don't know there's something
about having this this one plant with
the stored information of
such a vast worldwide genetic potential
yeah certainly as well as having this
super inbred line
as yeah you know getting that
consistency
um you know it's what i really love is
just like hearing all the positive stuff
from people's experience with it
it's been a lot of people where it's
helped them
with medical issues with addiction
issues with mental health issues like
um that it puts them in a place that
that helps them there's something about
the
the chemotype that
the terpene and the the cannabinoid
combination it's you know nothing like
specifically unique and it's not super
potent or anything but it's just there's
something the way it like connects you
with nature balances like it
and and people seem to have a very
similar experience
um and it's just so [__] pretty to
watch grow
and yeah yeah she's a special one
lovely so
i i assume you've heard a plethora of
feedback from people about it but are
there any kind of traits or properties
you're pretty neat to see the hashtag
blackdog kush and it made sure to put
the kush on the end so it's not buried
in a pile of labradors and stuff
which would happen
yeah
it's like if everyone just tags black
dog it's like no one's gonna see that
hashtag i promise you but if you do
black dog cush it's like it's pretty
good but there's thousands from all over
the world and it's it's really amazing
to see and you know super thankful uh
with a
relationship with um yeah the friend
ryan and eric and humble seed
organization with getting that
everywhere um it's really really cool to
see
and are there any uh characteristics or
problems you feel it's particularly good
for like for example if someone was
having like low energy or like is there
anything which stands out you think it's
quite good for if patients were having
that issue
i think it's good for
what it's good for for the person you
know i don't i wouldn't pigeonhole it um
but
the one thing that has been um
consistent though is
a connection with nature and a balancing
um
which helps with a lot of things i think
yeah
sure so do you prefer in general to kind
of work lines till you've got a pretty
good idea of what's going on or are you
a bit more like let's do some f1s and
kind of see what comes out of it
well i mean every year i
i work a few lines
i figure out what is possible and you
know maybe that's
one maybe it's four maybe it's six maybe
it's two
and then
on top of that i just try to do every
freaking thing i can so like yeah i make
and and uh yeah i make all kinds of poly
hybrids uh i you know
and i try to i try to set things up i i
make probability waves is kind of how i
think about it
and so i set multiple different timings
up and i have my like super planned out
like my four projects like i'm doing
this year that are like
you know i'm doing my cherry lime dog bc
uh one f threes and i'm making the f the
cherry lime dog f4s
um and i'm doing a very concentrated you
know effort towards
making those be exactly what i want them
to be but at the same time i've
i've planned i have
maybe 100 different varieties that are
staggered at different times that will
be
for different projects and um i will
just try to
see what makes sense at each
time you know there's a lot of thought
going into how i set it up but the thing
is the way the probability wave
collapses uh i might not know until the
days that they come you know as you you
smell a variety that you see their
resistance that you see
their profiles and that you see
you know what kind of male might
work with them or what the timing will
be um
and yeah what you want to save what you
want to clone what you pollen you'd want
to save what which ones you want to put
together
um and what kind of preservation work
that you might be doing just putting a
couple things together that you already
have or
or
are you going to do a whole lot of new
things um i want to do it all
so i just work really hard on a couple
lines and then i make a whole lot of
poly hybrids
yeah brilliant answer and and i guess
the question that comes to mind for me
is
like the athena do you think there's an
end point or is it a forever changing
and morphing sort of piece of art
exactly yeah forever changing morphing
piece of art um
yeah i mean yeah i can't i don't want to
manipulate that relationship i don't
know there's something about that plant
but
uh she's just given me so much and
yeah i'm just gonna just watch and learn
from her and and each year um see see
what happens and make sure to
preserve things i've lost some of the
things that i might have thought that i
wanted to continue but i've also gained
so many others so uh yeah i'm just open
to
to where that goes um
but
as long as i still see her in there
sure and out of the current crosses
you're working on i mean you mentioned
the cherry lime dog earlier on what are
some of the ones you're really excited
to delve more into
oh yeah of that flavor right now too
well the thing is it's it doesn't even
have to just like so i'm looking at just
cherry lime dog as multiple ways to dive
into the same thing
um so
you know i took
the
cherry lime dog
and you know i made my f2s from that but
then i was also like out of those f2s
i'm like
you know i kind of want
it to look a lot like
the black dog structure it too and bring
some of that back so i just i i put some
of that back onto the um
the 2012 black dog clone
uh to make the vc1
uh and then and then i made the f2s with
those and i'm making the f3s right now
so it's like it's kind of going down a
different line although it's still i did
make my selection holding on to the
flavor profile that i really liked that
a lot of the cherry lime pop you know
shines through from that from from
jackson from mean gene freeborn
selections
um
but it's like it's a super great blend
with the black dog it's like yeah it's
just got that
it's got the right
harmony of the blends of flavor and then
but it's a little more black dog in
structure so this is also a more um
uniform dwarfy and i also made a a a
dark selection and um a slightly lighter
selection so one that just turns purple
super quick and like right now it's like
really really dark just with the first
little like nugs coming up for the um
the breeding project i'm working on
right now with them
um frosted out like crazy just at you
know they're not even a half a
inch like wide yet but just
completely coated and dark
but they have the structure of the black
dog and so they're they're consistent
they're squatty um they won't need any
caging they need no effort i don't water
or feed or do anything i just let them
do their thing so i kind of like
breeding for plants that you don't have
to do anything to and that produce a
tremendous amount for their biomass
they don't they're not necessarily the
monster plants
um
that you need to cage and that you know
take up all this space and but um the
thing is they're producing more flowers
for the rest of the the plant
and they um and if you have them next to
each other you're probably going to have
a more productive square footage
so i do like reading about
thinking about those kinds of lines
um
and then with the cherry lime dog f4s
that making right now
um i'm kind of going with the more
classic hybrid growth where they were um
but they're a taller one the cherry lime
pop was tall um and it had a really nice
mix with the black dog where it was
still like a medium tall plant but it
was well structured from the black dog
but not the i had problems with the over
stretching of the the lime pop
um
in this area because the branches got
too wet or wind and stuff they they had
a tendency to break a little bit easier
and i really don't i'm kind of an
all-natural style and i don't want to
have to do cages and things
um so that the black dog structure
really worked
great to keep those those stems and
branches uh really strong
and uh but the you know the the f3
generation is is a nice tall fast
growing it's not all squatty
and you know that's nice for people too
um and then it just has a just insane uh
flavor profile and so i did a pretty big
selection last year and that god it was
so
i mean it wasn't giant or whatever but
it was so hard to choose because it was
literally like this is my favorite aroma
i've ever smelled in my life no this one
is no this one isn't like
um you know and so the one i ended up
like
popping from like god damn that the
aroma from that is just like yeah it's
from the gods for sure
and big big respect to jackson for his
his nose and his work
yeah most certainly i mean to me
yeah yeah yeah so it makes me wonder
then are there any other sort of modern
genetics or modern clones that you would
be interested in incorporating into the
black dog line just kind of seeing where
it goes dude you could literally
probably name every single one and it's
already happened
like go ahead
it's happening all right yeah i mean
yeah so i mean like well
and like hash lines too like the banana
dog is is uh been wonderful and um i
mentioned smoking on some of that
cash earlier too that um the garden of
greece did cush kirk and um amanda they
uh
they are just freaking hash artists and
and amazing regenerative farmers
dragonfly earth medicine uh
pure farmers up in oregon just just
making
i i honestly like their freezer it's the
best
the the highest concentration of the
best hash in the world legos is like i
went up with was simply adam and we're
just like
yeah they just took our breath away the
some of the best gourmet experiences of
my life uh with actually their puppy
breath which was the mendo breath with
uh an sfe uh black dog um and
yeah so i mean there's two you know sf
eog and mendo breath on black dog but oh
my god the the quality of that hash is
just unbelievable it's so um
just great structure great consistency
too you can just like snap it off and
like it just took a second to like
just press it and it just like i mean
the idea of rosing that quality of full
melt would be so insane because it's
just so beyond you just touch it and
it's already so beyond rosin um and then
and then it holds a consistency too
where it's like amber i can like break
it even at room temperature where like
other stuff would just kind of get a
little like
you know start to be a little more
volatile a little greasy
um you know either cake or grease and uh
this this has this like jewel like
quality to it the puppy breath had that
too
it makes it really easy to catch too and
they get really high yields and
they're very resistant too very mold
resistant
but i love breeding for high ice water
hash yields i'm really interested in
trichomorphology
and also uh you know bud structure and
and then also the terpene and
cannabinoid uh
production that is associated with
trichomes that are easier to work with
with ice water hash that lead to higher
yields and then also thinking about like
where the um
you know getting different unique
flavors and how you could do that with
out neces with still getting a decent
return on other varieties that might not
be as uh good for
for catching in a mesh
yeah what a what a sort of conscious
effort with breeding to take it in that
direction i and then with cbd too i
really want to do that with cbd and i
have the last couple years i have some
pretty
you know good uh beginning successes
towards that effort and i'm excited for
like
um uh the holy tonic selection which was
a big sur holy weed catatonic cross that
there's a two to one selection that has
the right kind of trichomes and then um
some of the different crosses with that
like um black
black sapphire on that which is double
black dog sapphire scout holy crack um
and then
just straight black dog on that too it's
like some of these are gonna
they
they're gonna come out with the right
trichomes i also did some banana og
harley sue but really the the cantatonic
and the holy tonic um crosses are
look like they're gonna work really the
selections that i made years ago of
these they're specific ones um
and a really orangey really beautiful um
high trichome content variety of the the
cantatonic that's a three to one
uh that the holy tonic was was was made
from
they
just more than most cbd varieties they
have the type of trichomes that could do
it and i've seen some good successes so
far so i'm really excited
uh for some of the research projects
that are happening this year with that
and seeing that with come to fluorescent
with some of the extractors and farmers
yeah of course of course so
i mean a question i've had for a little
while now is do you think that
ultimately terroir is able to manifest
itself more so in hash maybe than flour
like do you think it's more perceivably
noticeable if you made a product kind of
like what you described that that might
stand itself out a little more than the
flour or do you think not necessarily
like they could both equally be very
unique
um
yeah they both could be very unique i
mean certainly
there's a concentration that happens
with hash and i think
what one thing i've i've definitely
heard over and over again from hash
artists um and extractors
is
they
fully
have been blown away when they first
like run some living soil uh
base trichomes like when they've just
been running salt you know or indoor or
or maybe
less uh
organically grown depths or stuff with
dust and all the things
but uh
you know i yeah i've seen it happen a
bunch of times just like oh my god like
what is the quality of this is just
incredible and it's hard for them to go
back so um most extractors that i've
worked with who've been turned on to
that have been very
uh
they only want to source that type of
material
yeah so i think that shows something
about the terroir for sure
yeah certainly i mean just to kind of
stimulate a bit of discussion it wasn't
too long ago i was chatting with
burnside collective who were the guys
who won the hash category of the ego
clash and they did it in salts and they
made this interesting comment where they
were kind of like
we think that producing hash and
concentrates specifically it's more
about
like the watering techniques and like
the humidities and stuff
more so than organic versus inorganic
because you're just kind of getting the
glandular heads do you think do you
think there's any truth to that or do
you think sure sure um absolutely
environmental conditions like never
being stressed out having the right like
temperature and and you know just the
plant being happy all the time and it
being the right genetic in the first
place is it might be stand out even more
than uh other other things too um i mean
i think
every it first just starts off with the
genetic like is that genetic gonna put
off the flavor that's gonna work out
like if it doesn't then it doesn't
really matter what you're doing it's not
going to work um next though i mean i
really think yeah just like not having
an environment that has stress um you
know i remember when uh like simply adam
first like was washing some of our
living soil grown
um
coastal stuff you know like i think
there's something about the lack of
stress in the environment because it
never gets too hot or too dry or
anything and the trichomes could really
just be
what they wanted to be with never seeing
any stress so i think uh
yeah i mean someone putting a lot of um
effort towards environmental control and
not using any
shitty products at least or at least
stuff that would be very um
you know benign i guess like uh you know
people that are going to be using
pesticides or any kind of sprays are
going to destroy hash i mean obviously
it's not going to taste good and it
would be toxic and all that stuff
but you know some mineral salts that are
thoughtful um in a good environment um
i don't think it would be what it
could be but i do think it would be
better than a
uh something else that
uh was was stressed out potentially and
certainly better than something that
wasn't the right genetic in the first
place
yeah certainly
and so
an issue i've been kind of tossing in my
mind is do you think there's any
relationship between
like the trichome density that you see
on the plant and the quality of hash or
do you think they're not tied in
together and the reason i bring this up
is because i think a lot of people look
at like mac or whatever and they're like
oh it must make the best hash yeah next
um so yeah and like this is something i
like to bring up when you know like
just in that the idea of trichome
density it's like how do you even
measure that you know and i i would like
to establish like you know better
uh
better ways to
to measure that because you can't just
say there's this many trichomes that's
not telling you
what you need to know it's what size are
the heads you know like uh you know what
just you have to describe the next like
are they all snaking around and making
that illusion of the whole thing and and
you know it's like black dogs is one
that's like both you know it's got the
long necks and it's got the the heads so
it's got that like
it can have that super frosted out look
um but you know there's other varieties
that might even be packing more
trichomes but they they're not um
they're not poking them out with the
necks you know um you know like they're
they're just heads that kind of
grow
before the neck even or
um
or then yeah they grow and then the neck
will kind of come after and they'll hook
a bit but it's like the plants that put
that effort towards the head
but it's not just that too it's what is
the makeup inside that trichome what are
the terpenes and cannabinoids and a lot
of cbd varieties like why i was talking
about it they don't yield that well they
they have like high immersing um
contents quite often and different
volatile trips like i just they just
grease out really easy you touch them
and they grease out like you obviously
you're going to lose so much if you're
trying to
to separate trichome heads um if they
all just burst
um
so
there's a lot of things to think about
um in in the morphology and the chemical
makeup
beyond
uh trichome density
and do you think over time as the
quality of hash and concentrates in
general improves that we're gonna see
more and more people move away from
flower move towards concentrates or do
you think it's just like whatever floats
your boat
your flower's never going to go anywhere
and it's like the basis for everything
and
um even if
i want to smoke
all day i want to see where you know the
flower came from too and enjoy that too
or roll the joint with the two together
um
and
yeah
there's
and right now like actually it's kind of
funny in the california like legal mark
in all the markets there's really like
no end to the desire for really quality
flower especially after the um
outdoor season's been over for so long
and depths are just hitting and um
and indoor is so rare in general
especially also in the legal
market too that
people
uh yeah they i mean if you got really
good flowers they
people go for the flowers like it's
still you're gonna make more on that too
as the farmers in general um
it's still it still gets the best best
price um
but that's what's really nice about
breeding for
yield um that
let's say something you're growing a
variety that yields well in ice water
hash
let's say yields average you know but
it's good enough to work you know and
you're growing that but then
you get
genetics of another variety that yields
three times as much as that decent
yielding variety you just grew three
times as much in that same location with
the same amount of resources and the
same license and the same square footage
um
so that's huge difference and so i i
try to i want to breed towards things
that help farmers do better
yeah i mean a great point and on the
topic of breeding something which really
stood out to me about your breeding
which i'd love to chat about is that
i've noticed and i'm probably wrong but
i
when it comes to mind i've noticed that
you do something really unique with your
breeding that i've only ever seen res
dog do which is like explore these sort
of back cross and then take it to the
next filial generation and then like you
know interweaving back crossing and
filial breeding whereas most breeders
tend to stick to one or the other what's
your thoughts on that and do you think
that other people might be missing out
on a little something by just back
crossing or just philly or breeding
yeah i mean i think it's all something
to explore and like you know i want to
do both um at the same time because i
get to see what comes out of that and
i'm just interested to um
in how
to get to certain places faster and
sometimes i think uh yeah bc back cross
generation makes more sense
and
yeah
i like that to also like yeah people are
actually to have people think about that
too and like
because i remember like back cross you'd
like see it it was like so often used as
like
sibling pairing and stuff too and it's
just like it didn't yeah so just using
the terminology of course that gets
really difficult too because like
well which back cross is it on you know
so i i mean i actually do note it'll be
like oh the 2012 black dog selection you
know for the that cherry lime dog bc1f2
number three like so i know that but
like
um
but it could have been but the bc
the same thing what if i put it back on
the cherry lime pop or something like it
would still be the same notation and
yeah that kind of
i just have to write down all the things
basically like
being well labeled is is important and
then
yeah i just really love to see you know
later on i don't know what kind of
research i can do to you know like um
are already able to do a decent amount
and being able to see
how genetically consistent something is
and um
yeah being able to learn from what's the
fastest way to achieve something in a
generation of seeds
um
you know an interesting example that i
really love um
and we got these giant
beautiful
glazed cherry plants in the yard and
these are from green source gardens
and the first time we met nick from
greensborough's gardens i was with ryan
of the humble seat organization and
we went over to their place in
jacksonville uh before they got their
their current farm
and uh yeah we gave them a bunch of
seeds created a bunch of seeds hung out
had a great time put my hands in some of
the most beautiful soil i've ever seen
and
they had this amazing little like
medical
backyard grow that like in the pictures
look like the most giant amazing oasis
you could imagine and the most giant
pinkleberry flowers and um
yeah just the total magic place
but uh with these seeds the the glazed
cherries that that um ryan humbled seeds
organization gave them uh from keith
swett's uh work on on the glace cherries
which is cherry og and it was a cookie's
cross that worked a little bit
that nick ended up taking it to five
generations uh out there and um in their
their farm in
oregon and adapted to their spot and
everything and so like that's a an f5
from you know these seeds when we met
five years ago and then he'd also taken
the the black dog bc4 multiple
generations too so he had two very
established inbred lines that he put
together and made these f1s last year
and he gave gave me some of these and
they're just true f1s you know when we
talk about a hybrid like
um an f1 hybrid like normally it should
be coming from two established lines and
you know he just freaking did the work
spent five years you know and it's just
it's just cool like a gift from when
you first meet and then that turning
into this
amazing thing
but the consistency between these plants
and the giant leaves and the the the
vigor and everything it's just it's what
you'd expect in a f1 generation a lot of
other plants it's it's kind of how it's
done a lot of times you'll take
something to it
you know f9 before and and before you
start putting it together for an f1
yeah certainly i mean it's a really
interesting point you bring up there
because a lot of people talk about how
if you took two really inbred lines and
crossed them together that would be like
what you might think of as like a true
f1 because it's like you know two really
diverse things
do you
find that you like that sort of pairing
over the more like f1 cross f1 making a
new f1
yeah i mean i i guess
i like everything i super like these
these f1s of the chair the glazed
cherries they're just insanely nice uh
they they kind of yeah they're just the
standard of what you'd want from an f1
generation it's amazing um
yeah i mean i think a lot of other
things i'd probably classify as a poly
hybrid
instead of a f1
yeah sure because because you know i
don't know what the i don't have a
pedigree on the other thing and also
when you're just like which i do all the
time too crossing in the you know a
well-established cut or whatever you
don't know if that was a bad seed if
somebody did any work on that or if it
was just a found thing or not um or or
how crazy the the
um the generation was before it you
don't actually know
um because a lot of these things we
don't have any kind of uh pedigree on it
that's something i kind of look forward
to i really like dogs and
i like the idea of like kind of the
breed standard and different things
being built by breeders and so we have
this information that we can uh work
with and and um and actually know all
the you know i like when i look at a
plant i love that i get to like
think about their grandmother and their
great grandfather and all of that stuff
you know like it
and because i i label well
and i take pictures of everything like i
can really go back and just know all
these things it just brings me a lot of
joy to have that family history
yeah it sounds like a consistent theme
i'm picking up that is important to you
is like good documentation good record
keeping do you think that this is
something which unfortunately might not
be done well enough by others at the
moment
well i mean i can always do it better
too but you know i i uh
no actually i mean i go crazy if i do it
wrong
but yeah i don't know like it all works
but yeah
it's tough too and i go to these amazing
farms and they've mixed everything up
and it's just like no like
and then i try to be all positive and
stuff because everything looks great but
i'm like dying inside
um yeah no everyone label well please
please it makes breeders happy
yeah definitely and i think that
like this idea is something even both
myself and obviously you as well are
hoping to promote because there have
been times when you know maybe i've
messaged a breeder and i was like hey
man just so you know um like you should
put the female first and the male second
in when you're listing the parent stuff
and sometimes people get really
defensive and it's like i'm not trying
to have a go at you man i'm just it's
just you know the convention you know
like it just it just helps if we all
follow it right
yeah i mean i like female first it makes
sense to me
so i mean the next question i wanted to
ask was
i'm sure it has happened but just to to
really get the verdict on it have you
ever done a certain cross like maybe
you've taken a certain thing to the f2
or the bx3 and you do it and you're like
oh man i think i might need to go back
and redo that a bit different like i
didn't quite get what i was looking for
does that does that happen or do you
find you instead maybe just find
something you weren't expecting but it's
equally cool and you're like okay it
looks like we're just going to go down
this path
so much unexpected always happens in
life you know it's like you and
you know and
the thing is also
because you know the generations you do
know what to expect too
um
but
i do find that
quite often the plants fulfill my the
expectations because i know their
history but
often i find
that the things i think about first or
like oh that's the one it so often it's
a surprise at the end so often it's it's
like
yeah so you really don't know
anything until you go through the full
process
as far as selection goes
sure
and so a question our viewers always
love to hear our guest answer is are
there any particular traits that you
think are representative of a good male
like i remember just the common one is
like sub cool always used to say you
want a male that you know it's not super
quick flowering but also not the last
one in the pack so he always kind of
pitched it as though you know towards
the later end of things are there any
traits you think represent a good male
or do you think it's just variable and
it depends what you're looking for out
of the map yeah all of them all of them
um
that's the thing it's like what are you
going for i like to work backwards so
like
you know and i like to have a lot of
males
and
um and be able to really
choose what's going to make sense for
something um but every but what i'm
looking for is gonna be completely
based off of kind of the end goal so
it's not a blanket
you know question like and and how do
you do that search are you making a
high cbd
you know you're just making sure that
it's a cbd rich you know then you're
going to do analytics for your mail
search are you looking for resistance
then uh you might want to put them in a
place that's
you know uh gonna be
the place that would bring out uh
molds and disease and and see the the
strongest ones um
you might be just it's all about smell
and just the stem rub is really gonna be
what it's about um
you know you really might really care
about um flower structures so you might
really look at like what how does that
that male flower look too um
there's a lot of things to look at uh
general health bigger um
so it but normally you're putting all of
these factors together a bit um and then
paying attention to the things that you
have already observed from the past you
know if you if you know a certain stem
rub is associated with an end flower
like that's something you gain by just
paying attention to plants for like 20
years um
yeah it
it cracked me up at the it was one of
the regen conferences and and mean gene
was was talking on one of the panels and
uh somebody kind of had asked that
question you know and he just started
talking about all this stuff and he was
describing uh how you know if you smell
pickles on that early stem rub you know
that
ends up being like your gassy ones and
just all this like nuanced details of
stuff that he'd been observing for like
two decades and like at the end of it it
was just like the dude was like looking
for like you know a short answer you
know like you know what's a good male or
whatever and uh
you know it was like the answer was like
well you just pay attention for 20 years
and then you start to get uh
the beginning of an idea
yeah it was kind of uh so yeah there's
just a ton of things to to put all
together and what your selection
is gonna be for for what you're making
um
but you know i want them to be resist
and i want them to be healthy i don't
want people to
struggle you know
i don't want them to have to
use things to deal with uh mildews and
molten so like if i can have that be
part of the male selection that's super
great um but i'm not gonna do that at
the detriment of like the quality and
smell too like it's like still like
there's nothing coming off that stem rub
it doesn't matter how resistant it is
necessarily
um
well hopefully there's a really good
smelling one next to it that's resistant
too you know
yeah certainly certainly oh
actually for the males too you know you
brought up the like oh you just want the
ones that are the right timing i really
think that all the different
timings are useful you know like i put
some
just to play with it see what happens i
put some of like the most early mails
that came out of a orange valley dog
cherry lime dog cross uh onto some auto
ogs
just and see what that does next year
you know i'll observe that and there's
multiple ways i can go with that i could
make more autos with it or i could just
have an earlier flowering generation
make selections off that um you know see
a little mix of things
but like what do you want to do and and
where what's your environment like maybe
you only do want to be those using those
super early flowering males but like if
you have a really nice full season maybe
you super want that full stacking all
august you know you don't want it to be
you know wasting you know and flowering
early uh instead of continuing to grow
and stack
um so
it's really dependent on your your end
goal and where you are um
you know if you're closer to the coast
[__] use those earlier males maybe
um
but i think you should use them all too
the other thing is i i like staggering
of
harvest times and being able to work
with farmers to
create kind of a genetic plan to do that
so like if you want to be
harvesting from
you know
mid late september until november
you
like
then you get to do each week you know
we'll take down this and then we'll take
down that and we'll take down this um
when it's all hey it's october 20th and
it's all ready
at the same time drying space is is
difficult uh and then then quality goes
down if you're trying to like pack
everything in you're doing things
quickly and all of that and you might
not be able to save it all and
um so i think you know really staggering
um flowering times makes a lot of sense
so
you know making that notation which i
like to do like i note those those first
flowering males um and those later ones
and note
note that information so um
i can have an idea of the next
generation once i see that working then
i can recommend that to a farmer for hey
i know that
this variety is going to be done
on the first week of october this one
will be the second this one will be the
third
and that helps stagger that kind of
harvest and what i really like is for
ice water hash varieties and some of the
varieties like um
the banana crosses the holy nana crack
uh banana dog and the things are really
voltron um which is uh athena holy crap
times um sapphire scout black dog
um those are incredibly resistant and
later uh season you know it's like the
end of october there and they look so
mature and good and um
uh actually you could see the voltron on
the calendar i think you might have got
at the emerald cup um oh yeah on uh the
october shot is a candid cush uh photo
and from high water farms and it was dry
farmed and just like
just the maturity of the crystals and
the size
and this is a flower that really
literally nothing was done like it was
cover crop tilled correctly planted and
then let the winds just rip through it
and it was let to dry and to like
get like ravaged by the environment and
then it became hearty and strong and
grew like flowers that would blow away
any of the most cracked out indoor you
you'll see like it's so freaking just
frosted out dense and beautiful and um
but so like that holy nana crack though
is a great example for the really high
resistance and it does a thing with the
the flower structure where it separates
each different
nug just enough that
you don't have
air water being trapped
that each one is just segmented enough
that it that it has a good open air
and it's already incredibly resistant to
botrytis
and it also doesn't grow
in a in a shape that would trap that
moisture
and then that also lends better to ice
water hash because each one of these
nugs has more surface area and they have
the perfect trichomes for it too just
like um
large large sized heads
and heads first and not
a whole lot of necks like all that
energy is going to really nice heads
and you can harvest those in november
when it's like cold and not have any
worry of any mold and um it's a really
nice time to make fresh frozen after
everything else is harvested
yeah what an awesome answer there and
something you brought up i'd love to
talk a little more about is the role
autos might play in the future
do you see them potentially filling a
niche in terms of maybe little windows
where other cultivars aren't quite
suitable or do you think it's kind of a
different domain to what the farms will
be working with long term in a certain
respect
yeah you know it's been slow at first
but oh my god it's game on with autos
right now holy [__] they're [__] nice
they're freaking nice dude i have this
beautiful garden over here that um yeah
friend ryan had worked on with the
humble seed organization and um these
auto ogs
fastest growing plants i've ever seen in
my life like just stunning and i just
direct sewed them they're feminized
they're
uh yeah it's a project we did locally
and they are uh just phenomenal like i
have
um
yeah they're some of them are above my
shoulder almost as tall as me just
filling out everywhere freaking
smell amazing there's bubble gum there's
fruit there's gas
and um
incredibly sturdy stalks
and
an incredible trichome production like i
don't you know it's like it's not like
how autos were um
the work's been done
and uh there's a lot that can be done
and actually looking at these the just
the stocks i'm like damn these would be
amazing fiber plants too like if you're
able to both harvest the flowers and the
fibers because with autos you have so
many close to each other that you're
growing so many stocks you know that um
i could see like
there being kind of a cool
combo of that uh
because man they're they're thick and
stocky a thing about autos that's really
interesting too is um
just how reactive they are to their
environment they are metabolic machines
they grow incredibly fast or they gr or
they don't at all
the conditions really mean a lot it's
really easy to have them stunt out and
be really small
at different times a year like they
don't want to be like cold or too wet
they definitely don't want to be eaten
by banana slugs all winter long like
they were here um but the ones
that i i just drex out at the perfect
time for um to get them to be able to
veg in this
and and flower during the the mid of the
summer um or just it's just game on and
the ones that went right in the ground
uh grew incredibly fast and i've never
watered them
um just
and i think they really like that uh
they don't want to be
too wet there's
obviously there's places where they
would just dry out and die but this
isn't one of them they can tap in and um
the
the soil biology is is rich and so it it
holds onto moisture pretty well and i'm
in an area that's relatively
it's green and and it gets a
uh the marine moisture it hasn't rained
but
they uh they really enjoy just being
able to tap in they don't want much
water but they do want to be able to eat
so i did amend them ahead of time like
um some fish bone and bokashi and kelp
and um some trace mineral and that
that's all
uh and
yeah they just do they just go the ones
in pots are definitely considerably
smaller um and any ones that had that
were left in the four-inch pots like i
did
i planted a bunch and then i decided to
fill in some of the gaps a little bit
more with some plants that were weak uh
that were in some four inch pots a week
later
and uh you know about half the size just
in that time and that's how much like
you lose every day that uh
that they don't get to just go so
they're just they're metabolic machines
so when you you dial it in um and what
works in your your place like
super powerful what you can do with
autos and
um
as we continue to like just
cross in awesome flavors awesome
attributes like you know autos will be
doing
all the different things that we'd want
them to be doing you know whether it's
for good hash whether it's for cbd
whether it's just insanely good flowers
and but i also think yeah fiber and all
kinds of
other aspects are very viable with with
autos and um i'm just stunned with what
i've seen with these ones this year it's
a whole nother world the last two years
in autos
yeah certainly i mean you know the guys
at mephisto certainly really done a lot
of work in i think a lot of consumers
eyes they made people realize you can do
good stuff and now people recognize
across the board there's there's good
orders my question has been doing a lot
of great work too
yeah certainly there for that work
well i was just going to ask can we
expect a black dog auto down the line
and if so would you want to just cross
it to a root or alice and keep a black
dog or more like cross it to like an og
auto and have like a hybridy sort of
thing
uh yes that's being that's being figured
out
but but man these og autos are looking
so nice with it too um i mean i'll be
making the cross regardless but uh yeah
we'll see we'll see what works out from
there and there's definitely potential
for that and i think it would actually
lend really well to that because it's
already got a very consistent quality
that works well for lots grown uh
smaller together
and and high production so i think
that's
highly likely uh that would be a couple
years probably um but highly likely
yeah sure and the other thing you
brought up which was really interesting
to me was and you've said it a few times
dry farming and the reason why i'm
interested in this is because i feel
like
as the concept takes off more there's
more of a demand for seed because
obviously clones don't do very well in a
dry farming situation do you think that
is a possible situation where outdoor
growers
move away from clones almost entirely
and are just using seed because of the
benefits maybe in a dry farming context
maybe in general but do you think that
they're going to move more consistently
to seed and a little away from clone
um
i mean the market's still going to
demand certain clone varieties that's
always going to be the case and there's
certain dry farm areas that can still
grow
cultivars pretty pretty well um high
water farms being one of them but um
but in general they just grow all seed
actually these dry farms um and they
super prefer that uh the way they tap in
and yeah the expression
and um there are
a few dry farms grow in some of these
autos right now so um yeah we'll get to
see exactly how they're expressing there
i think uh that absolutely makes it like
the dream of just uh direct sowing
feminized autos and doing nothing um
on dry farms yeah i think that's
something that is very much uh
probably i mean well happening on small
scales this year and and we'll just grow
i'm sure next year in the following
years
yeah awesome awesome
so something i wanted to chat with you
because we recently had him on the show
was the legend himself irizan
and i know that you've been working with
some varieties and you guys are friends
and have got some sort of work together
would you be able to give us a little
bit of an insight into what you're
working with and what your hopes are to
do with that
yeah
man it just like made my heart sing to
hear that shout out from him i just
respect his work so much and consider
him a great friend and
um such a great friend to cannabis and
just honestly like the world uh really
respect the work that he's doing
tremendously i think
he's one of the most important people in
cannabis and uh i love him for it uh to
to be able to work with these things
from
all these different places where he's
done the the documentation
um not just of the plant which he does
an amazing job of but of the terroir and
the culture and the um the factors that
led up to
that you know that kind of variety
existing
um
yeah it's just amazing so all these
different parts of the world they get to
to read about
the culture what you know what they were
producing um you know and are these
hash
multi-generational uh hash communities
are they
um
specific farmers are they like
totally
true primordial land race and uh one of
the the most amazing things that's to
have in the garden right now is um
seeds from
sea plants from uh lolap valley in um
cashmere
and uh deepak razon had uh he had
brought these um
he was documenting the seeds out there
and
um
these plants growing in the forest of of
cashmere
in the low lab valley and
he paid attention to the pollination and
the males coming out and then came back
out uh to collect seeds and got just all
these amazing pictures of them and these
are true um true wolves basically like
if you were to
you put it in context of dogs you know
like we have all our different hybrids
and stuff and this these are wolves in
their environment um and it's kind of
like cannabis for the land before time
because it's not affected by any other
um feral varieties or cross-pollination
it's not affected by human encroachment
it's not affected by light pollution
um they just are
what they are and
what's amazing about that is cannabis is
cannabis man like these are still
straight cannabis plants and
uh they're incredibly
interesting and unique and uh i love i
have a time lapse on them right now and
i like watching them at night and they
like they just super tuck their leaves
down real tight to the stem and then
right at like four in the morning i mean
all the plants do this a little bit but
these do it really extreme they just
start to like wake up and it's a total
like morning yoga just like and they
already know where the sun's gonna be
wave you know like an hour before it
gets there just getting into position
and
it's a beautiful dance to watch and um
you know just right now i'm getting to
see the first mail
you know it's starting to show and the
first females and there's even a pink
pistol coming off of one of them um
amazing um you know carotene and
production and anthocyanin production
and um
like the um
yeah they're just really interesting
plants man uh
they're ready to protect themselves you
know from the environment the thing that
i find really interesting about them was
their seeds too um which are incredibly
small they're probably about
a tenth of the size of a normal like
domesticated variety like black dog or
something and
um they
they also take a while to germinate and
not a whole lot of them germinate like
quickly and
a lot of this i think has to do with um
you know what what works for
survivability out there because nobody's
um
being like nobody's saving the seeds and
then and then starting them like you
would in uh in a variety that would
start to be domesticated where
somebody's like oh i like this flower
and you're smelling it and then you keep
it and then you start the seeds from
that that's that's starting that work
towards domestication pretty quickly um
but these are because nobody's doing
that they're wind dispersed more they're
like small they're ready to like
fall out of the plant easy and so
they're kind of sharp lemon shaped uh
teeny little seeds
and then they don't want to germinate
before
the it's the right time of year
otherwise they would just germinate and
get killed by like snow or
you know the wrong climate so they're
just
they're well adapted like we're a
domesticated variety you add water to it
it's like oh a germ didn't like you know
within 24 hours you know and that's
something to celebrate um
but that would be death in the wild
environment you know it's like if all
those seeds germ this germinated the
second they hit the ground and water hit
them then they'd all just die that
winter um so it's just interesting uh
those quick changes that happen and and
not just the plant but just
right in the beginning with seed
morphology and seed behavior
um
so that was really interesting just to
learn from them and the way they
germinate is so slow like it's like they
don't just shoot out the radical it's
like this slow
goo of white radical that's kind of
just
over the course of days that starts to
come out and then they grow all small
and little and but when they go then
they start to like reach a bit and they
have like these amazing
branches that kind of swing down low and
come up and
nice narrow leaves and i'm sure they're
going to have a decent amount of color
and
well some will but yeah you see purple
and green varieties you see full on
trichome production you see
cbd and thc production so
it's just kind of interesting you know
even from the early uh
days cannabis had all this potential
stored in it and that's kind of what i'm
seeing in this too that it was all there
but what what we see with our
all the varieties and all the things
that we have now is
how that relationship has evolved you
know that that mutualistic relationship
that we entered into
um
with cannabis like that's what's
different
you know between
uh a true primordial and these
domesticated varieties is our
relationship with them
but i don't know it makes me think
though that maybe low lab was like these
the
these early varieties
still could produce all of these
incredibly useful things for humans um
and our medicine
and i i think about dogs and how
um
you know like wolves are
are adapted for a location for a forest
for
that place they're high you know they're
ready to survive
but they have no um
relationship with humans the humans are
something to be avoided and everything
but a dog is like
everything isn't they're engaged with
how
do we
interact and
bring
benefit to a human they're always
studying our face they're always wanting
to know what we're feeling they're
wanting to know what the next job that
they can do
um
and that was like this mutualistic
relationship that got entered into a
long time ago and that became this
evolutionary shift between a wolf and a
dog
and all of a sudden now like this wild
animal will
watch
our
livestock like it won't eat them it will
guard them and protect them for us i
mean that's a wild jump for
an animal to do um they'll go to war for
us they will watch our children they
will
um you know allow us to grow crops on
our land without pigs like rooting it up
they will hunt for us they'll in the
case of like yeah the uh
saluki in egypt like 3000 years ago
they'll chase a rabbit down and grab it
and bring it
back to you
like at 45 miles an hour highly
specialized bred
uh animals that that quickly adapt to
whatever we want and like human envision
something and creates a breeding program
and makes selections just so quickly
that stuff happens and it doesn't happen
like that with other species and i think
the difference is that
there was a moment of mutualism
um and an evolutionary strategy
for that between humans and cannabis and
humans and and dogs that that's it's
super similar and i think that's why
they're so similar in how we look at
breeding with them too
but yeah the low lab gets to teach me a
lot about um
about what was and and what is
yeah what a phenomenal answer i mean you
you actually answered the next question
i was going to ask which was why do we
see so many breeders also breed dogs but
there you go
you nailed it you nailed it well i did
the same thing too i had a dog and
vision in my mind and i went like crazy
for years and bred like the father the
video had the grandmother and mom and
like yeah all the generations and i did
it i made the exact dog in my mind and
it was so incredible but
they all passed away now and
and they're they're in the living soil
here and um
actually [__] that make that brings me
to a um
another uh
story uh
involving irasin
uh so he
he had uh i had got the
uh missouri sharif seeds from him he had
uh the missouri which were um
wildly they were labeled wild um i
believe they have domestic feral
influence because of
um how nice they are and also like the
way the seeds are
um
but they uh god just the biggest
the most amazing fan leaves like you'd
have like a plant that was like two feet
tall that had a fan leaf that was like
16 inches like long or something it was
crazy um and so these were really
beautiful plants to like have growing in
the garden and um
our dog ashley um
last year had uh
developed a cancer in her um
her jaw that just grew a big cancerous
tumor right in front of her face that
was just it was really
it was really tough you know just the
but she was you know she was fine for so
long you know we live in a beautiful
place took her to the beach every day
fed her fried chicken and
um
you know made every day you know great
until um
until it was
time yeah awesome
but um
so
when she passed though um
we dug a grave and uh right next to her
mom and dad and
her dad has a beautiful tree that's
growing above her and
um she
we laid her in the ground and inoculated
her with uh you know good beneficial
uh fungus and and compost and lots of
worms and
stropharia and oyster mushrooms and all
that kind of stuff shiitakes and
had her
adorned with things
ready to
return her to the living soil but then
um she liked to eat cannabis and she was
actually particularly good at um
identifying um she she liked uh full
spectrum uh cannabinoids too so she'd
get those like type twos almost always
like i like a little cbd with my thc
she was just
anyway so we grabbed some of the like
glass leaves that she was uh munching on
and then i'm looking at these giant
mazar leaves and i'm just like oh i
gotta
gotta add that to it and so there's a
bouquet of flowers and cannabis leaves
that were adorned and laid on top of her
grave
and uh this time of year her father's
tree had had all these white beautiful
flowers
blossom on them and they were starting
to they were in the
tail end of the blossoming and ready for
the petals to fall and i shook the tree
and all these petals started raining
down gently and and littered the grave
in a very beautiful aesthetic way
um with this nice bouquet on top of it
and i had taken a picture of this um
before we
buried her and had a fire and you know
drank some tequila and cried and um
and when i was talking to deepak i
re-risen next um he
had uh
i i told him this story and you know i
let him know that there was a mazar leaf
on her grave and he's like do you know
what mazar means
i was like no
he's like mazar means grave
mazar e sharif is grave of the saint
and i'm like ashley was a saint
so
so i um i had already actually
pollinated a uh
mazar uh with um
a black dog pc6
and so i put that on top of her grave to
grow the seeds
and so this year i'm growing some of the
um
st ashley mazar saint ashley's mazar
wow what a beautiful story
that's that's incredibly touching
i uh i it makes me wonder do you think
that the process of incorporating
whether it be ashes whether it maybe if
it's a dog you might be able to use the
full thing do you think this is
something which people could benefit
from incorporating more because i
remember i mentioned it to josh and
kelly of dragonfly and i think she said
her mom um has her she's got her
mother's ashes in one of her greenhouses
and i was like man that's that's what i
want for me
sure
well
i mean
i mean from a science it's just it's
impossible to say what's what or because
there's so many variables but one thing
i know that uh plants respond to love
and uh if you put that into it it means
something and
and um
and i mean the soil beneath that plant
the soil that's that returned her body
is is absolutely alive and all of the
organisms returning her are um
yeah doing a process of love of
returning
that organic matter back to life back to
rejuvenation so
yeah i think that process is powerful
certainly and and do you have any hopes
for
the long-term trajectory of the the the
strain and the cross or is it just a
like a gift holy crap is one of the most
beautiful plants i've ever seen in my
life it's so pretty so we'll see but oh
my god the leaves are just so
dark and big and reptilian it's so
healthy and it just i just love it it's
just the plant just screams like love
um
and so i have one that like started
early i had a whole bunch of slugs eat
my first rounds uh this is a very
intense area for slugs but um i started
a whole another round of them too so i
have a really good group right now to um
to make the next generation with but um
yeah there's a couple people growing
some right now too um i think actually
indigo farms up in oregon uh just let me
know that uh saint ash mazar made it
into their
um research
plot that will uh yeah so i can't wait
to go go see her up there and there's a
other couple other special friends i
i'll be able to probably see
see what she does in those places and um
yeah we'll see what the future holds but
man uh
she's it's just so pretty
but right off the bat
yeah what a what what like a powerful
and beautiful story thank you so much
for sharing that
the question which kind of come to mind
when i was thinking of that and
especially when you were talking about
the mazar and some of the indian
cultivars is
do you think that the expression you're
getting from this really nice natural
expression you spoke about where you
know they're almost given the sun
salutations
do you do you think that that might have
been lost almost if you tried to take
those same seeds and like grow them in a
like a sort of a salt and cocoa
environment like do you think that
there's a synergy from that you're
trying to grow them naturally in the way
they were origin originally conceived
well yeah absolutely um
i mean i don't think they'd be doing the
sun salutations if there wasn't the sun
going up and down and you know it's like
and they wouldn't be choosing the part
of the sky to start aiming towards
before because it's always the same
freaking thing right above them making
that buzzing noise um yeah i don't know
i think like do you how do you feel like
when you're in a
a desk with a bunch of like
noisy fluorescents in school like
first like being out in the woods like
at a botany tour or something you know
it's like i think yeah of course of
course it's different the
it's a completely different experience
for them um
yeah i mean
their environment everyone's environment
affects everything and they're very
alive and conscious and are constantly
adapting thinking doing things and
feeling things
and they feel our love they feel our
connection they feel the environment
that they're in and it's definitely
way different
in an indoor environment
than a natural one but i mean a natural
one could be really rough on them too
you know they won't they want to be
drying out and dying in the sun or or in
a whole cold harsh winter or neglected
in a greenhouse and forgot you know it's
like
they still gotta have their soils their
their roots uh in a nice soil or some
kind of nutrition
yeah of course
they're very efficient too that's the
thing too that yeah that's neat with the
low lab too like they you know you could
tell that they would just make do with
whatever they have you know they
they don't need this like giant amount
of resources put out in front of them
like they could grow in a crack you know
yeah i love that the hardy
so a topic which comes up somewhat
frequently on the show is the discussion
around the idea of
do you think seeds created in an organic
or even better regenerative farming
practice
produce better seeds like maybe hearty
things like that do you think that plays
into it or would you be happy to buy
seeds
that were produced in salts compared to
ones that were produced in soil
um
yeah so i mean there's definitely
difference i i mean
obviously i have my feelings about you
know the intention and love that we put
into things and so getting you know
seeds from some of my favorite
regenerative farmers who have been doing
this work and been breeding and been
putting love into their their land and
into their projects um means a hell of a
lot more to me than anything else and i
don't really have like any extra space
for anyone else's stuff but my own so
like it's just like the really cool
close people i really love what they're
doing that that make it in um so
uh
but um
there's a lot of ways to do things and
there's really
a lot of like you know let's say
you're making some feminized autos like
maybe that's the most efficient way to
do them i'm not going to say
it's not and if you're doing the correct
genetic work and you're doing the
quality standards ahead of time then um
yeah there's there's cases where those
seeds might be uh
desirable useful for me but the thing is
if i'm going to do something like that
there has to be the
there has to be the work behind it and i
have to know that like it is what it is
and it has to be like super useful
um and yeah so like and i think that's
gonna be the you know a lot of large
scale um
farming and stuff like you know they're
gonna need very consistent seeds
produced and you know the way
that that's done um isn't always going
to be you know a farmer pulling pouring
all their love and heart into their
living soil plants sometimes it's just
going to be straight production and if
the genetic work is is done correctly
then um you know then those are going to
be useful seeds
yeah for sure
so
good point to bring it up i think how
did you initially get into the
regenerative farming movement was it
just like a natural progression or did
you meet someone and they really kind of
changed your trajectory so to speak how
did that happen
it was being here
um during the time
when um well there's a lot of indoor
growing which was like you know it's not
regenerative at all but it was mostly
like kind of
college-aged kids growing indoor the
arcada area and just humbled in general
and there was a lot of outdoor growing
too but there was
um you know the the high prices of
purple and then bubba and then og uh
drove this um incredible
insanity of what was possible
economically
which ended up being very disastrous
environmentally um
so like all of a sudden like hey it
makes sense to freaking make some giant
underground
you know several hundred light
grow run by a diesel generator that you
literally truck tankers out and fill
next to a sensitive watershed and that
was happening a lot and it was just like
well this is insane and this is all
based off of prohibition you know this
is like they have to hide and we're
destroying
like our environment because of these
incredibly
high prices that are that shouldn't
exist in a real you know uh
economic
uh
reality that's not messed up by the
government's war on drugs um
it's just destroyed
you know it makes inefficiencies it
creates cancers it creates environmental
issues when things like that happen
and
at this time too a lot of the
indoor growers um that were more in town
that were you know college age started
going out to the hills and they were
taking what they had indoor where they
were making good money on these
uh you know varieties grown inside and
actually you know more varieties went
back then too but then you know og
started to become take over harder and
harder of course bub always got good
prices but there was a lot of great
varieties that still did pretty good
um but it was the beginning one was that
purple when l.a was just crazy about
purple it just drove this huge
um
change in the economics of the whole
thing and
so when all these growers started going
out with indoor tactics too and even how
they're growing their outdoor flowers
and depths and stuff where they're like
going to the hydra store and buying all
these expensive things that only really
make sense and small grows
inside and bring it like large scale and
just like wow you're spending so much
money and you're actually [__] [__]
up instead of you know cultivating the
soil you're like bringing a bunch of you
know
engineered soil from freaking really far
away and bringing it up into the
mountains and like you know all this
stuff like mined in canada and sent down
and then bringing all this perlite and
bringing it out to these sensitive areas
and then using pesticides and all of
that and it was just like
dude this is not
this is not working this isn't how it
should be um and it's totally out of
balance
and
uh and and the thing is a lot of like
good people are doing this too because
it's just like what do you know you know
what you know from the grow shop you
just take what you're doing small and
you apply it larger so it's like there's
not it's not like anyone's like
out there evil oh i'm gonna [__] up the
environment and do this you know they're
just trying to grow some good weed in
the way that they know some people gave
no [__] and like you know we're total
[__] about it but
i'm not saying not the case but you know
some people just were ignorant to it or
and just were and just for trying to do
their thing
um so i i just saw this moment where
you know there's a lot of education that
needed to happen and and change in the
way people did things and what i loved
about it is it made [__] cheaper and so
like going to like a grow where
you know they were just grown with salts
and you know using
avid and
maxi and
whatever extra crazy salt stuff whether
it's bushmaster or [__] whatever
insanity and uh you know and not really
getting the best results really you know
it's like
you're probably not gonna you know
like look kind of cool but it's probably
not tasting that great probably have
some disease issues all that stuff and
so
there are certain farms we're like well
how about we build a whole bunch of
biodynamic compost right right here and
or we just cover crop we mulch that in
or we just do simple things amending
with you know
fish and kelp and bakashi and trace
minerals and
um and then
there's one farm too where like the
neighbors were
cattle ranchers too and so
and they had a bunch of equipment so
they could just go and clean out their
um
their cattle bins and or their pens and
you know that was benefiting them and
then we had this like nice resource to
work with and i'd utilize all kinds of
other stuff on the property to to
compost that in and then they put that
on and then saw the best year that
they'd ever seen and had to use uh
i think they said a ninth of the water
that they were using before
and didn't have to buy anything and had
by far the best year that they ever saw
so it's like when somebody all of a
sudden sees that they're like wait i was
spending a bunch of money [__] [__]
up like
not be doing the right things for the
watershed or the the end patience and
it's like all i have to do is just like
do a few things thinking about the soil
plant do nothing
uh besides pull tarps or whatever
they're doing and
and uh
and i get better results for literally
like no money spent like
so
yeah yeah you know i just saw that as as
something hey i think these ideas can
spread
and they did you know and i loved it
when you know like more you know maybe a
when a redneck is spreading this idea or
a hippie spreading this idea or you know
an environmentalist or a law officer you
know all of a sudden like you know
became i ended up on a panel with like
the ag commissioner and the sheriff you
know and it was kind of funny it was
like ag commissioner
uh sheriff biovortex it was like what
the [__] is a biovortex you know like we
know what our commissioner is and the
sheriff is this guy's a biovortex
and it was you know super fun being on
the panel and having this debate there
you know they're not debate like they
fully were you know just like hell yeah
you know uh with all this stuff like
this that's the kind of stuff we want to
see
um you know and as things become more
open
um
it was kind of funny too like correcting
the ad commissioner on the pronunciation
of michael butinil because he kept
saying michael button hall and it's like
dude it's like one of the most important
like
issues with like cannabis and california
at that time because it was uh
um that's like the um active ingredient
in eagle 20 and like other things that
are designed for systemic powdery mildew
uh control
and they're
kind of nasty poisons
that concentrate really well in in
concentrated so they like so
if you're making hash you're making uh
bho or any of those kinds of
concentrates the
the microbutal concentrates would be
very high um and they kind of would come
out with the thc that it was hard to
separate it from
that and
what was actually kind of cool about
that is all of a sudden everyone started
failing that used that you know like
like all these different extractors just
started seeing fails everywhere
and um and the thing is it's so systemic
that someone might not
even had to use it they got clones from
the someone who had used it
and uh you know you might not see uh
noticeable levels in the flower but once
you get the the concentrate uh you're
you're actually at a fail level
and um that was a huge economic uh
driver for people to clean up their act
uh having those um
those standards and testing and seeing
what was coming out in concentrates and
just how pervasive certain things were
um
so yeah i mean sometimes you know like
there's a lot of like shitty things that
end up
working out
the way it needs to you know like end up
bringing more information or awareness
to things you know um
yeah yeah certainly and i mean you raise
an interesting point there something
i've heard a lot recently is this idea
it's just anecdotal but i mean i think
it might resonate with you as someone
said to me
you don't really see bud with pm these
days you just you just see a lot of
concentrates
and i was like i was like yeah that's
true isn't it like pm's just just you
know it's just gone like as in obviously
it's all just getting turned to
concentrates um and so yeah it speaks to
the point you mentioned and just to
build on that what do you think is kind
of the next step or the direction in
which big ag is going to go do you think
it's
still this existential kind of threat to
the the the people in the industry like
what we initially thought or do you
think there's going to be
more of an even playing field kind of
like what we see in canada where the big
firms are just really actually failing
quite miserably
yeah
i i don't think uh like i know of any of
the local or regen farms that are we're
planning on going into the um
large-scale phytochemical
like
business or into large-scale fiber
production and stuff too you know it's
like these are these are
um people still want craft flowers uh
and i kind of think
um
that those
that the more educated the public is the
more that they're gonna want stuff like
that and i don't really think
uh the large companies are gonna be able
to
really
take the place of that but they of
course like as far as production for
medicines for biomass for all of that um
it's a big ag world
but there's ways to adapt to that and
hopefully um
can get these ideas of how they can save
money in the way that they are growing
and not just have like it be uh you know
all these salts pesticides and all this
plastic that's a big issue right now too
there's all these hemp fields in oregon
all over
it's just the use of these
all the plastic mulching um and and then
all the the
the drip lines and just so much
resources to grow
uh plant and
you know that's one thing is is
people just gonna have to do it really
cheap and with less resources and like
all that stuff takes a lot of labor and
you have to buy it and all that stuff
and so i'm just
hopeful that
that those economic drivers will help
the ecological
outcomes
of farming practices on large scale when
it comes to cannabis uh because i mean
just think about that cost of like
running drip lines to everything and
putting that mulch out or the plastic
running all the plastic all the time
buying all of those things and then like
all that [__] just goes in the dump and
it's like
killing the soil and it's it's just yeah
i don't know it's insane
yeah but really like you know when i'm
looking at these autos in the garden
that are just were germinated and
growing i haven't watered or done
anything it's like to me that's the
future of big ag like
just the do nothing approach and it's
just like and really it's it's it's
actually the breeding and the genetics
and like you know getting quality stuff
you know sovereign fields and uh you
know done a great job like producing
seeds with the right quality for those
large scale uh
applications and having the feminized uh
with it which you know is like kind of
interesting from
because i really like all natural and
regular breeding and regen but
you know having feminists super useful
for certain things it's also useful for
selfing and understanding different
things about plants and doing other
things but
um but being able to direct sow i mean
[__] that's a big deal for uh less
resources if everyone if you have to pot
every plant and veg it and then go it
out and plant it and
every every step that you can take out
work or resource being used and still
get a
a nice production i think is
the way to go and and and in general
that's always going to be a more
environmental way because um ecological
is economical
sure
and what are your thoughts on genetic
modification of cannabis because our
buddies chimera and sam skunk man over
at molecular farms are certainly doing
it do you feel like that's a bit of a
step too far or do you feel like there
might be value in that i think there's
value in everything i just want i'm not
a i yeah i want to learn
everything and and if something
makes sense then
yeah i'm not like a
i can't just say
you know [__] i mean you can just pull
out like one thing and then lose an
expression that you didn't want like
that's great like that could be super
useful um
what i what i'm afraid of actually more
than genetically modifying or
and how you want to define that can be
different like is it are you talking
about crispr like or
i mean really actually breeding is
genetically modifying like what it just
what i'm doing is genetically modifying
it through
the work that we're doing as a human um
you know i might not be taking a segment
of dna and pulling it out or putting
something else in um i think there's a
lot of use in pulling out something that
might give an undesirable uh expression
and why not see what we could do with
that i i don't see why not
but i do have a fear that
with patents um once you genetically
modify something then
that's like a really easy place to be
like i own this or something and
so
making sure that we
don't
that we keep potential free
with this plan medical and breeding
potential for everyone to be able to
work with it in any way that we want um
so
yeah my fear is more the legal
repercussions of people trying to
own different things through genetically
modified work than the actual uh process
because i'm super interested to
see what we can do you know if you can
just pull out a little segment not rpm
like i don't know why not [__] it let's
do it
hey yeah hell yeah so
just
but i would prefer doing it through
natural selection and just observation
and working with the plant that way i i
do
i feel more um
hormone i don't know they're just that
resonates with me better but um i'm not
against anything really
unless it hurts the environment or it
hurts people's humans rights
yeah yeah good good rules to to live by
uh just to loot back to a topic before
because we we commonly get asked this by
our listeners
let's say that you totally in line with
everything you've said and everything
you believe but unfortunately maybe you
live in the city maybe in an apartment
or something like that you know and the
goal is to get to a farm one day but
just unfortunately that's not quite now
do you think that there is like you can
still do your best to you know do living
organic soil indoors and like is there a
compromise that you feel like you know
you're doing the best for the situation
you've got or do you feel like unless
you're outdoors it is really quite hard
to try to you know get to the standard
that you're at
yeah no i mean i freaking i think that
the the personal little indoor is just
such a oasis and a beautiful thing to
celebrate um
i'm not against that at all you know i
don't like the
insane large-scale use of
of lights like especially in areas where
the sun's just beating it's just like an
insane use of of resources and energy
but like man to have a relationship with
cannabis in your own apartment or
uh if you're in a place where the
growing conditions aren't that good or
just to be able to have cannabis
year-round like [__] yeah i i think
that's a wonderful thing to do and i
think it is super doable with living
soil type
production and i think people have a
really good time you know doing those
multiple years of cultivating soils you
know people are proud about how many
runs they've done in the same
living soil bed and you know they show
how they keep getting better when they
understand certain ways of of giving
back to it
but yeah i mean it could be really
simple too like but just getting started
off um
you know i mean ideally like you could
be doing a full living soil thing but if
you just
want to mix some amendments with some
with uh some nice potting soil uh well
one thing i like is is pumice instead of
perlite
um
and
uh you know getting some nice worm
castings um or
ideally making your own from your
compost but making sure you don't let
too many
uh unwanted
critters get into the indoor situation
that's the way the problem comes in it's
just like i want to just like be able to
use any compost or living soil in like
whatever cool way that you want outside
everything stays in balance but second
you go inside you know any little extra
critters can get out of balance um
there's nothing to regulate them and
you know so you don't want your thrips
and your spider mites and you don't want
your fungus gnats and you don't want all
those things
that
are yeah different flies that might like
compost so being wary of how you avoid
all that kind of stuff
i think akashi is a super useful tool
because if you just
mix like an amendment let's say you're
using um
well a really good one is like dragonfly
earth medicine makes those nice
products they're radiant green is a nice
one to mix in um
and but like just inexpensive stuff is
uh fish bone um
azomite or just straight trace mineral
um
you know some kind of fish meal or kelp
of course that's bringing stuff from the
ocean and you gotta think about like how
you feel about
you know what's going on in the ocean
but i guess you know we've polluted
everywhere so um
i don't know how you got to deal with it
i love all the minerals that is stored
in kelp and um
and yeah this the nutritional quality of
fish bone and plants seem to really like
it but kashi seems to eat it really
quickly and
um
compost teas um you know just having a
high quality compost some some good
quality fish hydro hydroslate
and
you know good amount of air in a bucket
it's real simple thing to do um
just and it's a fun thing to do like
looking under the microscope too
and it becomes a whole another part of
the cultivation experience because
you're like
now you're actually thinking about the
microbes and um
you know so just putting some good tea i
mean some good compost and some clean
water and i've been using rainwater
because i have nice rainwater catchment
system put in with
dan of high tide permaculture a little
bit ago
he's also the one that
has been a big influence on developing
the regenerative cannabis farm award and
and a lot of
the permaculture
um
techniques that we put forward and he's
been
working
with compliant farms and helping people
come
into environmental and
regulation and
compliance in the cannabis world
um
sorry yeah a little tangent there but
it's awesome to be able to work with the
rain water because it's like it just
comes from the sky it's like the ph is
fine there's nothing in it and you get
to
bubble up some really clean compost tea
that way
um
and
then after like 24 hours or so then it's
fun to look at it under the microscope
and see what you got going on see if you
could uh you can see the fungal hyphae
growing you can see the clusters of
bacteria you see like the four systems
that are created uh from the the
fungal networks that begin to
develop the mycelial networks and you
get to see the
um
the protozoa like roaming through these
forests and going around and eating all
kinds of stuff and like
um you know when you start to like know
what kind of life is is healthy and you
know that it's an oxygenated environment
then um it's a pretty simple and fun
thing to do i mean it's just
some food like caliper fish
really good quality compost water and a
bunch of air
you want to have a good aerator and i
don't go with stones just go with a
straight pipe
yeah just you just want it to bubble
there you go i didn't know that one
there you go i'm gonna be getting rid of
that air stone um my question it kind of
relates to when i was chatting with josh
and kelly of dragonfly they said that
when you get your property or your soil
to like the level yours is obviously at
you can even start to see different
cannabinoid profile expressions when you
know maybe your mate grows it out and
he's like yes you know there's no cbd
and then you grow and there's a little
bit or like just just there's a
different profile basically
do you feel like when you really get
your microbes working for you and you've
got your own little environment churning
away that you can get that altered
expression
well again genetics is first you're not
going to all of a sudden see a type 1
variety like you know that's all thc
just all of a sudden have some thc
i mean some cbd in it if it if it never
has before that doesn't really happen
um and you know vice versa with a few
different things although but like
you know something like cbg uh will be
affected on harvest time or or
environment potentially
um but there's just certain things that
are just set into place with the
genetics um but certainly
the
the levels you know are going to be
play you know it's like how much thc is
in this one and you know maybe in type 2
varieties there might be a play and
the percentages but you're not going to
just all of a sudden see thc or cbd out
of nowhere where there wasn't any of
that genetic to begin with
um
and then but with terpenes you are
definitely going to see some different
things happening
and certainly stresses could bring out
different um
compounds being
produced and
but another thing too though i mean
genetics seem to kind of sh at least
dictate what dominant terpenes are going
to be and and the order
um
a bit but like again the percentages
could change so all of a sudden there's
like
you know there's
instead of it producing two percent
terpenes the whole plants producing four
and a half percent terpenes and that's
way different and maybe the order is a
little shifted but
um the genetics are going to dictate a
lot of that so you're not going to see
super wide
changes normally but
but you do get different aromas
different expressions you know
different potencies different qualities
a lot of the the the differences you're
going to see are
um
in look too you know like what did it go
dark because it was
colder out or did it uh
you know did it dry out more or was the
wind just like ripping it or like you
know these environmental things are
gonna
mean a lot about the the end look and
that also means something about um the
trichomes and then
the curing process is just massive
though that's really gonna mean a lot
too um
you know like are all these trichomes
damaged uh did it get too hot did it
stay wet too long did it uh
did it dry too fast like that's gonna
just affect
you know what terpenes are are
are there
quite a bit
um
so yeah it all goes into it but like
there's certain things that just
genetics lock into place and they're not
going to change that much
yeah of course of course but actually
i'm really excited about looking into
this a lot more and you know there are
cool things like the grow off that have
done this with clonal varieties in
different locations and
um
uh
you know they actually noticed one
terpene that the
hadn't been produced by any of the other
of the plants
it might have been the eagles
but they um
it was only two plants that that
produced in both times it was a super
stressed environment they're like you
know when they asked the grower it was
like
so it could have been a terpene
because it wasn't in any of the others
like at all not no non-detect and then
there was like a considerable amount
like um
was that the uh near dial i think that
was and uh yeah so there's a good chance
that stress uh would affect that but
being able to look at that kind of those
kinds of analytics with control groups
would be really useful and i'm looking
forward to doing that this year i want
to do that actually with not just clone
varieties but with tissue culture too so
it can make sure that i have more
control on that and you know see what
like a black dog or cherry lime dog does
in a few of the different really cool
um farms in our areas you know showcase
like the difference of a dry farm or a
forest or a mountain top with um some of
the good farmers here i wanted you know
doing that with time lapse too and
having that linked up with the um
the uh
the weather uh data collection as well
which is happening with the appalachian
project
there's like nine
weather stations going in that are going
to be collecting all this cool data
and
being able to put that all together you
can do a time lapse of the plant growing
throughout the whole year and look at
all the different
weather
data at that exact time and then you
could take that all the way into
the drying and curing process and then
look at the end analytics of everything
and you know learn a lot about those
different spots and start to build um
you know
real real data on how genetics um are
affected by different uh locations
yeah i mean it certainly goes to show
that there's just so much work to be
done in the field isn't there
okay
yeah yeah because i always think i just
my mind always goes to wine because i
just think of like you know it's
established terroirs or even cheese
stuff like that and it's like yeah
they've been working on it for hundreds
of years and they're really getting it
in place now so we got a while to go but
um
and then when you think of like the
example of like uh erasing you just had
on like like those appellations like
when we're talking about a variety
that's just so adapted to growing you
know close to the equator or so adapted
to being in the mountains or being
you know a certain place north or in the
desert um
and the attributes that go with that
like
that's like real like land appellations
but then also the
the rich human history of cannabis in
india and people in india is just
amazing you know with like
just so many multi-generational
farms in just
decades or centuries or thousands of
years of relationships in certain areas
growing this plant like that's like
another level of appellation you know
when we're talking about well yeah we've
been growing you know these hybrids and
clones here for like a couple two
decades or something or three decades or
four uh it's like it's just a different
thing um and a lot of the farms are like
especially in the legal thing are like
relatively new
and there was a time when people were
just only growing clones too um
it was kind of funny it was like it was
super weird that i had
seed plants and males like it was like
this totally crazy thing for a cannabis
grower to have
like
um
like for yeah it was just clones um
so yeah i don't know i think we have a
lot of work to do to to define our area
but at the same time
california has been this freaking
epicenter of
just being
the
the current moment of cannabis like
we've been you know as far as like
innovations and breeding and the culture
and the hash and all of the things it's
like
i mean there's just so much of that work
comes from the culture here and
um it's it is a special
thing to
to
yeah honor and to acknowledge and you
know be nice for these craft farmers to
be able to have um that kind of
recognition um like a you know a wine
appellation um
where it's like yeah you are from this
place and you are doing these practices
and you know
and then the way that we mix that in
with genetics too will be interesting of
course we need to do it in a way that's
like super open um and that encourages
uh you know farmers to do what makes
sense for their place um i don't want
anything like
you know it's like we know what like
apino is and we know what a
cab is but like
you know we know about those grapes and
those cultivars but um
we don't want monocultures in cannabis
too we want the farms growing lots of
different varieties and we want them
breeding for it you know like
greens source gardens like
uh you know breeding
those multi-generations uh on on that
spot
um
that's building towards an appellation
and and year after year
utilizing their forest and their
barnyard waste to build soil fertility
like that's the kind of stuff that we're
you know we need to be talking about and
honoring um
yeah it can't just be
oh you grow this one type of thing in
this one place and anything goes it
needs to be more more special than that
um and it needs to be open for for
innovation
but i super look forward to the way that
that
the genetics tie into that because like
if you do have some a special genetic
you know that your farm becomes
associated with or you work with the
breeder to develop in that place like we
should talk about it and celebrate it
and and you know also have some
marketing power in and being able to say
that it is what it is and
so yeah it's exciting
how uh to see how farmers will be
um promoted i guess and you know the way
that it will hopefully
um help help farmers to
well as as things
become more international i mean i feel
like the
the world will just open up um that full
the cannabis prohibition is over just
how long it will take um
worldwide and hopefully we still see the
entire end of the war on drugs but
um
but uh
as that happens you know being able to
really because it already is special
everywhere in the world you see crazy
prices in the uk and spain and different
things for something that was grown in
california and as as as erasmus also uh
mentioned too the the insane prices uh
in india for really high quality uh or
you know
yeah i mean what you know dank weed or
whatever yeah just going for uh just a
tremendous amount of money it's just
staggering really to think about and and
how much cannabis is in india and how
having something that looks like it's
from california is worth that much money
um so that's that yeah that's real
perception those are real things and
hopefully it gets backed by the best
farmers and breeders and it is a real
thing that the world gets to uh to know
that they are
you know
getting that kind of quality um both in
practices and genetics
yeah i mean that's that's so important
right and i mean on that note you know
as we approach the quickfire questions i
wanted to ask you
it feels like historically the reason
why these precedents sort of exist is
because you've got you know your high
times and your whatever which you know
promotes certain types of cannabis and
you look at that you're like oh that's
the bee's knees however in recent years
we've seen events like high times and
some other notable ones even like the
emerald cup have kind of shrunk in size
a little bit but we've seen on the other
hand the uprising of more kind of
community-led things like the
regenerative farm award and the
regenerative farming conferences do you
think this trend will continue in that
we might see some of the bigger
corporate ones get a little less popular
and some of the more grassroots ones
grow in size what's your kind of
predictions for that
well
[__] i mean i don't know if i have any
predictions in covid world for events at
the moment
i think the way uh yeah some of the
you know award
based stuff
yeah we'll just have to be creative this
this year
um
yeah i mean it's it's always my hope
that
that it will continue in that direction
and so far i feel that it has um you
know like every year
at the emerald cup i just like i feel
like yeah there's just amazing talks and
there's amazing you know and it's
um
and more awareness
but yeah yeah
i don't know what the future of the
larger events are in the really near
future right now um i do like the idea
of
utilizing
the fact that large events aren't really
like
the appropriate
thing to do
at the moment um
and getting creative with um
in online ways of of getting this kind
of
information about cannabis medicine out
through contests and stuff so
um yeah i like playing around with the
different ways that we can really
explore
something fully because we can
choose what we then curate to go online
and to
um
it's
and you can really dive into a lot of
information am i uh do you know the
cultivation classic in um portland yeah
yeah i've heard of it cool
it was an event that i helped uh
start or start you know
i was working on from the beginning and
a lot of the con
concepts with it and it was a you know
the regenerative cannabis farm award
also um
was a part of that from the beginning
too and
um and kind of that idea towards
living soil
production
mixed with just really good science and
analytics and uh what was really cool is
the last two years it's adapted its um
contest
into more of a
like a real patient study um
and
dr addy ray of um smart cannabis and
steph earnhardt they
um
had built this this platform of smart
cannabis um
where
they get about a i think uh the year
before it was 150 um
patients or reviewers or
you know judges
and
that
fulfilled actually a wide demographic um
you know of
different genders and backgrounds and
ages and all of that and then um
they each are trained in sampling each
one and there's space in between the
sampling and they can
fill out you know the
how they're feeling uh as they sample
each different thing um
and all that information and data is
collected and
put together and then of course the
analytics are run on every flower and
they do these really nice posters
with um
that
include the terpenes as a full donut all
divided up so you can immediately see
the terpenes and the the different
percentages that are
um that are there and so you can quickly
see okay it's a
you know mercy and dominant like beta
karyophylline uh number two and then you
can and then there's a line that shows
all of the cannabinoids and it's a it's
a really nice long panel it's got
everything in there
and then it's got also a intake picture
of the flower and a
resource innovation score and a resource
innovation center started this power
tool that
basically gave a energy efficiency score
to the to the operation to the farmer or
grow
and then um it also had an aroma
intensity score on that too
and so you they there's a whole like
wall of our
hall of all these posters up and so you
can look and see all the type 1 and type
2 and type 3 and you can kind of see the
way the terpenes group and different
things and you can just get a lot of
analytics like all laid out in front of
you all quick and then you get to hear
about how the different varieties
affected the different uh people in the
group and they have different
um
awards that are kind of interesting like
one would be the nose nose and so
everyone that
said that they really liked the aroma of
something uh also really liked the
effect um and the one that was most
consistent for that i got that one i
think that was tropicana cookies or
something um
and then uh there was you know there's
other things too like the most
consistent cultivar so like if everyone
says yeah it made me sleepy and happy
and described like the same terms uh of
the effects
then that would be really consistent
where maybe something else like
somebody's super energetic and somebody
got couch locked you know like um so
there's a lot of different ways to look
at um
you know awards and and you know what is
the best and what are we looking at and
best for who and for what you know what
was women's choice you know that's
another category
um and these are all really useful
demographics uh for retail but also for
medicine and and also for people just to
kind of start to begin to know like
where they want to start with a cannabis
variety if they're working with a
certain issue or
um
so i see
that
curating different um
science driven and also quality and uh
experience driven um events like online
could be really useful i've been having
some fun ones with uh
different ideas with
um yeah enjoying hash and different
flowers and really diving into
both the science and then just the
gourmet aspects um putting that all
together i think there's a cool future
for it but uh it's gonna adapt and
change this year
yeah certainly and i mean you raise a
brilliant point there if someone was
just looking for not anything in
specific just good stuff in general what
of your lines are you currently really
vibing with that you would just
recommend across the board people being
like you'll be you'll be pretty happy
with this
yeah so that's i always have trouble
with that question normally when i work
with someone it's like okay we're gonna
sit down for four hours and we're gonna
run through your farm and we're gonna
work backwards on each thing and you
know i'm gonna
overwhelm you and then we're gonna work
it all out at the end um
so no it's like for what you know uh no
i don't but
yeah um i mean for ice water for just
really beautiful flowers um
yeah okay i'll just list them off let's
see uh
okay
well again i mean we already talked
about cherry lime dog in the multiple
different versions of that uh definitely
uh we'll be excited to
for how yeah how
that will look as as more things get
released um
black dog is just the
the good old flagship um and always
available humble seed organization um
probably yeah looking forward to some
new things with neptune soon um actually
i'm kind of
been slacking i just like to put
everything together really well and like
yeah need to get on that um
i think banana dog is gonna be really
useful for a lot of people
it just yields super well super easy to
grow grows fast crazy healthy
super resistant
works great for flowers or ice water
hash good chunky beautiful flowers that
look insane in the jar but also
yield like crazy um
yeah just real
yeah
simple great great one voltron has been
amazing um
really really powerful strong
flowers for sure
uh you get that lemon butter pepper
uh and
yeah some dough and um just super
powerful um
yeah there was just a write up with that
with dolphin glow had had grown some of
those
other ones um the orange valley dog uh
it's been really fun that's a really
bright
citrus uh incredibly high thc numbers
you know seeing in the high 30s
regularly had uh saw 34.
um and hallucinogenic like you know when
i first like saw i was like is this real
you know and then i hit it was just like
whoa i'm like in high school
hallucinating like but it's like that
kind of it's like bright energy and just
super strong and um yeah but the smell
is just wonderful it's total bright
orange candy citrus and gas and um
looking forward to what um
mood main farms is gonna do with that
this year and um
and also uh they're doing some of the
cherry moon uh version of the cherry
lime dog
which would be super fun to see
this is the thing that's really exciting
to see too is like the different farms
do the different versions of it too and
so bryceland forest farm is gonna have
these amazing cherry lime dog f3s which
and they're gonna be totally different
unique and amazing um they're different
they're totally different paths that i
was going down from the cross
so um yeah it'll be really fun you'll
get these
dark just freaking cushy freaking
amazing
flowers from the cherry moon and then
the cherry lime dog is like uh
just so the f3 is just so much bright
crazy fermented fruit goodness and yeah
it's gonna be fun to see
um
other things uh you know i mean the the
holy nanocrack like crosses and stuff
are just insane for for hash and for
resistance um
you know i mean
i've done uh
the citron is really nice the mandarin
crosses um for for cbd too um the can of
dog was really interesting and actually
um has had some really unique terpene
expressions too that um have to look
back into because
um they might be total announce
yeah
they might be important they might be
important ones um
um
uh yeah good like apple lemon and
kind of orange peel flavors and in that
and those are like nice three to ones
um the sapphire sioux that moon maid
farm's actually doing again there's a
few farms doing that and nukem family
farms too that
the extracts that came out from the the
nukem family farms uh
project with surprise surprise is just
incredible holy crap um
yeah some of the best cbd i've ever
tasted out of a pen too they made some
in the pens what's really
amazing with the this is solvent
extraction too but yeah with with that
extraction is um
they uh
it's just homogeneous like you know you
don't have the crashing of of of
crystals and the separation of terps
it's like this super homogeneous mix and
just so flavorful and consistently two
to one
um
yeah it's just like i could
it's i don't really like pennsylvania i
could smoke on that thing all day and
the cherry lime dog tastes insane out of
that too from the same farm uh well it's
called actually cherry uh sorry lime pop
dog in this case because there was a
little lime lime pop mixed in with that
one
um
but yeah those are from surprise
surprise and royal key uh
it's really fun to see those um papa
bark that washed some of the
sabertooth's um holy nana crack
uh
times uh
sfv dog that
just [__] the flavor was so so good
so so good um
yeah it was really cool to see that come
out wouldn't really love that farm too
saber tooth farms
um
other exciting things you know i mean
the dog named sue the harley sue uh
crosses with uh with black dog come out
really really desirable cushy beautiful
um cbd nugs um they have a little bit
more of the
um some of the
cbd spice and mercene and stuff that's
more associated with it but it has this
like earthy good coastliness and they
also come out um cbdv
um rich quite often too which is is fun
to see in
um
some other ones that
are standing out right now
i should just look through all the
plants um athena dog always yeah athena
dog and dog's gift um are both really
fun
um
so yeah my athena sauerkush uh number
two which i call asks2 a lot of times
which actually one of the plants behind
me right now is a
ask ask nana it's an uh
athena banana sfv dog but um
yeah those those athena dogs look
amazing and high water farms is going to
be growing it is growing that dry farm
this year and those are going to look uh
amazing
and i'm sure be
available at the urban market too
those are massive size trichomes really
just
yeah again gorgeous gorgeous plant
flower beautiful long
leaves but also with that hybrid like
thickness look to it um
and
yeah the flowers just fill in like crazy
and they sparkle like jewels and the
trichome size yeah just massive you
catch some really big heads
um
god some other standouts to the um the
you know i'm looking forward to seeing
what the gmo uh banana sfv dogs do this
year which i was just calling gmob
um
those are gonna be you know
hash monsters there's not really any way
to get around it anything that that that
dad goes on kind of turns into a hash
monster and it's going on gmo so
it's gonna work out so i have uh there's
a few farms running that and it'll be
really cool to see um all the uh the
percent yields that we're gonna get from
the plants this year will be really
exciting for the next year's uh
selections and
um yeah those progress
uh and yeah indigo farms growing some of
that newcomer family farms growing some
of that um
yeah and and uh
i think beau's nose is probably gonna
wash some and
uh surprise surprise we'll watch that
too
excited to see those
[__] i could probably keep going um
i love it
i don't know should i though
which area do i want to dive into much
though
um the p-funk uh
p-funk is pretty fun actually
um
this year this is kind of interesting um
so a friend ryan charlotte with uh they
have a chocolate company called aura
chocolate where they do probiotic
chocolates
but they're also
doing a
they have
really really nice chocolates and they
they really uh like sourcing the best
quality um
products and they work with all the like
kind of regen farms and the dragonfly
earth medicine pure farms and they've
been really connected and engaged in
that community and been great friends
too
but uh they also had a relationship with
uh this studio where a lot of really
cool songs were recorded and uh
one of those um the plant and one of
those was atomic dog and i happened to
have a atomic cush
crossed with black dog an atomic dog
that mood made farms actually sorry
moongazer farms
and men
got from me years ago and continued on
with and
um
we ended up
doing a uh
having they grew atomic dog last year
that uh we went to it
actually meet with george clinton and i
went to a parliament show
and basically like he was down to to do
the atomic dog so there will be like the
george clinton approved atomic dog from
uh moon gazer farms it'll be pretty fun
um
so i'll have to work more with that but
uh also working on this p funk right now
which is this really bright purple
funky incredible smelling um variety
that was
um it was a it was a sour bubble atomic
um
that was put on skyscraper uh or sorry
skywalker og and i was a guy called that
skyscraper uh that combo and that was
put onto a um
was
it was this girl scout a30 selection
from 2011.
um
that i
had
kept and yeah ended up
choosing a male from that and putting
that onto the um that the skyscraper and
it came out super just crazy
funky and dark and amazing and um
this year i just i put the orange valley
dog on that and i have that like right
behind me here too one of these
the larger one back there but the the
stem rubs are just insane just uh
unbelievably like bright and
fermented berry and and citrus and yeah
very excited about those too and some of
the prettiest leaves just massive
gorgeous fan leaves
um
yeah and then yeah it's gonna be really
fun
really fun this year as each different
thing starts to show because first i do
the earlies i do have some daps too to
get pollinated and then i start moving
on to like
the the full season early varieties and
then all the others and i can't wait to
start playing with all the cool stuff
from uraz and as as they're just
starting to show sex right now and i'm
gonna i'm gonna propagate some more of
the uh
the low lab uh together isolated just to
to make more to to play with too and
multiple others
um
god there's so many cool treasures that
he has in there too i'm excited to see
what the hanza do and uh the blocks done
um you know some of the hash varieties
the milana whaling valley
sheila wathey
it's gonna be really cool to see
everything
wow
that is that's really exciting that's so
cool and i think that's probably gonna
give people a pretty good range of
options to select for
oh god yeah oh yeah i go i went a little
crazy with it uh so
next year i'm going to do a few less and
do larger population groups but i just
kind of wanted to see everything because
i'm so excited but yeah no i think it's
great i love it i love all the info
um so i think that brings us to our
quickfire questions which i've been
excited to get to because i i feel like
these have just gotten better over time
so my first question
for you is
what's the most memorable cannabis
you've ever smoked in your life
or it could be could be hash either
um
well actually i kind of mentioned a few
of them
already um
so the crackhead
that i mentioned back when i was in high
school [__] that still think of that
smell it had this like musty mango a
little bit of that cat piss like linger
in the air and just like and just the
second you smelled it you were already
stimulated in the brain
um so super yeah memorable yeah i'll
never forget that that aroma and effect
um and yeah it was just such a shared
experience like all the friends just
like oh my god like
that's just the perfect thing to you
know for a show or you know going out
having fun um
yeah also around that same time that
golden indica that i mentioned too which
actually became i bread it just ended up
getting a purple variety and which i
just called purple indica and like that
had this like
thick beautiful earth cushy but with
cotton candy and i can just think of
one of these gorilla grows right now and
like
you know pulled it bringing it down in a
backpack and that cotton candy smell in
the air when it's all fresh and gooey
and
that smell will never escape me
um lovely what's another uh the cherry
lime dog from last year for sure the
selections some of the best smells of my
life um
what else
the the yeah tasting that puppy dog or
sorry the puppy breath uh from from
garden to grease it was one of my
favorite
experiences of this year and
honestly like the first time uh
hitting actually the athena sour kush um
the first time adam washed the fresh
frozen of that simply adam
um
that was uh yeah
it was like
feeling like you won the universe and
got kicked in the face with like a lemon
golden boot at the same time it was just
like i don't know it was just so good
just pepper and earth and butter and
lemon and just insane potency and then
the cleanliness and of his wash it was
just like
uh it just didn't even look possible how
clean it was like in the way it melted
uh it's still like yeah
surreal that it because that was like it
was still like that's bubble hash like
that's possible you know it was at that
time too so
um
that one still sticks out to me it was
really cool is actually that was like
really expensive at the emerald cup one
year and
um maybe the most expensive out of
anything and it's sold out so quickly
and i remember one person like had wrote
a um
uh
a post about how they went to that i was
tagged in they went to the emerald cup
on their birthday like drove nine hours
to
uh on my birthday to go buy the most
expensive hash i've ever seen or like
the most expensive hashtag i ever had
and then drove nine hours back home and
then like tasted it and he was like best
birthday ever like and then two years
later he made another post where he
pulled he'd bought two
and he pulled the other one out of the
fridge like and uh
and it had cured it just looked unreal
just the golden jewel of uh just perfect
cure of
yeah i mean it was just it was such a
pure um
pure expression of what what trichomes
can be when you separate them perfectly
i mean what adam did with that was art
um and the way it was grown too but
uh yeah so it's really cool to see him
like pulling that out two years later
like like a fine bottle of wine and you
know that's how it is it's like and it
was like at that time it was like damn
i'd buy that back for you for like three
times as much right now because that's
special you know so yeah
well there you go that all sounds
phenomenal i guess on the other end of
the spectrum what's a strain in which
everyone else was really into it and so
you were like looking forward to it and
then when you tried it you were like
this doesn't really do it for me
you know actually i mean i i like the
flavor profiles of most the popular
varieties and stuff um you know i like
the candies i like the gas though i mean
those those um you know cookies and
skittles and og i like all those flavor
profiles are great
uh
i mean
but it also really depends how it's
grown i mean cookies can be so terrible
like in cardboard and dance and and
skittles is a weak plant you know it's
like
you know it's not always super exciting
to grow but when you get it going in
living soil really good it looks good i
have it crossed with the black dog right
now some z dog that like actually right
right behind me if you look in the thing
and yeah yeah so healthy and well
structured and beautiful and so i don't
know
excited to see um
yeah i mean what what happens from that
because i love that flavor profile but
um
yeah i think certain things could be
better about the plant um but i also
think a lot of these clone varieties do
get viruses over time i'm pretty darn
sure of that that the hoplaton virus is
pretty
prolific and people like you know
cut from one plant then they cut to the
next plant and um you know don't really
have protocol like
um you know even like you probably
should be using bleach in between
everything and um
you know keeping your clones clean and
knowing your source and all that kind of
stuff
but you know so some of those things
that you know that's where tissue
culture makes sense but it's expensive
and it takes a lot of time so you want
to do that with those
flavors that are really worth preserving
um
i don't know yeah i mean if a lot of
people like a flavor i probably like it
too as long as it was grown well um
so like if if there was something like
that i'd probably blame it on the
the grower first you know if everyone
liked the certain flavor but you know
everyone has the things that they like
more too and it's like um you know i'm
not super
i'm not smoking hazes on a regular basis
but i i appreciate their quality um
a lot you know and i
enjoy that i love celebrating all the
variety but certain things that you know
click with other people more and uh
and a lot of times like what i find
myself smoking a lot will be um
the
well i really like the complex and
savory flavors that where it's like
you're getting a meal um and you get
that with like
some of the athena's and the banana
crosses and the black dog crusts
sometimes um
but
like the voltron and stuff too where you
get
butter and dough with lemon and pepper
and stuff i like those a lot but i want
i want gas and i want citrus and i want
candy um
as well because those are like
really addictive through the day you
know it's like there's a certain like
you take a quick snapper and it like the
way it hits your tongue and it just sits
there
um you know the first time you hit
oh i remember you know first time
hitting og and be like okay yeah i like
that like
might as well cross that in with a lot
of things
um
because like yeah and also like if
you're you know spliff smokers two
certain things um stand above the
tobacco and work really well and also
like you know become the flavor that you
want
to sing over something and to be on your
tongue and um and you keep reaching for
it and it's always interesting to see
like what jar like just
goes
first you know and you know it might not
yeah there's a certain certain flavor
profiles where it might be something
that's like oh this is so good and i
like it so much but you don't want it
all the time and other ones you're just
like i want to smoke this all day
um
yeah it's all different
so are there well how about you are
there any that stood out for you or
you're like excited about trying
something and then didn't like it
yeah good question i think that
gosh that i guess
i think that i've had some ogs that were
so good that it made others seem not as
impressive and
um so yeah i think that's interesting
yeah because i think the most memorable
weed i've ever had in my life was just
this random og i got one time and um
yeah i don't think i'll ever find out
what cut it was sadly it was just really
special
nice well yeah i mean like i was saying
earlier too it was just like we had a
lot of cuts of og but so many of them
are so similar uh and i just honestly
like
but it was the practices that really
mattered because it's it's powdery
mildew susceptible and like like and so
like the people really knew how to grow
og and make them work in the depths and
like knew the timing and the trellis and
like and you know what they needed for
their health and stuff like
it's just it's just night and day
because it's a lot of people [__] up you
know could [__] up og and you'd still
get that gas like singing over and they
could still
you know sell it okay you know if it as
long as it had that gas smell or flavor
but it would be like dang dude that
looks a little
small and discolored and little pm and
like
actually i'd like to see a little pm on
og because
at least you know they didn't use
microbutal on it
yeah that's a good one i like that i
like that
first of all if you had to go live on a
desert island and you can only take
three strains with you what three are
you gonna take
oh man
really good og cut
cherry lime dog and um
it probably
yeah uh i would
i would take one of the either canada
dog or sapphire sue selections um for
like a nice two to one that has tons of
flavor
lovely that's a nice little well-rounded
pick there so the next question which i
i really enjoy is opposite end
someone who you're not particularly fond
of you've got to drop them off on an
island and leave them with three strains
what three strains you're gonna leave
them with
the same
because they need to admit
[Music]
yeah they need all the help they can get
so
[Music]
i love that that's a very diplomatic
answer i respect that maybe black dog
too because it's good for yeah
you know getting their mind in the right
place yeah it makes people cooler
um so what's your prediction for the
next big flavor to take the scene by
storm cherry lime dog
for sure i love it confident
alrighty so
it brings us to our last question and
i'm really interested to know what it's
going to be for you if you could go
anywhere in around the world any time in
history to presumably collect seeds or
clones where would you go and what would
you be trying to grab
um
oh any any time
yeah [__]
i go run around with with deep hockey
rosin from just last year
looks like he
a lot a lot of cool pictures from his
trip
yeah um i agree but you know yeah huh
who would be i also would be interested
to just
be in
you know humble or santa cruz
um at the moment when like the first
hybrids were kind of happening between
you know something like a mazar or
afghani with um some of the stuff that
was coming from
south america
um
yeah just
it would be interesting to to be a fly
on the wall those those couple years and
see what actually
what did take place between uh that
beginning because a lot happened from
that moment
yeah it's a combination of surfers and
back to the landers and you know
um
yeah both people
who whether vets or peace activists
avoiding the war or
trying to get out of you know just
trying to get back to the land and
relate to growing their own food and
connection
with nature and
and uh and then also the surfers
traveling around and bringing stuff back
and like that where those kinds of
things met uh
yeah i think something really special
came from that so it would be
interesting to see those those first
those first hybrids who did them and
what happened
yeah i can certainly get behind that so
just from you know being being
california you know northern california
based growing up in santa cruz hills
that's an interest to me but
i'm sure there's a lot of better answers
too
but i would love to see so much
no it's a brilliant one
and uh so with that in mind i think that
just about brings us to the end of
things did you have any comments or
shout outs you wanted to make at all
i feel like i made a good amount of them
um again of course uh
incredibly forever thankful for all the
information and the genetics from
irration
um always uh humble seed organization um
yeah ryan has been a
incredible part of this journey for me
um and much love to eric to you and just
yeah um
um
yeah i i mentioned before too but shout
out to janine coleman for all her work
towards the appalachian projects right
now um
and just all the amazing regen farmers
too i mean we mentioned a bunch of them
but um they all deserve it i'd like to
um
you know sun roots farms i don't think
got mentioned and their breeding and
their their cultivation work is
incredible the uh you know the velvet
herbs and the massive plants that they
grow and the biodynamic
uh
cultivation strategies and compost
buildings that they
uh that they apply to their practices
are amazing um moon gazer farms mood
main farms bryceland forest farms
uh you know flower days
just yeah all
all amazing farms um doing really cool
work radical herbs biodynamic farm down
in kovalev as well and um
yeah big shout out to um
mean gene freeborn selections for just
always
putting out tons of information and some
of the tastiest varieties and just being
a cool dude and a good friend and
a great person to just talk about
cannabis with
forever
yeah and
yeah big thanks to you because i just
yeah i love being able to
intimately listen to um a lot of these
people that i respect i get to gain so
much information by just listening to
them talk so
big appreciation for that
no the pleasure's been all mine my
friends so you know thank you so much
for coming on and sharing all your
knowledge and
especially you know your positivity
around breeding around organics
regenerative farming it's been really
knowledgeable and insightful oh yeah one
other shout out to to uh mama publishing
um and they did the um
organic grow book uh that ended up i i
did a lot of um
um kind of consulting with them as far
as like a lot of the living soil based
stuff and the huge cultures a lot of the
information the kashi and um they made
this amazing book out of it they and
they ended up having chapters about me
in it
and different cultivation strategies and
there's one about black soldier fly
composting uh
and uh but so they ended up adapting
this this incredible reference book
about organic um
cultivation and they turned it into a
comic book and it's like a super cool
comic book it's got all these amazing
little hilarious detailed characters
like um and it and it really dives into
what's happening with living soil and
the relationships between
plant roots and the environment and um
and then goes into all these different
practices like yeah fermentation and
biodynamics and natural farming and
permaculture and google culture and uh
but in in really fun illustrations and
in really uh user
you know really readable and fun ways
that like kids in all ages enjoy bubble
man actually just gave a big shout out
to it uh earlier this week he's just
like oh my god i love this name this was
going love reading this to my kid and
like all this information super legit so
it was really fun like pictures that i
taken and things that i wrote were
turned into comic books and they have me
as like a little kid thinking about
compost and like uh and fire and like
the similarities and then like yeah it
just has me on this whole like journey
it's like pretty funny but um anyway
yeah so that's like it just got um
they did the uk version they did the
french version they did um the version
for spain and south america and then
they just did the italian version um
so yeah it's pretty cool to see all
these different
yeah these these concepts spreading
around in a way that's like great for
kids to read and
yeah just look forward to the next
generation thinking about
just how important living soil is and
our relationships with plants and
communities
yeah what a beautiful sentiment so thank
you again for coming on the show and
everyone be sure to go check the book
out
yeah
yeah it's the organic
grow book in comics
[Music]
[Applause]
a big big big thank you to jesse again
for taking the time to come on the show
share his incredible knowledge and to
talk all things organic and regenerative
gardening
make sure you go check out and support
our fantastic sponsors at seeds here now
best seed bank in the game got all the
best breeders if you're thinking they're
a good breeder they're probably on ct
now go hit them up check them out
guarantee on germination and
satisfaction
i don't know why you'd go anywhere else
likewise a huge huge shout out to our
friends at coppett biological beneficial
bugs beneficial predators beneficial
microbes and even feeds to keep the good
army alive help fight off the bad guys
it's a no-brainer guys go check them out
and finally a big shout out to our
buddies at the patreon gang these guys
are the lifeblood of the show we love
you so much hope you guys enjoy
listening to this one early if you're
interested in hearing the next episode
before it comes out go check out the
patreon patreon forward slash the
podcast
and that just about does it for this one
gang
i'll see you for the next one
[Music]
you