well hello my friends and welcome back
for another episode of the podcast a
cannabis podcast for budding enthusiasts
as always you're joined by your boy
heavy days here from the upside down
Library we want to give a massive shout
out to all of our incredible sponsors
who help ensure the show continues to
happen seeds here now number one seed
bank in the industry all the hottest
breeders the latest drops everything you
can look for and more whether you're
after indoor outdoor feminized regular
autoflow they've got everything under
the sun to keep you loaded on all the
hottest genetics producing the most fire
Bud you've ever had I hear they've got
some incredible lines from heavy days
still in stock if you want to go check
that out make sure to do it before it's
too
late big shout out to CT now we
appreciate you so
much as usual a massive massive thank
you and shout out to our good friends at
copit biological if you want to harvest
the best crop today you have to ensure
your garden is pest and pathogen free
pumping on all cylinders if you're
battling spidermites check out the
incredible spidex vital likewise I know
a lot of you guys are battling apids at
the moment check out their ay parm this
is another product I absolutely stand
behind from copit if you want to get rid
of apids get rid of spidermites check
out the apy Pam check out the spidex
vital big shout out to copit biological
thank you so much we appreciate your
ongoing support
the final piece of the puzzle to ensure
that your room is killing it is our good
friends at Pulse their sensors are
second to none industry-leading and just
recently they announced the pulse Hub
what more could you want an integrated
unit for all of your sensors to ensure
that your garden is automated and
tracking all of the variables you may
not be consciously aware of from VPD to
ppf Duo temperature humidity so much
more you've got to get yourself a pulse
sensor guys it is Revolution the way I
grow flour and increase the Turing
content the cannaboid content to yield
so so so much more shout out as always
to our friends at Pulse sensors likewise
if any of you guys have been listening
to the show you know that I am
passionate about helping people
transition to vaporized options if
they're considerate about their
respiratory health and for me dap are
the world leaders in this dap helped me
to transition from bongs to vaping and I
tell you what I've never looked back
their unit is the most potent the most
highly replicating of a bong hit I've
ever come across and through their
incredible M unit I was able to
successfully get off bongs a few years
ago now truly one of the most Innovative
and interesting Vapes on the market
using a totally different design to
others you have found check these guys
out you will not be disappointed massive
shout out to dinat thank you so
much and last but not least we want to
give a massive shout out to the
incredible patreon gang without you guys
we could not continue to make episodes
if you want to get early access to
upcoming episodes exclusive content just
on the patreon including the likes of
mean Jean Bob hmill Bodie triome jungle
so much more be sure to go check out our
patreon we give away genetics every
month to our supporters along with
artwork Vapes sensors so much more
please check out the patreon guys I
promise you you won't regret it you'll
get your money back in swag for helping
support us show you love thank you so
much to everyone from the
patreon we got a good one today for you
gang I know a lot of people have been
asking for this a long time I've been
thinking about it and we finally got the
Stars to a line and we made it happen a
big shout out to our buddy a longtime
fan of the show as well Daz of night out
taking the time to come chat with us
incredibly grateful as
always so without further delay
all righty gang welcome back for another
one and on today we have one of the
biggest names in the auto breeding World
head of Night Out seeds a company that
is synonymous with some of the highest
quality Autoflower breeding in the world
a massive massive thank you and welcome
to Daz for joining us today how you
doing good man thank you so much for
having me it's an honor to be here on
the show been a fan since the very first
episode and like I was just saying
before we started I've never felt like I
was at the level to even be a associated
with the guest you've had on before but
yeah thank you for for having me and
I'll do my
best man I love that because it's like
it speaks to the uh The Organic Roots
that a lot of people in the industry
have you know like yourself I I started
out as a fan just watching subcool and
who would have thought we'd be here
chatting to each other one day so that's
that's really cool to hear and you know
what's funny you referenced episode one
I haven't mentioned it to you got to be
told this before you got that same
southern accent that Duke has in episode
one ah spent a long time down in South
Carolina so that's interesting to hear I
um yeah I've definitely my my accents
I'm sure picked up from from quite a few
locations I've moved around all over the
place from Maryland to South Carolina to
West Virginia to Colorado to Boston or
Massachusetts to now I'm up in Maine so
I've been all over the place but yeah
definitely definitely Southern Roots
there wow that's that's awesome to hear
you truly have been a bit of Everywhere
by the sounds of it I'd love to ask you
know how would you just as a quick one
how would you describe the state of the
East Coast scene at the moment the
impression I get is that it's sort of
booming and going through a bit of a a
boom phase how would you describe it
it's incredible honestly I've had some
of the best flower in the world in New
York City here recently within the past
year the scene there is incredible it
reminds me of um the associations in
Barcelona or the coffee shops over in
Amsterdam except a little bit more wax
um the events they have in the city are
just absolutely Stellar you feel like
you're in a movie you'll you'll go it's
just a big office building you get on
the elevator go up to the 12th floor the
doors open the smoke just Billows into
the elevator and all of a sudden you're
in a lounge with you know a little
coffee bar food vendor tables everywhere
couches just it it's phenomenal they
really really have something special
going on I'll say Virginia as well is
really really doing big things so which
is a state I never really associated
with ever having legal cannabis um they
were always I got arrested in Richmond
Virginia when I was like 18 years old
for weed so that's a place that I never
ever thought would would Boom the way it
has but yeah then again when I was 21
years old so yeah Virginia I've had a
shady past with as far as that's
concerned but some of the best weed I
actually ever smoked was um I used to
have a business that or a job that would
take me on the road over
would stay in a hotel in this little
college town in Virginia and the the
girl at the front desk of this hotel
eventually became friends I'd be there
every other week and eventually asked
you know you want to come smoke some
weed or whatever and she was like yeah
sure and one time I didn't have any and
I was like you know where I could like
get some and she was like yeah my my
husband come come over to our house and
I went over and it was like the first
time I ever had fresh homegrown and it
was just like a game changer I was like
oh my God it was White Widow and still
to this day it was like some of the best
flowers I've ever had in my life so yeah
Virginia and I have a and cannabis have
a nice little LoveHate relationship um
but yeah the east coast is is doing
great things I can't wait for the rest
of it to open
up yeah totally what what a cool story
you know from Virginia and and white
widow what a brilliant sort of uh like
kind bud introduction to have I'm sure
that was epic out of curiosity have you
ever been tempted to to pick up a pack
of White Widow from somewhere and Chase
that Holy Grail
I really want to try the the Sharon
White Widow that's around it's um you
know I haven't asked anybody for it in a
few years I I I used to reach out to
breeders all the time and people that I
looked up to and tried to like let it be
known you know I'm not out here to rip
anybody off or do anything shady I'd
love to like try some of this even if
it's just a flower not necessarily
getting a cutter anything like that and
um yeah just never had any luck and it's
weird the way this has kind of
progressed
um I remember in-house genetics maybe
2015 2016 reaching out and being like
man I'd love to like collab on an auto
flower and he was just kind of you know
maybe one day maybe one day and just
last year he reached out to me I was
like man I'd love to collab on an auto
flower and I was like [ __ ] yeah dude all
right that's awesome let's do it so I
sent him some poen he made the seeds I'm
not sure if he's got those going quite
yet but he sent me pictures of the seeds
a couple months ago so yeah it's a a
weird turn of events the way Auto
flowers have kind of started to be more
recognized by the photo period world and
people are starting to understand that
they do have a place in
this yeah totally totally out of
curiosity are you willing to let out of
the bag which uh which pollen did you
send him and and if you could just pick
a couple hybrids you'd love to see made
out of his Library what what's on the
radar for
you um I believe I sent him the crinkled
cookies feminized poin and I think I
also sent him some wizards of ress
feminized pollen and I think it was the
crinkled cookies that he ended up using
and I'm pretty sure he used it
to um maybe a slurricane i he had a
something black cherry um I'd have to
look at my notes to to see exactly what
what he was going to use on that but I
had made a cross with the the slur cane
cut that was floating around back in
2019 or so maybe 2018 and it was the
first time and the only time that I
think I've ever had a plant that was
duding as what it was called back then
now I think it's you know
hlvd um but yeah it just kind of died
just kind of stopped midflower and so
those seeds that seed stock I just set
aside and never touched again because I
didn't ever want to reintroduce that or
like grow anything that had that vroid
and possibly contaminate other stuff so
I still have that seed stock locked away
separate from from everything else just
you know maybe for for future reference
someday but um sorry I forgot what the
question was you you answered it which
which hybrids would you like to see and
and you know it San would be a great
pairing I'm I'm a fan of it for sure and
you just mentioned HL the hopl en vroid
and the thing that you just stimulated
in my mind was an interesting thought
right you often hear about it in the
context of clones cuz they sort of pick
it up and then it's just in there you
really don't hear about it with ordos
and then I guess it got me thinking have
you seen plants with what you suspect
not necessarily your own but just via
other people Auto plants that have it
and and how does it manifest like is it
cuz I guess I'm wondering would it just
be like lower yield and stuff like that
or or would it maybe stress the plant in
a way that's like you know how sometimes
the auto will just like stop growing and
just go into flower at like this really
small stage have you have you seen any
Autos infected and what was the symptoms
looking
like I really haven't uh none that I've
been aware of um
um we were just speaking again before
the interview and I have seen some seed
stock going around from from other
people that um the plants are just kind
of stunned and inch or Too Tall
consistently across the board all with a
certain seed stock and so I've seen
people say you know have these been
tested for you know the hot platon vroid
or anything but I really can't say that
I've ever seen it in Autos before but
that's not to say that it isn't out
there I pretty much just stick to my own
stuff stuff that I'm familiar with stock
that I've had for the past decade or
more at this point so um yeah I I can't
say that I've ever actually seen it for
sure other than the one time where I
think I got the dirty clone of the
slur yeah fair enough fair enough and I
was thinking like it it's actually an
interesting question in that like who
knows maybe maybe in some sense Autos
are less prone to hopl and viroid I mean
obviously there's the literal aspect of
they they're not really cloned so they
don't stay around long enough um but
also maybe there's some other sort of
underlying genetic trait associated with
being an auto that who knows it's a
interesting one to ponder but uh to get
us back on track I wanted to quickly ask
you cuz a question I've wanted to ask
you for a long time CU you're the man to
answer it is in your mind what has been
the most impressive autof flower you've
ever tried do you remember like that
moment where you were like wow this is
it
h i mean I have some favorites for sure
I think to me the most
impressive thing that that I've ever
come across with
[Music]
them my my older brother and some of his
friends were my toughest critics and for
a long time you know I I started growing
then I found out some of his friends
were growing and they had some flones
and and stuff that I really wanted to
work with and it took me a few years of
growing autos and playing with Autos to
get to a point where they used to claim
you know we can taste the auto flow in
this and I was like well what does it
taste like can you explain to me what
the auto trait tastes like and they
could never really Express that um but
eventually I grew some stuff and they
were like wow this is amazing and I was
like that's an auto and they're like
this is this I was like yeah that's an
auto and at that point they let me have
access to a subcool clone of space dog
which is like the thing that growing up
in in kind of my circle was like the end
all be all top tier clone of that time
and they let me use that and I worked
with it and came back to them years
later with the flower from it and the
dude that that held that cut smoked it
and was just like this is the space dog
like you did it and I that was like kind
of the high water mark of like I know
I'm on the right path here I know this
can be done it just takes the the proper
work the selections and like you know
just just understanding kind of the
plants and what you're selecting for so
that was like the first one of those and
then again with the the zomo Delica
Express is one that I'm super proud of
and you know really really nice true
sativa and Autoflower format that's just
super uplifting and heavy and um now the
the the sour diesel stuff that I've been
working on here recently are some of the
stinkiest Autos I've ever come across
hands down so I mean there's a few
different kind of high water mark along
the the journey here but um as far as
pinpointing any one specific moment I
mean there's there's it just kind of
continues to evolve every couple years
there's something new that's just like
damn I can't believe like this worked
so yeah that's that's really an
interesting point you raised there I
mean the people will hate me if I don't
ask you know there's a million in one
sour cuts out there which ones do you
like and uh which one have you used in
the project
so in this one I used the AJ Sour Diesel
and I've currently got the Albany Sour
Diesel skunk Tech choco um got one from
a gentleman Clon soprano who people say
is like the real the real true Sour
Diesel but I mean nowadays they have
sour competitions every single year to
see who has the real Sour and it's like
there is no kind of one real Sour
anymore and people say you know the AJ
Sour Diesel isn't like a true Sour
Diesel and um it it just that that's
what this is the AJ sour diesel auto is
what I've been working on with this one
and now I'm using this pilen from this
to cross to the other sour diesels to
work those into Auto format um but I had
the the j plant speaker Sour Diesel
earlier this year and that was fantastic
um I've had some out in Colorado there's
a a little club called Cervantes out
there and the guy there had a sour
diesel that's super old and and that was
real nice too but yeah this one is the
the AJ Sour Diesel
that that I've worked into Auto and
that'll be coming out probably next year
I think I'm going to hold off and and
release the the blue Power collab this
year and then do the AJ next year
totally look that's that's exciting and
as a side note do you think AJ looks a
little bit like Edward
Norton you know now that you say that
yeah he does think I've always thought
that I mean AJ kind of has like a a
Timeless young look like he like he's
always in college you know what I mean
so I got to meet him I met him in in uh
the park in New York City this past year
with him and Top Dog I was like damn
this is like a real New York cannabis
history moment I got a picture with both
of them was just like this is this is
awesome so I mentioned to them you know
that I was working with him I bought a
little sack of AJ Sour Diesel straight
from the man himself I still got it in
my my desk here with his little
signature on it I was like yeah this is
this is pretty significant milestone in
in my life here so but yeah he
definitely I I do see the Edward Norton
resemblance now that you say that that's
cool man I I actually was looking at
your Instagram last night and I saw that
photo and I was like that would have
been a fun time in that Park on that day
so yeah there you go and just in the
last question I mean you referenced the
sour but in the last questions you
referenced the zadel express I wanted to
formally ask are you like myself are you
more a fan of the sativas than the
indicas are you impartial or are you
more of an Inda
guy oh no that's the T for me um with my
breeding I I always and it's strange how
this works people like they think they
like they like a breeder but they really
like their pallet and like of
unintentionally bred to help my ADHD and
depression and all just kind of like
personal issues and in doing so it's
helped a bunch of other people like they
they grow and they find the same relief
from these things that I've found but
yeah 100% sativa is for me that's the
the space dog was like a super sativa I
found actually what I I called the super
sativa feno within the cosmic Queen
which is the space dog Auto and I kind
of isolated that and been growing and
smoking that for myself over the past
couple years and that's a big big fan
favorite as well and I just did some
stuff with that one again here for the
the upcoming Halloween release so the
last time I I released it was four years
ago for Halloween so it's a nice little
reculation of of that coming back
around yeah totally totally I love that
you know what's funny I had a question
about the Halloween stuff and
essentially what I wanted to ask was I I
love how you do all these cool unique
little drops you know I'm sure other
people do Halloween drops but I I I feel
like you have a lot of fun with it so to
speak and I feel like there's a little
bit of a sentiment in the community at
the moment that things are all a bit you
know Doom and Gloom and no one really
seems like they're having fun anymore I
wanted to ask you how do you how do you
keep it light and you know how what's
your advice for people to keep keep you
know cannabis and growing
fun I mean I know it's cheesy but you
gotta love it like I would be doing this
whether I was selling the seeds or not
like this is this is what I I my mom sat
me down in sixth grade because I was no
good in school and she was like what do
you want to do what do you want to do
with your life I was like I want to live
on the side of a mountain somewhere
tropical and grow weed I was like that's
that's it that's like the dream for me
and I I mean I got partially there I was
on the side of a mountain in Colorado
growing weed but um yeah no no real
tropical location quite yet um but yeah
you really don't get in it for the wrong
reasons it's not a a cash grab situation
a lot of people get into it thinking
this is going to be like some big
booming industry I remember everybody
wanted to be a master grower for for a
time when that was like a a the term
going around and everybody thought it
was like big bucks and yeah you just
can't get into it for that reason that's
not what it's about the the plant won't
treat you right if that's how you treat
it and that's really kind of as simple
as that as far as keeping
things um invigorated so to speak man me
and my buddy Zan who's my Graphics guy
we just have an absolute blast with like
coming up with new Concepts and new
ideas um for this upcoming Halloween one
we're doing the collab with Sin City
Seeds they in Las Vegas obviously it
finally gave me the opportunity to do
some like Hunter Thompson Feer and
Loathing stuff and coming up with all
the designs for that coming up with like
we got some posters coming
out I've got like seven different sample
posters coming holographic ones um gold
um like variant just a bunch of
different cool graphics and I really
like to be able to express an idea um an
artistic idea to my my buddy who can
then put it into reality and create this
thing from a vision that I have whether
it's just words that I speak to him
whether it's a sketch that I send him
it's just it's phenomenal and doing this
business I never wanted I owned a a a
business before this and it was in the
fishing industry and it wasn't something
that I enjoyed doing it was something
that I did because it was the job and
when I started growing I was like wow
this is like really where my passion is
at if I can pursue this somehow and like
do enough to make a living where I'm
doing what I love like why wouldn't I
want to do that you know even if it's
not as lucrative as something else it's
like it's just way better this is what I
want to be doing you know so the
freedom I say freedom I mean you're on a
plant schedule and you know you're kind
of locked into to that and you're
constantly doing upkeep and maintaining
and and all that but yeah it's just it's
it's all encompassing this business
where I can Flex my creativity through
the artwork side of things or the plant
side of things um the interaction with
the customers seeing other people grow
stuff that I've created and enjoy it is
just so rewarding that there's I don't
think there's anything else on the
planet like
it at least for me
personally yeah totally totally and I I
think that what you speak resonates with
a lot of people you know you've got to
keep that element of passion alive
otherwise it does just become monotonous
and a way to pay the bills and you know
there's obviously a complex answer to a
simple question there another I don't
want to cut off but another thing with
that is I'm constantly working to create
something new so it never gets stale
there's so many amazing photo periods
out there more and more every year that
I'd love to work with and and turn into
Auto format that you know that that
constantly keeps me motivated too
because it's like damn Gary Payton like
I know it's it's a cookie family strain
and then people will [ __ ] on cookie
stuff but that Gary paint insire I love
that like I can't wait to to work that
in the auto format for people and you
know there's always something new I'm
I'm working on a pith Auto with pith
Coast which is like phenomenal that's
probably my my favorite smoke recently
the the pith S2 number three the
pineapple piff from Top Dog they're just
incredible stuff so there's there's
always something new to be doing and
kind of one of the the downsides of what
I do is people always want stuff that
I've released before
and to me I love all everything I've
created I'm I'm a fan of um but to go
back like takes away from the current
work and the current projects that I
have going and I only have so much space
and so many hours in a day that it's
like I have to make difficult decisions
on whether do I dedicate this space now
to reproductions or do I continue
working on new projects so that's kind
of like my big my biggest downside of
the whole thing is just there's never
enough time or space to do everything
that I want to be doing
yeah of course of course and look I
definitely want to delve into some of
the more technical aspects but while
we're on the topic you know you're
talking about cool and popular photo
periods um I want to know you posted up
an interesting photo where was sort of
like a grid of nine different really
popular strains that you had pollinated
and were sort of considering converting
to autos of those nine which were some
of the ones that sort of jump out to you
as ones you think you might pursue
I love that apples and bananas man that
one really caught me off guard because I
had no expectations going into it but
that one really was was incredible to me
that and the Honey banana man that is
another one that's amazing I've got the
banana OG Auto will be coming out next
year as well it's another one that I've
been working on but this honey banana is
is beautiful the hash it produces is
amazing it yields real well it's a
vigorous plant it's a a very beautiful
plant to look at so that's another one
that um was in that run let's see the
thin mint I'd really like to do just for
kind of the sake of that being like such
a sought after strain for so long and
the fact that it took me like eight
years to get get a hold of like the real
cut of it I was like man well I got to
do this due diligence to to actually put
this into Auto format so that's another
one I'm trying to think of what else was
in that I think there was two maybe two
grids of nine each but most of
those I I would fly out to um Portland
Oregon to Archive to grab from his
dispensary out there and it would take
me multiple trips and and I did this two
times I did it when I was in Colorado I
went out multiple times flew out brought
the stuff back and then once I got out
to Maine I left those cuts out in
Colorado I was like you know what I'll
just do it again I'll fly back out there
grab them again whatever so this time I
took my girlfriend out with me and we
get out there we could buy twice as many
clones per day because she was there we
we stayed out there for the weekend
loaded up with like 24 30 Clon something
like that and then there was a hurricane
in Boston which was the airport we were
flying back into so our flight got
delayed one day two days three days so I
had in our little hotel room I went out
and bought lights had a whole little
little veg Garden in the bathroom of
this hotel room and we went out to
dinner I get a text from the hotel
saying um there's been a smell of smoke
on the on the floor you're staying on
and we traced it back to your room you
need to get rid of this or else the
police will be involved something like
that I don't know I've got the the
screenshots in my phone still I posted
it up at one point and I was like I
should probably take this down but
anyway we get back to the
hotel I immediately drive back I don't
respond to the text and I had stayed at
this hotel six seven times before
because I would stay in the same Hotel
every time it's a hotel from like the
1950s it's just been around forever all
old people there at the front desk they
give you cookies when you check in and
the night before it was a new person I'd
never seen before like when I checked in
and so I was like oh do you have those
cookies or whatever kind of like trying
to buer with this new person that i'
never seen before and he like yeah here
you go and so when I get to the hotel I
was like I just wanted to let you know
there's been no smoking in the room um
but I understand what's going on and
I'll get it taken care of no problem and
there was a young behind the desk with
him that was like we went in there we've
got pictures we know exactly what's
going on I like oh [ __ ] so I was like go
up to the hotel room the door is locked
my key won't work for it and I'm like
[ __ ] are the cops gonna be downstairs
like waiting in the lobby when I go back
down was this just them wanting me to
get back there so like whatever could
happen so I go back down act like you
know nothing's wrong say look um the key
doesn't work like is everything okay and
they were like oh let me get you a new
key the old guy who's like on my side
against this this young girl that was
working there he was like yeah let me
let me get you a new key I was like I'm
so sorry just I've got my medical card
like everything is above board he was
like I understand we just can't have
that here in the hotel it's like no
problem so took some empty suitcases out
immediately to make it look like we just
took everything out then I sat there
these plants archive clones are are the
best possible clones you could get in
the world they're so healthy they're
teens they're I mean you can take three
four five clones off what he sells as
clones so I started breaking stuff down
chopping it into little clones putting
them in zipl bags labeling everything I
don't want to mess anything up took me
probably two hours to actually break
everything down and then really take the
actual not the decoy suitcases but the
real suitcases out with everything so
I've got the Clones I've got uh the the
Snips as well packed in two suitcases
take them out and just never go back
there and that was like the end of that
went to Some Mo Hotel eight just like
the lowest tier Hotel you could ever
stay in the people next to me look like
homeless kids like in the room next door
that I mean we got a smoking like a a
cigarette smoking room which you don't
find anywhere anymore so I was like all
right this place isn't going to give two
shits about what I got going on they've
got way bigger fish to fry they have
literal prostitutes in the parking lot
so this is perfect we're not going to
get in any trouble here anyway the
flight gets delayed three days so these
clones are just you know they're they're
they're growing they're like
they're they're whatever so pack them up
finally get on the flight well okay we
get to the airport and the flight gets
delayed again as we're there after I've
already sent my bags to be put on the
plane so I'm like [ __ ] well we got the
hotel room for another night anyway let
me pull the bags off the flight go back
to the hotel room we'll leave in the
morning so I asked them to pull my bags
they're like all right go down to the
baggage claim area they'll be down in
about an hour an hour goes by two hours
go by hours go by I go back up to where
you check in like hey they said they
were going to pull these the lady behind
the desk is like they didn't pull them
they're on the flight go now you've got
a half hour to catch your flight they're
on there and I was like I just want to
explain I don't want me to get on this
flight and my bags stay here I was like
should I stay here and send my
girlfriend back to to the east coast and
that way we've got our base is covered
and the lady behind the counter is like
no they are on there they're on the
flight it's like all right let's let's
go we get on the flight um another
family boards right after us starts
throwing up on the flight like a few
rows behind us they kick them off the
flight and they find their bags within
five minutes to remove them off the
plane it's like all right well if they
found their bags that quick then ours
definitely have to be on here we take
off I get a text in air mid-flight
saying your bags are on their way
actually yeah we were flying into Boston
all right bags are on their way they're
they're on board everything's good to go
we land it's like 6: in the morning the
bags aren't there she like oh
[ __ ] so they're like all right you gotta
go talk to whatever the the the the bag
agent now explain what's going on
they'll track your bags down I'll get
them to you so I go it's like this
70-year-old woman I'm explaining you
know we lost our bag she asked what's in
them like all right do I just tell her
the truth here like what the [ __ ] G
what what's going on so I tell her
clothes you know toiletries all that
stuff and then I say there's hemp in
there as well there's hemp plants I just
flew out to to the east coast to grab
these specific hemp cultivars that are
highly sought after for my business it's
like it's very important that I get
these and the lady's like my husband
just started growing that's so funny and
like this this old woman and her old
husband I guess since things went legal
in Massachusetts had had decided to pick
up the hobby so she was super inged by
the whole thing and like really really
helpful but anyway she was like yeah I
appreciate you telling me this like
we'll get your bags to you as soon as
possible she like it looks like they're
going to be flying into New York um
we'll let you know another day goes by I
hear nothing another day goes by I hear
nothing on the third day my bags just
show up on my porch plants in them they
all look like [ __ ] they've been without
light for you know three four days at
this point but man I I pulled them all
out of it got them set up in the tent
vegged them all back out put the Clones
into root got a couple to root but
luckily I had saved the actual rooted
like things that I had Chopped all the
Snips off of potted those up immediately
and you know within within a month they
were beautiful healthy plants again and
that's one of like the amazing things
about about cannabis man it it wants to
live you know so I've got pictures of
all that I documented the whole thing
because I knew one day I'd want to tell
the story and share like just how crazy
these experience are I think you know it
it rewards you if you put in the work
and you you're dedicated to it it the
plant knows that you know what I mean
like it picks up on those vibes so yeah
it's I don't even remember where again
where we started but oh you were talking
about the the grids of of the the nine
plants each so yeah most of those cuts
came from from archive there but yeah
all of them were amazing if you ever
need clones archive and Portland Oregon
can't find better clones than there
I I can attest uh certainly um I I too
have visited the dispensary in Portland
many moons ago and picked up some plants
and tried to make them magically appear
in Australia sadly didn't quite work
anyway uh I I I wanted to ask you and
this is a bit of a change of pace
because I love that answer but I really
want to get into what was your thoughts
on some of the early Auto work and
specifically low rider what was your
thoughts on low
rider I never tried
it I I saw it many times I've never
grown it I've never smoked it I
appreciate what the joint doctor did to
popularize it I saw it in High Times all
the times and um it intrigued me the
reason I got into growing Autos was I
moved down to South Carolina I used to
go down to South Carina and spend my
Summers down there because that's where
my grandparents lived After High School
I moved down there go to college and
start this business and um I I made some
connections to to get herb and after the
third or fourth meeting I ended up
getting jumped and robbed and this whole
messy situation and I was like well it's
not worth this to to do the plant thing
what's the fastest or it's not worth
like the the violence aspect in order to
get this shitty weed what's the fastest
way that I can actually get get a
harvest and auto flowers was that so
that's that's what got me into grow Auto
flowers in the first
place wow that's that's actually a
really interesting introduction let's
why don't we do it why don't we go back
to the start tell me about your first
memory first interaction with
cannabis so I told this story on on the
dark wars podcast before about my older
brother
um yeah I'd say the first time I smoked
was with my older brother going to this
little drag strip um I remember drinking
some Waka which is like this kind of
orange leor and smoking a joint and
going to this this Racetrack and just
being terrified just thought my throat
was closing up I like there this is lace
I must be allergic to it I'm gonna die
blah blah blah and then after that I
remembered oh my god when I was in
fourth grade I guess my brother was in
sixth or seventh grade my mom found his
bowl and his bag of flour and called the
cops to our house to arrest him or Scare
arrest him and that was truly my first
well wasn't even truly my first that was
the first of like I know what's going on
but before that um my dad had 18 Acres
down in Maryland and he had this old
country boy that would grow his own
tobacco and mixed in with that tobacco
were cannabis plants and I just didn't
know because I was you know four five
six years old at the time so that was
like my very first introduction to it
was that um without even knowing but
yeah there's been a few kind of first
introductions whether I was aware of it
or not but yeah I'd say probably fourth
grade was was the first time that I
really was like what what's going on
here and uh do you remember the first
time you got high was it the first time
you smoked or was it a subsequent time
after no it was the first time I was
going to that that racetrack yeah we my
brother 78 Cadillac DeVille like a full
sound system and I even remember like
the some of the songs we were listening
to at the time the the very first
ludicrous album and some some Mindless
Self Indulgence and it was just a a
weird um a weird mix of music but yeah
that was the very first time was was
going to that drag STP sure and how did
your interest in cannabis progress over
the years towards say when you did your
first
grow um there's a band called 311 that
everybody makes fun of is like one of
the worst bands in the world or whatever
but their first few albums had so much
cannabis related um so many cannabis
themes to them throughout that it just
intrigued me that this plant could like
motivate and bring people together the
way it did and then seeing their home
videos of like concerts and stuff it was
like more of a modern kind of dead scene
parking lot scene where you know
everybody was like smoking and trading
and doing that sort of thing and again
nowadays they're almost looked at as the
butt of a joke but back then they were
like something really they're still
really special to me I mean their their
modern stuff does sound like a pair of
of themselves but back then it was like
this this special thing of like just
this Niche community of people that we
into this music and this smoking and
this kind of mindset of like you know
[ __ ] what people are G to tell me to do
um it's not all about money it's about
community and like bringing people
together and sharing and joy and that
kind of influenced me so heavy as a kid
and still know to this day that that
that kind of continued throughout my
entire life and that was like when like
I was saying in sixth grade when my mom
sat me down that was so heavily
influenced by them I hadn't even smoked
at that point it was just like man to
see the effect that this has on people
the positive effect that it has on
people really left an impression on me
and I wanted to explore that as soon as
I could and so that was kind
of kind of like the through line of of
what's motivated me through all of this
was that early on introduction through
through
music and so so I mean at first were you
growing photo
period yeah yep and my first grow was in
high school um just some Bag seed stuff
I
remember finding out that you had to
flip the lights to get them to actually
flower and it's so funny so these plants
we were growing at my buddy's house in
his garage in like the attic of his
garage and his mom found them and was
like you got to get these out of here so
we took them over to my dad's farm and
then he found them and was like you
gotta get these out of here so I threw
them in the back of a truck and like
started to leave and he saw me leaving
with these plants in the back of a truck
was like no you can't do that bring them
back and so I kept them there on the
farm and grew them out there but I
remember asking my buddy like how did
you get these so big and like so healthy
and he was like Miracle Grow spikes and
diesel fuel and for two weeks I was just
like what the do I really put diesel
fuel on these like I shoved a 100
Miracle gross bikes in these pots and
then years later I was like bro like did
you he was like I was just [ __ ] with
you that was a joke I was like oh my
God all right fair enough but yeah um
that was that was my first grow I
remember what I did find out about you
know putting on putting them on
1212 um my buddy's dad came over to
visit and was like so stoked to check
him out and they were in a bathroom and
he left the overhead bathroom light on
that wasn't on a timer as they were in
flower and I was out of town doing my
business stuff and I came back and the
light was on and I like I I freaked out
at him and it like it soured our
relationship like the dude was like you
think I would yell at your dad like that
like I was like I'm I'm sorry I was just
this is something that I've invested so
much time and so much energy into and
like I don't know I just felt like this
whole thing just got [ __ ] up for for
nothing like I shouldn't have told
anybody what I was doing to begin with
and then for this to happen was just
like H but anyway we worked all out and
everything was good and still a friend
of this day so yeah know no worries
there but at the time it was like the
biggest thing that had ever happened to
me because I was so stoked to finally be
in flower like doing it anyway they
ended up being super long flowering
Mexican sativa things that I chopped
early and then took down to to South
Carolina with me that was like my little
little little bumper crap sort of thing
that uh yeah I took down and that got me
over in South Carolina until I met
people at the college down there to
actually get get flower from and then
all that other stuff transpired and got
me right back into to Growing but with
Autos so this time I was serious about
it so yeah tell me about that tell me
about your first time growing an auto do
you remember what it was what did was
that the Eureka moment or was it a few
more grows after
that so I think the first would have
been probably some Dutch Passion stuff
and I did it
I just found someone online that was
doing it well and that was yielding well
and that was having amazing results
excuse me and I just followed his method
exactly at the time he was posting
exactly what was going into his name was
um Seymour buds on autoflower.net I
bought the exact LED lights that he used
that were called hydr grow from this
company in the UK Cammy was the the
person's name that ran that company I
bought those there were the penetrator
LEDs and they were just massive massive
panels and then I started getting like
um Gotham Hydro LEDs was another company
that was big at the time so I would buy
those and I just followed exactly the
same seeds that he had the same
nutrients that he had and ended up
starting doing deep water culture and so
my first harvest was like 10 ounces off
of a single Auto and I was blown away
that I was able to do this and it was
like just yeah that was the Eureka
moment but the thing was and this is not
to throw this is probably more on my
skills at the time rather than genetics
themselves but it was like I've got 10
ounces of [ __ ] that I don't really want
to smoke like it's it's not good it's
lacking in almost every department and I
was like well this was my first run so
whatever and then I moved on to other
other breeders and other genetics and
each time it got a little bit better and
a little bit better and I was like you
know what people are doing this the
right way there's um a formula to create
creating and and making these things
better let me follow that formula myself
and try my hand at this that was kind of
what got me started in the whole
breeding aspect of
things before we jump into a bit more of
like your story I just want to quickly
ask you more of shall we say a
philosophical question which
is I have been wondering this and other
people have asked as well you know do
you think that to an extent breeding
Autos requires more skill or do you
think that simply it requires skill but
also there's sort of inherently like a
bit of luck involved as well um at least
in one step that you know you might go
really good in your first generation
then that sets you up for Success
thereafter but I guess I'm wondering do
you think it's just more difficult or
that it's difficult but there's also a
luck
component both for sure it's absolutely
more difficult every photo breeder that
I work with is like damn this is what
you do like by the time we get to
working they screen into an auto they're
like this is way harder even um shout
out to C here now James Bean back in
2015 2016 was like these guys are doing
real work this is so much harder than
photo period breeding like every aspect
of it is more difficult um there's no
keeping clones there's it's it's easy to
make the wrong selection it's easy to
breed back the ruderalis stuff to to um
impact the the gene pool negative
so there's a lot of like uh pitfalls
that you can find yourself kind of
jumping over um but there's also a lot
of luck involved absolutely so it's not
like you know any one person is just
going to be the best auto period breeder
100% of the time on default it's it's a
game of of skill as much as it is you
know I locked out and found the right
things this this time I mean maybe not
as much there's a lot of you know
running the proper numbers um making
sure you have backup plans for every
step of the way but yeah there's there's
a lot of hard work and a lot of skill
involved but yeah a lot of luck
too certainly certainly and I'm sure
we'll talk about that when we talk about
some of the technical aspects of
breeding but I wanted to quickly ask you
I've only spoken to a very small number
of people who have bred Autos but
they've all sort of shared many common
sentiments one of them being that it's
incredibly easy to sort of dud an autol
line um and I guess I'm wondering how
often is it that you find you sort of
say to yourself I think I need to go
back a couple Generations or you know I
need to restart this we've we've gone
wrong at some point does it happen
commonly or is it a bit less common
these
days I'm I'm knocking on wood right now
because fortunately it hasn't happened
too many times there's
maybe two two projects i' say that I
could go back and and revisit and redo
better than I've done before um other
than that I'm really really genuinely
happy with everything that I've put out
like I I think it's it's all been really
really good it's all been improvements
upon what they used to be um but yeah it
is easy to do that I do think um I don't
know epigenetics is the right term but
you can see stunting from one generation
carried over into the stock of the Next
Generation way more so than you would
with a photo period And I have noticed
that same for you know you grow a huge
Auto
um both parents being being huge grown
perfectly the the seeds resulting from
those come out impeccable so there's
definitely something to that and locking
in both negative and positive traits
within the line um but yeah we can get
into that I guess a little bit more when
we talk about breeding but really you
just you got to be there for him early
on there's a old Chinese saying proverb
thing that's like the best best nutrient
is the The Gardener Shadow so it's one
of those things where you really have to
be there and and care for him especially
the first four weeks or
so definitely definitely and there's two
follow-ups I want to ask you but the
first one is what would be your advice
for someone like myself who sees some of
the photos you post and you're like oh
my God that is the biggest Auto flow
like when you see a whole plant in a pot
at Harvest you're like that thing is
huge you know as you said like really
huge yield off it what are some of the
tips you would give people to help get
an auto to that size cuz I think for a
lot of us it's very rare to see
something go that
well um you know Hydro you can't go
wrong with with Autos the deep water
culture really LS itself to gigantic
autos because there's no resistance to
the roots same for Coke they get huge in
that really the fluffier the soil um the
less resistance against the roots the
bigger and the longer the vegge for um
if they run into twoo compact of soil if
it's too dense it sends a message to the
plant that hey you know we're out of
space here we need to do something it's
the end of our life we want to reproduce
we want to carry on into the Next
Generation let's flip into flower now
while we have you know ample space to do
so and so that's kind of of one of the
things is just giving them enough root
space early on and having crapper soil
and you know fluffiness to the soil so
that the roots can really spread out
easily and there isn't much resistance
same I mean it's really you can't
overwater them you can't underwater them
if you do either of those they'll stunt
out it's really learning kind of the
plant and as you know I cross back to
photos breed them out to Autos again
they get more resilient a lot of the
times each generation So and I've also
learned over the past 10 years of you
know you can transplant Autos they're
not going to yield as much but you can
do it properly where it doesn't
completely stunt them out and affect the
yield and nowadays with things like Auto
pots and the trade to grow system where
you know they're taking up the amount of
water they want to be taking up um I
mean you can start a bunch in small pots
in that sort of system and then
transplant them into bigger uh bigger
systems and they just take off they
don't miss a beat so it's really um kind
of developing the the understanding of
when to transplant them when it's too
late when to cut your losses and yeah
just just there's there's no replacement
for actually doing it it's just kind of
a Hands-On thing I could explain it a
hundred times and until you actually do
it and learn it in or Hands-On with it
it it just it's hard to to to wrap your
head around it's hard to grasp it's kind
of something that you have to do to
learn it
that yeah certainly and look I want to
ask a bit of a newbie question as
someone who has only grown about four or
five Autos before when people transplant
the Autos I often hear them having this
very particular focus on being like in a
tactile sense very gentle with the root
ball and of course you know no no one
advocates for manhandling a root ball so
to speak but I wonder do you think that
that very like literally as gently as
you can transplanting it and just just
just so lightly tapping it down you know
what I mean like do you think that sort
of thing does make a difference or do
you think it's more about like the
General Health of the plant when we talk
about stressing the plant
out I'm I'm a firm believer that the the
more gentle the better yeah to this day
that's something that I still focus on
and um I I rarely ever have help with
with anything in the garden I do pretty
much everything myself
from OB the Clones to harvesting the F4
Auto seeds at the end it's it's a me and
if I ever do have somebody come in
that's the most important thing that I
stress is if there's a transplant I
usually will explain to them exactly how
I want it done and then do it myself
it's like I just I don't have uh I'm not
good a delegating responsibility and
with this it's like that's the most
critical stage of of the whole thing is
like making sure to to minimize the
stunting as much as possible
um yeah I absolutely believe in that
that's that's that's
key yeah good answer there you go I
wanted to ask on that topic you know
you've mentioned soil I would love to
hear a bit more about your grow Style
just generally speaking because you know
I I do hear people at times say you
should grow with lighter nutrients for
Autos so love to hear your thoughts on
that but also if you could tell us a bit
about the the awesome collab you have
with our buddies at Builder
oil yeah so for the longest time um
pretty much as as soon as I stopped
doing hydro which um I stopped doing
because as I started to grow more and
more plants I upgraded my pump to a big
kind of like a pond siiz pump the a big
big boy I didn't upgrade the manifold or
the tubing so I was still running
through all super small tubing which
created back pressure on the pump and
then heated up the reservoirs and caused
me to get root rat and so I had to learn
about um what was it called at the time
Heisenberg tea was what people were
calling it at the time which was
basically a um a worm casting tea with a
few other things in it so I used that to
kind of get through and fight the root
Rod off and it went from being a what
was supposed to be a completely sterile
environment into well now I'm doing some
sort of hybrid hydroorganic uh synthetic
thing here after that I switched to
Super soil and I started mixing up the
Vicky subcool style super soil and what
I would do for that was I would take a
five gallon bucket and I would do the
bottom half with a super soil mixed into
Roots original and then the top half
would be just unamended Roots original
well out of the bag it has amendments in
it but just Roots original soil on top
of that so that the auto would had time
to establish in that before hitting the
hotter stuff because you planted them
into hot soil if you put them directly
into the Super soil they would just stun
out because it was just too much for
them so this would give the roots time
to establish before hitting that hotter
stuff and they absolutely love that man
I stuck with that for basically until
two years ago that was my my methodology
um now I use once I switched so I always
did like I said five gallon buckets and
then seeing all these Auto poot grows
and people just getting these absolute
monsters and autopots really had me
scratching my head because I was always
of the mindset that [ __ ] automation you
know like that takes the passion out of
it that takes your skill out of it like
that's just it's it's for for mids it's
for corporate cannabis whatever and then
I actually tried it with the super soil
and could not believe the results but
because of how big and how quickly they
grew in this autop poot setting they
would eat through all the Amendments
that were usually enough to carry them
through to flower so then it became all
right well I got to figure out top
dressing sometimes I'll have to hit them
like in an emergency situation with some
sort of organic liquid nutrients just to
get them something faster um but now
I've switched to build a soil
3.0 which everybody told me was going to
be too hot for Autos too strong but man
they absolutely love it so now I I
transplant into 3.0 I still start them
out in Roots original transplant into
the 3.0 into the 6.6 gallon Auto pots
and you can't beat it man they are just
they are
incredible that's awesome and and do you
top dress what are some of the
Amendments you like to use
as of now I haven't been top dressing
I've just been doing the 3.0 um but I do
have builda flower here so if I ever do
need to do that I I will um I did have
to top dress I was doing a warehouse in
Colorado about two years ago and that
was like my first major run in autopts
and again they just caught me off guard
with how huge they got and how quickly
they went through the soil so I did have
to top dress there um but yeah that uh
let's see as far as how dressing yeah
builda a builda flower is really the
main one I like to throw worm castings
on top I've started putting black trash
bags putting them out and putting them
on the top of the soil so they have
beeder Roots at the very top when you
lift it up they even grow mushrooms and
stuff under there but anyway so now in
case of emergency if I ever do need to
top dress the roots are right there
ready to take it in and that was
something that I saw um through Jeremy
at build soil through his video vide I
think with our earth box he pulled the
cover back and showed all the the feeder
Roots right there and I was like man I
need to implement this somehow with what
I got going on so that was kind of the
impetus for that um but yeah really it's
just Bal soil amendments at this point
and as far as the cab stuff goes
um he's amazing I'd love to do like a
proper Autoflower slow cab with him but
to be honest the 3.0 is kicking ass so
there's really not much if it was a
little bit fluffier that would be good
but even as is I mean it it works it
works amazing the the flower from it
phenomenal so there's really just a few
small tweaks that could be made to
improve that like when we first started
talking he he thought the 3.0 would be
way too hot so he made a very airy very
loose soil with almost no amendments in
it and that one he would have to top
dress and work with and as soon as I
tried the 3.0 I saw other people trying
it and I was like is that too hot and
they were like no man it works great so
I tried it myself and
Game Changer so there's nothing really I
mean I'd love to collab I'd love to do
an auto soil like we had talked about
but it's it's almost not necessary if if
you kind of know what you're doing with
with the 3.0 and kind of transplanting
at the right time um if I wasn't
transplanting into it I would do the
same kind of layered situation that I
had done before with the super soil
where I'd put the 3.0 in the bottom of
the pots and then an unamended soil
light mix or something in the top but my
My Method now I'm constantly
transplanting in so that that works no
that's that's really cool to hear that
the 3.0 works for you and I I was just
sort of thinking you know like it's it's
been so cool and interesting to see how
many people have been watching the build
of soil YouTube series like it's so
massively popular and uh you know to see
your genetic sort of shining in there
that must be really cool while we're on
the topic uh well sorry while we're on
the philosophical topics I should say I
wanted to ask you this what are your
thoughts on this sort of perception that
auto flowers are for beginners they're a
stepping stone to photo
periods I think it's just I get it
because of Otto and the name the
perception of them and that people think
you know they're not as good but the
fact of the matter is if you can grow an
auto flower you can grow a photo period
if you can grow a photo period it's not
necessarily the same a lot of photo
period people get their egos put in
check real quick when they try to do on
Autoflower and St them out stunt them
out stunt them out and just write them
off as you know these suck they're
exactly what I had in my mind of what an
Autoflower would be a little popsicle
blood when in reality you've got to
change what you're doing in order to
maximize an autoflow potential
so this is no slight to photo periods at
all I love photos I work with them every
single day but the fact of the matter is
in general autof flowers are way more
difficult and if you learn to grow on
Autoflower well you'll have zero issues
growing a photo period in fact photo
periods I've seen it time and again
where they actually make Autoflower
Growers lazy because you can veg them
for so long and you can play catchup
with them where if you look at an auto
flow let's say a longer running one has
a 100 days life cycle each day is 1% of
its life if you mess up early on you're
not getting that those days back and you
[ __ ] up kind of your foundation for
the rest of its life there's no no
rewinding the clock there's no revegging
there's nothing you can do at that point
so for a lot of photo period Growers
that that do try Autos it's I tell them
you know you're G to stunt these out
just go in expecting that you know
you're GNA stunt your first few out but
you know give it give it a few tries and
once you get over that learning curve
the reward is is phenomenal like the
explosion of growth the speed the
resilience of the plants once you get to
a certain point in their life cycle um
it's just it's awesome to see you go in
every day and you see the growth like
even you go you visit your plants a few
times a day you can see different growth
throughout the day like they're that
quick at certain stages and back to your
um top L and thyroid question earlier
with Autos part of me wonders if the
speed of their growth kind of is faster
than the vroid could catch up with like
I know like the vroid hangs out kind of
a lot of times in the lower parts photo
period so you can clone a healthy part
at top or even you can test different
parts of the plant and it'll be present
in some parts and not the others so I do
wonder if there's something to that of
like just simply the sheer speed at
which an auto grows does not allow for
that to actually um kind of manifest
itself but again I've not seen them in
Autos that I am aware of that I could
say yes exactly this is you know the
viroid here in this plant but yeah I've
been again
touch wood here I'm super fortunate that
that I haven't dealt with that at all
and I hope to to never deal with
it yeah it's an interesting question I
can't say either way but you're right
you know in in normal plant the Marist
stem doesn't attach to the the xylm and
FL for a certain period of time so you
might be right and because as you said
you know photo Autos can really be
taking off at a certain point that's a
that's an interesting hypothesis I
wanted to ask you I mean given we've
spoken about the
Autos are now at the point where they
don't need to be considered the the
stepping stone to something better and
you know I guess the implication that
has been going on throughout this chat
is that you know when when done right
it's it's high quality it's it's you
can't really tell the difference uh I
would love to ask with that in mind
where do you think the future of Autos
is heading do you think that um we're
going to get to a point what I've heard
other guests say in the past is that
they'll become very Comm Outdoors for
commercial
production absolutely I think even
indoors for production um years ago when
I first moved to Colorado there's a
photo period farmer there 60 lights just
crushing it with with photos and he
wanted to try autos and so I set him up
with with seeds to do the whole run and
he was hooked he he completely turned
his whole veg into you know flower at
that point and just had more and quicker
turnarounds than you'd ever had before
and if you do it right if you if you
figure out kind of the recipe to success
for you and it's different for everybody
there's a hundred ways to skin a cat but
he followed I mean it was basically like
my grow it's a super soil and it was
like everything was mine it was my
genetics the super soil and yeah he just
never looked back turned his whole grow
into Auto he never had complaints from
people that you know the the quality
decreased or anything like that it was
more profitable for him it was more
efficient and you know he did pay a
little bit more in power Bills running
18 hours of late as opposed to 12 hours
but other than that it made up for it in
in the end so yeah I think it is
definitely definitely a
um kind of the future of of cannabis and
it's it's weird for me to say that up
heard other people say it but now
sitting here thinking about it it's like
there is a lot of potential photo peries
will never go away nor should they nor
would I ever advocate for that again I
love photo periods I don't want anybody
to think I'm like some Autoflower purist
because I love it all um but Autos are
here to stay and that's that's kind of
the the long and short of it I've seen
grows out in Oregon Outdoors Auto
flowers that were just monsters just
beautiful beautiful fields of flowers
and yeah it's it's it's a special plant
and when you when you learn it when you
figure out how to maximize it there's
it's it's hard to go back to photo
periods sure sure I I love that story
and you've referenced a few times you
know if people want to give this a go
you you probably will stunt them a few
times but you'll get there just for
anyone who might be curious and thinking
about giving it a go what are some of
those mistakes people often make that
may lead to it not going so right the
first few times
pretty much just what I've mentioned
before just having two compact of of
soil uh overwatering or
underwatering um you really gota be
there kind of on a daily basis lifting
up the pots and checking to make sure
you know how are these guys well
nowadays you can you know put a moisture
meter in there or you can use Auto pots
or whatever and it's kind of just
completely changed the whole game for
auto flowers with kind of the evolution
of grow technology um it's much easier
these days to get into it not stun it
there's also way more resources
available and way more people that have
[ __ ] up and you can see where they've
messed up in the past that now moving
forward you can avoid their mistakes but
really it's just I would say the medium
is the number one thing of just not
having too dense of of soil or or medium
in general um and I do think as each
generation moves you know from an a new
photo back to auto back to photo back to
Auto they do gain a little bit more
resilience and and tend to really just
be a little bit harder overall so
nowadays Autos aren't the same as they
were 10 15 years ago even five years ago
it's just it's it's a constant Evolution
and I think it's only getting better
with with the rate selections again as I
I mentioned before it's it's not not
terribly hard at all to to mess up and
and you know go back to some rter Alice
looking stuff but with uh with good
selections and and good good grow set
good um kind of skill set and knowledge
beforehand yeah it's way easier to to be
successful with them now than ever
before yeah definitely definitely you
can tell we've made a there's been a big
leap and uh we'll jump into that in just
one second something I I forgot I hadn't
actually asked you at the start how rude
of me what have you been smoking on
recently uh the the piff S2 and the
pineapple PFF and
I just just ran out of those I've got
some honey banana here next to me I've
got some strawberry milk and
cookies
um yeah those have been been the main
ones here recently that have been in my
rotation look I love it some some
beautiful examples in there you've
you've mentioned you've been fond of and
you're doing some work with the piff
have you had a chance to try any of the
other Infamous nl5 Haze um clones like
maybe the C5 or the A5
five no I wish I had i' I've got quite a
collection of of seeds made with those
but I haven't ran them yet I'm sure like
you we probably have way more seeds than
we could ever actually grow that's like
I'm a seed hoarder collector I've got uh
let's see one two three four five six
seven
eight got about 16 totes behind me with
with seeds in them so I've got yeah just
the
My My My Life Investment is in seeds um
but yeah no I have not ever experienced
those even the piif I never got to
experience until the past i''s say 18
months or so and at first I was like
this is interesting but the more I
smoked with it the more it really really
kind of got to me this particular FS2
number three I think has something like
7% thcv which i' never had before and so
that's something I'm really excited to
like work into Auto format um but yeah I
I can't get enough of of the hazy
stuff I went to pcon this this past year
and that was oh man that was a hell of
an event it blew me away I had
expectations for it and it was far above
and beyond anything I could have ever
imagined it was massive um shout out to
piff Coast farms for putting that on and
making the piff accessible to to
everyone because growing up it was just
something I'd hear about in rap songs I
never you know thought I'd try it it
almost became like is this even is this
just a nickname like kind bud but to
actually have it and be able to like
smoke it on a a semi-regular basis now
is yeah it it's maybe because of the
sentimental reasons of like growing up
and not having access to it and hearing
so much about it but it's special it's
it's a good one yeah totally you know
what's interesting I've been lucky
enough to try the C5 and the A5 but I've
never tried the piff so there you go on
opposite ends of the spectrum and I
definitely have recently been thinking
you know shout out to piif Coast Farms
it uh it's undeniable that pifc con has
been a success and you know the fact
that they're going even harder is a is a
sign of how successful the prior ones
are I'll probably have to get those guys
on pretty soon I reckon yeah let me uh
also just say shout out to Lobster fam
Farms one of the best Growers I've ever
had the pleasure of smoking his flower
man he does stuff with that plant that's
just phenomenal um the the piff from him
the Harlem River Haze the pineapple piff
they are just absolutely incredible and
I I feel lucky to be in the same state
as him to be completely honest man he's
a he's a special cat for
sure yeah definitely shout out you know
it's always lovely to be gifted some
beautiful herb we've uh We've we've
gotten so sidetracked I I best get us
back on to our story which is what was
your first Auto breeding was it
intentional was it accidental lay the
landscape for
me oh it was intentional um my first
Auto to Auto stuff actually I didn't
even start out with auto to Auto my
first Auto breeding project was what
would become a sour stomper for misto
genetics and it was their sour crack
that I had so in 2014 I moved my little
cousin out to Denver Colorado and
sampled probably 250 different strains
of cannabis we we got there on the day
that re stor is legally opened there's
kind of this famous um Anderson Cooper
He's a news anchor he was a news ancher
over here I have no idea what he's doing
now but he sent one of his reporters out
to Denver to cover the opening of these
pot shops is what they called them and
she went on this like cannabis bus Flor
from dispensary to dispensary and anyway
the first place they stopped at me and
my cousin were in line to get flower
from so me and my little cousin are
standing there like you can see the
video online of us like in line waiting
to get weed here as they're doing this
tour and anyway this this went viral
because she ended up getting high like
and doing her news report super super
laughy and chatty and you could see in
her face she was just St like even
Anderson Cooper called her out on it was
like are you sure you didn't in Vibe at
all and yeah so um during that time grap
stomper was like my favorite of these
like 200 250 strains that we tried so
immediately when I got back to the east
coast I started trying to Source those
seeds and they were just sold out
everywhere but I found there's a website
called canazon out of the UK and they
had a pack of grape stomper OG and it
was their last pack they had of it and I
got it I had them send it stealth and it
came to me and it was a 10 seed pack I
ended up getting like 12 or 13 seeds in
it I reached out I was like man are you
sure you sent me the right seeds like
there was too many seeds in here like
just super suspicious of the whole thing
so like who would get seeds you know
what I mean and so I I kept a mail from
that in Maryland as I was growing down
in South Carolina I had my buddy from
high school kind of take over my garden
there in Maryland he didn't even have a
car his mom would drive him to this spot
that I had and he would water the plants
on a daily basis and I would drive 12
hours one way each weekend to go up and
take pictures of these plants to make
sure everything was going all right but
anyway there was a grape stomper mail
that I didn't didn't know much about
breeding i' had done a lot of research
and you know it had tacky stems and you
just rub it you could smell the grape
even when it was in veg and I was like
this is like there's something special
with this so I kept that mail alive
anyway down in South Carolina I had the
sour crack growing a Tyrone stomper and
some other stuff I was out for my job I
usually would take my dog on the road
with me every day but this day I left
her home I was renting a house my dog
was there I come home there's a note on
the door saying you know this property
is going to be inspected by the sheriffs
this house is foreclosed on I was paying
my landlord he wasn't paying the bank so
the house I was in went into foreclosure
without me being any wiser about the
whole thing so I immediately took those
two plants throw them in the back of a
truck drove up to Maryland with them had
him there and was like you know what
I've got this grap stomper mail here I
should like do something with these e so
I I put the pollen on both the uh Tyrone
special and the sour
and those became sour stomper and Tyrone
stomper which were the first photo to
Autos the first ever breeding stuff that
I did so and still to this day it's some
of my favorite like I I I love that that
was like really truly the great stomper
and auto format it's they're they're
both phenomenal plants um but yeah that
was that was my first interaction with
with breeding yeah wow from there I was
hooked it was it was Off to the Races
that's so interesting okay and then so
how did it um unfold from there did you
how did you get hooked up with the misto
guys so I'd been following them online
and their stuff was like the first stuff
that was like damn this is a game
changer for me this is like the next
level autos and so we became friends on
autoflower.net I'd followed them on
Mitch on there and on IC mag and was
just a big fan of everything that he was
doing he was you could tell he was doing
it right and he was doing the proper
selections and and running numbers and
doing real true breeding work to make
this plant better and that really spoke
to me so I started growing all their
stuff I would document the [ __ ] out of
it because that was I was like super OCD
about that I would get the VPN and like
run all my pictures through imager to
erase all the exit data and all that
stuff and uh we just became like friends
that way and that's uh I asked him
before I did the pollination like do you
mind if I do this or whatever and I sent
him the F1 seeds and he gr out was like
dude these are like the frostiest plants
we've ever seen like these are amazing
and so he I was like that's my gift to
you at the time I was trying to get a a
license to grow in Maryland because they
were about to go legal and I had him
write me a nice little um kind of
recommendation review thing that I could
give to potential employers people that
got licenses that like put me in a good
light and said you know this dude knows
what he's doing but in a professional
professional way
um and so yeah they they continued to
work that I went over there and to Spain
in 2015 and that's when we were running
the f3s and helped do the pollinations
on that actually just found my my old
imager account recently within the past
six or eight months with all the
pictures from Spain where I was there
like helping with the pollinations and
doing all the plants I was literally
sleeping on the floor of their like
Farmhouse helping helping to to grow
there for three months and move these W
and it became the first
artisanal um Mesto release and yeah it
was I just I fell in love with every
aspect of it Mitch had reached out a
couple of times because he was like we
get you over here how do we like get you
to be a part of this you know make this
all work out I just didn't have anyone
to watch my dog at the time and I was
engaged and my girlfriend my fiance at
the time did not she didn't smoke she
didn't like that I did what I did um I
ended up moving in with her in West
Virginia
and not to go on a tangent here but one
time we had some drama with the
neighbors good old boys that didn't like
me I was a new newcomer whatever
anyway fights happened cops got involved
I was harvesting downstairs at my sh my
ex fiance's
Place get a knock on the door
um I guess I should say the night before
there was an incident with some guns
involved whatever the cops came out they
said look you you you're in a stand your
ground state your armed I have a little
bit of a background in competitive
shooting I have my concealed carryer
permit all the like I did it all the
right way you know don't break the law
while you're breaking the law sort of
thing so um yeah anyway the cop
basically told me to shoot this person
the next time they came over and started
[ __ ] and I was just like threw all my my
training I was like I don't want to go
through that emotionally I know like the
consequences of that on a person to like
put themselves in that situation but
also I want to protect myself and my
family and whatever so anyway next day
something
happened everything I thought was good
after that I went downstairs started
harvesting have my headphones in as I'm
harvesting don't hear [ __ ] uh dogs start
barking upstairs I come upstairs as soon
as you open the door from the basement
you're facing the front door and there
was a cop with his 1911 drawn I'm
staring down the barrel of this 45
caliber pistol and it wasn't the first
time that i' stared down the barrel of a
gun I could I looked in the cop's eyes I
could see he wasn't he was like a an
older guy a mature guy he wasn't trigger
happy I saw he had Trigger Discipline
his finger was not actually on the
trigger I smell like weed I've got weed
on My Hands there's a I see out the
corner of my eye there's hand sanitizer
it's like don't move don't move got my
hands in the air I'm like sir I was just
downstairs jacking off I need to hit
this hand sanitizer real quick grab the
hand sanitizer rub it on my hands try to
get the resin and the weed smell off
open the door lock it behind me so he
can't go in throws me down on the ground
I had my pistol on my hip he takes that
off he's like is this the gun that was
involved whatever earlier I was like
know that went inside the living room
whatever um put me handcuffs from me in
the back of the car and this was a small
little West Virginia town but the FBI
was like right right there the next town
over so there was like six different
agencies all in our driveway the
neighbors were over there and the
neighbor literally had just gotten out
of jail known criminal but he was like
friends with the police officers so much
so that the night prior it took us like
four hours to actually get a cop to come
out to even like talk to us because he
had called in and told his side of the
story and they were like well you know
there's no need for us to go out
everything's fine blah blah blah
anyway the person that they wanted to
press charges on me as I'm sitting in
the back of the car they're trying to
call they couldn't get a hold of him two
hours goes by they're not listening to
me I'm trying to explain my side of the
story through the back of the cop car
window they're just [ __ ] this kid out of
town or blah blah blah
whatever eventually they get a hold of
the dude and the dude was like no he was
standing his ground he was on his
property he did nothing wrong I don't
want to press charges they let me go
gave my gun back I didn't have any keys
on me to go in the house so I had to sit
outside without a phone and a snowy West
Virginia holler for like three hours
until my chick got home from work she's
like I was trying to call and text you I
knew something was wrong but anyway that
was like the writing on the wall of I
got to get to a legal place and a legal
State and that's when I I decided you
know [ __ ] this I'm I'm done taking these
risks like this and that was like time
to go to Colorado that was kind of how
that all happened um what' you ask let
me get back to to the the actual
question no no that was it that was it
how you got hooked in with mempa okay so
I wonder what what are some of the
standout strains from that period that
you really stand behind and think were
are just awesome witho stuff yeah just
any of that early stuff you worked
on I I love the sour stomper to this day
it's one of my favorites it's it's an
amazing strain um I've got a lot of of
love and respect for what I did with
those guys um I think they they're like
that some of their stuff's been the high
water mark for a lot of the Autos
especially at the time like the the
Ripley's OG the Walter White a lot of
their older stuff was just phenomenal I
haven't kept up too much with any of
their their newer stuff but I still go
back and Dabble in my old Mesto seed
stock even before then um secret garden
seeds was like another company that that
Mitch had before Mesto and I've still
got my auto stock from from them from
back in the day and like I I I have a
lot of respect uh and a lot of
sentimental you know value in those
seeds for me and I I still love them to
this day and still still go back and and
check them out every once in a while but
yeah the uh the the sour Stamper for
sure the Walter White the
Ripley um they were all really really
nice yeah some some incredibly memorable
strains there that even in Australia I
remember we're getting grown out quite a
bit so shout out to all the people who
got to enjoy that so you know I guess at
a certain point that chapter wrapped up
for you and and you moved on to night
hour what was the inspiration for
starting your own project night
hour um we just kind of
had creative differences I guess is the
most diplomatic way to put it um
different Visions for how the company
should proceed
um we should move
forward um yeah I don't really want to
get too deep into it but yeah let's just
say creative
differences sure sure and so what was
the first project you worked on under
the name night out at least in your
mind uh the Wizards Apprentice the blue
microverse and the zelica express were
my first night owl releases I released
those all at the same time um so that's
the the blue microverse was blue Mago
bx2 from Dynasty who's like you know
another Legend in my eyes it was an
absolute honor to to work with his gear
and you know to have him comment on like
photos of my stuff and be like damn that
looks like the blue Mago and like I
don't know it was just it it gave me the
it was like the wind beneath my wings to
to keep moving and you know know I was
doing the right thing and going in the
right direction um yeah the Wizard's
Apprentice was a chich wizard from Bodie
that I worked in the auto format and
yeah everyone loves bod myself included
nothing but admiration for all he's done
like I think he's he's an unsung hero
especially nowadays I feel like he
doesn't get the the reverence he
deserves um but yeah he's phenomenal
he's an amazing amazing cat and I hope
to one day shake his hand he's he's he's
a special dude for sure um and then yeah
the zelica express which is the the
zelica from a seeds worked into Auto
format and again just the the land race
sativa stuff was just that's special you
know what I mean like everything I do is
something that I really want to do and
enjoy and that that that's what it boils
down to is just these are things that I
love and it's it's a really special
feeling to bring something new into the
world that hasn't existed before and
it's like it artists do it chefs do it
and you know cannabis breeders do it and
it's just it's it's a really cool thing
to experience and and
behold yeah to look so many epic points
in there and you know mad love for bod
he's I I think he's made of pure love
and light and I agree with everything
you said he's just a pillar in the scene
and uh Professor P 100% you know still
one of the few breeders in my tier one
category and anyone who listens to the
show will know that I I love the blue
magu Lon I I for me very biased opinion
but I think Blue Heron blue meu bx2 the
best seed lines you can buy I want to
ask you you know moving on to some of
the incredible work that we see under
the banner of night hour if you couldn't
know any specific details about the
grower but could only recommend one pack
of your seeds for someone what pack
would you recommend just as I guess a
general
allrounder probably the strawberry milk
and cookies remix because that's the
version that's currently available it's
a flower that will make you say damn
this is an auto flower it there's it's
frosty as all get out it's got
incredible turps um it it grow it's not
the most it's not the biggest plant
overall but it's the quintessential Auto
flower as far as you know structure and
it's just overall an amazing plant so
that would probably be my go-to
recommendation for what's currently
available worldwide uh out of my catalog
for someone that's never grown in Auto
just yeah that's what my guts telling me
to say right
now I Lov that cuz I was uh lucky enough
to try some of the original and
hopefully I'll be lucky enough to try
some of the remix and it it was truly a
beautiful strain you know and I guess I
wanted to ask for any breeder there's a
few strains that just really seem to hit
and and I had jotted down a few um
Cosmic Queen was another one that I felt
really hit with the audience at least in
terms of what I could see and and
Marathon OG what do you think it is
about these certain strains that really
seem to become super
popular the cosmic Queen
is with with with a few of my strands
it's like there's there's nothing else
like it on on the market there's nothing
else it's you just don't find these
flavors um it's like a honeysuckle
suntan lotion
creamy just something special that you
you just it it catches you off guard
where you're like what the [ __ ] is this
man this is like I can't even pinpoint a
single flavor and through the Cure even
the flavor will change it'll get
cheesier and funkier and um I think
people love that they love the resin
production of it they love the flow but
really the that one in particular is is
super uplifting sativa dominant just
really amazing nice euphoric effects um
the marathon OG was like the first in my
opinion really true OG Auto where it was
like damn this is like super OG um it's
a big yielder super dense OG nugs just
the the TPS are there um what what was
was there another one you mentioned oh
and I also had the the milk and cookies
on the list I mean there's so many but
those were just certainly some of the
ones that I've seen very represented by
people is grown and
loved yeah I think they they catch
people off guard and and they're strong
they they have amazing effects they have
amazing flavor they grow well and it's
people don't expect that from an auto
and when they get it that it it really
resonates with
people yeah totally totally and and I'm
sure you know you're you're lucky enough
to have that feeling quite often I'm on
your website now I can see that the uh
the Halloween drop with the blue Power
is coming it's just one of the many
collabs you've done obviously Sin City
super well regarded I call them a bit of
a darkh horse breeders breeder cuz you
find their work pop up in other breeders
works and it flies under the radar like
you know in cush mins there's C cities
work in there anyway um tell me a bit
about this blue Power Drop and uh what
would you re like what sort of traits
does it bring to the table what would
people get excited
for I definitely agree that he's kind of
another one of the the unsung heroes
that's putting in the work and and you
know just doing it quietly and and
staying in his own lane and um yeah he's
a phenomenal dude I I got to hang out
with him a couple times him and his wife
and they're they're great people we
really H it off we had similar
backgrounds with like skateboarding and
music and stuff so he's just a a super
good dude overall but with the blue
Power Man it's really kind of a
blueberry Master Cush just really really
nice incredibly resinous hearty heavy
hitting just overall fantastic plant um
it's got super fat almost like afghanica
style leaves um super nice dark foliage
it fades beautifully and uh the resin
heads fall off it as I was breaking up
seeds of it earlier just man it's going
to be such a nice such a nice extractor
um I ran a couple through through my
little tumbler before deeding and yeah
they they they dumped heads so I'm
expecting good things for the
solventless guys with that one which
also yeah the the strawberry milk and
cookies and the remix are also both
really nice washers um that's something
I've kind of tried to to start focusing
on more over the past couple years
because it seems like you know that's
where the Market's going as opposed to
back in my Heyday getting out the the
glass tube and Blasting away and taking
it to the back oven and purging and that
whole process was like a ritual to me
man I used to love chopping a a a plant
throwing it in the little cooler with
some dry ice and freezing it up and then
packing the tube and refreezing it and
going out to town just blasting away but
yeah the the solventless stuff is really
taken off and um people have found some
really good good Watchers in my stuff
one of my my buddies Growers down in
Virginia he swears by the strawberry
milk and cookies and it's like
strawberry milk strawberry Nest flavored
hash and dumps he gets like six% returns
one of his buddies in Colorado got like
eight and a half percent Returns on a
wizard stash remix and he actually just
sent me up recently being like man I'm
really looking forward to the the blue
Power stuff and yeah uh the solventless
stuff has just taken off so while I'm
not focus solely on that because I feel
like there's that's kind of a byproduct
of some of the photo periods that I'm
working with naturally if I do my part
properly that trade's going to carry
over and since I don't wash myself it's
not something I've ever been like I need
to breed specifically for this but it is
something that I do keep in mind now
during my
selections yeah you got me wondering do
we need to see like uh Mountain trop cut
of Tropicana cookies Autos you know like
it's such an infamously famous washer
that uh you just set yourself up for
success but um I wanted to to ask you
you know on that topic are you much of a
concentrates guy if so what's your
preferred type of concentrate
so I used to dab exclusively pretty much
well I mean I went from flower to
dabbing and then when I went to Spain it
was like an unknown thing over there so
I brought like a couple rigs over there
to like give to the guys and they were
like what what is this what do we do
with this and so over there I like
bought a whole setup to blast and it
kind of like changed changed a little
bit of the game for them in some
respects
because well I don't want to speak out
of school here so I should probably let
let them tell their story um but yeah
that uh the dabbing was a huge part of
my life I used to love glass there was a
a glass blower named Doom glass that was
just one of my all-time favorites and
he's kind of vanished off the face of
the Earth the past few years I actually
went on Instagram and searched his
hashtag Rec recently and found like the
most recent post of him with somebody in
it and reached out that I was like Hey
know is this dude all right like yeah
he's just taking a break but yeah I I
loved D and and live rosin and I love uh
just all of it I don't dabble with much
anymore I've got my little puffco proxy
pipe that I love and that's my my go-to
as far as dabbing now um but yeah and
the mountain trap that was like my
favorite strain for years and years and
I love that one and I'm a very I try to
be as respectful as possible with
breeding so I reached out to to Oni we
did some trades I was like man I'd love
to to work this trap cut and it was like
during the time that him and Joey were
like had their little kind of falling
out um Harry Palms went his way Onie
went his way Onie said yeah you know
I'll get it to you Terry said yeah I'll
get it to you I met up with somebody
that was like a mutual friend of theirs
to get it they gave me the wrong cut um
so then after I ran that it was the
wrong thing I reached back out to both
of them and at this point they were like
had nothing to do with each other and I
told both of them out of respect that I
reached out to both of them hoping to
get it from one of them to work with and
like I think that pissed off both of
them so I kind of shot myself in the
foot there being like
too respectful or cautious or wanting to
do the right thing and it it kind of
like pushed them both away but I've ran
into Harry palom since then and been
like man like I'd love to to work
something still I know for a while they
both kind of went their separate ways
from the trap and now it seems like
they're kind of starting to come back
around to the trout but yeah that that
was one of my favorite sering for a long
long time and I really kind of got
bummed out that I I didn't work with it
it's still something I'd love to do um I
know there's some I believe there's some
other trop Autos out there that I
haven't tried just because I kind of
stick to my own stuff just to to for
whatever reason um but yeah I'd love to
work with that one still and it's funny
that you bring that up because I still
to this day would love to to work with
that actually had some chop Cherry just
the other night I I I went down to New
York and met up with some people and had
some trap Cherry there like man I forgot
how much I love this [ __ ] Tropic can
of cookies I need to to get this back in
my
life that's it that's it this is this is
why I'm the best people I got that six
cent I didn't even know the backstory no
I'm kidding I'm
kidding um no you are honestly like I
said I've been a fan of of yours on the
podcast since the very first episode you
you've been my uh my best friend in the
garden many lonely nights so I
appreciate what you do oh thank you I
was I was just having a joke there but
that's very that's very lovely to hear
that and you know what when you were
talking earlier about trimming the weed
when the cop broke down your door I was
going to say I hope you weren't
listening to me I don't want to be
associated with
trauma yeah no that I don't have you
associate I was listening to a a show
called Ron and Fez at the time actually
I remember specifically what I was
listening to to so yeah you're in the
clear see what I mean I knew I knew you
would have remembered
there you go there you go okay well no
look I'm I'm we we've had a friendship
for a number of years and it's it's been
awesome and I'm so glad we're we're
finally doing this um I guess you know
while we're talking about you were
saying there's some other trop Autos out
there I feel like a lot of the uh bulk
sort of Cheaper largely speaking just as
a general rule of thumb what you might
call sort of European originated Auto
seed probably mostly from Spain um a lot
of it is is obviously nowhere near the
level of nightow of misto and I guess a
lot of those former negative a lot of
those things you hear about Autos that
were related to the the European stock
do you think that's just an artifact of
the fact that like some of those initial
breedings were not done that well and
it's just carried over ever since like
is that just a rational explanation or
do you think like it's more complex than
that I I think the game's changed now
now I think those bulk breeders have
seen what the the good Autos are and now
buy those seeds and and knock those off
so that they do have walk stuff that's
like much better than it used to be but
at the end of the day any bulk anything
is never going to be good as something
Boutique and that's actually has some
intention behind it as far as the
selections are going like that's kind of
the problem with I have someone reach
out to me every other month saying hey
got a million seeds would you want to
you know buy some of these we' run them
to you you want to sell them put your
name on it whatever and it's just like
never no why would I ever that's there's
so much it's such a personal thing it's
such a personal relationship with this
plant and the selection like I said
earlier is so much defined by the pallet
of a person so to see these excuse me
these huge Auto Farms these outdoor
Farms where they're reversing a thousand
plants and pollinating five ,000 plants
getting however many millions of seeds
and then combining them all into one
seed stock is just crazy to me like I
get it there's there's always going to
be a market for that and these people
spend their money on promotion rather
than actually doing the breeding stuff
and I it's it's always going to be a
thing there's always going to be a new
company coming in um there's always
going to be people doing white labeling
stuff it's just it's part of the
industry at this point and
you know it is what it is
it's a difference between you know again
the intentional pollination and
selection and having a a discriminating
pallet versus we're just trying to make
as many seeds as possible for as cheap
as possible to sell them for as much as
possible so I don't know my buddy was
down in a hydro shop in DC sent me a
picture the other day he's like for
every excuse me for every1 you spend you
get to stick your hand in a box and
grabbed a random pack of seeds or three
random packs of seeds it was and the
seeds he pulled out were auto companies
that you and I both know very well and
it was just amazing to me to see what
kind of level it I was talking to Sin
City about this earlier tonight actually
it's it's a race to the bottom with
Autos these days
because the sharks have seen what what
good autof flowers do and the the
Autoflower community has been like the
the bastard stepchild of the Cannabis
scene its entire existence they've never
been given like any respect or any
credit or anything it's always like you
mentioned earlier oh they're for
beginners and only you know beginners
grow these and it's even to the point
where they're like the hate for it is so
strong that it's kind of alienated us
into our own little Community that's
almost separate from the Cannabis
Community it's like the Autoflower
community and the Cannabis community so
people see and they want in on it and
yeah it's just it it's they're like well
let's take the best seeds that we can
buy and reproduce them and mass without
a care for anything other than just the
quantity of the seeds at the end of the
day let's get some cool packaging to put
them in let's name them something catchy
and let's just sell them for as cheap as
possible if you
see the some of these companies and the
amount of seeds they give out you buy a
pack of seeds for 40 bucks and end up
getting you know 20 seeds for that you
can just tell that's a white label
company that's like that's all B stuff
you know what I mean there's no way you
can't afford the overhead of an actual
true like breeding situation with Autos
they just don't yield the same amount of
seeds that a photo period does if you're
doing selections you're not pollinating
every single thing or if you are
pollinating every single thing you're
testing the plants afterward you're
smoking the seated Bud to figure out
what's what what's the best and you're
releasing the best at least that's how I
do it so a lot of these companies just
release everything they put it all into
one like I said there there's so much uh
phenotypic variation in some strains and
in some generations in particular if you
just combine them all together and call
it one thing it's it's it's impossible
to recreate or to to really do that
because there's now you can have in a
pack of of five seeds five different
phenotypes and I don't know it's just
it's a different way of doing things
than I do they they'll always be a
market for it um but yeah it's a it it
seems to be a race to the bottom right
now in the auto Autoflower world and it
almost reminds me of kind of like the
big multi-state operators in the
dispensary world coming in selling stuff
at a loss to get rid of the the local
competition who's actually putting in
the work has the heart and the soul and
the passion and are putting out the good
product but have to charge more for it
because you know they just have that
higher overhead and don't have this
reserve of money they're just sitting on
to get rid of the rest of the
competition which that's kind of where
we're at right now in the auto world is
just the the big bucks the the the Chads
or whatever you want to refer to them as
are here and a lot of them are very
deceptive in their marketing to make it
seem like it's not what it is but if
you're able to like I said kind of see
the marketing schemes and the way that
they're doing things and just the sheer
volume of seeds that they can afford to
give away it's just a completely
different it that's that that's not what
I do and I'll never be able to do that
and yeah I just it's it it hurts my soul
a little bit to see but it also makes me
happy that it's bringing new people into
the Autoflower world because once they
get hooked then they do their research
and then they find night owl and it's
like wow I wish I knew about this sooner
but I'm glad I'm here now yeah yeah
that's such an interesting perspective I
I have to admit I feel quite enlightened
to hear all of that because as you said
there is a bit of a subdivision and it
and it can at times feel a bit like
grower verse Autoflower grower you know
what I mean and um when you say all of
those points all of them resonate you
know I can completely appreciate all of
what you said and to be honest I I think
there's honestly a bit of a race to the
bottom in in even in photo periods you
know like all power to him but it was
just a few weeks ago we saw Top Dog post
about I'm getting back to a day job
because things are changing and credit
to him and there was other many other
breeders in the comments who shared that
same sentiment you know I know skun VA
used to be working as an electrician for
many years cuz he was like you know why
not I wanted to to sort of pivot for a
second and and ask you I think your
Instagram account has to be one of the
most faked ones out there you know
there's a few people I think cap he's
another guy but like you you were
definitely in the contention up there
you know I think I I like to pride
myself on never following the fake
account because you know give social
vouch and other people follow it and I
like to think I'm a good enough little
Instagram detective that it's pretty
clear anyway one time I got caught out
I'll be honest one time I got caught out
I followed the fake one I'm
sorry but uh I want to know from your
point of view what's it been like to
have so many people like cuz it seems
like
I have to assume that these scammers are
getting sales because that's why they
keep doing you
right flattering it's I'm dude I'm one
person I don't I live with myself every
day so I don't see myself as anything
particularly special you know what I
mean I'm just a person I'm just doing
the work that I want to be doing so to
see other people that are copying and
and completely taking my profile and
making it their own and doing tricky
stuff with like you know using a capital
I to make it look like an L or using a
period in the wrong place or whatever
like they've fooled me before I was like
is this my account like I tagged the
wrong account before so you know don't
feel bad about that I've done it too but
it is a tricky thing to navigate and to
have someone come to you and be like man
I just sent this dude money through
PayPal friends and family and like don't
have anything to show for it it's like
that's a a tough position to be in and I
always you know say you know send me the
screenshots I'll take care of you like
sorry that happened but it is a just
kind of the one of the evils of of
Instagram these days and I try to to
post about you know anytime I see one
and it's weird now with like the invite
collaborator post on Instagram I'll
invite my three other accounts I've got
four accounts and I'll invite them all
so that people can see these are like
the accounts and even still within those
the scammers will comment and for some
reason a lot of times I don't see them
whether I only have them blocked on one
of the the four accounts or whatever so
they fly under my radar and people be
like responding even recently somebody
was
like chem dog was commenting to somebody
about like dude that's a fake account
and he got his first fake account after
our collab together where they were like
pretending to be chem dog glass he was
like man this is like this is new I've
never experienced this before so you
must be doing something right but yeah
that uh that's tricky to deal with and
tricky to navigate but I try to steer
people right try to post fairly
frequently the The Fakes as they pop up
that's just that's one of the evils of
of dealing with that
platform yeah totally totally it's uh I
feel like it's actually becoming worse
more recently but hey you named the
magic word chem dog focal theme in the
uh the show overall and I'm sure a
strain a man a family of strains that
near and dear to both of our hearts tell
us a little bit about this collab I know
people are excited a few of the
listeners were like definitely ask about
the chem dog collab and uh tell us a
little bit about the chem Dogan as well
man that uh that was special to me that
dude I have so much respect and love for
him and really really that was something
special for me it was a project I've
been working on since 2018 or 2019
somewhere in there um I met him first in
like 2015 I think I commissioned a
little one from him and then a hammer
and some other stuff and you know it
just it was amazing the first time I met
him um James Bean introduced him to me
using my real name rather than Dez and
every time I'd see him after that he'd
be like hey and say my real name and it
was like so special to me that this
person cam [ __ ] chem dog dude like
knows my real name enough so to remember
it year after year like it was just it
was crazy to me and he like I don't know
his whole story was very touching to me
the fact that he's like a standup dude
and and you know did the right thing and
you know there's it's just I said
there's a difference because we're
different that's always been kind of my
my catchphrase with with night owl and
what I do and I feel like he's like that
as well I saw a lot
of similarities as far as you know
starting young and and trying to um be a
good Steward for the plant and to keep
things alive and moving and knowing when
we have something special and um yeah
man he's just a a really really good
dude and so I made the I worked the line
made the seeds and for for years I was
like dude we should like collab on this
I'd love to like collab on this let's
let's do this but just the timing never
worked out andd be like yeah like well
let's do it let's do it like he he never
[ __ ] on the idea he was NE always
positive about it never had a bad thing
to say always excited about it but just
the timing never worked out then you
know he got a job in the legal industry
has a grow out in Massachusetts for a
dispensary out there and that really
started to take up a lot of his time so
the seeds were ready well over a year
ago and finally I hit him up again I was
like man I'd so love to do that that
collab thing and the whole time I was
like I want to I want to do something
special for it I want it to like be a
historic thing you know at least in the
can world like this was [ __ ] chemdog
again like this is the man you know so
in 2019 I think it was I saw his collab
with swamp seeds actually see I have
them right here in front of me he did uh
the dog ways collab with Swamp Boy seeds
and they did bals that the seeds came in
numbered from one to 100 I've that
number 41 out of 100 right here in front
of me and it was like I don't even want
to open them I don't want to break the
seal on these because it's such like a a
special cool sentimental pack and so I
always had the idea I loved his ones
they've always been like my go-to piece
ever since I started smoking chillums
and little ones were always my go-to um
so I wanted to to
do numbered ones for a collab drop like
that would be so [ __ ] dope to have
some night
L
ones and I'm not like I I never knew the
business side of glass I never knew just
how incredibly expensive it is to have
custom Millies made and I mean it was
like mindblowing the amount of money I
spent on these things and I I charged
five dollar more than I actually paid
for them to be made which didn't even
cover the the credit card processing fee
for the actual pipe it was like it was
definitely like a a labor of love type
thing but man I am so honored and so
proud and so stoked that we got these
one's done with the night owl Millies
there's two UV reactive Millies in it
and one regular night Al Millie and then
the chem dog Millie and they're just
[ __ ] gorgeous man every single one
that I sent out I didn't want to I was
like I wanted to keep all 100 for myself
like they're all so beautiful and each
time I see one posted I remember packing
it up and like the specific details of
that individual one that really stood
out to me so any time I see one posted
I'm like this one was one of my
favorites because of this or this one
was one of my favorites because of this
feature but yeah that was like years and
years in the making and to have it all
finally come to fruition the way that it
did was just phenomenal and again not to
speak out of school but it was at a time
um in cam dog's life where his father
was sick and rest in peace his father
did just pass away recently but I think
it also really helped kind of with some
stuff that he had going on too um
financially so it was such an honor for
me to be able to pay back something to
this man who's given so much to the
Cannabis community
and I also released some chem 91 R Autos
which nobody really releases reg autos
because I feel like oh that's giving
away intellectual property or you know
you're GNA spawn a hundred different
companies that are all making seeds from
these Auto Rags which it did spawn some
but so be it I wanted that out there the
way the chm91 made an impact on the
photo period side of things I wanted
these othero RS to make that same impact
in these same waves on the Autoflower
side of things and I think it did
exactly that um so yeah it was like a
just an
amazing an amazing thing and to me a m
stone and a historic uh piece of
cannabis history here and truly an honor
to be able to work with this man who
I've looked up to for so long in doing
this thing so and and man nothing but
but love and respect to that dude I
think I think he may be getting into the
I I know he's been been making some
seeds and testing some seeds out of his
own soon so hopefully we see some chem
dog releases soon and I told him you
know any any help he need with that he
he reached out to me to ask about like
you know packaging and stickers and that
sort of thing but he told me he'd never
been a part of any genetic drop like the
one that we did he was like that was so
special and so unique and I mean they
sold out within minutes like it was
they're they're gone now all the on I I
we didn't even know how the ones would
sell I was like is this too much to
charge for a pipe if I just charged
exactly or $5 more than what I paid for
them like is that going to be too much
because it ended up being 225 bucks for
the the pipes ended up costing me like
220 with the I did like some custom
packaging some really really nice boxes
for them we did some pins a keychain all
sorts of stickers and just extra goodies
to go along with it and make it really
memorable and special
and yeah it it worked out phenomenally I
I thought initially maybe we'd saw like
25 even though I'd commissioned a 100
total and um yeah he made 40 the first
batch and I was like that should be
plenty I don't think we're GNA sell 40
of them but yeah they sold out almost
instantly and so he's like well [ __ ] I
guess I have to go back and make the
rest of them now so it was like another
week he made another 40 and then the
next week he made the final 20 and yeah
it was like people were kind of pissed
that they had to wait for it I was like
I'm sorry I just I didn't expect this to
blow up like it did like I knew in my
heart how huge this was but I didn't
know other people would respond to it
the same way that I was feeling about it
and to see that I think it really was
heartwarming to him as much as it was to
me to like get out there to a completely
new audience and like really keep the
The Legend of this beautiful person
alive and this beautiful strain and and
yeah man I I I I am so stoked and
honored to have done that to have done
it justice I think I did that really
truly proper
that's so epic to hear and you know I
Echo all those sentiments you know Greg
and uh just I think he's wife as well
you know they do so much for the scene
and uh very very much unsung heroes and
that's so exciting to hear that there
might be some seeds from him on the
horizon and that you were able to do
this really fulfilling and cool project
with him in in amongst that you
referenced uh dropping the uh the photo
period Auto hybrids with the chem 91 I I
wanted to ask about that because
I mean I guess you sort of answered it
but I'd love to get a bit more thoughts
about do you think the fact that there
are so few auto companies on the market
relatively speaking is a reflection of
the fact that people are a bit guarded
about releasing the regular stock as it
is kind of Ip and and I guess as an
extrapolation of that do you think that
you know like it's okay to give it out
because the real skills sort of in the
breeding anyway it's not just in the
base stock or what's your thoughts
overall on
it I think that I'm afraid to see after
all the work that I've put in the
Autoflower Jee pool get bottlenecked
from people you know reversing the same
[ __ ] onto the same [ __ ] over and over
again especially with all the bul stuff
going on right now and the fake name
game the renaming stuff um I've released
the Wizards Apprentice as Auto rigs I've
released the Zod Delica Express as Auto
rigs I've released the blue microverse
as Auto rigs I've done
a um a few more I've done Zod Delica
Marathon Auto rig Z Del of Tyrone stomer
Auto rig so I've tried to put a platform
out there for other people that really
want to do the work and do it properly
I've tried to give them the absolute
best splitting possible and the
foundation to move forward in the best
light so that was really kind of like an
altruistic type thing of like I want
this to be carried on and who know who
knows how long any of us have on this
you know what I mean and if this stuff
isn't out there if it's locked and
guarded like if I pass away what's going
to happen to my seed stock you know what
I mean like it's I've got so much here
if I don't get it out and don't allow
others to work with it what good is it
you know so that's kind of that was kind
of the motivation for it um and also
just people were gatekeeping autos for a
long long time and weren't putting out
Auto RS and even still there's like no
Auto RS out there so and honestly
there's really not a market for for they
they they most people that get Autos
want to grow them don't want to breed
them and I think
uh they're harder to breed they they
take longer it's a a very dedicated and
time space and energy consuming process
but to put these out there for the
people that actually want to do it right
felt like the right move to me and you
know a lot of people told me I'm
shooting myself in the foot by doing
that you know this that and the other
thing but at the end of the day it's
also pallet driven and you know there's
I'm super
fortunate that somehow I've I've gained
a very loyal following
and again I'm not a person that like
shots my own horn or have ever been good
about talking about myself other people
talk way better about me than I can ever
talk about myself and that's just the
way it's always been but the fact that
people are loyal and do want that want
to work it their own ways is like it's
an honor to me um like it's just a a
weird thing where it's like I don't know
sometimes I feel really good about what
I've done and sometimes I'm like did I
just like completely [ __ ] up myself from
a business standpoint but at the end of
the day I can't worry about it and
there's like I said there's so many new
projects to to constantly work on that
it's hard for me to even do the
reproduction so to put this stuff out
there for other people to do just so it
carries on one way or the other in some
format is better than it not being a
available totally totally because you
know we hear this sentiment shared in
the context of clones all the time it's
like it's all well and good to to sit on
it but if something happens to you it's
just it's gone and then you know it's
it's almost better to just give it out
there just for the purposes of keeping
it but then as you said there's also
just a lot of good intention and a a
sense of collegiality in sharing it and
saying you know I'm not looking to
hamstring anyone who wants to give it a
go themselves so that's really awesome I
love that answer that's that's beautiful
I wanted to ask you you know you you
spoke about how you let your work and
let others speak about you more than
yourself and I think looking at the
sheer number of collaborations you've
had all just you know sort of really big
hitter names in the mix there is there
anything fun on the horizon you might
want to give people a sneak peek into or
even just more generally any strains on
the horizon you are sort of locked into
working with that might slip
out um as far as stuff that I want to
share I've pretty much said most of it
the piff um the banana OG obviously the
blue Power um the AJ Sour Diesel um I'm
working with top dog to do a starg auto
um I've kind of [ __ ] that up and lost
the Clone got it back from him lost it
again um got it back from him lost it
again bought it from somebody else lost
it again so I really have like [ __ ]
that one up royally and I feel so much
Shame about that but you know life
happens and I'll I'll I'll get it back
again I'll make it right we'll do it do
it the Justice it deserves
um but yeah those are are pretty much
the ones as of now that that I want to
share and keep the rest Under Wraps I've
found that if I give too much away or if
I'm say I'm working on a certain stream
all of a sudden another breeder will
have on the market six months later
which you know unless they happen to
have that same mindset we're doing the
work which these people that all of a
sudden come out are the name game people
that just will slap whatever name sells
on something that it's like I just keep
it to myself at this point until I'm
like almost ready to release it so yeah
those are the ones that I'm I'm
comfortable kind of talking about now no
look I think you mentioned just a a
variety of strains there which is just a
plethora to get excited about no need to
feel bad about not dropping anymore
there was about four or five hitters in
there uh I want to ask a few of the fans
submitted questions we got from the
patreon but before I do a few last ones
from me which was uh just as a sort of
general question not not that I'm like
you know thinking of any project is
there one project of yours that you
think to yourself you know what I wish I
could go back to that one either because
it's just so good you want to continue
it or because maybe you think you might
have been able to do it better does
anything jump to mind when I say
that I think the Tyrone stomper at F7
started to get a
little the bud structure became looser
and isn't quite what it was before so
that is one that I would like to go back
to it still
hybridizes incredible it still crosses
out beautifully all the the hybrids from
it are amazing but in its pure form I
think I lost something just in the
structure alone but also at the same
time it's frostier now than it's ever
been I mean the main stock has tricomes
on it like the the the fan leaves
everything is just completely it looks
insane like it's some sort of mutation
happened to where the bud structure lost
its density a bit but it gained all
sorts of resin everywhere so it's like
this crazy just little freak plant of
pure resin that is amazing and like I
said crosses out well still but that's
one that I would like to to go back and
kind of lock back down on its own so
that it can be released you know nice
and pure again
um I
think I mean that's the only one that
I'm kind of hard on myself about to to
be
honest well I I think that one's pretty
fair to be honest I but you know it also
sounds like it's it hasn't deteriorated
it's just sort of diverged a bit from
the original but it's got all those
tricomes so that's a good answer I like
that one I like that one as a bit of a
tongue and cheek one I want to know will
we ever see any photo period from
you so it's funny you mentioned that I
um I did do a release of early bird fast
photos to go along with Night Owl so
there's a um from seed to Stone that's
YouTube channel it's like massive he's
got a huge Discord and he did a
strawberry milk and cookies remix grow
off recently and for his patreon members
I released for the first time ever just
just gifted them out just to see them
grown out um across called Majestic tie
which was an old thae clone cross to
wizards apprentice and that was like my
first ever photo period cross that I had
released or photo to Auto so the whole
concept was like early bird fast
finishing photo periods to go along with
the Night Out Auto flowers and I mean
I've got hundreds and hundreds of of
photo period crosses that I've made over
the years just photo to photo straight
up just for preservation sake and and
just for my own to dig into later here
and see what I can find um but I do feel
there's some Merit to staying in My Own
Lane I do feel there's Merit to
remaining loyal to the people that have
remained loyal to me and at the end of
the day there's just not enough space
and time for me to do both at least not
to the level that I want to be doing
them and so Autos are are my favorite
thing to grow I love how they keep me on
my toes I love how they keep me involv
um I've got if you couldn't tell from
the conversation so far some ADHD issues
so the autos and they constant changing
and their speed and everything just just
I don't know it it keeps my interest
from start to finish so that's really
where my my heart my passion is at but I
I wouldn't mind releasing some of the
photo period stuff that I've made just
to get it out there because again it's
stuff like with this space dog clone
that's no longer in existence I crossed
that to the blue mey X2 crossed it to
space dog seed stock which I went
through a bunch of packs of the the
space dog seed stock to find this same
clone before the people that had the
Clone allowed me access to it and there
was nothing like this clone in the seed
stock and come to find out later I guess
there was a mixup with with sub cool at
one point in his males where you know
the space dude wasn't the space dude
anymore and so the seeds that I had
weren't the same seed stock from
previous even though they were you know
labeled and sold as such and so there's
there's stuff like that that even the
the grap stomper OG um some aloha White
Widow stuff that I like I cross to flumo
and the space dog seed stock and a bunch
of stuff and yeah I'd love to get it out
there at this point a lot of it's older
maybe you know eight to 10 years old um
but I've made more recent photo crosses
too it's just I don't know man I don't
want to step on anybody's toes nowadays
you see more and more photo people
coming into the auto world and it's like
all right well if there is this
crossover maybe I will and I do try to
like
people that I look up to and respect and
and and like I try to give them the
proper guidance to do it right as far as
you know stepping in and like the I was
talking to C City earlier I was like
dude you've got an amazing Foundation
now to like use this blue Power Auto
against all your other stuff and do your
own Autoflower line he was like man I
was thinking the same thing but kind of
he has that same mentality of not
wanting to step on any toes and he's
like I was G to ask you about that and
ask for your guidance with some of this
and I was like yeah love to to help in
any way I can because I'm never going to
have the time and space to do all that
anyway and this stuff is phenomenal and
should be made into Autoflower format so
I'd love to to help with that sort of
thing but as far as doing it who knows
maybe one
day you uh you should do it I uh I'd
encourage you to but it's interesting
because you you sort of alluded to this
point that I like which is that there is
sort of this interesting stigma of um um
you know any anyone who photo breeds
they'll make an auto no one bats an I
but to do it the other way it's a little
bit more of a gap to jump isn't it so
that that is interesting now the final
question for me before we jump into some
of the patreon ones it's a doozy but
it's the one I wanted to know probably
the most explain to me how do I convert
my favorite photo period clone into an
auto sure excuse
me so you take your photo period clone
and you get some Auto Rags or if you're
proficient in reversing find auto female
that you
like either way reverse the the photo
onto the auto or the auto onto the photo
or again excuse
me again for the the sour stomper I used
a photo period male onto a female
feminized Autoflower so you can do it
either way it doesn't matter it's all in
in the selection once again but you get
that F1 generation of photo to Auto they
are all going to be 100% of the time
photo period you take those you find the
male and the female that have the traits
of the photo period you cross those
together then you get the F2 Generation
here's where you need to run the big
numbers so
25% give or take of that F2 generation
will be autos and then obviously if it's
a regular seed stock half are going to
be male and half are going to be female
so you run enough that you'll have a
good selection of that 25% of Autos to
pick out an auto mail with the photo
period Trace that you're looking for and
an auto female with the photo period
Trace that you're looking for and you
cross those two autos for fully auto F3
and then from there it's a matter of
whether you want to refine the line more
whether you want to feminize at that
point whatever you want to do um the
other way and I've just just started to
dabble in this way of doing it is trying
to work work the entire project
feminized so that it's that much easier
so that you don't have to do you know a
multiple male selection at any given
stage at any generation where you don't
necessarily know what the male is going
to provide doing it all a feminized
stock and potentially I haven't done
this yet but this is my next
trial trial and error thing to do is
making F1 feminized photo to Autos
growing those out picking the single
best female those that resembles that
clone only selfing that one for the F2
Generation to try to lock in those photo
traits and then in the F2 Generation
picking out the the one or two best
female autos and and sing or
cross-pollinating those and just doing
the whole project feminized so that way
it takes a lot of the guess work out of
it now again I haven't done this yet but
I have set myself up to do this now with
some new feminized photo to Auto crosses
that I'm looking forward to
trying that's that's brilliant and very
comprehensive I I was sort of in my mind
following each step and uh it sounds
like as you said a lot more involved
than regular breeding but very doable um
just probably takes a lot of time
patience and skill I guess my question
then is on that last step right where
you say you've got the F3 and most of
the time people release feminized
Autoflower seeds so I'm guessing you pop
those seeds and you pick one of the
females and you reverse it onto the
others and that's the stock is there any
way of which you can improve your select
cuz I'm assuming in an ideal world
you're going to reverse one of the
better females but you know you don't
it's not like a photo period where you
get to know which ones are the better
ones so is it just like you know the
good the good female would be the pollen
donor if it's not the pollen provider or
pollen recipient or is there any is
there any difference in that situation
of you
found and this is where photo period
readers have it so easy because they
could keep clones and I I don't want to
like again I don't want to Che my own
horn or anything but if I was to enter
the photo period world I do think I
could run circles around some of the the
current readers that are out there um
and again you might want to cut that out
I'm an [ __ ] for even thinking that
but anyway yeah no I always po I always
reverse way more plants than I need I
always pollinate way more plants than I
need and then it really comes down to
after those are harvested smoking each
one and figuring out which seed stock
from those to actually work with moving
forward so like I was saying some of the
bulk guys will just mix them all
together and call it one individual
strain you know what I mean whereas I
will only take one of those plants and
move forward with that seed stock to the
Next Generation and you don't know until
you actually smoke it because the
effects actually matter it's not just
well this one's really pretty so we're
moving forward with this one there's
there is it's way deeper than that so I
always do way more I'm always tossing
out way more plants and seeds and uh
I've got yeah seed stock that'll never
be released for that exact reason is it
just I made it thinking it was going to
be one thing but it didn't live up to my
expectation so it's just it's it's a
nonstarter at this point um but yeah the
the photo period guys definitely have a
nice benefit of being able to keep
clones and going back and then yeah
working back to the same stock over and
over
again yeah certainly I can appreciate
how that would be more challenging
definitely definitely my my final
question there does that mean that you
have to smoke like seeded flour cuz I
always found like it's it's more
difficult for me um to sort of guess the
winner um but I guess it's this fine
balance of making seed and having some
flour to smoke it's it's always
challenging how how do you combat that
one that's it yeah you just smoke the
flower recently got one of those I think
they're called the pollinator over in
like the EU and other places like the
tumbler where you can sift the the the
heads of the tricomes off without you
know destroying obviously I can't blast
seeded flow or whatever so I smoke it I
pick the seeds out and try to leave you
know the actual flower intact as best as
possible without having to smoke seeds
um but yeah I'll do the KE as well I'll
smoke that but that's it yeah it's a
pain in the ass but that's the only way
to do it there's no well I'm gonna smoke
this other plant that's not pollinated
and assume it's the same as the the seed
one you know what I mean like it's just
I smoke seed flower and that's that's
kind of all there is to
it thank you for falling on your sword
uh for all of our
benefit it's just such a funny idea like
smoking seed and flour no one likes to
do it but it's like in this case it's
truly for the greater
good uh okay so I mean the first of the
patreon questions we got some really
good ones the first one from one of our
supporters is wanted to know have you
ever felt like or found what you felt
was sort of the unique turpine that was
sort of brought or associated with the
ruderalis gene at all or do you think
there aren't necessarily unique profiles
associated with
it so I mentioned earlier that that my
older brother and some of his friends
would say you know this tastes like an
autof flow it tastes like an autof
flow I've never had anyone be able to
describe what that tastes like to me and
I've never Associated any individual
flavor with an auto flour a lot of
people even think and have thought for a
long time that all Autos taste the same
and it just couldn't be further from the
truth man there's like so many flavors
out there now that yeah it's just it's
it's it's not a real thing um I've never
actually had any pure
ruderalis um so I can't say whether I've
like tasted a ruderalis turp before um
I've gotten and and online discussions
with Todd McCormack who's like adamantly
against autof flowers saying they suck
and they taste like [ __ ] and they don't
get you high and I just try to as
diplomatically as possible explain to
him that that's not the case anymore and
tell them look I've got stuff I
guarantee you I have flavors that you've
never had before and like I've sent them
seeds before and I'm sure they just went
straight in the garbage but people like
that like my greatest compliment is
photo period purists that are like damn
this is an auto flower that's like
that's the tops for me like when I can
change somebody's mind through the work
that excuse me through the work that
I've done that's like that's the
ultimate compliment for me um but as far
as an actual Autoflower chirp I I I
can't say that I've ever had it speaking
of Rutter Alis this is the hundred year
anniversary of the discovery of ruter
Alis one of the people that grows my
gear is actually related to the person
that found it as an ancestor of the
person that classified it and he reached
out to me I was like dude this is like I
just wanted to let you know it's like
100 years since this happened I was like
oh my God that was like amazing so part
of me wanted to reproduce like a lot of
my old stuff and try to put out a
hundred different varieties of through
through the years of my catalog as like
the hundredy year anniversary thing but
I realized that was way too far-fetched
with all the projects I had going on and
just would have been an insane thing to
try to take on but yeah that's pretty a
pretty cool thing and I do I really want
to to do an Autoflower documentary and
go out and like interview you know joint
doctor and all Dutch Passion and misto
and all the people that have like helped
to create this thing and make it to
where it is today and that's kind of uh
I haven't taken like a a break from
doing this in a decade you know like you
get in the garden and you're on the
garden schedule and that's just kind of
what it is so part of me really wants to
take a break and and dedicate some time
and energy and doing that because I
think it would open a lot of people's
eyes to kind of see how far they've come
and see how much work has actually been
put into them but that's a pipe dream
for now who knows I hope someone smarter
and and more well equipped than I takes
the lead on that and does it and I'd be
more than happy to to help out kind of
give guidance as far as you know from my
perspective who are the right people to
talk to and who have been doing it right
but I think something like that would be
really really cool to to
see I love the idea of the documentary I
mean every think you said was great but
that you're right that sort of
documentary you can really see that
coming to life and being quite a
compelling story overall because you
know there's really not that many
players in it right you can really trace
it quite easily um and there are still
alive right now and it's it's become
such a like big thing where it's not
just for the longest time it was just
Auto flowers or european junk and now
they're worldwide I mean some people say
they're worldwide junk but they're
really just I mean they're they're
awesome they're out there they're
amazing they've come so far like the
sheer amount of progress and evolution
of these plants in the past decade is
unlike anything else that I've ever ever
seen so I don't know I think there's
potential to do something really really
cool and really special with that maybe
now that I put it out there who knows
maybe it'll come to fruition maybe I can
actually take some time off and figure
out how to do
it that would be cool that would be
really really cool uh the next question
we got from one of our listeners was
they wanted to know if you'd ever
considered doing like some land race
style work using some of the land race
autof flowers out there and they just
said oh you know like I don't know like
siberian By Thai or Siberian by Afghan
or whatever it is um would you ever
consider doing that sort of land race
work or do you consider that like those
core building blocks are really
necessary to make a highquality auto and
you know what I mean you it take so long
to go from scratch
no I think that's really intriguing and
I know um I think there's a gentleman I
think his name's like guardian of the
turps or something like that that has a
Siberian land race Auto flower and I
think that would be really cool to see
and I
think I mean there's just the land races
is where it all began and I think
there's um a real there should be a real
concerted effort made to preserve those
to continue to keep those pure and work
with them and I'd love to to be a part
of it but I see myself doing it from
Modern Autoflower stock as opposed to
actually going back to a ruderalis stock
because I feel like I'd be able to
extract the best possible outcome using
stuff that I know and can breed away
from my Autoflower traits and select for
the land race traes but keep the
Autoflower uh characteristic of actually
flowering under 24 hours of light and
man I love the land R stuff like that
that zal Delica Express is my favorite
one of my favorite strains if not my
favorite strain of all time like I I I I
think I improved on the actual zelica
photo period for my taste I like the the
Autoflower version more than I like the
photo period at this point and that's
one that I'm going to work back again I
recently got some um zelica was called
like this scary youo the super trippy
youo some F3 Zod Delica seeds from my
buddy on Instagram so I'm planning on
popping some of those and Crossing to
zelica express back to that working that
out uh same for the Destroyer I feel
like that's a strain that should be put
in Autoflower format I'm really looking
forward to I got some some seeds of that
that you know just aren't around anymore
so I'm looking forward to to doing that
one I'd love to also go back and do some
of the the Pakistani stuff and the
Afghan stuff and really like you know
lock those
in but there's just there's so many
projects and so few of me and so few
hours in in the day and I only I can
only do so much and I hope
to give
a provide the proper show the way to do
it right you know what I mean like don't
have
asset just do it right you know do the
proper
selections and and be in it for
creating something new that you want to
see in the world that's that's better
than what it was before I feel like the
other day I was like what what
businesses what things have gotten
better over the past few years I feel
like almost everything surrounding us
has like been in Decline these past few
years and what I feel like Amazon is the
only thing that's actually gotten better
with time like all right I can get
anything I want shipped to me in two
days now but other than that I feel like
everything else is gotten worse and
prices continue to go up and inflation
keeps happening and it's to the point
where honestly I I I do think I'm going
to have to raise my prices next year
just to continue to stay afloat with
everything else is when I started
selling seeds and 20 15 or whatever $50
then is now $68 in today's market you
know and I'm not charging more per pack
I'm still charging the same and
everything else has gotten way more
expensive so it's like
it is kind of hard to to keep doing it
the way I've been doing it and stay
afloat sometimes but at the end of the
day I'd be doing it again whether the
money was involved or not and I'm G to
continue doing it and I think that
resonates with people and that shows in
their grows with my stuff and and so it
is what it is whether whether I can make
a living doing just this or whether I'm
gonna have to you know swing a hammer or
figure out how to do electrical work
like JJ man nothing but respect and love
to that dude for even posting that you
know what I mean that was like a really
[ __ ] badass thing for him to do and I
was like yeah this is like this is where
we're at right now and again it goes
back to the bul seed companies coming in
and just it's a it's a different Beast
than it was 10 years ago so it's uh it's
trying at times um I know you know I
have a lot of followers on Instagram so
people think I'm some huge company but
it's just me and it it's it's a lot of
work a lot of deck dedication a lot of
Blood Sweat and Tears a lot of risks
taken and that's just I mean it's the
plant is special and it reverberates
with me and and I reverberate with it
and we we we have this this love and
understanding for each other that's
something I've only ever come close to
finding a dog you know what I mean like
just like weird loyalty to each other
where we we we just find each other in
the dark so yeah it's
a I'm sorry I went on a tangent there I
don't even know what what the initial
question was anymore but yeah I love
this and and I'm stoked to be able to do
it so I'm going to keep doing it totally
totally I I was about to say that's
beautiful I think I agree I 100% agree
with every sentiment and and again big
love to JJ for putting that post out
there as you said it's uh it's a bit of
the sign of the times but it's also a
sign of you know his character and
strength and as I said I I myself have
always advocated that people have a day
job and my reason for that beyond
anything else is that I think it allows
you a bit of extra freedom to explore
the weird stuff in counter that maybe
doesn't yield as well or whatever but
it's getting to that point now where as
you said you know it's just the times
are changing but look let's end the
patreon questions with a positive one uh
one that several people asked in one
form or another what would be your
advice for someone who wants to start
breeding autos and I guess the question
would be you know the obvious answer is
get yourself a pack of Autos but I mean
do you think that you need to have a
photo period you want to work with first
do you think get a bunch of exposure to
different Autos first and then figure
out what you want to do what would just
be some general advice for someone who
wants into the get who wants to get into
the world of autos and maybe braiding
them whatever way you want to do it
there's a million ways to skin a cat I
started out with photo to Auto and kind
of that was my path for it was like this
is what I want to to see something new
brought into the world that's never
existed before is an amazing feeling
it's an amazing feat especially when
it's like when you have high standards
for it and when you're I'm I'm
hypercritical of myself so I'm I'm
always trying to outdo myself push the
limits as much as I can and and make
things better I've done tons and tons of
Auto to Auto crosses I've done tons of
photo to autoc crosses there's no wrong
way to get into it whatever you're
passionate about doing
do that whatever whatever speaks to you
um I do
think a lot of people get into the get
get the idea in their head that they're
going to do a photo to Auto and once
they get to the F2 Generation realize
you know maybe I don't have the room to
properly do this to where I'm not going
to be able to pull out from this 25%
that show
Auto the actual things that I was
looking for and they get discouraged but
don't man there's just just keep going
keep pushing forward you know find a
male you like in that first run save the
pollen from that do the next run use
that pollen on a female you like like
there's multiple ways to do it and move
it forward and and do it properly um but
also at this point in time there's
enough photo or enough Auto per uh Auto
periods enough Auto flowers out there
that you can do auto to Auto and create
something completely new um but yeah
really get a pack of Autos just like you
said but now there's there's there's a
ton of ways to do it whatever whatever
speaks to you is the way you should do
it I love that it's it is good to it is
good to know the seed stock you're
working from I always would recommend
you know sink your teeth into the
genetics on one side or the other
whether it's the auto or the photo so
that way you know which traits to select
for or against um but other than that
yeah man it's really just whatever
whatever speaks to
you beautiful beautiful I love that
answer you know just get passionate and
get into it and the path will reveal
itself that's awesome so I think it's
about time we did our quickfire final
five so the first one what's the best or
most memorable experience with cannabis
you've ever
had well honestly I look back I was at a
point in my life at the
time where going to Spain and you know
sleeping on the floor outside of grow
tents and just busting my ass
in Spain was one of the best times of my
life I love that I really felt like a
kinship and a Brotherhood with the guys
of the time in misto and like we really
clicked and were firing on all cylinders
and we're really making a dent in the
progress and the evolution of this plant
and I really do look back super fondly
on that that was like some of my
favorite times and it's one of the the
reasons I really like always will hold
those guys in high regards is because
like that was super special to me I
really truly cherish that
time yeah that's that's brilliant I love
that answer I love that so on the other
end of the spectrum what was one strain
that all your friends had hyped up you
were really excited to try and then when
you did you were a little let
down let me think on that one what have
I been disappointed
by I
really I honestly can't think of one I I
like
weed a lot I really do um I think I one
time got a roadkill skunk from somebody
that now looking back in
retrospect I couldn't even I I couldn't
take more than two hits of The Joint
because it was so [ __ ] gross but I
think now knowing that person's history
and seeing how
they were and insane sociopath wiar I
think they sprayed some skunk spray on
that like some some actual skunk spray
stuff and I smoked some really bad [ __ ]
and I think that was the the one of the
worst experiences with cannabis I ever
had um but speaking of I I did recently
and I think I mentioned this to you
earlier when we were chatting I did get
gifted a roadkill skunk cut that you
know somebody reached out to me through
email three or four times and I just
kind of ignored it it was another skunk
Tail as I like to call it where you know
it had the SWS sorted history and lots
of negativity around it and anyway they
they went on to reach out on Reddit and
a few other places and I finally
responded to him and he was like yeah
man I've been trying to give this to
like CSI and archive and top dog and all
these people and nobody will respond to
me and like I see what you're doing I've
grown your plants they're amazing and
like I know you're an auto guy but would
you would you be interested in taking
this I was like [ __ ] it I got a a pretty
serious quarantine going at the moment
so I wasn't really at risk of anything I
didn't have any like projects going that
could be put at risk if for some reason
I did take in a dirty clone so I took it
in
and the gentleman went on IC mag and
started talking about it and posted
pictures of it and you know the the
internet is full of sleuths and
detectives and people found that the
pictures he were post he was posting
were from somebody else's grow they
weren't the actual plant and then he had
like a whole bunch of stories to try to
cover cover up for that and then he like
thought that I was somehow trying to
take advantage of something or lying
because somebody else reached out to me
with some skunks and said they wanted me
to work their skunks in the auto and
just for the sake of um just so nothing
got Lost in Translation I made a post
saying you know somebody else has these
three guns they're going to send me I
want to make this post here just for
posterity sake that I do have your skunk
and if I do get these other three skunks
I'll have those as well he sent me three
cuting so he was like oh he's trying to
say that this isn't my skunk that he's
getting these free skunks from somebody
else anyway this thread just went like
haywire and he eventually got banned
from IC mag and just because of this one
thread you know he's talking [ __ ] about
all this and so I've been I've just been
letting it veg I just haven't really
done anything with it because I didn't
know how to feel about it and man the I
was just with it a few minutes ago veg
uh but holy [ __ ] if it doesn't smell
like true road kill skunk I don't know
what does I sent out a t-shirt recently
that got picked up by the Postal
Inspector nothing else just a t-shirt
that was in the room with that plant and
that's how strong the smell is was that
you know a shirt got picked up in the
mail because of of this plant so I'm
super stoked to work with this um again
it's got a really kind of interesting
history and I don't know what it really
is it really is I think he says it's a
1988 roadkill skunk that his dad who
passed away had and it's like this
family heirloom thing it came from the
right part of the country um but who who
actually knows what it is but holy [ __ ]
man does that thing smell like true road
kill stun so I'm finally at the point
where I'm like comfortable enough to to
put it into flower and like see what
it's about and yeah go from there and
it's funny because he ended up losing
the cut so I sent it back to him and he
lost it again I sent it back to him
again like I said it's just been in veg
for like six months at this point and
yeah so now he was like man thank you so
much this is like my family heritage
here like the fact that you got this
back to me my my dad was probably
rolling over it his grave when I lost
this so thank you so much and it felt
nice to be able to do that too um but
yeah I'm um super stoked on on this and
I wish I had my road kill scum shirt
that you got on I bought one of those
Duke to and lost it somewhere in my
travels across the country but yeah this
is the first thing that I've had that is
like might be for real the real deal
roadkill skunk and you know I'm hesitant
to even say that because you you know as
well as anybody how how saying that can
even get you you know looked at sideways
so I've kept it under wraps I think I've
posted about it maybe once on on
Instagram but yeah that's something that
man it blew me away the past few weeks
just the smell off it is just absolutely
out of this world he he asked me if I
would self fit and like release the
photo period seeds of it so it's like
out there still he was like this is your
clone like to do whatever you want with
you can give it out but after the post
on IC mag like I I signed up just to
like comment on this dude's thread and
be like yeah he did send it to me
immediately started having people reach
out actually somebody on Instagram
reached out was like are you the dzz
that got this road kill stun from this
dude down south or whatever he like yeah
he's over like talking on a thread about
it right now so I went over and checked
it out timed in on there and that's
where things got sideways with the the
three skunks and so yeah anyway I'm
super stoked to to finally get that into
flower and see if if the smell continues
through flour and then into the the
cured product because man this is like
it might be that missing link that
everybody has been been after for so
long we'll all have to wait and see how
it pans out that that would be really
exciting if it did and and hey if it's
the real deal uh s1's what a way to make
a splash into the photo world I reckon
so um on on to the the next question is
our desert island question you know I'm
going to drop you off on a desert island
you can take three clones or three packs
of seeds what are you going to take with
you to grow for the rest of
time well I I made a stream called
desert I desert Isle that was like one
of my favorite indicas cross one of my
favorites a was that was made with the
intention of like you know if I ever
needed to I could F2 this and then go
from there and pick out like all the
different stuff from both sides that I
wanted to so that would probably be one
of them that's got the Zod Delica
Express in it so that's one I mean
zelica Express would be one if it wasn't
for that strain and knowing that I would
have the ability to dig in and like
refine some stuff from that um yeah I'm
gonna say the the desert aisle desert
aisle strain the probably Cosmic Queen
would be another one just because that
one is so so special and sentimental to
me
and let's see that's a really tough one
I'm um you know for for I've Got What I
Call owl pellets which every seed
Harvest I've ever made I throw some up
into a jar and I sell those as a mystery
mix I might just grab a handful of those
and then toss those in just for for
shits and giggles and you know find what
I find when I find it I love that that's
cool you know you got the time let's
let's have fun with it that's beautiful
so yeah the next question is if you had
to restart the company with just one
pack of your current seeds which pack
would you
pick dude this is my biggest fear I
think about this almost on a weekly
basis of like what would happen I I
there's been times in my life especially
moving across country where I split up
my seed stock into half and I'll send
half and drive with the other half just
in case like something happens or
doesn't make it then you know see each
other at the Finish Line sort of thing
but if I was to to start over with just
one seed
pack
wow zelic Express tends to to be
dominant in crosses so I don't feel like
that would be one that
would I don't think that would be the
one oh man this is a really really tough
question it'd have to be a pack of Auto
EGS just for for the sake of it probably
Wizards Apprentice or or blue microverse
one of those two I'd say um yeah both of
those I'm super confident in I'm I'm
extremely happy with the results of them
I know how they breed I know what I can
pull out of them I know which way to
turn at any given generation with them
so I feel like one of those would would
be it probably the Wizards Apprentice
because it's bigger overall it's got a
little bit Hardy hardier structure to it
um yeah let's go with Wizards
ofenis a great pick a great pick now
final question I've got a time machine
for you you can go anywhere anytime any
place what are you gonna get I'd go with
bod on some of his trips around the
world and see what he's seen you know
what I mean like that dude's lived a
life and I'd love to to to be along for
the ride and I know you asked him that
same question so wherever he was going
I'd be right there with him that's it
that's I can't remember I think he said
he'd go to the Ewok village and smoke
with them which again let's do it um I'm
down so I think that just about brings
us to the end of it any comments
thoughts shout
outs no man I love what you're doing
again I've been a fan for a long long
time uh I've never seen myself in the
same Echelon as the people you have on
the show so I hope I did it justice here
for you um it's truly an honor uh do
have a request I don't know if it's
possible if you could throw the old
theme song at the beginning of this one
that that that birds chirping and just
the it's so Serene and tranquil and man
I just absolutely love that I don't know
if that's even even possible but yeah no
thank you so much for having me on it's
truly been an honor in a treat I'm a big
fan of yours and heavy days you're the
man keep doing what you're doing bro uh
you far too kind and because you asked
so nicely just for you this one we'll do
the old theme song but uh as usual
massive thank you one of the biggest
names in the auto breeding World head of
night our seeds some of the highest
quality autoflow stock you'll find a
massive massive thank you to Daz for
taking the time to come on the show
today my pleasure man huge honor thank
you for everything you do and for
getting the information out there you're
Gathering stories and and information
that wouldn't be out there without you
so what you're doing is truly special
and unique and I I really do appreciate
it
[Music]
and there you have it my friends what
did you think a massive shout out to Daz
for taking the time to come join us chat
about Autos history predictions for the
future and so much
more if you love this episode please
consider supporting both the patreon as
well as the websites of our incredible
sponsors if you looking to transition
from combustion to vaping check out our
good friends at dap you will not be
disappointed cheap affordable and
Incredibly efficient units likewise
check out our friends at Pulse sensors
if you want to make sure that your
garden is dialed in and you are tracking
all of the variables that are going to
ensure your next Harvest is the best to
date you got to get yourself a pulse
guys it's a
no-brainer in order to ensure that your
garden is pest and pathogen free please
check out our friends at copit they are
the number one in bioedit technology of
SPID sper will make sure that your
garden is spidermite free copit thank
you so so so much for your
support likewise a big shout out to our
friends at Organics alive for all the
most incredible powdered organic
products usable in all systems both
organic and hybrid people winning cups
around the globe with their products
it's no surprise because the quality is
second to none a huge thank you to
Organics alive we recommend them highly
please check them out if you want to
take your organic game to the next
level finally massive shout out to our
good friends at seeds here now they got
heavy days beans go check them out guys
I promise you will not be disappointed
they got all the latest drops the
hottest breeders fem Auto photo period
CBD whatever you need they're here to
help you out a massive thank you to our
friends at seeds here
now and big love to the patreon gang we
love you so much thank you for
supporting the show they got Early
Access to this episode over a month ago
if you want to get extra content please
consider supporting the show you'll
score yourself genetics a whole bunch of
swag from our sponsors and so much
more so that just about brings us to the
end of it for this
one a big thank you to you for getting
to the end yet again and for the
support Big Love is always from your boy
heavy
days sign
enough see you
[Music]