[Music]
[Applause]
thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
all right all right all right welcome
back to the podcast your number one
podcast for cannabis enthusiasts as
usual you're joined by your boy heavy
days here from the upside down library
and as always we couldn't make the show
happen without our fantastic sponsors
huge shout out to CT now number one seed
bank in the game you know you love them
they got all the hottest drugs and
they're gonna sort you out satisfaction
guaranteed check them out seats here now
likewise a huge shout out to the topic
biological systems number one choice for
any beneficial predators that you need
to keep the garden happy and healthy
check out the akipagrams or the spider
vital two phenomenal products that are
going to keep bugs at Bay and your
Harvest popping and pest free carpet
biological systems check them out guys
[Music]
furthermore big shout out to The One and
Only Pro mix you know Pro mix they've
been around forever making high quality
mediums you might even be using it right
now but did you know they make a killer
mycorrhizal product pro-mix connect your
number one mycorrhizal product with a
guarantee on the viable spores inside
meaning you're getting amazing value for
money because you know the product works
go grab promix connect your number one
choice last but not least our buddies at
Charlie's cannabis you're after some
high high quality flour hit them up
they've got amazing strains that they
finally hunt themselves using the work
of some fantastic breeders you're after
a high grade product in Oklahoma check
out Charlie's cannabis you will not be
disappointed Charlie's Canada thank you
so much for sponsoring the show
and last but not least the patreon gang
we could not do this without you if you
want to get access to content early if
you want to hear unheard interviews
extra segments and so much more please
consider joining the patreon
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast gives you access to everything
you're after and more you are the
lifeblood of this show we appreciate
your patreon supporters thank you
[Music]
on this episode we're joined by The
Mastermind soul of sulfide genetics here
to talk all things Bahama Mama
black bananas Don Mega
breeding
science trends
so much more
let's get into it
alrighty gang we're back with another
one a big thank you and welcome to the
Maestro sulfide genetics the curator
behind the fire you've undoubtedly been
seeing in your feeds recently a big
thank you to Seoul of sulfide Genex for
joining us today
hey what's up man thanks for having me
not a lot my friend I've been looking
forward to this chat but the first
question we ask yes when they come on
the show what have you been smoking on
recently
uh you know somebody uh sent me some
some banana runs uh
uh hash and I've been smoking that so
lately I've been just smoking a lot of
you know solventless hash I just love
the taste of it so that's really my
go-to
um and yeah yeah the banana runs at
these this uh couple made is really good
so yeah it's kind of almost got like a
Sprite taste to it with like a banana
hint to it it's pretty awesome so that's
what I've been spoken on nice that
sounds undeniably delicious did you find
that the banana runs tended to produce a
range of flavor profiles or they were
more just sort of one parent or the
other
yeah you know the crazy thing is and
it's kind of like an inside joke man is
that when you when you cross runs to
things they almost always come out like
runs dominant especially in the in the
smell category of it like you get some
red structure and then you'll get the
runt smell and I I see that like almost
with all wrench crosses so it's like
when I see all these runs crosses I'm
just like dude you could have just got
one pack of anybody's runts cross and it
would have been you know similar to the
runts but
um about 20 of those at least in the
banana runs uh lean towards that
banana flavor so you'll get like I don't
know we've seen some that are just like
all purple and Frosty and then just
smell like bananas and that's the ones
that I like I mean there's some green
ones that do that as well
um and then there's some that just come
out super like rincey I would say on the
Run side of the things but yeah you're
gonna find that range from like that
runs dominant
kind of Fino all the way to this like
I don't know just like this crop this
just blending of both of them where you
get this purple Frosty banana flavored
Fino that's the ones I love
at about yeah look I mean that sounds
like the winner to me as well right it's
beautiful I guess I was sort of
interested in asking you we sort of
don't see that many breeders working
with the banana OG and I've always
wondered why because it's such a good
cut do you have any theories on maybe
why it's not as commonly used
uh you know I I really don't know so
I've always been like even if you go
back to my first line we were when you
know with the black banana I've always
loved that banana Turf like that
um banana candy flavor so that that's
one of my favorite flavored candies is
like the banana Laffy Taffy so some
people either like love this chirp or
they absolutely hate it so
and that's in like the food world and in
the pot world so but for me I love it in
both so
you know that candy fake banana flavor
it's just something I like I don't know
why more people don't work with it but
you know we kind of go through these
phases right like sometimes it's orange
and it's Tangy and everybody's just
gravitating towards that or sometimes
it's banana and you know people like
like that at a time like I know when
they had that uh it was like a
California Bennett Chiquita banana or
something like that people were loving
it at that point and then it you know
strawberry so we go through phases
yeah ain't that the truth it's all sort
of circular isn't it and you just
reminded me I totally forgot about that
Chiquita banana thing that you were
right it was huge for a minute so that's
some good Insight I guess the other
thing you mentioned was that it was
you're on like the solventless hash
where do you fall on the concentrate
flower sort of divider you more a hash
or more a flower sort of Guy where do
you sit
uh for me I like I like Dash like ever
since I I was really got uh turned on
onto it I just I don't know I love it I
smoked a lot of hash when I was a kid
that wasn't like the hash that we have
nowadays it was just like much different
but um
yeah I really got into it and then the
whole Don Mega line that we did
um just before this Bahama line my whole
focus of that line was hash like I went
out and bought a goddamn uh freeze dryer
and I turned a whole room into a hash
room and I was like you know what I
don't care what anybody wants me to do I
don't care about runs I don't give a
[ __ ] about anything I want to make a
line
that all washes I don't care if they're
pretty I don't I don't care I want to
show that you can breed functionally you
know you can
breed something to to do something
specific and that's what we did I I
hunted down plants that I knew washed I
put it with the dawn which we knew
washed and then I just washed all the
all the whole tests and smoked a bunch
of it and everybody that gets those
those seeds from that down line we're
constantly hearing from them about how
well they wash so it was kind of a fun
thing so yeah I love hash I love the
process of it
um I'm by no means an expert uh I'm I'm
a newbie at best at making hash
don't worry I'm right there with you but
it's it's cool to hear that like that's
sort of how you intentionally did it and
I was sort of wondering that so you sort
of answered the question so thank you
but I guess the next question it makes
me wonder is do you think eventually
we'll get to a point where for a strain
to be commercially viable it has to wash
well even if it's for flower or do you
think there'll just always be a sort of
divide
I don't know you know honestly at least
here in Seattle I don't see a lot of
guys that their whole company is based
around
washing strains I mean there's a couple
of them I know like no mids up here in
like American hash makers and stuff like
that but I think it's and I don't know
I'm not an expert on it but I think that
it's just really hard for them to make
the money on it you know in the store
right because
they got a the store has to put on tack
on their money and then the state tax on
their tax
and by the time they get done that gram
is so expensive the like casual smoker
doesn't want to pay like 80 bucks for a
gram of hash they just don't want to do
it so I just don't know how commercially
viable it is which honestly to me kind
of keeps it cool because it's like it's
more for the heady the heady guys you
know like the real
the real the guys that are really into
those terms
um and the and smoking the very best you
might have to get it from your homeboy
and not go to the store
yeah I get you and that sort of makes
sense it's interesting I've been
wondering about that sort of high and
low end divide but I just want to jump
back to a minute you know you were
talking about the runs and something
that I noticed about that was it seemed
like you hit the market just at that
perfect timing where you know like runs
was really hitting its stride with
consumers and then when you paired it
with say you know all of the other
feminized crosses you made it just made
some phenomenal results my question is
sort of do you feel like you have to
keep your finger on the pulse a bit with
the Canon community and trying to time
these things perfectly so they go off or
is it just a sort of a case of trying to
be in the right place at the right time
um you definitely do you definitely need
to read the crowd right like I don't
know people aren't really into hazes
right now so if you just go try to breed
like a whole line of hazes Because You
Love Haze it might not go over as like
you want it to
um but at the same time you can't just
breed because the names sound cool like
there's a lot of breeders out there that
are just like oh I got this cut and it's
this name and I'm gonna throw it
together with this you know these cool
names and here's some seeds for you to
buy that's definitely not how we do
things over here
um you know you have like our
I the way we do things is I could bring
that clone that cut in if somebody's
like if a homie's like oh this is
you know Soul you got to check this out
this is awesome okay I hear you give it
to me let me grow it let me see if I
really feel like it's gonna work in this
lineup it might be awesome and not work
for this lineup and I don't give a [ __ ]
what the name of it is
I could care less if everybody's talking
about it and it's awesome if it's not
going to work for this light like if it
wouldn't have worked for that that wash
line up even though it has an awesome
name it's out of here you know so you
have to use some of your own judgment on
what you're trying to accomplish in your
project and that should Trump the names
of of the uh of the strings that you're
trying to put together but
um I think we did you know we we were
one of the first people I think to to do
a wrench cross and I think that banana
wrench really you know caught people's
attention
um and then I know
my homeboy exotic right after I right
after he saw the runts uh the banana
runs he is like he reversed it and did a
whole lineup you know he reversed it and
put it to all of his strains
um for a whole runs lineup and that
thing went crazy people loved it and
then after after those two things after
you saw the banana runs and then Mike's
big runs drop just everybody who was
doing the ranch crosses and now they're
just I think people are almost over it
yeah it certainly had a good run the old
runs hasn't it but I guess the follow-up
question for me is given that you're one
for one with your predictions on runs
what do you think is going to be the
next big flavor to hit the scene
I mean you tell me man I have absolutely
hopefully it's the Bahama Mama I don't
know I I have absolutely no idea
um and I'm waiting on it like in our
circles we talk about that kind of stuff
right like what's gonna be the next like
big hit like a GMO or like like a runs
or you know because we want to catch
that that new one that's tight and get
it in the stable and grow it and see if
the hype is real but you know I don't
know Gary Payton seems to be floating
around and and uh We've grown it I think
it's awesome
um
yeah it's just really hard to say which
which way the is gonna go
yeah for sure it's a bit unpredictable
like that isn't it to to loop back a bit
uh we actually did some breeder awards
for the year just gone by and as it
turns out both James bean and myself who
sort of do the awards each year we uh we
both voted you as the sort of
breakthrough breeder of the year which I
guess not so much about like your first
year obviously but the year where we
feel like from a commercial perspective
things are really sort of taking off so
I guess first of all congrats on that
but the question is sort of did you
expect things to really gain so much
momentum over the past few years and in
the last year have you felt like you've
really sort of had an upswing in terms
of popularity and people growing your
work
um well first I mean awesome thanks for
you know recognizing recognizing me I
really appreciate that that's huge you
know like uh the opinions appears as
huge for me uh in the game but um no I
you know
I I don't know I don't really
concentrate on on that on the on the
popular it's really not about me very
much it's or or or anything like it's
just the company you know and and what
what we can do like um I talked to I try
to answer every DM which I probably
shouldn't say that because people are
going to be dming me all their questions
like but uh we try to answer every
DM every question and I try to comment
on anybody like if I see somebody that's
growing soulfire
um and I'm tagged in that in that
picture I will I will stop by make a
comment on there and I just try to
interact with absolutely everybody and
we've done that since you know 2015 so
um I think after you it once having that
rapport with people that you actually
give a [ __ ]
um
it's it starts to you know resonate with
them like oh you know so far actually
cares
uh what we're growing in
for me I'm all about the guys that are
in the trenches you know what I mean I'm
making these strains for the guys that
are in the trenches not really the guys
that are like in big commercial grows
and warehouses and and you know for the
recreational Market it's cool when they
grow my stuff don't get me wrong I I
like that too but
I'm really here for the guy that's like
growing pot in his garage or growing it
in a tent and blowing out the block and
stinking up the neighborhood that's you
know that's who I'm here for I like to
comment on their pictures I like to see
what they're doing
so yeah I think that it's starting to
build I think they see that like you
know we test our work
um we put a lot of thought into
what we put together
and and that that can show in the in the
end result and nobody can guarantee you
like you're never gonna have a Herm or
or nobody can guarantee like you're
gonna have the best results ever no but
if I can
if I can somehow
make you make it make you a little bit
more confident in what you see or and
what you're gonna get or or lower that
chance that you're going to have a Herm
or a problem
um that's what that's what it's all
about or if I can you know help you talk
to you and help you that's what it's all
about and I think that's you know that's
a driving force I think that's helping
build our popularity given a [ __ ] yeah
for sure I think that sort of customer
service really goes a long way and a
testament to the brand image you want to
maintain so while we're on the topic of
customer service let's say you got one
of those sneaky DMS and it's someone who
says you know pretty new to Growing I
like your stuff which one strain would
you recommend and I guess the question
sort of comes down to like without
knowing too much about a person's
interest what strain do you feel you
could really get behind and recommend to
most people
well you know when someone I get that
question all the time so when they when
somebody asks me that question I
I have to hit him with a barrage of
questions what kind of flavors do you
like how much room are we working with I
mean if we're in a you know we're in a
small space Maybe regs aren't what you
want maybe Femmes are what you want what
kind of flavor profiles do we look up
here are we looking for gas are we
looking for fruit you know uh
I I I'll have to ask him a bunch of
different questions before I can kind of
tailor something for them
um to grow and have success with because
ultimately what I want to see is them
have a successful grow and um you know
put their pictures up on Instagram so I
could be like damn you crushed it bro
look at that it looks like some heat so
yeah it's it's a it's a hard question to
answer like a lot of people ask me in
this uh this Bahama line well which is
the best one which all these pictures
look so so dope uh so far which is the
best one well it's hard to say what's
the best one because
if you like gas maybe this is the one
for you but if you like fruit maybe this
one or if you're looking for weight that
one might be the one for you so it's
really it's really different you know I
love them all that's why I chose them
for this this lineup
yeah and look totally understandable
right all of the new Bahama Mama lines
are just looking so incredibly Frosty I
I easily put them in the hype train
worthy category and that I'm I'm excited
to see them and to see how they do it
makes me wonder what was it about the
Bahama Mama itself that stood out to you
or made you think let's do a line with
this let's blow it up
well when I saw it when I saw the guys
at Rugged Roots growing it and those
guys were amazing Growers over there in
Maine right so when I saw them growing
and I was like dude what that thing is
black and it has crazy Leaf to flower
ratio right and as we were talking about
earlier I'm not a huge fan of trimming
like I got better [ __ ] to do it's one of
the least favorite things to do so if we
can get a leaf to Fan Ratio or a leaf to
flower ratio that's favorable
I'm all for that so first I saw the
structure the color the frost
they were nice enough to give it to me
and when I got it I was like okay we're
gonna grow this thing out
you know because
you gotta stick to the plan anything
that comes in it doesn't matter how
tight it looked when you were growing it
I'm gonna have to grow it assess it
smoke it and then decide if it's worthy
um did that and I was just like oh my
God this is [ __ ] amazing look at this
thing it's so Frosty it's you know it
looks like you could literally I'm not
I'm in line dude it looks like you could
go up with a like a little dab tool and
just scrape that [ __ ] off and smoke it
so yeah so I was just like okay uh this
is awesome I just killed it you know I
just crushed this but let me give it to
like a couple homeboys and let's see
them grow it they grow it hit me up so
far
this [ __ ] is crazy right here boom so
now we're kind of have a consensus like
all right this thing's awesome
so I think that's
um
how it got chose you know I mean we
looked through probably
over a thousand different Bahama Mamas
over from the time it was released
because we knew the first time we made
Bahama Mama we're like this thing is
awesome you know this strain is cool
like it
it dumps you know it's great for hash
it's
um beautiful colors but in so many of
them and it's not that it's a bad thing
but because that chopped cookies in
there we're getting that Tangy smell in
a lot of them right so
that's that's great but in what I wanted
to use for this lineup I didn't want
that Tangy smell and the rugged cut did
not have the Tangy smell it had like a
vanilla icing Hawaiian Punch hard candy
kind of smell completely devoid of
orange Citrus so and that was another
factor I was just like okay you know now
we got something unique we got the color
we got the structure we got the the leaf
to flower uh ratio that's insane the
weight was great I washed it because you
know when I I was going through my my I
want to wash everything hash phase and
you know even for a noob like me to wash
it and they came back like 5.5 or
whatever and that was me just taking the
best of the best too so not like full
spec or whatever so yeah it was awesome
and
yeah that's I think that's how the
decision came down on that yeah it makes
sense why you picked it I mean if people
haven't seen the photos please get over
to sulfi's Instagram check it out it's a
no-brainer but
I sort of hear this sentiment at times
that a lot of the Cannabis community in
terms of like The Connoisseur cannabis
Community they complain about you know
being burnt out on that Tangy turp in
general but then I also realized that
there's this huge part of the market
especially the more sort of casual
smokers who definitely don't share this
opinion and it makes me wonder do you
think it's better to cater to the
greatest number of customers or do you
feel like you have some obligation to
sort of the hardcore heads
um
well for me I mean again this is kind of
like a personal thing I love the Tangy
don't do not get it misconstrued you'll
see a lot of our crosses have that that
drop in it because I love that I love
smoking it I love the extracts that it
makes I love it
um I just didn't want it for this
because I feel like there's already that
in the market you know what I mean like
you can go get that from Trump if you
want it right like it's out there so I
wanted to do something different and
yeah that's and the only way I could do
it is if it wasn't present and it took a
long time to find something that is
present but do I feel like loyalty to
um any one group when I'm doing my
breeding now I'm
casual or hardcore heady guys no I'm
just trying to make the very best that I
possibly can make and
and you know
bring it to the market at a price point
that anybody can
afford to grow us you know back to that
like I love the guys in the tents I love
the home the home grower that's breaking
it off in their backyard in in their
garage or or just out in the sun
um and
yeah so I just try to keep it
keep it accessible for everybody I guess
yeah I think there's huge value in that
and I you know obviously being in
Australia I'm one of those people who's
like not burnt out on Tropicana cookies
at all so I'm totally in the same boat
as you love it I think it's amazing I
guess it makes me wonder then how would
you describe the uh the rugged mountain
cut itself is it very drop heavy leaning
or does it bring some other sorts of
flavors and turps to the table
so it the
how to explain it is it grows similar
kind of to Trop but I feel like it's
heavier
um and it's just jet black and it comes
on kind of late so like when I was
growing I was like I don't know man you
know like I don't think this is going to
be very heavy and I don't I don't know
if it's going to be very colorful and
then we're like pulling into like week
five and boom the color show starts it
starts going like like sunset orange
Frosty Madness and then from there it
just goes to jet black so it's it's just
really cool
um and then like yeah flavor wise it's
just it's like this vanilla it's like a
vanilla icing
Hawaiian fruit terp kind of like a
fruity pebbly terp it's weird
and that's another thing I didn't want
the
flavor of that to overpower everything
in the in the lineup right so like
when I choose the the one that's the
other side of it right the the other
part of the cross I want that to kind of
shine because I choose some of those for
their their flavors and I want some of
that to shine through and sometimes if
you choose something that's just too
dominant then now it's like the runs
thing right runts beautiful beautiful
plant does excellent crosses breeds very
well
but makes everything taste like rice I
didn't want that yeah sure it does bring
this topic to mind for me which is that
a lot of the Casual consumers out there
as I'm sure you're aware they're
obsessed with like the idea of exotic
you know everything's got to be exotic
for them to want to have it and to me it
raises this fundamental question what is
exotic like what makes a strain exotic
and I'd be interested in your
perspective on that
I don't know I really don't
hey it's irritating that oh exotic but I
what I think it is is one it has to be
it has to be an amazing strain right it
has to almost be kind of known worldwide
but not able to be
obtained so it has to have some sort of
like really hard to get because once
everybody gets it is it exotic no it's
not now it's mundane so it has to be
hard to obtain well known and it has to
be absolutely amazing that's the three
things it has to be to be exotic
yeah that's a that's a good criteria you
know I've heard a lot of different
answers and it's interesting that
there's no consensus on it you know I
think it was compound who we had on not
too long ago and he sort of said some
many similar things to you except he
also said oh I also think it's got to be
purple to some extent which I think was
an interesting sort of Tibet and I guess
your work sort of fills that criteria
anyway
um yeah but I mean are we saying that we
can't have an exotic strain that's like
green I mean I guess we're just not in
favor right now and I understand what
he's saying that it needs to have some
color to be
exotic but
um I've seen some of the banana runs
fenos that are green and are absolutely
exotic you know what I mean like when
you pop that jar up and you smell it and
you look at how Frosty it is whoa so I
don't know if that if I agree completely
that the colored part of it
yeah no I definitely get yeah and then I
can't remember who it was but someone
else thread an interesting answer I
think it might have even been Masonic
but someone was like what about like
Acapulco Gold you know like that is that
like that's sort of exotic just by
virtue of how hard it is to get but I
digress so we could go down a whole
rabbit hole with that one
um yeah but but I mean speaking of
exotic you notably have a have a pretty
good friendship with exotic mic as far
as I know how did that all come about
yeah I mean we go all the way back to
like Community College so
um we've been buddies since way before I
mean I would say it's like brothers so
we we go all the way back
um before exotic genetics the company
and and
soulfire or any of that I mean we go
we go back to uh Community College uh we
met in uh
pre-cal math class and uh and we used to
take trips down to Humboldt to uh see my
uncle who's a farmer down there uh for
obvious reasons uh back in back in the
day we used to make that run back and
forth and we've just been friends for a
long time man he's a good dude
yeah what an organic sort of connection
you guys had and it you got me
interested now what were sort of some of
the old school strains you were smoking
on back in the day when you were doing
those trips
well back then we were doing it we were
like
oh at least that like we would go to
school and then we would come back and
we would watch like uh uh sub cool in
his old uh in his YouTube uh channel
right yeah yeah yeah so we were really
into like TGA sub cool back then so we
were like smoking the flave and
um
and like a bunch of different different
stuff I know I was growing up uh some
cool Crazy Train
uh a lot of train wreck was floating
around back then
um yeah yeah I think the first award
that that Mike won like I had was it it
was a great God I had the
it was Grape God crossed with the flave
and I want to say so it was my Grape God
selection and he took a flave male
crossed that and won his first High
Times here in Seattle I think he got
like second place or whatever it was
exciting you know what I mean it was
like one of my selections one of his
selections and it was the first time
like he won some [ __ ] and that [ __ ] was
so exciting I think that really kicked
off
everything yeah wow I mean before we
move on I want to quickly ask you out of
personal curiosity because I I too used
to watch a ton of the weed nerd and you
know big up subcool we miss you
um the question is what's your favorite
TGA strain you know I I just when you
mentioned the Flav it it brought all
these memories to mind because there's
some TGO strains where you hear a lot
about them like Chernobyl and space
queen but other ones like the Flav have
got like a bit of a cult following so
I'm curious to hear what was your
favorite TGO strain
uh I think it was that like Mike had a
really good cut of the flave like we
loved growing it it grew like these eggs
all over it and then it just like these
egg-shaped nugs all over it and it just
had a crazy smell like I was talking to
him like a month or two ago and I was
like bro we need that where who has that
[ __ ] cut like where's that where's
our flave cut at we just don't got it
anymore but
um
that I loved the Crazy Train just
because the colors that it put out you
know like the smell wasn't it was like
kind of more of an earthy smell but the
color show that that thing would put on
um and the frost for like even back then
was like ahead of its time so yeah I
think those were my two favorites yeah
solid picks solid picks and just to
follow up on another thing relating to
Exotic Mike I think it was James Bean
who told me that uh you had been sort of
one of the influential people who had
sort of helped get Mike on board with
Femmes is that true
yeah so I mean he had uh tried a few
times I mean he had used different
sprays that are on the market and he'd
done um different things and they just
weren't working they were like burning
up his plants and they yeah they just
weren't working so I just
you know I got a background in science I
I put my my head in it and I you know I
kind of came up with my own little
recipe and yeah I
I made it and then I I reversed uh I
made that banana runt and then
he kind of helped me get the timing down
because my timing wasn't very good like
I was a little bit off and you know my
community was like man you know you got
it like this your reversals are amazing
and I was like tight you know so I
showed you know I helped him to do that
and then he's like yeah but we got to
get this timing right and that's
something about Mike that
you know he's a really focused in on
what he's doing so he was able to like
focus in and really tune our timing down
so that we could we can nail it so
um yeah I I definitely helped him uh
learn how to make Femmes and I pushed
him in that direction
um to make friends because I felt like
the you know exotic genetics company was
missing that portion of it and I I want
to see all my homeboys
um succeed there's nothing more I want
to see than than uh everybody at the
table if anybody knows me I want to see
all my my people uh do well so I was
pushing him on that I was like look man
you're just gonna have to make some
fence and finally he was like all right
I'll do it and um and he really helped
me get that timing correct so I
appreciate him for that yeah brilliant
and that's that's a question we get
regularly from listeners is like what's
the optimal time to pollinate your
Harvest I remember back in the day the
subcool actually was he would always say
like I think that you want the females
to sort of get hit by the pole and
around sort of end of week three week
four sort of thing where do you fall on
that one
yeah I think that's a that's that's
about right like we're weak
yeah end of week three like so what are
we talking about like day 28-ish
yeah like right around there I think is
the best I mean it needs to be like nice
cotton balls everywhere if you do that
if you do it too early you're just gonna
cheat yourself you're just not going to
get um as many seeds as you you could so
you gotta watch it um and I've learned a
lesson on that
jumping the gun a little bit too early
on that but yeah so you want to have
really nice nice cotton balls for it so
timing is key especially timing with
your with your family creation you have
your timing right yeah definitely I
think I've one of those people have been
burnt before and you end up with like
100 seats or something and you're like
what happened there yeah that could
happen so I mean on the topic of
feminized work or you know obviously you
do a mixture of both regular and
feminized work and I'm sort of wondering
do you have any preference and as a
follow-up do you think it's easier to
make a good feminized cross than it is
to make a good regular cross
[Music]
um
I don't know if that's quite true I
think
from the selection standpoint it is a
little bit easier to make a good
feminized cross because you're looking
at that female plant you already know
what it's gonna do you know what I mean
like well not what it's going to do but
you know what you're looking at so
you're looking at it you're like oh man
it's got beautiful color it's got frost
it's got all these different things
um that's a little bit harder to see in
a male plant right like you select
differently with the male criteria I
mean some guys select for like Frosty
meal plans some guys have a bunch of
different ways they select male plants
like stem rub all those different things
do you really need that when you're when
you're reversing a already known like
Banger probably not
so yeah it might be easier
um but then again I mean you're going to
need to grow out all those Femmes
because
uh people's people seem to say that that
Femmes have this reputation for her
being easier I don't really see that I
think that's kind of Bro Science really
I I've popped a bunch of guys regular
rag seeds that hurt them all over the
place
so you know I don't know
yeah I mean you you just answered the
next question for me so thanks for that
and as a follow-up sometimes you hear
breeders say that they feel using a
mother that comes from Femme stock is
like a bad practice if you're gonna make
seeds do you do you also have a similar
point of view where you think that's
maybe not true
yeah I don't know I I don't know that
it's
uh true or not true I mean I guess
that's part of the problem with
um where we're at in like cannabis
breeding because a lot of it is just
anecdotal right it's like oh well this
happened to me this one time so this
must be the science and me kind of
coming from like a science background
um
I just don't go unless it's proven I
just don't go for it you know so hard to
say I mean there's guys that reverse
Femmes all the time and use them in
their
in their stuff so uh hard to say
yeah so and I guess just as a bit of a
far out question would you ever consider
making like S2s or something like that
if you found a killer say Bahama Mama S1
um I mean I would I would be open to try
it it would just have to have to make it
through the rigorous testing you know
like we have to see what that with the
progeny would do would they come out all
weird I don't know
yeah I I guess so right I mean you're
stacking a lot of jeans on top of each
other right yeah it'd be interesting if
you could somehow get some sort of like
ABC or freak Show sort of expression out
of doing that
dude that freak Show thing looks crazy
yeah it's interesting isn't it I mean
you you've got me you know on this freak
Show train now so I'm gonna ask the
question I look at plants like that and
I'm sort of like this is cool and I see
the value in it but I also don't see the
commercial value in it what's your
thoughts on those weird sorts of strains
um for me it's not I mean that
particular one isn't something that I
would breed with or I would grow so I
agree with you there it's not it's
interesting
I'll give you that it's it's interesting
I'll just that's that's about that but
um like uh we bred with with uh the
creature from from bee Leaf over there
he sent the cover we grew that out
that's a weird plant
um it just like makes these fingers a
super Frosty uh so it was a little bit
odd an odd plant but it wasn't like that
where like I don't even know what the
freak Show really is is that a mutant
I've never grown it I haven't seen it
grown personally so I've only seen
pictures
yeah I think it's like a a weird hybrid
of Big Sur Hollywood and banana OG of
all things so yeah it's pretty weird in
genetics in it
weird I didn't even know that yeah there
you go okay well take me back to the
start what was your first experience
with cannabis
I mean the the very start goes back to
my my uncle from Humble like just being
a little kid and just walking into his
uh his girl room and being blinded so I
mean I guess I've had a a relationship
with it since I could walk but
um
I think in high school like in the
middle of high school you know just
oh [ __ ] even before that I guess I was
I would steal my my uh my cousin's car
when we were 13 and go to Yakima and buy
um Mexican brickweed ounces and smoke
with all the all the homies back in the
early early 90s
so I guess there and then
um Midway through high school I was I
mean I live in a I live in West Seattle
White Center area it's kind of like the
shitty neighborhood of of Seattle and
back then when we were kids I didn't
have any money we didn't have [ __ ] so I
was
I was like a water a water boy for uh uh
you know grow house here so I mean I got
I got a real intimate
relationship with at least taking care
of plants I guess that was like
94 94 95 Maybe
so yeah I mean [ __ ] man we didn't have
filters we didn't have any of that dude
it was just like the whole block would
just reek
it was it was crazy but yeah so
um that and then with breeding like
those guys that I was watering those
plants were they were like older guys
you know like I was wearing those
password they were doing some breeding
back then
um
and then like near the end of high
school I would we live really close to
Canada so back then
um we would drive up to Canada
and you could go to these coffee shops
where you could go in the coffee shop
you could roll up joints and they sold
seeds there right so we would go there
and I would just buy all kinds of seeds
enjoy smoking weed inside in a coffee
shop like I thought that was the coolest
[ __ ] right and uh
then I would smuggle all the seeds back
and we would pop all these different
seeds and go through the Finos and stuff
stuff I guess that's kind of where it
started
yeah wow is that sort of like the mark
Emery days of it all yeah yeah that was
definitely the mark every days yeah yeah
wow that's cool that you got to
experience that and you referenced that
you know some of the the more senior
guys when you were younger were toying
around with breeding do you happen to
remember what they were working with by
any chance
uh I mean everything back then was like
um
like skunks and like Northern Lights and
just I mean I thought that the part that
we were growing back then was amazing if
we saw it today I'd probably be like oh
but
um yeah I don't know I mean they were
they were making all kinds of things it
was it was a wild time
um
and just super illegal right like back
then it wasn't
romanticized as much as it is now like
where
nowadays in Seattle your neighbors don't
give a [ __ ] they don't everybody is pro
pot well back then it wasn't that like
it was a
it was a operation so uh it was a good
learning experience I mean I learned a
lot
watering those plants and listening to
those guys and a lot of those guys now
are are in the industry today in the
legal industry here and uh
in Washington so it's cool to see them
move forward yeah definitely it's always
good to see the people who sort of lay
the groundwork initially getting some
recognition for that if we fast forward
a little bit when did you decide to get
your first sort of grow going in terms
of like it's yours you're running it
selecting the genetics and whatnot how
did that occur
oh I mean we've been growing
we've been growing since
96 at
for different reasons and
from then on so always I mean I I feel
like
growing
is almost therapeutic for me you know
what I mean it's like church it's it's
where I go sometimes to think it's where
I go sometimes to just get away from
people
um and sometimes where I go to you know
to have to talk with the homies or or
whatever so I don't think that
I'll ever no I have a grow and and
growing goes back all the way before you
know before 2000 for me so
um
yeah yeah
it holds a it holds a place in my heart
I guess I think I'm gonna steal that
line from now and growing is like church
for me I like that a lot
yeah it is I'm not very religious myself
uh I'm pretty agnostic but uh but
there's there's some sort of
religious connection from a spiritual
connection I guess for me with with
growing if if I didn't if I didn't make
a dollar from it I'd still be doing it
every day
yeah for sure and I mean you sort of
raise an interesting point when you say
that you know even if I didn't make a
dollar from it I'd still do it it sort
of makes me think about the trajectory
of someone who's looking to craft
themselves out a position in the
industry maybe as a breeder maybe as a
just a grower and having a brand but
obviously at some point everyone starts
off where they are getting paid a dollar
for it and they're just sort of doing it
for themselves what might be some advice
you'd give to someone who wants to you
know sort of do things in the right way
and not just you know sort of cut
corners or whatever what's your advice
for a newbie breeder or brand
well I don't worry about the money you
know what I mean like don't don't do it
for the dollars man because there's
other [ __ ] you could do you can make
better money you know
um yeah at least if you're doing it
right I mean you see me I we don't drop
a strain every day or every week you
don't hear a new strain from me every
week yeah that's because the [ __ ] takes
time and if you're doing it right and
you're testing you're growing everything
out the proper way and you're really
um doing it the proper way in my opinion
there's no real proper way right you do
whatever you want but this is the way I
do it we just are able to drop a strain
every every five minutes like that [ __ ]
takes time so
um and time is money right so
you know don't do it for the money you
do it because you love doing it and then
that should it'll show in your work you
know if you do it if you're doing it
because you love doing it because you
absolutely
enjoy doing it
we're gonna see that you know we're
gonna see that in your crosses and you
might be surprised we might love it too
yeah that's some great information and
you gave me a brilliant segue right
there and I remember you know Chad I was
having with James Bean last year he was
telling me that you had a release sort
of scheduled to go live but sort of as
it was getting close to the date you
decided to pull the plug because you
sort of weren't happy with some of the
results you were seeing and it raises
the question you know what's it like to
have to make that call you know and how
does it feel to have done that and what
many would say is probably the honorable
thing if that's how you feel While
others in the industry you know have
sort of knowingly dropped strains that
are just horrible you know and I mean
the one that everyone's probably
thinking of is it Candy Rain from the
cookie fam you know like they don't give
a [ __ ] about that like so what was it
like to have to make that call and how
does it feel when you see that other
breeders don't do that sort of thing
when maybe they should for me it was
absolutely easy easy
call to make like you know we looked at
it and we're just like
and that was that was a Don Mega across
there's a bunch of crosses in that and
we're just like you know what maybe with
this mail the mail that we used which
was awesome what we thought was awesome
now we're just seeing too much too many
problems so in some of the in some of
the crosses so we're like we're gonna
back up we're gonna just hold back then
I mean the money's not that important
the money's definitely not worth my
reputation and the money's not worth
um people having all kinds of issues all
over the place like nah that's not what
we're about so we just pulled back off
that and then and we went and then we
went at that
um with a different Focus you know and
then that's when that when we made the
the line with uh the washing in mind we
came at it with a different mail and
then tested all that stuff again and we
didn't see those problems so we're like
boom we found it you know
yeah again just emphasizing you know I
feel like that's a very honorable thing
to do which you don't really hear a lot
about and it makes me wonder what is
unacceptable and there's this
hypothetical I've been giving to guests
on the show because I think it's an
interesting sort of moral dilemma let's
just say you've got a seed line and like
half of the seeds Herm right so a very
high percentage like 50 but the 50 that
don't hurt is the most fire thing you've
ever seen or created what do you do with
that line
well obviously you probably should work
it some more even if it's even if it's
super fire but you know what you could
the one thing you could do is be honest
about that and and tell people like hey
this is what it is you know uh uh get it
at at your own risk or or you could go
back to the drawing board and rework
that or you can take some of those ones
that you found in there and work work
from there out
um there's a bunch of different things
you can do rather than just drop the
[ __ ] like 50 that are actually harms
like intersects from the bottom to the
top yeah that's a that's a problem I
mean
I I get some guys that will say you know
hey this like things harm for a bunch of
different reasons right like sometimes
if it's just on like the lower like you
see some stuff on the lowers that could
be a bunch of different things like one
guy could get a plant and it'll pop out
some nuts on the bottom and another guy
get the same plant and grow it just fine
so
you know there's a difference between
problems in your grow room and problems
with your Tech versus problems with the
genetics if you got a if you if you're
testing some seed 50 of those seeds have
full-blown herbs I don't give a [ __ ]
what the other 50 look like you need to
probably start over
yeah and you raise a brilliant point
there sort of about honesty like is it
you just be up front just be honest
about it like this is what you're gonna
get and it further segues into this
discussion about do we need to test
seeds even because we've sort of entered
this new domain of breeding where you've
got some breeders like Masonic for
example where he's just open like I
don't test my seats straight up don't
test them and then it makes you wonder
is it better to be honest or is it
better to test
dude that is exactly why I [ __ ] with
Masonic so strong I love that guy you
know what I mean I I get people I did a
cross um
uh I did a collab with Masonic
um I used his papaya God and with my Don
Mega and my Don Mega cross right and I
got guys in my DM talking [ __ ] to me
because I use masonic's um work and I
you know I don't even get into it with
them but here's the thing about Masonic
the guy has never lied to you
he's never he's told you the truth from
day [ __ ] one he told you straight up
I'm gonna take everything I'm gonna
cross Wilson with it
and that's what it is and you know I was
listening to him one time he was like
you know you can go buy seeds from some
breeders that they do all this testing
and they do all this stuff or you can
you can get these right here you know
that that we made and you can get these
deals on them and I just I don't know
man I just support the honesty and the
openness that that he brings to the
table and furthermore when I popped that
uh that papaya God and I grew it out
that [ __ ] was tight straight up that's
why it made it into the line for no
other reason it was a banger and we see
pictures of people that grow out the uh
the Don Magic Wand all the time that
that found it to be heat so Props to
Masonic I agree he's he's an interesting
character very polarizing but the thing
which I find most interesting is exactly
what you said there's like people like
to hide on it but it's really hard to
point to anything ethically so to speak
bad that he's done because as you said
it's been it's been so upfront you know
yeah I mean he he's never lied to you
like that's all I gotta say like hate on
him if you don't like his personality or
you don't like it his trolling that's
you man but the guy in the at least in
the breeding from the breeding
standpoint he's been up front and he's
been
um honest with what he's doing the
entire time so
yeah yeah it's funny likewise I had a
lot of people in my DMs and even
publicly you know really upset we had
him on the show and you know this whole
get real breeders on the show and I'm
just I always just thought he's opening
a store in like Fairfax like he's
obviously doing something right like
don't you feel like you've got something
you could possibly learn from him yeah I
I don't get it like I said I I have
popped a bunch of breeders uh I'm not
gonna out anybody or whatever but I pop
anybody in the game that's somebody I've
popped their gear and I've grown it
and I just like that I mean I we met at
uh at the Denver show he was like yo so
far here's all these seeds and I was
like bro this is so many seeds I can't
pop all these seeds tell me which one of
these is a banger and I will pop that
pack he's like these ones right here
these ones are a banger I said tight I'm
popping these when I get home just like
I said when I got when I got off the
plane I got home I put out all my
different seeds because I always collect
seeds don't think that just I'm buying
seeds all the time I get seeds from
everybody so I his winning in the in the
group to get popped and when we were
going through it I was just like this
[ __ ] is tight like the smell was tight
the frost was tight everything was like
it just came together man and I was like
and there's a few of them right like
there's a couple Keepers so I was like
yeah this is some heat period That's why
I made it in the lineup no other reason
and it shows in the like the progeny
with that dawn like it crossed really
well it washed awesome like yeah so yeah
he also referenced that that one when
we're interviewing human he said it's a
banger so that's good to hear but if we
take a step back and look at the mail
we've spoken about it a few times the
Don Mega it in itself was you know what
I consider to be a pretty successful
commercial release what was it about the
Don Mega that stood out to you and how
would you describe the Terps and sort of
flavors it brings to crosses
well
you know that that came around like it
so it's a GMO cross so you know right
off the bat you're going to get those
funky terms but it was a little bit
different it was kind of like a funky
gem sock corpse plant
nasty funky terp like you got to kind of
be into it and then um
the commercial guys like the
the wreck Growers really liked it
because you're getting this funky terp
you're getting a high THC uh test score
you know most of the the keepers are
testing around 30 30 plus and
they're just weighing super heavy and
they're finishing before 65. so that's
kind of like a trifecta for those guys
you know what I mean the guys that want
to make money
um and they have like these this like
little box criteria that they need to
stay in to be able to hit these numbers
for their investors or just to stay open
in a market that's overly taxed and
overly regulated
um
they they love it yeah so and it washes
so and I think you know that comes from
the GMO and probably
um the Black Banana I have in that
blackberry kush in the background which
is also a good washer so yeah it just
checked a lot of boxes for people
commercially I think that's why it was
really popular
it's I hey if you're like a home grower
it might not be the one for you because
that thing gets so tall and gnarly
uh you know if ceiling height is like a
a thing for you then and the
vigorousness of it too it'll it'll
overshadow other [ __ ] in your garden so
uh it'll just crowd them out
yeah okay I mean would you have a
specific cross you might recommend that
has the Don Mega in it that is maybe a
little more sort of indoor tameable or
would you just say stay away from the
f2s because that's sort of the more
vigorous lanky one you referenced yeah
the F2 super vigorous
um but like the the happy hour is a
great one I mean um uh the Scorpion crew
those guys out of Spain they've won uh
they've won some competitions with that
and extract uh it's got a nice
strawberry with that raunchy turp it
stays a little bit shorter you know
that's a really good one so if I was
gonna do uh if I wanted to Don megacross
and something indoors that's probably
what I would go with
nice and I mean as we wrap up on the Dom
Mega quickly I'm just wondering will we
will we see it show its head again or
are you just sort of always moving
forwards
um I like to I like to move forward
sometimes if something's like really
popular and people are just like hey we
need come on do something bring it back
then you know we'll consider it but I
think part of like going back to that
when we're talking about Exotics I think
it's cool for things to go extinct right
like the banana runs uh we're probably
gonna let that run its course and be
done at some you know
um because
then when you have that pack in your
Vault and we're not making it anymore
it's 16 it's done
um that value goes up kind of like a
baseball card and I think that's part of
the culture with seeds and I think that
is what makes it cool seeds are not
going to be as cool if there's huge
companies making so many of them it's
like
you know
celery and watermelon seeds or whatever
that you can buy at Home Depot they're
never going to run out so it's going to
be the exact same
that is boring to me
so I think it's much cooler if things
become rare or or gems that you just
can't find anymore
yeah definitely I definitely feel that's
got some value to it and before we move
on too much I did want to actually
quickly ask you you referenced the happy
hour the strawberry jelly that that
grabbed my attention because you can
find so little information on it I think
it might be one of Mike's strains can
you give us any backstory on that one at
all
yeah so the strawberry jelly actually is
a is a cut it's a cut a mimosa it's a
very unique cut at the most so where if
you've grown Mimosa it kind of has like
a citrusy orange
smell generally but this one did not and
um it was given to Mike at a show uh by
a guy named pure Mel and
uh
Mike recognized it right off the bat he
was like oh this is this might be
something because he just had the flower
you know and then Paramount brought uh
Mike the cut and Mike gave it to me and
he was like Hey man
grow this out I was like all right just
like anything else that comes into our
crew [ __ ] gots to be grown out right
it's the number one rule
comes in I grow it out I'm growing it
with a bunch of different stuff you know
I got I got some cap stuff in there I
got I got the creme de mint from Mike in
there which was kicking ass like just
doing amazing
um and then I had this strawberry plant
and it was wild I I remember I was like
it was day 52 finished
Frosty as hell uh green this is a green
plant it's more on the green side of
everything right kind of like a little
bit of pink on the under leaves but
overall green
um
and just super like dense
and frosty but what the real kicker like
the what grabs you is the super fake
artificial strawberry smell it's never
smelled anything like it and I've I've
grown Strawberry Cough I've grown a
bunch of different strawberry crosses
all over the place and I called him up
and I was like yo ax what's up he's like
what's up I said the strawberry plant
this is the real deal this is it it's
awesome and uh yeah he and he grew it in
his facility and boom he made
strawberries and cream a bunch of
different uh strawberry crosses all
bangers like look at his red pop line
with that heaters so
yeah that's a that's a cool little
backstory on that I guess yeah I
wouldn't have expected that out of
mimosa everything I've seen was like
what you mentioned so orange dominant
but sort of you touched on the idea of
you know testing stuff and it we've seen
a bit of a move in the past few years
from breeders having uh like public
testers and admittedly you know
sometimes getting a bit frustrated
because you you know you don't get back
all the reviews and the grow reports
that you're hoping to get to sort of
more of an in-house testing format how
do you test things and do you like to
have external testers or do you just
keep it in-house
uh we just do it in-house right now but
uh I'm thinking about well here's what
I'll say about it nothing's better than
you doing it yourself
because when I test something myself one
uh I can talk about it to people so if
somebody if somebody hits you up and
you've used all these different testers
and they hit you up on Instagram they're
like hey uh how does the hoodie dough
grow well you don't know how the hodi
dough grows because your testers know
how it grows so that for me is
problematic right off the bat the fact
that you can't talk about your own
strains
um I know guys do it for whatever
reasons and it just bugs me personally
so I have to be able to be able to have
a long drawn out conversation about
exactly how it grows what the phenols
look like that I found how they smell
everything I can tell you everything
about my strains because I grew them
before you did not a tester
nobody else I grew them before I ever
thought about selling them to you so we
can have whatever discussion you want to
have about the plant and I can hopefully
give you an informed answer I I should
be able to because I've seen it
um I mean that said though I we kind of
want to open up a
a testing program at soulfire we put an
application on our website
um for to take in some testers maybe
like 30 but they have to be amazing like
when I look at your picks they have to
be that dope that you can be accepted so
it'd be a high bar and then those things
that they test
um
would probably I'm thinking about just
doing it with one line right and then
taking these applications
picking say 30 testers and then dropping
a line and calling it you know and
labeling it Community tested and maybe
they'll have a different price point
like a little bit lower because
obviously I'm not doing that work which
is vital
um and just trying that one time not an
all the time thing but maybe one time
have this community tested
line drop I think that would be cool as
like an interaction thing but outside of
that nah I'm testing everything myself
yeah it makes sense for a variety of
reasons and especially for getting you
know high quality photos of the end
result and that's something which I
think you along with a few other people
really excel at and if there's anything
we've learned from our chats with James
Bean in the past it's the good photos
sell packs so I guess I'm sort of
wondering how much Focus do you place on
getting good photos and what sort of a
setup do you use to get these photos are
you using like a DSL like a high-end
sort of camera or just like good quality
phone
I just use my iPhone
I use my iPhone to take the uh the
pictures when I do you know I'll just go
into like 4K mode or whatever and just
snap a picture
and and that's really it and you know
yeah I have a DSL camera and I bought
like this badass DSL camera and macro
lenses and all this [ __ ] but honestly
there's so many different settings on
there and like different
apertures and f-stops and it's like I
need to go back to college to take
another course on how to use this damn
camera and then when I take the pictures
with the camera they don't come out any
better than my iPhone so yeah I just
stick to the iPhone
yeah I mean it's sort of like good and
bad we're at that point like it's good
that you can just use your iPhone but it
sucks that anyone who's got really good
cameras it might not be given them that
much better results and I I do want to
touch on your days at University but I
just want to squeeze in one question
first which is sort of related to the
photos we've seen a lot of people
getting a lot of photos taken down by
Instagram and some people even having
their Pages banned and I guess what's
sort of more notable is that this is
occurring even in the case where like
like yourself your legal business
operating in a legal State just doesn't
really make a lot of sense do you think
this is a problem with as a community
have to sort of address somehow and what
do you think might be a solution
first of all it sucks and a lot of it is
Guy competition and guys telling on each
other
um
for whatever reason and and that part of
it is I'm not going to get me started
out that part of it's despicable but I
think until there's like some federal
legislation
this is going to keep happening and why
is it going to keep happening because
Instagram wants to get paid right I mean
let's just be real that's what it's all
about like they're not getting paid on
cannabis guys marketing their stuff
um on Instagram they can't sell you
little ads they can't legally help you
sell seeds so you know they're trying to
bully us I mean that's basically what it
is until they
are able to make their money because
Instagram's not free right I mean we it
social media has been around long enough
just because they let you use that app
nothing's free like your time your data
uh what you look at them using the
algorithm to track you all that stuff is
is how they get paid for that app and
it's kind of like a free ride for
cannabis guys right they don't get any
money from us so until they do I think
we're going to be in for this you know
the persecution
yeah great point and do you think that
you know we see the rise of alternative
social media platforms Focus for
cannabis users do you think they'll take
off or do you think ultimately Instagram
will just change its rules and try to
become profitable office
I think ultimately Instagram will change
his rules and try to become profitable
of us I've popped into some of those I
popped into burners like Social Club
thing when it was up and instantly
popped right out because there was some
crazy [ __ ] on there
um
so you know I commend him for trying you
know for trying to uh to make a
different way because he was obviously
sick of having his account taken down
but I think he probably wasn't really
ready for how much like you have to do
to have one of those apps up and and
police it properly but
um yeah I think we're just stuck with
Instagram for now I don't see a way out
but I will say I did pop over to
calculator's um Bean basement so he's
kind of brought back that like forums
thing and uh you know I just kind of
lurked through there and was reading
some of the the grow journals and
whatnot and I thought that was it was
pretty cool you know like I read um uh
one of the guys that grew a banana runs
I saw banana restaurant I was like okay
let me check this guy's Journal out and
his journal was so detailed from like
they they do it from the the start of
the seed pop all the way to the end of
the plant so I don't know I thought that
was kind of cool you know not that's
obviously not Instagram where
everybody's there and like liking and
but much more like
intimate with the the whole grow process
and you know if
yeah if you're into that kind of thing
you should pop over and check that
because I thought it was pretty cool
yeah hugely I mean I guess we don't
really see a lot of like dedicated grow
journals and with the very nature of
like the the feed that just flies by
it's sort of hard to do it on Instagram
in a sense but yeah it's cool and I mean
I guess it makes me wonder you know do
you think those forums will ever take
off or it's more of a side thing for
like the the hard cause
nah it's the side thing for the hard
course I think
here's where I think things are going to
go and I think everything's gonna go to
Discord
we have a we have a big Discord
following
um right now I mean not big I guess we
got like a thousand guys or something
um
I know Masonic has his own Discord but
yeah uh
Discord is where it's at because we can
do all those things we're auctioning
packs of seeds in there we're actually
you know things that are hard to get
from myself and from other breeders
um
and we're able to give you that
one-on-one like you can ask questions
directly to me or to other team members
there's moderators in there making sure
it's you know there's nobody in there
saying things they shouldn't or posting
things they shouldn't and I just think
like
if you're in this game right now you
should be looking to to move your people
also to Discord because if your
Instagram goes down at least you have
your community there
yeah hugely everyone go go jump on the
Discord for sure I'm gonna have to join
as well yeah you should I mean we're
giving away we do huge I stopped doing
the giveaway like we do a lot of
giveaways on Instagram
um I stopped doing those on Instagram I
just do them in Discord now we try to do
like a giveaway every week where you
just interact with the little Emoji you
see the giveaway there and then it it
just randomly picks who wins and then we
congratulate them and we have like you
know we could see we could do the image
you know we put up your images or
um you can show your grows you can ask
all kinds of questions if you have a
plant problem you take a picture of the
plant put it up guys are right there you
know to assist I mean it's it's pretty
awesome so it's kind of like a mix of
like almost like Instagram forums and
like
chat all together it's it's pretty cool
yeah that you know what that's an
interesting prediction and that's that's
cool to hear so I mean let's just jump
back a bit you you mentioned how you had
your first grow going and you're growing
things like TGA and whatnot I'm
wondering at that time before you had
really got the ball rolling on your own
breedings were there any specific
breeders who you sort of really looked
up to or who you felt you learned the
ropes from
well
I mean obviously I I learned a lot from
from watching those TGA videos and then
the homeboys from here in White Center
um growing up I mean they didn't know
what they were doing at all they were
just doing things just for seed like
there's no money in it there wasn't no
reason to do it except for ourselves and
then uh and then just Mike you know like
being around Mike
um while he was taken off like he
started exotic and I went to University
um and just being around that uh the
entire time like a lot of times we joke
that our style of growing I watched a
lot of kung fu movies as like a kid
um and it's almost like a Kung Fu style
you know there's a bunch of different
ways to grow a pot there's a bunch of
different ways to do things and that
doesn't none of them are are wrong per
se but in our crew we have a specific
style that we grow and yeah and it's
cool to be part of that it's cool though
to be in a group of individuals that you
know I mean Mike's got a big facility
now I know he he uses uh trellis and
[ __ ] to but I know he misses staking up
all those [ __ ] plants because that's
part of our that's part of our our style
like staking up everything you see it in
our pictures a lot we use bamboo steaks
um yeah so yeah I think being around him
being around I mean he's a giant in the
game like you can't deny him so
um just all the things I've learned from
him and and the people around us I think
really shaped it
yeah great answer great answer and you
sort of referenced it in some prior
answers but I'd love to know a little
more you know like you went to
University and you did a bachelor of
genetics how do you feel like that's
impacted on your growing and your
breeding do you think it's sort of
beneficial and something you might
recommend others sort of look into if
they're interested
uh yeah so I went to the University of
Washington here in Seattle I mean it's a
it's an amazing
um public uh University it's one of the
best in science like it's number one in
for Family Medicine so uh it's Top Notch
as far as as far as universities go in
my opinion go dogs
um
I graduated with my bachelor's of
science
I don't I wouldn't say that it like
really helped my breathing like a whole
bunch so what it did is it gave me like
a way to think
um it rounded me out for sure like as a
as a person
uh I feel like being in those groups and
and working through problems and failing
failing [ __ ] ochem
um and going back and like doing it
again you know
um it just it it really brings that that
resolve to the table like you're not
gonna quit you're gonna you're gonna do
this [ __ ] regardless I mean dude I'm I'm
just a a kid from the hood man from a
broke ass part of a town you know just
raised by my by my mom Brothers in the
[ __ ] in the joint
and I got I have kids too so I wanted to
show them like
hey man you know
I if I can do this you can do this if I
can pass oh Cam you can you can
definitely pass ocam if I can pass a
genome you can do it and um
I don't know I just loved it I loved
learning that stuff I don't think that
it help helps me be a better breeder
except it helps me to solve problems not
quit and just like really stick to like
a protocol
um I guess that's what I learned in the
lab I worked under I think some of the
most Brilliant Minds
um in plant biology like uh I worked in
a in a plant lab with this professor
Taco uh this Japanese guy from uh the
University of Washington he was just so
smart like we were doing tissue culture
and like what hopefully I can talk about
this I'm sure they already released
their paper but they were
um working on the Circadian clocks of
arabidopsis and able to to make them uh
better pollinators or get pollinated
better by moths and it was just super
interesting you know like like what they
were doing in there so I got to learn a
lot there I know the lady above us was
like even doing cooler stuff like she
was
genetically engineering plans to be able
to have stomas on the bottoms of the
leaves like add them or remove them
which I mean that's I mean think about
that like you can make a plant not lose
water as quickly and could like you
could grow maybe corn and like a much
more arid area or desert or something
and they wouldn't die so I don't know
it's just I love the university I loved
my time there uh I'm proud of myself for
for graduating and sticking it out and
when people ask me like
you know should I go there I'm I want to
get into cannabis should I go there I
always say you should just go there
because of the experience and and
what you learn about yourself and about
how working with other people and
and you know how science works you know
I love physics too and yeah I just love
the whole thing really yeah that's so
awesome to hear I'm glad you felt like
it was it was beneficial and likewise
encourage everyone you know get amongst
to get yourself a Bachelor of Science if
you're into it it sort of makes me
wonder how does it feel to have this
sort of very formal scientific
background and yet to be on Instagram at
times and you know you look at other
Growers and you sometimes see some
Highly Questionable slash maybe even
pseudoscience about maybe growing or
just in general you know do you just
have to sort of ignore it at times or
what's your take
yeah I gotta bite my tongue sometimes
like I just I don't like the Bro Science
you know what I mean where because you
saw something maybe happen one time in
your garden that does not make it a
scientific fact that's actually like you
know I just it it irritates me but I
just leave it to what it is I mean we're
all
doing the best we can it's this is
mostly a game of of selection it's it's
a lot of art to it
um
you know and the scientists really
haven't got in the game yet and I'm a
little nervous for when they do
um so right now this is more akin to
breeding dogs than it is to
you know genetically engineering a plant
to be the very best plant on the planet
which they can do so
you know I don't know it's it's an art
to me more than it's like this hardcore
science
um where people are
people are paying for the art people are
paying for your eye for your selection
and then for your your work making sure
that that your your selection and your
eye comes through
so I look at these guys more or less
artists than I do as scientists so yeah
look you you raised a brilliant
discussion there in that you know like
fundamentally do you think the braiding
is more of an art than a science in the
sense that do you think one day we'll be
able to like program a computer to be
like a better breeder than a human or do
you think it'll always have a sort of an
element of like that feeling you get
when an experienced breeder like looks
at a certain planet is like that's the
one
yeah I think it's I think it's art and
you know maybe a computer maybe the
crisper will come into play at some
point but
um not right now I think it's I think
it's completely art like uh even in this
last in this Bahama Mama lineup I did a
a collab with a a local graffiti artist
um the name creature panic and he I
didn't even know the guy you know I just
anytime I walk outside my house uh in in
West Seattle White Center we got a lot
of graffiti around here uh I always see
this like squiggly bear graffiti and
it's [ __ ] everywhere you know what I
mean like it's on a fence it's on an
overpass it's up on science it's
everywhere right and to the point where
like when I'm driving around or when the
homies or with my kids or something like
oh there there you go there's another
another bear there's another bear over
there so I tracked the guy down on
Instagram I found some other graffiti
artist I was like who the hell is this
who is this who is this they finally I
finally found them and uh I hit him up
and I was like hey man you wanna you
want to do some uh a box art collab I
was like I really enjoy your the bear
that I see everywhere you know it kind
of [ __ ] makes me happy when I see it
for whatever weird reason and he was
like hell yeah let's do this so
um he did the box art and then we we uh
have a sticker for that's in there of
that bear and you know if you get that
strain
um uh this month I don't even know how
many of them we saw quite a bit I'm
gonna buy a a can of spray paint for him
for every box that we sell so and I'm
gonna pull up in my truck and give them
this pallet of spray paint so he could
[ __ ] Seattle up so uh you know and and
the reason I did that is because in that
box of seeds you get
two pieces of art from Seattle you get
the soulfire art which is in my seeds
and you get that little that that
graffiti art from Creature panic and
that's just because I feel like you know
it's breeding and graffiti are just two
subcultures
of of Seattle or of of American art you
know
uh breeding in
and graffiti it's just it's just two
forms of Art
yeah look thanks for bringing that up
because I was going to ask about that so
you you saved me the effort and that's
really cool to hear that you're you know
collaborating with other artists even in
a sort of less than conventional sense
and I was hoping to ask you do you have
any other of these sort of more
interesting slightly left of filled
co-labs like you know shoe collabs like
stuff like that or even just the more
standard ones breed a breed of collabs
what can we expect in the future
yeah well I love doing I love working
with other breeders
um you know if if it's tight you know I
I love um doing that and definitely
gonna have some more
uh collabs that are outside of the realm
of cannabis um
I just don't know exactly what they are
yet I mean they they got a fit with what
we're doing and they got to have a
purpose in it it just really worked well
with creature panic because um you know
These Guys these graffiti guys man
they're going out there and they hang
their ass on the on the line
um and they don't get anything for it
they do it for the culture man you know
they do it for they do it for the love
of the [ __ ] and that's why I do what I
do too I I do it because I love it and
so I recognize that and I loved his work
so I had I had to track him down and get
down with it so yeah that's awesome and
a cool backstory so fill me in when did
sofa as a brand officially start what
was the first sort of project you did
where you were like it's time to launch
it ah that was the Black Banana I think
we was like 250 2015 2016 right there
um back then we could still go to shows
so we were just doing the whole show
circuit just shaking hands uh you know
picked up an award out in Michigan I
love Michigan props to the Mitten I love
that state a lot of The Growers out
there great concentrates out there too
um and that was it and that's really
what launched it and it was like just
people loved the the line that's where
the Don Mega came from the the work was
all very very stable and uh it just kind
of took off from there you know like I
said just talking to absolutely
everybody who
who grew our grow strains
yeah and I noticed the brand has like
the slogan arise with the Phoenix and
it's called slogan you don't see a lot
of brands with slogan what does that
sort of mean to you and where did the
name soulfire itself come from
um so soulfire kind of came from uh Mike
and I had a glass shop in in Seattle so
we were selling like uh bongs and [ __ ]
for a while there and that was the name
of our our glass shop and it just kind
of stuck with me I came up with it for
the glass shop and then and then the
slogan which wasn't part of the glass
shop
um
it uh it just kind of
the Phoenix you know represents rebirth
anyway and what better of an icon
um than that for like a seed company
right because every one of those seeds
is potential every one of those seeds is
rebirth so that's where the Phoenix part
of it came from and the rise of the
Phoenix is just kind of like you know
our ethos I mean that's just kind of how
we think like you're you're right we
want you to rise we want you to do well
our whole
goal is to see you crush it nothing
makes me happier than to have somebody
hop in the DM show me their plant and be
like Soul fire look at this crazy [ __ ] I
just grew and then I you know I love
that [ __ ] I basically live for it so
um and that's Rising with the Phoenix
man every time I see that uh or see
people happy because of the genetics
you're growing that's that's where that
came from I Love It
yeah that's that's so cool to know that
you had like this glass shop and that
it's all sort of even further
intertwined back with Mike than what at
least I previously knew oh dude it was a
nightmare man the glass shop was like in
the uh so like I said our neighborhood
right here White Center is a rough
neighborhood as far as Seattle goes
right
um it's just a nightmare man like people
were [ __ ] breaking in we're having
all these problems eventually we had to
shut it down man they just can't let you
have nice [ __ ] but uh it was a it was a
fun time definitely back in the day
yeah that's cool and I mean I'm sure you
are smoking lots of cool stuff back in
the day are there any old school cuts
that you have particularly fond memories
of maybe ones you can't get access to
anymore and and if so what's some of the
ones you would love to get back
yeah I mean well obviously the Flav like
we missed that we had a a grape God that
smelled like it was very similar to how
that Str you know that strawberry jelly
is where it had like this fake grape
smell I feel like I'm constantly
searching for like a fake grape
um I'm you know I I think I have some uh
bloomco's um
grape cream or something like that I'm
gonna pop some of those or whatever's
grape something I'm gonna pop some of
those and go through uh some of his work
because I see a lot of his stuff it
looks interesting
um
that and blueberry like we used to have
this blueberry cut that would it was a
super it was like a [ __ ] to root can't
seem to ever get a that blueberry smell
or it's just not that popular anymore
right but I used to like it so I guess
that if I had to answer yeah nice look
is that does that happen to be the one
that Mike used a few times or he had
some crosses where it was like old
blueberry and that you don't really see
it anymore is that maybe related
yeah that is the cut like he he had a
really we had a really good blueberry
back in the day and I know he used it in
some of his crosses like in the early
Works
um
and yeah and it's just gone I mean
that's kind of like the story right like
we have these
sometimes amazing cuts that we wish we
still had like that that flave and the
Grape God and
yeah there's a lot of them really yeah
wow that's really cool that's really
cool to hear so I'm Keen to chat about
some of your releases that have come out
but before we do that I want to quickly
glance to the Future For a Moment what's
on the horizon for soulfire what's the
next big project you're looking to sink
your teeth into
um well I've I've already kind of
started to formulate uh the next project
but I don't want to talk about it too
much yet until we're
until we're there so
um I think maybe that Community uh
testing that Community project I think
that might be something coming up where
if I can iron it out uh I'd like to do
something like that because I have so
much fun testing our stuff it would be
fun to do like some sort of interactive
like where we send them out to our our
few testers and they
they run them down but again it it
wouldn't be like something that we do
all the time or I I just don't know so
um
yeah a community test project that that
would be fun
um yeah I don't know we got a lot of
stuff coming really just takes time it
takes we just people say the whole time
when's your next drop or when when is
that new stuff going to come or banks
are like where's the drops at bro I'm
just like hey don't don't rush it man
because we don't do it like that you
know yeah sure okay well look if we go
back I was looking at the banana fire
cookies from Relentless genetics that
you used initially to do the black
banana cookies
and I was sort of curious as to what was
it about those genetics that Drew you to
it initially and thought you know let's
make a line using this
yeah it was awesome I mean it just it
had that banana smell to it but it had
the cookie structure and I'm just drawn
to that like we were talking about that
banana smell early and
um I was like I like this you know and I
I you know I loved it and I I hit him up
and I asked permission
um to use it you know and he said go
ahead so uh
yeah yeah I I just it just checked all
the boxes
and then
uh I went through all the progeny I grew
out all the Prodigy before I landed on
that the the Black Banana so there was
quite a bit of
um
I would say testing and second guessing
and OCD perfectionism that tends to
mire me down sometimes
some things that may be awesome to some
people will just get thrown out by me
like oh no I don't like it but but it
was actually awesome
you know so that's just a personal
problem
yeah look the problem I think many of us
have faced before when you when you bred
the f2s of the Black Banana was there
any specific traits you were looking to
sort of hone in on
yeah I was trying to narrow it to try to
bring that the jeans down a little bit
and narrow it and also
um because I was using you know a stream
from Relentless I didn't want to release
the F ones I still have all the f1s from
that
um so I wanted to
have it be my own you know a step
further in my own selection
so that's why
you can only get black banana F2 you
you'll never get the F1
and is that sort of like a concept do
you think you'll use going forward or
more just in this case it was the
appropriate thing
uh just in this case because you know I
used his work even though he gave
permission I didn't want to just take
his mail and cross it with you know and
then release it now I wanted to take it
the next step of of my own selection
sure so I mean when you're looking to
select a male for the next generation of
breeding are there any particular traits
that you look for or think are you know
sort of synonymous with a good quality
mail
uh yeah there's a bunch of different I
mean I have a checklist of things I go
through on a male and before it's like
the one so it's really
uh there's just a lot of different
things you know the leaf structure the
way the plants lining up you know I've
heard some guys talk about reversing a
male to see what it looks like I've
never done that personally but I want to
I think it'd be interesting to do
yeah that I think that would be hugely
cool wouldn't it
um so I mean it sort of gets us to this
place where we normally ask the Growers
about what style of growing they do but
you're so very transparent on your
Instagram about it it's probably easily
known by most people listening but for
the sake of it if anyone hasn't checked
out your Instagram what style of growing
do you utilize and uh do you have any
tips on you know how people can get the
best results out of growing your
Australians
uh okay so for me and this is you know
kind of going back to our our style we
use
um we use pro-mix HP for the medium it's
kind of like an inert dirt right it's
like a soil that doesn't really have
nutrients or anything like that it's
like kind of a peat based
uh with a little bit of perlite and
stuff in there so
um I don't add it it just comes like
that
um so I love that medium one because
it's not too water locky it doesn't it
lets me get that water in get the
nutrients in and it just doesn't hold
the water for too long so it allows me
to pound them
um if I need to so
um I use that and then size a pot it
just varies depending on what I'm trying
to do
um I like to give my plant structure
mistakes so like in my pictures you may
notice that I I use bamboo Stakes which
is can be a [ __ ] when we're talking
about hundreds of plants but uh that's
how that's how I like to do it
um
than as far as nutrients I use House and
Garden I've used House and Garden for
ever so I'm over a decade there
amazing newts I I think it makes uh I'll
see a guy grow with something else and
I'll be like dude why don't you just go
ahead and use House and Garden here's
how I use it and how I use it is exactly
how they have on the um on their little
feed scale so I don't go aggressive but
uh I just use the housing Garden I use
uh the aquaflakes with my for the a b
part of it
um
and this last run the guys from Power SI
or whatever they sent me some and I saw
the hype around and I was like you know
I'll give it a shot the [ __ ] was amazing
like I didn't have to bring in those
bamboo Stakes till way later in the game
um and I I really saw a benefit from
using it a lot of times guys will send
me products I'll give them a shot and I
just don't see any change you know what
I mean so no I'm not gonna use that I
like to use things that I see a direct
change
um
and in house with House and Garden you
can you can see that like when you hit
week six and you use their shooting
powder I tell guys this all the time you
use your shooting powder you go in your
room the next day you see a change like
a marked change so um yeah I can't say
say enough good things about House and
Garden and uh I really like the power or
Si I think is how you say it
um other than that this was my first run
with LEDs really impressed uh with the
LEDs I might never go back
um that's about it man that's
comprehensive and I tell you what you've
now got me wondering is it power SI or
what would the alternative be like power
C
oh I don't know I mean
it's it's I mean they're using the
periodic table for silica right so is it
do you just call it power silica I don't
know but great guys I mean they they uh
sent me so they're hitting me up and
they're like hey you want to give this a
shot I was like yeah they sent it it
took me a long time to um to use it
because I was like making seeds so I
didn't want to use it well as we could
see it's because there's really nothing
to to show or see or whatever so
they didn't like hit me up like hey are
you using that stuff or if they didn't
bug me or anything and then uh that I
told him I was like you know what I'm
gonna I'm gonna use it for this test so
just stay tuned and we'll see you know
we'll see how it is
um I know uh my buddy Miss Jackson Co I
I saw him using it I saw uh cush Forest
over in Boston using it and I was just
like yeah man let's go let's go for it
and I like it I like it yeah nice nice
and I mean an ongoing discussion we have
on the show is organic and non-organic
do you feel like the style of growing
you use ultimately affects the end
product in the way that it's sometimes
made out I know that like I'm a die-hard
sort of Organics guy but I also
recognize that at like the very Pinnacle
I it can get hard to to see the
difference though I I like organic I
guess at the end of the day do you feel
like if you grow a well-grown product it
makes a difference or do you think
there's like a bit of bias from people
um I think there's I think as long as
you as long as you have a well-grown
product I think you're good
um I think people bring in their own
biases if you've ever went to like a
grow store or whatever and like waited
in line and like four or five different
people will give you different advice on
what is the best thing in the world to
use right so I you know it's to each
their own there's a bunch of different
ways to get to the finish line there's a
that doesn't make any one of them the
right way or the wrong way it's like
we're all from different uh we're all
from different dojos we're all from
different styles right we all have our
style you may have the crouching tiger
style I might have the Crane style
um it doesn't it doesn't change it one
bit I I've smoked organic and I I
thought it was tight and I definitely
like mine so
um it could be
yeah everybody has their own biases I
guess
yeah sure and I mean it makes sense
makes sense
so if we move now on to some of your
work I mean many of your Australians are
very interesting for a variety of
reasons so the first one that grabbed my
eye was the green which you use the Lil
value OG and I guess I was particularly
interested in the Little Valley oh gee
I'd never heard of it before is there
any backstory on it and what's it sort
of like on its own
yeah so the Little Valley OG came to me
from
um my homeboy Duke over in Yakima so
Yakima is a small town over on the uh
the east side of Washington so
Washington is kind of divided by this
mountain range where over in Seattle on
the western side it's kind of rainy and
more I don't know North Westy and then
on oh on the other side of that mountain
range is more like desert and hot over
there right so anyway my my homeboy
lives over there and he's always telling
me about this this uh OG plant they got
over there and I was like okay and then
he he had came over to our side for for
a night we were playing dominoes and
[ __ ] and uh I smoke some and I smelled
some and I was like oh that is like old
school like OG like that [ __ ] is tight
go ahead and bring me three of those
things I need to grow them out dude my
homeboy's name is Duke he's like okay I
got you I got you so he brings him over
I grow them out and it's like it's got
that structure that stick and ball OG
structure and then that just that smell
and I was like this is gas like this is
real gas and they didn't really know
what it was you know they don't they
just know it was like the OG that they
love so we just called it Little Valley
OG because it didn't really have a name
and they're from a little Valley over
there in in Yakima
um
so shout out to the 509 and Yakima Duke
and and to the Little Valley OG which is
one of the gaseous strains I've probably
ever come across
nice I like that I mean there's I think
everyone has a few ogs that they've
tried throughout history and they're
like if only I knew which one that was
right like they're so like they're
mysterious but like these guys over
there in that area they like that flavor
profile
um much more than like fruit and [ __ ]
like I saw I got them some packs of like
uh Trump cookies maybe back in the day
and they're like yeah we don't like this
[ __ ] it smells like perfume like where's
the OG at you know just old school
gangsters I said they don't want those
they want that they want that virgin gas
yeah okay well musty mojito that's
another interesting strain where you use
the Grim bastard OG as the male in it
and I I guess you know seeing as we're
sort of discussing it where does OG fit
in the Arsenal for you you know like are
you a big fan of the gas and do you like
to breed with OG
um I do I mean I am a fan of the gas I I
think we're kind of it's kind of getting
harder to find as we get all these poly
hybrids especially with like this like
everything crossed with gelato which I
don't know if anybody's tired of it I'm
kind of I try to limit it you know like
if you look at this line there's not a
whole lot of that whenever we whenever
we sit down to create a lineup we try to
make it diverse you know like if you
look at any of them there'll be a little
bit of gas we'll maybe try to slip a
lemon in there we'll try to slip some
different fruits in there we try
to make the menu diverse because who
wants to sit down at a restaurant and
there's just nothing but meatloaf like
okay like Meatloaf's good one day but
not all the days so or maybe no days
depending if you don't like me though
um
so I like to keep that menu diverse
maybe there'll be a gas maybe there'll
be uh you know
age gelato but not the whole damn thing
um yeah I think that's kind of the
direction something for everybody you
know yeah sure and I now this train I
wanted to flag was you've worked with
the northern fire cookies which one that
comes from a body of the show The
Northern fires shout out to him what is
it about this cut that you like and how
would you describe some of the hybrids
you've made with it like the I'm going
to pronounce it wrong but is it the NF
sheesh
oh you gotta you gotta say it right and
if she
yeah uh the end of sheesh came out
awesome like that thing is so Frosty and
that's why I love using um the north
Fire's cut uh shout out to North fire
man he's a he's a great grower and you
know we appreciate him let's use that
strain so
um yeah it's just a banger man like it
has beautiful structure it washes very
well
um it's it's got a good smell on it and
it breeds well like you know caps I
think Captain was that the El Norte with
it
um we've done a couple with it it's and
it really I think with the Bahama
together yeah I mean it is so Frosty
like if you look at some of those
pictures it is crazy
so yeah it came out well yeah nice I
might just try to bang off some of the
ones that I was personally curious so
just get them all done in one segment
but the the Mando was another
interesting cross because it used a
mother called Yoder and you had me
wondering is that related to the the
baby Yoda we see from compound genetics
and if not what is it
yeah so that's another one like that we
just don't know
um so it's an unknown like that got
slipped out of a out of a warehouse or
out of a wreck in in La I can't really
say a bunch about you know where it came
from uh per se but no he just was like
Hey grow this out it's it's gassy you
know super gas you got to grow this out
so I got it back to Seattle
I uh I grew it out because he doesn't
know [ __ ] and I'm definitely not it it's
just in the pool of things until it
makes the cut to even go to the next
phase
um it's nothing so and when I grew it
out I was like oh yeah this is tight you
know like this is gas it I love the
frost on I love the structure of it
um it kind of had like this
almost like
oh the Mando crosses had like this
gray blue tint to them which I found
like really cool I didn't see a bunch of
those in the females but I did see a
couple that were like this blue gray
color with like heavy Frost and like a
gassy nose so I mean that's what got it
in to the
to the lineup and like the other females
were tight too so yeah it was tight
um but as far as like the background
lineage there's so many different Yoda
Cuts there's like a Yodo G there's over
the years there's so many of them so who
knows
yeah it can get like a bit of a myriad
like that at times I guess yeah like I
think it might even be one of the most
recent posts on your Instagram but the
Bitties it looks phenomenal like these
super swollen hand grenade type buds
just gorgeous Rich purple hues
do you find that the purple lines like
this sell well or do you feel like that
somewhat prevalent myth around purple
strains not being super potent sort of
cancels out any increase in terms of
like sales or interests
no I think they they go well people
people like that colourpop you know what
I mean and that Bitties that is comes in
a bunch of different colors so like I
had
that's a great strain because you get so
much selection in that you got Mike's
selected cut of the jigglers which is
already [ __ ] awesome and then you get
this selection of Bahama reversed onto
it and now we're getting you know crazy
phinos so yeah the one with like that
hand green hand grenade size nug you're
exactly right like it's that big it
fills the palm of your hand so it was
super heavy had a a great you know more
gelato East Side nose on that one
um
and like the leaf ratio there's like no
leaves on that like that's there's like
no trimming to that and yeah I mean
that's I can't I definitely kept that
keeper cut to work with down the down
the line but um
some of the other femos that were in
there had different uh almost like gassy
kind of weird smells to them and
um there was even like a grape one like
a it was ugly like it it was one of the
tester ones that it just didn't have the
right leaves to it to be a keeper so I
didn't keep it but the smell was crazy
um it smelled like grapes uh but yeah
like there was quite a few cool jigglers
some of them look
awesome
I love that I think it's one of my
favorites Miami uh mommy too is one of
my heavy favorites I I really loved
everything in the lineup
yeah look strong sales pitch and I got
to admit the the Bitties was one that I
was looking at myself thinking this
might be the one I'd pick it makes me
wonder I like the name Bitties I think
it's cool and and I always think how
important is a strain name do you think
it's sort of only really matters if the
strain isn't good like if the strain's
good enough it doesn't really matter
what the strain name is or do you think
it really actually makes a difference
I think it does to an extent I mean I
named that Bitties because if you know
my boy Mike he'd be coming up with some
of the most outlandish sometimes
borderline offensive names ever so I I
figured like okay if I'm gonna you know
it's a it's an exotic soulfire collab
it's got to have a name that
that would be proper so I went with
Bitties but um yeah I think the names do
matter a little bit people want some
creativity in the names people want you
to take some time and figure it out and
it's not easy with like absolutely
everything you got to make sure that
nobody has the [ __ ]
or it causes a desktop so yeah names are
important and I guess there's a little
follow-up to that do you tend to name
strains before you've grown them out or
do you like to grow them out and sort of
use that experience as some inspiration
for the name
yeah I got to grow them out first
yeah I just the reason why I ask is
because I find it interesting you sort
of see it more commonly these days where
people put a post up being like hey the
name Bitties is now taken and it's like
they've just dusted the female with
pollen and it's sort of like don't you
want to grow it out first or like I
guess Bitties is a bad example for
people like you know orange lemonade
cookie and it's like don't you want to
make sure that's actually like the
flavor in there like what if what if you
don't find it right
yeah I mean how do you how do you name
something before you've seen what it is
because it can be completely different
from what you may think
so yeah you got to grow it out because
and honestly it's going to help you name
your plant much better like you're gonna
see something in there that maybe
triggers like a name that
like has a distinguishing characteristic
for that plant so yeah grow your plants
out before you name them in my opinion
yeah I get yeah I feel you I feel ya but
I mean a lot a lot of people just don't
grow their [ __ ] out so maybe you know it
is what it is that's it isn't it so one
of the final strains I wanted to grill
you about was the baby cakes it looks
great and I love that you the
description you know you're sort of
talking about how it's a very consistent
cookie type Finos but something which I
was also curious about was how did you
get that cake mix clone like I swear
that's got to be one of the most locked
down cookie fam clones there is how did
that happen yeah I mean they're not that
locked down because they just be sliding
around and we have a really good circle
of friends that that get these get these
things so
um yeah they might not be as locked down
as you think there you go I mean like I
think people always uh talk about Envy
genetics in that regard you know it's
like how did he get but I guess you know
it just sort of speaks to the crew
you've got
yeah definitely I mean Envy's right
there in the mix he's down in La he's
got you know he's got a good network of
people so he's able to uh he's able to
find find things that other people uh
might not be able to
that's awesome that's awesome so as just
someone who has a very you know soft
spot for sativas I'm wondering do you
have a plan to do any work with some
like you know strongly sativa type work
or is you just more into the indicary
sort of hybrids
um I definitely am open to it man I I
want to uh I was just talking about this
the other day I want to grow a sativa
plant it's almost
like people always ask like is this
sativa dominant or is this in the
dominant and it's almost to the point
where like
that nomenclature is kind of dead you
know where we call things sativa or
indica everything is so hybridized now
it's almost hard to like find a true
sativa
um I guess unless you're ordering seeds
from like the UK so in general which of
your strains do you think is sort of one
that's most sort of slept on by the
public like sort of like that secret
dark horse that you think's a real
winner but maybe just needs a bit more
time before it catches on
um I think our mind flare is you know it
it came out in the white jelly uh lineup
and it was just I thought it was amazing
um it just all these different flavor
profiles were in there and then we just
used it again
um we used our keeper uh in with the
Bahama Mama and that's what made the
Miami Mommy and it's
just crushed in there like so many
Keepers I was throwing them away like I
just can't keep them all you know so
I think when people dig into the Miami
Mommy and see what that's all about and
when you get these kind of like
chocolatey really rich Fino like
smelling phinos and like this Frost that
is putting off
um and the the colorways that they have
I think that you know it's going to
really open their eyes to the Mind flare
and the selections that we've done over
time with it
yeah heck maybe we can change that and I
mean sort of in a similar light what do
you think is the most consistent line in
terms of plants produced like what the
plants produce and the reason why I ask
this is because we've got a lot of
listeners who grow outdoors and for them
they ideally want to be able to you know
like Harvest a bunch of plants and it
just all goes in the same bag so like
consistency for some people is quite
important which line do you think gives
pretty consistent results
right so you're talking about like
phenotypic consistency across across all
the crosses sure
um I mean you're going to see a lot of
that in this Bahama line because the
Bahama was so dominant in like and like
passing on that color Frost and
structure
um you're gonna see a lot of uh
phenotypic similarities in this lineup
um if I would say not in the um
in the Black Banana lineup because
everything was vastly different in that
one
um
yeah and probably could see some of that
in the in the white jelly because the
white jelly kind of did that as well
like where it
it brought those similarities but yeah
definitely the Bahama line you're gonna
it was it was a strong
strong presence of Obama in there yeah
nice nice
so what genetics in general excite you
you know like what are you sort of
excited to hunt next and and if you were
to sort of pop some other seeds from
someone else how many seeds do you like
to pop to get an idea of what's going on
with that line for me I'll just grab
like interesting packs so if I can't
find something tight in just one pack of
your seeds I'm probably not [ __ ] with
you so like I said I'm gonna pop this
bloomco
um pop some of his stuff so uh that of
course Mike's Creations I'm always
popping [ __ ] out of his stuff uh mostly
because I can just hit him up and get
him like what's up bro those are looking
Ty with some strawberry gears bro I need
I need my fix so um yeah uh so any of
any of the Exotic stuff is Ty uh like I
said bloomco
um
uh
uh Relentless always has great work you
know you can really see that he puts a
lot of time in his stuff uh I might have
my papa a pack of masonics um stuff
because I had such great results with uh
what I got from him last time
um
who else I want to pop some dead pan I
think his name is I want to pop some of
his stuff I think I have some of his
Peach stuff uh I might be popping
some of the wave genetics I think I got
their what their peach rings I think
it's called Uh I really want to find
this Peach chirp that people are talking
about so I'm gonna hunt a bunch of peach
flavored stuff see what I can find I'm
looking for peaches and grapes
kind of
um so we'll see what I can find I enjoy
popping other people's work
and seeing what what cool [ __ ] it's fun
for me yeah for sure I definitely can
get down with that sentiment
so the Lumpy Space Princess that's uh
that's a cool strain both because it's a
great reference to Adventure Time as
well as
um you know it looks phenomenal when you
look at the plants it's both been bred
with and it on itself
do you find that like you name strains
with references like also there's the
Grim bastard OG which is phenomenal
reference to Trailer Park Boys
um do you name these because these
strains remind you of that reference in
some way or it's just special to you and
like what sort of makes you think oh you
know I'm gonna give this like a cool
name that's a reference to a show or to
a game or something like that
um both so uh that thing looked like
Lumpy Space Princess so uh like what we
were talking about you got to grow them
out once I grew them out I was like I'm
slumping on these lumps right here
because that thing looks like Lumpy
Space Princess
um
so yeah I I
I like the LSP I think I you know and
that might be something that we revisit
at some point because people just
absolutely love that
that cross like the pink Hues that it it
comes with and the and that that musky
lemon flavor that you can actually taste
they they like that strain like those
things have been sold out for a while
but um yeah I like to I like to
reference pop culture
um I play a ton of uh I'm a I'm a gamer
myself I play a ton of video games with
my kids
um we even run a uh Grand Theft Auto uh
server like uh where people come in and
play like Grand Theft Auto online it's
kind of wild
um yeah so I mean we just we're we're
pop culture Fanatics I guess that's cool
you got your own GTA server oh yeah we
love it man I I yeah it's like an RP
server so you get in there and you you
know you role play whatever you're
playing and people like really get into
it so uh yeah it's it's pretty awesome
there you go a whole new world for both
me and the listeners to go and explore a
bit more
yeah I think we're gonna I was thinking
about doing like a seed drop in the in
the in the GTA uh server so you know you
would just get in yeah and do something
maybe to get a specific pack of seeds
that you can only get by hopping in and
and hopping into 5m and and uh coming
into the uh the city so might be
something in the future to look out for
now that's the next level drop that's
right
so I noticed amongst the various strains
you've made you've worked with a few
different cookie Cuts or sort of cookie
related strains like you know from just
straight cookies to the northern fire
cookies to even things like biscotti
stuff like that which of the cookie cuts
are your preferred ones if you had to
pick say one or two and do you like to
breed with cookies generally speaking
uh I do because I like the structure of
cookies I like the smell of cookies I
think that
um the creation of cookies really was a
uh
turning point in in breeding and in
cannabis culture or you know and however
you feel about the cookies machine and
brand and burner and all that put that
[ __ ] to the side and you really just
can't take away from these guys what
they you know what that what that plant
has done
um at least breeding wise for sure so
yeah I like it I
uh right now I like the the north fire
cookies I used to have the cut of
cookies and cream that I thought was the
best one
um to me far better than the 13.
um
in my opinion
uh but
yeah I I do I do enjoy breeding with
cookies I think it's I think it adds
some characteristics to the progeny that
can only be found in the in those plants
so
uh I I don't try to over add too much of
it to the lineup like I said I like to
have a little something for everyone
um I guess I'm missing missing that Mark
by not having enough sativa and maybe
we'll fix that in the future
uh but yeah it's a good one to add no
fire cookies right now is the one
yeah I love it good answer
so on the final question before we do
our quick fire questions at the end I
noticed that you'd had some nice
write-ups in high times and I feel like
in the past High Times played a huge
role in our scene and in promotion and
awareness but as Instagram and other
social media platforms have taken off it
feels like it's faded a little bit did
you feel like you got a bump out of
those write-ups and those features or do
you feel like they are sort of fading a
bit Into Obscurity
um I think I I mean maybe we did I
didn't pay too much attention to him I
feel like
High Times is kind of
it used to be like this
like Flagship for our industry it used
to be like oh High Times you know and
maybe it's because the covet and the
shows are gone or the shows have been so
[ __ ] up with like the regulation like
you can't even answer any of these damn
shows anymore without being licensed in
that state and it's just turned a bunch
of [ __ ] so
I'm just disappointed in in High Times
in that aspect like
it used to be the one thing that we all
used to come together to do to go to
these competitions and they've really
just turned it into like an
advertisement for whatever local
recreational breeders are gonna line
their pockets and that's unfortunate
like they've really I don't know if it's
the new owners or what's going on over
there but I think the general sentiment
from like most of the
heads in the industry is just like
they're pretty irrelevant at this point
and they need to come back to like what
started them
and
I don't know
so
if we got a bump from it I I don't know
but
I missed the old High Times to be honest
when you say that do you sort of mean
like before it was like pay to play
um yeah like well I'm sorry I should
clarify obviously it's not all pay to
play because I I can bet my left like
you didn't pay for that article but like
that's one of the criticisms which gets
leveled against them at times I guess
yeah well it's I I don't know man people
used to like I I know when Mike and and
Q and Cuban were winning all of their
um just on that run like winning all
their their trophies and whatever those
guys weren't paying to win that stuff
like I you know I'm right there in the
circle they still didn't pay that [ __ ]
they just had fire and they were winning
you know so like I hear so many times
like oh like if you want a cup that's
because you paid or that's because you
did that that's [ __ ] like that
that's not absolutely not true those
guys won that [ __ ]
fair and square
um but now yeah I think it's like
I don't know they're just I think maybe
I don't know their financials but maybe
High Times is upside down they need to
make some money
but they can make all that money by
showing by making having some awesome
shows uh once maybe covered gets up off
of our ass
yeah that's some really valid points you
know I definitely have heard that
criticism raised uh before about the
purchasing of the cups and I think like
what you said is really valid you know
people like exotic Mike and various
others clearly not paying to win clearly
got the fire I think some of the
frustration is more like when you see
strain right UPS in the magazine and
it's like we're doing a write-up this
week on crop Kings blueberry and you're
like oh come on
yeah I think yeah but anyway so I mean
bringing us to sort of our quick fire
questions that we'd love to ask all
guests at the end uh the first one I
wanted to ask you is what is the best or
most memorable single weed experience
you've had so it might be like smoking a
certain flower smoking a certain hash or
just whatever what stands out the most
to you
uh lemon tree yeah I don't know why but
uh uh one of the just the when Mike and
I smoked a lemon tree at the I think it
was the emerald cup or something we just
we're like just love the flavor so damn
much we had to get a get a cut for
ourselves so I I remember that
yeah nice it's a really it's a really
interesting flavor isn't it
yeah it's one of a kind actually like
the it's the aftertaste man like that it
stays on your palate and that's like
what we're looking for when it comes to
Flavors like the weed can be pretty the
weed could be this or that but if it
leaves that aftertaste in your mouth
like that lemon tree does uh yeah that's
memorable so that's that's definitely
one of the most memorable yeah a
brilliant answer and I can I can
understand why you'd say that so on the
other end of the spectrum though was
there ever a situation where people
around you or people who you sort of
generally trust the opinion over like
hyping a strain up and then you finally
taste it and you're like oh is that it
hmm
yeah
I know there is I just don't know it off
the top of my head
um one that we're just like oh that's
not that tight
yeah I'm not sure not for me personally
I can't think of one off the top of it
it's almost a good thing right
yeah yeah definitely there you go the
people around you are only suggesting
and hyping up the good stuff that's good
to hear so let's do a bit of a
hypothetical you know I'm gonna drop you
off on a remote desert island with just
three strains and you can theoretically
grow them for the rest of time what
three are you taking with you they can
either be clones or seeds whatever you
want but just three
just three uh GMO
uh probably take uh my kind of banana
runs
and I only get one more
Let's see we got some funk we got some
uh
uh do you say I'm on the island yeah
I gotta bring the Bahama Mama it's an
island
good cross good cross Okay cool so now
there's a chance to be a little bit
devilish here let's let's say the the
roles are reversed and instead of you
being dropped off we're gonna drop
someone else off and let's just say that
you're not a big fan of this person you
get to pick what three strains you're
gonna drop them off with what are you
going to leave them with
I'm gonna leave them with a CBD strain
um I'm gonna leave so I'll leave them
with some some CBD I will I'm not a big
fan of this person right okay
um
other strangers that are not that great
right now
um
what junk would I leave somebody with
I'd probably still give them GMO even
though I don't like them because we know
it's going to take them 12 weeks to
finish it so that's just going to be
frustrating either way
and then uh I'll probably leave him with
so he's got some CBD he's got some GMO
and maybe I'll leave him with some some
apple fritter
oh you're not a fan of it
uh no not that I'm not a fan of it but
um yeah I'm just leaving yeah
leaving with some freighter it seems
like what everybody wants to grow up so
he can grow that yeah no look we've
heard a lot of blue dreams in the past
so I guess it's sort of like that
oh I mean hey dude there's a time that
blue dream was awesome I don't know why
people hate on that [ __ ] that's it yeah
that's it okay so final question if you
could go back in time to any place
anywhere in history and just collect
some seeds or a clone if you wanted
where would you go what time and what
are you collecting
um
I don't know because if you go too far
back in time it's going to be some boof
so I would probably go back
I would probably go back to uh
when I was a little kid and my my uncle
was was growing and it probably snatched
snatched some of uh his clones from
from the uh garage that I that I would
walk into and I was a little tiny kid
blind myself yeah I'd probably grab some
of whatever he was growing he's a he's
an old hippie from uh from Humboldt from
Arcata
so probably grab some of his strains
yeah nice I'm sure there's probably some
cool gems lurking in the vault from him
I think that just about brings us to the
end of things was there any comments or
shout outs you wanted to make
uh just shout outs to all the homies man
and uh you know shout out to uh James
for you know seeds here now it's a great
great uh spot to grab grab beans from
he's I was really uh proud when we got
put on this teacher now back in the day
like that was a really big big move he's
one of the first banks that ever really
uh took a shot with us so appreciate him
for that so shout out to Jones being on
that one
yeah likewise you know shout out James
Bean we appreciate you being a sponsor
and also you referenced earlier one of
our other sponsors Pro mix you know you
use their medium shout out Pro mix oh I
didn't know they were one of your
sponsors yeah they're great um shout out
Pro mix it'd be awesome if you could get
it to Seattle more because we we have
pro-mix like deserts sometime where you
just can't get it it's like gonna like
stock up on it it's crazy yeah there you
go are they Canadian they're Canadian
right yeah they are but I think they're
sort of more um the other side of
Washington unfortunately like the uh
what is it the Quebec side yeah let them
know man sometimes I stressed out
because if I don't have the pro-mix then
I gotta get something else and I hate
using anything other than Pro Max
yeah good call well with that being said
we've been very grateful to have you on
so again thank you so much soul of
sulfide genetics for coming on giving us
the lowdown on all your strains and a
bit of history and predictions for the
future
yeah man thanks for having me I
appreciate it
[Music]
so there you have it gang huge shout out
to Seoul sulfide Fanatics for coming by
talking all that Science History
breeding so much more we're very
appreciative likewise hugely
appreciative of our sponsors seeds here
now by Steve Bank of the game they've
got soul fire go grab it
likewise copper biological systems thank
you so much for everything you do
without your amazing predatory bugs our
Gardens which is so much harder to keep
clean check out the acupar M or the
spidex vital to Absolute killer products
that will help your garden to be
successful
shout out to Pro mix for their pro-mix
connect best mycorrhizal product in the
game increase yields resins cannabinoids
herpins whatever you're after it's
probably going to increase it check it
out guys pro-mix connects
Charlie's cannabis number one spot in
Oklahoma if you need fire of any sort
they got you back remember Charlie's
your bud
big shout out to all these candidates
last but not least thank you to the
patreon gang we love you without you the
show really couldn't happen if you want
access to episodes early additional
interviews unheard content giveaways and
more check out the patreon
www.patreon.com
[Music]
I'll see you for the next one game
I'll see you
[Music]
foreign