yeah I was like it's gonna get it's got
to go three or four hours and my wife
just poked in her head she's all can you
be done this was like 20 minutes or an
hour ago I'm like yeah she's like it's
been like six hours dude
[Music]
[Applause]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts
this episode as always was brought to
you by our phenomenal sponsors seats
here now number one seed banks in the
game guarantee on germination and
satisfaction why would you go elsewhere
they got all the hottest breeders and
the latest drops likewise a big shout
out to Cropper biological systems they
got all the beneficial microbes all the
beneficial Predator bugs and the feeds
to keep the good army alive go check
them out to make your next Harvest a
success got acids grab the affidan got
spider mites grab the spider end makes
sense
[Music]
also a huge shout out to our family over
at the patreon if you want to be a part
of the lifeblood that helps make this
show happen getting early access to
episodes exclusive unreleased contents
and prizes giveaways so much more go
check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
foreign
[Music]
part two of The Epic chat we had with
main Jane of Mendocino talking all
things creating history trends for the
future and what you can expect going
forward
[Music]
so without further ado
let's get into it foreign
[Music]
that is a question for the ages and I
mean what a what a brilliant answer as
to how to sort of work a line I think
everyone including myself will need to
re-listen to that once or twice because
it was just gold in there and uh
speaking of working a line I've always
been very fond since being able to try
your cherry pie S1 I think that's got to
be one of the most intoxicating flavor
profiles there is so I've always
followed the Cherry West and just in
general your cherry work and I see that
there's a lot of really cool projects
you've been doing be it like you know
the Cherry West back cross
um you're doing the collab with uh
biovortex the Cherry Lime dog we were
chatting to him with about that and that
sounds great I even noticed that you did
a sunset sherbet cherry limeade cross
which is also cool did you have any
immediate plans for what you want to
kind of do with your cherry lines any
ideas where you want to go in the future
because I know a lot of people Beyond
Myself are really into them and follow
it
I have some different things that I've
done I mean I even this year I took a
you know the lime and the cherry limeade
is the PK black lime
um which was the brother of the lime one
so when I made the cherry limeade
without mail I also put that
on the live one and then I have various
lime lines that come out of that that I
just call a lime instead of black lime
um
and so this year I took a lime a really
nice lime F5
and I put that on the Cherry clone again
to remake a cherry limeade
F1 which is the same thing I did to make
the Cherry Lime pop which was when I
used the lime Pop Mail which was a lime
F2 instead of an F5
um and that's what that's what uh
biovortex started with for his project
and
um so I went ahead and did a different
one and
it'll be a little bit different because
you know the lime pop was what it was in
the mail I used this time is what it was
and the F1 lime male that I used to make
cherry limeade was was its thing
um every time you do that you pick a
different male of the same strain and
you put it on the same mother you get a
completely different cross it's not a
you know it's not just like you take
lime and Cherry you cross them together
and you get the same thing every time
you use a different male you get a
completely new thing with some of the
same
um traits so I went ahead and I did that
um I did a lot of cherry lime
cross gelato
um gelato 33
.
um I liked that one it seemed kind of
silly when I made it but I tried it and
then once I grew them I was like wow
this really worked out nice because it
was they had really pretty color which
you know who cares but still they're
pretty and nice
um it made it a little bit more
substantial and dense than a lot of the
Cherry limeades even though the cherry
limeade has that in it they're not all
super heavy and dense
um and easy to trim but the gelato
really brought that to it the cherry
limeade still kept a lot of its Terps in
there that really popped out and made it
sharp whereas gelato is more kind of
like a kind of the 33 is kind of like a
fruit loopy ice cream thing
um
and then so I took that and I did that
on a lot of stuff I took the cherry
limeade gelato I put it on the Cherry
mom again so that'll reinforce that
cheriness but the lime will start to get
lost a little I like the lime in those
CR and the cherry limeade crosses
because it brings some of that
citronella lemongrass lime peel
um kind of stuff which the Cherry
already had some of it but it's more
like Star more like lemon Starburst uh
candy kind of a thing
um
and then
the Cherry so the Cherry the Cherry West
back cross was cherry limeade cross
Cherry West Cross Cherry West
then that male got put on the Cherry
West again and then out of that that got
put on the Cherry West again so I have
quite a few seeds now of the Cherry West
bat cross three instead of one which was
the last release
um
and those are cool
and I'll probably come out of that and
go back to it again which is eventually
just kind of making the Cherry West
clone by itself
and you know you could have taken
um
Cherry West the original males from that
seed and put it on the Clone and taken
those forward
except the cherry limeade
I liked better in the cross because it
had more of the crazy
far out Terps that the Cherry West 10
clone had whereas a lot of the sisters
of the Cherry West 10 and the Cherry
West Cross they were more of a plain
cherry pie thing and uh like regular
Cherry Pie and as exotic as regular
Cherry Pie as and people really like it
it's not like the Cherry Pie weirdo that
I have from clone which is a lot more
rose oil and uh
that Starburst candy thing going on
um
so I I like to you I like to use that to
lock down the cherry West in seed form
um the cherry limeade instead because
the males I feel like
um the Cherry West 10 was kind of like a
one in whatever 50 throw and the rest
some of the rest were a little more
dumbed down regular
um cherry pie Terps which are a little
more musky and deep and dark
which are cool and tasty but
not the unique thing I was trying to
bring out of both those things and so I
liked the cherry lime
um
better as a starting place for that so
that's what I've been doing with that
and then so I'll probably put out like I
might put out some cherry West bat cross
three
I might just wait and put out the back
Cross Four or the back cross
that cross one f2s or the back cross
three F twos just depending you know
we'll try them and see which ones kinda
are the coolest or you know do them all
if they're all really cool and different
um
and so there's that and what you saw was
the Cherry West back crops those were
different ones what we smoked when you
were here
um
and that was funny because we kind of
took the one we thought was the worst
and we smoked that and I was like [ __ ]
this shit's still good I thought you
guys wouldn't even be that stoned
because you had a heavy tolerance and I
didn't as much and then I was sitting
there super ripped and I was like look
I'm probably the only one high here and
then you guys were like dude that's
Stoney and I said all right cool cool
good to see you you know like out of
that since it was the one that didn't
look like it was the the best you know
um
but uh so there's those
and then
I did you know I kind of I want to find
like a cherry limeade that can actually
make like water hash bubble hash because
it is so greasy you can only really make
um
you can really only make oil with like
butane uh or CO2 and it just doesn't I
don't know like it
I
um
I want to see it I want to see the same
Terps on a more solid resin head so that
you can do different stuff with it so I
crossed it like with with Chrome's white
and I crossed it with Katsu babakush
uh and I crossed it with black dog and I
crossed it with purple snow Bubba from
CSI and that's in an attempt to see if I
can go in a direction where I get the
cherry limeade Terps on
um a more solid
uh
resin so we'll see if that works out
um
and uh
so
yeah man
um I'm trying to think if there's other
stuff I did but those I think that's
kind of what what I really have going
now and then of course
uh I did cherry limeade cross with the
Cherry
clone again so I took the F5 cherry
limeade and put that on the Cherry clone
and I was watching Game of Thrones and
they had the guy who was the fire guy
and they called him the pyromancer and I
was like ooh cherry pie romancer that's
a cherry pie cherry pie romancer I'm
gonna [ __ ] call it that so I slapped
that on it because I knew I knew it came
out of a funny it's hard to name things
you know
um but uh but also you know that's a
funny thing because it's fire and
there's pie in there and you know
whatever
um so that was like one thing that I
have and I'm gonna keep working on that
and
um
other Cherry stuff cherry limeade I have
a lot of f6s that I need to go through
different directions I'm gonna go back
to the oldest ones
um while they're still viable so I can
make lots of them to put into storage
that's always important even if you kind
of successful with your newer ones you
don't want to abandon the old ones
because that's where you found the good
[ __ ] you know in the first place
so you got to make more of those before
they get old and maybe find new crazy
things
I got the wild strawberry clone I got
one I call Cherry Lime four from back
because that was Cherry Lime four which
was my original F1 keeper of cherry
limeade and then I hit that with seeds
from in it
so
um it was a back cross and then when I
popped those I got one that just has the
craziest Terps and it got some balls in
my depth but it didn't seed itself so
hope you know I'm doing a bunch of
crosses with that and seeing if I can
kind of get that to go in a direction
where it'll straighten out and
um
that one's like really really crazy
lemongrass it's hard to describe
citronella
chemical
with some of the Starbursts from the
Cherry but mostly just very limey but
the special part of the Cherry without
any of the berry cherry smell to it so
that's cool and then I think that's kind
of you know
um
that's kind of where those where those
are at at this point is just kind of
like still hunting through and trying
different different stuff with foam I
always have different you know
outcrosses I did with them and um
you know there's there's a lot of a lot
of neat a lot of neat stuff that pops
out of those lines
yeah for sure I mean it sounds like
there's a variety of different Avenues
people can go down if they're interested
in exploring the the Cherry work there
and I I love that name the uh the Cherry
Pie romance so that's it's a nice little
pun I noticed in that question you
referenced uh having done some work with
gelato and I had picked up on that as
well looking through your Instagram and
I was wondering do you like the results
you see having used the gelato mother in
some crosses and does this give any sort
of credence to the idea that maybe some
of the hype boys one day will see a runs
across from Mean Gene
uh well I mean I took that gelato 33
cherry limeade
um and I grew it and then I got the
runts clone and I grew that
and
um
you know the runts when I grew it it
kind of had a cool shape to it where
there's a lot of Bud to it and then the
leaves kind of separate it looked a lot
like my old dirt perp
and
I lost that years ago kind of a narrow
Bud that wants to kind of hug itself
and when you take the Leafs off of it
it's just kind of the bud left there and
it's not hairy
um
and uh it had really pretty color even
in the middle of the summer I liked the
smell
I mean of course now everybody knows
gelato everybody knows Skittles but I'm
of the opinion that if we would have had
all the same
quote unquote hype [ __ ] in the mid 90s
we would have been like this is good
this is like uh so-and-so's [ __ ] you
know like nah that's cool I like it you
know
um I feel like any time you win
um
everybody says you're full of [ __ ]
so
there's like an aspect of Underdog stuff
that happens where as soon as the strain
is popular
it's really hard for people to not say
it's [ __ ]
um I feel like like chem dog maybe and
OG have been able to kind of
be big and popular
purely for the reason that they're like
straight up probably the most knock you
in the head [ __ ] that anybody has access
to
so anybody who's really into those sees
anything that's not as potent
and because ah that shit's [ __ ] like
if you smoke the most potent weed all
the time anything that's not the most
potent weed doesn't really do much to
you
um
so you know it's kind of weird like for
me I'm like well I don't really want to
just smoke one kind of weed so I don't
even really want to smoke chemd chem 91
and ghost OG every day all day all the
time because then when I smoke other
[ __ ] I won't really get high we went
through the same thing when we started
smoking hash all the time and then we'd
smoke a joint we'd be like I'm [ __ ]
just don't even bother let's just smoke
some [ __ ] hash because this isn't
doing nothing to us and so I kind of
like to keep what I'm smoking varied and
then that way when I smoke something
that's super potent I really get [ __ ]
ripped and it's like I can notice it
otherwise
don't get me wrong I've smoked the most
potent [ __ ] every day all day
um that I have available after a certain
point
every time you smoke you don't really
get high anyway and then you you kind of
go oh this is the one thing that no
matter what it gets me high every time
but it's like yeah kinda but not like
you would be if you smoked Urkel for a
week and then you smoked some [ __ ] OG
or chem 91 or chemd then you'd be like
oh [ __ ] okay I'm [ __ ] Rich so like I
like to
I like to switch [ __ ] up and even you
know beyond the high of everything like
I don't like to taste the same weed
every time there's only a couple kinds
of weed that I like so much because I
just they make me happy and I like how
they taste that I like get really into
them where I want to smoke them all the
time
so
I like to have like you know I don't
mind that there's a ruts or a gelato or
a cherry pie or whatever it is because
for me it's like those are you know all
these different things that to me are
pretty good and then they are something
different you know like I I [ __ ] I
love
you know pizza or burgers and fries or
sushi or [ __ ] you know whatever nice
light Thai food Japanese food whatever
it is
um and there might be something that I
like better than everything else or only
two things but I don't really want to
eat that [ __ ] every single day I really
like that I got access to a lot of
different things it's like my favorite
song I don't want to just listen to it
all the time or pretty soon I'm like all
right well it's kind of played out and
you know it just I just the way you know
I think of [ __ ] so
um I like all the variety and everything
so like you know yeah I got the runs I
[ __ ]
bread it with the gelato cherry limeade
we'll see if it's good
um
I bread it with the sky cuddler double
Kush because I thought that would be odd
and there might be stuff that comes out
of it that isn't like what a normal
runts cross would be because it's like a
cush that's a that's a that's kind of a
weird Kush with
um a runt so I'm like okay we'll be kind
of neat if you get like a gnarly Stony
OG Bud that smells a little bit like
gelato or something or something that
you wouldn't it unlocks something that
you didn't get out of either parent so
you know I tried it see what they do
um
but um I've always done that like if
there's something that people say is
really good and like I have friends who
grow it and they're like oh no dude it's
good I'm like yeah it's not just [ __ ]
it's not just some [ __ ] that that's
popular but no like I like to smoke it
if one of my friends says like they're
into it I'm like cool
I get it I make some crosses and if
they're good they're good and if not
they just go in a [ __ ] pile with all
the other [ __ ] I never do anything with
you know I I do it every uh
you know I do it every year whatever is
something that's around that people say
is cool I'm like huh I wonder how it
breeds I wonder how it looks I wonder
what it looks like when I grow it
um or when I you know like what's what's
it like the way I dry it or handle it
like is it good is it not good like you
know let's see what it does because
um
you know originally like I didn't I
didn't like OG and we even had types of
weed that were so similar to OG back in
the old days and we were like I don't
know you smoke it it's really [ __ ]
strong
you don't really feel that good you just
feel really [ __ ] stoned
um you don't get Giggles you don't
really get any kind of
you know like it doesn't give you a lift
you just it's [ __ ] holy [ __ ] that's
potent and we didn't really ever like it
and then that became really um popular
and then I started smoking tons of
[ __ ] weed and then all of a sudden it
was like okay this this shit's good and
then I liked those kinds of weed but um
you know what one person likes isn't or
doesn't mean that's the best for
everybody you know so I like to try to
keep everything going and
um make something out of stuff when it
comes around if I think it's good and
especially like if it does good in like
blind competitions with real heads you
know like the ego Clash or the emerald
cup or whatever where people don't know
the name but everybody's like damn this
one's good I'm like well what is it it
can't be that [ __ ] bad if it's if
this is blind it ain't the it ain't the
mylar bag selling it to people in a jar
when there's no name on it you know
so um
you know it makes me makes me curious so
I I uh I do stuff with um
with everything you know I got agent
orange crosses I got runs crosses I got
[ __ ] big bud crosses I got
Northern Lights crosses Like You Name It
Whatever came around that at the time
was something that people thought were
cool and people who I respect thought it
was good dope I'm I [ __ ] hit it with
some pollen you know
that's a good philosophy to have for
sure and I'm sure all the hypebeasts
will be thrilled to hear that they're
going to be able to get the runs gelato
cherry limeade combo and the sky cuddler
one also sounds like it could be a cool
little um hybrid in the works there I
mean on that same topic of catering to
everyone I was so stoked to see that
you're getting some nice sativas in the
mix recently when I noticed that you put
up that post about having pollinated a
C5 plant you had and it got me thinking
are you planning on you know working or
maybe even releasing some of the uh
older sort of haze hybrids because I
think that although there are a lot of
people who say that they're super sick
of you know the Amsterdam profile like
that Meme you put up perfectly embodied
it where you were kind of alluding to
that you know there is a more nuanced
side of the haze terpenes which people
can sometimes discredit what's your
plans for this hybrid and do you want to
do some more sativa work going going
forward
you know the thing about sativas was for
me my thing was always I wanted to be
able to make plants
I wanted to be able to make seeds that
somebody that somebody like I'm a funny
person like that I don't I don't have a
whole lot of stuff that I like just for
the sake of me liking it I like to do
things
for other people's enjoyment
um like I really like to
make plants that I think someone else is
going to like to grow you know
um so I mean
I always kind of did stuff that I knew
like people because I didn't used to you
know be on the Internet or nobody knew
that I had anything I didn't know
anybody outside my little circle so it's
kind of like okay well I think so and so
you know they know this stuff and and we
all thought it was good so like I'm
gonna work on it and then you know see
if we can get some people to grow some
of this and that'll be fun to see them
and I don't want to make something
nobody's going to grow that I'm just
going to grow
um because you know that's kind of the
fun of it like you're gonna make music
you want to make music that people are
going to want to hear you want to make
food you want to make food that when you
feed people they'll think it's good food
you know
um
so like I always kind of just was doing
that and then at a certain point I
realized that I do like just for myself
I do really like the highs on some of
the sativa stuff like I had some swazi
and some stuff people gave me and
um way back in the day we had like a tie
that would completely like be like half
male half female that the weed was
really tasty on it and we'd say [ __ ] it
put you know one way over here and grow
them and have a you know a couple Joints
off a little plant or whatever and um
my buddy had some Mexican he brought
back from Mexico and grew back in the
day and I was like oh that's that's cool
but they grew terribly so I was just
like you know it's just a novelty
um but I I realized at a point okay I do
like to have a little bag of this swazi
or a little bag of whatever it is you
know
so you know I've grown some swazi some
Congolese and I I I I realize that you
don't have to grow plants
to have a crop
you can grow plants just to have one
little shitty plant in a little pot off
somewhere to the side and just take that
and you wind up with a little bag of
weed and every once in a while you're
like I'm gonna smoke the weird weed and
you take five bong hits of the really
weird weed with the high ceiling in here
really [ __ ] high and it's different
than anything else you know and it gives
you it gives you cool um
these are cool Vibes you're not just
smoking the same Afghani based stuff
that is is good for a lot of things but
doesn't necessarily give you the real
[ __ ] lift of being tripped out and
[ __ ] so um
you know I I got the C5 I got the A5 I
tried the weeds they both have a really
cool high the plant itself smells like
lemon peels which I think is [ __ ]
awesome but the bud really has that kind
of Amsterdam Haze when you have that
terpenoline like that and it's sharp and
like turpentiney and gnarly like so like
the like the Pakistani CSI has like
where it's more earthy too is a little
different but anyway so I you know I
went ahead and crossed it with stuff
that's really weird and there's a lot of
potential for different terpene profiles
and you know we'll see if it goes
anywhere I'm not going to have a lot of
those seeds but enough to try some out I
think
and uh I'm more interested in working
with like this Malawi I have and this uh
Congolese the Congolese is kind of in
that ballpark but it has more of a deep
grassy thing to it that
you would think you would like if you
don't like those types but then there's
something about it that's kind of just
nice and uh
they're neat they didn't have any Hermes
in them and they were straight from
straight from the Congo and like they
were they were good for that kind of a
like a land race heirloom
um African thing and uh really Hardy in
a lot of ways
it's like you know just I want to play
with some different things like that but
it's not the it's not the main Direction
I want to go but I really would like to
get my hands on the old Haze
type that I saw in the 90s where it was
just so tasty and it was more like
a
a I don't know like a I don't know
really hard to describe but more like
Cedar
incense
um
it's really really tasty like you're
just like damn that is so
enjoyable you know
um
more like how like
that's funny as it is like opium
straight off of a off of the head of a
poppy when you smoke that house just
you're just like wow some that's just
made to be smoked that's not like
smoking
weed that's like a whole different thing
you know which is what a lot of the best
weed weed strains are like that they're
just you can't believe it you know
um
so I'd like to dig into those kind of
things more the A5 and the C5 are really
famous
Neville you know like you can't downplay
his his legacy and you know like the
Northern Lights I was talking about
earlier probably was straight from
Neville based on the packaging and the
labeling and [ __ ] time frame the C5 was
really cold resistant really moisture
resistant that was neat
um the A5
has a taste that I like
you know everybody who's chasing those
as being really amazing like definitely
try them
yeah so a good answer there and I guess
as a follow-up kind of based on how you
said you'd love to get some like real
Hayes and maybe as a larger extension
this applies to the roadkill do you
think that there are really many if any
Growers who are shall we say like you
know hidden up away in the Hills or the
mountains still holding on to some super
old cultivar from Years Gone by and like
the you know late 80s or 90s or do you
think maybe not so likely because even
those people who are tucked away still
come into town every so often and they
get exposed to the new stuff and they
probably dropped it at some point
I think real heads have certain plants
that they're just in love with
and they keep them no matter what
and uh
you know they may be sharing with a
couple people who know how good they are
and I think that there's probably a lot
of stuff out there
um that you'll never hear about because
I think in general
um you know like even me like I
sometimes I don't even understand why I
have any interest with like really
um
breeding and sharing seeds and like the
whole scene and you know I even you know
just the trying to trying to keep up
with the social interactions and the way
everything goes and
um
you know the whole scene which I'm
relatively new to compared to a lot of
people who have been more into it for a
long time like I had a certain
uh naivety uh with the whole scene like
you know initially like I met people who
were super into seeds and we're and I
was like oh I never you know I don't
know anybody who's really into that I my
friends are like hardcore
you know old school dope Growers who
they you know they get the good thing
here they get the good thing there maybe
they have something they make a little
seeds here and there and stuff and
whatnot and then there was people who
we're super into it and I was like whoa
these people are really into it and then
over time you realize well yeah the
reason why they're into it is because of
the way the scene is laid out where
you can manipulate people so heavily by
being Mr seed guy or
whatever little role that they're that
they're playing in the scene you know
and then after a while you're like oh
like
you know y'all don't even really
I don't even know if you really like any
of this [ __ ] like I don't know if you
have any
interest in the biology or the plant
aspect beyond the clout and
all this other kind of [ __ ] that
like surrounds anything that is
you know an opportunity to gain any kind
of like that kind of energy like you
know there's some people who are really
they really love cars they grew up from
when they were a little kid they're like
oh you know my dad or my uncle or my
grandpa or whatever was into cars and so
I learned about the pain and I learned
about the transmission and I learned
about the engine and I know everything
about all these things and you know
probably at a car show there's probably
like maybe half of the people are like
that and this is just random I don't
know half ten percent ninety percent I
don't [ __ ] no there's a lot of people
who are there too who just heard that if
you have fast [ __ ] ball and cars
there's people will think you're [ __ ]
cool and you can just be you know into
that and it's all good and you know and
then there's even
you know I don't know I feel like that's
how it is with weed there's a lot of
people who are just into it
to try to [ __ ] milk it for for what
it is and wouldn't have really done any
of it when it was when nobody was
looking you know what I mean and
um
yeah I don't know man the whole the
whole scene is just it's a it's a Trippy
it's a Trippy thing to learn like to
to see how [ __ ] is and and uh
and all that and really kind of see it
and then go okay well there's probably a
lot of people who are smarter than me
who aren't as naive and gullible in
general who just look for a [ __ ]
second and go oh this is all douchebags
a lot of these people are just full of
[ __ ] and you know there's that's
probably scares off a lot of people so
they don't get to meet somebody like
Bodhi or you know there's probably
people who think body is just like the
rest of everybody if they don't know him
if you know Bodhi you're like no bodhi's
the cool dude he just happens to be in
the mix you know and then even like me
compared to Bodhi I'm probably [ __ ]
20 percent more douchebaggy than Bodie
is or you know like there's just like a
certain there's a certain thing that I
think is probably really off-putting to
a lot of people who are really into just
having the [ __ ] they like
to where you'll just never hear from
them because they're just [ __ ] cool
you know and they don't they're not
going to be they're not going to get the
interest in thinking like oh I want
somebody to grow my stuff because you
know like no nothing ever happens with
it and I put all this time into it and
that's like what happened to me I was
like just so [ __ ] excited that
there's people who are into [ __ ]
seats you know that I was just like whoa
this is crazy and then like all said and
done you're like okay cool I have a
better feeling for a better feel for how
things are there are people who are
really like into plants and they really
really like to do this and then there's
a lot of people who just want to say you
know they're the guy who found the rks
and sell a thousand packs for a [ __ ]
bunch of money before they [ __ ] you
know whatever just the not just to kind
of sum it up if there's a million
versions of that but it but it but it is
you know the guy who's sitting there who
really has some [ __ ] that really smells
like a dead skunk he's probably like
yeah but I already have it and what what
the [ __ ] do I want to give it to anybody
for and I don't need anybody to give me
a pat on the back for having the real
skunk you know like [ __ ] like I said
like me I I do a lot of things because I
want to like be able to hand something
to somebody and have that interaction of
like oh you know like cool we're we're
looking through stuff and I like that
you know but a lot of people they don't
have any there's no incentive there for
them because they're just chill and they
they are good on doing whatever they're
doing and they got it and that's great
me I'm like I want to make something
really good and then sit there with
somebody and go hey is it really good do
we are we having fun like is it a good
time to you know but that that's not how
everybody is so
I think I think there's probably a ton
of stuff
and then those people just are never
going to come out of the woodwork and in
a in a sense it's it's unfortunate for
the plants themselves because
there's no way to really that's not
really sustainable as far as genetics
like how are how are those plants going
to survive past the person who gots
their hand on it
um
but you know like that's their
prerogative they have those plants they
don't need to give them to anybody for
preservation or whatever it is and um
you know but I I am of the belief that
there's people who have crazy crazy
stuff
and they're holding that original clone
you want they have the crazy seeds that
everybody wants and they're just like
yeah what you know because I know a lot
of people I have a lot of friends who
are who are
really weeded out and who you know you
talk to them about something they don't
they don't they have no idea of this
whole scene I didn't know you know like
I at one point I thought there was like
maybe like bog and sub cool and
Greenhouse and Neville like I think
that's probably at one point that was
you know I thought that was that's the
whole thing you know I didn't know there
was all these people who were on the
forums and I didn't know there was any
such thing as a forum and like the
forums were gone by the time I even
heard of them pretty much
um
you know and I you know I I think we I
think we get to see a little slice like
the people who want to come out and have
the interaction for whatever reason and
some of them like I said some people are
like Bodhi they want everybody to have
cool staff they get a kick out of it
they spend a lot of time doing stuff so
they want to make something of it
um you know and then there's people who
will just straight up [ __ ] you know
say they
made OG when they didn't and made
[ __ ] whatever when they didn't and
they're only there to to do something
and you know I don't even think there's
anything wrong with any of it like it's
not on a scale of of of like I was
saying earlier who are you hurting
the very worst of the weed guys you know
maybe they're kind of charlatans but I
mean
you know [ __ ] they're not matching up
meth and probably half of those
charlatans probably were a little while
ago to be honest so
oh God did a real wisdom right there I
love that I noticed in your answer that
you uh mentioned bogg who sadly passed
away recently and he's a guy who was
really influential both in you know
sharing knowledge but also his work you
know it shows up in a lot of various
breeders work I don't know if any of
your current lines you have for sale
have his genetics in them but I do know
that you've grown out a bunch of his
work and have posted about it before was
there any of his strains that
particularly stood out to you as like
some of the more favorites from him so I
haven't actually grown out
um a lot of his stuff
um
I had a clone
which came to me as Bubba d
and
um
I realized after a long time after
knowing his his sour bubble from him
given me the the flower when I met him
because he sometimes he'll just if you
see him at a cut he'll just like give
you a gram of flour or or like a you
know a piece of bubble hash or something
and one time when I was there he gave me
a bag of flour
and you know it was like a gram or two
and I pulled it out and I was like this
is so familiar and I got it home and I
realized
this is the same as Bubba d
and so what I realized when I thought
about it I went sour bubble Bubba D sour
d Bubba bubble it's pretty likely that
this was a sour bubble and somebody
called It Bubba D you know just because
of the two the two words you know it's
like they go together and the weed was
so similar and I never knew what it was
and I was always like I don't know how
this could be a sour diesel cross
especially because I I bred it a little
bit too
um and there was no you know sour pops
out some trippy weird uh kind of larfy
foxtaily stuff when you breed with sour
uh initially
and so
I think that what I had is Bubba d
was really a sour bubble Club
and so you know that was one that was
around here for a while and people you
know some people around here are kind of
recognized oh yeah I remember that
um and then I got sour strawberry from
them and I think I got uh
maybe Boggle gum
and or one of those ones like that
uh one of the bubble gum ones and then I
got the sour bubble so I grew the sour
strawberry and I told the story on a
thing a little while ago I grew the sour
strawberry and I didn't really mean to
do anything with it I just wanted to see
what a half pack looked like because I
was gonna if I liked it a lot I was
gonna get a couple packs to look through
um
which I didn't you know I should have
but I I didn't and uh that's a good
lesson for people that if you want some
seeds get the damn seeds and put them in
the fridge because whether you're an
older guy like like bog or your younger
guy like uh you know it doesn't don't
just think that these people who make
these seeds will always have the same
stock or they'll continue making seeds
or they'll always be around for you to
get seeds from if you want something you
should get it you know
um because this has happened you know
this is something that happens a lot and
people go ah [ __ ] I should have got them
all I could get them and uh you know the
seeds honestly the thing with Bob was
not being able to get his seeds is the
very least of the loss that you know
everybody has to take with with uh him
leaving because he's uh
he's just a really cool guy I mean I you
know I didn't really know him and I I
sat with him and he told me about how he
uh he was riding in this car I think
with with Shanti Baba it was somebody
like legendary like that and we're
riding on the Autobahn in this car with
a [ __ ] 700 horsepower some [ __ ]
Jag [ __ ] V12 or some [ __ ] and you
know we're [ __ ] we're going for
[ __ ] 100 miles 120 miles an hour or
blah blah blah you know telling these
stories and I'm like wow this guy's a
character you know and he was just cool
because he was telling me these old
stories of being in Europe and
different stuff and you know I wish I I
wish I could remember the stories more
clearly but what he did leave me with
the impression he left me with the
impression that
he was just a really uh
um just a nice guy really really a real
guy and had done real stuff and uh
and you know was was uh he was a
one-of-a-kind guy you wouldn't you know
and and everybody I've talked to was
like oh he you know he was the coolest
guy you could talk to with the shows and
stuff and he would go to the smallest
shows and the biggest shows and he was
you know the most approachable guy he
was a really good um he was a really
good role model I feel like for for
people in general and especially for
people like on the weed scene he was not
uh
he was not a
um pain in the ass he wasn't a douchey
dude he was just like uh
did what he liked to do and came to do
his thing and
um
you know I thought he was really uh
really kind of a remarkable guy in that
sense
um but anyway I I got the uh I got the
sour strawberry and I I grew my half
pack I still have a half pack of them
and I still have the other pack that I
can't put a finger on exactly what it is
but I think it's Boggle down because I
was interested in that because he's like
this is straight the straight bubble gum
in the bubble gum sense as opposed to
the sour bubble which you bread to be
more cushy and um
so
um
I grew those sour strawberries out and I
what happened was I missed a male in a
five and a half inch pot
in a flat of plants and I just looked I
had looked through them looked through
and looked through them and it was
probably like one where I was like ah
it's unsexed but it looks like a girl or
whatever you know classic story
and you know by the time I saw it was a
male it had a couple balls that had
popped so I wanted to put these few
stray seeds and one of the thing that
was in the flat with that
um there was a plant or two
um of this uh animal cookies cross
animal cookies cross Cherry West
and uh that cherry West was like one of
the ones that I was talking about where
they're not
um not crazy and exotic no tear penalty
no no fruit punch no watermelon no
floral it was just like uh one of the
more normal of the Cherry West like what
they usually are which is more like what
I call black cherry which was just this
deep Cherry kind of
um Berry flavored thing and uh
so
it was basically like animal cookies
Mutt and Seed you know and um super
Frosty really really nice
and my buddies in the bay called it the
knowledge and I have a picture like way
back on my feet somewhere of theirs from
indoor that's real pretty and
so I found these couple seeds
um
and you know I might still have a couple
of the original seeds I'm not sure I
really should you know hunt through to
see but anyway I took those and I bred
them and uh
and I have to them
and
I happen to find just a gorgeous male in
the F1 and put that on
two females that were my favorites and
one of them was more green and kind of
garlicky and one of them was more purple
and more kind of cookie gene pool type
stuff and so uh those ones I've uh I've
gone through them and
uh so you know kind of turn that into a
thing and those are really nice they're
like the sour bubble
um didn't the sour bubble added that
that broadleaf gnarly little squat thing
um
that they already had but it kind of
accentuated it
and it didn't take away from the resin
because it was really resinous too
and it added kind of like a jelly thing
that made it so that overall they kind
of have this like peanut butter and
jelly cookies thing
um but in a good way
and uh they're just gorgeous and it made
them have that more like classic uh
gnarly broadleaf chunk bud
um kind of like
kind of like hinduy look but
um just really really nice and and a lot
of them get really dark
and uh and I I was stoked because I have
the I have other lines that are the same
kind of cookie stuff
but the sour strawberry gave it this
other thing that is um I don't know
they're just really nice I like them a
lot and I did a lot of those
and I'm trying to you know I have f3s of
them now and hopefully they're good and
I'll probably make them into
f4s I'll probably clone some of the best
of the f3s and then uh you know try to
keep around to F maybe a pair of f3s to
make f4s
um
for a long time you know to just have
that be a thing and then I have you know
like I said I still have that uh half a
pack of those sour strawberries left so
if I can get those to crack I'll
probably breed that with the sour
strawberry again and try to make more
sour strawberries pure to have to to dig
into deeper knowing now that I like what
came out of it and then uh
I had to pack a sour bubble
and I had it for years
and then 2019
I grew them
and I was I kept the mail for a long
time
and I was gonna see them and I just kind
of didn't do it and then they really
started budding and I think I had only
got
like four plants out of my pack because
I had kept them for a while and I hadn't
had them stored well for a while because
I had left them out because I planned to
pop them for a whole year and then I
never got around to them and then
finally I put them away so I screwed
them up a little bit and uh
you know I always saw bog at the
different like he would come to the
farmer's market here
um and so like I was used to you know
seeing always his booth and I'll just
grab more you know
um so I didn't grab any of them and I
had that one pack I only got so many I
think I got a I think I got a boy that I
really liked and I should have kept
and uh I got a few girls and the girls
were just not quite what I wanted
um as far as the smells that they had
they were a little too plain but I
should have [ __ ] seeded them all
because the reality is that strain is
plain anyway
and there's some good ones that pop out
that have like a special liminess to it
and that contributed to like the sour
dub but
um
it's just not getting what you want out
of the few plants it doesn't really
matter you should just seed them and
then you'll have so many that you can
find what you want because all of a
sudden you'll have you know whatever
[ __ ] hundreds of thousands of f2s you
can look through and get exactly what
you want but I just kind of I kind of
[ __ ] them off and uh now you know I
kick myself because I'm like man I would
have had a bunch of those and if I had
had them in bulk right now I could
probably
um I could probably you know auction
them off and and shoot the shoot the
proceeds over to miss bog and [ __ ] and I
you know I don't really have anything to
do that but I do have the sour
strawberry cross and uh you know I could
do something with those and I'm waiting
to see how everything pans out right now
with their GoFundMe and if it doesn't if
it's if it goes slower than it should
you know we can maybe maybe go on go on
and do something online and then uh
and then uh their niece hit me up and
she she was kind of just filling me in
on where everything stands because I
guess she had seen my post
and um I told her you know I go hey if
there's anything you guys need up there
don't go without it because everybody
everybody loves them and they're you
know we'll get it we'll get it together
so hopefully they're
um you know hopefully everything works
out smoothly and you know if it if
there's any
real issues we you know everybody will
figure it out that's one cool thing
about a bunch of weed heads is they kind
of all
they kind of all have a good idea that
everything can go wrong when you're not
a square and you don't have a pension
and you don't have you know the things
that come with being a square so I think
there's a little more compassion in the
um amongst a bunch of weed heads uh and
Growers than there would be among people
who who don't like understand that world
you know
yeah there's definitely some good
camaraderie within the community when
people fall on hard times and so yeah
everyone check out the GoFundMe if
you're listening to this shortly after
the release and by all means if there's
any bug genetics you can scoop up now
would be a great time to add some good
ones to the library and funnily enough
I've actually grown out and worked with
some Sour strawberry hybrids a friend
did and they were all fire too so I'm
totally backing you on this sour
strawberry cross sounding like a a real
winner
I wanted to ask you we've spoken about a
plethora of different mythical and
Awesome Genetics
what seeds do you have in your Vault
that are some of the most special to you
you've probably got more than just one
but like some of the ones that come to
mind when you think of like the really
special ones to you and do you plan to
crack any of them anytime soon
my craziest stuff is the stuff I was
talking about that I can't get to Pop
um I'm really glad I got them in the
fridge when I did because I know they're
alive
um I know they're not rancid and they're
not overheated and dehydrated like
there's live cells they just don't have
enough to go
but
you know the old I have like Big Blue
Cross Big Red
those are old two afghanis that I mixed
together because I could never get a get
a good big blue male
and I wasn't I didn't know enough at the
time to realize that it's it's pretty
likely that the big blue male that
there's a sex-linked trait with the boys
that the boys never grow very fast
um and that's just how they are and I
just thought I had the terrible luck of
always having small boys
and now I'm like no dude those were all
fine males you just didn't know that
the males of big blue are small plants
you know so
um that's my theory anyway and I I think
it's probably accurate
um so I crossed it with big red uh
the black Affy
um I had a real special plan of the big
red that was different than the rest
that I crossed with the black coffee and
those got grown out and were incredible
but I didn't ever by the time I tried to
plant them they just wouldn't quite grow
it was like they would you put them in
water and after 24 hours Boom the tail
would be popping out and then it just
doesn't grow you know so those those
went in the fridge they've been there I
know they're good
um they just need tissue culture you
know they need more than I can do for
them
um those are special I still have the
original uh
uh p-o-g NL oil can
seeds
um that were the father side of the
uh black lime that were made with the
same with uh with the female
um that was the sister of the father of
black lime I still have the original
black lime F1 seeds I still have
a couple of the sisters of black lime
the original plant that I crossed with
the
with the POG
um
so I have those so they're basically the
same thing as black lime except instead
of the the black lime mother it's like a
what I called like black cranberry and
then one that looked like an NL
um I have those seeds
um I have uh
you know those things those older things
that the the the the black Affy cross
Hindu
the Hindu cross black Affy I mean and
the Hindu cross Hindu cross black Affy
those are right there in the top of what
I would get going if I knew I had a
reliable person to do tissue culture to
pull out cells and turn them into callus
and turn them into roots and shoots
um
and then you know there's a
there's the stuff that's newer that saw
that's also really special I mean as as
neat as those old things are and as much
potential there is and all that the
reason why I have what I have now is
because I made improvements on those
things
overall as far as like jarrow is like
you can still get kind of the Hindu AFI
type but they're way you know the plants
are five times bigger
um they're way more mold resistant and
you can still get the same kind of weed
out of those seeds
so that's the reason why some of these
things didn't get planted originally was
because they weren't practical and I had
made hybrids with them that were
practical and still had all the same
good things
it's like I was saying earlier though
you get attached to the idea of The
Originals and the provenance and the
Purity and
um all that and so that's why those
things are real special and then I have
like some seeds
um
I have some seeds uh my good good friend
Maurice passed away in
um 2008. and his dad was like a kind of
a legendary guy a really really good
artist
um a Frenchman and uh
he
um
had got some seeds from me around maybe
2006 and he had his own seeds that he
had kept for years and
um
he you know he's passed as well past
like the following year uh
after my buddy and he was my buddy too
you know and he
had a big seed collection and
um
his uh his his wife found it a few years
later in a fridge and she said hey I
don't know who else would really want
this and there might even be some of
your seeds in there and do you want them
and I was like yeah
so she gave me that collection and some
of those are still viable but at the
same time I'm afraid to plant them a
little bit I took them out and repacked
them and made sure they were real dry
they actually had some moisture in them
and I thought that it would have ruined
all of them because when I opened up the
bags there was like literally like water
in some of the bags that had probably
been there for two or three years at the
least and uh I repacked them and I tried
some of them and I got a couple of them
to get a couple of uh uh plants that
actually grew and then they wound up
getting messed up and I didn't get to
get them to go all the way but they they
would have it was my fault but I had
only tried a couple of ones and there
was a lot of them in there so it made me
know they were viable and those are
really special
um
there's one in there called I forgot
there's one in there called BMW Bob
Marley and the Whalers
um there's one
there's a couple in there that have like
just a symbol and I don't know what it
means there's a couple with initials and
I don't know what they mean there's one
in there that have seeds that are huge
like they're almost as big as peas
really you know they're like very big
big big seeds from some kind of an old
Afghani I assume he always had really
tasty weed like when he would be rolling
up weed we'd always want to check it out
um
so old school dudes spent a lot of time
in uh in Goa in India and uh is just
like
really really
um cool dude and kind of you know uh
you know old school dude
um grew we'd totally secretly
and was just an artist and you know had
his little had a couple plants and stuff
and you know always had good smoke and
stuff and uh
but um those are really special just
because of the of the story and and who
they're from and and
um all that and then
thinking of what else I'm trying to
think of if there's anything else that's
really really crazy I mean you know
there's stuff that I have of course
um
you know Cherry limes limes root beers
those are all cool but those older ones
that I can't get to pop are actually the
ones that are the most special
and you know I've looked into a couple
Labs I've talked to a couple people
um and I'm just trying to find somebody
who
won't kill him won't
rip me off and you know and has the
right knowledge to do that kind of stuff
and it's a pretty standard technique but
there's a divide between people who do
standard tissue culture for things like
orchids and who really have the right
Tech and for people who do
um
who do stuff with weed tissue culture
because weed tissue culture tends to be
like meristem and maybe putting seeds
into a meaty into a into a media and
getting them to sprout helping them
along but I'd really like to find
somebody who can just slice that seed
down the middle like a mushroom pull out
a little chunk grow that callus and turn
that into plants and it's not that
people don't do it but like I said
there's a little divide and I you know
apologies to anybody if I talked about
the [ __ ] on the last one because uh I'm
always talking about this [ __ ] because
it's like the the holy grail for
everybody because people have there's a
lot of seeds
that won't come up
that still have the genetics inside of
them so it's like a really important
thing I'm always hoping there's somebody
who is
uh legit who you know winds up getting
into this ship because it's pretty
important for sure if anyone has that
knowledge or ability you know the man to
hit up let's make it happen
I have to admit I was kind of trying to
uh bait you with that question to talk
about the seeds I've seen on your
Instagram page of the Big Sur it's an
interesting one for me because I find it
really hard to get like good information
on Big Sur it's sort of like this
mythical strain anyway what's your
experience and um if you had to guess
the genetics behind it what do you
think's in it
so interestingly enough
I haven't actually grown Big Sur holy
weed I have a thing from Big Sur
called Dolores
and I got it from some friends of mine
up here
who I trade seeds with and they
um are just old school people who like
they grow something and they're like oh
this is good you know and they keep it
and maybe they make some more
move on to something else and have had
stuff from you know from way back in the
day they're they're old school they're
in their 60s you know and uh
really nice people and you know they
told me hey we have this really cool
Mexican do you want to grow some Mexican
and I was like well does it finish here
and they were like yeah yeah no it's
it's really nice
and I was like oh that's interesting I'm
always interested in Mexican stuff
that's more fast and and can be grown
here because there's a lot of different
climates in Mexico some of us some of
Mexico is really mountainous and you
can't grow like crazy sativas you know
so
the oaxacan's always been really popular
here from the 70s and
um it was kind of the best thing as far
as I can tell before The Afghani and
Pakistani came in for this climate and
um
so
they gave me these ones and I grew them
and what was really interesting to me
and my mom said the same thing they're
kind of the closest thing to the type of
Northern Lights that we had which I
believe was
not the one or the two I think it was
you know like the two crossed the five
or something
or whatever
um I I just think that the Northern
Lights we had had something else in it
besides straight Afghani
and growing these
the way they look when you grow a lot of
them it almost makes me wonder like is
this like a relative of the type of
Mexican that might have been in one of
the kinds of Northern Lights that was
used by the seed bank because you know
the Northern Lights was like there was
there was straight Afghani and then
there was Afghani across a different
Afghani and there was Afghani across
Hawaiian and there was Afghani cross
Mexican and I'm like well
they're really really like really
familiar
um the way they look the way the plant
looks the way it grows the color of the
weed the color of the resin the type of
resin
the fact that they're not particularly
smelly in any real outstanding way they
kind of have like yeah they're a little
sweet they have something to them not
sweet enough to call Fruity
sweet Kefi Hashi you know
um
but I was told
that the Mexican used in the Big Sur
Hollywood
is Dolores
um and mine came from Big Sur from
people who have had it I guess since
like the 70s
um I mean that's this that's the story
and this isn't from people this is from
people who are not in the whole scene of
um trying to show off any provenance or
anything like that so you know their
story with me uh holds water because I'm
like hey what are they they're like oh
this guy he's our friend you know he's
had this Mexican since the 70s he really
likes it
um I'm like well do you know where it's
from and they're like yeah it's it's
from Dolores and I'm like oh okay
so
you know Dolores Hidalgo is this place
that's in the mountains in Mexico
um it makes sense that what came from
there would have been something that
probably would have finished a little
bit quicker than other stuff after they
had selected it for their climate
um
I don't know it's been big Surfer
[ __ ] 45 years or whatever
um and uh that's the closest to what I
have so this this year I made a whole
bunch
um there's two basic types there's one
that's more
of like
you know what people would call an
Indica where the buds are more easy to
trim and the plant is a little more
squat in there the buds are a little
more round and fat and uh and when I
first grew some of them a couple years
ago I went these seem like they're not
the same type like maybe they're
pollution from some other line
and so this year I did a bunch of them
and then
I went ahead and got rid of the males
that looked like that type
but I kept the girls so that I could
kind of get an idea of what they are and
now at this point I don't think they're
a different type
I think they're just a little bit better
of a of a bud shape and a little bit
more squat of a plant but still the same
thing
so if I make them again from the
original seeds I'll probably split them
into two lines and do like open
pollination with the tall
slightly more leafy ones and do an open
pollination with the short more golf
Bali ones
and um
this time what I did was I just did more
of the taller ones because they were the
ones that I related more to be in like
the true what I expected from a from a
Mexican type
um and uh they
think are probably the ones that are a
little bit more
um a little bit more what I want and a
little more like what our Northern
Lights was
the other ones are a little bit
um
I don't know like uh
like more of a squat little Christmas
tree more
you know they're definitely not like you
can't say they're like an Afghani type
Indica type thing broadleaf they're not
really but they just have a little bit
they're a little bit less
um they're a little bit less of a narrow
leaf type and the the ones that are the
more narrow leaf type are still like
more almost like kind of like a OG plant
but the squat ones are more like a OG
shaped bud you know
so
um they're really interesting and so you
know I made a whole bunch of those and I
asked if I could
um if I could share them and they were
like yeah we don't you know they thought
I was crazy for even you know wondering
if I they're like yeah like what do you
mean I was like well can I like make
stuff with them and and you know do do
whatever with them and they're like yeah
nobody cares it's like Okay cool so I
think what I'm probably gonna do I was
gonna give some of them to CSI so he
could look through them because he has a
a really cool Big Sir holy weed cut
um
and then I'll probably just try to
spread them around a little bit and then
you know
somebody will be able to kind of tell if
there's any if there's any relation
there and maybe they're not just because
they're you know
um from the same place doesn't mean that
they have anything to do except it'd be
kind of weird if there was
Dolores in the
Big Sir holy weed and there was Dolores
in Big Sur since the 70s and they didn't
have any relation
um
that would be really [ __ ] strange so
I think there's a relation there but as
far as Big Sir holy weed I don't
I can't even remember seeing it I think
I've seen some of it before I've
definitely talked to people a lot about
it because people said it was so good
but um I have some
from SoCal seeds
and then I think I have some possibly
from Coastal
which are slightly different lines and
then I think Bodhi has one a little
different than what Coastal has but I I
was interested in it but I've never
actually done any of them so I can't say
like Hands-On what they look like in any
similarity or whatever but I will say
the Dolores
I
smoke
and it has a very interesting potency
where it kind of makes things seem
like lightly absurd like you kind of get
a chuckle out of everything from it and
when you like you can like stare at a
wall
and it's not like directly visuals but
you really look and you're like am I is
something happening
is there like
am I getting a visual and you're like
look and you go no it's normal but you
stare and you go I
I feel like there's something I feel
like I'm almost getting like a visual
here you know it's pretty neat it's a
cool um it's a cool kind of high and I
don't know
if you're a super super heavy daily
smoker like I used to always be I don't
know that you would notice that Nuance
of it but um it's definitely not just
your normal high it's definitely
um there's definitely some you know
narrow Leaf stuff going on there it's
not a it's not a dole high at all it
makes you feel
neat you know there's something to it so
those are cool plants and they're really
hearty they don't mold
um they don't like to get PM unless you
really kind of making them unhealthy
uh they're not the sturdiest because
they Bud pretty gnarly but like
they're they're they're they're a really
really good plant there's something that
I'll definitely uh I'll definitely try
to spread around and I don't know how
many I have now but I think I have
thousands of them I think I have maybe
like 10 girls fully Seated on The Late
side so they're not like corn on the cob
but they're like all around the outside
of the bud there's a bunch of mature
seed you know so there's there should be
enough to um that after you know a
couple years there should be something
that's kind of uh around you know
what a great answer and um a really
interesting High by the sounds of it you
mentioned in there wanting to figure out
you know if Dolores was the same or a
part of the Big Sur at least and it made
me think back to a comment you made
earlier about phylos and like how they
elude relationships between strains and
stuff and I guess what I'm interested in
kind of discussing is obviously people
have pretty valid concerns for not
trusting file us with genetic samples
anymore but I do Wonder
do we have any faith in the technology
but you know if we kind of put aside
personal feelings about the people
running the company and their intentions
do you when something on filos shows
something else as a relative for example
do you put any stock in that anymore
you know I do
there's levels to what they can do so
if it says something is related
it's very closely related
if it says something is not related
it might still be very closely related
and if it says something is the same
it might just be related
meaning if you give them s1s from a
plant
they'll think they're all the same plan
but they're not
if you give them something that's been
bred apart for a few Generations
they'll think it's not very closely
related to anything even though it
really is
so
for example I have cherry limeade F3 in
there right
um
they can't show that it's related to OG
or Urkel
or
you know black line Reserve which is in
there
um
Northern Lights like I know what's in
there right
but in their
analysis they're like oh yeah it's not
related to anything closely I'm like
well there's a lot of Urkel and a lot of
OG in it I just know that you know
um
and it just doesn't show it so in that
sense they can't quite do what they kind
of say they can do
but at the same time
it makes me realize that if they tell
you that it's related
it's related you know what I mean and
they've shown relations that
are easy to know through other avenues
and then you look at their thing and you
go yeah they know it
there it is you know
so
um
you know I it's a weird thing because
it's like okay should you trust them and
think that everything they say is true
and no
but at the same time I'm like I I don't
really see what I lost by having my
stuff in there
um
I didn't really gain much
but with certain samples I think you
could you know there is something to
gain I think it might be worth putting
in Big Sur holy weed and putting in
Dolores but knowing what I know it's
likely that because Big Sir holy weed
has been bred several times and Dolores
has been bred several times they
probably won't show
um any relation even if they were
related because
what they're good at showing is when
things are sisters or parents
or progeny
um
as soon as something's not a first
cousin
or a second cousin it seems like they
kind of can't see it and as soon as
something is a
full
um like as soon as something is an S1
and there's no outside genetics then
there's no outside genetics so it's
obviously the same but that's not true
you know so they'll tell you that ghost
OG Skywalker and every other OG cutter
all the same cut
so when you grow them you'll think oh
well there must have just been some kind
of uh
you know epigenetics or
something happened where this got turned
on and that got turned off and then you
know it caused this uh outward
appearance of a mutation so that now it
seems like this one's different than
this one but look there's the genetic
test they're both the same it's like nah
they're they're not they're not the same
because people have actually taken
a couple s1s
that they know they started themselves
from seed and sent them in and they're
like Yep this is all all three of these
are one plant and they're like no I
popped those and I know I didn't mix up
the samples and they're like yeah sorry
I guess you you you mixed it up like I
asked them on there on one of their like
on their Instagram one time I was like
Hey like you know do you guys realize
that you can't tell the difference
between plants from seed that come from
one parent with no outside influence and
they were like no we can tell the
difference if we say it's the same it's
the same and I was like you can't though
and they didn't want to admit that which
to me was you know uh
a fundamental issue in in in scientific
work like
you know a scientist has to be able to
go oh there's an anomaly here okay well
let's look into that as opposed to going
no our our technique is sound it's like
hey you know
you have to be able to throw everything
away that you thought right now
everything you know if you want to be
actual you know if you want to be a real
scientist
you have to be able to to be able to be
handed new evidence and be able to throw
away every [ __ ] thing you knew
yesterday and go we have a new
understanding today that's what science
is otherwise if you if you just cling to
thinking you're right that's that's not
what science is Science is based on you
know science science is is uh is data
driven you know and evidence driven it's
not based on you know just thinking that
if it's if it's if it's like this it's
like this it's like no this evidence
says it's not like this but
anyway you know so those are the issues
that I see with their thing
um I see issues with them ethically
um because of what they did they
basically told the community this this
data is completely worthless
and they told their investors this data
is completely priceless
and one of those things is a lie so
either you're lying to your investors or
you're lying to the people who are
paying you to do analysis and
um you know I think they were not lying
to the investors I think that they were
creating a data set that was actually a
valuable
um a valuable thing because
you know we we don't really know the
other stuff that they were doing besides
that little Galaxy stuff they also could
be putting things together and they said
it's worthless because we don't know
about the plants so if you don't have
the plant you don't know what it is but
it's like ah so you don't already have a
description of an OG
like they do have a description of what
it is and when they can find these
things that pop up commonly they could
find markers and they could do Marker
assisted breeding and they could use
that data to drive their breeding
program which they basically admitted
was what they were going to do
and uh
you know that's that seems like some
[ __ ] to me but at the same time like
I said I'm not completely against giving
him something it's just that when you
give them something they should be
saying hey you give us something and
you're going to pay us money and we're
gonna make money off what you give us
too and for me I'm like yeah I mean I
maybe I'll give you something but I
don't want to pay you because you guys
are already making money on the back end
so [ __ ] that you know that's my take on
their on their operation
I think a lot of people will rightly
feel the same way as you and uh it's
kind of quite backroom Shady practices
all the trying to selling of the data
they did I think I heard or read
somewhere probably read somewhere like
they tried to sell
the data set to a big ad company and
because of the exact reasons you kind of
discussed the big AG were like this data
is useless like it's incomplete but it's
just kind of funny that they might have
like screwed over themselves in all
regards
yeah I
I mean I kind of feel like that's their
story is that the data was incomplete
and worthless
um and that that's what they said to
cover their ass and once again like I I
can't say that that's true or that it's
untrue
but
I kind of feel like
if they had a pretty thorough analysis
of all these different things I feel
like there's probably
a way that they could have looked at
commonalities between certain
things and seen a trend enough to know
if they did a little research that oh
these are the strains that are powdery
mildew resistant
and look they all have this in common
and these are the strains that are high
THC and they all have this in common
these are just examples I don't know
that they would really need any of this
yeah yeah but
I feel like if they collected that many
plants and they say oh well you have to
have the plant to be able to know what
these things mean
I feel like you don't really necessarily
have to I think all you would really
have to do is know
the outward features of the phenotypes
of these plants
and be able to see trends
you know what I mean
to be able to say these are the genes
that rule potency these are the genes
that rule high terpene content these are
the genes that rule mold resistance
these are the genes that rule
um that control
um fast rooting these are the genes that
that that control fast uh you know the
the fastest maturing
um samples
like those things aren't that hard it's
not that hard to to find those things
out in my opinion you know to know like
um
you know I mean I don't know how much of
that they really got but it it's just I
don't know I I feel like they're they're
they're
um
even if it was worthless to them they
could have made it worth something you
know
I don't know it's just a
just a theory but
you know I mean I feel like you could
kind of go through and and do a little
research and go oh what's good about
this plant what's good about that plant
what's good about this one and put that
all into your program and go oh these
all have this in common and look hey
they have these markers
this is the thing they all share in
common so that must be it must be this
gene or it must be these you know 32
genes these control this when they're
all when they're all here that may that
means you get this this is purple weed
this is mold proof weed or whatever it
is because that's what you know that's
what other people went through and did
they went okay this is the gene that
controls
um
THC and then they got rid of that and
they went oh [ __ ] that was also the gene
that controlled mold resistance so when
you get rid of the THC to make hemp then
you just destroyed mold resistance so
now all these people who have this who
who spent this money to in their
breeding program to go oh well our hemp
will never have THC because we went
right around that Gene we don't even
have that Gene present in this
population then they grew it and they
found out oh [ __ ] that also adds mold
resistance so they had all this perfect
temp that all rotted in the fields
because they had completely eliminated
it when they just needed to figure out
how to minimize thca they eliminated
thca and all their crops rotted you know
so however those guys went about getting
that data I would imagine that philos
could have done the same thing with all
the samples they had as they analyzed
them as well you know I mean I don't
know but it just seems like that would
be
a practical thing to do with such a huge
collection of various genetics you know
I don't know how many samples they took
them but it was a lot they have a pretty
big Galaxy
but there'd definitely be some Trends
there I think it's called concordance of
like traits or something but um
definitely definitely still valid points
kind of on that same topic of being a
bit skeptical of sort of bigger AG big
companies in general I remember about
four or five years ago when um wreck in
Cali rolled through there was this big
fear that like the big sort of companies
were going to come in and just build
these huge facilities just pump out
Production Drive the prices down and you
know everyone was going to lose it seems
as though over the past year or two
we've seen kind of the opposite in that
I mean at least in Canada for example
some of the biggest producers are just
failing and just losing I think the
industry lost billions of dollars over
the past Financial year and I know that
there aren't any notably big companies
in the states who are just on top of the
game like they're all kind of producing
lesser quality stuff do you think that
this is like an accurate sort of
portrayal of things do you think like
the bigger companies are going to
generally continue to struggle to
produce good quality product
and do you think that the small time
producers will have a chance to jump
back into the game
well it's an interesting thing
and I probably shouldn't even really
tell them but the the the the people who
had the big bucks and could afford to
bully their way into the market
I think they could have probably done
all right if they would have come in and
understood that you need to have minimal
investment in infrastructure and minimal
investment
um in you know in in various aspects but
really focused on okay
who can we get that can really grow weed
that already grows weed how do they do
it
and let's invest in them
and give them the ability to grow more
weed
um
and then kind of rolled with it but
instead what they kind of tried to do it
seems
uh it seems like they came in and they
went okay we have money and this was no
shock to anybody but
we have a lot of money
will come in
and we will do everything the way all
these dumbasses should have been doing
it but they're all dumb dope Growers
they don't know how to do this [ __ ]
we're going to come in here with a real
professional [ __ ] we're going to build
this 250 million dollar Greenhouse
complex
then we're gonna get a bunch of [ __ ]
random people and we're just going to
tell them how to do it because
it's just a plant and people grow plants
all the time and we're gonna we're gonna
be bigger and better
um
and I you know I think they just kind of
dropped the ball with that mentality it
seems like I mean I'm not on the inside
but
um
it's nuts because I see the facilities
that they built out and I'm like you
know guys you could have just instead of
building those [ __ ]
you know 150 greenhouses you guys could
have just built like four of them
and got a guy who's used to growing like
a quarter of that and got him some good
help where he could just point point
fingers and tell him tell tell the
workers what to do
um and they could have they could have
taken you know somebody's existing
expertise and scaled it up by giving
them the ability to do that
and it would work and I feel like that's
kind of what the little guys did
um
because
they had a better idea of how [ __ ]
really works
and so I think it gave them the
advantage
um and when I say little guys I don't
mean little little guys but I mean like
you know jungle boys or whoever seems to
be kind of hanging in there
um
it just seems like uh
it's a really hard thing to do if you're
just gonna come in from the outside and
just have it work and I mean I I could
tell you that because I know what it was
like to try to figure it out it wasn't
easy and um you know I did a lot of dumb
[ __ ] when I started and you think you
can try this and you know you know what
to do you know what you're doing and
then you're like huh okay
well that didn't work but at least I
didn't invest 300 million dollars into
it and then it didn't work because when
you do that it's like well how are you
gonna you know everybody thought they'll
just have endless money to put into it
but
they you know they don't have that much
money
you know
um so
yeah I don't know I I think everything I
think
in general the way
everything works is everything's kind of
designed for
the bigger people to do the best
and they still have the advantage
and
they came in and did stuff so miserably
that they still [ __ ] it off
and uh
you know I mean I don't know I mean the
way the way everything's set up is like
if you're the big if you're the big
company if you're Walmart if you're
Amazon if you're Costco if you're
whatever the biggest things are that's
the easiest things in these times
to really have be like
sustainable and keep going you know like
the bigger the better
and
um
if you look at though with the way those
things operate though it's like they
really figure out okay what are what are
we really trying to do what kind of
service are we bring in
um you know it's like they they figure
it out and then they get it right I'm
sure a lot of people tried and failed
um there was probably a lot of
competitors to Amazon or to Walmart at
the same time
but um
you know maybe we'll see that maybe
there'll be this one company that
actually didn't
you know [ __ ] everything off but um
I don't know at this point it's looking
like
um
you know they're making it really hard
for the little guy but the little guy
still understands what it's like to do
something that's really [ __ ] hard
because that's what they're used to and
the big guys
are maybe a little a little too
comfortable with how they did stuff you
know I don't really know like I said I'm
not in the inside of it so I don't know
exactly what goes wrong but I do I do
see what goes right for people and it's
usually
you know a guy who's good at doing
20 lights so he goes we're going to do
200 lights and I'm going to hire six
guys and then they you know they're able
to they're able to do it they keep it
going and and it's able to work you know
as opposed to somebody who's used to
running zero lights and they decide
they're going to do 2600 lights and
then you know they're just [ __ ] it's
a it's a weird thing it's really easy to
have huge disasters when you're trying
to grow plants and then it's not like
it's even regular agriculture it's this
weird massive Horticulture in a sense
because it's you're growing indoor on a
huge scale
in these greenhouses it's a I don't know
it's a weird it's a weird thing I mean
the pressure in those operations from
pests and pathogens and stuff is huge
and then it's all you know it's mono
cropping and there's a lot of room for a
lot of room for error so you know
hopefully the little guys can continue
to make it it just seems like it's
it's almost impossible for the big guys
to do it and then they try to make it
really really hard for the little guys
to get their foot in the door and um you
know like I it's just this kind of
um kind of [ __ ] up balance of stuff
you know but um
you know I I hope I hope it's the the
little guys went out and the big guys
can't make it you know and um that would
be great but we'll you know we'll see
where it's going it's really interesting
to see I'm really happy to see like you
know you looking on something and
they're like oh 250 million dollar
greenhouses and they're just shutting
them down they're not going to reopen
them like wow okay sweet because uh
you know nobody needed that [ __ ] that
was a weird that was a weird play in the
first place like what are they going to
produce out of that
there's going to be a bunch of you know
it's weird it's like an operation to
make really good weed but it's on such a
big scale it'll never make really good
weed so the same dudes who did that they
should have just planted [ __ ] 150
acres of hemp and sold CBD all over the
world or something but
um instead they spend a million times as
much money and then
they you know
frazzle out it's a weird uh
it's it's it's silly you know it's a
funny thing to watch
yeah understandable and do you think
that the average grower or consumer is
in any better position after the changes
brought in with legalization and if you
could make say a couple of small changes
to the laws that would ideally improve
you know the lives of Growers are there
any that immediately jump to mind that
you'd want to do I remember that for a
long time there was the discussion about
the uh I think it was like the one acre
per Farm sort of thing do you have any
ideas like that
I mean my opinion of the whole thing is
that
they already know how crazy the economy
is fed by
cannabis in general it's huge
um
I felt like if they would have made it
so that you can have weed stores but if
you want a store you have to sell safe
tested product
and if you want to sell at a store you
have to have safe tested product
um
and then maybe make one little
regulation that
um it's illegal to sell something that
has something that's toxic and make a
list you know
so that there's some kind of recourse if
it turns out that somebody oh these
people are selling all this stuff and it
turns out oh it's poisoned or whatever
you know
um
but I felt like if they would have just
kind of made it so that it's like oh
cool
everybody can do what they want but it
is capped you know like uh
maybe if you want to grow more than 100
plants you need to have a permit
or something like that you know what I
mean like if if you're going to produce
more than
100 pounds a year then you have to have
a permit but you can go ahead and just
produce that because it's just it's
[ __ ] weed it's pretty much harmless
you know
um it's pretty low impact if you're not
growing a ton and then if you do want to
grow a whole lot of weed then cool get a
permit you know but basically like I I
think you know this is just me throwing
it out there and I'm not sitting down in
a in a room and we're not writing it all
down and figuring out what's really the
best but
I think stuff could have been kind of
more just just more vague like that
being that we already had a functioning
system
of people growing weed and smoking weed
and selling weed and I wasn't hearing
about people having a bunch of bad
experiences from bad weed or
any of this kind of stuff the the only
stuff I can find that's really bad about
wheat is prohibition you get busted or
the price gets artificially inflated
which causes a lot of crime because now
there's too much money in the business
that wouldn't exist if
it was legal because everything would
level out a lot of people wouldn't be
doing it and a lot of people who
have no opportunities who find
themselves in weird positions doing
shady [ __ ] they could just [ __ ] sell
some weed instead
you know if you have
a neighborhood where people are all just
hanging out like [ __ ] you can have a
couple people selling sacks there and
you know you might have somebody selling
this weed this person's selling that
weed like it's a really great
um
tool for any economy because people want
weed it's good for them does a lot of
good stuff makes people feel good people
are interested in it so it's not like
one is the same as all of it it's not
like selling hard drugs where one
person's hard drugs the same as any
other hard drug like it's not like
people want a different flavor of heroin
or a different flavor of crack they just
are trying to get it so one person can
lock down the whole trade but with weed
it's like oh well yeah that person might
have locked down OG but this guy doesn't
like OG wants sour well this guy over
here he's selling sour and
it's as an economy it's really a lot
more it's like such a neat thing the way
it exists
um for people it can be used for a lot
so like for me it's like
make it legal and if people do other
[ __ ] that's already a crime with it
maybe you'd have to add like I said okay
well you're selling unsafe weed that's
not
uh there's no law for that because all
weed's illegal but you make it legal you
go well it has to be safe weed maybe
make that you know some kind of a
offense
but other than that like
you know like hey you rob somebody for
weed well [ __ ] it's already illegal to
rob somebody oh you [ __ ] you know you
smoked weed and you drove something and
you [ __ ] drove somebody off the road
[ __ ] because you're not used to it or
you ate some crazy Edibles and passed
out or some [ __ ] which probably wouldn't
happen but that's what people are afraid
of but sweet it's already [ __ ]
illegal so like there's no reason for
just a drug to carry a crime for the
drug just make all the dumb [ __ ] people
do that's illegal that's what's [ __ ]
illegal you know that's all that's the
only way you really have to do stuff
um the way that they did everything with
so much regulation and everything it
just it's to me it's just backwards from
the start like you got a plant
let people grow the plant
and then you know like when everybody
was making tons of of money it's funny
because they go okay we want to get
uh we want to get our money from the
taxes and everybody goes yeah that's
good the tax money the tax money that's
like well when weed was illegal but
everybody was making billions of dollars
off of it in California because they say
it's like a 10 billion dollar business
or something in California well
the state was realistically already
making probably a billion dollars just
off a sales tax
and every time there's a tax on all
these other things that are on all these
different things like you know you've
got different taxes that go into you got
Hotel taxes you got gas tax you got
tobacco tax you got all these things
well guess where the money comes from
that is getting taxed when you buy all
these things it's coming from a lot of
weed trade
so
now they're like oh yeah we're doing
good we made a billion dollars in
California off the weed trade this year
I'm like well but you just they say 8.7
billion that they didn't tax
so I'm like well if it was 10 billion
and you guys already had eight percent
sales tax plus all these other random
taxes that are all worked into
everything some of them that are high
like hotel rooms in San Francisco is
like 22 percent and [ __ ] hotel tax like
all these things that are producing all
this stuff the money is all coming from
it I'm like well sweet so now you guys
are getting your billion dollars but
you've always been getting the [ __ ]
billion dollars if the trade is 10
billion dollars and you guys have been
getting 10 of everybody's money not to
mention everybody who was who has a
business
and has a like you got a restaurant the
people coming into your restaurant a
bunch of them are spending weed money
well the owner of that restaurant pays
income tax you know a lot of these
people who grow weed and have money they
might be they might have a they might
have another business and that business
is paying income tax there's all this
stuff where there's all this different
[ __ ] going on and by having a healthy
economy
they're making billions of dollars
anyway
so they just want to be able to count it
but it's like nobody realizes they were
already getting a billion dollars now
they're like we made a billion dollars
off of weed this year it's like you you
know same [ __ ] old billion dollars
except now there's a bunch of people who
you know are uh
you know not not you know and then I
gotta wonder about the the biggest the
biggest corporations and [ __ ] who are do
have these 250 million dollar
greenhouses like those people might be
paying the taxes
on
stuff now and on like the weed and
everything but as soon as they were in
the game for a little while and they
Lobby for [ __ ] to change and all this
and those little [ __ ] rules and
loopholes and their [ __ ] fancy
[ __ ] attorneys and all this [ __ ]
those people probably would have been
just like all the other rich people who
don't really [ __ ] pay taxes anyway
um
so why give it to them you know and the
rich people don't spend money at the
little businesses
the rich people don't the the money
doesn't really [ __ ] you know or
whereas talking to the talking about
this the other night on this with some
buddies on a on a zoom thing like the
money
the money from Little People
who have their little weed or their
little business or whatever they do that
are you know they they don't make that
much money that money goes everywhere
not only does it go into the not only do
they walk into the little liquor store
the little the little General Store the
grocery store the clothing store the
restaurant all this different [ __ ] they
do all that and then they also pay the
money that goes to the government and
then okay it's going up to these people
who have more and the people who you
know it's also going to Walmart and
Amazon and these bigger corporations too
but you don't see you're not going to
see
um Bezos or Gates or any of these really
rich people their money doesn't go to
the little businesses it's just not how
it works they're not taking their money
and going and shopping at the little
store they're not going and buying their
clothes at the little store they're not
doing the money from up there never
comes back down but the money from the
bottom goes up so you really want the
[ __ ] to be healthy on a small level and
it'll feed the big level you know but
the way the whole system is set up is to
favor those bigger players and their
their [ __ ] doesn't go down so it just
it's not a
it's not a healthy model and it's not a
real form of capitalism
um
it's just a weird it's a weird perverted
capitalism that's more uh
predatory and like it's more like uh
more like Barons and peasants you know
so
um
you know hopefully we see that hopefully
the small guys can can can do well and
it can shift a little and we see you
know maybe it's one thing where like
they have the advantage and it pans out
over time and I think it can but like
that's a that's a crazy thing I don't
think that there's any
um
there's any point to trying to you know
feed these these these uh fat cats when
they're not really the the money goes
with them and it stays with them
and if you uh if the money comes from
the from the little guys the money goes
everywhere it goes all around and it
goes up to the top too so that's in my
opinion just on looking at things and
through history and what's been helpful
and uh
mechanically what works you know the
whole trickle-down [ __ ] is total
[ __ ]
um and and having a small having a
healthy economy on the on the small
um level and the little guys is where
things really go and just by leaving
people to do whatever they wanted with
weed like it was basically in 215 if
they would have basically just stopped
putting people in jail
um and tell people you can't sell
poisonous weed pretty much with it
solved the whole thing and maybe one day
we'll get to that point you know and if
that if if we got to that point that's
when I would say okay that's where it
should be it's um if you want to have a
big business cool maybe you need to be
regulated because you're big but if you
just got a little bit of weed you should
just be able to do whatever the [ __ ] you
want with it in my opinion you know
totally and what an insightful sort of
uh take on the whole situation if we
kind of look at uh one of the people who
the public sometimes forget are in fact
uh one of the smaller guys we reference
jungle boys they're certainly doing
things right and uh getting a little
bigger but still smaller guys compared
to the big AG I wanted to bring them up
because recently an interview came out
with them where they said they don't
cure their flour before sale and when
Ivan was pressed a little bit about why
that is he says oh you know it's because
um the Terps are like at their most
highest concentration and they're kind
of most popping at that point so my
question is do you think that all weeds
should be cured and do you kind of
understand this underlying idea that
he's presenting that like the most
freshest the Cannabis is ever going to
be is before a cure
I mean I've seen some weed and I know
like with like um some crazy narrow Leaf
stuff like that would never be anything
they'd be growing because it's not
practical and it's not so much what
people want you know
um I think some of those things are
better after they sit and cure but I
think for people who just want really
loud
stinky weed with the most Terps and the
brightest color and kind of what people
want in the market
I think people do want fresh weed you
know and I am of the opinion
that when your weed is when your weed is
dry
like I don't put wheat away when
it's a little wet and burp it like to me
that always winds up fermenting the weed
and I've done it side by side lots of
different ways on accident on purpose
jars bags tubs whatever and to me you
dry the weed so that it takes a while to
get dry and you keep it cool
and when it gets done
to me that's it it's there like you know
I I
believe that the drying process is the
cure and to me that takes between two
and three weeks ideally about three
weeks to really be there
and at that point it should be all the
way dry and you put it away and I don't
think it ever gets any better unless
maybe it's like I said an odd odd type
you know but as far as if you're growing
like OG and cookies derivatives and all
these things I think you know let it
that it should be it should be hanging
up until
it is
dry throughout
and that at that point you should be
able to put it away and it should be
sticky and dank
and the stems should be Snappy and dry
the weed should be sticky
and it should be dry weed as dry as you
want it and that's it and you seal it up
and it's done you know and that's how
um that's how it comes out best for me
that's the way that it smells like what
it's supposed to smell like and it
tastes like what it's supposed to taste
like like that is its identity captured
like you wanted OG well smell this this
is OG and you're like damn that's
[ __ ] good and if you put it away when
it's a little moist and you burp it and
[ __ ] it'll just you're just gonna make
it smell like dough you know it's just
gonna get
um fermented and there's gonna be you
know Funk and it's not you're gonna lose
it's it's gonna lose its sharpness you
know in my experience
so the reason why I asked that question
actually is because I noticed while
reading the sky kind of the cush
description you mentioned that it has a
long shelf life and it kind of got me
thinking about the two polar ends of the
spectrum where you know you've got Ivan
saying it's best at the start but then
you're kind of introducing this idea
that these genetics are designed to kind
of retain the Terps and it's gonna have
a longer shelf life and a stability in
that regard do you think that's kind of
an accurate take on the situation and
um as like a bit of a follow-up do you
think that it might benefit shops or
sellers to think about this and try to
stock like one of each so they've got
like both the short and long term
covered
yeah I mean there's certain things like
um you know I say like the sky cuddler
cushions Sky cover Kush jarrow root beer
they have good shelf life because of the
type of resin that they have the resin
stays in the resin like it is on the
weed but it's where it is and it stays
there and it's solid and it's not greasy
um something like cherry limeade when it
sits the resin is so
um
oily and the resin heads have such a
thin membrane
um
that it actually the the weed itself
will soak up the resin because it's it's
it's wet it's not wet but the oil is
um
the oil is so thin and runny in a sense
you know what I mean
that it wants to soak into the weed and
so it turns the weed dark it stays tasty
it's not like there's anything wrong
with it but it's like you look at cherry
limeade fresh it's not every plant but
most of them you look at it fresh and it
looks incredible and then you have it
for three or four weeks and you're like
oh it looks really dark
and
and it almost looks like what other weed
looks like if you were to go to [ __ ] up
and go oops I spilled some oil on it or
um you know somebody was being a
goofball and dipped it in [ __ ] uh you
know like the first step of moon rocks
or some [ __ ] it's just like it's greasy
and dark and if you're really
um if you really know what's up with it
then you just look at it and you go oh
damn crazy you know like that's nice and
you can appreciate it but people want a
certain type of product presented to
them when they buy a jar or a bag of
weed
um and it doesn't really fit so for a
smoker if I give you some year old
cherry limeade and it's all greased out
you're like oh damn okay this is nice
and you roll it up and you're like [ __ ]
how's that so tasty so technically it
has a great shelf life too but the sky
cuddler Kush
you'll look at it when it's fresh and
you'll look at it in a month and it'll
be the exact same weed
but it's not that it gets better a month
later it's just that it doesn't get
worse looking so that's why I say it has
good shelf life it's not like it's
improving
but it's not going down the tubes
visually now the cherry limeade isn't
going down the tubes as far as what
you're going to smoke you're going to
smoke it and it's going to be dank but
people are going to look at it and be
like ah it's dark it's not shiny why
does it look like that there's something
wrong with it and you have to be
educated to know that oh that's because
it has it's approaching five and six
percent terpenes on it and the type of
terpenes it has are the type that want
to basically soak into anything it's
next to and so it it breaks itself down
with with this very fine oil
um and it actually is is a sign of its
quality that it looks so terrible you
know but there's no way to explain that
to somebody who just grabbed a jar and
looks inside and goes what'd these guys
sell me I don't want this anymore you
know so
um there's definitely a thing to shelf
life I think it's even discussed in
marijuana botany back in the 80s like
some weed lasts and looks pretty some
doesn't some weed drops its resin easily
so if you handle it a lot of the resin
winds up at the bottom of the bag and it
doesn't look as pretty and some holds on
to its resin and like there's different
there's different
um qualities to the way resin is on a
plant that make it good for some things
and not as good for others like cherry
limeade the shelf life on it flavor-wise
is amazing but the color gets dark so if
you wanted to sell pre-rolls use you
sell pre-rolls of cherry limeade people
get a pre-roll and they get it goes
through the whole system and they get
away later and they smoke it they're
like damn this is still really bomb
whereas some of the stuff that might
look pretty at that point it doesn't it
hasn't maintained its Funk like
something with so much terpenes what
like the cherry limeade so you have to
kind of know what product you're trying
to make and then you have to make you
know you want to make tomato sauce you
use a sauce tomato you know you wanna
you wanna ship Tomatoes you use the the
one that's going to ship the best
you want to use do you want to make like
ketchup you want a sweeter tomato or
whatever it is you know you don't want
to use a
you don't want to use a Carolina Reaper
to make pico de gallo to [ __ ] sell to
everybody like you're gonna have to tell
people what that is and people have to
know what that is you know so like
everything's got its place but what
people want right now in a lot of cases
is what pleases the most people and
needs the least explanation you look in
there you go whoa that's some [ __ ] boom
you got it and that's why there's such a
popularity with cookie derivatives and
things that are you know have OG in them
or whatever because you just take a look
and you go huh this seems like it's
pretty crazy this is not you know this
isn't the weed at home you know this is
something that and that's why they call
it exotic because it looks like
something crazy and people people laugh
at that because they're like well it's
common so it's not exotic but it's still
you know it's still the look of um
of what people kind of as that knee-jerk
reaction and it's a crowd pleaser all
those kind of looks
um
so you know people buy something they
want a lot of resin
um it's nice if it has if it has a look
to it where you go oh that's pretty it's
not just plain you know purple weed the
first time someone sees purple weed I
guarantee every time they go whoa what's
up with that is that real it's like yeah
it grows like that what does it do they
dye it is it watered with dye is it you
know it's it's not real right and like
you know then people have seen purple
weed for a while they're like oh
whatever it's purple who cares you know
but it's it's uh you know the market is
is selling to people who are um
impressed at certain things so I think
like uh
you know shelf life is good uh in
certain ways for certain things you know
and then there's other types of shelf
life and then but like you know
something like I was talking about was
just like you look at it in a jar and
it's a few months old and you're like
boom this is nice good fresh weed so it
sits and it lasts you know
um
but you know it doesn't have to sit to
get good and it doesn't have to be
totally fresh to be good and that's
that's what's good I mean any any any
kind of agricultural thing you really
want the shelf life you know you want an
apple you can ship you want a tomato you
can ship you don't want it to go bad in
two days but in you know like with like
heirloom tomatoes the best ones they get
really juicy and if you stack them up
they'll squash each other and they're
you know to the best strawberries have
too much sugar they'll they'll rot
really fast you have to pick them and
eat them right away and that's like
something like cherry limeade it's
killer but it's not really fit for being
packaged up and um you know so there's
that there's that thing there where a
fruit or a vegetable has to be able to
ship it has to be able to sit it has to
be able to look good to the most people
even if the people who know the most
might think it doesn't look the best
um you know that's with Mark with
marketing things that's what people are
trying to hit they're going you know
they want to they want to have the most
sales to the most people the most often
and they want to have the most returned
customers and um you know you try
different things and certain things work
and it might not
you know they might not be the best to
certain people but if they average out
at being the best to the most people
then there's your product you know
that's what a hit record is that's what
a hit pair of shoes is that's what you
know whatever whatever it is those are
the things that catch on and get uh you
know get some steam
yeah wow there's certainly a lot more
complexities than what might seem
apparent on the surface isn't there
speaking of uh loud Terps I've been
wanting to follow up with you about one
of the favorite things I tried from you
the male emsky project have you figured
out what is your favorite pairing with
this one for the listeners who aren't
aware this is a a cut that Gene has
that's like Tangy on steroids and also
roid raging and also even then way
better and different to that
yeah so it's actually a seed line which
is cool because it's totally every every
plant has the same has the same turps
and there's a slight variation some are
a little better smelling than others
but um my buddy Jim had it and he had
been calling it lemon kush and I told
him hey there's already a lemon kush and
he goes well I used to call it Green
Lantern but then I heard these gangster
rappers rapping about Green Lantern and
then so then I changed it from that and
so I changed it to Lemon Kush and I go
well there's a lemon kush too you know
and he's like oh [ __ ] okay well and I go
you know it's not so much that you don't
want to use the same name but I go
there's people who think of it as like
being like a a train wrecky kind of a
thing you know that people uh when they
hear lemon you know like it's like a a
different thing and he's like oh okay
well you know I don't know whatever and
he didn't really care and and uh I was
like I was like [ __ ] it smells like
Meyer lemons you know like it's like
lemon but it's really sharp and then it
actually when it finished it developed
this passion fruit grapefruit thing you
know but I was like oh I'm gonna call it
Meyer Lems Meyer lemsky like Meyer
Lansky and Meyer lemons you know and um
and uh you know so I called it that for
when I when I worked it for myself I
haven't done anything with it but I told
him I'm like hey I gave it this handle
and he was like oh cool right on you
know and he didn't really care he's just
it's his old stuff so what it is is it's
old he had this old uh Santa Barbara
gold from from the 70s
and then
somebody passed him a joint and it was
this killer uh it was this killer weed
and he's like damn that's the tastiest
joint ever and he was like what's that
and they're all it's called indica and
he's all Indica huh so this was like 83
or 82 or I don't know sometime back then
and it was uh it was like you know an
Afghani or Pakistani and it was just
like that really good nice
um you know those best ones that are
like Hindu you know the really tasty
deep rich flavor like what I call big
blue or kind of like what the black Affy
is and
um you know from his description and he
and he was like yeah it's that's killer
and the guy was like the guy was like oh
cool you like it here and he had like
two or three seats from Rolling The
Joint he gave him to him and so he
planted them and he crossed them and
then he said like late 80s he got the
stuff that they called the red vein
which I think
based on the neighborhood he was out of
that it probably is is related to what
we call the perp which is in the black
lime and the Pina
and um has the reddish purple stems and
um
but I'm not positive in that but it
makes sense and so he said he crossed
those together and then he just started
breeding him every year
so they don't have the red the red veins
anymore
um they don't have the Colombian
stretch they're these squat little
Indica plants they don't produce quite
as much resin as you want them to have
but the terpene levels are insane and it
smells like Meyer lemon grapefruit
passion fruit which is like my very
favorite Tangy throws that are really
rare and pop out like in the sour Tangy
too
um but instead of it being like this
rare thing and being mixed in with like
you know like kind of like train wreck
Terps and stuff like how Tangi seed is
it's just all of that and then every
once in a while one's a little toned
down or one has like a hint of some
other kind of like
sweet banana or whatever kind of thing
in it but pretty much they all do that
and when you cross it with anything
turns into that terp like it bullied the
hell out of GMO and turned it into
purple Mario lemsky with tons of resin
so that one's promising
um and then there's some other ones too
and skunk Tech was the one that made the
outcross As I crossed it with lime I
haven't grown them yet and I made a ton
of the pure seed because as soon as I
planted them I looked at the seedlings
and I was like these are killer right
here and by the time I found out the
back story on them
um
I already had plants that were like
butted out and I was smelling them and I
was like what the hell are these and
then I I got them from from Jim's
daughter and then
um in a little trade with them and then
I saw him and I go what is the story
dude and that was when he told me what
they were and uh so it's just a really
neat
um Pure Line from the 80s of all old 70s
and 80s stuff
and uh it's one of those things where if
it was put out pure people would be like
nah this is they don't want this this
doesn't have enough resin although
uh if you make oil off of it is insane
and it tastes really good too it just
doesn't look it's like
how skittles looks like it's not that
good but then it's tasty it's like that
except the oil is like
tasty as tasty or tastier than Skittles
but the weed is like
worse looking so it's a little Greener
it's a little more bright but it just it
doesn't look like there's a lot of resin
on it but what's cool is you take that
and you cross it with anything that's
super resinous and it just comes across
in every plant on the Terps So
eventually I'll probably do
um something with it but
um at this point we haven't done
anything with any of the crosses because
we didn't want to step on toes and uh I
had talked to them about you know if I
ever do anything like is it cool and you
know what will we can do some kind of
split on it because it's your old
genetics and stuff and he was totally
down but um I just haven't ever put any
more focus into it I have thousands of
the of the pure seeds I made I think I
did like six different plants and they
were all killer but I have like the the
best three put aside
oh nice but look I'm sure when the
time's right you'll uh you'll do
something special with them when I was
looking at some of your other strains it
made me realize that many of your lines
we see a lot of resistance to mold and
to rot and to drought and I think that's
obviously because for the longest time
you're growing outdoors and those were
obviously like really important factors
but kind of if we think about the
producers we were talking about a few
questions back do you think that some of
these traits might ever start to become
more seen or try to be expressed by
these companies because there are so
many companies moving into Greenhouse
cultivation and like many of these
problems like mold rot
um are just some of the biggest issues
these larger producers face
yeah I think there's a I think there's
quite a bit of focus on it already
um depending on who the who the people
are
um people who have dealt with those
issues are the people who are more
likely to kind of steer in those
directions
um
so you know I think right now it I think
there's a lot of stuff going on that
hasn't really been seen yet I think
right now there's probably already
people in Labs finding all the markers
for all these desirable things and
making it so that you could basically
send them samples of your plants and
they'd say hey here's your mail that
won't that will breed for no mold for no
mildew for this past resistance or
whatever it is I think it's already
being done and it's just not really
quite
um
it hasn't the wave hasn't quite hit but
I think it's already sitting out there
you know what I mean I think it's
already uh I think it's already a thing
for sure I think it just there's people
who have already
done it out of necessity and
um and I'm not the only one you know uh
biovortex green Source Spartans I think
they're called uh
uh uh homegrown natural wonders Odie and
mush
um
you know there's they're they're out
there there's people there's people
doing it you know
um and then I but but I think that also
there's people involved in big AG who
who are doing the same thing behind the
scenes and that'll be
that'll be the new I think in a year or
two that'll be the Big Marketing push oh
buy our pounds of hemp seed because it's
you know it will get zero mold you know
they'll figure out
um things that offer resistance and and
see what really really does that you
know
yeah sure
so earlier on in the episode we spoke
about the emerald Cup and the ego Clash
there's been a lot of sort of mixed
thoughts about some of the bigger events
recently particularly as they sort of
Rebrand themselves especially the
emerald cup is sort of a more casual
smoker event it's not as catering as
much to the hardcore Growers especially
not the Breeders and the sellers do you
see yourself continuing to go to these
events or do you think the smaller ones
like the ego Clash are gonna bloom more
and become the Mainstay of the industry
um you know
I kind of like the I like the aspect of
of the of the big shows just because
they
they put the most people in in one place
um
so it's like a super cool uh it's a cool
opportunity to
meet the people who you might not meet
at the smaller ones I think probably the
most really the the the most uh kind of
renowned official real head event is the
ego Clash that b puts on
um because he's the most like
connoisseur minded he's you know kind of
has
uh he he he has a really good uh feel
for Terps and quality and um and has
that Focus he's one of the one of the
best at that and recognizes that in
other people and and and reaches out to
the right people to where if you win
that to me that's the one that's like
damn okay
um you you really had some [ __ ] because
it's blind and it's the same people who
enter who are judging and it's kind of
uh more of an invitation only
um and so I think you know that that
that's the more like the serious one but
there's you know an event isn't only
about the contest and how official it is
an event is also about a social space
and
um a gathering of people and
um you know when it's opened up to so
many people from everywhere and it's
just whoever
you know there's an aspect there that's
kind of cool and um so you know I
support both both sides and I think they
both have their own uh they both have
their own thing going to them you know
going for them and I think uh you know I
think they both deserve their their
respect in their in their own space and
that
um
what the emerald cup was for a while is
kind of now what the ego Clash is where
it's like okay that's the most
uh probably respectable a word you can
get but I think that the emerald cup is
still is still a respectable award as
well at this point to get you know and
that they're kind of the the two the two
the two main things you know
we're very diplomatic I like that
so just a few more questions as we're on
the tail end of things before the Fast
Five I remember I asked you this in our
first interview so I'd love to see how
things have changed are there any
breeders work that's caught your eye and
you're kind of enjoying the work they're
doing
oh like I was saying I like souvenir
seeds
um pip he does great stuff I don't even
have to get into it it's just real nice
people can look them up
um
oh man this is the one where it's always
like I know guaranteed there's gonna be
uh there's gonna be a lot of people that
I don't
that I don't name him I say is cool just
because he's bringing out old stuff
um
and you know everybody wants something
real Sour his stuff is real he's got the
real cool sour
um everybody else I mean I think I've
probably mostly given shouts to
everybody who's
who I can really think of
um doing a lot of stuff uh my buddy
Dutch at regenerative is cool he's been
going through some stuff with crazy
pressure
uh and like the bad weather in
Washington and pulling stuff out of out
of my Gene pools I've worked with and
kind of you know Finding what is really
really can take the bad elements and
stuff there
um
he uh
I'm trying to think of anything that
just like pops out as being new like
pick was kind of somebody I didn't know
a year or two ago I think about their
work and they didn't I don't think he
had dropped stuff really
um
and I don't know you know just everybody
who's everybody who's doing stuff that
they're that they're interested in and
going with their flavors and
all that you know
um
yeah I don't you know I don't besides
what I've already who I always say you
know
always uh
I always like to watch like you know
what CSI is doing 707 seed bank
but there's tons of them man there's
tons of people doing really cool stuff
all the time so
yeah uh you know uh J trees and skunk
attack have been doing really neat stuff
um yeah
yeah some solid answers there for sure I
um I definitely agree I've been
following both of those guys doing some
some really good work uh so the next
question I had for you was what's the
most unique tur profile you've ever come
across and do you still see it around or
is it gone
most unique terp profile
um
straight opium
um straight opium which is similar to
like a Sharpie or a flea collar or
um there's a certain smell that that
straight opium has it's the one thing I
saw in the 90s that I really wish I
could find again
um it's a certain smell and taste that's
just incredible and uh that would be the
most rare that was really a standout
because everything else is like there's
like things close to it that's
completely unique and I've never seen
anything like it since
what a great answer I I can't say I'm
familiar so hopefully you're able to
find that one and it is still around
kind of on a bit of a different topic I
did want to ask you we heard some word
recently from none other than Chimera
that Tom Hillard passed away and then it
turned out that that was like a bit of a
fake report did you hear from Tom
himself or Through the Grapevine sort of
thing and you know what he's up to or if
we'll ever see his seeds come back
um I don't think he's too into it really
um I think he does stuff for himself and
he's kind of good with that
uh he's a really cool dude I don't know
him personally but I went to school with
his brother and sister so you know I'm
online and I see like Top Dog posts
about it and I and it's like it looks
like it's official so I go okay well I'm
gonna go look around so I look and
everybody's like yeah and people are
like yeah it's you know from people who
are close to him it's true and blah blah
blah so I'm like [ __ ] okay so normally
if something like that happened and I
had just got like a little word of it I
would I would hit somebody up if it's
like their family and I'd be like hey
you know is is that is that true you
know but I've had that experience before
and it always feels kind of weird so
instead of even bothering with that I
just was like well it seems like it's I
know it's real I thought it was real at
the time
so I I hit up my buddy and I go hey you
know
um I'm sorry I'm sorry to hear about
about your brother if there's anything I
can do just you know reach out like uh
you know love you dude blah blah blah
and so
he hits me back and he goes wow my
brother and I go oh [ __ ] I go dude I
hope it's if you haven't heard I go I
hope it's fake you know like I just it
seemed like it was real I apologize if
it's you know if it's if it's if it's
fake I hope it's not true you know he
goes hang on let me check
but I go huh it seems like there's
nothing he he didn't [ __ ] know so and
I was able to get a hold of him right
away why would I be the first person to
get a hold of him right I'm like [ __ ]
hopefully it's fake but I'm still
sweating it you know
and
um
and uh and so uh you know because I'm
[ __ ] bummed out like I'm like huh
dude he's serious you know and so
he goes up just heard from him he's all
good
I'm like
oh [ __ ] I'm like dude I feel like such a
piece of [ __ ] right now for like I just
basically told you your brother died you
know like and it wasn't true like this
is the worst [ __ ] [ __ ] I can
really remember right now like I don't
remember doing some [ __ ] this dumb for
for a while you know like this is this
was [ __ ] you know you know I tell
him like Hey sorry dude and then I
explained like this dude Chimera he's a
big seed dude he he told people on the
forums and said it was totally for real
and he had heard direct from from from
people who knew and this and that
and uh I'm like [ __ ] okay
so that was that was how that played out
and then I ran into him I ran into my
friend you know like uh down on the
street in Ukiah I didn't even want to
mention it I just was like hey how's it
going you know like I was still like
embarrassed really you know because I'm
like dude what a what a [ __ ] thing
to do but it was but but at the time of
course my intention was just to like
reach out and be like hey you know like
it you know just offer help and [ __ ] but
so I was like my heart was in the right
place but my brain was [ __ ] you know
in the wrong place and it was just some
some [ __ ] that was in it and it was
frustrating that people had put it out
in such volume that it was
fake you know that it was real and then
it was fake but at the same time it was
like well you know it's the last time
I'm ever going to do that without just
being like hey you know if I heard I
heard something about so and so like is
there is there is that is there any
truth to that or you know so uh that was
that was my experience with it so I was
like man [ __ ] Jokers like it you know
because it uh was
um
you know like I can think oh man it was
embarrassing for me but the reality was
like my real thing was I just felt like
[ __ ] because I was like damn like how'd
I make him feel you know so
um that was that was what that's how
that went you know [ __ ] Dumbass
Dumbass gene on that one so
oh man too harsh on yourself I I'm sure
he probably wasn't too put off fire but
there you go a good answer to the
situation
so a new question I've been allowing to
ask all the guests recently before we
wrap things up
do you have any other passions in life
besides breeding we see on Instagram
like a lot of breeders like to breed
dogs some dabbling cars some dabble in
various other things is there some other
aspect of me and Gene which the public
isn't aware you're invested in
um I haven't been doing it that much but
I like to I like to DJ
um to mix
um make mashups like play one thing over
another like
in in real time like on turntables or
like CDJ turntables you know like uh
you know drop something out of this and
and play this over the top of that and
make make mashups and [ __ ] and I I've
been doing that since like 2006 or 2007
like
often but then I I stopped for I haven't
really done it for years and years now
um I really like that I really like to
just listen to music
um do some music I I've done over the
years done some done some vocal [ __ ]
um
and uh I like uh I like to look for
mushrooms I like to look for arrowheads
and uh
I really as funny as it is I really like
[ __ ] movies like I just like to watch
great movies or shows or things like
that just like music like it's just uh
you know
um I really like comedy I like crazy
epic stories just just neat interesting
stories about you know human [ __ ] like
Outlaw Josie Wales or Last of the
Mohicans or Gangs of New York or like
kind of like big crazy ones like that
um
you know but beyond you know beyond just
being like Oh I'm just gonna stare at
this and I like really I I really like
that kind of [ __ ] like if it was easier
to be involved in like making movies and
[ __ ] I'd probably want to be you know
want to do some of that but it's not
something I have that much ambition in
but I really do love uh I love that kind
of stuff
um
and uh you know I mean I like food I
like to cook there's not there's not
really anything that I'm as into as
um as I am into weed you know but um
but I like you know I'm into I'm into
stuff that uh involves checking out
Aesthetics and stuff and but as far as
doing stuff making stuff made some music
over the years like I said I like the
mixing making remixes mashups
you're probably my main things really
I'm pretty simple I like to
observe things I like to absorb
information
um you know so I like to read stuff I
like to check stuff out like that
um
love to go to the river in the
summertime go swimming go to the ocean
like I really enjoy that
uh part of nature probably more than the
average person I just like really soaked
that up that's like my happy place you
know
and
um you know
family
for me is big I really I really like
chilling with my son and my family and
it kind of sums up my life you know not
super I like to travel a little bit but
it's not my thing like I have friends
who that's really what they're into is
traveling I'm like cool I like to do it
sometimes but it usually takes it out of
me
um and I get I usually wind up getting
like burnt out and sick or something
from either partying too hard or just
the travel and the stress of the actual
travel and [ __ ] but um but I like that
too and um
you know I'm pretty uh I'm pretty simple
I don't really have anything that's like
a big
a big thing that I like to like you know
spend money on or
um
you know I just just kind of chill
pretty pretty
um
yeah pretty simple dude
a man of Simple Pleasures I like that I
like that a lot
so this brings us to our final five
quick fire questions pretty confident
they're different to the ones you did
last time so I'm excited to hear the
answers to this one uh first one is what
is the absolute most memorable cannabis
experience you've ever had be it smoking
flower hash being somewhere doing
something which one stands out the most
to you
oh man
um
there was definitely some some memories
that were
that were really interesting like
getting getting way too high and being
like almost blacked out when I was young
where you know they just have that
impact of being like holy [ __ ] I think
I'm going to be high for the rest of my
life like I'm just you know you're just
clouded in a daze and you know those
kind of those kind of stand out and then
um
um you know I don't know like just
everything is so much weed man like I
don't it's not anything that stands out
but one really crazy one was uh one time
I took a bong hit dude and I stood up to
go spit in the in the in the bathroom
sink as bomb heads sometimes have to
spit after they're coughing and stuff
and I went to stand up and I got a
little light-headed so I sat back down
on this big bean bag and
then I stood back up because I was good
and I went and I spit in the bathroom
and I went and came back and I started
getting a little bit like kind of kind
of my vision started getting white you
know and so I went to like kind of belly
flop onto the bean bag but as I was
going to belly flop onto the bean bag I
like lost Consciousness and my body
moved a little bit and I fell to the
side of the beanbag
and when I woke up my my jaw was so
dislocated that like my my one my right
side of my teeth was underneath the left
side of my top teeth like the bottom
bottom right was underneath the top left
you know what I mean like my jaw was
completely dislocated to the point where
I was like damn oh am I gonna die or or
like in that like still that's why I
said like good things or bad things that
still stands out as the craziest [ __ ]
weed experience I ever had
because I thought I had like ruined my
life like to look I wish if if they back
then if it would have been like we had
camera phones around all the time and I
had a picture of it you would be like
holy [ __ ] [ __ ] because my my my my
whole face was just [ __ ] twisted
around the wrong way I was nuts dude
um and that was that has to be like the
craziest weed experience ever and it was
just a [ __ ] bong hit you know but it
was like dude it was insane all my all
my teeth were bleeding between the teeth
you know because I had hit so hard yeah
and I had this big berry on my chin and
I was like man I I had to straighten it
out you know I had to like open my mouth
real wide and push on the sides and it
like
[ __ ] popped back in and it you know
it it it it never was 100 you know it's
still a little tiny bit off this you
know 20 years later [ __ ] was nuts
but uh that's a crazy story
yeah wow I think we've got a new
Benchmark with that one on the other end
of the spectrum we're gonna think least
memorable was there ever a time when all
of the people you know hang out with
were just like super hyped on this
certain strain and then when you finally
got around to trying it you were like ah
is that it
foreign
I don't know I mean you know usually
things haven't been
um super hyped or if they are so hyped
then I kind of assume they're gonna suck
anyway and then when I see them I'm like
this is actually pretty good you know
so uh that's not something that I've
experienced a whole lot
I wouldn't say
yeah that's that's good considering
you've been living in the heart of the
weed Mecca since the start really so the
next question would be if you're about
to be dropped off at a desert island and
you can only take three strains with you
that you've got to smoke for the rest of
your life which three would you take
with you
but definitely take line one
I'd probably take root beer or anything
that's kind of in there in that mix of
the jarrow stuff
um and then
um
a third one
yeah I don't know maybe just because it
would be a good a good
the other side of it and I've I know
what it's like to have not had it which
I and I really like it it's really
enjoyable for me I like that sweat
but I don't know if I would put it as in
the in the top
in the top three as a third one would be
like then it gets hard you know like I
really know lime one's my favorite I
really know root beer I love to smoke
anytime when I'm like I've already
smoked a bunch of lime and then after
that it's like a big wheel of a bunch of
different stuff and then I would be I
wouldn't be super super concerned as
long as I knew I had as long as I knew I
had the lime and then something else you
know
yeah that's a nice little selection
there so if we flip the tables now and
you're going to be dropping off someone
who you're not particularly fond of to
that same island and you get to choose
what three strains they get which three
are you going to give them
some kind of cardboardy
peanut Shelly Rooter Alice oh love it
I mean I just remember like some
ruderalis stuff that had that kind of uh
you know where it's just like there's
nothing really redeeming about the smell
and then you smoke it and you don't
really get a high you would want and uh
that's like you know like the basically
what I think a lot of people would
recognize as the auto flowers that you
don't want I think a lot of people have
probably seen that style I I can see it
in pictures all the time people are like
oh I got this Autoflower such and such
and I'm like yeah that's that that's
that very undesirable Rooter Alice look
with the really dark red hairs that has
like the this dark greenness to it and
just not there's something there's this
thing and it's like I know that type and
I can see it as soon as I see it I know
it's just that plain
kind of just this that the high that
just doesn't really do much for you and
uh that would be that's like my kind of
my least favorite thing that I can think
of and I've seen it come out you know of
different stuff like even out of kind of
cool afghanis and then it'll pop out and
you're like oh there's that [ __ ]
thing
um
and then
oh
you know [ __ ]
um
I don't know
it's really I really like plants a lot
so
for me even things that people might go
oh that's terrible somebody will tell
you oh I can't stand Jack or I can't
stand train wreck or I can't stand a
blue dream or or I hate uh I hate
whatever it is that they really don't
like I kind of I kind of like weed like
you know
I can tell you what's really gnarly and
what's not as gnarly but a lot of the
stuff that's just you know whatever I'm
still kind of like uh I'm still kind of
just impressed that it's weed if that
makes any sense like
it's cannabis I mean I don't want to be
that guy but like
if somebody has some weed I'm like hey
that's some weed I remember times when
like I was saying
like somebody has some moldy weed and
you're like [ __ ] it it's weed
you know so for me
even though I you know I have access to
what people consider to be what's the
goods and and whatnot I still
um
that's there's that one type that just
leaves it leaves a bad taste in my mouth
just like the memories of it as like
wheat as far as because it's a strain
that I can really put a finger on and go
that one but other than that you know I
I don't think that um
I don't think anything's too terrible I
think honestly if you were on a [ __ ]
desert island and someone dropped you
off with whatever you'd be like [ __ ] I'm
glad this is cannabis dude you know
amen amen what a good answer
so on to our final question if you could
go back in time to anywhere any place
and collect some seeds or a clone which
one are you going to go back and get
um so I think last time I said I'd like
to go
like to the Hindu Kush region back in
the day
um and Hunt around and look
um
so we already know that so outside of
that man we have this White Widow in the
in the 90s
and we have this Northern Lights in the
90s and I had this dirt purp clone in
the [ __ ] 90s that was so good and we
didn't realize how good it was and we
had already killed the moms
um
for me personally I would say I'd
probably want to go back right to that
little slice of time when I still had
all three of those things and when I
know that there was tons of people who
had other stuff that I was too shy to
ask for
I'd probably just write go back to the
90s in this area grab the stuff that I
had
and that I lost and then start knocking
on my friend's doors and asking their
parents for the stuff that I was too shy
to ask for
um you know and and I know there's a lot
of other places to go
and there's all kinds of neat stuff to
find but like those are the things for
me personally as opposed to going you
know these are the things that really
should be brought to the community I
just want to I would I would want to go
back and just get the [ __ ] that I have
seen that we had that I smoked and I had
my hands on and I remember it and it's
gone I just want all that [ __ ] that
would probably be like
1996 or something like that you know
yeah brilliant answer I guess you know
the first episode we got seeds second
episode we got clients so it kind of
rounds it out yeah seeds too though when
I'm talking about that those you know
that's for me there was those few clones
but then I'd want to go get all those
seeds from the from the from the family
friends you know
uh yes yes of course okay
so with that being said I think that
just about brings us to the end of a
second Monster episode thank you so much
for taking the time were there any
comments or shout outs you wanted to
make
um
man I don't know you know I could well I
could go lots of directions with that
but I'm gonna um
I think I'm just gonna uh
probably
um you know say thanks for everybody who
listened to all this crazy [ __ ]
run-on sentences and Rants and um
and uh you know thanks to everybody
who's interested in uh
in the plants and trying to figure out
you know what what to do in the whole
scene of everything and um
you know thanks for having me on and
you know I think that's a pretty pretty
uh positive way to to uh close it out
and I there it is
well listen my friend thank you so much
yeah thank you man
[Music]
and there you have it Gang part two of
an epic discussion with our man me and
Jane thank you so much for taking the
time to come on the show James
likewise thank you to all the listeners
for making it this far I mean it's not
hard with such a wealth of knowledge fan
drops all right
as always we appreciate our sponsors
seeds here now number one seed bank in
the game they've got some Freeborn
selections go check them out if you want
all the hottest genetics in the game
they just got a fresh drop from CSI
Humboldt that's my pick
likewise copper biological systems they
got that beneficial Army to keep your
garden happy healthy and the next crop
on track to be the best today
go check out the website I guarantee you
it pays to keep the garden happy and
healthy carpet biological systems
they're the one you know it
and last but not least a huge shout out
to the patreon gang you guys are the
lifeblood of the show you know it I hope
you enjoy getting early access to this
episode hearing it before the rest and
if you want to become a part of the
patreon family please go check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast you'll get early access to
episodes unheard unreleased content
giveaways and so much more
thank you so much patreon gang I
appreciate you and the sponsors so very
much
[Music]
so that just about does it for this one
my friends
[Music]
I'll see you for the next one
we'll see you
[Music]
foreign