hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
buting enthusiasts as always you're
joined here by your boy heavy days here
from the upside down library and as
usual we want to give a massive shout
out to our incredible sponsors who
helped make the show happen seeds here
now your number one seed bank in the
industry a guarantee on satisfaction not
just germination with all the hottest
breeders and the latest drops why would
you go anywhere else
if you finish a grow and you're not
satisfied with the end product hit them
up they'll make it right they only stock
the highest quality breeders and I know
they got some fire packs from your boy
heavy days there check them out before
they're gone guys massive shout out to
C1 now your number one stop for all your
genetic needs but in order to get your
garden pumping on all cylinders and
producing the best crop to date you got
to make sure your rooms dialed in to do
that check out our friends at Pulse
sensors Number One sensors and
integrated hubs in the game game
measuring all of the variables PPD VPD
temperature humidity Duo all the extra
variables you don't consciously track to
help ensure your next crop is the best
to date whether you're running a single
tent a single room or a multi-state
operation pulse sensors are the number
one in the game and they've just
recently released the pulse Hub a
central unit to integrate all of their
monitors to make sure that your rooms
are the best they can possibly be
massive thank you to pulse sensors we
appreciate you so much
likewise you got to keep your garden
Pest and pathogen free and to do that
you got to check out our friends at
copit these guys are the world leaders
in Sustainable biocontrol Solutions for
pests and disease if you're battling
spidermites check out their new spidex
vital plus sachet these are new pillis
breeding sachets that release predator
mites into your crop consistently over a
period of several weeks providing you
with sustained spidermite control now
you don't have to spread carrier
material through your garden just to
introduce predator mites just hang the
sachets on your crop let the person
millist walk out and do the work for you
trust me guys you don't want to have to
go up against a spidermite infestation
without spyx vital plus these are truly
the best predators in the game I promise
once you use it you'll see the quality
you'll never go back massive shout out
to copit likewise you got to check out
our friends at Organics alive if you're
growing
organic and want to use high quality
powdered organic fertilizers you simply
cannot go past Organics alive these guys
truly walk to walk and talk to talk they
have been picking up cups left right and
center with Growers all around the
country sweeping categories using their
products that is the ultimate Testament
in my opinion if homeg Growers are
winning competitions using their
products the proof is in the pudding
guys no matter what stage of the plant
cycle you're at veg transition flour in
need of micronutrients or a very
specific sort of boost in late flour
they've got it you got to check out
Organics alive guys truly one of the
best in the industry we're super stoked
to be working with them because we know
how amazing more products are us in
heaps of breeder Gardens that we have on
the show again check them out Organics
alive massive thank you massive shout
out for supporting the
show finally a massive shout out to the
entire crew at dap these guys make some
of the best vaporizers on the game I'm
really passionate about this one because
they helped me to get off combustion and
smoking bongs if you have any concerns
about your respiratory health or Heck if
you just want to try a different mode of
ingestion maybe try to get a better
flavor hit you've got to check out the D
ofap these guys units are cheap they're
incredibly welld designed and most
importantly they're very customizable
you can take your Vape game to the next
level getting insane turps all while
retaining the potency you'd expect of a
combustion or a bong truly I was smoking
bongs for over 10 years I'm now Vape
only massive shout out to DAP they're
one of the best in the industry and we
owe a massive thank you shout out again
dap massive thanks for supporting the
show finally a quick little mention to
Our patreon Gang truly the lifeblood of
the show if you want to get early access
to episodes unheard and unreleased
interviews as well as going in the
running to get amazing genetics each
month and fortnite come on check out the
patreon at
www.patreon.com
slthe podcast we do live smoke with
heavy sessions every fortnite and give
away heaps of Swag every month come
check it out we love you the patreon
gang thank you so much we are so
appreciate and on today's episode we are
stoked to be joined by none other than
the originator of the GMO head breeder
at skunk house genetics a name you'd all
be familiar with creator of the Mike
Larry so much more skunk master
flexx here to talk all things
breeding the journey he's been on thus
far the GMO some plans for the future
and so much more without further delay
all righty gang a big thank you for
joining us for another one on our
episode today we are joined by The Man
Behind skunk house seeds a name you're
all familiar with the man who found the
GMO creator of Mike Larry so much more a
big welcome to Master Flex for joining
us on the show
today hey thanks for having me big
welcome thanks so much for coming on the
show tell me a little bit about what
you're smoking on
today um always got some jars of some OG
Kush um always got some
GMO always have my version of GMO the
the burger lines um
TKO little bit of modified
banana
um some Bubba Cush
you know a lot of the classics I like to
keep around um big Kush fan big OG fan
so always have to have a good jar of
it you're making my mouth water that was
like an Allstar lineup you just read off
there before we jump into some of the
more newer ones I'd love to quickly
touch on you mentioned the Bubba I feel
like Bubba doesn't get as much of a
mention as it used to are you a fan of
it I'm a huge fan of Bubba Kush um
really really really like the high from
it really relaxing High
uh it's always been a favorite since the
first day I smoked it um it doesn't
doesn't make its rounds anymore people
aren't really using it too much you know
some of the older guys I mean I see uh
CSI and a couple guys still working with
bubak Kush but definitely not as popular
as it was in the past it's kind of
upsetting
really yeah I mean I think the the the
main criticism I hear of bber is that
it's a slow veger I guess the question
is do you think that's the predominant
reason for the decline or do you think
there's other sort of types of high that
have replaced it I think I think it's a
little bit of everything really you know
um it is a slow veger but so is URL and
so are a lot of other ones um I think on
a production standpoint the prices of
cannabis in the United States right now
I mean I don't think people are doing it
to scale but I mean on a personal Garden
I always have a couple in there um yeah
I said it's just yeah just not as
popular I think people are going through
these new you know designer strings
these
hybrids sativas I'm even seeing starting
to pop up more than they were in the
early 2000s 2010s so who knows where
it's going to be here for
now yeah look you just quickly mentioned
it so I'd love to touch on it where do
you sit on sativas versus indicas
because I think if a lot of people
looked at your catalog of work they'd
see a lot of indicio work do you have a
soft spot for C
uh I'm not a sativa guy for just
medicinal purposes myself I'm heavy Inda
smoker um sativas give me anxiety
sometimes
man
um bod gave me a cut of Temple Haze
years ago and it was like my first entry
to like a full-blown sativa that was
like super racy and I like drew it out
got all excited did um rolled up the
first joint of it and took like maybe a
quarter of it down and like wanted to
crawl out of my own
skin it was just it was just too much
for me you know um not my cup of tea I
do need to work with some though because
I do you know appreciate that people do
like sativas but um yeah on a personal
level it's just just not for
me yeah wow look I think I think most
people can relate to uh you know
indulging in some sativa and going a
little too far feeling a bit like
yourself there that's that's really
interesting to hear I mean out of
curiosity um have you ever had any
requests to breed with sativas I feel
like super silver hay is having a bit of
a comeback do you ever get any request
to do any Harbridge with things like
that absolutely um and Super Silver Haze
is a classic man um I had like this 45
50-day pheno um like a decade ago that I
used used in some of my earlier stuff um
it
just kind of got overshadowed by
everything else you know but I do agree
that sativas are kind of like you know
hot right now they're definitely coming
back um lots of people requesting it I
just haven't really you know dip my toe
into that sativa world really and uh
gotten to appreciate it because I don't
you know for my personal use I don't I
don't really touch it but for other
people I mean yeah obviously as as a
breeder you want to offer things in your
catalog for every everybody so
definitely some sust work coming down
the
line yeah nice stuff cool to hear I
guess this might seem like a silly
question to you but I've actually heard
a lot of people discuss this um before
we delve into you know the the rabbit
hole that is the GMO I'd love to just
quickly ask as a preface do you
understand what people say when you
maybe sometimes hear people say that
they feel GMO is a sativa absolutely um
the thing about GMO that tricky that I
think a lot of people caught in on is
the amount of time taken to flower that
plant to get it to completion where it's
where it's actually fully matured um if
you take it early it can get racy you
know um proper GMOs like close to 90
days so I mean if you're talking about
you know somebody maybe running on a
commercial scale maybe trying to stay in
the 9we 60 63 day range um I mean I've
I've had race batches that I've taken
down early some people love it for me my
sweet spot for the GMO is like 80 to 83
days it's it's a perfect balance it's
not too hard I can still enjoy it um it
won't put me down to sleep but I don't
get any of that sativa out of it but
that's you know that's a personal thing
that's again you know I'm not a sativa
really smoker so that's where my sweet
spot
is yeah interesting and I mean what part
of the genetics do you think it is that
leads it to have that what most people
would consider to be quite uh like a
longer flowering time than what you
might expect from the parents on paper
any idea where that might be coming from
there's like you know I've had this
conversation with a lot of people over
the years and there was mentions about
maybe something got mixed up in a bag
maybe it's not what it's you know it's
not CHD crossed with Forum cut maybe
it's something else maybe there's you
know maybe a sne seed stuck in the bag
that I got was different it's you know I
mean it was completely different than
the rest of the [ __ ] seeds that I
popped out of that that um bag of seed
that I got you know it was the standout
the entire time from sprouting the seed
in a Solo Cup to um you know
transplanting it to everything like that
that grew finished looked completely
different than everything else in that
in that group so I mean I wouldn't be
surprised if it if it might be something
else
but you know who's to say you know that
whole Cham lineage is so you know
unknown really that maybe it's something
in the back genetics you know a
grandparent coming through um who knows
you know so hard to call it you know I
just kind of take it for what it is and
it's just a just a really unique plant
that I I just really love to you know
breed with and people seem to love to
hash and it's just really really you
know epic it's an epic
find yeah tell me a little bit about the
concentrate potential and how maybe um
you know that doorway has opened up
since finding the GMO because I know for
a lot of people you know GMO was a game
changer for concentrates to them how has
it changed your perspective on it I mean
I've had people walk up to me and say
the GMO made me a
millionaire you know like and it's like
like a big group of people like many
people um it's a hash monster you know
it just dumps the type of triome it
produces um it put you know it puts out
that Sandy type of you know
Tricom and it just it as a breeding tool
for you know making hash strains is just
amazing you know especially if you can
if you can breed read it where you can't
really see its presence as much but some
of its attributes gets passed through
it's just like I said just just an epic
fres yeah incredible and I mean like I
think one of the comments I've
specifically heard a lot is that you
know the the turpine profile it really
translates to the end product of
concentrates and obviously you know not
every strain does that as well as you'd
like what's your plans in terms of
breeding concentrates going forward is
it something you actively think about or
is it just a peripheral thing and it's
like well if the genetics facilitate a
good plant then like you know
cool I mean these days you have to
basically breed for part of the intent
to be
concentrates um the concentrate Market
is just so big between you know people
making these um rosin and resin pens um
just the demand for hashers is so big
that to breed and not take that
consideration would be a major mistake
in my opinion um
luckily the majority the bulk of the
work that I do has you know small
amounts at least of GMO in the lineage
so um any cross really if you really do
a proper hunt you can come across
something you know that'll just dump
that's that's awesome you know amazing
and unique um the GMO does tend to be
dominant in genetic crosses um so I
found like if you kind of like knock it
down to where it's like 25% of a
pedigree um you can really start finding
some amazing things that don't get
dominated by it but just offer you know
their own you know unique twists that
are
just you know amazing and yield and and
dump and just tastes great and have
unique tur
profiles
um a lot of the work that I do you know
it's it is for hash so luckily the GMO
kind of definitely assists in that
department yeah that's awesome to hear
Look I think we may as well we jump into
the discussion now because we've already
we've already basically started it but I
just wanted to ask one one last quick
question which is I um I I got given a
bud of a GMO from Adam Dunn last year at
one of the events and I have to be
honest it was it was so putrid smelling
in a good way I was like I don't know if
I can smoke this have you ever had any
experiences like that where it was like
a little too gnarly and you're like this
is this is full on yeah it's like so
when when I first started doing a of it
you know obviously this is um premedical
um at least you know we weren't doing
medical grows it was just a you know
kind of a black market grow um we would
have to move a bunch of the you know
pounds and go from City to city and it
was just so gnarly smelling you know um
my buddy that was helping me you know
move a bunch of it he had this uh this
two-door Cadillac and uh we always threw
a bunch in the in the trunk and drove to
Ann Arbor which was the first place that
we were kind of doing drops at um Tree
City and uh we moved so much weight in
that trunk that it permanently stained
his car it just the smell never came out
they had to you know they had to send it
out to I think it was like Dubai or
something like or Lebanon or some some
other country just to just to get rid of
it you know anybody that sat in the
thing in the used car lot was like man
this thing smells terrible like it
smells like weed they just couldn't get
the smell out of it so I mean it
definitely has a staining attribute to
it and it's putrid and and some people
love it and some people just absolutely
hate
it which you know I get you know you
know everybody has their own you know
preferred flavors for cannabis but um
it's it's almost unbearable to some
people and I find that kind of
fascinating and hilarious at the same
time you know like it's just from the
first batches of it it was just like I
said like it was a standout it was
unique lots of opinions on it you know
like you said you know you got got a bud
and it was just like so so so offensive
that you didn't want to smoke it like I
think that's I don't know I find that to
be
funny definitely and I mean another sort
of comment SL observation I'd heard is
that you know GMO really illustrates the
point that you know with just I I guess
I'll have to sort of paint in Broad SS
here but like a lot of males in the
industry are really attracted to the
most accurd offensive off-putting sort
of smells you get and GMO really
highlights that and then you know you
you find that some of the females are
really not that interested in that sort
of smell you know have you ever noticed
this yourself that it's like it's like a
bit grotesque and some some people are
just inherently really into it and
others are just like not absolutely um I
mean I I now that you kind of you know
mention it it's it is kind of um guys
definitely tend to draw themselves
toward the the they want the funkiest
lead you
know the uh the um females that I smoke
with or or have in the past typically
tend to like Fruity genetics things that
aren't as offensive um you know like the
kkes and stuff like that um obviously
not exclusively but like you said it's
it's definitely guys like stank
weed yeah totally totally and look all
I'll put it out there I'm I'm a fruity
guy myself so what does that say about
me I don't know okay okay okay little
feminine in there no no I like I like
Fruity I like Fruity too man I just I
like if I have my fruit in there I have
to have some gas to it you know
something that kind of like makes it not
just
fruit um you know but I you know I I
like to get some uh purple punch every
once in a while and you know just
something that tastes good that doesn't
necessarily like get you [ __ ]
annihilated but like it's just enjoyable
smoke good
flavor yeah totally totally all right
well let's let's dive into it tell me a
little bit about the Genesis of the GMO
in the sense of what was it that Drew
you to those seeds and how did you get
them you know did you have a friendship
with mimo did you just happen to find
yourself with those seeds how did it all
go down initially so initially mimo was
not even mentioned at all in it um you
got to go back this is like 2012 2011
201 12 THC farmer I'm a moderator on
there or was a moderator on there um
along with you know cap and all those
guys um Divine genetics was ran by Logic
who was the owner of THC farmer um not
sure if you're familiar or not um yeah
yeah lots of lots of bad a couple good
lots of bad though
um uh he had a bunch of seed that he
wanted tested
um so I you know I threw my hat in the
ring and said sure you know I'll I'll
run some seed I'll see I'll see what
it's about you know um cam D cross with
Girl Scout cookie Forum cut was one of
the crosses that landed in my lap which
um didn't really actually get named
until like you know probably years down
the road um did the pheno hunt didn't
know that he was white labeling the
genetics
um not until years later um like years
and probably almost five years later did
we find out that Miko made uh the seed
so I mean as soon as he as soon as we
fig you know a lot of us figured it out
he definitely got credit for it um but
logic was kind of keeping that like
tucked away he wasn't really letting
anybody know about it so it was kind of
news you know to our ears but yeah man
um the seeds wound up because they were
they were tester sees wow okay so you
you really got them truly early on in
the picture I guess yes sir like like I
said I think I believe it was like 2012
was when I got him feno hunted him right
away
um feno hunted all the seeds that he
gave me and then over the years uh ran
into other people that wound up buying
the seeds after they had been released
um and they they shot me the seeds that
they had left and everybody was
convinced that just you know it's
whatever was going to get tapped out of
there was tapped out of there and the
GMO and there was a couple others um
honorable mentions that I found in the
seed stock um but the GMO was definitely
the stand out um there was a root beer
feno my buddy used to say smelled like
root beer it was a it was like a stout
plant completely different um there was
a bunch of weird stuff that popped up in
there but you know like I said nothing
nothing that was do anything close to
GMO
yeah wow that's interesting as a quick
little digression have you ever spoke to
mean Jean about that because it's almost
coincidental that he's done some
pairings with his root beer in the GMO I
thought maybe maybe you'd spoke about
that with him and he thought oh I'll
pair them together no big fan of his
though um love his work don't know him
personally haven't really had much
interaction with him but yeah I saw that
GMO across with his root beer bx1 or or
whatever it was that he was working um
love to try those seeds haven't had the
chance but yeah I saw it and I was very
interested very intrigued in what he was
doing with that line wow that's some
synchronous stuff right there that you
know you sort of got a pheno like that
and he's sort of paired them together
that's cool okay well if we loop back to
the story I guess the question is you
mentioned a little earlier that you know
even during that first run you flowed
him out you could tell this was
something a bit different to the rest
the question is did you like you know
you've acknowledged you realized it was
different did you realize like how
special it was and I guess let's say
when you had the first or second batch
of flour from it what was like the
public SL your friend's responses did
they realize what it was or did it take
some time to catch on so that that pheno
hunt actually went down in the basement
of the house that I lived in the time
and uh you know used a couple carbon
filters but that thing was like a carbon
filter
Destroyer that one plant that one plant
that I had the first during the feno
hunt I mean I had buddies that came over
house and you know we're like dude your
house like stinks man like it's it's
worse than it usually is you know like
what what do you got going on down there
like you got something different like
what's up let me see what you got you
know so I I showed I showed it off a
little bit in the in the testing phases
and everybody said the same thing they
were just like look at the stack on that
thing it's throwing out like baseball
bats you know like never seen anything
like it before um it was just a unique
plant like from day one you know was
just so vigorous and it just it stood
out always and um we didn't really find
out how well of a Hatcher it really even
was until um I did you know larger rooms
and we kind of like started processing
it like by itself and the numbers that
we were getting back just like holy cow
the hell is going on here this thing is
incredible like these numbers are
nothing like what you know anything else
we're
running yeah wow just a game ch
so I guess the question then
becomes was it like a linear progression
did was it like everyone you showed it
to was interested in it was just
building in popularity or did it take a
little bit of time for it to really
start to spread like wildfire cuz at a
certain point it obviously hit critical
mass and just exploded and I'm just
wondering when was that so pheno hun
kind of started to scale it up a little
bit realized it was something special
and it could yield and we could use it
for hash making um the name itself was
kind of a big deal in the beginning um
the first places like I said Street City
and an Arbor Michigan here that we would
drop it at uh when we first dropped it
it didn't move it's sat on the Shelf huh
nobody you know no a lot of people
didn't want to touch it it's kind of a
kind of a vegan area kind of a hippie
area you know and uh the name was a
turnout for them so the owner said uh
you know look would you be offended if I
changed the name of this and I said no
absolutely not like you know if it's you
know not going to move I'm I'm not gonna
you know get you burnt here um so he
said what do you think about you know
everyone says it smells like garlic what
do you think about calling it uh garlic
cookies and I said you know should give
it a try so he did the name change and
then it just couldn't stay on a shelf it
just flew so the demand grew so we had
to produce more and then it just kind of
like was a Snowball Effect it just
became you know a huge favorite in the
area amongst everybody that tried it
just it just really started to explode
at that point um we just couldn't even
keep up with
demand yeah wow and I mean you touched
on a a point that comes up in almost
every website if you Google GMO which is
you know as you mentioned the name you
know what what did the name originally
mean to you and does it mean now if
that's changed at all so GMO to me was
just like referring to its like how just
wild it grew just like how how strong it
was you know like it grew at three times
the speed and veg that anything else did
that I had in the rooms and just how it
threw out these huge baseball bats you
know I'm like this thing's got to be
like you know genetically
modified um so I started kind of giving
it the nickname GMO you know it's like
joking around like this thing is you
know kind of a force of its own um also
coincidentally at the time the Girl
Scout uh cookies were getting like you
know a bunch of press in the news for
putting GMOs um in their in their bait
goods and stuff so it's just kind of
like I don't know the Universe telling
me to just call it GMO um which is
actually kind of ironic because um logic
was completely against and like forbid
me to call it GMO
and then years down the road put out GMO
seeds which is just I don't know I find
kind
ofal yeah he made him backflip on it I
love that I love that and I mean I guess
as a how would you phrase it a question
that people are probably wondering and I
certainly am is you know given the
dominant chmd profile within the GMO
what's your thoughts on the chmd and the
chem dogs in general I love the chem I
think the chem are amazing I mean I like
them on a personal level to smoke I like
him to use in genetic breeding I like
them to just grow for flower um I think
the chem D is
amazing
um probably my favorite chem at least to
grow I do like the chem 991 but the
whole chem line itself man is just it's
so strong it's so you know epic in in
genetic crosses it's just to to not like
would be insane to
me yeah no certainly certainly and I
mean I I was probably meant to slot this
in just the prior question but just to
100% rule it out what's your thoughts on
when people say that GMO stands for
garlic mushroom onions do you think like
oh it's just a funny coincidence and it
sort of works out or is it just like no
that's definitely not anything related
to it I think it's just funny
coincidence it kind of works out I mean
some people get garlic smell in there
some people get onion smell in there to
me it just kind of smells skunky
you know um definitely not what I
intentionally you know put the GMO you
know out there for as an acronym but um
I think it's cool hearing the stories of
people kind of like going in their own
Direction with it and it's probably one
of the most asked questions I ever get
is just you know did the GMOs you know
stand for this or me and my buddies are
having a debate and you know I bet him
that it stood for this or that and I
don't know it's it's fun you know I I
have a good time with it you know the
Cannabis Community reaching out and kind
of trying to get the the lore of the
Back stories of everything and you know
I think it's I think it's cool I enjoy
it people can call it whatever they want
but to me it's it's always just going to
be GMO and it's just based on how it
grows and you know my experience with it
but yeah that's beautiful so I mean we
we've sort of touched on this but I just
wanted to delve into the topic a little
more you know you referenced earlier
maybe there was some pollen
contamination or something like that but
I guess my question is to me the GMO
seems like like a lottery ticket
phenotype in the sense that you know as
you've said many people have popped
those seeds and no one's really found
anything that similar I guess the
question is do you feel that it's like
in my mind I guess maybe an analogy is I
feel like it's kind of similar to the
Mac 1 you know it's like it's this
insane cut and no one's really been able
to find anything that stands up to it
while hunting those same seeds is that
how you think about it or do you lean
more towards the possibility of pollen
contamination as opposed to like this is
just the one fer where we really locked
out I mean I think in my opinion I think
it's just something in the back genetics
that came out and popped out um for one
random seed to pop in there and just
kind of like be that much of a game
changer would just be I
guess to me it just not as not as
possible um everything to me just leans
toward just the cam is just
awesome and uh just it was just a freak
feno that came out and you know kind of
made its way and just it was meant to be
kind of thing you know
um our group kind of held it in our our
little circle for a while but we just
felt like really the world need to
really enjoy it you know get out there
and uh make some people's Gardens
happy yeah that's awesome to hear have
you ever made or ran any s1s from it and
found anything interesting in there so
the is with the GMO when you start doing
s1's and reversing it is obviously
hermod [ __ ] you know Tendencies it
wants to throw poin and the lowers from
seed doesn't necessarily stay in the
traits kind of like i' I've done some
s1s and um I've cloned them before I ran
the seed and didn't run the straight
seed and I didn't have the issues but
like you know as a breeder you can't
rely on people to do that so I've always
kind of like steered away from putting
out
s1's and do doing a lot of fem work in
general um not that fem are always going
to be you know Herm issues but something
about that particular strain um I've
just had issues with it with f seeds not
so much being the palen um receiver but
being the donor ah okay and so I guess
the flip side of that question is what
sort of genetics do you think the GMO
pairs well
with I like to put it with stuff that
kind of you know stays shorter stays a
little squatter though I mean I love OG
Kush and pairing it with OG when I when
I did the Han Solo Burger um was just
amazing you know but I'm a big gas fan
and I like that kind of stuff um but I
did some I did some work I did some
Urkle crosses with it um I did an obamus
cross um with the BX the donni burger
which is a GMO bx1 um some of those
fenos came out just incredible um
you know I like to pair it with stuff
that it's kind of like opposite of you
know it already has that funkiness it
already has that that wild stretch so to
pair it with something that's you know
kind of fruity or kind of more Stout and
you know has attributes that kind of
like mellow it out with the stretch and
everything I I found to be the most
beneficial yeah sure and I guess an
extension of that is what sort of traits
are you looking to improve so guess if
you had to you know be critical what do
you think could be better so I mean
everybody's everyone's complaint with
the GMOs it takes too long to flower um
which I agree with you know it does it
does take a long time so it kind of
negates the commercial standpoint of it
though you can run it commercially it's
just most people nowadays because of how
the industry is they want to run like
nine weeks and proper GMO just can't go
nine
weeks
um so when you when you breed with it or
use as a tool your main at least my main
goal is to shorten flower times which
I've you know I've been able to do um
and still be able to pull a lot of that
funk a lot of those things that people
love about the GMO it just people just
don't have the patience to run 90 days
85 days so definitely the time got to
knock that down the stretch some people
have an issue with it that have short
ceilings or more confined space so
knocking that stretch down a little bit
is is always something that I I Look to
accomplish when breeding with it
um I like to kind of like dense it up
don't really like to give it things that
have fox tail
Tendencies um the GMO can kind of fox
tail sometimes on its own so anything
that can kind of like help densen it up
so basically flower time flower density
stretch those are like the main my main
concerns whenever I use it as a tool for
breeding yeah nice and I'm really Keen
to jump into some of the Donny Burger
Han Solo Burger all that sort of stuff
but before we get there I just want to
quickly ask you I read an interesting
comment by a good friend of the show
dirolf he's a well-known Canadian grower
and he made a comment a few weeks ago
that sort of stuck with me which was I'm
paraphrasing but essentially he said you
know GMO has done more for the Canadian
cannibis scene than any other strain
since breeda Steve sweet skunk which
obviously you know made a big splash
many years ago have you heard sentiments
to this effect and how does it feel to
be associated with a strain that's has
such far reaching impacts in a you know
a place like Canada which is you know
well-known cannabis
producer H I think it's amazing I think
it's amazing that I was able to be part
of that and just you know I didn't I
didn't breed it I just selected I just
found it I'm just the the person that
bought the lottery ticket that you know
hit a jackpot so to speak but um being a
part of that
and being able to share that and and
hearing people's stories about how it's
changed the industry in such a positive
way especially like I said you know
these these guys that are big hashers
and make a lot of rosin and you know all
these concentrates and just hearing
their stories about just how it's
changed their lives financially just
like personally it's just it's amazing
I'm so proud and happy to be a part of
that and just be part of the story you
know just to be somebody that
contributed to it it's just fills me
with
joy ah humble man I love it I love it
all righty well let's jump in to some
more breeding stuff but before that take
me back tell me about your first
experience with
cannabis um started smoking at a young
age um
the first time I smoked I knew that it
was going to be something important in
my life um it just like had this hold on
me where it was really calming and it
just went along with a certain type of
lifestyle that I knew I wanted to be a
part of and I just just haven't really
put it down um since you know suffer a
short little period with uh with the
court system
but besides that it's just been a been a
constant in my life man and you know
I've I've feel like it's just changed me
for the
better yeah wow that's awesome to hear
that you had that connection with it so
early on when you first started smoking
was this at a time frame when like there
was strain names or was it before that
and do you remember the sort of effects
you were feeling when you were first
starting
smoking so like I'm decently old not
super old in the community the majority
of the peers like you know all the
Breeders and stuff I'm I'm in my late
30s so the peak I guess when I started
was like 99 you know um we weren't
really getting genetics that had like
full-on names they would come around
every once in a while but the area that
I'm at wasn't really like a cannabis
Capital here in Michigan
um we would get stuff like northern
lights every once in a while from like
older smokers some skunk skunk was
really big in Michigan here um if you
could get your hands on it but couple
years maybe into smoking we started to
see um some of my buddies like older
brothers and stuff started doing little
closet grows and go to like Amsterdam
and bring back seed and some of the some
of the early centy stuff and and serious
seed stuff like AK-47 and um sensey star
I remember being just like amazing where
it was just like once you got your hands
on that like you're like I'm not I'm not
smoking this uh you know offbrand
whatever it is like this is this is all
I want now this is it's a game changer
it's just you know unique and the highs
are different and they're exciting and
yeah
just early on you know it's just they we
didn't have what people have now with
this variety and the accessibility you
know I'm I'm sure that you can probably
somewhat relate to that um I'm not sure
how available genetics are there in
Australia but um you know it's it's to
grow up in an era where you had to seek
really good weed and it wasn't always
available and then to have what we have
now here where you can just walk into a
store and pick off of a menu it's just
how times have
changed yeah hugely hugely I mean yeah
paradigm shift for sure so I guess then
I'm interested to know what was the
progression from you know having the
first few encounters with it realizing
this is something you're highly into to
then progressing to your first grow do
you remember that and what you were
growing absolutely so I went to Jamaica
on a trip and got to tour some really
cool ganja Fields out there um found
some seeds and some
buds uh brought him back horrifyingly
brought him back and uh built this
little
box um and just did my first grow with a
400 light bulb and it was just like I I
didn't even think about it it just came
naturally or it was just like you know
nothing that anybody I knew was doing at
the time no one was no one was growing
any flowers I was you know 18 years old
and it was just something that people
weren't really talking about there
wasn't even like grow supply stores you
could walk into and just openly talk
like you can now um so it was
like you know was kind of difficult it
was you know internet wasn't even
something that you know people were
really much using at the time it was you
know just starting to get where you know
forums were you know getting formed and
people were talking about it openly like
on the internet it was it was a lot more
difficult to start back then
um but it was progression was was
constant it was just a flow just
something that naturally I wanted to get
involved in and seek out other people
that were doing the same thing
like-minded people and kind of led me to
like I see mag and and you know THC
farmer and stuff like that um where I
could just interact with other people
that were going through the same stuff
and could relate to what I was trying to
accomplish and give me ideas and we
could just kind of like feed off of each
other
and it was it was a unique thing to
experience um growing flower when nobody
else in the area did you know now it's
you know everybody's involved some way
in either cultivation or cannabis
and it just wasn't the case back
then yeah totally everyone's a cannabis
consultant these days aren't they
um so tell me what was the first plant
you grew where like it was like a stand
out you know I remember the I remember
when I first started growing you know a
lot of the plants were pretty midy and
it was mostly because of my skill but I
do remember a plant you know tolerating
my my horrible grow Styles and still
producing a nice sort of crop and you're
like oh some plants produce really good
bud what was that moment like for you I
started growing with this group of guys
in Detroit um they were doing Warehouse
grows um they had already developed
their own kind of tech I went along with
um they were growing this strain that we
just called the per it wasn't the same
as the seed bank perss it was what I was
told years later was something called
Green Cross or something which is kind
of you know hilarious considering it was
pure purple but um they were doing like
one gallon pots like 40 of them per 4x4
just packed side by side growing like
single colas
and I knew if I had gotten my hands on
it that I could kind of develop a better
method and grow it more efficiently and
better and I did not that it was like
you know a game Cher but um you know
just doing a scrog of just one gallons
was just not not the method but that was
my first like obtained clone that was
like something special that I could do
you know
different types of grows with and and
kind of like document it and kind of
figure it out and play with it and you
know screen grows and and you know dwc
grows and when you
know Hydroponics and all that stuff you
know first kind of like I got introduced
to that it was unique seeing the
differences but I wanted being a soil
grower and stayed with organic soil for
for a lot of years and um
that's pretty much where I stayed for a
long time until I switched over to Coco
and I didn't switch over to Coco until
like I don't even know maybe maybe four
years ago or five years ago but yeah
that that one per that one purple strain
was definitely um the one early on that
kind of changeed the game for me open
some
doors yeah incredible incredible okay
and do you remember in your early years
I think a lot of people you know we end
up getting these seed addictions and we
end up buying lots of and lots of seeds
what sort of stuff were you buying oh
man I was buying
everything seeds were like my I don't
even know they were like by drug I would
just anytime that seed drops would
happen and I was following them I just I
had to I I still to this day have seeds
that I bought like you know 15 plus
years ago that are just sitting in the
refrigerator that I just never did
anything with it was just like a it was
like a habit you know it's like got to
have these seeds these are these are
going to be these are going to be the
ones and you know some of them touched
and got into and some of them are still
sitting there just waiting to be messed
with I like to go down little Memory
Lane every once in a while and open up
the fridge and go through all the
containers of seeds that I have and but
I was I was buying up you know earlier
days I was getting a bunch of like centy
seed stuff and you
know uh Syria seeds Flying Dutchmen you
know I was getting stuff over from like
Europe and then um once the Forum days
kind of started you know these this OG
Kush kind of wave started and you were
just looking for things that had like OG
Kush in them or you know Bubba Kush in
them or any of the chem if you're lucky
enough to get anything with cemin it and
you know um which is the whole just
buying seeds and bulk thing was just
kind of like why I started making my own
seeds because it was just I I was
Finding not great representation of what
I was really looking for in seed form so
it kind of like mentally put me in this
position where I'm like you know I need
to I need to start doing some creating I
need to you know get my get my hand in
some of this genetic stuff and
uh kind of changed you know me buying
seed to trading seed and kind of things
kind of went in a you know different
directions from
there yeah so tell me about it what was
your first Endeavor with
breeding I was playing around with male
plants kind of trying to you know
understand you know how dropping pollen
and and what kind of traits you know
plants put out or gave indic you know
looking for indicators stem rug and you
know stressing out plans to kind of play
with them see what it made it do and you
know starve them out or don't give them
water for a little while and kind of
drought them out and see what kind of
Expressions come out with them see if
they you know makes them drop pollen and
you know my whole thing my whole
breeding experience is all it's all
based on trial and error you know I'll
make things and and they'll be awesome
you know make things and they're [ __ ]
terrible and you know it's like it's all
just like a constant learning experience
for me and it's a you know there's a big
learning curve to the whole breeding
thing and and just growing in general
and I don't think you can grow unless
you have failure and just breeding even
more so like like I've been work I
worked at Larry line still work in the
same Larry line um for like 10 plus
years and I had certain Generations that
I you know made and and went back
because I wasn't I wasn't happy with how
you know The Offspring was so I mean
even to this day I still make plenty of
error like constant error but you know I
pride myself in you know when I have
success in it and you know it's it would
be naive to think that everything that
is ever made is is going to be you know
awesome yeah sure look you touched on
the the Larry and that was certainly
something I was hoping for us to delve
into you know wanted to first off start
by asking where did the passion for the
Larry OG come from well a lot of the
passion came from it being the only OG I
could get my hands
on so kind of wanted being the leading
horse there in the uh in the race but um
luckily I mean the Larry is epic like
it's it's a great OG cush like I wish I
still had the original cuddle Larry i'
would be thrilled to have the original
Larry um pretty much worked it into a
solid SE and something like basically
spot on or close to pops up on a regular
basis for me
but it was definitely like you know it
was my first dealings with OG Kush the
first genetic that I got in physical
form of of a clone of OG Kush and I just
love the plant so much and you know I
was lucky enough to get it have a real
version of it and it kind of just like
made it in no Briner for me like that it
was going to be something that I worked
with and uh early on in the game I was
blessed enough to um kind of get to know
Elite
genetics and he was also a big Larry fan
um he had worked something that he was
calling the lemon Larry which was Larry
OG Kush crossed with sour diesel IBL
from um res
seeds uh he passed me some of the seeds
uh to work with so I was able to do like
a little BX across the uh mail that I
found from his seed stack to the Larry
clone only um making the first VX and
then uh I just worked you know FG from
that point on and and you know finished
up
f10s and you know I'm still going to
continue to work the line until I don't
know just probably forever it's just
such a great line it's it's amazing um
the the outcrosses that I've made from
it people loved it's just uh it's
something that's special to me as a
reader it's just I put a lot of time and
work into it so um I'll probably always
continue align to
that ah that that's awesome to hear and
I I read on your website that you'd sort
of um you know briefly discuss this
experience where you got to try this
legendary OG while you're on Venice
Beach do you think that was the
Larry I think that was probably just the
original OG um grown really well by
somebody there in Southern California
um
I've grown the original just briefly um
I just I just got it back from Josh um
him and I are actually uh working on a
collab project together an OG project um
so it should be cool to see how the
original which I think is what they were
calling the Venice OG um grown locally
in the area of Venice at the time um how
that grows and and contrast to you know
being hit with the lar that I've worked
on for so long and seeing what kind of
Expressions come out of that what kind
of fenos I can find and and just kind of
lines that we can work together from all
that it's you know something I'm really
really really excited
about that's awesome to hear and uh yeah
definitely shout out Josh D just a a
lovely guy shout out JH D Man Josh is
the man yeah i' I've met met him two or
three times in person when I've been in
the states and he's always been such a
lovely you know just really easy to talk
to guy so definitely shout out joshd I
got a question that's more of a personal
one for me than anything else but years
ago probably at least 10 years ago I
tried some lario that was imported Bud
from the States you know came to
Australia and I remember thinking you
know it had this sour lemon sort of
flavor to it and then years later I
tried Larry OG at Mr Bob hemp's house
and it was like the original OG and I
was like oh this isn't lemony like the
one I tried years ago and then you know
as you've sort of touched on you hear
that there's this other one you know
this electric lemon Larry it's got a few
different names do you think that that
ex that is the explanation for the
experience I had I probably just tried
the electric lemon and the original
Larry OG is more like the original OG
where it's like an earthy cushy like not
really a lemon thing or any explanation
for maybe how I had those two different
experiences yeah I mean I've gone back
back and forth with a few people on this
and the original is just a lot a lot
more rare than people would think it is
there's a lot of um seed genetics that
have been created I know swerve did um
did a Larry uh bx2 or something um years
back and some of those phenos that
people found were getting pasted as the
Larry um I know that some of Elites from
Elite genetics I know that some of his
seeds that he made of the lemon Larry
were getting tossed around is just Larry
clone only um so most likely I mean if
my opinion it would probably be one of
those type of situations where if you
got something that was truly like
lemony then it was probably like had
some some of that sour diesel or
something in it you know that gave it
kind of that twist it does it does have
like a little bit of a a more citrus
than you know the original but it still
has that classic OG to it you know what
I mean it's it's it's not like candy
coated typee of thing it's more like a
mouth coating cush that has like that
little slight like electrified kind of
you know little lemon to it it's very
very light though it's it's not like the
lemon Larry or the one that swerved in
but there was and I know because i' I've
gotten past a couple Larry's that I've
grown out and was like you know this
isn't the original one this is one of
the ones from seed um so I think there's
a lot of that going on or was going on
there for a period of time uh I don't
really see the Larry popup at all
anymore um there's been a couple people
I've talked to recently that have been
like on a you know wild Witch Hunt for
this alleged you know real Larry and I
don't know I've I haven't been able to
you know track it down myself and grow
it and get a get a real version of it
so it's out there somewhere somebody has
it but probably the difference that
you're seeing is that the one later on
down the road that you tried out that
was more like the original that was
probably the real lar and the ones from
the earlier days were were crosses is
what I would probably best uh gas on
that yeah okay cool that that certainly
makes sense in my mind so I'd love to
hear a little bit more about your Larry
OG line and some of the specifics about
it because we did have some fans
submitted questions and I guess one of
the obvious things that jumps out to
most people is that you've bred it a
number of filial generations I think as
you mentioned up to the F10 the question
is what sort of traits were you looking
to preserve and what sort how would you
describe the plants that you'd get from
that line in general the the seed line
as opposed to the Clone so what I was
really trying to do is just kind of
capture the original into seed form um I
wasn't really trying to necessarily in
the beginning
um add anything to it or strengthen it
in any ways um I guess maybe like
subconsciously I would select you know
plants by structure that had better node
spacing than the original the original
kind of you know has a little bit of
lengthiness to it um maybe I was doing a
little bit of that subconsciously but it
was really trying to just lock down the
original and um you know just in case
down the road I kind of lost it which
you know it's exactly what happen um I
could kind of like pop seed and just
kind of you know start over again you
know
um
definitely think that some of the
generations that I ran through some of
the sour popped up in and I would get
phenos that ranged almost on the diesel
side um the f6s that I made I got a lot
of sour in them and even some like
purpling that came in which was kind of
different than some of the other
Generations but but
um the f7s were the ones that I started
doing out crossbreeding with the f8s
were more public ones that I did drops
with
um it's like I said it's probably really
just like the goal was to get that and
just lock it in in seed
form yeah and and would you say that in
general you feel like you've been able
to do that or do you feel like each
generation sort of represents the Clone
in a slightly different
way um I think I've been able to do it
for the most part I mean there's there's
certain Generations that I I favor just
because I like you know how they are but
um the last ones the last two the the
f8s were pretty locked in there wasn't a
whole lot of variation really at all um
there wasn't any sours that came up the
f9s were just like amazing they were you
know straight OG push like every plant
looked very similar there was no you
know massive nug fenos or no sour fenos
or nothing weird that was popping up it
was you know it was real uniform where
you know as it should be you know that
far work down the line um but it's
surprising even when you inbreed some
stuff that far like you know you get
some things that pop up every once in a
while especially if you're popping
enough seed and and looking through
things properly you know some of the
back genetics that'll come up in it and
it's
just I mean at this
point it's just keeping the gene alive
and kind of preserving it it's just for
fun it's not like you know I'm trying to
accomplish anything more at this point
with it but um the outcrops are really
what what really exciteed me about that
Larry line and um look forward to kind
of like what that can mix with the whole
Josh collab and you know it's just uh an
honor to be a part of the OG Kush thing
and trying to make my way with that like
like I did with the GMO you know yeah
nice and I mean you just sort of touched
on it there what was the first outcross
you did with it that really got you
excited um I had did a
chem4 uh cross with Larry OG and that
was just like so unique and it drew like
different types of hems in the phenos
that were like ranging from just huge
flowering um plants just covered in
resin
to just gas and just it was just amazing
the chems in the ogs mesh very well
together um in my experience they have
um I did some other OG C I did the TK I
used the TK and cross it with the Larry
um
the Louie a lot of the ogs that were
around
um I just thought you know like what
could go wrong mixing an OG with an OG
and some of them did well some of them
didn't do as well as the other ones um
but yeah lots of exciting stuff when you
work with those you know types of
genetics the kushes and and the Bubbas
and that stuff what kind of pops
out yeah for sure and I mean in general
would you say there's a certain type of
plant that you're all line pairs well
with or is it more of like a case by
case
basis it's kind of case by case you know
I mean I obviously like tend to want to
breed with plants that I enjoy
smoking so um you know I've done a bunch
of work with Bubbas and and kkes and um
drape ape and you know just some of this
some of the older Classics you know and
um I'm glad I did because some of them I
don't even have anymore
um but I wouldn't say it necessarily
pairs better with
some but I did do a early on super
silver haze cross and um it did not
really pair well the fenos kind of like
were all over the place and I just
didn't really find anything that I
really enjoyed and wanted to
keep ah okay that's interesting that's
cool I guess as a as a general question
you know when we when we talk to
breeders you know we often talk about
the crosses that work but you you
interestingly have touched on a topic we
sometimes discuss which is that
sometimes crosses don't work and I guess
as a general sort of discussion you know
how often do you find that's the case do
you find that most of the time crosses
work and it's only rarely you have to
sort of be like you know what this one
didn't quite work out or is it a bit
more even across the board so like I I
gauge what I'm going to you know drop to
people and release um and offer publicly
based on my testing experiences with
with the crosses so I mean sometimes
I'll run 20 seeds sometimes I'll run you
know 100 seeds depending on the cross
and um some things just don't work and
like I have a huge stock of things that
I'll never release because I did not
find them to be good at
all and like I'll never revisit some
things you know like there's just it's
like a a lesson learn
just super skunk I did a couple Super
Skunk crosses with the Larry um didn't
enjoy any of those um years back when I
still had the mass Super
Skunk those plants just the structure on
them just was not like desirable at all
like from a grower standpoint
cultivating them they were just branches
flapping all over the place
and just just wasn't something I would I
would ever you know pass out even for
free like just just waste of time or so
I mean I've I've definitely had plenty
of trial and error and plenty of
error which is kind of like you know
obviously helped with you know success
because I know what not to
do so yeah there's there's definitely
plenty of crosses that went bad no I
love that I'm going to steal that phrase
you know I've trial an error and I've
also just had error that's a good
um you mentioned the mass Super Skunk
you know recently we've had a few
episodes sort of with discussions around
that featuring skunk VA and Staten
Island um how would you describe the
mass Super Skunk you were familiar with
um it wasn't so much like on the rotten
skunky kind of side of things um it
wasn't sweet either but it just it
tasted really good it had a really good
turine profile to it um it yielded
really well they kind of grew in like
this kind of crazy Bush um I haven't
seen that plant in probably a decade
it's probably been about 10 years since
I've had it um but yeah it's it's you
know it's not what people think of when
they think of like a roadkill or
something like that but um it was a
unique one it was a fun one to play
around with sure I can see where like I
can see like where like the jel and and
some of that stuff you know like I can
see the relation in that line yeah nice
okay and and have you ever been in
search for the the roadkill like Sama or
has it not quite piqued your curiosity
in the same way yeah I mean being from
Michigan we used to have tons of
roadkill skunk here that's kind of like
what I grew up smoking like when I got
good flowers um I just I I have not been
able to find it it's something that's I
haven't like gone out of my way like in
a crazy way to try to find it but it's
not something that I think is kind of
just like floating around anymore I
think maybe maybe some old heads kind of
keeping it close maybe but I mean I've
had discussions with a lot of people in
the industry and everyone's kind of like
leaning toward the same thing as me it's
like maybe that phenotype has been kind
of like isolated away or something and
just people didn't find it desirable for
a period of time when you know growing
wasn't legal and you know people were
worried about you know smell issues and
stuff like that it kind of maybe just
kind of faded and took like a back seat
hopefully it's around somewhere because
I know that you know people would just
love to have that in seed form and and
have somebody that's working with it and
breeding with it but you know it's
something I think is kind of rare now I
don't I don't know I haven't seen it in
years probably 2004 2005
maybe and and what was your recollection
of it because you know some of the more
modern accounts we get from people who
are really on the search for it they'll
say oh you know I found something that's
kind of similar but potency is really
not there do you remember it as a potent
strain or was this back in the time
where you know weed was scarce and so
maybe tolerances were a bit lower and
you know I guess maybe if I just still
this question down do you think it is
that mythical hype thing that some
people make it out to be or do you think
there's an element of like reminiscent
Rose shade sort of
glasses I mean if I'm being honest I
think it's like a reminiscent thing
where it's just like you're
you have this concept or this idea of of
something that really wasn't what it was
you know I think I think that stunk
smell was tremendous I remember like
smoking a joint and just wreaking to
high hell of skunk and it just like
would not come out of your clothes and
just like if if you had like a gram or a
couple grams in a in a little baggie
that you could smell it like when
somebody walked into a room you know
they were had they had the skunk on them
it was just stuck to the stuck to the
sandwich bag resinous funky but I don't
think that the high was probably
incredibly like Earth shattering
compared to some of the stuff that's
available now um I think that part of
it's kind of like mythical in the sense
um my tolerance was not incredible then
I was young I have been experienced at
that point a bunch of different kinds of
cannabis and what cannabis really had to
offer so to me it was shatteringly
strong it was it was just wreck your
world type of thing but in comparison to
you know what something that's you know
10% or 12% or something you know like
it's in the world of lab testing and all
this stuff that you know everybody so
concerned about THC content percentages
and everything I don't think that it
would be something that
would basically like dominate records
you know I think it was just good at
that time
because it's what was available and and
that was the best of it you
know yeah certainly that that all makes
sense and that that correlates with some
of the accounts I've heard from other
people you you touched on a number of
really interesting talking points in
that answer so I would love to touch on
a few of them and the first being you
know the THC percentage predicament
which is a bit of a tongue tire so you
know there's like a bit of a common
sentiment in the community that uh you
know we're too Dominator by THC
percentages and I guess more
specifically there's this push that we
need to try to educate consumers to to
not focus on it so much I guess the
question is do you think it's possible
to do this or do you think that the
general consumer is going to follow
numbers to an extent and it's really
like the hardcore Community like that
yourself and I exist in that you know
have the luxury of sort of being like
well you know THC percentages aren't
everything yeah I mean I agree with that
I wholeheartedly I agree like it's when
I when I go into a dispensary not that I
do it often and you know but if if I go
into I'm not worried I'm not looking at
THC content percentages like I want
flavor I want you know I want to
experience something other than what I
have at my house
so I don't base what I what I buy or or
what I grow on THC content but I do also
as a as a seed maker realize that people
do get seeds and they want High testing
THC content genetics so it's really like
this place in the market and in the
industry right now where it's it's like
you're damned if you do and you're
damned if you don't you know um you you
have to produce things that are going to
have high test scores because at the end
of the day you still have to give the
people what they're looking for but
you're also fighting like the ignorant
of saying
like you know THC doesn't matter the
content doesn't matter this lab test
doesn't matter and it it's a weird point
right now that we're at where I think
that the dynamic will shift and people
will start to just appreciate flowers
again because they can just go get wax
or go get oil if they want to get
wrecked
um but I think that that whole thing is
going to kind of change soon and I'm
kind of seeing it where people are kind
of like more interested in turine
profiles and you know basically those
kind of lab tests where it's like what
kind of active flavors are you going to
get out of the flowers as opposed to
what's the THC content um but is it a
breed or it really puts you in a really
hard place where it's like you just kind
of want to you know mess around with
with things and make something unique
but it's like you're kind of also like
forced to kind of like C out to this
whole we need High testers thing so it's
definitely a definitely an issue in my
opinion like I don't know it's a weird
place to be in right
now yeah certainly certainly I mean you
know another another point that you you
touched on is that you know the roadkill
skunk likely wasn't as potent as some of
the more modern stuff and there's
there's like an element of being
reminiscent and I guess you know
recently there's been a Resurgence of
older genetics especially in the context
of people looking within them to sort of
make new hybrids going forward and you
know you can sort of look at like Tom
Hills sort of you know been um toying
with his Hayes and we've seen Todd
McCormick and Caleb and Matt Riot do
their nl5 re-releases respectively have
you ever had any curiosity to look in
some of this older stuff and do you
think it might be like a viable path
forward to blend some of that old with
some of that new absolutely I mean in my
opinion a lot of these current genetics
used a lot of that Old Dutch you know
cense C seed bank you know some of some
of those lines um and I think it would
be foolish not to revisit some of the
older stuff you know especially the
northern lights or or this you know the
some of the skunk lines and I mean I
would love to to do a bunch of Sensei
star work I used to love Sensei star um
it was just like this funky you know
stank gooey flower that just like I I
was lucky to get my hands on and you
know was getting grown locally and it
just every time I got it it was just
amazing you know so I I personally love
to work with something like that or like
the old
AK-47 you know some of the guys I've
seen you know over the past like decade
or so they they did a AK-47 a cherry
feno it still wasn't what I remember it
being but it it was pretty good
but yeah I think that's great I think
you should always try to bring back some
of the old stuff and kind of like pay
homage to it and and give it the respect
it deserves it's you know part of the
stepping stone to where we are now is is
due to you know some of those genetics
so yeah I'm I'm pumped to see what some
of these guys do with some of the older
stuff yeah likewise likewise and you
sort of touched on it with that answer
there but I guess I'll throw throw it
open to any other ones you know are
there any strains besides say the Sensei
star that have left a lasting memory for
you but sadly no longer have access
to yeah so like I have I have the
Indiana bubble gum it's good but the
bubble gum in the late 90s the early
2000s was amazing it was completely
different than the Indiana bubble gum
and if I could get my hands on that one
I I would love to work with that the
bubble gum was
just it had like this like really
playful kind of like uplifting kind of
buzz but it wasn't like anxiety driven
it was just kind of like euphoric you
know um I loved it um the cotton candy
back in the late 9s early 2000 that was
a great one great flavor great
High there's a small handful of ones
that I would I would personally put on
my list there to uh to do a couple
projects with for
sure yeah awesome awesome take me back
to earlier we were discussing how you
were getting into cannabis you were
growing you were getting your hands on
these cool genetics at what point did
you officially decide to start skunk
cast genetics so the concept the idea
the name skunk house was kind of
something I threw around in the Forum
days in like you know 07 and 08 it was
kind of like my tag my sign off line it
was like skunk house you know came up
with skunk Master Flex is as a screen
name um you know it was just kind of
like my little my little house my little
you know grow I used to call this this
skunk dungeon skunk house so skunk house
genetics was kind of just
like kind of like organic it kind of
just like happened on its own um it
wasn't
until I had Matt respects on the
forums and he was going through some
stuff um
financially uh his wife had some health
issues and he was he was in a tough spot
and we kind of went back and forth on it
and he was like Hey you know let's let's
let's drop this seed let's create some
you know Revenue it really really you
know it would be a big deal to me it
would really help me out we kind of
launched skunk house and I was you know
just it was a bunch of projects that I
had done just breeding and I'm you know
with the intent of just you know being
basically personal work of my own and
not really being like you know a seed
breeder and dropping genetics for public
but um that was
basically how I launch launched stunk
house was just based
on his situation and I'm like well you
know I'll start skunk house and he had
California seed bank so um we did all
the vending through California seed bank
and uh that was Rock and Roll history
there yeah that's that's awesome to hear
and what were some of the first releases
and and were they the first ones to get
some traction with the public or did it
take a little bit of time before the
general public started to realize the
quality of the
work so the first releases were like um
20 2017 I did my first drop um it was a
bunch of Larry uh OG
F7 uh work bunch of crosses but the year
previous to that I went to the High
Times cup here in Michigan and was just
kind of like giving out packs of seeds
you know just kind of like spreading
them out like hey you know hunt these
have a good time with them and and bunch
of my buddies hunted them a bunch of
random people that years down the road
you know when I had a booth and was
bending seed came up and they said hey
man you know you gave me packs like just
TOS me packs back like you know two
years ago and they were just epic and
you know just want to support the brand
now and
um the original releases were the f8
stuff and I think it was like I did like
cam 4 cam 9991 TK
um a couple different OG kushes I think
I did like the original Bubba the 98
Bubba um there's a handful of other
crosses that I made but that was that
was our first my first seed drop that I
ever did was was the OG stuff um which
is was just amazing some of the stuff
that came out of there was incredible um
people got their hands on that uh they
just wanted more so I further worked the
Larry line f8 I was working with the f8
mail um that was when the GMO got
brought in
um with Han Solo Berger that was the
first GMO cross that I did for public
drop um also the um pollen donor to make
the Donny Burger to create the the VX so
it was that was a pretty legendary
drop yeah hugely hugely and I've got a
bunch of questions about the the Donny
burer the Han solid burger and all that
the first one I'd love to swing by you
is one we actually got from a listener
um which was what sort of stimulated you
initially to begin the burger
Lawns um I wanted to work with the GMO
because it had such a like impact on my
life that it just it was something that
I needed to do a cross with and then
once I did do a cross with it I realized
the potential that it could use down the
road genetically and doing hybrids with
it and um like I said isolating certain
phenotypes that just flowered shorter
and
just expressed things that were kind of
unique it just it was like a gene pool
that you just kind of like rolled the
dice with and you're like you know let's
let's kind of see what comes out of this
let's see what kind of unique things we
can do and what we can accomplish you
know when I was making the seed I didn't
really
realize how it passed um you know hash
potential to other genetics ones that
maybe necessarily didn't really hash
super well and how it kind of like
lended a hand to kind of give them a
little boost and um once once I did
realize this it was kind of like a
no-brainer to be like you know we're
going to do we're going to do a GMO line
and we're just going to do like you know
kind of like back cross it a few times
and then kind of work that
and kind of just see where it goes and
just you know it opened up a whole new
door to things that were were amazing
that just kind of like went their own
directions you
know yeah no that's brilliant because it
Segways exactly into what I was going to
ask you next which is as you progress
further into the GMO back crosses with
the burger lines was your intended
process to create something that's
essentially the GMO in seed form or were
you looking to do something that was
sort of standing on its own two legs and
maybe representing both sides of the
lineage a little more so like when I do
the straight GMO crosses when I do the
bx2 or the bx3 or the BX 4S that I
finished a couple months back or you
know do a bx5 like my intent with that
on its own is to definitely lock in the
GMO um but like kind of alter a little
bit you know to kind of like isolate
certain traits certain things that I
find less desirable like you know like
I've said a few times now like you know
the flowering time and stuff like that
but that's definitely to keep the the
majority of the GMO in there um when I
do the
outcrosses my main goal with that um
what I Envision anyways is just using
the parts of it that I like and trying
to eliminate the parts that I don't like
and kind of let whatever um female I'm
using in the cross kind of like
influence it more than the actual poen
from uh the bx2 the bx3 or any of the
burger stuff you know I just I want to
bring in a little bit of funkiness from
that
GMO um but I want to like you know bring
in the stuff that that you know people
are really looking for you know they
want they want hashers they want yields
they want you know stack they want you
know that smell but like not dominated
they want
like something else you know it's like
the gmo's just like a incredible tool to
kind of like loan to other things to
kind of like enhance them you know it's
like the secret it's like the secret
ingredient that like you know your
Grandma leaves out of the cooking recipe
that she doesn't tell you
about that's cool I mean you you sort of
touched on it but I did want to formally
get an answer to you know what would be
your Sal pitch for someone who's sort of
looking at the double burger the triple
Burger maybe even the Han Solo burger if
they get their hands on some of the
seeds you know how would you describe
this to them into terms of what they
should expect if they run a pack of
these
seeds um expect something that is
completely different than the rest of
the stuff you have in your garden it's
it's going to be foul it's going to have
you know kind of like that sank you know
that that something different you know
what I mean it's it's not a it's not a
candy it's not a dessert kind of thing
it's it's like its own class which you
know I which is what I believe is kind
of like what makes it stand out you know
it kind of created a different category
I mean it it existed a little bit you
know obviously the chmd was around and
the KD's got that kind of funk to it but
there wasn't like a whole category of
those kind of genetics where it's like
disgusting foul you know and now you
have that getting crossed with something
that smells awesome that's you know
fruity and and now you got funky fruity
and you know
it's I guess my sales pitch would be you
know it's just different
it's a it's a breath of fresh air to
have something that's not the same thing
regurgitated over and over and over
again yeah certainly certainly and you
know you you sort of touch on this idea
that you mention in I don't know if I'd
call it your slogan but I remembered
seeing it on your website and it just
says that you know you got to focus on
high yields and unique turps and you
know by virtue of what you've just said
that stands true I guess the follow-up
question is to what degree do you feel
like these are important factors in the
current market because to be honest
we've never really heard people talk
about high yield being like a necessity
or like something that they're looking
to actively breed But as time goes by I
think we are seeing an emergence of this
becoming like a more accepted um
attribute that plants need to have in
the modern climate you know where do you
sit on that do you think like you know
unique turps obviously but High yielding
do you think that this is something that
needs to be factored in by more people
across the board to make strains more
viable so I think I think in places
where you're seeing uh the price of
cannabis you know Bing them out I I
think that the yield does matter um
obviously not everything has to be drone
for for personal smoke and and you know
um not everything that's incredible
yielding is going to have devastating
Highs but you need to offset something
genetically to make up for um you know
expenses so yield is important it's not
the most important but it's definitely
in the top three if you're in the legal
Market or even you know non-legal Market
it's just where cannabis here in in the
States has gone is just it's gone down
like the pricing and and the
availability is high so I think that
yield is becoming more relevant I think
people used to say that the yield
doesn't
matter but I think that Dynamic is going
to shift it already has shifted here
where I'm at I know that you know
commercially there's just some things
that aren't viable to grow because of
yield like you couldn't do rooms of
veral and some of this bubba and stuff
and and if you did your your price tag
would have to justify the fact that it
yields or it Veges or it takes you know
more time and and cost more to cultivate
and um I think a lot of these companies
are offsetting with things that yield so
um like I said that's taking some of
this burger genetic and Crossing it to
things that don't yield and kind of
utilizing the the GMO and you know what
it does in a commercial setting minus
the time
is I mean it's it's a great it's a great
method for for
Success yeah certainly certainly and I
want to touch a little bit on the
Michigan scene because it's not one
we've spoken about extensively in the
past and yeah I do remember reading an
article the other day and I I might be
getting this wrong but I it basically
said something to the effect that like
Michigan is one of if not the the
largest flower producing states in the
USA right now which again I might have
misremembered that quote but it
regardless of whether it was the most or
like still second to California or
whatever the point remains like it's
it's a very quickly rising star and it's
it's I shouldn't say rising star it's
been doing its thing for a long time
right but how would you describe the
state of Michigan at the moment and do
you feel like it is having a big Surge
and putting it on par with somewhere
like
California oh yeah The Surge is enormous
here I mean I've been to uh countless
facilities um done a bunch of
walkthroughs there's some I mean
Michigan has a very impressive
cultivation um Department in general
like our our cultivating here our hash
making here I mean it just it escalated
so quick um there's so many companies
that are involved now and the market is
just so saturated that you really have
to be like at the top of your game um I
know I just entered the legal Market um
shout out to PR gr my team over there um
they guys do amazing job I mean you eat
up the floor it's so clean in the place
um just on scale like it's just you
really just got to be at the top of your
game and and those guys over there are
just incredible and I mean it's just I
don't I don't know how to describe it
besides like maybe like the boom in
California Market you know what I mean
it's just it really makes people rise of
the occasion really hone in their
craft yeah nice okay and I mean you sort
of just touched on it but do you think
pairing with like a big facility is one
of the only viable ways to go forward as
a breeder or do you think you could do
your thing as a small um home Scout
hobby Enthusiast sort of operation or do
you really need that size and scale to
be making an impact um I think you could
do it on your own I think quality just
has to be has to be there um I mean I'm
still you know a caregiver of sorts like
on my own M personal grow and stuff like
that and and I always will have some
kind of a grow going um so I mean
there's always room for that but it's
definitely becoming smaller and the
opportunity is is less um these big
facilities are
definitely crushing the caregiver Market
here but I think that high quality
flower is always going to be in demand
and if you can you know find a way to
cultivate like like my guys over there
have um and scale up to that level and
still produce that kind of quality I
think uh I think it's a win-win for
everybody yeah hugely hugely and what do
you think is the future for the m and
pop growers in Michigan do you think
that you know we're going to see a
similar thing to what happened in
California where over time the smaller
producers may get forced out of the
market due to economies of scale and
other sort of factors like that
absolutely I mean you're you're already
seeing that now you're seeing you know
even even commercial grows I mean that
just aren't hitting their numbers and
just doing work properly and and just
really you know honing in their
cultivation departments they're they're
getting wiped out I mean it's it's sad
to see but
it's it's the same thing that kind of
happened in California or any of these
other states you know it's just you you
really got to step your game up and
really just take advantage of a full
work day and and put in the work put in
the time and take pride in what you're
trying to produce and um I mean to
answer your question I mean it's yeah
it's these these small places are going
down and it's not necessarily because
they're small but just because you know
other people are rising more to the
occasion yeah okay and and so what would
be yours glass ball prediction for 10
years time where do you think the
industry will be do you think we're all
going to be puffing on Vape sticks and
no one cares for flour anymore cuz I
have to admit you know I um although I
live in Australia my brother-in-law he
he lives in America and he's like 22
right so he's young and he's like my
pulse on the general sort of um you know
casual smokers and he he calls me a
dinosaur for smoking flour he's like bro
get a babe stick like you know where do
where do you think we'll be in 10 years
time if that is sort of the sentiment we
see from some of the younger
Generations yeah I get that I mean I
definitely I get that I understand where
where you know you're coming from on
that sentiment like you're
seeing flower kind of becoming less
relevant but you know here like 10 years
ago people were like flower was dead to
them and everybody was just dabbing they
were just hitting oil you know and now
it's like the oil Market's like probably
10% of the sales or something you know
so I think things are you know kind of
not necessarily dying or transitioning
but there's like little phases and then
people kind of like get out of that and
they're just like well I you know hit
flower the other day and it's just like
wow I missed it like I don't know why I
was just smoking so much oil and wasn't
really rolling anything up so I think
that you'll go through these little tiny
phases where you know things will lose
relevance and then they'll gain
relevance again so I mean it would for
me it would be devastating because I am
a flower smoker like through and through
and I can't really
appreciate oil as much as you know some
of these other guys um these Vape things
are super convenient like I'm not going
to lie I carry a rosin disposable pen in
my pocket most of the day and it's just
you know I can't just spark up joint
anywhere I go and you know sometimes I
don't want a smoke ho joint and I just
wanted a couple hits
and whole Vape game has just made it
very
convenient
and I mean I I I love Vapes but it's
never going to be flower to me it's
always just
like an ease to get through until I can
smoke some flour
I like that I can relate for sure and
you know you you talked of how you know
these things sort of e and flow like
when you were mentioning like you know
the BHO and concentrates in that same
vein you know on the show we often talk
about the flavor of the month being very
cyclical you know it's like fashion you
know these things go in circles and at
the moment the consensus seems to be
that the dominant flavor in the market
you know for lack of a better term is
the purple candy gas you know if you
look at people like compound and cookies
and the guys who are sort of dominating
the market that's the general Vibe I
want to know what's your flavor
prediction for the future what do you
think Jud to come back
around oh is coming back gas is gas is
making its way back around nothing would
make me more
happy uh yeah but yeah I get I get what
you're saying there's definitely like
this huge wave of Lemon Cherry gelato
and and and that whole kind of vibe um
it's it'll be like you know it'll be
like cookies you know when cookies hit
here people were like you know what's OG
it's everything's cookies like OG's dead
and then you know cookies kind of
started to fizzle out and then you
started getting these different gelato
kind of things that were kind of similar
and people went on these little tiny
phases where you know it was like the
lemoner gelato and the nonsense and you
know they all have their place and I've
had some of them and I was impressed by
some of them and you know
I kind of get tired of them after a
little while they're not something
that's you know like a cush to me where
I can smoke it day in and day out it's
not like a desert island strand for me
but um yeah I've enjoyed some of them
and I can see their relevance for a
period of time and these guys have
really good marketing so that doesn't
that doesn't hurt at all um but yeah
it's like flavor of the week for sure
stuff um the Diesels and the chams and
and the kushes are going to make their
way back and they already are I think
it's just they're not as accessible to
some people as some of this other stuff
is so it might take a little bit longer
but done properly and you know I guess
marketed correctly I think that the uh
the Kush wave will be here
again yeah beautiful beautiful and you
know you mentioned cookies and then how
it gave way to gelados and the more
newer waves I'd love to ask you you know
a lot of people talk as though you know
cookies and then progressing to gelato
and then maybe the more modern extension
is you know like your RS 11s now do you
feel like this is a genetic dead end
that sometimes people talk of it as do
you do you agree with that sentiment and
would it ever stop you from breeding
with that stuff or are you not quite of
the view that you know it's this Doom
and Gloom genetic dead
end I mean I think that some of these
guys are going to hit dead ends where
it's just so many things combined that
it's just not unique and and just has no
value to really contribute to cannabis
you know what I mean um some of these
other guys um that are doing some of
this breeding they're really kind of
looking to isolate certain things and be
unique and I think that will make way to
the next phase of where things kind of
go and they'll be heavy contributors to
helping out
um where we go with all this genetically
but there's definitely people you know
and a lot of that stuff's like money
grab stuff where it's like I'm going to
use the hot labor and cross it to um
whatever it is that I got going on and
kind of you know do it for sales you
know everybody has to do a little bit of
it but you know some of these guys like
you said you know they're bringing back
some of this old stuff and I think some
of those genetic lines are definitely
responsible for a lot of the stuff that
we see so you know through isolation of
of certain traits and other things I
think I think we'll have different waves
and different directions that we go in
and people have different needs and
wants and they'll breed for those and
then we'll move on to the next phase
trying to be as optimistic as
possible yeah definitely definitely it's
sort of you know I've said this once or
twice on the show but it sort of makes
me want to like get like someone on the
show who's like hectically down the
rabbit hole of like the craft beer
industry or something because I'm sure
there are other industries that have
gone through what we're experiencing
where like you know bud dominated the
market and the real heady you know the
equivalent of the haze of craft beer or
whatever falls off cuz no one wants to
pay for it and and yet we see you know a
Resurgence of The Craft Beer scene now
so I'm sure that in time these things
will stay around and pop back up but I
wonder what the life cycle is yeah I
mean like with the beer industry because
you brought it up I'll use that as an
LGA like you know if you told somebody
in the 80s that sour beer was going to
be a thing you know they'd be like yeah
for what you know it's no it's not well
there's a whole category of sours now
you know um so I mean I think as long as
people are kind of like being you know
ingenuitive about how they're doing
their breeding I think that people are
going to stumble upon things that kind
of like open up doorways to different
paths that kind of really help benefit
you know the industry as a whole and you
know who knows what those are you know
it could be you know some of these
Northern Lights projects that you're
talking about people working with or you
know some of these other old school ones
um getting brought and mashed together
some of the newer age genetics and kind
of opening up doorways that we didn't
know I
think certain things are going to
basically be maxed out or are maxed out
I don't think weed is going to really
necessarily get much stronger um as far
as like lab testing goes I think we're
pretty much maxed out in there I can't
really imagine something breaking 40
plus percent it just
like doesn't seem possible
you know you need so much of it to
actually be plant matter to hold
triome so I think we're kind of getting
close to a dead end or at a dead end
with potency unless they figure out some
like chemicals that are in certain
genetics that they're not able to test
for or not testing for maybe a certain
combination of certain active chemicals
um basically making you feel more stoned
as a whole but I think flavors are going
to be the Turing game is going to be
where things are
going yeah that's a that's a great point
and uh I'd love to ask you cuz you
mentioned it what do you think is like
the the rough ballpark percentage you
would be comfortable accepting because
for a long time you know I talked to
people about I think in the past I've
said anything above 30% I just don't
know if I can really believe it what's
your thoughts on that
one um you know it's like one of those
you take a you take flowers and you get
attested at three different labs and you
get slightly different numbers from
every La so I guess until they figure
out some honest gold standard you know
who's to say what is and what isn't you
know um I have the Han Solo that that we
have here in Michigan that we have
available um on the legal Market it'll
test at 37
38%
and I mean when you smoke it you know
it's strong it's you know are those
numbers accurate I don't know we tested
at a few different labs and they've came
up like that they've retested it and it
came up the same um so who's really to
say um that kind of goes back on the
whole what we were talking about earlier
like do numbers really matter you know
and shouldn't it be more on the end user
and and the effect that they get that's
that's what I think I think that THC
kind content is not irrelevant but it
shouldn't be the thing that you're
focused on as a consumer when you walk
into a
shop yeah certainly well look you know
you touched on the idea of
standardization and I think in order to
get that there would probably likely
need to be Federal legalization so I'd
love to ask you what's your thoughts on
the idea of impending Federal
legalization in the States and how do
you think it might change the landscape
of the industry well I think it's going
to happen eventually because the
government wants their money
um and that's as simple as that is I
mean that's the majority of the States
you know besides people going in there
and actually voting but it's tax money
you know it's it's Revenue it's
standardizing it across on a federal
level is eventually one day going to
happen because it would it would
eliminate you know the black market
basically for the most part um it's
definitely the impact that they've had
through legalization has has destroyed
the black market um to a certain point
already so I don't see why they would
stop it's only going to get them more
money in their their their hands by
making it federally legal um I think
it'll be cool to see how it unfolds with
these companies doing multi-state now
and continuing to spread across where
you're going to get companies that are
like the marro of weed where it's like
you know just absolutely trash there's
no craft at all to it it's just packs of
joints for dirt and some people will be
okay with that some people don't care
you know there's people go into a store
and buy Bush beer all the time and it's
cheap as hell um and some people you
know buy a four pack that cost as much
as a whole case of beer and that
Market's always going to be there so
whether it's through full legalization
on a federal level or things stay how
they are and probably probably will for
another what maybe two or three years
but
I think it'll be a hard push through
that
and I think we're going to see some big
changes and it's going to be harder to
play ball here for
sure yeah sure and I mean what might be
your advice for anyone who's you know
trying to establish themselves in an
industry where it feels like it's
becoming increasingly difficult because
I have heard this sentiment from a few
people who are you know just sort of
starting to get really passionate about
cannabis and the gist of what they
express is that like it's never felt
more difficult than ever to say try to
be a breeder or to be a grower who's not
just you know providing myself with some
flowers but trying to actually get into
the industry any advice you might be
able to give people yeah I mean it's
it's the same sent that I've said you
know since
299 98 when I first started smoking like
it's all going to be genetic you know um
to cultivate that genetic properly and
and on a craft level is obviously a huge
ticket to that but um you know having
something unique if if every store you
walked into to buy any product if all
the products were the same then why are
you buying one company over another
company you know if if quality is the
same and and the product's the same then
what is it matter you know so my thing
that I would say to people to not
discourage them is that you need to
[ __ ] pop seeds man you need to find
some unique [ __ ] that people don't have
and kind of separate yourself and and
kind of make your own W and kind of you
know kind of do that whole route
because it's you know only a race to the
bottom if you're playing by the same
rules if you're making up your own
genetic pool and you're kind of like you
know got Unique Products then it's
there's always going to be an audience
for that you know just it's part of the
whole adapting to
um the whole game you know it's just you
got to have your own unique Twist on it
and play yeah definitely that's
certainly a sentiment I can get behind
I've been trying to sort of push that a
bit myself you know encouraging people
to do their own thing and as opposed to
trying to do your own Kush Min hybrid
I'm sure jbz can probably do a better
one than you or I so um in that line of
thought you know what would be your
advice to someone who wants to start
their own breeding project and
specifically how would you advise them
in terms of like selecting the genetics
would you say work with stuff that's
totally different to what other people
are using or would you say work with
what you're passionate about and then
try to drive it in a Direction That's
Unique where would you start I mean I
always use the passion route because if
you don't really stand behind anything
you're doing then the second that it
starts to not make sense like on a
financial level you're GNA want to back
away and that's breeding is like a long
game if you're doing it right it's I
mean you can't like Rush the process um
you're going to want to use stuff that
people like but put your Twist on it you
know what I mean
it's take take your passion and kind of
make a fusion of of what other people
you know around you have passion about
when it comes to cannabis and I mean I
do it in my lines you know not I'm not
crazy about you know
gelato and some of these other things
that over the years I've used um but to
take something like that and then put my
Twist on it and kind of like put my tag
on it and say like it's like gelato is
okay but this thing that I did to it
makes it better and you want to run
these seats you know so my suggestion to
people is always use passion it's always
always the thing that's going to be um
the accelerator in in your
career
yeah certainly certainly and uh before
we get to talking about male selection
which is always a topic people ke to
hear about I want to ask I've heard
increasing sentiments not just from
breeders but more importantly from
actual seed banks and seed bank owners
that they feel that there's been a bit
of a change in the market demand and
that the majority of the market is
primarily only interested in feminized
seeds these days have you noticed that
reflection within your own sales and
what's your thoughts on a growing demand
for feminize and less interest in
regular
seeds I mean femin seeds have definitely
progressed to be more popular than they
used to be um without a doubt um I think
that's great I think that there's a
certain Market a certain percentage of
the seed popping Market that doesn't
have the space to deal with male plants
so they don't care for them they don't
they don't need to have it in their
stock and I think I I mean I do
understand that completely so that's a
big part of what makes feminized seeds
you know
relevant
um it kind of
eliminates the selection process and
makes it easier to make genetic
combinations but there is trial and
error involved with reversal of of
female genetics and sometimes some
plants don't want to so there's a lot of
you know trial and error that goes along
with that
so I mean they both have their own
obstacles but traditional breeding is a
lot more on the
selection now none of these factors
matter if you're running and testing
your seeds and and seeing what comes of
them you're just kind of wasting space
and you're not burning people's time and
their money so
um that's really on the Breeders end but
I mean I definitely see where feminized
seeds are are kind of the majority of
the market probably more than 50%
they're probably you know maybe 60% on
the market some people are really
actively looking for fem seeds and I
mean some people use like Autos you know
I haven't really gotten to Autos myself
but
um there's a place for
everything well you read my mind cuz I
was going to ask you you know I've seen
a myriad of GMO autos on the markets
have you ever tried any Autos in general
or more specifically any of the GMO ones
and what's your thoughts on autos in
general I ran some Autos in the early
2000s when I had really really
restricted space and um wasn't really
super knowledgeable genetically um had a
buddy that went to Amsterdam brought
back some some autos and can't even
remember what they were at this point so
long ago but um not my thing um I guess
for out outdoor Farmers that you know a
lot of these guys are doing
Autos um
I just don't see them dominating the
market over traditional or feminized
seeds in general but the couple guys
that are doing the Autos are really
doing a good job with them I mean
they've i' I've seen the progress they
used to be really bad and uh over the
you know maybe past five years some of
these guys have really um kind of dialed
it in and actually gotten some not hemp
looking nonsense to come out of them so
you know props to them on that some of
the some of the Autos were just terrible
for
years definitely you know I think low
rider might have left a bad taste in a
lot of people's mouth low rider that's
what it was yeah low
rider there you go there you go um so I
guess you know if we just loop back to
the question before about the feminized
stuff I do wonder you know for a long
time people had concerns about breeding
with feminized seeds you know and I
think that empirically this has been
proven to not be a big issue if you
think about it in the sense that like
canado compound a whole bunch of
breeders out there you know they make F
and then they find stuff out of that and
they make F and doesn't appear on the
surface that all of the seeds they make
are now just hermy riddled but the
question is do you feel like over time
we may run into issues if we are just
using FS to breed endlessly and we don't
necessarily incorporate regular males
into the genetics
I mean I think so for sure but I'm not
basing that on any kind of scientific
information I'm just logically in my
head it just seems very plausible that
you're going to get more reoccurring
hermaphodite traits that are going to
pop up when you're ref feminizing ref
feminizing and ref feminizing um I mean
I know a lot of these guys are using
feminized you know fenos and reversing
them to make further lines um a lot of
them aren't having issues right now but
I mean you got to think like some of
these clone ones maybe some of these
chem look at the chems you know those
were bag seeds so that was a Herm or
some kind of possible pollen that
floated around but if you talk to you
know I believe Kem even said like there
were all every seed that he popped was a
female so what are the odds of that
being you know a pollen donor you know
from the dog bud or whatever the uh the
mythical pem line was
um yeah I think that if you kind of work
that long enough for enough years that
you're going to fall into some kind of
issue um traditional breeding shouldn't
be like completely abandoned I think
there's definitely always a place for it
especially with
preservation
um I think it's just something people
got to be careful about and make sure
they don't isolate too much of a
hermaphodite trait in the lines that
they're
doing of course yeah it sounds like a a
reasonable point and that's what my
thoughts have been is you know maybe we
don't see it now but maybe is here it
down the track but to help antidote that
I'd love to know what do you like to
select for in a male is there any
particular traits you look for or do you
feel like you know I guess maybe a
better way to put it is for you is it an
art or a science is it things you're
looking for or is it more of a feel and
you know certain males you're like this
one's talking to me so it's like a
little bit of both it's like a sweet
spot in between um like I won't use a
mail that I don't feel something toward
you know some kind like pull
gravitational pull of me wanting to use
it um I'll flower out sometimes I'll
flower out multiple males I want to see
what the flower sets look like I want to
see how they stretch I want to see
certain qualities that that you you know
wouldn't know if you didn't flower them
out um in my lines I never use multiple
males I always use one but I'll save
like the best three because if I use a
male and I'm like you know what this
didn't you know translate to The
Offspring how I wanted it to let's let's
try a different mail so I'll I'll remake
it oh I just look for you know I I look
for you know a structure I want to see
stress test I want to see drought test I
want to see stem rub I wanna you know
what I mean um certain Leaf set um
certain markers that I see
um that I think would be like
stressers um stuff like that it's really
like a guessing game but with a safety
because you have other males you can use
you
know yeah certainly I remember you know
uh DJ Short expressed the sentiment that
you know he sort of felt like ultimately
it was just about popping the seeds and
then that was how you decided if it was
a good male or not do you feel like that
in a sense is where it leaves you
absolutely man shout out DJ Short the
guy [ __ ] is amazing there you go I
love it I love it okay so we got a few
more of your lines I definitely wanted
to touch on but before I name any
specific ones I want to draw some out of
you which is the first question being
what out of your lines do you feel was
the most unexpectedly successful you
know a bit of a Dark Horse so to
speak um I used obam cush and I hit the
I hit it with the Donnie burger and some
of those fenals that came out were like
this mothball kind of
like Fruity mothball kind of just crazy
tpine profile it was the most like one
of the most overlooked genetic crosses
that I made it was just
like people needed to really like hunt
those properly like do like proper
selections on them not everything that
came out of that line was like just epic
but some of it was just like amazing
like I was I was just mindblown by some
of it um the obam cush is like in the in
the FR have you ever had the obam cush
uh we to I think I think there's two
right there's the one from CSI and then
there's the other one I think I've had
the one from
CSI okay so I think I think originally
it came from maybe some of his stock or
it was an accidental cross that somebody
got a seed in some of his
flower it's like uh I think it's like
meno per cross with like Bubba I think
is what it is yeah that's the one I've
had okay that is how did you feel about
it did you like it yeah it was awesome
like real chocolatey awesome vibes yeah
I love I love that one um use that one
and just you know like The Offspring was
just was just epic in it man it was just
I didn't expect it to be as good as it
was it wound up when I tested the seeds
it was just uh it was really
unique Ah that's cool and it brings up
this question I've asked people in the
past which is where do you delineate
between something you're happy to put
out and something you're not which is
like let's say you made a cross and 50%
of the seeds are like five like everyone
unanimously would say this is a keeper
this is incredible the other 50% of the
pack Herms consistantly would you feel
comfortable putting a pack like that out
like where do you draw the line between
something that's good versus like or
only some of the plants are good and
some of them may be a bit you know not
ideal so the Herm thing is is a is an
issue for me like I wouldn't put out a
line that was like a 50% Herm um
now 50% of what comes out of it being
good and 50% not being great I would
just put that as a disclosure and I'd be
like the stuff that came out of it that
was good was so [ __ ] amazing like you
guys really need to to crack through
these beans it's it's worth the half
that aren't good to get the other half
you know but the Herm trade and in that
thing is just it's difficult because
some people don't have a lot of space
and you don't want to burn people like
that and I've seen I've seen some
breeders put out some stuff and they
they give people heads up and they're
like hey look you know like I made this
genetic cross I made this line um Herms
have popped up like is is something that
you guys want to see how would you feel
about me releasing it you know and I've
seen it I've seen breeders like reach
out and ask the people and they're like
oh well you know if it's if what's good
is good then you know it's you know it's
worth it and whatever so I don't know
there's like I guess a fine line there
where I guess if you tell people what it
is and and the issues that you're having
with a line but for me I just I just
stay from it I don't need that kind of
problem and you know not everybody's you
know fluent on social media where they
see everything that's posted and if
somebody just goes on a on a seed bank
or on a website and they buy something
and they don't know the potential you
know harm that can do their Garden I
would just I would hate to be somebody
that ruins somebody's time like that
growing should be
fun to eliminate as much problem for the
consumer as possible is just it's the
only honest way to do any of this
now yeah totally totally so so I mean on
that same sort of line of question if
you could only recommend one of your
packs to someone without knowing
anything about them which pack would you
recommend and I guess the easy way to
think of this is what's just a general
sort of I don't I don't want to use the
word cookie cutter but like what's
something where you think most everyone
would be pretty stoked with what they
got from it so I would be like if if
everything was available you know I I
only make genetic crosses once so
whatever I get yield Pro seed wise out
of it I'll never remake A genetic cross
um it's just my way of keeping things
unique but if if it was all the same and
I had unlimited amounts of everything I
would tell everyone to run the Han Solo
Burger because um that's just that's
something special for me you know that's
it's got the GMO in it which has got its
place in my heart and and it's got the
the Larry OG line um that I worked on
for so long and it's just kind of like
its first mashup of those two where they
where they met and just the section on
there and the range of fenos that popped
up were so great that's like if you if
you just if you're a OG Kush lover there
was there was plenty of that in there
for you if you loved chem there's plenty
of that in there for you and it's
just it's just it would be my go-to I
guess to be like if if you want to see
what skunk House's backbone is like this
is this is us represented in seed I love
that I love that well I wanted to touch
on um a few more of your strains that
had been particularly notable for me
this one's going to be a bit of an
extended question but I feel like I got
to get it all out there to help lay the
ground workor so um I want to know a
little bit about the Mike Larry and how
it came about but specifically you know
the followup is obviously this one made
a lot of waves in the water it was
picked up by jungle boys they ran with
it so the followup question is how much
of a boost does that give to your
company to have someone like jungle boys
running with one of your strains so yeah
how did it come about Mike Larry and how
did it get picked up by jungle boys and
what effect did that have so with the
Mike Larry um and with a lot of genics
that I actually put out I'm really like
like pop culture kind of like infused
into cannabis and it's where I get a lot
of my ideas for names and and just kind
of directions and you know like Han Solo
bger and Mike Larry and just just just a
lot of
these things that are kind of
like I don't know bringing art and
bringing pop culture into cannabis is
kind of like it's that's like my
backbone and
um I guess the most easy way to describe
it is like you know I'm a I'm a
cultivator myself so I sit around a trim
table and Bs With Buddies while we're
you know spending hours and hours and
just kind of like go off on crazy you
know talking tangents and we listen to
music in the background and there's you
know sometimes movies playing in the
background and sometimes that stuff in
the background is is the influence to
where I get um names and and ideas from
and um the Mike Larry was
just it was Larry OG and there was bad
boys playing in the background the movie
when we were when we were trimming fenos
of it and uh you know just him saying
I'm Mike Larry and over and over again
you know I'm like this is just this is
the Mike Larry you know
this just some goofball stuff like that
you know like that's there's nothing
crazy like wildly creative about it it
was just um kind of like put in my head
and then it came
out that's cool I love it and like how
did the cross come to be was it
something you were thinking about on
paper for a long time and then finally
did or was it one of those ones where
you know it was just in the mix and then
it sort of stepped forward as a real
front runner it was um there was a bunch
of you know there's a bunch of different
gelato and um I had I had done the cross
um with a few different variations
different gelato cuts and um there was a
few that really popped out that really
mixed well with the with the Larry
um I think I and over at jungle boys
kind of recognized that I tossed him a
bunch of different seed stock that I
made he wanted to do a collab and U you
know that one stood out to those guys
when they ran it and you know he said
why don't we do a uh why don't we do a
TK BX you know I'll take your uh your TK
Larry um triangle Larry and and I'll
I'll cross it back to the TK and we'll
do a a mail line with that and um we
really like this Mike Larry line and
we'd like to use it in a bunch of
crosses and I said cool let's let's run
with it let's see what you you know
let's see what we can come up with and
uh that's pretty much uh how the jungle
boys collab went down that's killer to
hear that you know they they recognize
the the potential it had and I guess as
a as a general sort of marketing sort of
angle what what effect does that have on
a company to have jungle boys pick it up
my gut instinct is that it it helps
expose you to a whole new demographic of
consumers but maybe that's not
necessarily the case how do you feel
that that collab sort of affected your
overall popularity and
notoriety uh definitely positive um I
is a beast in the industry um anybody
that would say otherwise is just lying
to themselves um he sets Trends they you
know the jungle boys do their thing for
sure man um that collab definitely took
some of their their viewer base that
didn't recognize or didn't know who I
was um and kind of shined a little bit
of light on that
um and then outside of what it did or
what it didn't do for me it was just
kind of cool to work with um another Big
Industry guy and and that was really my
first collab I ever did
so it was kind of you I was lucky on my
half that I got to you know be part of
something that
cool yeah hugely hugely and um I just
wanted to quickly clarify you know cuz I
I have seen a number of um the jungle
boys seed releases and there is that TK
back cross mail in the mix is that the
male that you were referring to that
they built off that Mike Larry stock
yeah so the TK bx1 is um I had made um
TK crossed with Larry uh backat cross
one
f8 um I gave them seeds of that they
found a killer mail they crossed it back
to the triangle cush and then they
hunted through stock of that and then
did their line based off of their
find that's pretty cool I mean I guess
it opens the door to a followup question
which is you know how do you feel about
people breeding with your work cuz I
think the majority of people are usually
pretty okay with it but sometimes people
have certain requests where do you sit
on that one specifically we did get a a
message from one of our listeners who
said that um you know they popped a
single pack of Donny Burger found what
they think is like a unicorn just a
really special plant they said great
structure incredible growth good yield
deep funky smells test high would you
have any issues with people breeding
with your
work um
the the only thing that I where I stand
with that whole thing is like the only
thing I would want to see out of people
if they're going to use any work is just
for them to put their own unique Twist
on it I mean I I think it's awesome when
I see people use stuff that I've made
it's it's like contributing to the uh
the industry you know what I mean um I'm
I'm glad and I'm lucky I'm able to do my
part um but I do love to see when people
actually take something that I did and
kind of put their Twist on it I think
that makes it like just that much better
and more refreshing than seeing somebody
just take somebody's work and like make
f2s or find a male and then just dust a
bunch of Clone ones with a mail they
found and then release the seeds you
know I don't I don't have any issues
with either one of them regardless it
doesn't it doesn't really bother me but
on a on an artistic standpoint I I mean
I I think it's just way more flattering
when somebody says your work was so good
I wanted to put my own twist on it and
then seeing what they do with it
is to me that's just the highest
compliment yeah that's awesome to hear
you know hoping that it inspires some
Innovation so another strain I wanted to
touch on was the modified banana line
and the reason why you know our
listeners are probably sick to death of
me saying it banana OG one of my
favorite I feel like it's super under
represented especially banana as a
flavor you know you don't see it as
often as you might hope can you tell us
a little bit about the modified banana
line and how you might describe it to
people I love the banana OG it's like
one of my favorites um I never get sick
of it it
was not even a thought in my head um
when I was doing a bunch of the burger
lines to somehow work a banana into that
um I thought that cross came out Epic
uh we do a selection here for the legal
market and um in Michigan of the banana
and it is just it's killer it's strong
it has great flavor it produces well um
it's an all-around winner and
just like you man I'm just a huge huge
banana OG fan you know shout out to
Oregon
kid yeah 100% 100% so what sort of
plants can people expect to get if they
buy any of those crosses cuz I noticed
that um you know there's still a few
seed banks who stock your work who have
got a healthy amount of stock and that's
one of the criticisms we get of the show
you know we talk about all these awesome
strines that they're all sold out so
thought we better touch on something
where they can still grab it you know
how might you pitch some of those
hybrids or in general what traits do you
feel the modified banana M brings to
things it's like a rotten banana peel
you know like that's the Turing profile
that I would I would say describes it it
definitely has that banana peel to it
though
um it lends it lends in some of the
yield the plant yields very solid um
it's not super picky with feed so you
can kind of like you know Juice It Up
and not have to worry about like you
know overdoing it it can kind of take a
decent feed decent heavy feed
um if you like banana OG you're GNA like
that banana line it's just that banana
comes through so much on it it's it's
hard not to appreciate it oh man that's
gorgeous to hear cuz I I have ran a few
banana OG hybrids over the years and I
feel like it was hard to get a banana
dominant expression out of them is this
something you ever
heard um yeah because it's you know the
banana in there is not like really
really heavy heavy hitting so um a lot
of times whatever you're working with
genetically and Crossing it to it kind
of like Powers over that now you taste
is kind of like a like the cushy kind of
you know standard kind of oish kind of
[ __ ] thing but um I did a back to
banana cross which is banana OG crossed
with modified banana and that yielded
out some massive banana OG plants um
great buds great structure great
turpine um arguably if you hunted enough
of them you'd find something even more
banana than the actual banana um
but just really cool if anybody ever
comes across those and they're still
available like grab them and and just
enjoy the [ __ ] out of them because
they're they were so much fun to to run
oh that's excellent to hear I love it I
forgot to ask you a question a moment
ago when we were talking about the Mike
Larry but we did have one of our
listeners ask what sort of traits SL
plants can they expect to find in the
Mike Larry hybrids I think they were
eyeing off a few of them any you'd
recommend yeah so uh we i' offered the
straight mikee Larry
V2s um the V2s I thought were better
than the
v1s because I liked the gelato that I
used in it better uh the V1 the original
Mike Larry used the gelato 45 um which
was solid it was a solid plant um but
the V2s I used the gelato
41 and that one I thought was a lot more
unique and kind of brought more to the
table and the cross also it wasn't just
the Larry OG in that I used the Paris
Larry which was Paris OG crossed with
Larry um f8 and I thought that male kind
of brought more of the traditional Kush
so if you can find the the Mike Larry
V2s I don't I don't know if there's any
still available or floating around there
but those were pretty amazing um
some of the Mike Larry
crosses um I haven't really messed
around crazy crazy amounts with the V2
crosses that was something that
respected um so I personally didn't you
know make or run those um
but I could only imagine that there's
some killer stuff in
them yeah certainly certainly I did
notice that you'd use the Paris OG and a
few hybrids and I I wanted to ask you
was there anything specific about the
Paris OG that really Drew you to it yeah
it was just um you know the Paris OG was
like a really I like enjoyed it as like
an OG Kush lover it was just a really
unique kind of OG it kind of
structurally grew a little bit
differently it wasn't so lengthy it was
a little bit more Stout um so I thought
that kind of trait was cool from
aush um when I made the cross and I
hunted through the original Paris
Larry's I just noticed that it kind of
was bringing up a bunch different type
of kind of like OG Kush um clone only
you know traits from like some of the
Louie traits and some of the you know
some of those other ones that I didn't
even work with
so I think it kind of was I don't know
like a like an amazing tool you know to
use in a hybrid and kind of just like
brought the Best of Both Worlds and and
didn't overpower the gelato and kind of
brought its own you know OG and just
kind of just you know know just really
unique and it was just really fun to
grow fun plants nice nice and like as a
followup to this I noticed that the uh
the Mikey mic was pretty similar in
terms of the genetic combination it had
a lot of real All Stars in there you
know between the gelato the Paris OG and
the Larry OG and interestingly I noticed
you know you bred it to the F2 and I
guess I wanted to ask was there any
particular reason you decided to Philly
or breed this one forward were there any
sort of goals you were looking to hit or
was it just a cool line
uh so the Mikey Mike was just Mike Larry
F2 um that was a that was a respect
cross um I wasn't involved in the
breeding of that so that would be kind
of like more like a his him question on
that one
um I don't know if he was breeding it
toward certain traits or I'm not really
sure exactly what he was looking to get
out of that one um probably just more
isolated uh whatever fale that he was he
thought was good I
guess yeah sure and do you guys uh tend
to do crosses
independently um how does the whole
collaboration process work with you
two um so for years I was the only one
that was pretty much producing seed uh
he had an outdoor space that was larger
that he was able to
utilize um so he did a couple of lines
he did uh the lemon lime orange apricot
um it was a smaller project he
did some double burger crosses and then
he did the Mike Larry the the ones that
dropped this year the Mike Larry's from
this year were pretty much a California
seed bank trap I didn't have any part of
those ones at
all okay cool cool and do you guys
discuss crosses together as like you
know I'm going to do this so you should
pursue that or how does that side of it
work um we did when we were still
working together kind of like brainstorm
and say okay well you know I'm gonna I'm
gonna go in this direction because this
is this is what I want to do this is my
passion project and you know he would
say okay well I you know I want to do
this or whatever and it's like cool you
know make the seeds pop them see what
you come up with um ultimately at the
end of the day uh we both just kind
of Envision things differently than one
another so we just kind of parted ways
and um he's doing his California seed
bank thing and um I'm pursuing the path
that I wanted to do with the skunk house
originally so yeah yeah that's awesome
to hear that you guys have been able to
sort of leave it on a good note I wanted
to ask you about a Hot Topic in the
industry at the moment uh something
that's been prevalent in the EU scene
for a long time but something which is a
bit bit more freshly discussed in the
Americas which is white labeling of
seeds or more specifically you know
making seeds for other companies and
then just sort of letting them decide
what they want to do with it I'd love to
open the door to this discussion because
I believe you have made some seeds for
other breeders in the past what's your
thoughts on white labeling as just a a
general sort of topic to begin with uh I
think it's I think it's an acceptable
thing to do these days as long as you're
just open about it and tell people what
you're doing
um again it all really falls back on
seed testing um the main concern that I
think anybody has that's buying seed is
they want to know are they getting
viable good tested genetics and I think
as long as that's true on a seed release
then I don't think anything else really
much matters if it's authentic it's it's
what the breeder says it is and they're
standing behind their product um I think
it's all good
yeah certainly certainly I can
appreciate that sentiment I guess the
follow-up question is like where do you
draw the line you know so I'll give you
an example and maybe that'll help you
know flesh out some of the details a
little more but let's just say that you
know old heavy days buys all his seeds
from skunk Master Flex and um you know I
on the packs I list all the proper
genetics you know the lineages are all
correct and all the information is
essentially correct um and then when
people asked me about them I'm like oh
you know I made these ones last year
like I guess the question is at at what
point do you feel like um you're sort of
crossing a line with it you know is it
okay to say you made these seeds if that
in your opinion is integral to you know
the sale of the seeds or do you feel
like you'd have to be just 100% upfront
and be like oh you know I actually
didn't make this but like this is what
it is and this is what to expect where
do you sort of draw the line between
like you know Protec businesses sort of
identity versus being upfront about it
oh that's a tough [ __ ] question man
good job uh sorry uh I
mean there's I I I feel like there's so
many people in this industry that are
just really not even making their own
seed so I would
just it's a weird that's a that's a
that's a great that's a hard question um
I mean I guess you're if you're being
honest about it then it is what it is
and
[ __ ] it's that is incredibly tough to
answer because I feel like you know when
I when I offer seed I want to be
authentic with people and you know open
about what's going on and uh respect did
some some some seed making for skunk
house and you know he popped up and was
like Yay made these seeds and people
were like cool cool and he did it under
skunk house and he'll probably continue
to do under California seed bank and
he'll use lines that he worked on and
um he's putting his own twist on it so
it's you know good for him do whatever
you want um be open about what you're
doing um with some of these like where
where do you draw the line I guess
people have to draw the line I guess as
a breeder you're not the one that's
drawing the line or the or the company
the one that's Drawing the Line just
you're just offering a service and and
you let the people I guess decide if if
they want you know seed stock being made
from who they claim it's being made from
and you know I guess ask the breeder for
thorough you know information on on how
the seeds were made and and the process
and as long as the the consumer can
stomach whatever information they're
being told then I guess uh I guess
everyone draws Their Own Line of some
sort
yeah sure and do you think like this
idea or this sort of concept will expand
further because as you said there are
some breeders in the industry you know
I'll use the word Loosely breeders um
who who don't make their own seeds and
so I guess you could say well you know
maybe they're like burner you know
they're the hype man and they sell the
product and that's cool so I guess the
question is do you think that that Trend
will continue and over time we will see
people who are like the middleman or the
hype guy and reading becomes you know
more of a back room sort of thing you
know like maybe maybe the analogy is
like with rappers you know we're going
to have the rappers on the front and
then the producers in the back room
doing the hard yards like how do you see
it playing out over the long term
absolutely I mean the music industry is
like a perfect reference to using that
um you know like they'll use some super
attractive girl that maybe necessarily
doesn't have a great voice but then
they'll use like a voice synthesizer and
and you know use a studio and and make
her sound a certain type of way and then
you know you hear her live and you're
like wow it doesn't even sound like the
same person that's you know her voice
isn't that great you know using that is
obviously just an analogy to you know
like you said with Burner you have a
front man and you know who's really
doing the work who's behind the scenes
um I guess that's part of their whole
marketing though you know that's that's
how they're choosing to you know make
people look at them as as a company like
you know
don't be interested in the guy making
the seeds be interested in the guy
that's talking about the seeds um I
think it'll continue to happen probably
something that's been happening for a
long time you know um it's not like Adam
dund days anymore where it's we got
these crazy crazy breeders you know that
are just like working these crazy lines
it's there's a lot of F1 stuff coming
out some people like that and some
people want stuff that's further work
some people don't want fenes some people
want you know IDL lines and they want to
see you know f2s f3s f4s before they
want to really you know dig too far into
a genetic pool and kind of do some pheno
hunting um ultimately it's people
dictate the market so if they keep
buying things that you know justify or
don't justify a price tag they're kind
of they're kind of creating the market
and legitimizing it
um so we'll see what people keep buying
and what people stop bu I
guess yeah no I I totally stand behind
all of that for sure I get what you're
saying no doubt so as a as one that's a
bit of a I'll give you some specifics
you know I've heard of situations where
some people get upset that someone else
has made the seeds on behalf of a
breeder so I'm not talking about white
labeling let's just say you come around
my place you bring around a bunch of
plants and you're like hey here's the
male I selected it out I want you to hit
all these femal with it and then you
know we'll have our agreement I'll give
you whatever and we're all happy with
that and then later on you know the the
person will be like well I did the
pollination you know it's it's not you
didn't this guy didn't actually make the
seeds I guess the question is in my mind
it seems reasonable to believe that like
if you select the male and drop off all
the plants you know you sort of made the
hybrid you just someone's just
facilitating that pollination to go down
do you think there's any difference
there between white labeling or do you
think that like it's more like what I
described where it's like the person who
does all the selection and comes up with
the plan like they're the one who's made
it even if they didn't physically
facilitate the pollen hitting the
female yeah I mean there's there's a
difference I mean the selection is the
whole art of the whole thing I mean as
long as you keep the plants healthy and
you know facilitate the pollen to the to
the female and and you know do the
basic the basic grow the basic flower of
it it's the rest of the work is done the
hardest the most difficult the most
challenging part is the selection of the
male and and the isolation of whatever
female you're going to use and and
lining up that you know it's kind of
like drawn out a map of what you think
is is going to happen and the other
person's just driving the car from point
A to point B you know
um it's definitely some different type
of white labeling it's definitely kind
of white labeling at the same time
though so I guess it's like one and the
same but different
H yeah I get you it's definitely a bit
of a a quagmire of like specifics isn't
it sort of you got to Wade your way
through it yeah
absolutely okay so I mean as a little
bit of a a change of pace um I would
love to ask you about testing and this
is an interesting topic because I truly
feel there's no wrong answer here and I
guess if you look at the Spectrum of
testing you know in the past there was
this expectation that absolutely
everything came very thoroughly tested
but as Times Gone by I've had many
guests on the show who Echo this
sentiment that if you were to do things
like the way we did it in the old school
days and you you know you're doing these
really vigorous testings on everything
you're sort of are not going to be able
to keep up with the market you know by
the time something's actually ready to
go to market because you've done your
all the testing the way people want you
know the Market's sort of moved on a
little bit and then you look at the
other end of the spectrum and you've got
guys like Masonic who I I really like
Masonic and um you know he says no I
don't test any of stuff and I'm very
upfront about that I will tell you this
pack is $50 cuz it's not tested but like
you know it's 50 bucks like H I guess
I'm wondering where do you stand on that
do you feel one side is more correct
than the other do you feel like it's
just a distribution and it's like just
as Masonic say it's just about being
honest it doesn't really matter where do
you sit on that one yeah I don't think
there's a right or wrong as long as
you're transparent about it I mean I
think if you know if he like you said
masic whatever uh if he's telling people
hey look these are not tested seeds buy
them at your own discretion they're
their 50 bucks or whatever and people
can wrap their head around like I'm just
going to spend 50 bucks and I'm going to
see what comes of it then you know that
that cool you know there's there's
nothing wrong with that if that's what
somebody the direction somebody wants to
do with their breeding project um I
think that some price tags when you
start to get more expensive certain
things are expected I think when you
start getting into the multi do price
tags I think that lines should be worked
I think that seeds should be somewhat
exclusive I believe they should be
tested I think that you know you should
know what you're getting if you're
spending $200 plus dollars
um and I think yeah if you're going to
offer some cheap stuff
and you know make it available to
anybody then you know just disclose that
you didn't do any testing on it and
that's cool too you know I think if you
I think if you try to sell seeds that
are crazy expensive and you don't test
you just kind of drop them and you don't
tell anybody I think that's di Mo and on
the topic of testing you know what sort
of a protocol if any do you have for
figuring out if you like a strain you
know in the past we had bod on and he
was like when I make a new strain I I
just popped 10 seeds like I try to
emulate the average consumer experience
and if I don't find anything nice then I
think maybe I shouldn't release this one
you know I don't want someone to have
that experience what's your thoughts is
there a certain number of seeds you like
to go through or is it a bit more like
what bod said what do you do so with
some of the past lines I've made so many
crosses and sometimes space is
restricted um it depends on how what I'm
trying to release what you know what my
goal is if I if I got 10 different
genetics I'm trying to drop um then I'll
do something like you know a 10 or a 12
seed or something like that something
that you know the average consumer would
purchase a pack and and pop a pack and
see what comes of it um sometimes you're
not allowing yourself to see the full
expression so if I can pop more I'll pop
more but I like the I like the B
approach I think that's cool man I like
you know you're emulating what uh what
the people getting the seeds are going
to kind of see and I think if you have
four to six good females that you're
kind of looking at and there's no issues
with those then I think you should be
all right sometimes it is cool though to
see a bigger pool and and kind of get an
idea of kind of more rare things that'll
pop up some people want to see that they
say you know what's the what's the most
common you know feno that you're seeing
or or did you see any that kind of stood
out and you know some people want a
little bit more um information but yeah
I think his approach is cool man I like
that yeah yeah brilliant I like that too
so I'd love to ask you I haven't asked
you already what style of growing do you
utilize um so we do a lot of mix
Spectrum
we do we've been doing a lot of LED type
stuff lately um I use a lot of
screens
um I used to do everything handw watered
um soil I switched over to
Cocoa
um I use irrigation systems now because
I have too many plants to tend to and
take care of to kind of hand water and
do everything on my own um when I'm
doing testing I like to not pop plants
I like to just kind of stake them and
and kind of see what they do naturally
on their own um kind of see what kind of
natural structures come out of them and
stuff like that um when I'm doing more
of a grow for flower yields um I like my
cyes to be even and I'll top them and
kind of get a nice SC kind of thing
going
yeah yeah beautiful and do you have a
preferred medium or preferred nutrient
Source anything like that uh yeah like I
I've been sticking to Cocoa lately
because I had so many batches of of soil
that were
just
contaminated you know a lot of these
supply stores out here will just like
kind of like leave all their soil
sitting outside and in the summer the
winter months or something and just
you'll get gnats or you know they'll
come with all this stuff so I've been
kind of like staying with like um
hpcc um
just kind of running cocoa mix you know
and I haven't had any issues with that
um switched over
to um couple different nutrient
companies
and
um I think once you're just dealing with
salts you're dealing with salts and um
Athena has been a product that I've been
utilizing over the past four or five
five months and yielding great results
um we do tpine profile testing and we do
lab testing and and we're actually
getting better numbers using Athena than
um the cocoa line that we were using
before um I use apus for a while apus
was good I liked apus um too many parts
and couldn't use it in irrigation system
so that kind
of forced my hand
um to steer away from that but when I
was handw watering I just did really
well um but yeah the the line's good
it's really clean great results um I
recommend it to anybody that's uh
looking for ease and solid
results love it nice and simple always
good to hear so I wanted to ask you
what's your advice for anyone who's in
the industry who might be a little bit J
ated with the state of things you know I
personally feel like there's never been
a better time to get involved in
cannabis but I do talk to a lot of guys
who were probably um pretty heavily
involved in the scene back in the 215
days you know back the sort of golden
years when you know pounds were 4K plus
sort of stuff uh what's your advice for
people who feel like it's all gone wrong
and you know they don't really see a
pathway
forward um I mean if you're around back
when pounds were you know I've been
around when pounds were 60 $400 you know
so I mean everything
changes um supply and demand higher
Supply demand probably hasn't gone down
if anything it's it's gone up but uh I
mean to to compare when you know you had
to actually go out and look for weed
compared to um driving down the street
and just buying it of course prices are
going to [ __ ] come down and fluctuate
but if your passion's in cannabis and
you believe that you can produce a good
product and unique product then I don't
see why anything should be dictated
otherwise then you just get involved and
just kind of like you know master your
craft and do the best you can um the
people always appreciate quality
regardless doesn't matter how much
demand or how much Supply there is
they're always going to seek the best
flow the unique flow or something else
that people don't have so I wouldn't let
the current state of the market
dictate whether you are going to be
involved in it or not it's you know let
the passion kind of steer you in the
right direction and figure out your path
and Blaze your own
trail yeah I like that that's awesome
we've got a few fan submitted questions
before we get to the the final five
quickfile ones and the first one I
wanted to ask you is can you tell us a
little bit about the
Hashburg sure uh great yielder
[Music]
um very Burger
es the GMO definitely dominated in that
um you have to like hashy
strains
and basically you have to be okay with
the GMO profile it's just it was so
dominant in that cross it was
just it was basically like running a
triple burger or a double burger it was
just it was just straight GMO most of
the time um so if that's your bag te
then yeah it's it's definitely for you
yeah perfect perfect and what strain
would you recommend for any listeners
who want to run some of your genetics
but they're thinking look I do produce
flour commercially you know not
necessarily in a facility but like you
know I I make my income from this so
strain does need to lend itself a bit to
that you know maybe a little better
yielding some good turfs maybe easier to
grow anything jumped to mind from your
range that might fit the bill for
someone who's Keen to run your stuff but
it just needs to be a little more
commercially viable yeah I mean it's the
cool thing about most almost every skunk
house strain is is it does yield and it
does have bag appeal and it does have
nose so any of the genetic lines that
I've developed um has a pheno in there
that is for a commercial grower or any
circumstance that you know somebody's
going to select you know any feno from
any pack um there's hash shielders
there's there's you know flower yielders
there's everything because it's it's
most of it has GMO spliced in it and it
just it'll just yield like a beast you
know so um the burger lines especially
so stick to those um the OG lines yield
very well but they don't yield as much
as the GMO lines the burger lines so I
would definitely say sticking to some of
the Donnie
crosses um even the modified banana
crosses yield super well and can you
know completely be viable in commercial
settings
um yeah I mean there's really not a bad
option I guess it just depends on what
kind of T profile you're looking for and
and there's something available in
almost every
other yeah that's beautiful to hear that
there's so many options and another fan
submitted question we got is
do we ever have any chance of seeing
maybe any s1's of your
Keepers absolutely um I want to do a
whole S1 line I just I've had a couple
projects that have just kind of Taken
front seat to it so um that's kind of
gotten bumped back I've done a bunch of
small S1 work just to see what is and
what isn't viable and I've gotten great
you know results they've yielded amazing
plants so there is going to be a bunch
of S1 stuff there's also going to be
clone drops uh breeder cut clone drops
that are going to be available here in
Michigan um for people that maybe don't
even want to um pop seed and they just
want um keeper genetics off the bat um
yeah I mean I I got a bunch of stuff in
the works I'm just trying to make you
know things possible for anybody in any
circumstance beautiful there's something
for everyone I like that I like that so
what are the plans for skunk house or
you know skunk Master Flex more
generally in the future have you got any
projects you're Keen to start or any
long-term
Visions yeah I mean right now we're
doing the uh Josh D collab one really
really really psyched on that um just as
a OG lover it's my favorite it's it's
the end lbl for me and to work with
somebody like Josh that's such an OG vet
you know helped kind of like just
catapult the OG and and bring it to to
the masses it's
just it's a it's a it's a dream collab
for me you know he's he's a great guy
really looking forward to that one um
there's a few other people that I'm in
the works of of negotiating collab work
with that I'm really really excited
about um if they go through um always
going to keep running and working on the
Larry line that's just a a a fan
favorite um the burger line are not
going anywhere there's always room to
expand on those and and bring in
different genetics to kind of outcross
and and work and see what comes of that
so lots lots in the works for skunk
house over the next couple of years not
planning on going anywhere
and G to keep things still with the same
idea concept I've always had which is
like only make across once the people
that actually get it like let them have
something that's really unique and let
them do their selections and kind of let
them have that you know um exclusivity
is very
important yeah I like that I like that a
lot so a question we love to ask all our
guests what are the rarest seeds in your
Vault or the seeds that you're most
excited to pop I do have
some original chmd GSC where the GMO
came from seeds laps um a small little
pile of them those are everybody's like
pop those pop those
um man I got some Northern Lights
crosses that I got from a a guy that
made some uh out of New York um Northern
Lights seven cross with like this I
Northern Light that he did um talking
about what we did earlier with the whole
bringing back old school stuff um those
have been kind of like burning a hole in
my
fridge um I have have some I have some
some AK seeds I don't know if they're
even viable anymore but original
packaging AK seeds from like 97 or
something um been just dying to pop
those um a bunch of older stuff man
that's just been sitting there that I'm
like I I like I'm afraid to pop it
because if they don't pop I'm just going
to be so devastated so I've just like
kept putting them off which is like the
dumbest thing I can do but yeah it's uh
the seed vault is just so extensive man
it's just I got to find time and
dedicate space to it
and it's just one of those things you
don't want to mess up because they're so
old and or you're not going to get them
again yeah totally totally I can relate
to that concerned with the seeds Okay so
on to our final five questions uh the
first one it's a a new one that we've
been doing recently if you had to
restart your seed company with just one
packet of your seed seeds presumably to
find a male but you know you might also
pick a a f pack and find a female and
want to go from there what pack would
you
pick uh this is seeds that I've released
or in my collection uh seeds that you've
made okay so I've never released them
but yeah I would probably just use the
Straight Larry uh backat Cross f8 or F9
or F10 and and start a line from that
it's you can pick them up and put 20 30
of them into water and just find gold
and work a whole line with it and it's
easy peasy like it's no no difficulty at
all in
it perfect perfect I love that so next
one is what's the single most memorable
or impactful experience you've had with
cannabis uh getting
arrested easily uh hands down um yeah uh
just realizing how fast like for
something that you love so much how it
can just mess your whole life up and how
stupid it is that it's that illegal and
um just it makes me realize all the
people that were before us and kind of
paved the way and it just it it really
levels me out and grounds me that um
people did so much for legalization and
and allowed us to be in the state that
we're in right now it's just that that
one act of just going through years
years of of Courts and all that stuff
just for just for something stupid like
having
flowers it's outrageous man but yeah
it's uh that's probably the most
impactful thing with cannabis that uh
that I've had to go through it's good
answer I don't think anyone can deny
that so uh next question would be what's
a strain that everyone around you was
hyping up you were really excited to try
it and then finally did and you were
like oh is that
it
um I would
say is this over like the whole duration
of just working with cannabis or just
recently yeah
ever okay
um that's a tough one because there's
been some really hyped up stuff that
I've really gotten a hold of and really
didn't H that is a tough question my
man um like from like things from like
just you know like
not to pick on purple punch because I
actually enjoy purple punch but like um
people were talking about how like
amazing it was and then you smoke it
you're like I I get it for flavor but it
just it doesn't have some kind of
wrecking devastating high and especially
coming off the era of like OG kushes and
chems where like you know these things
hit you're expecting this fruity
tropical bomb of just pure insane high
and not really quite getting there um
a lot of the gelato I've been kind of
disappointed with I didn't really think
they were that
great
um yeah it's hard to it's hard to
pinpoint one genetic I'm like kind of
dumbfounded right now I can't think of
one that I'm just been completely like
just in awe of how people even enjoy it
but
[Music]
um yeah one of these freaking designer
ones that have came out recently and
just I don't know there's a lot of like
boring turp I'd say any of the boring
Turf ones that just don't really do it
for you on the high or anything it's
just uh you know you expect more from
the people these days with all these
options they
have there you go there you go so next
one we have is we're going to drop you
off on a desert island presumably you
can grow three strains for the rest of
time what three are you going to take
with you uh OG Kush number one not any
specific one I'd say just an OG Kush the
original the Larry any of them any of
that category would work for me um a
chem either the chem4 or the chmd um and
possibly a Bubba Kush man probably the
original one um those are just like if I
could just as long as I have jars of
those in
like one of the three of those will
always do it for me um they're desert
island strain for sure um there's a
couple close competitors it's like maybe
the URL sometimes the Urkel can the 's
weird man it's like sometimes it can
almost be too
much like the realle is like
devastatingly crushingly high like it's
just it's strong and I don't know if I
want to go to bed all the time maybe
that one but um I could eliminate it
down to the number one in it just being
OG Kush that would be my my desert
island strain single desert island
stream yeah good pick good pick so we're
going to turn the tables now uh you're
going to drop someone else off on the
desert island someone you're not
particularly fond of what three strains
you going to leave them oh man uh Temple
Hayes from from bod so they just [ __ ]
wig out and have a terrible
time no no that would that would be
terrible some people I'm sure love that
[ __ ] and it's just not for me
um I'm not a green crack fan I'd give
him some green crack Green Crack never
did it for me um I'd give them the the
skunk the sweet skunk that's what I
would do to him that'd be a terrible
thing to do to somebody all the weed you
can smoke is just sweet skunk what a
terrible what a terrible terrible life
um yeah that's probably dude that
probably be sweet skunk or something
yeah I love it I love it okay our final
question for the interview today I've
got a time machine for you you can go
back anywhere to Any Time Any period
presumably to collect some seeds or
maybe even a cutting where you going to
go what are you going to
collect I'm gonna go
to like I'm gonna go to like Amsterdam
or like Europe and it's going to be like
the mid to later 90s and I'm going to
get like some old Sensi stock and it's
going to
be [ __ ] I don't even know I don't even
know what would be maybe some of their
earlier skunk work some of it I feel
like some of some of that stuff has just
been used whether it's been admitted or
not in so many crosses and so much of
the foundation of what we know is
cannabis now that it's like ridiculous
you know it was just such stabilized
work and just maybe if it wasn't the
most de devastating high it was
just it was such an important part for
cannabis genetically that it would
probably be something like that era
yeah that's a that's a good pick there
was some Killers around there for sure
so I think that just about brings us to
the end of it for this one today were
there any comments or shout outs you
wanted to
make uh yeah all my guys man uh shout
out to progrow my team H shout out to
shout out to Lance my homeboy helping me
uh do the skunk house thing uh Josh D
um all my friends here in Michigan um
just like amazing
cultivators shout out to uh Chris over
at ghostbudster farms he's really helped
me uh in the in the in the legal Market
kind of uh rub shoulders with people and
kind of put me in positions where um I'm
able to meet cool people um shout out to
you for having me on the uh the show man
um I had a great
time man you are too kind so you know
again a massive massive thank you the
head honcho of skunk house genetics
finder of the GMO creator of the Donny
Burger the double burger Mike Larry so
much more massive thank you to skunk
Master Flex for coming on the show today
thank you thank you any time man reach
[Music]
out and there you have it friends shout
out to skunk Master Flex for taking the
time to stop by
today and shout out to you for making it
to the end as always we want to give a
massive shout out to our sponsors if you
want to help support the show support
our sponsors CT now number one C Bank in
the industry you know them you love them
all the best breeders the hottest drops
guarantee on satisfaction not just
germination why delay guys I promise you
will be stoked if you get some seeds
from them they only stock the best in
the
game likewise a massive shout out to our
friends at Pulse sensors all the best
and latest sensors in the game including
their New Pulse Hub which integrates all
of their units together to ensure that
your operation is on point producing
bigger yields better turps higher
potency whether you're running a single
tent a single room or a multi-state
operation pulse are here to help you
guys get serious get a
pulse further shout out to coper the
number one leaders in Sustainable
biocontrol Solutions for pests and
disease if you're battling spidermites
please check out the spyx vital sachet I
can't tell you how annoying it is to
have to spread carrier material in your
garden just to get the Predators out
these new sachet circumvent that just
hang the sachet in your crop let the
personalist walk out do the work for you
trust me guys you won't look back if you
give it one go you will see the quality
you will be converted a massive shout
out to copit we appreciate your support
so much these guys are industry leaders
check them
out huge shout out to our friends at
Organics alive number one for powdered
organic fertilizers if you're thinking
about giving Organics a go get on board
their products make it so easy whether
you're in veg transition or Bloom
they've got products that make it easy
to dip your toes in the water likewise
if you're a seasoned veteran of Organics
I promise their products will help take
your next crop to a whole new level
massive shout out to Organics alive they
have some of the best products on the
market really fast release because
they're small particle size you will not
go wrong with Organics alive hit them up
massive shout out and thank
you finally a big shout out to our
friends at dap just a week or two ago
they came out with some new models the
titanium M Series in two different
colors you can get yourself the nebul or
the quantium I've been rocking the nebul
I love it guys please give it a go if
you've ever tried a vape and felt like
it didn't hit the way you were looking
for it these ones will truly a game
changer based out of the US owned in the
US dap truly one of the best Vaped
companies on the market I really really
love their product and we are super
appreciative of their support massive
shout out to
DAP last but not least massive shout out
to the patreon gang thank you so much
for your support if you want to help
ensure the show continues to happen
please consider checking out
patreon.com theep podcast you will get
early access to upcoming episodes
unheard exclusive interviews and you go
in the running to win a whole range of
Swag each month we give away genetics
cannabis artwork a whole range of
awesome products all while ensuring the
show continues to happen again a massive
shout out to the patreon gang we love
you so so so much thank you thank you
thank
you that's about it for this one my
friends I will catch you for the next
one thanks so much for hanging out heavy
days signing off from the upside down
Library I'll see
[Music]
you