hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast the cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts this episode as
always was brought to you by 420
Australia the premiere store for all
things lifestyle in a powder organic
garden sessions for organic gardening
needs as well as aficionado seeds and
freeborn selections be on the lookout
for the newest lines from both in this
episode we're lucky enough to have main
gene from Mendocino on the show chat all
things breeding strain history and
service plans for the future let's get
into it
all righty so a big big big thank you to
the man behind all the badass genetics
you seen it aficionado Mean Gene of
Mendocino thanks so much for taking the
time to sit down and talk with us today
yeah thank you for having me on that no
problem so first question I like ask all
breeders is what was your first
experience with cannabis well I mean
there's different there there's layers
to that one my first experience with
cannabis and memory was actually being a
really little kid and and seeing seeing
cannabis growing at my house you know
when I was like 2 years old or something
and uh I remember like 1982 or something
my mom getting arrested for it the
roommate had a had her roommate had an
argument with the landlord or something
the landlord called called the cops and
yeah there's six plants on the back
porch or something like that you know
but as far as smoking I'd say I was
probably about I don't know I was a kid
man I was probably like eight years old
and I had a buddy who always you know he
had older brothers and they always had a
lot of weed and um whatever they were
totally house is for a crazy contraband
of all types
oh and I I remember you know them being
around and being like you know smoked
the joint smoked the joint was staying
the night at my friend's house and you
know I took a couple hits off the joint
and I didn't feel anything nothing
happened
and you know I probably didn't really it
probably didn't go past my mouth and I
was like you know okay cool well this
was nothing all right then I stayed away
from it and then you know a couple a few
years later I I smoked and I actually
felt it and I thought okay this is what
it was like
and then I think maybe I was 12 or 13
and I was with my buddy Jody and Jody
had this weed that he got from this dude
that lived in Napa and for whatever
reason that time I think it was probably
because of the way we smoked it we had
like this little
was like a little bottle with a little
down stem into it and a little tube that
came back up out of it like it was like
a miniature bong or a miniature chalice
you know and I remember I smoked that
with him and I remember telling him you
know this isn't wheat there's something
else in here you know that dude he gave
you he gave you weed that was laced and
you know those guys out Napa that I
don't know man they laced the weed and I
was so gone and I remember thinking oh
I'm gonna be in trouble my mom's gonna
show up and he's like dude it's like
1:30 in the afternoon and I'm like yeah
I know man but I'm so high I'm gonna be
in trouble and he goes to your malt what
time's your mom getting you I'm like I
don't know like 8:30 or 9:00 he goes
dude no wheats gonna get you high for
eight hours bro just have fun you know
and I just remember being like honestly
like probably like half blacked out
almost of being in and out of really
known what was going on I remember like
running around in circles by this pond
at the hog farm and just kind of like
falling down chasing him through the
through the water and the edge and just
like you know playing like kids do but
just high as a kite man and um that was
um that was the first time I remember
getting really like really going okay so
you can get this high awful wheat before
that it was like I thought I was getting
high but I realized that I was I was
just kind of you know dabble in and
tasted it and whatever so and what
strain do you think that was geez I
don't know man but I wish I had it now
because it was killer I mean I had
smoked a lot of weed before that before
that I had smoked Northern Lights I'd
smoked different like Afghani and
different crosses at different stuff
that was around you know like turn of
the 90s weed I probably that first time
I tried weed when I was probably like 88
didn't-didn't really just kind of smoked
it to not get made fun of you know and
then probably you know later on then
smoking like really killer weed but not
not smoking it so much but getting high
and then man I smoked that weed from
Napa and whatever that weed was it was
some major stuff because I imagine was
probably like hash plan or
something really potent um it just it
knocked me you know and I didn't get
that high again even smoking for maybe
another year or something and then then
I that was the first time that I smoked
a lot of Keef and that was the first my
first experience with a concentrated
smoke and and that really got me to but
strain wise man it'd be hard to it'd be
hard to say really what that would have
been but some bomb 1990 to whatever the
hell was there you know and nobody would
would really know back then you would
have just said oh this is this is either
this is either good leader bad weed you
know so yeah okay and so from that point
how did you then transition into growing
was it the type of thing where from
these experiences it was just implanted
in your mind like I've got to do this or
was it more of the type of thing where
everyone around you is doing it so you
even even might make a conscious
decision to start growing it just it was
just like oh I just started doing it
well that was going on and people who
were older than me of course everybody
in the area was kind of growing but at
my age when I first started growing it
was more like um you know I used to work
with the family and you know like when I
remember being a little kid and like
transplanting some pansies or like some
little flowers for the yard and um you
know like supposed to water the water
the trees in the front yard and half
acid and and then at a certain point
just being like oh I want to grow one of
those plants you know and they were like
alright well you you know here this
one's yours this is your baby plant go
ahead and you know put this stuff in the
dirt and stick this in and you're gonna
water it and if you take care of it you
know you can have it and I was like ten
years old it was a Northern Lights plant
and that was kind of that was kind of my
introduction to it and then I you know I
I don't remember growing any other
plants until maybe I was probably like
14 that was 94 and you know I got some
killer seeds and I planted them and I
grew them in in in a big garden and I
just had my my few little plants I had
like whatever 10
sir ate plants and you know that the
weed that came off of that was you know
that was like basically my second try
that without weed was as good as
anything I've ever grown or still grow
to this day it was just a really good
place to grow and that was down in
Sonoma County it was a really good place
to grow I had the knowledge that you
know you should use all nice organic
stuff kind of you know
minimal handling slow cure slow dry and
great genetics you know so it really
came out and that was um you know it I
think anybody who really ever tries it
the first time that they get some good
weed in their hands from trying it
they're gonna go oh god I got to do this
I want to do this some more I want to
learn more aspects of this you know yeah
with that doubt and so what was the
catalyst for your first breeding project
was it accidental was it intentional and
a question I haven't asked anyone so far
did you stop breeding because you were
particularly inspired by someone or just
because you kind of wanted to just have
a crack at it I mean I'd say what
happened was probably that time like 94
I got some strains one of them
there was an Afghani called dirt that my
buddy had see money he had this um he
had this dirt plant and it was this
earthy Afghani so they called it dirt
and it came from a crew of people who
were big old-school growers back in the
day and this guy Randy brought it back
to the branch Kamaria which is in
Mendocino County he brought that back in
like 83 or 84 and so he gave me some
seeds that were across there was a dirt
cross big bud and dirt cross the thing
that they call purp out there and so
basically they were they were Afghani
crosses I had those I had some other
different stuff and then what happened I
think 95 or 96 my buddy said oh I took
that dirt purp and I crossed it with
Mark stuff from down the road you know
there's this guy named Mark he had
really killer Afghan ease we called his
stuff Mark's red because it always had
like more red hairs than than most
not not a not more abundant but that
they were at a more true red color and
so he told me hey you know I got the
this dirt purp cross marks red and he
gave me those seeds and he only gave me
a few maybe a six pack of seeds so I had
already had the dirt purp grown him
cloned them had a really good clone out
of the dirt purp at really good clones
out of the dirt big bud and so I said
well you know I wish I would have kept
the males when I cloned those plants
before you know a year or two ago so uh
97 I went ahead and I took those seeds
and I planted them in in one pot and I
let him grow up and they were just
little like knee-high plants and I let
him do a little open pollination and
then I got those seeds and then after
growing those you know I was I was
hooked because I started off with this
nice stuff and I wound up with a bunch
of seeds that were you know just as good
and a bigger number of them so I found
even better ones in there and you know
then the same then the first year that I
really got to grow those out in quantity
I think was probably two years later and
I grew out a bunch and I made a bunch
more seeds and I made it some different
out crosses and uh so that was kind of
you know really this really the start
and it wasn't the inspiration I would
say kind of came from those guys like
from from steve-o and c-money and these
guys who were who gave me the seeds and
I saw that Wow ok they gave me these
seeds and I got this and now I made
these seeds and I got this so it just
made sense to keep making seeds and try
to do selections and improve and
recombine and you know I had read High
Times since I was like 10 years old and
I saw the stuff from the cannabis cops
and you know people with seed companies
and it just all seemed really cool you
know to be able to like make your own
types of weed and keep around good ones
that were that your liked you know got
more seeds yeah so I mean just fast
forwarding to
20:15 for a moment when you got your
first first place with cherry lime at
the Emerald cup what was that like you
know to go from the guy reading the
magazines to now being the guy in the
magazines taking the first base type
thing well it was a trip it was kind of
surreal you know like um you think okay
was like all right I 2000-2006 my buddy
enters a plant that I gave him and he
wins second place of the Emerald cup
2007 I go okay well I got more stuff
from those same lines I'm gonna grow
some and enter it and see if I can do
okay the next year there's almost twice
as many entries and I still did 6th
place and I saw I was pretty excited
about that and then then that was 2007
and so then you know the next year hit
and in in autumn that year one of my
really good friends passed away and it
set me back like I was like not in the
mine state of going okay well I'm gonna
go ahead and and get this get these
entries together and do this stuff and
so I just kind of stopped doing it and
then 2000 2012 I went up and I entered
some stuff and I kind of my entries
weren't entered right I entered big
chunks of weed they had to pop them
apart for the judges so the judges
didn't get to see my trim job or
anything I might have done good all
right you know I might have still not
placed but I didn't do anything that
year so then the next year I go up I
kind of have some more idea like okay
the judges only get two grams only on or
two grand pleat pieces or they're gonna
pop your stuff apart they want to trim
really really tight which i think
usually makes really pretty we'd kind of
featureless so I don't usually I like to
show the features a little bit so I
realized okay well they don't care about
that they're just gonna take it crunch
it up and they're not gonna pull out
leaves or stems they're just gonna
crunch it up and smoke it so I better
make it like as close to a good you know
ready for smoking as possible and so you
know I improved it in that way and then
I took third and then the next year I
entered again I took second and then you
know when I won I took first so it was
kind of
weird to me because it was like I read
it at third I did second and went well
it would be you know it's not realistic
to think I'm gonna do third second and
that first so when I won first I just
kind of low is like okay and I mean you
can look at the video and look it up and
you can see when I'm up there I'm like
hey okay I just I just won the Emerald
cup so all right I didn't even know what
to do really it was it was a weird
surreal thing and I remember it didn't
really soak in until you know that night
we went and we went to this pizza spot
in Santa Rosa and we order food and
we're eating the food and I'm like hey
guys this is a victory dinner right here
you know we just won the cup right here
you know sitting with my family and uh
you know we all kind of laughed and and
I was you know I was we were we the
Emerald cup was Saturday and Sunday and
Monday morning we were gone on vacation
the first family vacation I took my
family on so uh you know the whole thing
was just kind of this crazy like hey
that happened and you know you kind of
expected to have like an impact when it
happens like hey you just won and it
kinda it was like I want and I grabbed
my cup and I didn't really even realize
that I had won until dinner sitting
there you know so it was a trip and it
was it was really trippy because
honestly up until like 2013 I really
didn't know you know I had never been to
any other Cup except the Emerald cup
which was kind of a was kind of a little
local thing and I've never been to a
High Times cup I'd never met any other
people who who were like breeders who
were on the scene I know a lot of people
over the years who always made their own
seeds and and worked lines and stuff but
I didn't know anybody with a company I
didn't I had never seen any of that
whole scene that was going on I didn't
know about the forums I didn't know
people were on Facebook and Instagram
posting weed I don't even really know
Instagram on Instagram was just some
place people put up pictures of their
food and stuff you know and then a
that I will you know once once I kind of
started seeing it when I went on social
media totally changed so to all the
sudden go from being completely in the
dark and not know any of this stuff is
going on and then all of a sudden be
like hey I just won like one of the big
contests you know it really it blew me
away was a trip man it was a trippy
experience for sure yeah with that dad
and certainly deserving if we just take
a bit of a wine back for a moment how
did you make that progression from you
know you said you were making your own
seeds you had friends doing really well
with them how did you progress from that
point to being you know the head breeder
at aficionado seeds well you know what
happened was uh I got I got a hold of I
got a hold of Leo and Ali and they were
the people who built aficionado and I
said hey you know I want to get some
seeds from you and there was this party
going on at this place up here called
the peg house and the peg house is like
a cool place you know like really cool
vibes up there and I'm like hey if you
guys are going and they're like actually
we were gonna go and I go hey cool cool
cool incidents so you know I'll meet you
guys up there and I'll you know I'll
smoke you guys out and stuff so I
brought up some cherry limeade and they
saw the cherry limeade and they're like
dude did you enter this last year cuz
they had won that year you know and I
was like no I actually haven't seen it
till now this was it was a 4/20 party so
it you know 4/20 and um I I go no I just
I just went and took this out this was
hanging up in the drying room I haven't
try even tried it yet you know and they
go dude they go if you would have
entered this you would have blown us out
of the water and I was like oh you guys
think so I go I entered the mother of it
but it's not that potent and this one is
crossed with the black lime so it might
have some potency to it and you know so
we smoked it and they were like dude
that's that's like that's the baddest
weed there is like we never seen nothing
like this before
and I was like okay well damn maybe you
know maybe I'll enter because I had kind
of come I had honestly gone like oh you
know I'm not gonna bother I don't know
I'm not just gonna give people weed for
him to tell me that it's good I already
know the weeds good I'm not into this
whole contest thing and so when they
said though that it was that much better
than the winner I was like whoa all
right well I'll enter this next year and
that you know so next year I entered it
and I got that's when I took third place
with it and so basically you know I
showed him different stuff I was working
with and I saw different stuff they were
working with and they were like hey you
know do you wanna um do you want to do
some projects together because you know
they they they lived like four houses
away from me at that point and so I was
like yeah you know I go I go you know
let you know show me some more stuff
they go you know and so Leo drops by one
day and he goes hey this is the rest of
the winner that won the the Emerald cup
and I looked at it and I went wow dude
that's crazy cuz that looks a lot like
what I call lime one that's my favorite
black lime clone that I keep around
that's a pique cross black lime and I go
you know we should do that cross and so
he goes I go you know do you have a male
of that that's that's proven that you
like and he goes yeah I got the pollen
right now coming out of the tent I go oh
cool let's let's go ahead and do that
bring it by and I'll make it I got stuff
going into flower pretty soon you know
and so I went ahead and I did the lime
one crossed with um with the chem that
he had and that's what black lime
reserve is you know and so I did that
one and I were I did a couple more
crosses with them and um that's just you
know that just kind of that just kind of
worked out to be that stuff you know and
so it was just kind of it was kind of a
trippy just just a weird luck kinda you
know like hey I want some of your seeds
and they're like hey you know your seeds
are your seeds are really good you want
to you want to do some stuff and that's
you know that's how it happened just
real organically like that yeah it
certainly sounds like some of the best
collaborations do happen on that
Organic side of things the question I'm
interested in is a lot of breeders or
you know companies will generally
describe their work as a certain style
you know like maybe someone would say I
tend to do like one parent will be old
school one will be new school you know
like kind of the merging of the flavors
or someone else might be like I just do
to new school things how would you
describe a fish in a day's work do you
think it follows a general style or not
particularly well I mean you know it's
it's the positioning on aficionado is
basically like all right this is this is
the best stuff there is this is the
stuff that you know growers who are
experienced want to grow this to get
stuff that's basically the highest end
product you know not necessarily you
know there's some people who are like oh
these are the monster this grows the
monster stuff every plant is gonna be
huge and heavy or this grows ladder
aficionado I'd say it's really aimed at
being something that's quality so that
you can say okay this is this is craft
cannabis this is boutique quality
cannabis and you know I'd say really
that that is the style that it's that
it's kind of shooting towards and then
also with like a little bit of added
Heritage stuff so that's why I'm leo
works with a lot of stuff like from
Mandelbrot because Mandelbrot at this
point is is kind of like a more of an
old-school staple breeder like you know
like royal cush is something that people
who are from around here they're like oh
yeah I've been buying royal for you I've
had oil for years I've been growing that
stuff for years now like a lot of the
old school growers I know if converted
over to old stuff like that and so you
know by kind of infusing that going okay
well here's something a Mandelbrot's but
then it's crossed with something that's
more new you know it's vents more like
it's not I wouldn't say Mandelbrot's
like a real old-school old-school
breeder but time flies so fast to the
point now where royal cush is kind of
like an old-school Emerald triangle
staple strain and you know like some of
the some of the chemists a few know it's
like yeah it's been around for a while
but I mean that's kind of the whole the
whole aim of aficionado I think is kind
of to say okay here's stuff that's
really high-end here's the stuff that's
really good in your joint in your bag
and it has you know some history to it
so you know like um I'd say that's kinda
that's kind of the thing and then
there's you know for me like as a
breeder personally like my whole thing
really has always been okay I want a
better plan like I want to grow I you
know I've honestly over the years I've
kind of slipped from being a proper
preservationist in that I tried to
always go okay what's the bet what's the
best possible thing so I had like some
Afghan EES they're too short they get
mold too easy then I cross them with
this I cross them with that now I have
the strain and now I don't even have
that Afghani anymore in some cases so um
for me it's all like improvement and
trying to have a plant that I really
want to grow and that when I show it to
people who are other growers who I who I
know they really want to grow that you
know so you know that's like the basis
of my work pretty much yeah okay and so
I mean if we just touched on one of the
points you made that heirloom slash land
race type stuff does pop up reasonably
frequently in aficionados you know the
line in general the thing which jumped
to mind to me is how do you resource
these types of genetics like they're not
there is certainly not easy type of
stuff to source like you know like I'll
and Afghani stuff like that I have to
imagine that would be some of the
hardest type of stuff to try to acquire
right yeah like I mean as far as like um
as far as like Highland Afghani that's
like that's something that Mandelbrot
God I think from Salmon Creek around
2003 or something like that I don't know
the exact story on that but um you know
a lot of like a lot of what efficient
auto stuff is is like stuff that comes
from Mandelbrot or that comes from
Shiloh where that comes from me like
guys who have been here
for a long time we're like the the
family vault purple that comes from a
guy named Larry who actually passed this
year he was a great dude
hippy Larry our crazy Larry and so you
know it's just a matter of people who
have these things and who have kept them
because they like stuff enough to not
just just switch over to commercial
mainstream clones I mean you kind of
have you kind of have of course there's
a million kinds of growers but you have
kind of two major subgroups in this area
you have people who either grow all
diesel and blue dream and they bust out
units and they make money or you have
people like there's people like me who
take a big hit on on money because it's
like okay I want to grow everything from
seed like the last time I grew a clone
in my garden to actually grow weed from
it and not just to seed it for fun um
was probably ten years ago you know and
in between then and way back before that
there's probably only maybe one or two
seasons where I ever really you know
produced clones to Hass say okay I have
I have this weed and it's all comes from
this one clone like I I sacrifice you
know basically like ease of manufacture
I don't just go okay I'm gonna grow all
this so somebody wants all oh gee I got
all oh gee I'm like no I got a plan of
this I got a plan of that I got a plan
of this you know they're all different
because they're from seed and and even
if your stuff is is completely
consistent as far as like you know like
if you have like you know quote unquote
IBL stock it's like - you know you're
still people are still probably not
gonna take those plants and mix them in
the bag and if they do people might go
yeah I don't know you know I smoked one
joint out of that bag and it looked the
same as this other joint but the one
joint got me a little higher one joint
was a little tastier there there's still
these fine variations anytime you come
from seed it doesn't ever get to the
point where it's a hundred percent
consistent so you know people don't like
that
commercial stuff so the the main thing
is with sourcing genetics is you have to
track down the other set of people like
me who actually want to grow from seeds
so they still have seeds because most
people are like I don't need seeds dude
I just go buy OG clones I just go buy
cookies clones whatever is the flavor of
the week I'm gonna go buy that and I'm
gonna bust it out and and kill it and
that's all I want I don't want to mess
around with having a bunch of different
stuff you know but um if you really have
a love for like different genetics and
stuff then that's when you're gonna be
one of those people who says no I
actually have I have stuff like I have
strains I have old seed strains and and
they're they are unique because they um
they were bred by people who were
isolated for a long time so you know
that's how I have stuff and that's
that's where that's where that all that
kind of special stuff comes from when
people have it and then you know then
there's people who preserve things
through cloning which is awesome - you
know also really important but um but
it's definitely not quite as good as
having you know open pollinated
population of plants that come from that
gene pool instead of just one select
clone that's been around you know yeah
for sure and so you kind of almost
hinted at this idea I've been interested
in a while do you think there's any
value or maybe a better way to phrase it
is would you ever consider doing a
breeding cycle whereby the mother and
the father were from the same stock each
cycle but you know like you would you
were doing it from seed every time so
that each batch was kind of a little bit
unique within its own right well you
know that's really interesting that you
said that because I kind of have a
concept that I'm working on and I want
to see how well it flies that's how
people have grown weed for thousands of
years at the very least you know and a
lot of these like these people say oh
there's all this improvement and it's
yeah there's there's improvement but I'm
sure there's been points in history when
people had you know reached a point that
was similar to this or in certain areas
people have a
particular type that's a sir you know up
to the standards of today because you
know the way genetics work is those
traits have to exist in the original
stock in order to be able to lock them
down so maybe the old seeds weren't as
consistent but they still had all the
stuff we love in them today like people
are crazy over cookies and when I smell
cookies it's I'm like oh this is like a
hindu kush and the resin is a little bit
more waxy as opposed to being a little
bit a lot of the hindu kush might have a
little more dry feel to the resin or you
know like all the things that are hot
today i see those traits and they just
look like old stuff i saw from hippies
weed from back when i was a kid and when
i was a teenager so for me i always grow
from seed that i make basically over the
years maybe it's not last year's seed
maybe it's seed from five or ten years
ago or whatever but i always grow seed
that way so and and i really like it so
i'm kind of interested in maybe starting
to put out seed in that way where i say
okay this is cherry limeade numbers 1
through 20 from 2017 these are the
keepers out of you know run a big
population and go okay here's the
females that i like the very best there
was ten of them there was 12 of them
whatever these are really stand out and
then be able to release the seeds and
say okay here's cherry limeade these are
the f5s that i made from this line from
this year and then it's like people get
a window into the way that people
actually used to grow weed and get seeds
because everyone's into clones now or
they're into getting a breeding that
came from cloned parents and i have
appreciation for like all of those
different ways to do stuff and they're
all really good tools but at the same
time it's trippy because I don't see any
companies who are putting out seeds that
are made the way that weed growers have
been growing for you know all of history
so it's when you said that it's trippy
because it's something that I've really
been playing with going okay yeah I'm
gonna
this is gonna be the 2000 batch one
through 10 of this strain and people who
get that they get it and if you don't
get it then you got to get the 2018 you
got to get the 2019 they're all a little
different but different lines will come
out that way and that way instead of
providing the public with a really
narrow snapshot of the genetics that are
in a gene pool they actually get access
to the whole gene pool in all these
different little ways so that somebody
can go oh yeah well I made knockoffs of
this strain but you know they it turns
out they're knockoffs or this cool new
novel thing that they wouldn't have got
if I just take lime number one and and
lime male number one and I just put out
seeds like that and that's it because
they're only gonna get this little
window into the gene pool that way you
know yeah sure and so I mean I'm just
thinking I think the loss breeder who I
can think of who actually did that was
Tommy Hill when he did like the deep
Chum that was kind of open pollination
wasn't it as far as I know tom hill when
he did deep chunk yeah he just did open
pollination with that and you know
that's one that had been bottle necked
so much that it's one of the more
consistent strains i've seen from seed
but even in that you know there's ones
that are really hard and chunky and
there's ones that are really leafy and
loose and there's ones that are green
there's ones that are purple there's
ones that are sweet and earthy and then
there's ones that have to really like
the magic coffee Hindukush smell where
like when you smoke it it smells like
magic from a mile away and those ones
are really rare in those breedings but
when I first saw deep chunk I think he
released that 2004 is deep chunk but in
like 2000 I saw it as monkey balls in
spy rock and in those earlier ones
before the release I smelled a little
bit more of that old like what I call
magic purple indica that's just this old
Afghani where when you burn it it smells
more like a like a really good true
old-school haze or it's got that spicy
incense II funky light just really
special stuff to it you know but I
I think those were when he did that was
just an open pollination and then he
probably I don't know if he mixed the
females or if he just took his favorite
female and it had mixed males and he
only released him from one female or he
took all the seeds from a bunch of
females and put those in packs I'm not
really sure you know what he did with us
yeah it's interesting because I mean a
lot of his lines are just open
pollination of stuff he's had earlier
have you ever dived into any of the
other lines I know that the you know
he's has often got a good route but the
ones I'm more interested in we're the
ones people seem to have been less known
about like x18 I'm really interested in
no one seems to really run it too much
or pine ties yeah another one like that
you know the pine tar cush we used to
see back in the day people used to get
it from his family you know I went to
school with some of his family and so
his stuff would pop up like when I was
in high school and they just called it
the pine and my buddy c-money remembers
it more clear than I do I don't really
remember it I just know that um it's
dank and and you know like he says it
was super good and um you know like for
me back in those days all the weed was
so good that it was just kind of like oh
this guy's got this and this guy's got
that not that much stuff really stands
out unless I was the one who grew it
kind of for me but um but he but the
x.18 is another one I haven't personally
seen but Aaron from DNA said that that
really blows the deep chunk out of the
water that it's just a way better plant
with way better weed and so that makes
it interesting to me because you know
deep chunks one of these ones with crazy
mixed reviews because it's such pure
stock that people really love that
aspect but at the same time most people
don't really like to smoke it because
they usually only get a few seeds and
then they started with a pack and they
made some so they didn't ever see like
the older when it was really the line
was really more opened up and
so they haven't seen those special like
there's there's ones in it that are more
like a master Kush or a Hindu kameen it
is Hindu Kush but it's more of that um
classic classic funk to it so why not
when someone tells me that X 18 is way
better you know and I mean Aaron sees a
ton of weed too so I figure you know
that the X 18 must be killer and then
there was one I had a buddy who I used
to work for and he had this stuff and I
was like dude what is this this stuff's
incredible and he was like oh you like
that one and I was like yeah dude what
could you not like it as it has buds as
big as my arm
they're basically black and silver
because the weed is so purple and the
resin is so silvery white on him
it smells like spray paint and ammonia
and skunk it was just amazing and you
know I was told that that was probably
the North Indian but then when I talked
to another buddy he said the North
Indians not really liked that it's not
quite so big then I saw Bodie run out a
little bit I only saw like maybe one
picture something it didn't really look
like what I saw so anyway Tom Hills dad
when I asked well what is this stuff you
know my buddy said oh this is this is
Tom Hill's dad stuff you know because um
you know Tom Hill was his buddy and he
had just given him a bunch of seeds and
said oh this is my dad's is my dad
strange you know and you know everything
that Tom Hill has as far as I know comes
from you know from his dad and and and
those guys that had worked with it over
the years in um in Mendo and so to me
that was the one that for me is one of
my holy grail strains and I still can't
really figure out 100% what it is it
might be the North Indian maybe if I can
finagle some seeds from bode at some
point and try some out I can see if I
see that one popping out and maybe lean
it back if it is it but I'm not really
I'm not really positive you know and
unfortunately to ask you know to ask
around to try to sort it back out I'm
sure Tom Hill would say my dad has lots
of strains and I'm sure my buddy would
go
no it's Tom Hills dad stuff it's just
the stuff chemist you know so that one
to me was incredible so if by any chance
someone ever tells you I have this stuff
from Tom Hill and it's gets these big
huge black and silver buds to smell like
skunk and spray paint pneumonia
definitely you know like if you got a
biome or you got a trade or you got a
fly somewhere together
don't worry get those suckers those
things are that that was a really really
incredible line and to me that was the
one that I saw from Tom hill
that was incredible I just don't know if
he ever released it I mean for all I
know it's x.18 you know what I mean
I just I've never seen x.18 I don't
remember the pine I don't remember the
pine tar cush really well I just
remember it was stony and it smelled a
lot like like a pine tree like cut and
pine you know and and that's that's all
I really know I have some I have some
haze that I got from from backyard
farmer at southfork seeds I have some
deep chunk cross Hayes F twos and those
probably have some really neat plants in
it my buddy at round table selections he
grew out some of them and he got some
incredible plants that looked really
neat like a deep chunk but very narrow
leaf which is kinda like the Achilles
heel of deep chunk it's cool to look at
but it lets in no light and it causes it
to really only get little buds on the
outside whereas the the monkey haze as
its called
it gets uh you know it lets the light in
so it gets these long butts they still
get the deep chunk color and you know so
for that's a neat one for sure yeah well
so many points you just hit on like I'm
a little total fanboy sorry I just I
need to clarify something quickly
he's the chemist Tom Hill's dad yes ha
ha all right cool I heard he might be
hanging out in Southeast Asia somewhere
still keeping on okay yeah I mean I
would imagine you know like I don't you
know I don't all I know is I was working
with my buddy and I said oh what is this
and he said that's Tom Mills that's Tom
Hill's dad stuff you
he's uh he's and at this point I didn't
I didn't know who Tom Hill was until
maybe two years ago or something
I just knew him as the guy who was my
who was my buddy's friend who came from
these killer seeds you know and and so I
said what is this and he said oh this is
Tom Hill's got stuff you know and he's
like he's like scientific with his
breeding you know he's like he's like a
scientist and I remembered it for years
as him being called scientist but it
turned out I was talking to so I was
talking to uh I was talking to backyard
farmer and he goes no no is his name's
chemist and I went that's right chemist
but that's what my buddy said he's like
these this guy's like a scientist with
his breeding he knows all the tricks he
knows all the ins and outs his strains
are true breeding and so that that's how
I know you know that's really who he is
and stuff yeah just as a little side
note quickly I've I've grown out
probably close to 40 deep chunk females
from this store I had probably falls
exactly into the category you describe
but only one of those was like kind of
as you described that that magic Hindu
thing and haven't been able to find it
since I didn't clone it it's neat though
when you get it right it's like coffee
and earth and a little bit of any
interesting oh yeah oh yeah it's
interesting because you know
quote-unquote indicas her you know
broadleafs they they kind of get lumped
into this category of being very kind of
bland on the high but I've had some over
the years I used to have this indica
called big blue which i think is a
different line from the same import as
the deep chunk because it's pretty much
the same plant and when I grow a big
population a deep chunk I get ones that
have the same form it's the one that's
like as hard as a rock and it has the
extra flavor and it gets the extra
purple on the leaves and down all down
all the way through the veins of the
Leafs where it's usually white it's it's
very like psychedelic and and laughy and
giggly and cerebral and you would never
think it from looking at this plant it's
the definition of a boring
broadleaf high when you look at the weed
but when you smoke it it lays people on
the ground with the gig loss per hour so
you know yeah well I give him some seeds
from a friend and all he told me was
that that was supposedly from an
unreleased Tom Hill line called the the
blue Afghani and so maybe okay
something to do with that I'm interested
I'll have to get him haven't ya you
haven't tried him ah no are they is with
are they large seeds yeah I think I got
about six or seven of them I'll have to
get them again today
yeah they look do they look like they're
they're they're they're big muscle-bound
look like a piece of rock and they're
really big or they little seeds they're
reasonably big but I know what you're
talking about I've seen the real real
big you know Afghani ones they know that
but they aren't small ones by any means
okay and that's interesting too because
um you know like I generalize like oh
that's what big blue seeds look like but
the deep chunk is well like Bodhi gave
me some of his deep chunk seeds that he
made I was stoked on that and I was
stoked in another way because they are
small seeds and all of the ones that I
do from my old stock that came from a
friend at Tom Hills before the release
they always have really really big seats
so that made me know okay well this
might be a little bit different of a leg
of that line you know so do you think
that the the size of the seed is
entirely dependent on the genetics or do
you think it also has some part to do
with when the pollination occurs in you
know the general timeframe of the plants
life cycle well I would say that when
you start with the pollination where
you're you're in very early flower and
you just have kind of the primordial of
the flower is there you just have those
first those first hairs are showing
you're gonna get fewer seeds they're
gonna be bigger they're gonna be
healthier they're gonna have a thicker
shell you'll probably have a higher
female ratio from them they'll take
longer to germinate but you'll get a
better germination ratio and they'll
store longer better but if you make if
you take the same strain and you seed it
a little bit later you'll get a lot more
seeds they'll still be fully viable and
the genetics will still all be of course
intact
good but you'll have smaller seeds with
thinner shells and so there's a
trade-off there like you know you're not
gonna get a lot of people producing
seeds for money who are gonna want to
see them really really early I like to
seed stuff when you can barely tell it's
flowering like just when it starts to
get enough to get so you know you're
gonna get some seeds and then I
basically get like you know really close
to a hundred percent just perfect
flawless seeds you never get the the
wonky ones you get a lot less twins you
get a lot more of the seeds are a lot
more symmetrical you know so there's
definitely something to be said for that
but you know you're never gonna make
you're never gonna take like you're
never gonna take sir these certain
strains like you know I'd like blue
dream for example you're never gonna
make seeds on a blue dream plant even if
you make it right when it first buds and
you juice the hell out of it it's in
full Sun it's the most happy plant ever
and you leave it until the buds almost
nearly dead and the seeds are as good as
could be they'll never get as big as a
well produced um deep chunk seed from
the or big blue you know like from these
really crazy afghan e's they they get
they just genetically they get these
really really big seeds but like bori
seeds are always great and these seeds
he gave me were beautiful and so that's
what makes me think that they're
genetically leaning a little bit to a
different side in the gene pool yeah for
sure yeah but there's definitely like a
correlation there certain you know like
a certain variety has a certain range of
seed size like some just can't get as
big as those suckers get huge you know
yeah man those things are like little
nuts yeah so if we just loop back to a
topic we were talking about a while ago
you were talking about how you know
broadly speaking there's two types of
growers in California the seed growers
or the clone growers so to speak it's
interesting because this idea seems to
be coming up more and more especially in
terms of how advantageous seeds can be
compared to clones specifically in the
outdoor setting you know the idea of
having the taproot you know that's
really advantageous the one major
argument I've had against this though is
that you know
not every seed is gonna yield a product
as good as what an elite clone would so
the question is do you feel that through
strict and high quality breeding you can
with a reasonable certainty offer a seed
that is going to produce on average
quite a high quality product yeah no
problem and I think a lot of it comes
down to taste so what happens is you
might have a gene pool that can
consistently do it can consistently
recreate these plants with potency with
yields with this with that a lot of
times it comes down to a slight
variation in anything makes people get
turned off to it based on taste so you
might have 10 female plants and you
clone them all and you have a bunch of
people who think the number three is the
greatest weed ever and then you have a
bunch of people who think that the
number nine is the greatest whatever and
then there's some people and and you
have somebody who loves every plant that
comes out of those seeds once they're
bred really well but there's certain
plants that are just more pleasing to
there they're like they're like pop you
know they're they're pop plants they're
like pop music you know or pop art it's
like this is what people people just
like these you can sell this weed at
Walmart you can sell this weed at
Tiffany's you know like it doesn't
matter who you are you're gonna like
this and of course there's always some
people who don't like it but generally
if people like strong weed they're gonna
think oh geez pretty good if they like
strong weed they're gonna think kam is
pretty good or if they like those more
indica kind of highs so I think like a
lot of it comes down to not so much are
the plants can you create plants that
are all quality but it's like then you
have to lock them down to be this
particular thing in which case you kind
of you're gonna kind of alienate the
people who might have liked the other
thing that you didn't lock down you know
so I do believe you can make a strain
where everything is really high quality
like I grow my my stuff that comes to my
black lab crosses and I don't ever
really get a plant from them that I go
yeah I don't like this one you know I I
like them all if people have never seen
something from the line that they're
attached to the first time they see any
given plant they go wow that's good
stuff I like that one but once they've
grown attached to one type then they'll
start to see some of the other ones ago
yeah I don't like that one but it's
because they like that because of the
one that they do like you know it kind
of turns them off to the other ones so
um you know I think a lot of it comes
down to just your taste what you like
and and then and then of course you know
bottlenecking out the stuff that just
nobody thinks is gonna be quality so
that's what I spent years doing is
trying to get rid of the stuff that
nobody's gonna like and try to keep in
the stuff that I know somebody's gonna
love even though I know you know you
can't please everybody with every single
plant so an idea I've been thinking
about a lot recently is do you think
it's possible to selectively breed for
either one trait like either breeding in
or out and I guess what I mean by this
is let's just say you had a clone or you
know a strain in general and you love
everything about it there's just one
trait specifically that's for example so
maybe you know resistance to insects so
you know something like that do you
think you can breed that out and breathe
it out in such a way that you only get
rid of that one trait or do you think
you're always going to lose some
peripheral aspects that will be related
to the genes involved in that tray and I
mean maybe more specifically if you
could actually do it do you think it
would just take a ridiculous number of
generations to achieve the goal I kind
of outlined or do you think you could do
it in a reasonable number of generations
you know it's interesting thing because
it's really like the perfect question
for like why would you want to hybridize
something because if you already have
something good why would you want to
screw it up by adding something else I
think like in the case you said of like
insect resistance
the further there's to bei there it's
like this if you have a gene pool and
this there's already plants in it that
are exactly what you want except they
are very insect resistant and you don't
have to go outside of the gene pool then
that's a case when line breeding without
adding any outside genetics is a great
tool so you can say okay well you know
when I grow five of these they all get
attacked by insects then that's a great
time to go okay well let's go ahead and
pop ten thousand seeds or five hundred
seeds or whatever you have room for and
then basically introduce that insect to
that population and see if there's one
that really shines and then if you can
get actually a whole variety of those
particular plants then hopefully you
find one that was insect resistant and
it also has the other traits that you
already liked about the strain which in
this hypothetical thing would be likely
because it was already a strain you
liked a lot but it just wasn't resistant
to bugs so in that case that's when you
really want to do selective breeding
within the gene pool and bottleneck out
all the plants so by taking that one
plant and you can back cross to it and
back cross to it and back cross to it
and because it's already consistent
strain back crossing to that plant is
really gonna dominate the gene pool with
itself and that's actually like a really
good time to in breed and that cross and
do all that stuff you wouldn't want to
throw out all the other stuff because
down the line you might realize hey wait
there's another trait we didn't know
because we had never seen this type of
wilt before or we've never seen this
type of mildew or blight or new strain
of insect or species of insects so you
still want to have the other ones you
know put in cold storage or whatever but
now you have this new line where you can
go okay sweet we're not getting eaten by
thrips every time like who's getting
eaten by thrips is obviously a terrible
plant so we got to go ahead and go for
this
part of the population preserves the
part that we really don't want right now
so that we know we have it in case we
need something from it later but now
we'll take this new direction where we
have this the other the other place
would be okay now while we grew out 500
or we grew out 10,000 and we didn't find
any plants that are not resistant to
insects which means that in the past
somebody's already bottlenecked these
traits into this population and they're
all gonna get attacked by insects no
matter what in that case you're gonna
have to borrow genetic material from a
different race of plants so you're gonna
have to say okay we're gonna go to this
land race over here or we're gonna go to
this this heirloom breed over here and
go okay look these ones they just and
you grow a big population and of course
it doesn't have to be that they all grow
like this but that's the best way to do
it is to find a breed where none of them
get attacked by insects and maybe if
you're lucky this plant already breeds
true for a lot of the traits you liked
about the other strains so that way
you're making less work for yourself so
let's say you have a strain that gets
attacked by insects it has a great smell
that you really love it gets you high
like you want the plant grows like you
want it to it finishes when you want it
to and the only drawback is that it gets
attacked by insects then maybe by some
luck you know you find another strain
that has all those same traits that you
really like and even the terpene
profiles are similar so it's similar
weed but you go well this one over here
it doesn't get attacked by insects in
any of the population the whole thing is
insect resistant so it obviously has it
breeds true for this particular trait in
this case which is insect resistance so
when you cross the two together you know
I mean if it's too if it's so close to
being perfect like I just said it was
then of course you'd probably just throw
away the first strain cuz you just found
a second strain that's already perfect
but there's gonna be
right yeah for sure but but I mean I'm
just saying that was I that was kind of
the ideal you would be looking for to
have a lot of traits that line up of
course they're not all gonna line up so
let's say strain a yields well but
strain B doesn't yield well but it
really has the insect resistance so you
go okay we do still need something from
the old strain that doesn't have the
insect resistance and it still is the
one that has the better buds with the
better resin and all this stuff to it so
okay so it's worthwhile so then in that
case you know you're gonna make that
hybrid now when you make the hybrid
you're gonna go through and you're gonna
look for all those traits you wanted but
you're gonna look for the plants that do
possess that in fact that borrowed trait
and now those are going to be the plants
that you're gonna breed to go forward
and you know it all really depends on
like you know the frequency that this
particular trait pops out in the in the
population like is it a one-in-ten is it
a 100 is it one in a thousand and if
it's already like the strains really
true for that it's gonna be pretty easy
to borrow that trait into the other one
because at the very least you're gonna
start off and you're gonna get a quarter
or a third or half or depending on how
dominant that strain is for that trait
so to answer your question in a simple
way which I never do I would say that
you know it's not it's not really that
hard it just you have to approach it in
that way where you go okay what is our
list of traits that we need for this
strain and then what is what what are we
looking to borrow from another strain
and does this string and does this other
strain really have it to donate and in
that case then yeah you'll make your new
hybrid you'll find your plants that fit
the description and as long as they fit
the description you take them you breed
them together try some different
combinations of parents and then you
know at a certain point you'll find one
that has all those traits that you want
I mean that's kind of just what you know
like I mean that's not what you do when
you're making
simple hybrids but when you're breeding
a strain that that really is something
that's going on you know like I do that
I do that what strains a lot yeah for
sure and I know that that type of
approach is used in many many men there
are many many many other fields of
agriculture around the world and it's
certainly effective yeah while we're on
the topic of you know kind of locking in
traits I remember having this discussion
with mr. Sol about back crossing and I
specifically was interested in why he
chose to use the Shiva's gonca model as
opposed to one of the brothers of you
know the princess and the genius in the
stock and he said to me well it was it
had good traits obviously the shape of a
skunk that he wanted but more
importantly it was really easy to see
those phenotypes when he was going
through each generation back crossing it
that kind of brought up an interesting
idea because I mean one would you guys
consider doing back crosses in
aficionado because a lot of the work is
more kind of f1e type stuff but the
other question is is that at the type of
approach you would take would you want
to use something that was really
different just such that it was you know
almost just doing the job of providing
the y-chromosome and then you could
easily weed out most of its traits or
would you look to use something which
was more similar as you just mentioned
but the the implication of that is maybe
it's a little harder to weed out exactly
what you don't want yeah I mean as far
as to be able to see something out right
I mean I used to always go okay you want
to use if you're gonna take say like
you're gonna take a G and you want to
make a G from seed let's find a male
that's already almost just like Oh G in
every way and then we'll do that and
then after a while I went yeah but I
can't see it once I did it in practice I
went I it's really hard to see what it
is so what I realized and I started the
project and I never did anything with it
dying breed and round table selections
and cheese I don't know probably a
couple other people did stuff with it
what I did was I took that I took the
deep chunk and I put it on the fire OG
and I gave that to the guy who
who gave me the deep chunk seeds
originally and he called it great balls
of fire
and so what's interesting is deep chunk
is a really trippy plant because it's
totally inbred and it is of course it's
its dominant in breedings for all these
traits like I would say in a lot of case
the dark color a lot of resin broad
leaves but one thing that it wasn't
dominant for in out crosses that I did
meaning that I guess it's probably a
double recessive trait in its gene pool
is that its height it's not dominant in
out crosses so what happens when you
make deep chunk cross something that
grows fast is you get basically deep
chunk plants but they're very fast
growing right so I haven't grown out a
large enough population of that but what
I really wanted to do with it was go
okay it's gonna be easy to see these
plants that are the ones that aren't the
broad leaves they're gonna be a lot more
likely to be the OG types and it's so
dominant for that trait that I think
I'll probably have to grow out a
thousand of them to be able to get a few
good plants to try combinations with
that have the narrow leaves and dying
breed took that and they actually
selected one that was a little bit more
narrow leaf and they put that back on
the fire road G again I haven't seen
that grown out yet but I'm curious about
it but that's an example of doing like
what what mr. Sol was talking about
where you use something that's really
obvious and then it's easy to take out
the problem with deep chunk or it's not
really a problem it's just that when I
do you know you plant 20 or 40 of them
you go hey we have a bunch of giant
sized deep chunk with a little bit more
THC coming from the og but you don't get
you don't get many that have any kind of
an OG smell or a No
you look to them and so it's kind of a
pain in the butt but it is um it's
definitely it's definitely a valuable
thing to do and I don't I don't see any
reason not to do back cross projects if
you have a plant that you really really
like you know I think it's a I think
it's good and I think that you know
doing something that pops right out at
you like that using a plant that is
different so that you can weed it out of
the population really easy I think
that's you know that I think that's
smart it's a sharp idea yeah and so you
just touched on this idea of you know
popping you said popping a thousand
seeds how many seeds do you like to pop
when you are gonna look through a line
for a mile for example and and a little
side question if you were to pop another
breeders seeds how many would you want
to pop to get an idea of whether you
could be like oh that's Bunco they do
good stuff
I'd say it's all dependent on the
genetics I don't think I think there's
some strains that the way they're bred
like if you're gonna pop something from
mr. Sol I don't think that you probably
need to plant more than a pack or two
because of the way he breeds he's
locking down traits he's using parents
that actually mesh and make the gene
combinations that he wants and he's um I
mean the dude he's a he's a nuclear
engineer or something I mean you know
he's not just gonna be jumping into and
doing stuff like that now that in
comparison to somebody who says hey I'm
gonna take this and throw it together
with this you know I mean deep chunk
cross og was one that was that takes big
numbers because of this interesting
interplay between the genetics where
deep chunk basically eclipses everything
it collides with there's nothing that
really can stand out like deep chunk
just throws a shadow on anything in the
genetics so you are gonna be able to get
ones out of it but it's gonna take you a
bigger population to find them because
there is really true dominance for a lot
of its traits that it has
but like I said height is not one of
those traits so then that kind of shows
you with my knowledge of genetics you
know like I'm no rocket scientist with
it but that that's probably a double
recessive because it breeds true in an
inbred population but it doesn't breed
true or it doesn't dominate anything
when you do out crosses with it at all
so you know there there's your two
examples of okay here we got you know
Cindy ninety-nine seeds or Cindy
ninety-nine FEM seeds like hey grow
three you're gonna get a good plant you
know grow rags grow ten grow 20 grow 30
you're gonna have a lot of cool stuff in
there and it's kind of gonna be that
because that's his goal as a breeder
then there's other people and there's
stuff that I make too I make stuff I try
to make stuff that is really really
consistent and I try to make stuff
that's really really wild because in
stuff that's consistent when you go
ahead and you plant a row of it it
behaves just how you want it to it does
everything that you you want it to do it
finishes when you want it to finish and
all this stuff but then if you want to
find something that's really gonna be
out of this world and it's completely
different than anything anyone's ever
seen you're not gonna get that out of
your true breeding seeds your true
breeding seeds only have what you've
seen from them because that's all they
do deep chunk does deep chunk you're not
gonna grow deep chunk and go whoa I grew
this deep chunk and now I got this crazy
you know just crazy plant with this
crazy terpene profile it's gonna be like
oh it's just a variation on deep chunk
it's pure Cindy 99 you're gonna get a
variation on Cindy 99 which is awesome
when you're looking for that and then
you know doing crazy crazy Polly hybrids
and stuff is really cool if you're just
looking for something that's really
weird like I got I got one called
Nubia that my buddy Braveheart found out
of some seeds and it's like one of the
only CBD plants that's that high in CBD
two-to-one ratio and it makes really
really good full melt hash and that's
not common with CBD plants and I
kind of attribute some of that to the
old genetics like the dirt purp in it
that has it has you know it's terpene
rich it has really nice resin that's
really it's really melty anyway but then
you know at the same time then it's this
crazy this crazy poly hybrid thing that
I did and then you get this plant that
you don't really see this in other
populations people grow out tons of CBD
and they're like it's great but you
can't make full mount Ashley it but
through doing some weirdo stuff you know
you get these weirdo things that you
realize are valuable once you actually
put him into practice as far as like for
to get somebody's seed to know if it's
good it just depends like I feel like
with breeding it's all about like
honesty like if you're gonna if it's
wild say it's wild if it's ultra
consistent say it's ultra consistent and
then that way when people go to select
what they want to get from you or what
they want to spend their time on to grow
they have an idea you know which ride
they're buying a ticket for because you
you don't want to try to grow you don't
want to try to grow something where you
want to get all good stuff that's all
the same and have it all be wild and
then some of them aren't even that great
but if someone tells you hey these seeds
are wild they're not all good but when
you find the best one in it you're gonna
have something that's incredible then
it's like cool now you know what you're
signing up for and so it's not so much
that maybe a better breeder is going to
have more consistent seeds it's that in
my opinion a better breeder is gonna
tell you what is what so that when you
get into it you know like okay do you
want to have you want to find this
purple one here that's got this really
special terpene profile it only pops out
maybe one in 20 so you're probably gonna
want to plant about 50 or 60 seeds just
so that you know you got more of a
likelihood because if it pops out one in
20 in a big population somebody could
buy one pack or two packs and get 20
seeds really easily and go well it
didn't come this
because you know it's not gonna hit but
do you want to know that when you buy
the seeds I don't want to get seeds from
somebody and have them go yeah they're
all this and then you plant them and you
go dude I didn't get any of that and
then if somebody tells you oh there's
all kinds of neat stuff in this and then
you plant it and you go dude I only got
one thing out of like 50 plants they're
all exactly the same either one of those
is gonna be a disappointment you know so
it's really up to long for you know
through the breeder to be ethical and
give you an idea of what you're getting
yourself into I think yeah it sounds
like good philosophy and so just on a
slightly different topic recently we've
seen the launch of your own new company
freeborn selections what what inspired
you to start this is it kind of a bit
like bodis companies where it's just
kind of like a different type of work he
wants to do and what type of things can
we expect from it well tell you what I
mean like I said you know I was 10 years
old looking at height I'm seeing people
at seed company is saying oh that'd be
cool you know to have a seed company and
breed and then I started breeding I got
all these different breeds you know and
um so you know like when I when I first
talked to Leo from afficionado you know
he said oh yeah you know you should you
should you should come on company and
well you know you can do this and do
that and I was like yeah man you know I
go uh you know I'm down to do stuff I
like to work with people and you know
that's it it's cool but you know I'm
still I'm not just gonna be you know I'm
not coming in to just be like part of
somebody else's thing you know I've been
doing this for you know I've been I've
been you know improving in creating
strains for 20 years I'm not just trying
to just sign on to somebody's stuff so I
basically I basically just thought well
I have all these things that I've made
efficient auto the way the marketing is
positioned is to say you know this is
basically the best weed you've ever seen
the best seeds you've ever seen and you
know I feel like when we add black lime
reserve I was like I feel like this is a
game-changer I gave them to people I
gave a lot of lime stuff over the years
to
a lot of different people and I always
ask them you know is this business
blowing stuff away is this what you want
to grow now or are you just gonna retire
it you tried it you don't want to do it
and everyone who I gave it to always
said this is something that I really
wanna that I really want to go with so
that's like something that I felt like
was appropriate to release and say hey
this is this is good you know this is
like the best stuff anything that I do
of course I'm gonna think it's great but
I have to know that okay it's kind of
match with the market it's gonna it's
gonna it's gonna be really big good
yields it's gonna be great for this
gonna be great for that kind of you know
check all the boxes and so I was
comfortable to do that but honestly like
to say okay I'm just gonna make seeds
always to be released as being you know
the greatest thing around and maybe they
don't really you know there there's not
really anything that different you know
I'm not gonna sit here and tell you I'm
a better breeder than then mr. Sol or
bode or inspector or Fletch or any of
these guys I'm not you know what I mean
like I'm not gonna sit here and tell you
that I'm that I'm you know mr. awesome
so it's hard for me to to position stuff
that way so for me I'm like okay I just
wanted to do a company where I could say
I'm gonna um I'm gonna make this stuff
it's stuff that I think is great I think
it brings a lot to the table and people
will enjoy it and and so that's why I'm
really you know making the push on doing
on doing my own stuff because any time
when you're when you're working with
people you know your visions have to
meet and if your visions aren't meeting
up then you know it's not it's not
really conducive to to success in that
in that way so you know freeborn
selections is just like you know my
middle name is Freeborn you know these
are my selections and you know like you
see like on my thing it's like oh it's a
company you know it's it's a new company
it's a wise it's a since 1997 because
you know freeborn's been selecting since
nineteen
97 that's what the work is so that's
basically you know that's that's the
whole thing of of it is just going okay
this is a place where I can put my work
I don't have to worry about meeting any
kind of standard beyond what I say it is
if I say it's wild its wild if I say
it's unstable its unstable if I say it's
if I say it's the best strain I've ever
seen it's the best training I've ever
seen I can just do whatever I want it
doesn't all have to fit into the heading
of going okay this is the best you ever
seen because that's that's a lot of
pressure and that's hard to UM that's
hard to deliver on you know yeah sure
and so just as a bit of a personal
curiosity even though cherry-lime took
first place and black wine didn't which
one do you think is actually the most
and out of there to you know black lime
is really trippy it's one of these ones
like I know a guy who used to get all
the weed from from you know the main
diesel guys on the East Coast the chem
guys and you know he'd buy their weed
for you know huge amounts of money stuff
that's just ridiculous like people don't
believe people pay this much for for
weed and he used to come over here and
get black line before I crossed it with
OG and you know I I didn't ever know
until I was talking to him last year in
here two years ago and he goes ah you're
the black lime guy I go yeah I go you
like that and he go and he told me the
story goes man that was the best weed
that I ever got was black line and he
goes I used to get the super skunk I
used to get the diesel likes to get the
camp you know I've seen all the oh geez
he goes the black line he goes I was my
stuff dude like that was like I could
kill it on that back in those days I was
like wow I didn't even know back then I
didn't you know like you're very
isolated when you're in the um you know
in the woods for one you're very
isolated but beyond that when you're not
you know you're not really tied in I was
never one of these guys who flew to
Amsterdam or did any of the stuff so you
know um anyway you know the my point
being that for me black lime is like
it's like
best week there is and I crossed it with
with the PK the og back in the day not
because I wanted to make any
improvements but because I took the og
and I hit it with every male I had at
the time trying to get oh gee seeds
because nobody wanted to grow my seeds
all of a sudden they were talking about
oh we want to we want to buy only OG
because we can sell this you know we can
sell this in LA for $8,000 a pound and
all the rest of the stuff we can't so
you know black lime for me was really
like that the heavy it was heavy hitting
it had all the flavors had fuel had
fruit I I've been looking for years for
something that was like lime because my
buddy who was from that crew who
originally gave some of my friends some
of the original seeds that I got they
they had a thing called lime and I was
always like I want to find this lime I
want to fly wanna breed a strain that's
lime like a lime popsicle you know and
so once I finally did it it was just to
me I was like here's the ultimate cherry
if I have cherry limeade and I have
black lime and I have a baguette each
say ah the ounce of each and I'm smoking
heavy I'm gonna probably smoke the black
lime like ten to one and the cherry
limeade is incredible it just it's not
it doesn't resonate with me as well and
I think that overall the cherry limeade
is more of a crowd-pleaser it's purple
but it's stony like OG it has an
incredible amount of terpenes when you
smoke it and I literally taste sweet in
your mouth not just like it not just
like a sweet smell but it actually on
your tongue is kind of like sweet like
sugary and it's just really really good
weed it's really resistant but black
lime for me is just like black limes the
king of the jungle for me and then and
then my other one that I call root beer
which is a which is a headband with some
you know some old Afghan ease in Hindu
it
that's super that's super dank - those
are the two for me cherry limeade is
totally like a backburner strain for me
a smoke but if I want to really impress
somebody with a bud you know I know that
in unless people have a relationship
with uh like a history of smoking those
other things like me I know that when
they smoke the cherry limeade that knee
jerk is gonna be like oh that's the best
that one's the best but if somebody has
a lot of them for a long time you know
it's um the lime for sure the lime is
killer yeah that's really interesting
because I was listening to you on the
cannabis connection talk about the
creation of the cherry line and
interestingly enough he's I think you
said that the mother was a cherry pie s1
and yeah yeah and what I find
interesting about this is we're seeing
this happen more and more you know
people are breeding with s ones as
mothers I've even seen people breeding
with an s2 as a mother how do you feel
about this do you feel like you know
it's fine to do as long as you do the
necessary testing on the progeny or like
what's your feelings on this well here's
an interesting thing you know I mean
some strains they have exceptional
stress causes them to seed themselves
and the the progeny from those breedings
will it'll take an exceptional amount of
stress to make them seed themselves
something like cherry pie does it take
any stress at all just seeds itself
right unless you're like some kind of
phenomenal space grower I don't know
everybody who I know is like dude you
grow cherry pie you're gonna be picking
off some balls off the bottom of the
plant before you flour it out it's about
day 21 today 25 or something day 30 and
it's just gonna start getting these
little balls at the bottom of the plant
so if I would have used that as a mother
and hit it with the lime and released
cherry lime seeds it would have been a
disaster like I would have never done
that so even at this point I'm still you
know I'm still having people Testament
or I'm growing them outdoor on that s4
with a few different directions and
they're all very stable outdoor they're
even stable indoor for really good
growers which is better than Cherry Pie
but they're not they're not stable
indoor in every it's not every line is
good like the number seven line is you
know one out of five my buddy my buddy
Jasper had to do before he got a good
one the number eight quality over
quantity love them and he had no
problems whatsoever and the number eight
there's also Kevin Joe jury has a
cut-off of that that you know I guess
does really well no matter what so you
know it's a matter of okay what kind of
an S one is it and then in that case you
know like here's the deal if you take
the wrong road and you get to s five
where you get to s ten or you get to s
twenty you're gonna have plants that are
so herm that you won't even know there's
females in there they're just gonna all
be producing pollen like mad if you take
the right turn you're gonna get plants
where you're like dude I watered it with
all this stuff I used like everything
they use to make feminized seeds and I
can't get these suckers to reverse just
depends on which road you take so you
have to take it in the right direction
so honestly think that there's a big
lack of people making s1 seeds and the
reason I say that is because people lose
clones so like my buddy right now has
this skunk six it's this incredible
plant and everybody wants it and nobody
has it and he has it and he's almost
lost it and it's my opinion not that
these seeds need to be distributed
necessarily but that they do need to be
made like I told him I'm off dude get
some of those cuts up there to inspect
and have them s won those out so you got
the seeds to put in the fridge because
um you know as long as you test out a
stress test
Zess ones you're gonna find s ones that
are more stable than the mother they
came from and you're gonna find some
better less so that's the nature of
genetics is that you always get
something that's more so and one that's
less so you get like you know a more
resinous plant and you get a less
resinous plant you get a more purple
plant and you get a less purple plant
you get a taller one you get a shorter
one so you get all these combinations of
whatever is in the gene pool of the
plant you know and I really think that
that selfing stuff is neat I had this
Northern Lights back in the day the one
we got an 89 from seeds and it was
incredible and it still did this day's
one of my favorite plants I underrated
it for years because it was a little
plane on the Terp side although the
flavor was incredible I just kind of
didn't I don't know I was a little bit
infatuated with smells that were a
little more crazy so I didn't really
realize how amazing of just like a hash
plant this thing was and it used to in
cases where like the generators would
die for you know a couple days before
they could get back up and running or it
would get heat stressed or whatever
these different issues are it would seed
itself and these seeds we always want oh
they're hermie seeds and we always threw
them away
and every year there would be one or two
that would be in the compost pile it
would come up and we go oh it's a girl
let's go ahead and grow it give it a
shot and they'd always be perfect and
you know we just thought just throw the
seeds away I like wasn't looking at the
evidence that no look these plants are
good because we already had the clone I
figured I'd never lose that clone you
know we got it in 89 that clone was
around to like 2005 but then that clone
got lost the only guy who had it he
lived by the Russian River which is
notorious for flooding he had it in a
trailer in a grove by the Russian River
the Russian River flooded it washed the
trailer and all the stock was law
and and now I go god I wish I had some I
wish I had one of those bags of handfuls
of beautiful brown pear-shaped Northern
Lights s1 seeds that I threw away you
know and so I think it's important that
people do it for preservation I don't
know as much for distribution unless
people kind of let you know like you
really got to know the parent is it
hermie Brown is it not hermie prone
because if it's a hermie prone parent
and you know if it's prone to intersects
trait then you're gonna you know you're
gonna have you're gonna have some
problems with those seeds but for
preservation purposes I think that
feminized seeds and soft seeds are a
really neat tool and especially in the
case where you have the clone and you
don't have the population of seeds to
pull a male from or whatever you know
yeah awesome and so maybe it's like a
little follow-up question do you think
that if you have a plant that doesn't
display any humanik traits on in normal
cases you know like it's just a stable
plant by all measure but for whatever
reason it's exposed to some serious
stress maybe a light leak for example
and it produces some nana's and makes ms
ones do you think that those seeds are
necessarily more homey prone so to speak
because the general consensus would be
that like a plant that tends to Hermey
you know the seeds will likewise tend to
hear me so I'm interested like if a
stable plant makes us one that's due to
the stress is is those offspring any
more likely to hurt me than the mother
like were they stable as well so to
speak yeah I think there's a crazy
stigma surrounding the whole thing where
people though feminized seeds hermie and
I think the reason why is because a lot
of people take plants that are easy to
reverse they reverse them they make
quote-unquote feminized seeds which
really aren't feminized they're usually
about 90% I mean you can go all the way
back to marijuana botany that I read
when I was a kid and they tell you hey
if a plant seeds itself you're gonna
probably get about 90% female so you're
gonna get the rest of them are gonna be
like true intersex plants which means
you know you're gonna have like you're
gonna have balls on one side and hairs
on the other side
I think that because people did that
where they took these plants that go
really easy you know like the apple
doesn't fall far from the tree if you
have a plant that likes to seed itself
and it seeds itself you're gonna have a
progeny that are gonna like to seed
themselves if you have a plant that
won't seed itself unless it's in very
unusual circumstances then you're gonna
get progeny where the bulk of those
seeds are not going to they're not gonna
seed themselves unless they're under
those same extraordinary circumstances
so yeah I really think that that I
really think that the the stigma
surrounding feminized seeds I really
think it comes from people choosing poor
parents and that if you use the right
parents then you know you're gonna get
something good and then I think it's
important that people understand that
being that there's no male in the cross
and that some of those plants in the
cross are gonna represent the male
plants basically those are they're gonna
be the ones that are like males with
hairs they're like 50/50 so you you know
you shouldn't be surprised if you get a
pack if you get it if you get you know
ten seeds and one of those are two of
those seeds in that pack is gonna be a
full-blown intersex plant because those
are basically the males in the pack not
that you want to use those as males but
that those are the ones that are in the
population trying to ensure that they
make more seeds you know so no oh sorry
going yeah no no no go ahead go ahead
man
I was just gonna say you kind of jumped
in on the next question I was gonna ask
him that yeah should you ever use those
into six months as males because I know
that the most notable example in my mind
is and this is not like a bad thing
because I think the strain is quite good
how many purple bike Ana buyer and they
said that that whole project initially
started by finding what was essentially
a mile above a Koosh out of what was
meant to be a pack of s ones and
bread that for several generations so
maybe not the best example but overall
the work doesn't seem to be super homey
prone but I mean it also has basically
no potency as far as my own growing sure
how do you feel about using those mouths
and the other little point I'll add is
DJ short once said that he thought they
were the best males like the male's
which had a few pollens there are a few
pistols on them and stuff and so I
always thought that's really weird like
was that just like a an idea he just
pulled outta nowhere you know I don't
think it is it's something that I've
kind of been trying to explore talking
to people it's something that I've been
able to read a little bit on forums a
Tom Hill talking about DJ short various
people I know a breeder of a really
successful strain who doesn't actually
want to be mentioned by name or by
strain because he used a mail like that
and he got basically the most stable
progeny anyone's really ever seen out of
any of their stuff and it was a male
alright there's that there's a division
though if you have ones that are
straight feminized and then you and then
they come up and they are self tore
whatever you know they come up and
they're they're like 50/50
there's hares at first and there's balls
at first ok those ones to me those are
very unattractive because in in in my
mind although I've never seen it in
practice in my mind that's what they are
gonna bring to the table is more plants
that are just 50/50 and 50/50 doesn't
play for us you know so there's a big
difference though between what DJ shorts
talking about which is actually a male
plant which shows mail and grows as a
male all the way until it reaches
towards the late part of its life and
all of a sudden starts to grow hairs
right now there's there's females we
know and this is where people are gonna
start to go oh man genes lost it here
and I'm not saying just as a disclaimer
I'm not saying this is what I'm gonna
start doing this is what I
do I haven't actually done any real work
with this so it's not solid stuff it's
just something to basically tickle your
brain so you can actually go okay hmm
this is this is where this is a this is
a human all right you have these plants
that grow and they're completely male
and I have seen them and they come from
ultra-stable lines like some of my
Afghan YZ and I got this stuff from
Kentucky from a buddy of mine
Shanti Farms that was really good and
really stable and showed no problems
whatsoever with the females ever but the
male's when they reach a late stage of
flowering they begin to produce a little
bit of female flowers in the male
clusters so what I think is interesting
is that we know that there's things like
hemp that basically are 5050 like those
plants we're talking about to come out
of the S ones they're 50/50 because when
they grow hemp they want it to finish at
the same time and males finish early and
they begin to basically break down and
you start to screw up your hemp they
don't get as big you don't have a
consistent agricultural crop so that's
normal we already know that that's
normal and can happen in cannabis so if
we know that a 50-50 state exists then
we also know that we have these plants
where the females when they go late the
females start to actually stress or feel
overdone or feel freaked out because
they haven't set seeds yet or whatever
it is and then they start to get you
know some balls late in life usually
there's a lot of different types of it
but you know some of them get just the
bananas or some get little balls up at
the top or however they do it
it's just interesting to wonder that
okay if that is one side of it could
that could the in in it and it's
genetically influenced because we know
it is because plants that are you know
quote-unquote
herby
they are hermie prone it is their gene
pool let's not all environment you know
so you have to wonder okay is there an
opposite state to that is there a state
where the females like assuming that
it's possible that the the the females
that go hermie are our gene pools that
are like so male that even the females
are slightly male could there be an
opposite state where the females are so
female that even the males are slightly
female and would that be the most stable
form of genetics for what we want it for
where the females will never produce
male parts and is that what that would
look like and I'm not saying that that's
how it is or that's the case but that's
the point that Tom Hill GJ short who are
definitely not rookies in the breeding
game they're they were curious about it
and when I read about it I became
curious about it too because you have to
wonder okay if we have a 50-50 state and
we have a state where the gene pool is
so male that even the females are
slightly male is their gene pools where
the females are so female that even the
males are slightly female so that anyway
that's that whole thing you were just
you brought up from DJ short yeah that's
that's actually how should I say
reassuring to hear is that I've done the
same thing with one of my lines and I
too found that the protein you are all
extremely stable I haven't found any
herms but what I wanted to ask was have
you ever done it yourself in that you
had the male produce some calluses and
then it pollinated itself so it's made
an S one off the mat and then you grown
that out cuz I've done that no I mean
the property to get males no I got a
female and I'm growing it out okay I've
been told that if you do that then
you'll get males but I've never like I
said I've never done anything with it
it's all theory for me it was just that
I I see these guys who were kind of who
who were who are experienced and who are
older than me and here they are you know
playing with this idea I'm like
yeah I don't know I mean it looks
interesting so for me it's all totally
speculation you know that's why I was
making sure that people know that um you
know I'm not on the I'm not drinking the
kool-aid I just am curious you know how
it tastes good phrase good phrase
so just to jump off topic for a moment
at the Emerald cup I was really grateful
to be able to try some of the skunk you
were playing with the thing I remember
taking away from it was it had this
awesome skunky metallic vibe and it made
me wonder what do you think is the deal
with metallic tasting terpenes or we'd
like surely it has to be a terpene
combination right like surely we're not
inhaling you know larger than normal
levels of aluminum or something like
that well I can tell you you know that
because I because I grew it and I tried
it I know that there's nothing weird in
that weed
it's very metallic to me it smells like
blood was kind of my take on it um it
really like it smells like you have a
nosebleed kinda in it
it smells like skunk like the animal it
was kind of a true skunky smell with a
lot of metal behind it and that came out
of the black lime it's a weird throw and
you know I don't really know but I do
know that there's stuff going on that is
separate from terpenes you know we
consider terpenes to be responsible for
a hundred percent of the smell and weed
but there is other stuff that goes on in
there that creates smells aside from you
know things in nature that create smells
like you know bacteria or fungus or
whatever but um you know III wonder I
don't know I mean what is what is that
what is what's the blood terpene it's
really weird man that weed was so killer
though that's so really that was a
really exceptional plant and luckily I
made some seeds on that so in the future
I'll probably go through them and I
still have some of the weed I suppose I
could get it tested and then you know
that might give us an answer I think I
need to probably start doing
not basically filing away a sample of
every single plant just so that if
something comes into question in
hindsight we can go ahead and test it
even though it we kind of missed the
boat because I can still test that now
yeah but yeah really really really
that's a really weird one dude I I don't
I don't know what that is but I mean
there's there's um you know there's like
the purple color and weed has has a
flavor to it depending on what it is you
know there's there there is stuff in
there it might not necessarily be a
terpene but it seems like it's it
probably is a terpene it's just weird
because I don't ever see like on the
terpene wheel them going yeah this
smells like an old dirty nickel or you
know smells like the gate the chain on
your gate or an old dirty lock or
something that's how that weed smell
does really yeah it was some really cool
stuff thanks again for that jumping at
my next little skunk question the
roadkill skunk long debated much talked
about on the show we're slowly getting
there though first and foremost what do
you think the genetics are because over
time we've had a larger and larger
amount of guests seem to either agree or
throw it out there that it is also their
belief that the the name roadkill skunk
is likely just a name saying for how it
smells but not a reference to the
genetics and most people have been
throwing it out there that they think it
was maybe an Afghani even what do you
think yeah I mean I can Chuck my two
pennies from the peanut gallery here I
don't really have you know this is
definitely not my expertise is what is
skunk but what have I seen that was
skunky you know the super skunk was
skunky and we know that was Afghani it's
across a course it's like a skunk Afghan
ears I you know like I said it's not
really am I not my thing is the skunk
but um I have only ever grown one plant
that to me was like really like a dead
skunk I got it from I got it from Steve
see money's dad that was uh what he
called pissy pungent favorito he gave
like Spanglish names to a lot of stuff
that's where I got the name
Pina for my pineapple strain that I got
from those guys you know pissy pungent
favorito man it was that kind of weed
where if you have it you know you like
God who apologize to people even if they
smoke because it's like hey sorry I'm
sorry I got this in my pocket guys like
you know like hey you need to you need
to probably wash your t-shirt and go you
know take a bath and some tomato juice
cuz you smell like you got dirty laundry
and skunk all over you man it's just
funky and raw and it was here's the
thing to me is the reason why I'm
interested in skunk is not because I'm
not impressed by something that smells
like a dead skunk it was because when I
had that weed which was an Afghani it
tasted so delicious it's so hard to
describe what it tasted like it was this
like I don't know man like I you know
it's one of those weird ones where I can
only describe it as tasting like the
color of like a like a parking cone here
in the States you know just like it was
like this orange not like citrus but it
was this it was just this thing that
just lights up your tongue like so hard
to describe man but it was such an
incredible smell and taste and it was
just like my favorite weed ever and I
had one little plan of it and I grew
that that was the first time in 94 that
I grew those seeds that I got and I
never had another thing like it the
closest I saw to it was what I called
the arcade of Super Skunk which I'm not
positive if it's the skunk 6 or the
skunk 4 or any of these other ones that
people have I'm excited to see the skunk
6 cuz talking to talking to a couple
guys it seems like it could be the same
one that was like the closest thing that
I ever smelled to the pissy pungent was
a super skunk and then you know like
honestly like out of the lime like you
know you smelled that one it's in the
ballpark of animal animal funk skunk
there's a lot of skunk enos in the lime
the lime will make your clothes smell
like a skunk it'll make your car smell
like a skunk but a
close it smells like usually like a mix
of like you know gasoline lime peels
urinal cakes and you know Spearman in
earth and moss and funk and but but from
a distance that smells like a skunk and
there was a lot of weed back in the day
that was really skunky from a distance
more so than now but then there was some
stuff that's there's another skunk to
you that was Afghani based actually
there I had a buddy up here and we
called him we called him Grimble and the
weed that his family had we'd call it
grymps grapes and to this day grymps
grapes is one of those strains that is
one of those lost lost Grail strains
like if somebody had that it would be
incredible it was like when you would
open it up in the car you wouldn't think
someone opened weed you would think
somebody drove by a dead skunk and then
when you smelled it up closest smelled
like a skunk but it smelled like pine
and the only reason why it was called
grapes was because it was purple and it
had nothing to do with a smile it was
skunk pine and it was skunky really in
an amazing way it was super super funky
and that was another one and that was
one that you could really easily look at
the weed and go yeah that's Afghani
that's just a straight Afghani so and I
mean you can go back and you can read
like marijuana botany and you can read
any of these old books and they'll tell
you if you want
acrid skunky funky weed you know it
comes from Afghani and when I smell a
skunk I smell coffee onion burnt rubber
garlic and what everybody calls skunk
that you think of when you smell a skunk
at a distance but if you've ever had
like a house skunked or a car ran over a
skunk in an old car it makes your eyes
burn and it smells more like burnt it
smells like it smells like somebody you
know put you know a piece of a tire a
bunch of garlic a bunch of onions and
they took that all and they lit it on
fire and blew it in your face that's
and some coffee beans you know that's
what it really smells like a real
[__] dead skunk on the road for
people who haven't actually you know
smelled a you know an American skunk
it's it's a really really funky smell
and then there's the smell we think of
from weed that's the skunky smell but um
if anybody's gonna have a real roadkill
skunk I mean there's those noser smells
that I've smelled come out of afghani a
lot it's not rare to smell a garlicky
oniony a coffee ish those things come
out a burnt rubber so you know someone's
gonna have to find the right combination
of something that smells kind of like
what I gave to you and then have the
heavy coffee the heavy burnt onion the
burnt garlic at the burnt rubber does
those things are you know and I smell a
dead skunk up close that's how it hits
me in the nose yeah I mean that's that's
so interesting in relation to that
grapes the gramps grapes about how is
purple but it smells like skunk because
we also referenced earlier how a lot of
purple stuff tends to smell the same so
that's really interesting I think
ultimately the question is though is do
you think in theory cannabis as a whole
has the potential to generate almost or
including every smell possible so to
speak I as far as I've seen I think so I
mean I know at least at one point it did
I don't know about our current gene pool
and what we've done with it because you
know it takes who knows how many
thousands or millions of years it took
to reach a point of diversity where it
really produced everything and then we
kind of grabbed it all and did what we
did with it and now it's been bottle
necked out and what's interesting with
genetics is that everything's still in
there but it's not maybe in there short
term like we like there might be tons of
stuff with roadkill skunk and I know we
could get it back to be that exact thing
and maybe it's there right now but if
it's not there right now we don't know
if it's gonna take six months or six
thousand years to get back to the point
where we've opened the genetics back up
to that point because things get
bottlenecked out and we think of them as
being completely gone but if you were to
grow millions
these then you know things would pop
back out it's just we're not you know we
don't have there's not enough people in
the world I don't think to bring back
the diversity that was there possibly at
one point but just to answer the
question yes or no I think yes I think
cannabis has the potential to produce
any smell that exists anywhere else in
the world including bacterial and fungal
smells I think so
that's awesome that's so I think so as
well so I mean yeah interesting to see
what it would take to actually do such a
thing
given like I mean certainly like for me
mango pops up more than any other flavor
to me maybe it's just the things I
select but it's like given that like
yeah there's a lot of things which must
go unrepresented yeah and there you know
there's things that just really take
over gene pools it's really easy um for
you know I mean you know I'm not a I'm
not a terpene scientist but um you know
if such a thing exists but as far my
understanding is that a lot of times
it's like like limonene and and Mersin
tend to be kind of the like the
precursors to a lot of the other
terpenes that developed and I kind of
noticed that because I'll smell
something and I'll go this one smells
like train wreck and then I'll go over
here and I'll go this one smells like
that sweet Afghani kind of berry grape
Tootsie Pop kind of smell and then later
on they develop and I go there's none of
that left it's not there at all but it
kinda is there to start and you know I
think that those things what happens is
they kind of take over they kind of take
over gene pools to where it's like wow
okay if you got anything that's got that
kind of train wreck II Amsterdam haze
smell in there or you have anything that
has that kind of great be raspberry
sweet thing it's like they they take
over gene pools so much that I think
they've given themselves the reputation
of being generic smells at this point
because they're just so dominant in gene
pools and I think that that
you know everybody hybridizing things
and kind of mishmash in and hodgepodge
and stuff up I think over over the years
that it's like okay well you have this
you have this real special thing over
here that smells like roses and now you
crossed it with this thing that smells
like train wreck and guess what you know
Rose is not going to overtake train
wreck so now you just took a gene pool
that had something special in it and you
kind of erased it unless you want to
grow like I said you want to grow
thousands or millions of plants to try
to you know recuperate those does kind
of funk you know yeah I guess it's safe
to say one wrong step forward is gonna
take a crazy amount of effort to undo it
in using those seeds generated yeah you
know cuz because you have these
different genes they behave different
ways they don't play well with others at
all they just come in and they just
basically you know they just they just
bully the whole yard you know and then
it's like okay well we now we have this
you know I have one that's really cool
um it has that smell but it has all
these other smells and it it actually
keeps the smell and the other finer
smells with it it's called candelabra I
got it from a friend of mine in 2004 and
it was I used to call it the ten
thousand smiles and some people smell
and they go oh it smells like train
wreck and I'm like dude smell it again
and they're like oh it smells like great
you're like smell it again they're like
oh it smells like orange asked all these
terpenes and then when we see it get
tested
you send it to SC labs where they test
for like 35 terpenes and it hits for
like 33 of them and there's not many
strains that do stuff so it really does
have a lot of it really does have
thousands of flavors in it you know but
um but that's a neat one where it has
that thing in it that I kind of turned
off by that's kind of the train wreck
smell because it just is it's like kind
of overly common you know but it but it
has something really nice to it you know
so it's they don't yeah
they don't always ruin everything but
they pop a tendency for sure
so I mean while we're on the topics of
like labs and all the modern kind of
techniques that go along with that the
emergence and growing popularity of
these kind of um pre sexing science kits
you can get seems to be growing
initially I figured it would probably
something more a breeder would be
interested in but I don't know it seems
to be just on the rise growing in in
general is this something you'd be
interested in because I mean given how
many seeds you run through I figure
maybe not like I mean you did be
spending crazy amounts and money on it
but at the same time it seems to be a
growing technology like do you think
it'll stick around long term or not
really
I think it'll stick around long term I
think it has its benefits I think that
when new technologies come around the
price line tends to drop really fast and
anything that's based on technology it
has a big expense to start and as soon
as it's been established then the price
drops and that price carries from the
labs to the consumer because they want
to get everyone's money right they don't
just want people who have a lot of money
so they're trying to get their prices
down and I think eventually it would be
practical my joke as a as a as a troll
on social media was that I'll do it when
it costs less than a pot in some dirt
because I can I can grow the plant till
it's a male for cheaper than I can get
it tested you know they want $8 a test
and I can grow a plant until it sexes
and see what it is
for less than that so in that case I was
like yeah I'm not gonna I'm not gonna do
it myself but it would be practical and
it could be practical for certain
projects like if you really don't want
the males I think that it's practical
for people who have their areas maxed
out and they want to only transplant
their females so that they don't have to
grow the males for me losing the plants
before they show what they are is just
foolish because I'm a breed
you know like if it's if it's a terrible
plan I'm gonna kill it and if it's a
good plan I want to keep it and if it's
a male
even better you know like I don't want
my best plant to be if I you know
whatever I can do whatever I can measure
just by looking at it and smelling it
and stuff in veg I'm hoping that's a
male you know cuz I'm like okay this is
the one in this breed that I know is
killer like if I was growing a bunch of
deep chunk and I see the one that has
the smaller leaves that taco on the
edges a little harder and I'm and I'm
looking at that and I'm associating that
with the best type of deep chunk then
I'm like fingers crossed I'm like I hope
this is a male you know because if this
is a male I can tell which ones of the
females have that but the males are a
lot harder to tell and if I can see
these things that I really know relate
to the traits that pop up in the females
then I'm gonna be going ok cool I'm glad
it's a male so for me it's not that
practical but for people who are who are
growing to produce flowers exclusively I
think that you know I think it's
worthwhile I think it's something people
can do and you're gonna go from being in
your little six-packs or your little
four-inch pots and instead of going
instead of up potting into all these
bigger pots you're just gonna be able to
take your females and stick them right
into your final pots you know so number
one you can skip a transplanting stage
you can skip a nursery stage where
you're actually building them up to be
ready to go into their final homes and
you can go ahead and get them into their
final homes established right away which
is it can be a benefit to if you have
the right strains so yeah thanks for
that call
yeah and so how about on the other end
of the spectrum with the labs ha tops
are away for this truck to go past my
house I don't know if you can hear of it
it's really loud sweet so on the other
end of the spectrum with labs how do you
feel about the THC values and I guess
the newly emerging terpene values for
someone like you I guess terpene values
are quiet
Orton given you know how well your
strands do chart on them there's always
been you know the ongoing debate about
the the validity of the THC values given
and how they seem to be kind of creeping
up over time what's your take on all of
this you know and and how do you think
like the terpene values are gonna slowly
over time become more highly valued than
the THC values well to to start off like
I can say that uh I know there's a lot
of people who are as far as inflated
numbers I know there's people who are
adding resin to their flower samples and
in that case it's really easy to jump
from 21 to 29 or 27 to 32 or you know
then I know also there's breeders who
are using testing to make sure that the
males they're using are the highest THC
male and that is a new thing and the
feem testing the females as well as a
new thing you didn't used to be able to
test so I think that that will make the
numbers jump up to you know I think that
for me I'm not looking for the highest
THC I'm looking for the strongest effect
so my joke is that I test on humans you
know you can test it in the lab all you
want but I've noticed over the years
that I smoke some stuff from reputable
guys that test at reputable labs and the
THC might be really high and it might be
really high in certain terpenes but when
you know people smoke it they don't
really think it's that strong it doesn't
really hit you that hard
so I think really like labs are neat but
I think basically they're a little bit
more they're more valuable as far as for
finished product like telling what's
good if we already know it's good then
the lab is cool to tell us why so if we
go okay this is the most potent weed
I've ever smoked we want the lab to tell
us why now we go and we see okay well
turns out it's only 14 percent THC well
how can this be the most potent well
here we got CBG and then it turns out we
didn't know but there's THC V and then
it turns out that there's this certain
ratio of this terpene to that terpene
and when they're all together you get
this effect that creates the most potent
weed with the 14% THC content or you
know however it is that's hypothetical
of course but um for me as far as
breeding to answer that part of the
question you know I I you know I I'm I'm
too young to be a hippie and I'm too not
hippy to be a hippie as well but I'm
kind of a hippie man like I like to look
at the plants and kinda talk to the
plants and communicate with them and see
which one really you know when I smell
it like there's these certain smells
that pop out I mean cherry limeade and
black lime or bred purely on stem reps
and it's not really something that I can
show people what I'm looking for
it's this thing where I go mmm that's
that one I've seen that before and when
I saw that before that was incredible
and so for me the labs are cool to tell
me what that means okay when I see this
what does that tell me
and then if I can see a correlation that
says every time I see this and then when
I test it it turns out that it has this
in common then maybe I can test and I
can go for the ones that have more of
that you know but at this point for me
it's really it's really more a question
of you know like what do I like and and
what kind of makes my brain jump when I
see it or I smell it or you know that
kind of stuff and I really like it
because I know that all of the good
things like I said earlier that we see
in weed they've been there for a long
time and all of the genetics that we
have are still here from people doing
traditional breeding where they
basically are doing just you know what
I'm talking about and so you know I'm
comfortable I'm comfortable honestly
like with just picking plants and making
seeds and I feel like as long as I do
open pollination 's
to preserve the genetics that I'll be
all right you know and I've wired up now
because I know that I know the value of
stuff I used to think that everybody
would have the seeds that they gave me
because it was their stuff and now I
know better when someone gives you
something you might be the last person
that has it you know so you know I'm I'm
into trying to do trying to do you know
use labs to get to new places but at the
same time I've like I've really realized
like in you got to keep it all you got
to keep it the old stuff intact and you
got to you got to take the new stuff in
new directions and for going in new
directions the labs are cool but for
keeping the old stuff intact they're
worthless the labs not gonna tell you
anything about your open pollination you
know they're just you got to keep it all
no matter what and then when you're
gonna selectively lime green then you
know the lab telling you that this is
the highest THC male that they've ever
seen Hey
well you want the highest THC line out
of that then that's that's gonna be
worthwhile you know so yeah I think
they're good too to tell you what you're
seeing you know why is this like this
they can explain that for you yeah
without some awesome information there
just to loop back on one of the points
you made a bit earlier about using
humans to test sir this is a great point
that I've always stood by the
interesting kind of counter-argument to
that point though is is it not the same
people who over time have driven the
prioritization of aesthetics which has
led to the loss of certain other
qualities because I only kind of thought
of this idea not long ago and I I
realized it is like almost a bit of a
dichotomy you know it's like the best
weed is the stuff that you've got to try
for yourself and it's just overall
effect but at the same time we also know
we push for the most aesthetic weed
which we do at least now no is generally
not the best um yeah I mean you know
like a big fat bud a really really
sugary look you know they don't
necessarily I mean like the black happy
that I had sure had big fat buds and was
purple and pretty but it looked like it
had no resin on it even when I crossed
it with a Hindu Kush which is a really
white looking bud like incredibly white
weed when you grow at Indore once it was
crossed you'd look at the weed and you'd
go
there's no resin on this and you'd break
it up and your hands wouldn't get sticky
and you'd roll it up and you'd inhale it
and you would go holy [__] this is
potent I mean just on the it was the
expansion and the exhale and the flavor
and then the effect that just
immediately got you it wasn't you know
to look at it you would think this is
this is the stuff sucks and based on
looking based on that I would say that
probably in tests it probably couldn't
have that much th Sikhs it didn't have
that big of a percentage of resin but
the flower was incredible you know and a
lot of the a lot of the stuff that's all
those really cool sativas that people
loved so much
it looked it looks bad it's not good
looking stuff but I'll tell you what if
you start to think okay this is my
favorite kind of weed is the sativa all
of a sudden that look is gonna become
attractive to you because you're like
woohoo that looks like that one that's
the stuff I like you know I think that I
mean it's been documented and a lot of
people have spoke on it before that
everyone bred things to be fast
sugary fat those you know as a smoker
fast sugary and fat it that doesn't
really do anything for you man
it's gotta have for me I've always bred
it sure I like weed to be you know all
of those things but then I want to have
the really nice smell that really nice
taste I want to have a good effect and
I'm not I'm not locked into a one effect
type of thing you know like I'm not
worried if it's
Gracie sativa or a heavy indica or ultra
potent strain or a very mild strain for
me I'm like whatever special about that
strain that's what I want to maintain
about it so you know like I really like
I like to laugh you know what I mean I
love like comedy I love funny movies I
love funny people I love funny stories
so if we don't make you giggle I'm like
oh what's that one I gotta try to lock
that in you know I got to make sure I
keep that around and um and so like
though there's those little things that
really those don't show up at on a
picture on Instagram you know so I think
that's why right now kind of the king of
everything is like if you look on
Instagram and you see a pretty picture
and you go oh that's a nice strain and
you click on it you're like yeah it's
probably something probably cookie fam
you know it's gelato it's sherbert it's
cookies or if not then it's probably OG
or you know cam or something from that
from the family of all those fuels and
everything like that and and those are
all great strains but I think the reason
why they took over is because they look
so pretty and then when you get some and
you try it you go oh okay and it's good
but a lot of the stuff over the years it
did just kinda go down the tubes it
looks great and then it's just not you
know it's not all that good I know there
was a deal where for awhile people loved
the the nested calyxes that's the look
where you have like you have like the
you have the pod inside the pod inside
the pod inside the pod and what happens
is there's no room really for the resin
to develop so you wind up with stuff
where when you break it up there's
really not that much resin the resin is
only on the outside of the bud or in
between you know hairs yeah people think
you know the the the stigma the hair is
is attractive so they breed for their we
need to be very hairy Harry's burn hairs
burn hot they don't produce they don't
produce res
and I mean I've seen somewhere seemingly
they do produce resin but they certainly
don't produce resin like the rest of the
like the flower so yeah I mean I I think
it's definitely you know aesthetics and
and ease of of growing have have taken
stuff down down a notch for sure yeah
yeah
so not trying to have a jab at you or
anything but recently in the aficionado
catalog we've seen the introduction of
some crosses with zeros and sunsets sure
but you know I think a lot of people
wouldn't have predicted these ones
coming out in your opinion you know what
was the reason behind doing this do you
like those cuts like do you the zoodles
is an interesting one because a lot of
people reference how like it in itself
is not a great strain but there's so
much potential to make something with it
you know a you of that school of thought
as well I think that the the skittles
has a lot of um it has a lot of neat
stuff to it I personally it's not
something all grow it's difficult to
really have do nice you know to come out
nicely I saw recently archived just days
doing some stuff with the dote with a
dose IDO I think it looks really nice
it's got a lot a lot of resin dying
breed those guys are the guys who named
it skittles and you know they they've
done cool stuff I like the I like the OC
cush that Eddie lap basically OG seed
crossed with the with the skittles I
like that better than the skills myself
it reminds me a lot of what I call sky
Cutler cush that I have that's a cross
that has some of the old stuff for mine
then mixed in with some like Skywalker
and PK and stuff you know honestly for
aficionado people because people know me
from from from
uh you know being at the booth putting
stuff out with aficionado the only stuff
that I ever really did with aficionado
was I gave Leo some pollen and told him
that it would be great on the in the
Pines clone that got released as in The
Pines I told him I had the black lime
and it would work really good with the
cam he gave me that pollen that was
black lime reserve I released some f3s
of what I call red Hindukush which is
big red cross Hindu cross pure Kush and
what I gave him some some of my Skye
Skywalker cross Skye djaro
to put on to put on some stuff and he
did that with a Louie og and we called
that Versailles and other than that man
no no none of that stuff is my work I
mean all the royal stuff is all coming
from Mendel brought given that to Leo to
work with anything that you see with
cookies cherry sherbert skittles I you
know I you know I didn't I didn't make
any of that stuff so I can't really
speak on it okay and so another kind of
interesting topic I've seen is that
we've seen both an increase in price of
seeds and an increase in quality or
maybe consistency in recent years
however we've also seen an increase in
price for some seeds that don't equally
have an increase in quality do you think
this is going to continue do you think
that like you know I think that there
will always be a market for high-priced
seeds that are incredibly good quality
and we've got some of that right now but
I also think that yeah like we might get
more and more people selling bunk seeds
for just more do you think that's gonna
continue or do you even agree with the
idea that the price of seeds has kind of
increased over time you know I mean I
think the most expensive stuff that I
really saw was like some of that I guess
like alien stuff I heard people were
doing those for like you know a thousand
and 1500 and of course people do like
chair
any auctions and stuff and and stuff
brings in like ridiculously high prices
but people people spend different for
that kind of stuff because you know it's
just a different thing and it's like
buying a thousand dollar plate of food
or something you know but um as far as
like stuff being high-priced I mean like
black lime reserve the donation on that
was two hundred and fifty and a lot of
people said that's ridiculous that's way
too much anything over a hundred bucks
for ten seeds is crazy and then you know
they were gone and then everybody was
like oh where are they and it's like
well there's only 300 packs that's why
you know that they they have it there's
an added value when you when you have
leverage basically for your product
because it's super limited you know and
I don't mean for myself but for the
people who actually got those seeds you
know black lime reserve is a little bit
more sought-after than something that
comes out of a pack of seeds that you
could buy from a huge company and
there's millions of packs you know
because you know it's harder to get but
um I think you know there's there's been
stuff over the years that's that's um
ridiculously expensive and there's stuff
that's not ridiculous of course and I
you know sometimes I kind of wonder like
you know I see breeders that make
certain stuff and I'm like wow those are
so that's that's such a small amount to
get for the seeds and it's not because
the seeds it's not the value of a seed a
seed is worth nothing you know what I
mean
it's the genetics that are inside the
seed what is this seed otherwise it's
you know a hemp seeds a hemp seed you
know buy it by the pound but for me if
there's something that is really special
I'm willing you know I've I've given
people I've given people $200 $300 for
ten seeds because you know it was
something that I wanted and I know the
value because I can take a pack of seeds
and I can get a whole ton form I mean
not for them but out of them you know
what I mean like you can go okay well
like right now I have bodis
super snow Lotus it's Super Skunk cross
snow Lotus and I'm like well I just want
to butt them out and see what they are
but I go I'm gonna keep that one male
and I'm gonna go ahead and make sure
that out of my one pack of seeds I have
like a few hundred more seeds out of
them so it's like four one pack of seeds
you can get hundreds of seeds and and of
course you could get thousands or
millions if you were to clone them up
and stuff but um you know I think seed
values a trip like if it's really
special enough I think stuff is worth it
like if somebody told me oh dude I got
chemist stuff that's the stuff you were
talking about dude I'd be like well what
do you want for them you know I mean
like if I gotta trade somebody that I
gotta trade somebody like three pounds
of cherry limeade and they got the real
thing I'm gonna be like dude dude here
we go right now give me those give me
fifteen seeds I gave me three pounds of
weed because it's something that I
really want so you know value is weird
man like you know what's a dog worth
what's a horse work worse well you know
some horses are worth dog food and some
horses are worth you know eight hundred
thousand dollars or some horses are
worth five million dollars it just
depends on how it breeds what it brings
to the table and all that kind of stuff
and so I think we're gonna start seeing
a lot more seeds that are a lot cheaper
because seeds are really easy to produce
and if people are willing to part with
their genetics for cheap then you can
produce seeds for very cheap it's the
same process pretty much as producing
hemp seeds and you can buy those suckers
for cheap right so uh I think also that
there will start to be seeds that are
more and more premium as well to where
people go yeah these are you know this
ridiculous amount for this pack of seeds
you know and I did black lime reserve I
told everybody hey if you don't find
what I you know I showed everybody what
the weed looks like got off of good
plants I said if you don't get this like
this in your pack come back to me I'll
give you two more packs so people look
at it and they go oh well that's so out
of control and I'm like yeah but there's
not any there's not anybody else who's
you right up front if you don't get what
you want I'm not saying if they don't
germinate I'm not saying if you get
something that's intersex or if you get
these issues I'm saying that if it just
you don't like it like a restaurant like
you says you send out the steak and you
asked it for it to be rare and it comes
out and it's rare and you didn't realize
you don't like rare steak I'm giving you
another steak you know like even if it's
their fault basically I was still
guarantee in those seeds and I didn't
really get anybody who ever took me up
on that and I didn't get any complaints
or anything but I think that um that if
people are willing to you know like I
when I put those out people would
contact me and they'd say hey is it all
right if I make seeds and I'd be like
there's only the only rule is that you
make some good ones you know make some
nice stuff and then they'd say well what
do I look for and I'd say well what do
you want from the seats and as a breeder
I would tell him here is what here
here's here's some of the markers for
these traits and here's some of the
markers for those traits so that hey you
want the one that's really really limey
let me send me pictures of your plants
and I'll tell you which one is most
likely to be that throwback to that old
lime line that is you know the genetics
are basically you know lock together
where you get this leaf type you're
probably gonna get the lime smell you
know you get the smell there it is you
know and so I feel like if people want
to really put out seeds for really high
prices and they're willing to give you a
service that goes beyond just this
little thing of seeds I feel like
they're valuable and they're worth
something extra and then if somebody's
gonna say hey here's some seeds I don't
ever want to hear nothing about it these
cost 20 bucks a pack cool that's cool
too you know but it just all it all
depends on how people want to do their
thing and I think it really comes down
to just being ethical and saying this is
what this really is if you find out it's
not what it is put it on your website
put it on your you know do whatever like
I have my my root beer I thought for
years it was seven oh seven headband it
turns out no it's the headband they call
la cush it's the mother of the 707
band suits in the ballpark but I'm like
sorry guys it's not 7:07 headband and
this is strains not even released but
I've been putting out info about it and
I you know I feel like you're supposed
to have the right info so when you do go
to breed like people like don't breed
with my stuff I'm like dude you ain't
gonna live forever you know like
everybody it shouldn't have to wait for
you to die to go okay well now I can do
these seeds like you know it's just it's
just a question of I think um um you
know quality and like you know
commitment to what whatever the thing is
and so that's your difference between
your $20 seeds and your and your
whatever $20,000 seats who knows how
high prices are gonna get the future
when stuff is you know whatever is more
sought-after because now there's a
bigger community of people which causes
more demand you know so we'll see
yes I almost raises another interesting
point at which point do you think
someone can call some work I went say
across because maybe you've just
actually lined reddit but at what point
can you call work your own you know if
you took Mandelbrot's royal and took it
to the f20 do you think you'd be fair to
say it's kind of your own at that point
and likewise you know if you make an f1
is do you feel like you can really kind
of say it's yours in the sense of like
it's you know what I mean like it's not
just kind of borrowing off other
people's stuff too heavily I think that
I think that where the line is drawn I
think that when you make a hybrid and
it's just a fresh hybrid of other
people's work I think that it's just a
hybrid of other people's work and you
did a selection and that's cool and
that's like the beginning of a process I
think that as soon as you take it in a
new direction where what you get doesn't
come out of the things that you started
with
then it's deserving of a new name
because otherwise it's almost a
misrepresentation of the old genetics so
like in this case if I take you know
like I have cherry limeade right and I
go okay here's a black lime across
a pie and I make those seeds well it's
black lime cross cherry pie but when I
take a selection out of the F ones and I
breed it in a new direction and now it's
got some of the terpenes of the cherry
pie but it's got the it's got the
strength and the stone enos and the
increased size of the black lime and you
know I keep taking it in further and
further and further to the point where
you can't get those plants from what you
started with then you know that's a new
thing and I don't think you ever get so
far into something where you don't need
to give people credit or you don't need
to give a background of it I feel like
that stuff is more of like academic
thing like it's more of a like thing for
science where you say hey here's what
this is because when people know what
this is if we ever need to recreate it
we can recreate it like what if you know
say like cherry limeade I lost it all
but somebody has one clone and it turns
out that it's the cure for some crazy
disease and then I lose then they lose
the clone and they're like well what was
it and I'm like well I don't know what
it was no it's like well then now nobody
knows what it was so they don't know
where to look for it so if it became
really useful and valuable at a certain
point from a scientific perspective it's
like he just screwed things up there now
it's not really what it's supposed to be
nobody can backtrack nobody can figure
out what it is and you know so I think
like that's like why it's really
important in ways to have your have your
you know your lineage is there and and
give credit to people because they did
do some work and then you know for your
work then you do then you deserve some
credit - everyone deserves what they
deserve but they don't just deserve
everything you know like just because
somebody has a plant doesn't mean now
they deserve all the credit for that
plant like there's other people who
should get some credit too like if I
knew the people who
gave the seeds two dudes who brought him
here to California that were in
Afghanistan I'd be like yeah its dude
over there in Afghanistan so and so he's
he was the guy who had him in
Afghanistan and but I don't I only know
him back to a certain place and and so
I'll tell you you know black line comes
back from Heath and Ian and goes back to
John and it goes back to this Burmese
and it goes back to Afghani and hawken
and Northern Lights and you know that's
that's all I know about it that's as far
back as it goes and I don't lose
anything by saying that that it all come
that stuff comes from from places like
that and it's like yeah that the reason
why black lime is black lime is because
I chose a sport plant out of you know as
an oddball in in a population and then I
crossed it was something that was in a
completely different side of the
spectrum and then I got it to be where
it took something from both places for
the flavor and for the plant and I made
it into something and it's something
that's it's totally different like you
can't show it to either the people who
it originally came from and they go oh
that's my stuff they're like ooh this is
nice this is something new I've never
seen this and so at that point I feel
like now that's a new thing and sure you
deserve credit for what that is but you
know ethics is ethics is weird man you
know ethics is a weird subject because
it all comes down to belief and belief
isn't um you know belief and right or
wrong or good or bad it's not like a
concrete thing you know some people are
some people are spiritual and they're
cannibals you know or some people are
you know it's like whatever just
everybody basically what I what I think
comes down to with like ethics with
what's yours and what's not yours and
all that is basically like if you have
rules or you have things that you hold
other people to you know you make the
rules so follow the damn rules they're
your rules you know don't be mad about
somebody doing something that you do all
the time like that just isn't that
doesn't make any sense you know
you know I think it just it just all a
matter of you know do real work make
real stuff happen and then you get the
credit for what you did you know I don't
need the credit from from Ian I'll need
the credit from Heath I get the credit
for doing what I did and they get their
credit for doing what they did you know
so yeah for sure so I mean on the topic
of ethics and potentially questionable
ones I remember around the time of the
Emerald cup or I think maybe even the
day after you put up a post basically
saying you know along the lines of you
you knew that you weren't gonna get
placed where you should have been and
you know hinted to the idea that maybe
there was some more politics behind the
scenes in regards to the judging than
what the public was aware of did I just
kind of misinterpret that post or is
there something a little more yeah going
on no you know what was going on
honestly was people were saying that I
was gonna win and they were saying that
I was gonna win because it was fixed and
the reason why I won was because I was
gonna win no matter what
and my we'd probably wasn't really that
good anyway
and the contest isn't blind and all this
different stuff and you know what I
basically was saying was look I've won
third I've won second I have won first
all in a row if you guys think I'm gonna
take first again when there's gonna
probably be a thousand entries from all
over California you guys are tripping
because it's just not gonna happen there
was no way that I was gonna do that
again it's just not it just wasn't
possible there's not like you know like
yeah I got good weed but even if you
know there is people were like oh well I
know who's gonna win that guy's gonna
win and I'm like you guys really think
I'm gonna win again you know and they
were like well yeah of course you'll win
again because that's why you want in the
first place and I'm like no I really
want in the first place and I can tell
you right now that I'm not gonna win
again because I know I really want now
if it was fixed I'd be like yep I'm
gonna win I know I'm gonna win because
it's fixed
I always win but you know that's not why
I won man I won because I had because
everybody entered fuel and everybody
entered fruit and I entered fruit feel
and everybody's purple doesn't get you
high and everybody's cush tastes like
cush and I entered I entered purple weed
that gets you high tastes like purple
tastes like cush takes like a bunch of
other crazy stuff - I took seven hours
to trim three ounces you know and that's
just how I did it you know I didn't
touch the weed when I cut it off the
plant I did all this special stuff and
you know it gave me an edge and I just
knew the reality was that's why I put up
the post I'm like dude if you guys
really think that you know I'm
big-headed enough to go in here and
think I'm gonna win you know I just I
don't I don't believe that I don't think
it can be done I don't think anybody's
gonna win this sucker two years in a row
sure third second first you know I
always do pretty well but it's because
of those tricks I use to make my stuff
look unhandled I you know people's weeds
dry in seven days why we ain't dry for
24 days you know people's weed is cut
down and put in the wheelbarrow mine's
cut down and stuck on a hanger people's
weed is touched with hands I touched the
stem people trim the weed and they put
it in a pile people pull weed out of
bags their trimmers are trimming I'm
like no man this stuff is like this is
like scientific grade right here you
know that's like these are specimens of
the plant perfectly preserved but I I
you know did I think I'd probably be in
the top ten yeah I did because I know
how much care I put into those entries
but you know I knew there was no way I
was gonna win and that that's what the
post was about and there were and I was
joking
it was tongue-in-cheek I was saying oh
yeah you know here's Swami talking to
Tim figuring out how to let me win you
know but um but it was really it was
because you know I was making fun of
people who were making fun of me because
you know it was just unrealistic people
basically if people if people lose its
fixed if they win its fair that's how
people think you know
they're like wall my friend didn't win
so it's fixed and then when their friend
wins they're like hell yeah this is a
good contest because my friend want it's
like dude people's weeds not just good
cuz it's yours it's not just good cuz
it's your friends it's only good if it's
good and the weed I entered was good and
that's why I won no it doesn't mean I
can do it every time yeah I mean it's
interesting you mentioned that because I
was gonna say your online presence in my
opinion I hope you don't take any
offense to this it's kind of like semi
troll in a little ways like it's like a
lot of good jokes followed up with kind
of like a no I'm just kidding type of
thing and no it is I'm I'm I'm I'm a fun
lover you know I'm not mean about stuff
I don't bully people but um but um you
know like I said I like to laugh man I
like to make people laugh I think like
laughing is one of the greatest things
there is that's why you know like if if
people if people are into the weed
community and they don't like to laugh
like I don't know what they're smoking
you know yeah yeah so I mean just
relating to that do you think that
things in general have gotten a bit
uptight and tense in the community and
maybe we could use a bit more of this
kind of just you know kind of
light-hearted fun yeah you know I don't
know I mean it's hard because
everybody's got a different sense of
humor
some people take things too far some
people don't know when they're being a
bully
some people don't they're not really
intelligent enough to actually make a
joke that's like a joke and their joke
is just you know calling somebody fat or
calling somebody stupid or calling
somebody a [__] and they think that's a
joke you know like some people just
they're they're not they then they're
missing it and they're like oh well you
do the same thing and I'm like no I
don't man I make jokes do these are
jokes you know and that joke might be
yeah a little over the top and it might
you know generally if you see me say
something offensive to somebody that
means they're my friend and when they
read it they know that that I'm joking
with them because we have we we have a
rapport you know some people just are
just you know trolling strangers and
they're just you know I get people on my
stuff sometimes who just come on and go
oh and make you know tell mom jokes and
they don't
and I'm like dude you know that's you
know you're an idiot this is not not
acceptable but I think as far as like
you know like yeah as far as like just
like fun-loving stuff I mean and this is
this is you know everything's different
now there's all these people coming in
and they're up tied in they're different
people but back in the day it was like
if somebody smokes weed and they grow
weed you know they're kind of a smartass
you know they're kind of a joker and all
of us who are a little more old-school
we can recognize each other and go yeah
that dude that dude right there he's
full of [__] you know that's why you
know he's funny because he's he's being
funny he's not you know it's just it's
just I don't know and there's different
levels to two peoples banter and
different stuff like that and you know I
feel like a lot of people just they just
basically bully people and they're jerks
and they you know people don't know that
it's not serious and you know it's just
out of context and style so it's like
it's got a you know it's got a kind of
you got to kind of have a context I
don't mess with anybody who I don't know
like honestly I you know I I know human
nature well enough to be like no I'm not
gonna I'm not gonna mess with people who
I don't know they have to know I'm
messing with them and you know otherwise
it's dangerous and it can be cruel and
it just kind of not staying in your own
lane you know like talking to you know
I'm from the counterculture man like you
talk about people that's like you know
that's not cool that's like snitching
Kiko so for me I'm not into you know I'm
not into being a jerk like that but yeah
like you said like I'm a little trollee
but you know I'm trolling my friends man
i troll roundtable selections i troll
you know i I just
then we say troll and now it used to
just be called [__] with people
you're just messing around you're having
fun you know and uh and that's what I do
and I think that that needs to be like
something that hangs around as far as
people being able to laugh at themselves
being able to laugh at stuff that's
going on laugh at situations laugh at
idea
you know I'm not really trying to laugh
at people I'm trying to laugh at myself
I'm trying to laugh at the joke you know
and um and I think that goes hand in
hand with weed weed is funny man weed
makes you giggle it makes you laugh
people look funny when they're high you
know people get high and they look like
you know you might have a buddy who gets
high and he looks like a tired giraffe
or something you know you're just like
man this is you know it I think it goes
together with the whole thing and I
think if that kind of gets lost and it
becomes this you know I see people who
are all science and they're all
technique and they're all this and
they're all that and I'm like man do you
guys smoke this [__] or what you know
sorry
so I mean on the topic of [__] with
friends or maybe just more generally
friends we in regards to Freeborn
selections would you ever consider doing
any collaborative work and if so you
know who are the kind of friends you
love to jump on board with man yeah I
mean that's like a cool thing about
about doing something like that is you
know like you know like man coastal
seeds super cool I've already I've
already done round about stuff with them
Bodhi a course bodis just the nicest guy
just super cool dude let me see coastal
Bodhi you know coastal being bamboo mr.
Bob
Hannibal CAG you those guys they're just
they're really kind of on to like the
whole they understand weed you know and
you know like let me see I you know this
every time people get into lists it's
like oh I'm gonna leave people out Chris
at AG the real OG Cushman at source
genetics you know Kingston at verified
genetics are at roundtable selections
and I just I know I'm gonna leave out
half of everybody but like these are
people who I already kind of work with
you know like I've already people have
already worked with stuff dying breeds
is already what dying breed has already
worked with stuff emerald mountain I'm
sorry if you get a flood of inbox
messages from your friends who are angry
they're gonna be like man you didn't
give me a shoutout you know like I'm
just trying to think of stuff I have
going like what do I got going right now
like a good buddy yeah of course man
arts hella cool and like unknown prophet
who else you know man I did I'm trying
to think of like what I'm growing now
that I'm actually probably gonna wind up
making something with that I can just
hit him up with oh hey dude we said you
know you want to do something with this
so there's a good we know say the least
I guess yeah it's a good list I mean I
man I really like the people who I like
the people who go back a little ways I
like the people who are really into it
you can kind of talk to people and know
that they're into it not for the scene
but because they're into the plant you
know any anybody man who's really into
weed who's who's who's chill and who's a
smartass or whatever you know just like
man I know there's a bunch I should I
should I should have been probably on my
phone looking at stuff right now so I
could tell you but yeah I mean you know
I do some work like with Kevin Joe jury
up there he he pops stuff for me he
hooks me up with clones I've done some
stuff with him there's a lot of going on
because that's my that's my brain
hitting the hitting a wall with all of
it it's super super slick man this is
lick talker but yeah man basically like
you know just just just anybody who's
really into doing stuff and you know
most of the people who I named it's not
because
there's a lot of people who I'd like to
work with who I don't name the people
who I did name are people who we've
already done something with or they gave
me some stock and said I could work with
it or I gave them some stock and said
that they could work with it and maybe
they've already made some crosses I've
already made some crosses and so that
you know that's that's the people kind
of that I mentioned it's less people who
I'd want to work with and more people
who I already do work with you know so
as far as people you know who I'd want
to work of course there's there's a
bunch of them and like I you know
Brothers Grimm man they're super cool
people geez just you know there's
there's all kinds of guys actually um
Duke diamond he gave me some really cool
seeds and I'm looking forward to doing
something with those next year I'll
probably pop all of those that's like a
super generous dude who when I asked him
yeah can I get a pack of this he's like
well how many would you plant you know
I'm like man I don't know probably only
like you know thirty five at a time or
something and he's like oh cool I'll
give you like 50 or 75 you know so you
can go through him and I was like [__]
okay right on you know like Bodie man I
I met Bodie maybe for five minutes and
the next time I saw him he had a gift
for me for Christmas you know like
they're just there's some people you
know bamboo man super nice guy you know
calves up there he always hooks me up
with stuff he's always looks out for me
you know all the art you know they're
they're always it's just people who
we're all kind of looking out for each
other we're trying to see each other do
better and we all kind of know where
we're coming from because in the past
everybody was kind of in a certain
regard as far as like society we're all
kind of like you know on the outskirts
like deemed by society is kind of like
being looser potheads you know and now
all of a sudden people are like oh no
you guys are the top you guys are the
best
you guys are good at this I'm like all
right cool you know that's great I'm
glad it can turn into something since I
heard he spent my whole life doing it
but um but you know you can kind of you
meet those people in you and you know
you know that they're that they've been
around and they've done stuff you know
meena swamp boys those guys are cool
like I've still never met him but you
know I you know we troll each other
lightly and like I said you can just
tell like people have been around their
smart asses we're all kind of on a on a
little level we're all totally different
you know what I mean none of us are
really you know that's the thing is
that's what's the same about us is we're
all hella different so yeah man anybody
who's really into doing stuff for the
plants sake for itself and not just to
not just to come up and look hype you
know so yeah sure and so I'm interested
you know given your kind of you know
closeness I'll put it as with Frenchie
through howl aficionado has that
influence any of your breeding like has
he ever mentioned anything or have you
ever tried to maybe create something
that was more well suited for kind of
you know these really high-quality hash
production methods and if so what type
of things would you be looking to do if
you were trying to pursue that well
that's kind of an interesting one I mean
Frenchie's cool in that you know he'll
take something and he'll make it and you
know he might make a few different
things at once and you get to kind of
see okay well this comes out like this
and this comes out like that you know I
was making hash for a long time and then
as soon as I started seeing people
really do it a lot I kind of got bored
with it as soon as I saw people get this
really really crazy high grade hash I
was like well I was just waiting to see
that and they already did it so I kind
of just stopped doing it and so I really
like to give stuff to people who do take
the time to do that because to me that's
like a whole other aspect that's kind of
like going all into that where you know
for me it was you know I used to make
hash I used to make dry hash I used to
make water hash and you know I've been
able to go now and go okay you know
Frenchie here's some of this uni and he
makes it up and it's like okay wow look
at the difference in texture on this
it's not that what's gonna happen okay
this stuff is like liquid this is water
hash but it's like liquid or give
something to somebody who makes
who makes um butane extracts you know
and go okay that does that look at how
much terpenes is in this this is
ridiculous it gives you a little insight
into genetics and as far as like
steering the breeding what's really cool
is that
I've always bred really for the smoke
and when you're breeding for the smoke
coincidentally you're breeding for the
extract because a plant that doesn't
smoke well doesn't typically extract
well although I'm sure there's
exceptions to it because some plants
don't smoke well because they have a
tiny amount of resin and once you
extract it the resin might actually be
exceptional but for me it's been cool
with seeing some stuff that Frenchy does
where you know he makes it and I'm like
wow this stuff just turns into straight
liquid or well this stuff sugars out
really crazy and um you know then you
know Frenchie's Frenchie's old school
dude like you know French cheese from
like the generation of people who taught
me about weed and so they're in two
different things he's in the dark
pressed hash and I was making dark
pressed hash when I met him he's into um
you know he's into he's you know he's
different man he's not number one he's
older number two he's European and that
comes down to you know some different
there's different mindsets he's looking
at different stuff than other people are
looking at and then and number three
he's Frenchie man he's [__] character
French is hilarious dude like uh he's
just like you know the he's just uh he's
Frenchie man he's is a trip you know
he's got a lot of charisma yeah yeah all
righty and so how do you feel about the
topic of tobacco and cannabis being
mixed together it's something we very
very briefly touched on with Bowie but
there's something I want to get into
more because I feel like as times gone
by and there's been an increasing focus
on the flavor and the terpenes of modern
cannabis
I feel like tobacco's slowly crept out
because it's almost like it's a lot of
people would argue that it can do
from some of the natural flavors and so
given there was that focus on flavor its
usage kind of fell off a bit do you feel
that's the case and do you feel like it
is an overall negative or maybe it has
like its place in the world of cannabis
well this is a this is a trippy one for
me it's kind of uh it's kind of a
slippery slope because for years alright
I never smoked I never smoked tobacco
I'm not a tobacco smoker I didn't like
you know some people are like oh I'm 15
I'm smoking cigarettes you know I didn't
ever smoke cigarettes my mom smoked a
little when I was a kid I hated the
smell I was never into it and then uh
you know I think maybe we had a we got a
friend and he in his dad is I think
Spanish I'm not sure man he had one of
these accents where he lives in like
three countries in Europe so you can't
really pin down his accent really well
he's like Italian Spanish and something
else you know and he was like one of
these kind of one of these old-school
hardcore dudes he was he was a he was an
outlaw you know and he would he would we
saw him when we were smoking when I was
like 15 or something you know 14 and we
were really getting smoking we saw that
over there at their house they would
smoke with tobacco so we never really we
never really did it and then you know I
was I was a dude who you know like I
took mushrooms for the first time man
when I was like 12 years old at school
you know what I mean
so like I'm like I was like a cosmonaut
at one point you know so basically one
time my buddy
c-money he goes hey let's roll one up
like let's roll it up like those guys
down there he goes I'm gonna take a
little bit of tobacco and a little bit
of weed and then we're gonna put a
little bit of hash and a little bit of
quiche in there and man we lit it up and
I think we each maybe took like four
hits and we were so
gone we couldn't believe it because we
had never experienced nicotine before
and when you're not a nicotine user it's
a really really intense drug it's one of
the strongest drugs there as it gives
you a really heavy heavy rush in the
face and it makes your feet feel light
you kind of feel like a spaceman and it
was really neat and then I think it was
all the way maybe two or three years
later one of my closest friends man a
guy named Louis he was uh he was like aw
let's smoke this I got this I got this
Jamaican tobacco it's called front toe
you know and I was like oh yeah and he
goes yeah you know you put it in a bong
a little bit with some weed man it gets
you super high you know like it's like
nitrous or something and I was like oh
okay crazy and so I was like alright and
so I tried it and I couldn't believe it
I was like oh my god this is like smoke
this is like smoking that tobacco but
this is way more intense you know and so
um you know that was my kind of my
experience with it but I was always anti
tobacco like I said I like to smile I
don't like the fact that you know I knew
a lot of smokers who got cancer and you
know like not to blend not to say was
definitely tobacco but of course there's
smokiness you know big tobacco products
that aren't probably even in anywhere
near as good for you considering there's
like 800 additives a lot different than
smoking a plant that's growing in the
ground you know and so then I think it
was maybe about 2006 you know I'm
hanging out with moniece and every he's
always smoking blent we call him Oh
blend you know blend blend he smoking
blends you know so he's rolling these
big Bob Marley cones all the time and uh
so I'm always like man roll up roll up
roll up a ital roll up one would note
aback oh just roll one with weed roll on
the feet he's like nah man I want to
smoke a blend so I'm like alright so
after a while I'm like man screw it let
me hit the blend so I start hitting the
blend and after a while I like get this
real like
you know just like and hard to describe
like just this feeling of like
well-being and not the edge that the
heavy weed would give me where I'd get a
little bit of like unexplainable
paranoia a little bit you know and so
after a while I see yeah I started I
started smoking man I started smoking
blimps and so from 2007 maybe until
probably 2000 G's 2007 - maybe 2010 or
something I smoked blends and what was
interesting was I was breeding at the
time and I don't want it you know I
don't I don't condone smoking tobacco in
any way anybody who's listening to it
you know that's why I said it's a
slippery slope
but here's the deal there's very few
strains that the terpene profile can cut
through tobacco and there's very few
strains that when you are a nicotine
user will boost the effect of the
nicotine to a point of giving you a
really heavy head rush even when you
smoke tobacco fairly often and those
strains are the really heavy duty ones
that are the very best weed and so if
you have a plant and you're a blend
smoker and it's good in a blend you know
it's the best weed you know and I I
don't you know it's a it's one of those
weird things it's like you know it's
like you know like a badass jazz dude
like bird who shoots heroin telling you
not to do heroin you know like it's like
it's not that it's not the tobacco that
helps you breed but you know I can't
really say that it didn't um then it
didn't help me to develop a couple of
strains you know black lime and root
beer were the two strains that no matter
what you could always put him in a blend
and they would launch you straight to
the moon every time and then you try
some other stuff and it just didn't work
you know it's just like they're the ones
that really work that way so for me I
can say you know if anybody is gonna
smoke tobacco
smoked any of that big tobacco stuff
smoke smoke a grow a plant learn how to
try it you know I used to smoke I know
it's big tobacco too still you know but
me and moniece would smoke American
spirit and at least it doesn't have the
additives and it's probably still pretty
nasty just from how they grow it but um
you know it's a plant man it's it's you
know I think it's really got a bad rap
because people use it wrong I talked to
my doctor about how I was smoking blends
and he was like yeah you know that's not
really a tobacco user who usually falls
under the statistics of people who are
gonna be really unhealthy for it they're
smoking a lot more tobacco than you're
talking about right now you know and I
was like okay and you know I just wound
up quitting because um I can tell you it
is hard on your lungs but my lungs do
feel like they felt before I ever smoked
tobacco you know they do feel like
they've come back to being totally
normal again but you know I couldn't
breathe as well I didn't do as good like
trying to run away in the woods or
anything like I was smoking changing to
tobacco so you know it is dangerous and
it is harmful but um that doesn't mean
that it's dangerous or harmful to take a
puff of it here there or you know
whatever so it's an interesting thing it
definitely it's definitely a trippy
subject and you know they're there man
there's tobacco I got this tobacco I got
this tobacco back in the day uh uh and
this guy gave it to me and he said oh do
you blend and I said you know yeah and
he goes I'll just put a little of this
in there and I took it home and and I
put in the bong and I smoked it in the
bong and what happened was I woke up you
know 45 seconds later on the ground
asking for a towel laughing and crying
because you know I had snot coming out
my nose and I had drool running down my
face and I was laying on the carpet like
I was doing snow angels and
you know I couldn't I couldn't believe
it and that what that was that was the
that was that um you know the old stuff
that was the Rustica and that's the
original thick leaf Indian tobacco
that's that's um you know basically for
for a medicine man to smoke you know or
kind of what they really what they would
smoke when you see people smoking you
know and a peace pipe and stuff it's
this thick hardcore tobacco um it's like
if tobacco's like paper it's almost like
cardboard and when when you smoke that
that's not like smoking a cigarette and
that's like that's like you know but
it's like something you'd see in a movie
somebody you know looked like somebody
must have blew ayahuasca up my nose or
something
yeah well oh god it was yeah that's
crazy so anyway that's my experience
with with some tobacco if people are
smoking it now every once in a while I
might smoke a little bit I didn't quit
in the way that I went I'm quitting I
just went I just quit in the way that I
just didn't smoke it anymore you know I
never got smoking it with weed I feel
like I didn't get addicted like other
people got addicted to it I don't know
if there's something to that or not I'm
really strong-willed so I was able to
just smoke tobacco every day all day for
years and then just quit in the day I
cold turkey and I I did that a couple
times I started smoking again after
another year or whatever and then I just
quit again cold turkey you know so yeah
well no I'm sure a lot of people wish
they could do that yeah for sure but I
think a lot of it you know I was talking
to to an old school friend of mine and
he said you know he used to smoke um he
used to smoke some big-name
tobacco back in the day and when he
would quit he would get terrible
headaches and he would feel really bad
and then he started smoking American
spirit and he smoked just as much and
then when he would quit he wouldn't get
the headaches and he wouldn't be that
bad to quit and he associated it with
the additives and he believes that the
gives our more addictive than the actual
nicotine so yeah the anecdotal evidence
but he felt that way so no I think
that's very much very much true because
a lot of people I know who have tried to
use the nicotine type vape pen say it's
nowhere near as gratifying as an actual
an actual cigarette and that should
automatically show that yeah like a lot
of the other chemicals Plus also there's
studies that show that like organically
grown tobacco like non big stuff it the
the chance of it giving you cancer is
greatly diminish because all the
additives are far more carcinogenic than
the actual tobacco plant itself yeah I
mean I can believe it you know I spend
and we know there's a lot of those
additives and we know that those
additives are related to addiction and
and health problems and and and most of
the studies done on tobacco are done on
they're done on that tobacco they're not
done on on pure tobacco so it's really
hard to pin down what is really the
problem I I can tell you for sure that
smoking my own tobacco that I grow it's
still really bad for your lungs and it's
still really hard on your respiratory
system and everything but um but you
know I feel like there's um I feel like
you know it's it's definitely a step up
from smoking all that other nasty stuff
they put in there yeah without a doubt
and so I mean you please just to take a
step back and take a more macro view of
the whole scene I've heard a few people
describe breeding in general as falling
into kind of two categories at the
moment we've kind of got you know you
new school breeders who are you know
running with you know at your dose Eidos
and your Girl Scout cookies and all that
type of stuff and and that's got its own
merit and then you've got the other camp
which is more looking to delve into the
older work preservation work landrace
we're just working in that general
direction do you think this trend will
continue and if so do you think the
divide will get bigger between the two
schools because already I can see that
it seems to be becoming more and more
present like more breeders become
becoming more kind of known for working
with that old school stuff
less for working with the new school
stuff and vice-versa for their
counterparts yeah it's an interesting
thing man I think that um that they both
have their place I think that the kind
of the new school mindset is what it
kind of takes things in that bottleneck
direction of things being narrowed down
to these things that everyone can kind
of agree are you know good in the market
the bag appeal the general like it's a
crowd pleaser kind of effect but then
you know I think it's very very
important for people to keep those old
genetics around because that's where
everything came from and people tend to
think of that in a vague sense like you
know while Girl Scout cookies you know
40 years ago you know there was things
that turned into other things that
turned into these things that turned
into cookies but like when I smell
cookies it's like I said it's it's an
Afghani to me and it has a little
something else so if you love cookies
you might be able to go grab a landrace
[__] or a landrace a fee and go okay
well here's that same thing and it turns
out it didn't take a whole lot of work
to arrive at this place where this stuff
is here so people think of like landrace
and heirloom and old school as being
like this far-off thing from our
modern-day weed and in reality you can
take a lot of those old seeds I'm sure
you could go back and get seeds in 1900
or 1850 and you know if you still had
those and they were viable are you at a
time machine or whatever you could pop
them now and you'd go whoa look it's the
next og or it's the next whatever like
I've never really been sold on this
whole concept of people doing these
crazy hybrids that all of a sudden give
you these new things that were unheard
of in the past I think that the old
genetics
have them right there just either just
under the surface or just right there
and the same population it's just that
nobody grows anything man everybody
grows the same things so they're
thinking like okay well I'm gonna use
this because it's the hot thing and not
going back and going well hey dude did
you ever think that's why I'm excited to
see like what Bodhi is doing right now
and coastal because they're going back
into the old stuff to make new stuff
that you know I think I think in the
long term you know is gonna wind up
being there's gonna be some stuff that
comes out of there that's the new stuff
you know because there's no one else
doing it otherwise it's just basically
regurgitating other people's work as
it's like you know people make a cookies
cross and they're like look how resinous
it is I'm like wasn't cookies residence
though like did anything new happen here
are we just kind of doing this
everybody's doing the same thing it's
like it's like music you know and
everyone's doing down by the boardwalk
and it's just down by the boardwalk like
yeah it's old records but isn't this
just down by the boardwalk you know what
I mean
so III respect it both but I really
think that the modern guys really need
to understand what the modern stuff is
it's just a good clone or a good cross
of something people have and I really
want to see people dig in and find all
the old stuff before it just doesn't
exist anymore you know yeah so I mean
with that in mind what old-school gems
have you got in the works first I mean
cuz you're known as someone who has you
know from time to time delved into their
bag of goodies and I mean Bodi even
hinted at it saying that he likes he
likes all the old stuff you pull out
anything on the horizon you may be
thinking about popping maybe some new
schools some old school stuff gonna be
coming back you know I got a really
really neat collection of stuff that I
totally did not understand how neat it
was because at the time it was just like
these crosses of stuff people had given
me and I was like well I made the cross
but I'll just get back to Pier 1 and
then I didn't store him right because I
didn't want to grow them nobody wanted
to grow them and then um you know I just
I knew like I know how to store seeds I
knew that I should and and I was just
like oh yeah whatever this is I
basically thought my stuff was trash
because I was seeing other stuff or the
stuff that it had come from that was you
know either more consistent or more
marketable or whatever it was and then
just the thing of mmm when things are
too close to you it's hard to see them
it's hard to see the big picture like
you're used to it this is the you know
like I tell everybody whatever you smoke
all the time that's the Reggie that's
Rex you know like if you have it then
you're gonna think it's Rex people who
only grow OG or like some of them still
like it but a lot of them are like I
kind of want to try something new
because this is just oh gee now and when
they first got it it was like oh my god
I got OG and now they're like you know
gee ok same old flavor so for me that's
how it was with the seeds that I had and
then it would be like oh this one's
prone to PM or this one likes to mold or
this one doesn't get tall enough and
then you make the hybrids and hybrids
better so you don't plant the old seeds
and so man I got some seeds that
basically are still viable because I'm
not saying I like store them in the
Attic in the heat they came up for 10
years but then all of a sudden I hit
like 12 years and they wouldn't come up
anymore they sprout a tail but they
won't come out of the dirt and so I
basically need to link up with somebody
who and I have a couple leads right now
who can do the tissue culture where they
either do the seeds and test-tubes with
the plant version of antibiotics that
prevent everything from attacking the
seeds and and forming bacterial colonies
and stuff while they're trying to sprout
and that give them a little extra
carbohydrates to replenish their
they're their stores and hormones to
really make them want to grow faster so
that they can really get out and then
there's another way you can do it where
you can actually cut the seat open get
inside the germ get viable cells and
grow them out as a callus in a petri
dish and then you can add hormones to
make those effectively become basically
like seeds or you can also encase the
cells through a process where you make
like artificial seeds and that's another
way to bring stuff back it does exist it
is practical it's been used for other
stuff I just have to find the right way
to do it and man I have some really neat
stuff I have the original f1 Paula
Nations that were the original black
line I have I have the old dirt purp
mark that I made you know stuff from 99
2000 2001 I have all this old stuff and
I have like a thousand of each and they
they're totally they're totally viable
I'm just afraid to risk losing losing
genetics out of them by trying to pop a
bunch only to get a few when I know that
in a laboratory they can come back so
that's one aspect of it the other aspect
of it is that I've been asking around to
four people and saying hey you know what
do you guys got who's got old seeds
still and there are some people and some
people don't want to part with them some
people don't want to share them even
though they have plenty and you know all
those I totally understand how when
people are where people are coming from
on stuff but like recently I scored this
one I don't know if you saw the post
that was the santa marta indica red vein
did you see those little plants yeah I
think I did I'm actually looking at them
now okay so so those ones there are a
really special one I you know I'm
talking to the guy and he's like yeah
1977 or 78 I get the santa marta cold
and i'm growing that and i in 1980 i go
to the bar and these guys smoke the best
joint i've ever tasted with me and
they're they're like he's like what is
that and they're like oh it's called
indica and then they give him like five
seeds and he crosses that one
the Santa Marta then you know a few
years five years later six years later
something he puts in the stuff that's
like what I call the perp that he called
the red veined because the stalks get
really red it's like you know you see it
like in DJ shorts blueberry except
instead of like instead of the purple of
it it's like red it's I think it's
different than what I call pert but it's
that same look of the where the stems
have color instead of being green and I
think it's what's in my black lime
honestly because it came from the same
area and it's really interesting because
there's these all these old things you
get and people tell you the story but
they only have the story they have you
know like I can't say without a doubt
that everything is only what is in it I
just know those things are in it for
sure you know because back in the day
it's like oh this is so-and-so stuff and
then you ask him what it is and he goes
no it's Afghani and you talked to him
years later and he goes oh no it's
Afghani and Burmese the Northern Lights
and you go oh okay it just behaves like
an Afghani so he called it an Afghani so
I know what it was cuz he thought I'm
just gonna grow them and grow dope you
know people don't know you have interest
in it so there's all these old things
that are like that and so that's what
I'm trying to track back down you know
but that's true that particular strain
you know he's like yeah test at 25
percent THC he goes I call it lemon Kush
I'm like there's other people who have
stuff called lemon cuz she's like well
name it for me man and then people will
know what it is and I'm like dude you
know I'm on social media I'm able to
show people stuff you know it's I know
it's gonna be the bomb because this guy
is he's this old school dude who's like
an old school you know rock star party
animal badass dude from the area and you
know he's I don't know how old he is I
don't want to date a mess being older
than his but you know he's like my mom
he's like 60 or something you know maybe
older maybe a little younger but he he
was a you know he was around growing
dope to get seeds in the 70s and he
didn't ever go he didn't ever do what I
did with a lot of my stuff and go oh I'm
gonna cross this with OG or I'm gonna
cross this with diesel or I'm gonna
cross
with our coal or I'm gonna cross this
with whatever these clones are that came
floating around that everyone wanted you
know you try to make things be happening
for the time for the market for the
people who want to grow the seeds and
and be able to go and be able to have a
reference you know like people want to
be able to tell people oh it's an OG
cross ok cool now they now people know
what to make of it when they show it to
them so it's old peer stuff I mean it's
not pure of course it's still a
three-way cross but it's a three-way
cross of strains that were around in the
70s and the early 80s and he's never
changed it and it's still tests at 25
percent THC and it's super resilient and
it gets huge yields and the weeds of
[__] you smell the stem it smells like
gummy worms and now it's starting to
develop into like a lemon-peel smell not
like a not like a lemony like what
people call lemon and we generally but
like real lemon peel and it's exciting
to see when they were tiny little tiny
little sprouts they had more resin than
anything else in the greenhouse out of a
whole you know like five big tables full
of six inch pots so it's dead that's an
exciting one that's something that I'm
doing something with and I asked him I'm
like dude do you know do I need to like
keep this tight or what he's on nah dude
blow it up popularize it put it out
there and you know so um I yeah so
that's one of those ones and then so you
know I've been trying to find things
that are like that and then you know for
me like a lot of my stuff it's just
worked poly hybrids so I made these poly
hybrids and then I bred them in
directions and now they're real strains
like they could have been there like
something you could have got from
someone back in the day that was a real
strain you know but as far as a lot of
the stuff that went into them it's not
you know it's not viable and so now
these these new true breeding hybrids
that I have they're like you know that's
where all this stuff is and honestly I
like the new ones better than the old
ones it's just I value the old ones
because they had other ways I could have
gone with them
yeah that's good well I think this
brings us to the last little bit where
we just got a few little quickfire
questions shall we blast through sure
Matt so first one what's your favorite
strain of all time ah man
I really liked this old-school stuff
that we thought was garlic but I don't
know if it was or not came through the
hog farm in the mid 90s it was
incredible it was just the most amazing
like definition of a broadleaf Afghani
the weed was completely solid white it
was purple on the very inside the bud
actually was mostly like colorless
because it was so dense that light
didn't get in through the outside of the
bud after like a couple weeks in I never
got to grow it that was incredible
grymps grapes was incredible pissy
pungent favorito probably to this days
we're not right up there with my
favorites as far as something that like
this is still around like what like
what's my favorite smoke what's my you
know like yeah if I had to only have one
thing probably something out of the
black line the black line is for me
that's like just I don't know it's when
I smoke a lot that's what I want to
smoke black line you know so it's uh so
what's one strain that you used to have
but you've lost and you wish you could
get it back ah let me see like a seed
strain yeah I really liked the black
Afghani that I had that was really neat
I still have a bunch of the seeds they
just don't quite come up and that was a
neat one that I lost that I really
condemn like darn it I lost it and then
man the old my old Northern Lights clone
as far as a clone you thought was that
was really one that I just am bummed
about
yeah for sure all right here Tito you
brought up twice it must have been
special well it was it's it's a lot of
what the black line is is not cloned
okay yeah yeah so if you were just to
grow up and you could only have one pack
of seeds it's kind of
on the market which one pack would you
go with one pack of seeds jeez man
you know I haven't grown a lot of people
seeds I know there's a lot of people
seeds who I might you know if I had that
if I had their stuff I might throw mine
away and I you know I haven't done a lot
of them and out of everything I've seen
I still I mean I'd have to say probably
like you know oh my lime one clone with
with something from it so just lime
cross lime but as far as like from other
breeders dude I just don't I don't have
much reference I haven't grown a lot of
stuff from people and so it's kind of a
loaded question and that I'm gonna say
something from me because I'm so I'm
just not that experienced with seed
packs you know yeah no I understand
that's so good I'm sure I'm sure many
people would have picked you alarm cross
as well next one if you could go back to
one place in history and time to collect
see so what would they be and where man
for me I think I'd probably have to say
like go back like probably to like the
50s and then go in the Hindu Kush region
and you know collect collect everything
there that was like what I know what I
saw here when I was growing up I know
that's the genetics you know it was
basically the Afghani before it got
before I got messed around with by
outside stuff and yeah okay you know
yeah back before anybody really brought
anything over yeah and so final question
which person or groups do you hold kind
of in the highest regard for the overall
progression of cannabis throughout time
you know man
hippies for sure I gotta put hippies up
there because that's where you know a
lot of stuff happened in that part of
the counterculture coming from the you
know the 60s and the 70s and all those
people going through the 80s and the 90s
and all that but you know other than
that I'd say you know like um I really
think there's not enough value placed on
a lot of what people think of as
landrace in a lot of cases is from
places where the weed doesn't have to be
tended very much so people don't really
know that people are are influencing it
I think in places like Afghanistan and
Thailand and India and Africa I think
there was a lot of people who were
actually making selections in the field
and choosing which seeds got planted
over others and cutting plants they
didn't like and I think that I think a
lot of the land race stuff was actually
being bred in a sense although you know
it's a land race cuz it's wild but I
think a lot of times it's it's wild
because people don't have to grow it but
they're still influencing the genetic
drift so you know basically the hippies
and all the you know those those are
those you know kind of counterculture
people and you know not to get too
specific basically just to kind of say
yeah just like people who were like yeah
we're gonna smoke dope and hang out and
have a good time and enjoy life and
nature and the mountains and you know
and then those early people who kind of
get left out of the story like people
are like oh it was just good though good
weed was just good in Afghanistan it was
just good in Thailand
I think people influence that you know
how to keep it from being hemp so I
think those you know those ain't more
ancient and traditional people and then
these more modern back
to the earth types who moved up into the
hills and Santa Cruz and the Sierras and
Humboldt and Trinity and Mendo and stuff
you know I think they kind of they
shaped how everything is now you know
dead heads and hippies yeah all these
guys we don't have dead heads especially
I think but yeah so yeah for sure man
yeah so thanks so much for coming on the
show for dropping all that knowledge did
you have any comments or shoutouts you
wanted to make you know I am man we went
through so much material right now I
feel like I feel like we touched on a
lot of stuff and you know it's the same
like you know I can give shout outs
right now but of course I'm going to
space out a whole bunch of people and so
probably better just everyone just shout
out everybody you know everybody that um
everybody that uh you know is is
interested in weed and you know all my
all my my old school friends and my new
friends and my family and you know my
sons and my kids and my lady and yeah
everybody yeah awesome so again thanks
so much for coming on the show yeah
thank you Matt thanks for having me on
it's awesome to be part of do
a huge thank you again to Jean for
coming on the show taking the time to
talk to us as well as 420 Australia and
OGS and help make this show happen if
you guys haven't checked out the patreon
yet there's tons of extra content of
their I highly recommend you look at it
guys thinking about possibly increasing
the length of time that content stays
paid from early because frankly on
reward the guys which have been for the
show you know that the response has been
overwhelming and I am actually gonna
make more content for dishes that I
would so get on board and enjoy all the
good
[Music]
[Applause]