[Music]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis show for body
enthusiasts this episode was brought to
you by 420 Australia the Billy shop
organic gardening solutions and all
things people on this episode we're
joined by the man P bud to talk all
things camden so get comfy and enjoy all
righty so big welcome and thank you for
Peapod coming on the show today and for
anyone who hasn't seen the earlier
episodes pay bud and joy brand with the
two guys who sold the weed mass G at The
Grateful Dead show which then went on to
give birth to the camp dog strains but
with all that being said my first
question is how did you meet drover in I
met Joe B at Western State College in
Gunnison Colorado in 1987 I clawed to a
few schools out in Colorado with the
only one I got into aka wasted state my
parents were real proud but this great
school I had a really fun time there and
I met him in the cafeteria I was just
going to get something to eat I didn't
really know anyone there and I saw him
sitting in a table with a couple other
of his friends that he came out from New
Jersey with and they had tie-dye
t-shirts on Grateful Dead t-shirts so it
kind of journey over there and just went
over then just started talking to him
and we've been friends ever since and so
it was a John who got you into the
Grateful Dead / you were a until the
fold on I was already into it he was
already into it we both got into it in
high school I probably got into it my
freshman year in high school my brother
was a big deadhead and
we lived I grew up in Connecticut so
there were a lot of shows right around
right around us within 2-3 hours many
places they used to play so I got to see
many many shows in high school so I was
a pretty big deadhead by the time I got
out to Western State okay awesome and so
before we get to that infamous show what
type of we were you guys smoking growing
up in Connecticut notes were lived about
an hour outside New York City so we've
got a lot of like strains from other
countries like Vietnam and you know
Afghan bud and a lot of like taught real
Thai stick just a lot of different
different flavors that are smoking in
high school we got out to western state
the infamous P bud we found started
smoking that which is outdoor strain in
in Colorado a huge like forearm size
call us or you get like a pound just
folds little popcorn buds that were just
lime green and piney tasting and yeah
just really beautiful beautiful looking
pot awesome and so was this something
that was around when you had access to
the dog but Oh was it a full after that
it was before the before the dog but
enduring but you know I moved there in
87 and the Peapod was around for since
at least the early eighties I would
think my friend Rob would know a lot
more about that than me but it was
definitely before the dog bud yeah okay
so you know just kind of segue into the
dog bud what was that like for you guys
because you guys I think if what I read
was correct was the
had access to that for a wall before you
know that fateful encounter at D Creek
we are actually not like it was so long
ago so I've talked to Joe and other
people and got like the real just a
pound and a half came into Crested Butte
the summer of 91 and Jo Brand bought it
I think he bought a pound of it or all
of it guy approached him and because he
knew he Joe and would you know had money
and yeah could get rid of it you know he
was kind of the Peapod man too so Joe
bought it you know he bought bought it
all and I think and so and we're going
on tour I'm not sure in like a couple
weeks or something so it was kind of you
know perfect and you know we're we kind
of took it he took it all on dead tour
which kind of pissed off a lot of people
in town because they couldn't they
couldn't get it but it was just
absolutely amazing we had never seen
anything smell anything like it before
we're smoking a lot of people were
smoking some indoor hash plant which is
called the pox scaly hash plant a puck
which is a pretty famous lot here in
Colorado I can tell you the story on
that one too but we were smoking bad m39
big bud skunk number one some good
indoor strains but we had never seen
anything like this or smelled anything
like this before we it was called when
Joe got it what it was called dog bud
because it after you smoked it
it made you roll over like a dog that's
what
the meaning of the dog bird that I
remember it was so we we smelled it we
started calling a CEM weed because of
just the the odor off it it smelled
chemical fuel just insane terpenes as
they say today it was just amazing the
Smith the smell of it and so we started
calling a chem weed which kind of just
as a joke so we kind of changed the name
to chem weed and and then brought it not
sure exactly how much we brought on tour
but uh probably close to a pound on dead
tour and so um these are kind of the
days leading up tonight's show am I
correct
yep weird that was summer of 91 so not
sure where the tour started but uh that
happened at I think there are two shows
in Deer Creek that happened at one of
those shows in Deer Creek I think that
was I think we were just smoking it
ourselves for the first shows and then
we we had split it up into eighths and
and just decided to bust it out at Deer
Creek and it was yeah it was amazing
because it was summertime too so like I
said before is pretty dry weed in that
in that in the summer on dead tourists
though there were a lot of lucky people
in that parking lot that death and so
when G mass G came up to you guys was it
you know just just any old moment for
you or did you have some inkling ly you
know like a skunk VA mentions when he
was a first approached with the guy who
would give him the candle like he knew
that it was you know as the guy walked
towards him he knew it was an important
contact you know did you feel the same
way about mask G or it was just kind of
an every since case it was just kind of
a well he was more friendly because
is so long ago but uh we we just started
selling it at our cat Joe's car at you
know that Joe Subaru I remember green
Subaru and we started to just say kind
bud and one guy came up and he was just
like holy [ __ ] look at this stuff and he
ran off and brought up to people and
they ran off and brought up two people
we had like a line at our car to buy 8th
and G mask GE was one of them I think he
bought one or two and came back and
bought some more put him and joe
exchanged numbers of the show there and
and then that's how they they stayed in
contacts them cell phones back then
souls more just you know on a piece of
paper and I'll call you when I get back
to let me get back all say did you um
were you aware of the kind of the
exchange that took place after that when
you guys got back and then Joe sent him
the stuff in the mail or you weren't
fully aware of fun I know I think he
said I'm some P but first and then send
him to dog but and I'm sure we're all I
got old send it to him you know very
glad he did but you know because that
was that was it there was he never saw
it again the dog blood I've never seen
it since so it's probably a little like
don't send it to him but uh I think he
said him two ounces and I had never seen
a seed in any of the stuff that I smoked
or anything if I did I I didn't save it
for sure but uh you know one of those
some of those buds receded so and Greg
fell and one of the ounces I guess I
think Joe sent two ounces and one of the
ounces he found the thirteen seeds so
when he found those seeds did he mention
to you that he found them straight away
or was it more of just on the back
thing you know what no cell phones back
then so we could kind of just lost touch
with last year for years I didn't keep
in touch with them at all
and Joe probably did a little bit but
then you know just fell out it so out of
touch with them so yeah he can you know
mask gee if you can get him on he can
definitely take it the story from there
finding the seeds and all that stuff we
didn't really get back in touch with him
until you know oh five something like
that 2005 from just on the internet and
seeing the Sour Diesel bud and from
Massachusetts and so Joe kind of put two
and two together and was online for a
couple of years trying to corroborate
this story of meeting mass G and sending
them that and it being the dog bud and
and then I was back east and got a bag
of a Sour Diesel I'm like oh four or
something and called Joe jobra and
California was like this stuff smells
just like the dog bud and he was telling
me about this story online and finally I
guess JJ from top dog got mask G and Joe
together and and yeah from then on they
they they reconnected and G sent him Joe
you know for the remaining seats that he
had left so that's how they got back
yeah okay so I mean I got two little
questions so I mean that was the the
whole reunion thing that people talk
about exactly yeah and then the second
thought is does that mean that you know
essentially you and Joe we're just doing
your own thing for about ten years and
the chem dogs were in existence so to
speak but you weren't we didn't know
about him
no you're smoking Homer or anything so
it was nice to you know reconnect with
mass G and and those guys and and you
get those things you have those genetics
for sure so when you did kind of put the
story together slash you know at
whatever point you did believe it all
were you just like kind of surprised by
you know how many killer cuts had come
from those 13 seeds I was a little bit
overwhelming at first it's crazy how
that one strain has changed the you know
the face of the weed world for sure it's
I mean I know we know that back then I
had never seen anything better than the
dog until you know we hooked back up
with mass G and got the you know the
chem 91 and the D and you know and then
you know Gio popped the four and but
yeah I mean ii just never seen anything
like it before otherwise yeah okay
and so when you were first exposed to
all the chem dogs what was your initial
favorite I liked the 91 the best at
first maybe the admission is how in what
order were you exposed to them in order
I was exposed 90 or so we hooked back up
with mass G and I was in Connecticut and
I would meet him up at the Basketball
Hall of Fame in Springfield Mass such a
nice master he was just such a nice guy
that you know he drives you know I don't
know how long it was for him but we meet
there and he'd have this package for me
you know of just all that Kem's and so I
got exposed to the 91 D
yep see and then you know the chem cross
is what he did the bubble cam and then I
got exposed the chem sister but I liked
the 91 at first the bet the best I
thought after years it kind of got the
taste kind of faded but I've smoked some
recently the last few years from from
Duke and it's you know it's he brings
the flavor out for sure yeah it's funny
you mention that because um I mean when
I first try I was surprised by how what
you know weak or absent the flavor was
but at the same time I was also
surprised by how it was more present
than I thought it would be at the same
time I know that sounds very paradoxical
but yeah the strength still there I mean
it's still just as strong as but the D
that is you know the smell is still
there the taste is still there it just
reeks I mean I know a lot of people love
that just rotten smelling funky you know
yuck smelling my wife calls it yuck yuck
bud it just smells just nasty but a lot
of people ate I love it a lot a lot of
other people love it too and so do you
find that the D is I don't know I refer
to is like more functional than the 91
or do you think it's just still too
crippling its crippling it's close to
the 91 I think the 91 is probably the
strongest of of all of them
it's got no ceiling and you just get
higher and higher and higher
DS pretty close though yeah okay and so
I think stung mentioned that your now
favorite is the D is that the truth
yeah yeah I I that's taken over and in
the years just the smell and the taste
and but that 91 is a close close second
and so I guess my question is why do you
think that
sorry hit the D why do you think that
the D has been able to maintain those
characteristics of all the naughty ones
fade it off
it's not as old he popped that he popped
Kim D in 2000 I believe so it's 9 years
you know younger probably the you know
the biggest reason I would think okay
and so if we go back to the story /
Heather the timeline so we just jump
back to when G send Joe those further
beans obviously you were in the loop at
that point we were really excited for
what was going to come out of those
beans yeah it was great Joe Brown was in
California I think I moved out there
moved in with them shortly after he got
those and so the wood chem 1 2 3 &amp; 4 4
was you know the best Joe thought it was
it's definitely the biggest producer of
all the cams the DS you know probably
close second
and so Joe kind of picked that one out
as the best one and you know it was
generous with it and gave it to you know
a lot of people gave the one two and
three to a few people that think there's
a couple people that have the three and
maybe one or two people that have chem 1
&amp; 2 they were more from what I remember
more though G like I was big I was a big
producer smaller smaller buds but the
floor was the one that called the
reunion feet out Joe named at that and
it's it's it's everywhere and it's I
love it a lot of the people in the chem
family don't like it
it's kind of funny it's but uh it's I
like it it's it's good it's the
different smell from the rest
which I think a lot of terms a lot of
people off but I think it's it's it's
really strong for sure yeah I mean I
wasn't the biggest fan of it but um I
think it's good one that they won adam
dunk up this years I've seen something
today it was the theis like it was like
the Deaf it just not as good in taste
wise it's different it's definitely a
different taste than than the others for
sure but I think the strength is is is
right there
yeah yeah sure I think with all of the
chem notes that the strength is always
there so I've heard some rumors from
some people that the the pheno one that
you just mentioned that that may have
been the plant which went on to be that
infamous jobra a 91 would you be able to
shed new light on oh no you got any
opinions on that on the job rather could
Joe be 91 yeah I I'm not really sure
where that one came from and uh I mean I
kind of have an idea but I kind of
really don't want to want to get into
that it's no it's kind of confusing a
confusing issue I really can't really
explain okay yeah well I mean maybe it's
good though it's it's really good I know
there's people here in Denver that have
it yeah I mean there are people who
still breed with it because they think
it's that good you know obviously they
name it correctly but um but yeah I mean
one of the things I find so interesting
about it is there seems to have been so
many fake 90 ones and I don't just mean
like outright fakers in some random
person has it but as in like maybe
someone close to the chem fam or even in
the chem fam has a cut at one point and
they think it's the right one and that
it turns out it's not
and just soon so like there's so many of
the ninety one out of all the cuts you
know it was the one which there would
seem to be like the most replicas
floating around yes I would have to say
it's the hardest one to get the original
you know the real
besides the warning too but of the ones
that are out there think the 91 is
definitely the toughest one to get if
you know and I think a lot of people
have I've ruined ruined a lot of
people's day when they send me pictures
and I gotta just tell them that it's
definitely not it or it'll smoke me out
on it and I have to tell them it's not
it but yeah it's definitely I would have
to say the hardest one to get and that's
you know thank God that you know Scott
VA as as protected that thing over these
years for sure because it's a special
one just to kind of just point to bed
cuz I I don't know how but I get a lot
of messages people telling me the same
thing that they've got the real 91 I
don't know why they messaging me but I
said it's probably not it so my question
is has anyone you know like and I don't
mean to be rude to the people but like
just a random person not associated with
you really in any way has anyone ever
like sent you a photo and you were like
hey that's the real deal or is it always
like sorry bro it's pretty much always
because it's you know it's one see
people I don't know so I know who kind
of has that cut out there but most of
the time it's it's no I mean I'll see it
on the internet you know and different
you know different media web I'll see it
I'll be oh yeah that's it but uh most of
the people that send me pictures it's
not it's not it or smoke with me it's
not it yep and so what were your
thoughts on the initial cam dog hybrids
you mentioned the bubble cam I think
another one she made was the dog waltz
how did you feel about that that's JJ's
a fabulous fabulous
all the chem crosses are are great skunk
fears I see collect over skunk VA has
that uh cam Scout which is you know one
of the best crosses that I've
one of the best chem crosses I've ever
smoked chem D by I 95 is a really really
good chem cross but yeah they're they're
all good they really are if you have the
real Kim and so when you saw how good
these were as breeding stock essentially
did the thought ever cross your mind to
do a bit of breeding yourself no I've
not really been interested in breeding I
let that to my buddies but I'm always
just been straight clone and kept
mothers alive and it's kind of what I've
done preservation and never really
gotten into interested in breeding I've
always had I was a golf course
superintendent for four years and so I
always had a career and working you know
80 hours a week and so I never really
had the time growing was always just a
really part-time all growing marijuana
was always a very part-time thing for me
always did it but just part-time growing
golf courses was my full-time gig yes
okay cool how did you transition into
the job you have now which is that
incredible edibles sorry I when my son
was born he's four now I we didn't
really want to put him in daycare at
that young of age so my wife makes a lot
of money so I decided to stay on them
and take care of Bobby for the first few
years of his life and so this past year
he was old enough to go to we wanted to
get him into daycare and in nursery
school and stuff so time for me to get
back to work I worked for early cannabis
for a little bit a great company in up
in Longmont and they do CBD so I was
working in their greenhouse and managing
their
they're a garden supply store and then
wanted something a little more closer to
home and kind of put my name out there
and Derek contacted me and it was really
a company that I wanted to work for
because they just have such a good
reputation they just put out such a good
product they're there everywhere in the
state and I just wanted to work for a
good good company and things worked out
and yeah very happy and so if we were to
kind of talk a bit more about the
edibles do you find that the chem dog
strains work specifically both edibles
or not really about potency is a lot of
other factors involved in what strains
make the good attitude not we're gonna
get um we're working on getting the chem
for first in and start growing that and
doing I think it'll work better with the
live resin and the and the dabbing and
the you know the oil I think it'll make
for a fantastic I smoked some come for
oil before and it's absolutely amazing
so I think that's what we're gonna do
with the camphor yeah so I think it
works better better better for oil and
so I mean you know this may be out of
your kind of realm of scope but do you
find or ever get any feedback of the
strains that you're growing that they're
specifically good for edibles yeah
that's something I wouldn't I wouldn't
know I just are I'm just locked in that
warehouse and growing grown the plants
but I I need to get to the other parts
of the company but uh you just be
concentrating on the on the garden so
yeah that would be someone else's
incredibles you'd have to ask
what's good for you no candy bars and
yeah and that yep okay so when speaking
to skunk there was a funny moment he
described where you know he got back on
the forums and you know he was kind of
unaware of how the community perceived
him in this sense it was you know as
like you know a very well-respected
figure do you ever feel that way about
yourself like do you ever have to pinch
yourself and say like hey like I'm a bit
of a figure in the kind of a scene or do
you just not really view it that way i I
mean I I know I am but I don't really
view it that way I was just kind of just
living my life and that to me it doesn't
seem that exciting but but we get you
know we had good times dead tour and met
a lot of people and smoked a lot of weed
and saved a lot of strains and you know
so we just kind of live and living our
life that's it but it's just amazing
that what I just get blown away on but
on the on the weed that that dog bud
just created I just it amazes me that
you know masterji found those seeds and
in what became of them yes so I mean
this is an interesting point I always
think about is I think G was I think he
was 17 at the time of the concert and
maybe he was a Shane when he popped the
since but he's young and but the thing
which always stands out in my mind was
that um he was very young when he popped
those seeds and regardless if it was him
or friends close to him like you know
those clones have managed to live on
have you ever been like surprised or you
know maybe more so impressed with how
someone that young was able to kind of
hang on to things loosely for all that
time because I just think that submit
yeah it's amazing the inside he heard
that I like I said I could have we could
have had seeds you know and just
throwing them away he was one of those
guys that went around and was
in precedes and at a young age which is
you know pretty pretty impressive and to
do what he did with those seeds is is
very impressive in in my mind yeah and
so have you ever really spoken to him
about how many people he actually gave
it out to because I mean I've heard from
a lot of people and you even mentioned
it earlier yourself that gee just a
really nice guy and you know he he does
a lot for a lot of people and I've
always heard that he was never a hoarder
per se but at the same time I always
hear that you know like no one has the
real chem dog so it seems almost like
paradoxical like the guy who's got the
real one seems to give it out but no one
has it at the same time I think they
held him pretty tight in their circle
and you know I not totally sure you'd
have to ask him on that one but just
because it's just not you know it's just
not out there after 25 years you think
it would be out there a lot more but uh
yeah it's just not it's just not one of
the conclusions I thought might have
been the case was that like the people
who was giving it to they they realized
kind of the magnitude of the situation
and they decided not to give it out
because that could kind of explain that
that could be it too you know if you get
something you're like oh my god this is
this is special I want to keep it you
know for myself and you know a lot of
people you know I'll take these and you
know go make try to make money off them
and I you know I I don't really give
them to anyone so just out of respect
for those guys and just I don't want
people to go take it and go make a ton
of money off itself yeah I I really
don't give them out I get asked a lot
but I just can't I'd spent all my time
at the post office may only mail in cuts
to people so
so how do you feel about people who are
making money off it and more
specifically especially when you're
pretty much 100% certain it's not even
real that's the part I don't like when
you just using the name I mean anyone
can throw a name on something and trick
people and into buying their product the
guys that put out a good product and
I've taken the chem dog strains and like
JJ for instance and and made really good
quality genetics with them and you know
I think it's I think it's awesome I
think it's great the people that are
being deceitful and calling this chem 91
or calling this a chem whatever and chem
whatever and not having real chem
genetics and that that kind of rubs me
wrong yeah so I mean on that same note
do you think that just generally
speaking we will be able to put the cam
dog into seed form or do you think it's
just one of those one in a millions and
you know even if you could find the
parents and do it than most of the seeds
may not come out as strong or you know
as similar yeah I personally I don't
think you're ever gonna get that you're
never gonna get you know exactly what
you know the clone is and I just don't
think that's possible I mean you can get
something close but I think's country is
working on something that's lucky dog
seeds that's what I that's what I'd be
waiting for his work but if you want
something close you know like start JJ's
star dogs are really strong and there's
a lot of crosses out there there that
are really strong but you're not gonna
get you know the real the the chem 9uo
Nordik md or V Kemp for so yep with that
in mind do you do you want to kind of cg
get into doing some seeds of his own
because we've heard whispers and maybe
him doing something oh yeah I would love
it now that
you know Massachusetts it's legal he
told me is gonna he wanted to do
something so I think that would be you
know he deserves it the most he's really
the one that there wasn't for him you
know I don't want to be smoking don't be
smoking the chem so yeah anything he
succeeds that makes me happy yeah yeah I
think I speak for everyone when we say
that so you mentioned earlier that Joe
is online were you ever really going
online or not until the story kind of
got pieced together and you realize that
there were people online who knew about
you I was I think I was online before
that I think I started on the overgrown
and the icy mag and I just picked P but
as as my handle and then an icy mag this
guy with that name high and lonesome
Virginia I believe he kind of laid out
the whole chem dog 101 story on there
really really good pictures and the
whole story pretty pretty accurate you
know he did research and talked to
everyone and that's kind of how the
whole and that was 15 15 years ago or
something so let's kind of have a whole
P bud and Joe brand an internet thing
kinda kind of blew up yeah I was gonna
say that's actually an amazing threat
for anyone who hasn't looked at it you
gotta go that's great and dog yeah you
can search Ken dog 101 and I see Meg and
it's that's about pictures and yeah Kim
dog one oh yeah it's got a lot of lays
out the whole story's got the pictures
just killer Joe Joe actually comments on
it just under like one of the first
comments he's like just under a guest
profile like he didn't even have an
account at that point yeah it was like
he's just like hey I'm that guy from the
story first and he basically post proof
and it's like whoa
yeah that's Joe did a lotta I mean he
was on the internet for a few years
trying to sell that's sell the story
which was true
and yeah finally it I mean he must have
said it so many so many times on the
internet jumping into forums and saying
this is you know where it came from and
just got shut down for years and then
finally got reconnected with mass G and
yeah vindication
yes so so after you did reconnect with
mass G through Joe B or whatever it
might be
did you stay in contact with him or was
it still kind of a sporadic relationship
I've stayed contact with them since you
know oh six they've been you know we saw
him at the dead shows last year in
Chicago and no talk talk a bunch of you
know texts and stuff like that so yeah
we we keep in touch for sure and i you
know i buy i buy a pipe from the you
know every six months yeah
[Music]
so basically when when g went down due
to that whole res business we were you
just peripheral to that or were you kind
of like I was pretty peripheral to that
yeah those and I guess they got the last
couple seeds to the feds got the last
link to seeds so which was too bad but
yeah I was kind of not really around in
them and so did you have any experience
with the res because it's a like I mean
it's it's almost a taboo thing to talk
about res but at the same time what I
find most interesting about it is for
all the negative things he's done
there's almost just as many people who
want to talk about how good his chem dog
crosses were love people loved his cam
down crosses just go I only knew him
just from the internet he's just a turd
you know big attitude and you know
wasn't afraid to
get into it with people and but yeah he
made some good crosses but uh yeah just
just a bad yeah bad just don't like to
talk and talk about the guys yeah yeah
now that's no worries when when G was in
jail I mean this might just be totally
unrelated but like I mean how did that
affect Kem family I'm also like what
we's Kem family just this loose term to
you or is it actually something more
than that you know like it's like it's
that's it's kind of loose term but it's
you know there's you know people that
know the story and that are involved in
it and you know friends of geez friends
of know my JJ those guys but uh Joe's
but yeah that's kind of different groups
of people I guess together that are
associated with it and so have you guys
ever thought about like maybe pushing is
not the right word but you know like
creating a brand similar to the way
cookie fam have done it and you know in
my opinion they've almost detached
themselves from being a hundred percent
associated with cannabis and it's more
just a brand now you know have you guys
ever thought about that with the chemcam
not really I think about it all the time
yeah I would I would love to it's just
we're kind of all in different areas of
the country and doing different things
and I've always had a career and just
you know just the the time but uh would
love to some day would love to I know
the messaging as the copywriter for that
got the names chem dog or chem family or
something so yeah you know yeah that was
funny Duke told us the story about how
pretty interesting so how do you feel
about chem dog being put into feminized
form regardless of which cutting it is
because the reason why I asked that is
because it's one of those strains where
you you really never find
real-deal chem 91 feminized or a
real-deal chem d feminized do you think
that's something which the chem pam has
thought about and thought like we don't
want that to happen
or it's just you guys thought they
wouldn't like the seeds themselves
wouldn't turn out very good or what's
your opinion on that I would love to see
it happen but I would like to see you
know skunk Pierre last year you know one
of those guys do it
not you know not no not anyone else so
yeah well I think that's what is a
really good reason to be getting skunk
stuff because as far as I'm concerned
like I don't know if I'd really trust
many people except for like you know you
and Tommy to be having a legitimate 91
yeah no I I would jump on the skunk EA's
seeds actually my friend got some for me
and at the Emerald cup which you were
out at right yeah I was hanging out yeah
cool
so he's got those in Durango for me so
next time I see him off so yeah it's I'm
excited I'm excited for those and I'm
not a seed guy at all so yeah but I'm
excited for this so this is a question
I've been asking ever in the chem fam
and I think I might not actually get an
answer into like an ostrich e himself
but I remember reading this post online
that said that like I think it was from
like G's point of view like he was
writing it and and he said that he
always found that like can't intercept
chem dog so I assumed maybe it means the
91 he said that always came out best if
you good organically but then in the
later part of flour used like a
synthetic PK booster and it really
brought out the chem flavor do you know
if there's any truth to that have you
ever heard anyone say anything like that
or not you couldn't really comment on it
yeah I couldn't really comment on that
we had you I just know I I'm I'm not an
organic I mean I'm like 80% organic so
and I take I guess that taking it a lot
of people take it to 70 days
and you know Duke likes to take and I
think skunk va2 a lot you know shorter
than that like sixty days so they say
that really brings out the flavor let it
go too long gets more of a narcotic I
and the taste kind of kind of fade so I
got some now going in my basement that
I'm gonna take it sixty days this time
I've always taking it like 70 so I'm
gonna give that a shot see what happens
well I mean with that in mind what was
the strongest batch of 91 you've ever
had and then who grew it I would have to
I mean just the first time I really
smoked it you know it was from a Jeep
from gee so I'm gonna say from him just
just you know memory is just like wow
it's just so strong and just brought me
back to smoking that dog died in Crested
Butte on dead tour 1991 so I'd have to
say mass G's the best 91 I've smoked
with Tommy Tommy a close second yeah yep
have you ever have you ever tried on
skunks cuz i Tommy actually says the
heating's yeah I have five tribes
I've tried his in his is phenomenal -
yeah yeah yeah but I've I've had more
masteries and Tommy so yeah and so when
you I mean just going back to when you
were first smoking the 91 for example
with it was it just like I mean I try to
describe to people what smoking the 91
is like and I all I can say is like it's
just a different beast you know like
it's really just uncompelled or to a lot
of strains in many regards did you feel
that way at first like was there
anything that could compare to what it
all or was it just so foreign at the
time just because I had smoked you know
we smoked the dog but 91 that summer
that was it and then you know I smoked
the 91 and not until like oh five so
yeah it was absolutely
just amazing the narcotic high it has
and expand it that expand us in your
lungs where you try to hold it in and
it's just like it's just growing and
expanding in your lungs and you got it
just you got to blow it out and then
just instantly instantly high after it
it's just just strong it's just strong
strong weak yeah I mean the first time I
had it I think I was kind of green dad
so I tell you understand what and it
says you don't get immune to it there's
no ceiling it's just it's great medicine
I mean if you have stomach problems or
you know anything like that it's it's
great for that so I mean the the dog but
you know that's often referenced as you
know the parent or maybe just loosely as
like the closest thing to the chem dog
at least back in the day but I mean you
also mention the Skelly hash plant which
is kind of a new cutlet to come on the
scene where do you think the chem dog
originates from you know there's a lot
of debate the dog blood from people that
have over the years that have asked the
guys that brought it into crusted be
where it came from was like some valley
in Oregon where it came from I don't
know it was being grown there indoors
there or not but that's why I heard it
came from the Camus Camus Valley in
Oregon I think is what it was called but
we still don't you know don't know for
sure where it came from the scaly hash
plan is that was from 1987 I believe
friends of friends went over to
Amsterdam and brought bought some seeds
just labeled hash when in a coffee shop
in Amsterdam and brought him back
to Leadville Colorado and I think there
are six seeds and this this one was the
key was the keeper and yeah went to
Crested Butte and some guy named Skelly
that was his nickname was kind of the
guy that grew it was kind of a master of
growing it and that's where it came
scale we hashed plant yeah it was called
and then got I got renamed the talk
because my friend would go over your
friend fatty will go over to my friend
Rob's house always goes you have any of
the puck do you need the puck farther
were like what the heck are you talking
about and Rob had kept his hash plan in
this fly-fishing container that holds
flies it's like a plastic and it was
black from the resin and they looked
like a hockey puck so fatty would he
just kind of named it the puck and so he
must have spread that around I've lost
contact with him but he must have spread
that around Colorado pretty pretty good
and so when I got back I moved up here
to Denver and with a friend and he's
like oh yeah I got this string on this
hash plant strength he's like oh you
need the puck and I just put two and two
together I was like fatty he or just
he's one of the funniest guys I've ever
met and he spread that word around
Colorado the puck so that kind of
changed the name of it but it's just an
old strong mother's really just strong
strong strains yeah I mean it's another
one that's in a league of its own yeah
it's just it's crazy
have you ever seen anything that maybe
you know the third trifecta or do you
think at the moment they know anyone in
the Parker in a league of their own
pretty much in the league your own and
then they always you know we smoked that
hat we're smokin T bud and then the hash
plant Skelly ash went pop came
around and that just was just insane and
then we've really never compared
anything to houseplant except the dog
bud so those two really are just the two
strongest most incredible strains that
I've ever seen yeah without a doubt
so how do you deal with people trying to
give you you know quite the real history
of the CHEM dog is it at the point now
where you've so many people try to tell
you you know about your life you just
don't even care anymore we just got into
the guy Instagram the other day about
his uncle was his uncle at the kem dog
before mass G and it was always spelled
d AWG and so yeah it's a you know a
weekly monthly thing at least but I've
heard so many so many stories and so
many people's claims and it's just
frustrating because we lived it and I
know it's true you know it was our life
and you know mass G's life and you know
there's a guy there's last ye and you
know there's the guys that should get
credit for it and Joe brand and you know
those guys won't people try to take
credit for it it's that's pretty weak
but uh it's I'm used to it now
yeah and so I mean it's probably a
question a lot of people have asking is
the Donnell thinking in their mind is
that Joe brands been seemingly absent
from the scene for a while do you think
he'll ever pop his head back up or maybe
he's not interested so he's never really
been a you know Internet and out there
kind of guy you know I hope someday he
does but uh I tried to call him and see
if he wanted to do do this interview but
uh I didn't get in touch with them but
you know hopefully someday you know he
will
I love the guy and hope for the best one
for sure yeah and so maybe a little left
of the last question is you've been
around long enough now that you've seen
come and go and you've probably seen far
more quote fad strains than just blue
trim and Girl Scout cookies
what do you think will stand the test of
time and what do you think is hot right
now that's gonna pass I mean I I'm
really starting to get into although
geez like TK and that's that V and you
know I think those things are always be
around you know the headband and all
those you know those good right I think
TK and sfv are just two of the best OGS
out there and I think they'll don't
stand the test of time and whatever
people can you know that Kemp Scout is
amazing you know the state now JJ stuff
is amazing so there's a lot of people
getting more and more chem crosses out
there and I think you know if you have a
good Kemp gross it'll stand the test of
time for sure and so I was gonna say it
is how does that stock Hill you've been
raving about lineup to those it's good
it's good you know I'm not a big fan of
this the Scots OGE or the rugby I mean I
think they're good but this star killers
a step above it's it's it's right up
there with with some of the better
orgies for sure and it's one big it's
one multiple multiple awards to so this
is my first time growing it so um I'm
excited to see I get about 30 more days
on that so we'll see so have you got a
little seed library of your own I mean
you probably do but the question is what
what's the next thing you're excited to
pop because I'm always interested to
know you know like what are you
personally interested to get going soon
go give people get me seeds all the time
so I do have a pretty good selection
what I do is just because I don't have
really the space and the time as I give
them to good good friends and have that
are into you know pop and see
and and then they'll find good stuff and
then I can get clothes of that or or or
whatever but uh these Kendall acam seats
I got which is chem D by 95 my buddy
just pops some of them and so yeah we'll
see all right he actually harvested some
of that and it turned out great so uh
but yeah mostly i i i give seeds to a
couple good buddies and and they they
pop and then you see what we get
yeah and so in terms of your personal
garden you like kind of like just a few
strains and they're your staples you
just run them or are you always
experimenting or you like you know me
and do call it the or is it the lonely
island wait where you know you just read
the one i like just I'm growing now just
for you know personal these were before
I grow for income so when I was going
for income it was more one strain and
you know the money strain the big
producer now I grow a nice you know nice
variety so I got you know SF vtk star
killer chem D by 95 chem 91 candy so I
got you know all those going right now
so it's uh it's nice to have different
flavors for sure yeah
and have you ever had someone tell you
that like a scam dog cut was
specifically good for a certain
condition because I remember when I
asked Tommy this he said that the camo
anyone is great people who want to gain
weight because it gives you the munchies
you know this is good for Crohn's or
something like that Crohn's I chem for
I've got a couple people that have
Crohn's and love the Kemp for works
works great for them I guess stronger
strains I don't know me may work for
that
that disease but yeah and then you know
no the chem 91 is good for any stomach
issues for sure got me through my
stomach flu last year during 4/20 so
yeah it's there they're great medicinal
strains for sure yeah and do you ever
see chem dog being explored more by the
general public as a medicinal strain you
think it's just not it's I mean I guess
the way I think about it is it seems
like it's like like a band-aid for a
bullet in some ways you know like it's
it's a very broad acting strain but I
don't know if it seems specific in many
ways if you know what I mean yeah I'm
not really sure and specifics I would
love to see it you know used in medicine
for sure it's just so strong I don't
know how you know the side effects or
you know no I'm just not sure on yeah
you know the the medicinal part of the
Kem's but I I know for Chrome's camphor
and stomach issues any cam yeah we got a
doubt I think it would be interesting to
see like you know a 91 or a D cross two
really strong yes yeah sure so this is
just a bit of a hot question here but I
think it's a good one the 91 show itself
right despite everything that happened
you know he was going down as a
legendary show do you remember the show
itself like was it actually a good show
because I thought wouldn't it be so
ironic if like arguably the most
important you know dead show kind of his
history was actually do context for me
the dad kind of started going downhill
you know after Brent died he died 90 I
wasn't a big Vince fan Bruce Hornsby
played with him for a while but he had
stopped shows good I just remember a
Jack Straw Berthe opener which is like
my favorite combination opener
but don't really remember the show -
well the dead were kind of you know 91
man he was a good year 92 93 94 95 were
all kind of the scene was getting bad
and jelly was just ill and the dead were
good when they were healthy yeah
straighten us straight up when there are
healthy they were doing J was all [ __ ]
up you know it was sloppy and the shows
are still good but they weren't great
when like 1990 was probably the last
[Music]
great great year spring tour 90 was
probably the great last great year so
yeah okay Wow but it was a good show it
was a good show it was good cool venue
Deer Creek is great it's out in the
middle of nowhere like farmland and
cornfields and camping and there's fun
times yes I mean the Grateful Dead you
know they kind of passed on the torch
metaphorically to fish when they kind of
finished up but yeah I've never heard of
there being you know that same impact on
the cannabis in is what the Dead had you
know like I've never heard of there
being like a car park scene at a Phish
show for example do you think that that
was a camera sorry a Grateful Dead
exclusive thing like do you think we'll
ever get another you know I don't know
how to say like cannabis revolution the
way we did with the Grateful Dead or not
necessarily I think it's people getting
them getting it other places now just I
think back then it was me likes country
a said is she said this or someone said
this that you know dead tour was kind of
like the first Facebook so it was a way
of connecting with people and you knew
they were gonna be at that next venue
and so it was kind of I don't know if
fish does that I don't really go I've
never
into a fishtail before but yeah I'm not
really sure if what the scene is like
there so I probably couldn't comment on
that but I know the dad was the first
the first Facebook really for social
media and do you think that besides the
CEM dog the quite car park scene of the
Grateful Dead's contributed a lot to
cannabis in terms of like recognizable
strains like had you ever heard of like
Oh someone got you know like a TK cut a
dead show or like it seems like Kem dog
is the big one that gets talked about in
regards to the Grateful Dead
yeah em dogs definitely the the big one
I think more it was more of you know
selling flowers that the at the show
sellin selling buds and and you know I'm
sure you know cuts and stuff like that
were traded but the chem dog one is that
is the is the big one that you know most
people associate with it
so I mean how do you feel about the og
in relation to the chem dog because I
mean I realized just as I asked that
question there was a big major floor and
that I mean in my mind I feel like the
chem dog is either the daughter or a
sister or like some some close relative
to the chem dog so I mean you're
probably not gonna get an OG cut at a
Grateful Dead show back in the day but
how do you feel all of that relates
together are you of the same school of
thought that it's probably some close
relative or I think they're I think
they're related for sure I think oh geez
uh just you know an S one from a bag of
91 I mean I can't prove it but that's my
thoughts I think now that I'm grown oh
geez they they they remind me of the
ninety one you know not as big of buds
but they definitely remind me of it so
that's that's what I think but
the og question is kind of a tough one
to crack for sure yeah yeah so if you
were in G's position back in that time
when you know he was fresh 17 or 18 do
you think that would have been able to
keep the cuts alive as well as he did
depending on my back at that young
probably not know just because I
wouldn't have had I wouldn't have had
that spot to do it just I was living
just at my parents house and I wouldn't
have been able to to do that sort of
thing but thank God he did yeah I mean
the reason I'm just so amazed like I
just I I don't I haven't met anyone
who's truthfully said that like yes oh I
could have been in that position and
also kept those cuts alive for all those
years it's just so mind-blowing it's
it's awesome and just yeah the work and
that he did to keep those alive and the
crosses and all that yeah it's it's
awesome
have you ever asked him why he waited
such long periods of time him between
popping the successive seeds like I've
always wondered why did he wait four
years between popping the first and the
next batch like so yeah I'm not sure why
did that I think it was smart I think he
knew he had something special and didn't
want to blow it all maybe uh yep and do
it over over time just nice because he
sent those four seeds to Joe which was
which was pretty cool so yeah I mean a
lot of what he did that yeah a lot of
people probably really kind of I don't
know how to phrase it you know like they
were probably thinking I wouldn't have
done that if they're in his position you
know given that he knew what the seeds
were at that point yeah no I think that
was huge of him to do and just such a
nice nice thing because
after Jo got back in touch with the kids
it's been like a yeah nice to nice to
talk to you again yes you know you can
have some cuts but you know not not for
the seeds yeah I think that was a great
thing you did yeah so I mean not
necessarily in relation to giving the
seeds to Joe because obviously that was
a very nice thing to do but if you're in
G's position would you have ever done it
differently like would you have popped
them all at the start or just sat on
them for longer or you know what would
you have done
tough questions I would have probably I
would have probably popped tomorrow and
just you know gotten what we got and
then save save those you know kept all
the keepers and saved them so yeah so
this is an interesting thing I've been
told which you've probably been told as
well is that someone's told me before
they said I think that the chem dog seed
to a result they're all s vartanus
basically and I said yeah but there was
that male you know and that kind of
ruins that theory yeah and then they
were like yeah but no one ever saw that
male it's almost like that male is like
conveniently inserted into the story so
that people wouldn't think they're RS
ones and I thought about that and I
thought well I see what you're saying
you know like the fact the male was
there does show that they probably
weren't s ones but at the same time I
don't see why she would lie about them
you know like what does he have to gain
from that really there's nothing to gain
I mean he wasn't putting himself as he
killed it so it wasn't really putting
himself in a good light but yeah I told
that yes tell the truth yeah yeah that
so I guess what the question really was
was that um given that there was males
there what do you speculate the father
was you know I don't believe their
response how I guess you've kind of said
the same yeah I bet I'm not I'm not
really sure what the father is
Tommy would probably know that better
than better than me being a breeder and
knowing that sort of thing but uh yeah I
would I wouldn't know yeah the reason I
ask that is just because I'm a lot of
people have this you know thought that
the father is what passes on the potency
more so and so yeah I'm always
interested to know what the father of
things yeah for sure
I think maybe the puck could be related
to the to the dog bird someway yeah it's
kind of always thought that for very
similar so I mean see you given that you
have been trying all of this you know
high-quality weed from back in the early
roots so to speak do you think that the
modern-day hybrids are standing up to
those old favorites or you know do you
still find yourself reminiscing about
the past
I think the pair yeah there's a few that
can stand up to the to the cams but the
most of them just don't they just don't
and so do you think that modern hybrids
have mostly improved on flavor and not
so much potency per se yeah I think a
lot of people are out there for the
flavor where I've always been for the
potency not real I don't really care too
much what it tastes like it's got you
know but could we taste good I mean they
it just doesn't I like that expanding in
your lungs and coughing and all that
stuff I like I like the strong stuff
that's why I've just I smoke Kem's and
oh geez that's about it
yep you don't ever dabble in any glass
wax do you no just just by yeah it's
just the reason I ask is it's like it
seems like there's so many people in the
chem fam who dabble in you know whether
it be on yeah I'm not sure he's real
name which is a weasel I think he's also
a glass blower yeah he's yeah he's blows
glass he's got some Jay Jay as a couple
good pieces from him
Oh is he the one who did that fish one
for JJ yeah yep that's no I'm not not
that the fish one now it's a guy here in
Colorado but it's like old school
there's old school pipes yeah the other
nice work for sure but yeah jeez G does
great he does great work I love his
style old school just I just love it
yeah I need to get um one of those lot
little mini Chilam type things Tommy had
one and I was using that and I just like
fell in love with it yeah that's a cool
the many hammers are really cool and
then you know it's bubblers they're all
it's all all good stuff yeah
yeah for sure and that's the other thing
I'm always telling people like in
Australia just getting into class really
heavily now people like cuz they say you
know I mean I'm not a glass expert or
anything but they they always ask me
know who should I get my glass from this
why well there's only one name I minato
yo dog glass he makes I love his colors
and the Milly's he puts in on there it's
nice yeah and I remember Tommy was even
saying like some of those Milly's are
like quite old and rare even so like you
truly are getting your money's worth
oh yeah in the time he puts into them
and yeah
oh hey man yeah they're great I've got a
dead 50 piece that he made oh wow for
the dead shows last year and it's got
like 10 dead Milly's in it and yeah it's
it's it's my favourite piece that's the
one if I break I'd be I'd be crying yeah
it's funny I got a few dead ones in mine
it's like I always have to tell what
they are so I think a good way to get
back into this would be um you know like
count dog is just the epitome of indica
you know you really can't get more
indica than that how do you balance the
sativa side out because I it's
interesting when I was talking to mr.
Sol the way he described was chem dog
was like it was that perfect
counterpoint to the really super sativas
he enjoys smoking you know
kind of bringing you back to earth when
you've blasted off too hard how do you
view sativas in relation to chem dogging
or is it just like chem dog filled your
need and you don't venture to that side
of the river so to speak
I don't really venture to sativas I mean
I think the teams are really good like
daytime you know get you up and going
and good for like at work and stuff but
uh I've just always liked that you know
that just the knock you dead hi so I've
always I just wanted to smoke the pop to
get you the highest that's that's my
personality so sativas really never
really did it for me so yeah just I I
just love the the pose really strong
strong stuff and so how do you think the
scene would have progressed if there was
never any chem dog so it seems like a
bit of a weird question but I always
think about I don't know it would be a
sad world out there I think yeah I don't
know it's like there you'd have another
favorite weed out there yes I don't know
everything kind of everything I like
came from camp so yeah that's exactly it
isn't it because it's an interesting
kind of thought exercise to do with
yourself where you think of like all
these big name strains and if they've
got care Minotaur is suspect be kind of
cross them off the list you're not left
with March I know you know like no
gorilla cruise out and you know Sour
Diesel zat house and all those really
good go strains wouldn't be her
you just had the special word gorilla
glue what do you think about it yeah I
like it
I mean I've grown it than one one time I
like that I kind of got sick of it but
they were strong and I'm a fan I'm a fan
of the girl look cool yeah why something
about the gorilla glue which really
if the cam is I mean a a lot of people
love Gorilla Glue but no one really
shows that same love to the khemsa's and
I think that a lot of the high or the
enjoyment of the high from the Gorilla
Glue yes from the cam yeah definitely
definitely yeah the taste is the
chocolate it's kind of chocolatey and
smell to me but yeah the high is
definitely the the sister for sure I
mean that's where it gets its strength
yeah and the other interesting thing
about the gorilla glue which I think it
it definitely has parallels with the
chem dog is that it seems now you're
starting to get these fake gorilla crews
going around much like the fake chem
dogs and so you get this situation I
think it was Tommy who said it where
it's like you know everyone's had the
chem dog but no one's had the chem dog
right anxiety to know about that person
like do you feel like that's a pretty
accurate reflection cuz yeah like
something yeah I think a lot of people
you know claim that they haven't smoked
it or whatever but I think the
percentage of that is pretty it's pretty
low and now the night I know that's the
case on the 91 you know the four is out
there and more available Joe is really
generous and giving that out to a lot a
lot of people you know six and it's kind
of made its way around yes
and so I mean if we look at it both JJ's
and Reza's work we see that they both
chose to work with the chem D and we
know that you like the company more but
in many ways I find it an interesting
choice because just the the raw potency
of the ninety-one seems like it would be
just an obvious one to work with do you
do you agree with this trade-off they've
done so to speak where you know the
presumption is they've thought well it's
not quite as strong but it's got better
flavor or maybe better breeding
properties do you agree with that choice
they made or would you have done it
differently no I agree I think the D is
so close to
as potent as the 91 it's close it's just
got that I think more people like that
have that have smoked the real 91 and
the D like the deep better overall I
think yeah and it's it's it's very close
to being as strong as that 91 so I think
that's probably the the smell and the
it's it's a better yield er than the 91
so could be another reason well I mean
do you agree with I think it was not
skunk himself but he's his former friend
in the story he told where he was saying
you know like he feels like there's
something about the chem dog where it's
like it's tied to the stars well you
know like it's this real fickle plant
that's hard to master so to speak do you
think that's true or maybe it's just we
didn't understand plants the way we do
now no I think it's true I think you
gotta have experience grown the cams
they got stuff they like and stuff they
don't like but in its comfy a has been
growing that strange for these probably
the you know number one expert on the on
the 91 for sure yeah yeah with you know
whatever he says I would I would believe
it yeah yeah so if you had to pick the
genetics which you think would best
compliment the 91 I guess to put it in a
realistic sense if you had to pick a
male
you know which genetics do you think
would complement the 91 the best because
I think I asked Duke and he said that
yeah he agreed that the Afghani land
race that both JJ and res picked was a
good complement to the D how do you feel
about the 91 yeah I don't know I don't
know I think I agree with with what
those guys
yeah yeah so you know not trying to talk
negatively about it but what are some of
the the downsides about the chem dogs
which don't frequently get mentioned I
mean the flavor was brought up a few
times by a few people including us what
what are some things which people don't
often consider which do you regard the
the chem Deacon you know throw manners
and could very gate and the chem 90 ones
you know a lot the biggest producer but
you know those things really don't you
know the DS probably that's probably the
biggest problem with that one is
throwing out those bananas but they're
not really there's nothing in them and
they don't really it's not like a lot of
them unless it gets stressed but uh
these are probably the biggest problems
with it yeah it's interesting you bring
that out because a lot of the best
strains throughout history of being
created from the 91 throwing pollen on
other things but as you just mentioned
that that the nanos on the D they're
infertile so to speak yeah so do you do
you find that the 91 is easy to her me
so to speak because that's that's
something I'm always thinking about you
know given all these strains originated
from it I would have thought it was easy
to herm how do you find it no I think
they are all yeah
easy easy to herm for sure okay
interesting and so I mean you know if
it's not too much effort how you give us
a quick rundown of what your gross style
is I do soil or cocoa I just switched
over to cocoa I'm Ronnie botanic air I
got a friend that works for botanic air
and he's hooked me up with their whole
line they're cocoa and this running
everything's everything's looking good I
just I just like a hand water and just
out of a watering can I'm very
very you know nothing nothing special at
all just in my basement and three lights
and enough for me and my wife and some
friends so uh it's it's it's good and
it's all legal and which is great so
very happy with uh with my basement my
little basement grow that's that's my
new Moto's my cuz I work at work I'm
taking care of thousand plants and so I
come home and take a ten and it's it's
it's pretty easy so yeah okay well I
mean I'm not know what some tips for
people who're looking to grow large
numbers you know like you must have to
do things in you must be looking for
shortcuts all the time given you look up
as so many plans yes and we're we're
doing soil right now so we're and water
and everything which takes quite a bit
of time but we're up close and personal
with the plants and it's when you get
into big things like that you just have
to be more just on top of things
preventive and start one that you know
the plants small and you know just make
sure it's really really healthy to fight
off any just bugs or diseases or mildew
or anything like that just really start
from the beginning and make sure the
plants healthy all the way through it's
hard and in the warehouse but uh staying
on top of it but uh it's just it's just
a lot of hours and and in hard work and
a good team for sure yeah so do you see
yourself ever trying to turn chem dog
into like a full-on thing for yourself
like I just remember briefly trying to
skunk and he just mentioned that you
know like he would love to be able to
open like you know like the chem dog
mekka so to speak is that something you
would envision wanting to do or you I
would love to be a part of it for sure
and help in any way I can
right now I'm just kind of focused you
know and you know my job in working at
Incredibles and and stuff like that but
uh I would love to be involved and help
any of those guys out with whatever I
could whatever I could do as far as I
know you were or people seem to tell me
that you you were the first person to
kind of get the Skelly back into you
know the the familiar crews hands what
was that process of tracking it down
like well my good friend Rob was in
Crested Butte he's the one that won the
he won the Adam Dunn Cup came in second
place with the hash plant two years ago
and then won it this year with the chem
four he's been holding on to it since 87
he's lived in the same place in Crested
Butte so he's stable but he has kept it
you know for all these years him and a
couple other people because to be that
been keeping it alive for since 1987 so
you know all the credit goes to rob and
those guys down the crusty Butte yeah
and have you ever made an attempt to try
to track down the growers of the
original dog butter would you think of
it just it just be too hard to do it'd
be hard like the guy that I think
they're all probably a lot or you know a
lot older and you know not on the
internet and to find them would be hard
the guy that brought it into Crested
Butte still lives in Crested Butte and
he's the one that told my friend that it
came from the kamas Valley in Oregon not
sure if he's in touch I don't think he's
in touch with the people that you know
he got it from so
it's it's been 25 years of trying to
find that that strand again and it's
yeah I haven't I haven't found that or
where came from her or what so maybe in
the future yeah maybe they're still
growing it the dog bug in Oregon so who
knows how his name changed yeah so how
do you feel about how the public has
received the kam dog I mean it's I think
I saw an interview with g-unit way he
said that he feels over the past few
years the public is really like warmed
to it where in the past people used to
really ride it off but I think just
maybe due to exposure more people have
had the real thing and I like really
impressed by it I think yeah if you
smoked the real thing I think you know I
think more people have smoked the real
thing and once you smoke the real thing
it's you know met you you won't forget
it I mean I've had so many people tell
me in the last couple years that it's
their favorite string it's it's the best
one that they've ever smoked and never
will smoke yeah and so you know at
certain parts throughout the history
because obviously a lot of people you
know basically everyone excluding you
and the people directly involved there
they're getting a lot of their
information from online so there are
periods where for example I think it was
around that High Times article that they
did with G where certain cuts we just
thought not to be around like I think G
thought he had lost the 91 and it was
just gone
we whoever in that boat where there were
times when you thought I well there goes
the Kim D forever and then like it turns
out you get it back from a friend of a
friend or something or was it always
pretty well controlled and you never
really thought things were gone forever
since we got them it's pretty much it's
pretty controlled it's never been last I
think that happened you know
earlier back in the 90s and early 2000s
but since weeds and my friends have had
it there's pretty much you know if you
lose it I know someone else you know
reliable has it so like we got the chem
D back I got Mike MD back a couple years
ago and this guy's had it since we gave
it to him and you know I was six when we
first got it and then got it back from
him a few years ago so he's he's kept it
and he still has it and will have it for
forever and then people don't want to
lose it so they they put in a lot of
effort in trying to preserve it yeah and
I mean Tommy mentioned that you can
revitalize clones by vegging a man in
the Sun for a season and letting him get
really big and then taking some nice
clones off them and rings inside have
you ever seen that done with any of the
chem dogs and if so did they come out
any better than beforehand never seen
that done with the chem dogs it's always
kind of been an indoor venture the last
since we'd since you know since I've
since I've Adam exhale still so it's
always been yeah just keeping them alive
indoors yeah and so if you could only
pick say two of all the chem dogs which
would you want to keep 291 in the D is
it an easy choice yeah that's that's
easy you give me two choices that's easy
and so I get you know what's three then
what comes in third from maybe four
would be the for a lot of people who
would wouldn't say that but I I like
before I like the high of it I think
it's very medicinal instant high taste
isn't the best but yeah bros before
would be third yeah okay and then I
guess the the number one is the D number
one is D 91 close second if you're
taking everything like smell taste hi
everything is D is d is number one in my
book and that names like you know the
only thing you if you had to pick one
strain you could only have that would be
it oh that's just the favorite that's my
island strain yeah that's my desert only
strange Kim D I might have thought you
might have said ah it's my favorite but
it veggies too slow that's a good
producer and the only thing is that that
that banana issue but we've got it
pretty much under control okay so I mean
Tommy's got another he's got another D
cut that I got some flowers from the
other day I was up there and so I'm
gonna I'm gonna grill that one out and
maybe replace Tommy's with Tommy got
this one from from G Pat way way back
when so yeah and it's it's phenomenal I
don't know if you got to see any of that
but it's it's it's phenomenal and it
doesn't it doesn't throw out bananas and
it's never variegated on them so well it
may replace replace that I think that
was the one I tried and then I tried the
real one later on but I think I kind of
like Tommy's one yeah Tommy's is good
it's it's the real it's the real thing G
was telling that he thinks it's the
sister but there's no way that's it's
Kim D it's it is that was a long time
ago and he gave him that cut so
mistakes happen yeah
so if you could only change one thing
outside of the banana issue because I
think that's probably the obvious choice
if you change one thing about the D and
the 91 you know it could be different
things about the cuts what would you
change about them nothing not even like
bigger yield I mean bigger yield since
the 91 if you get a bigger yield it
would be nice but uh I did I juris I've
always thought bigger it doesn't
necessarily mean better you know my
parents live in Maine and you know that
big fat six seven pound laughs just
don't taste nearly as good as a to two
and a half pound lobsters so and I don't
like I'm more of a the shoulder so I'm
the plants I like the buds like it's
shoulders instead of the tops yeah
so the 91 not being that big it really
doesn't doesn't bother me but if I had
to pick you that would be at the bigger
bigger yield is always good yep
and so what's the most annoying thing
about trying to talk to people about the
kam dog because I obviously the history
is maybe the the obvious one but like
sometimes I find it's even just like
people get really lost up in all the
names because you know there's there's
all the different cuts and it will just
lose track of things really quickly well
I probably biggest one is I've been I'm
gonna spell guy it's just the DEA WG its
chem da its dog it's it's a combination
of dog bud which is what we got in
Crested Butte we started calling it chem
weed so I think when we saw mass G and
Indian Indianapolis we were calling a
chem we'd probably probably Tony was dog
done and chem weed and he just combined
the names cam and dog and there you have
it so it's it's do do G it's not D AWG
it's never been da w g JJ uses star dog
just out of respect for G and
and that's the you know that's that but
it's always been do G yeah and so I mean
do you think in a way you know that by
JJ using that naming nomenclature that
he's almost you know inadvertently made
it a little made a little more confusing
but I think the biggest culprit was
another company changed it before JJ
teams actually cam dog do G to D aw gee
I forget what company it was but they
they kind of started it all yeah yeah
dog I mean that version of dog really
didn't come out to like the later 90s I
know there was David Griezmann has dog
music D AWG but that's not what they're
referring to they're referring to like
dog like the urban way of saying dog
yeah no chance he's just smoking Kim dog
right now
yeah I've read online that aj has
actually taken credit for at least he
said that at one point in time he was
selling or giving kem dog to people in
new york that calling it diesel but at
the same time so many people say that
diesel and chem dog and not the same
thing how do you feel about that because
some of the older guys say like oh i
know like there is no such thing as
diesel it's actually just chem dog no I
think they just they changed they didn't
age it in like this goes in like the
name chem associated with it
a chemical didn't like that name they
thought it brought it down so they
changed it to diesel I don't know if it
was the smell or the word diesel meant
something in New York but yeah it's the
same thing chem 91 is the diesel
because when I got a bag of the diesel
it was chem 91 and then the Sour Diesel
was more of a that was an s-1 of a chem
91 or something or I'm not really sure
on that story the whole Sour Diesel
story it's kind of been changed a bunch
those guys yeah have the whole story
I think they I'm not really sure they
know what exactly happened but it's
definitely from the 91 I mean it's it's
it is I mean the smell is similar
Saturday's a little stronger but yeah
I'm not really sure on that yep
yeah so I mean I'm gonna spring an idea
on you know here a lot of people give a
lot of credit to Oregon and California
for helping to kind of you know
establish the color of the marijuana
stay in America but the more I kind of
delve into the history of things the
more I think New York is like this
unsung hero of the scene because it's
like seems like when you trace back a
lot of the best breeders in my opinion
not not just the chem dog ones like
obviously all the chem dog ones but they
trace their roots to New York and it
seems like that environment they had
where people willing to pay for really
expensive weed like bread this
environment where it was like productive
to be a breeder and also Steven just a
really good grower you know have you
ever thought about that at all and do
you agree I totally agree I think just
the combination of just people in New
York or just go-getters you know they
just get things done the market for the
weed was I mean just the you know 6,000
a pound 7,000 a pound so you know it was
worth it for those guys to do what they
did and
to be able to make that money and yeah I
think it's a combination of those those
things but yeah I think New York was a
good an outdoor two up in the UH the
Finger Lakes region and if it could
college and a lot of Cornell and a lot
of uh a lot of outdoor weed up there for
sure
did you ever get to try any of the stuff
that Duke talks about coming out of
Virginia or that never really got to you
never really got to us Lee I smoked a
lot of living out growing up outside New
York City you smoked a lot of like plant
like you know pot from Laos and Afghan
Afghani just really exotic exotic we
that will come into New York so I was
pretty spoiled as a as a teenager yeah
and were you smoking weed the full the
introductions of indicas to the scene oh
we you they had always been around there
kind of I created the kind of look great
at the beginning when I was smoking uh
you know just smoking a lot of Mexican
and Mexican weed and stuff like that and
but yeah a lot of it started kind of
when I started smoking and those things
started coming on the scene yeah okay
it's interesting because I've kind of
found anecdotally the people who were
around especially growers before the
advent of like commercial indica seeds
like Afghan ease they you never find one
of them who says in because of their
favorites you know because like they
obviously grew up on sativa so I know
sting if you fell into that category but
the chem dog had run you over with that
in mind throughout you know your whole
history of smoking weed what's been the
most enjoyable terpene or flavor profile
for you I know you said you don't really
care too much for flavor but for a lot
of people there's you know these really
kind of
exotic terpene profiles from another
younger because you know things were
more land Gracie what is it for you I'm
really into these the sfv and the TK the
oh geez for taste you know I really love
love that taste like the Kem's get you
still get you a little higher but yeah I
love these these og tastes their ID I
believe the hype for sure and so how do
you think that the laws affected the
scene as it progressed on because I mean
the immediate assumption one might make
is like if the laws were more loose you
know maybe cam dog would have flourished
even more do you think that was
necessarily the case because at the same
time it was still very you know as you
said somewhat close God you know is it
in the right circle type thing yeah I
think back then was definitely you know
there wasn't as much trading going on
and there definitely held closer the
reason I ask that is just because I I
kind of think that it was the perfect
breeding ground with the illegal
environment in a sense because it
allowed there to be you know if you look
at the New York crew for example you
know like those guys who were selling
the chem dog for crazy prices in the
park you know like if it was legal or
more lacks you know like those prices
wouldn't have been there and then maybe
maybe they wouldn't have been as much
incentive to keep the chem dog around
because that's part of what I think has
helped keep it around was because it is
obviously so valuable in so many regards
it just ensured its survival exactly I
think just the laws and people it being
worth so much money and people were you
know held it closer and protected it
more I would I would think that would
say yeah and so you mentioned earlier
that you generally just grew from
Klein's over the years but with that in
mind whether ever any breeders who you
kind of
their work was pretty good and bonus
points if it's besides JJ yeah yeah guys
from God what is their company called or
southfork seeds about in California are
really good they got all the real you
know chem genetics if you have the real
chem genetics and you're a good breeder
then you know your shit's gonna be good
there's on Instagram mr. Bob Hempfield
his you know starting to breed now and
he he's gonna be coming out with lots of
good crosses cam and puck crosses JJ of
course and then scum PA I would
definitely check his stuff out with it
when his comes out you just got to be
careful you want to find someone that
has the real the real deal and not just
claiming they have it and breeding with
it and just putting out whatever yeah
without a dad there's too much of that
at the moment yep and so at what point
did you really notice that the cam dog
was taking off in the mainstream and
even an extension of that is but you
know at what point were you kind of
starting to get recognized as the figure
from the story that you are probably an
Icee mag kind of from then people have
just been reading about it for the last
whatever ten years or so and it's just
kind of taken taken on a life of its own
but probably after that that I see mag
had started to really I really only got
back in the Facebook and Instagram and
all this media stuff a few a few years
ago so probably when I went on the Adam
Dunn show is probably when it really
kind of really blew up okay fantastic
Thank You Adam I mean you kind of Polly
answer this question of it is there have
you met many other people who did you
know have claimed they got to experience
the dog garden and you know
they describing it correctly to you and
it works out the timeframes about right
or not reveal not the dog but I've never
I've had a few people over the years
told me that they have it and this that
I've even had someone send it to me send
a sample and it I mean it was not it so
I've never known anyone besides myself
Joe and mass G that have smoked the dog
blood I mean I know there's people out
there but I have never heard of anyone
getting it back then or I mean it was
just so incredible for 1991 this this
pot was just so incredible for that time
we just had never seen anything like it
and to this day 25 years later I've
never talked to anyone that smoked the
real dog bird before was it outdoors uh
indoor awesome yeah so this is just a
bit of a personal question I was
thinking to myself while trying to know
anyone is how functional do you think
someone can be you know the average
person in the real world if they are
smoking these chem dogs all day do you
have using people who are still you know
real go-getters or do you just find it
to still takes its toll on you I think
it's your personality I think if you're
a go-getter you can you know smoke it
and you know no problem I mean I smoked
it all day and um I'm motivated and it's
it helps me so that wouldn't I would
know what I'd do without it for sure
yeah and so I always like to ask people
like what are their reasons for I'm
hanging on to cuts but you know I
specifically not giving them out and
with when you're talking to breathe is
it's somewhat obvious but one of the
interesting topics I had brought up was
that um not necessarily like you're
looking to keep it out of the hands of
the masses but the reason I got told was
that you know people can not look after
the plant well and you know they take
all clones and poor clones
and then eventually you know you've
you've got like for example it's a it's
the chem dog you know it's like it's
just really degraded and then and then
it's giving everyone a poor
representation of the chem dog even when
it's done well just due to the clone do
you feel like that has some what
happened to the chem dog because when I
heard that reasoning the first thing
that pops in my mind was like that seems
like that's kind of what it's happened
with the chem dog in some ways like I
mean I've just been told from so many
people that you know the biggest reason
why clones fade off so to speak is
because sometimes you know you're not
taking the healthiest cuttings yep yeah
that's yeah that's you gotta take
healthy kind of starts from the
beginning you gotta take them for a nice
healthy mother and and it'll just that
plant will be happy for its as long as
you take care of it okay happy for its
life so I think people I think people I
don't think that's the reason people
kept them close I think people kept them
close just because it was special and
you know they wanted to I don't think
people thought you know that if I give
it to this person they're gonna degrade
the plant I think people just found
something special they wanted to they
wanted to hold on to it yeah
or they got conditions someone gave it
to them and said don't give it out stuff
like that okay awesome well I think
we've only got some short answer
questions left so these are just you
know more far away but okay what's uh
what's this is a tooth powder you know
what's your least favorite strain you
like the worst strain in your opinion
and then the second part is you know
without necessarily giving away the
breeder what's the worst cross you've
ever seen the kemon you know because
obviously some strains just don't work
when you cross them to others it's just
you know genetic yeah what's the worst
one you've seen what is it not agree I
don't like fruity strains I'm not a big
fruity guy so you know any of those
purple grape e ones or tangerine e ones
you know all those I'm not I'm not into
those in the chem cross I'm not really
sure most of the chem crosses I've
smoked if it's the real chem it's I like
it maybe came close to some fruity
purple thing yeah maybe at first I've
seen a couple people crossing them to
some fruity stuff and I haven't tried
them but maybe the chem will make it
strong at least yeah the one silver
lining yes what you know you obviously
you've been around the scene for a long
time what's been the worst thing to
happen to it in your opinion the scene
just Oh God
just some of the people getting in the
in the business and in it for the wrong
reasons and just seeing people 20 years
ago or 15 years ago that would just look
at me and thought I was just the biggest
piece of [ __ ] you know low-grade person
in the world and now they're you know
now they're all put marijuana and it's
just kind of weird people that would
look at me differently 15 years ago I
look at me differently now so that's
kind of what bothers me the most I would
think about this business have you ever
had someone you know like try to get
back in contact and kind of like getting
in with you once they realized who you
are and maybe they had previously
written you off yeah most people from
high school you know mostly but they're
getting back in touch with me because
they know they have a sick you know
relative or something and they're
looking for answers stuff like that and
yeah you know happy to help them out you
know they're not they're not looking for
strains and stuff like that
I get people asking me for the Kem's all
the time and they
I have to just say no all the time so
yeah that's kind of hard yeah I can
imagine
and so what do you think is like a big
mistake people make when they're growing
the chem dog because for me it's you
know a lot of people say it's so finicky
so you know what what's something about
it that it likes that it or something it
doesn't like like m91 doesn't like a lot
of light I usually put him kind of on
the outskirts of the light they seem to
do a lot better Wow but if you you know
follow your your you know fertile
program and tender loving care they play
like a lot of cal-mag you know Dee likes
cow bag up until you know week seven so
just a couple things like that but it's
it's it's a very hard plant to grow yeah
so I mean I've thought about the same
that the Grateful Dead created and it
seems like you know it was like that
perfect storm for progressing the scene
do you think that it trying to create
something similar to that in a modern
sense would work out or you think just
the the climate is too different and
it's just yeah it's not it wouldn't work
in the same way yeah I think it's just
different I think people are just more
out in the open and trading things just
you know you can buy cuts on Craigslist
now so it's just it's a different time
we live and so yeah I don't think it
would I think it was just a just that
time that we were in and well do you
think they even like so much of the
masses are now newly jumping into
cannabis cultivation at least in America
do you think that that could be harmful
in any way because it seems like there's
a lot of growers who don't necessarily
know how to deal with a lot of problems
that could have flow-on effects like you
know
the climbing one yeah I think yeah the
cloning ones one and you know as for
that's for sure
you know get more people and but yeah I
definitely problems for sure the more
people growing and how do you feel about
what's you know widely regarded as
somewhat over-the-top rules in you know
you might not be fully involved in it
but I'm you know in the Oregon I believe
it is I've got you know some pretty
insane testing requirements how do you
feel about those testing is I'm kind of
up in the up in the air I'm testing
until they you know have like a
standardized test I guess like a no
machine that's this is the way it's done
I think they're kind of different
machines and so I really don't you know
the testing don't really believe in the
testing too much and if you have you
know twenty seven percent THC crystals
on your whatever flow bud and you know
you have in the chem test set twenty
percent or 18 percent
I think the chem crystals the makeup of
those eighteen percent or better than
the then the you know the twenty seven
percent on the on the other but I think
the crystals the makeup of those
crystals are stronger and better so I
don't you know saw a seventeen could get
you higher than a twenty seven so yes I
mean what do you think you know it's
obviously probably gonna be a guess but
if you did have to guess what do you
think that you know the average sample
of well-grown chem ninety-one does sit
up because you know like if that is the
strongest weed then we shouldn't you
know and it's not testing higher than
you know who cares about numbers yeah I
think that 91 and the for those day old
they test like mid-20s I think so it's
never you know like 30 percent or
anything like that
but yet they're the strongest strongest
strains that I've ever smoked so yeah
I'm not a big believer in testing yet
and so a final question if you could go
back to any time and get any seeds from
anywhere whether it be you know seeds
you could buy from earlier in the day or
just landrace seeds and you know you're
allowed to just obtain them what would
it be
man I think I'd have to go back to 1991
and take that out from G and take those
13 seeds from him no I you know I you
know those those are those are special
seeds yeah but like a nice you know a
nice African laminaria strain seeds from
Africa would be nice have you been
wondering about to go back to Amsterdam
in the 70s or you know early 80s and see
what they had I get some of that old
sensi seed stock something like that but
I think I'd go after those 13 seeds that
G found I was trying to bite you into
the Skelly seeds you gave it better oh
yeah have you tried
JJ's Nigerian yeah yeah that's that's
one of the better sativa so like kind of
reminds me of you know but all that weed
I used to get in high school from
different countries and stuff but it's
good the Nigerians great yeah it's great
yeah I just thought maybe that was where
the the African comment came from yeah
awesome so I think that brings us to the
end thank you so much for coming on pay
bud
is there any bones or shoutouts you
wanted to do just shout out to
Incredibles and everyone everyone down
there great company to work for go
and get some bars and pretty much every
dispenser in Colorado I think
Incredibles is in and shout out to to
Matt to to g4 you know doing what he did
with those seeds and you know thousands
of people thank you and my good buddy
Joe brand shout out to him if he's gonna
be listening I miss you buddy
and that's yeah that's about it awesome
shout out to my wife shout out to my
wife of course you spike my better half
yep thanks so much for coming on thank
you so they have it a big thanks to me
about Mike Kim family
[Applause]
nasty ODS 420 straya individual
[Music]
[Applause]
the Cannabis show for body enthusiasts