hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts
as always this episode was brought to
you by our amazing sponsors
seeds here now best in the biz only seed
bank with guarantee on satisfaction as
well as germination why would you go
anywhere else as well as 420 australia
and organic gardening solutions your
one-stop shops for 420 lifestyle and the
organic gardening needs
on this episode we're joined by the one
and only leo stone of aficionado
genetics to talk all things high-end
brands top shelf bud and strain history
let's get into it
alrighty so big hello and welcome to the
mastermind behind aficionado genetics
thanks so much leo stone for joining us
today thanks a lot and i really
appreciate it man
no worries so first question what are
you currently smoking on
uh
we haven't named it yet it's a cross
between uh cherry noir
which was a collab that uh
me and gene and i did
back in 2013 i gave a mail from my uh
pollen from my chem dog special reserve
mail and he put that on one of his
cherry limes
and uh that plant ended up becoming the
mother of one of the selections from
those seeds and to become the mother for
the white cherry truffle so we took that
mother and we put a testerosa mail on it
to see where it would take it it took it
in an entirely different direction so
i've been smoking on it for a week
and i've been talking to professor q
who's my partner
and uh you know he lives in france right
now and so i'm telling him he's like man
you you know what the [ __ ] are we gonna
we have a working title for it you know
but it's like you know we don't know
where we're gonna name it it's just it's
a new flavor we haven't you know we have
yet to you know come across so
we don't want to give it some generic
ass name that's not going to give it
some justice
yeah okay i mean gosh there's so many
questions i want to ask and i'm going to
forget a bunch of them i guess the first
one and the most kind of recent thing
you mentioned at the end there was the
idea of giving relevant names to strains
i've always felt like this is an
important point like you know someone
made a point in the past where they were
like oh you go give some awesome name to
a strain and then it turns out to be a
shitty strain like
yeah what do you think should be our
conventions around naming strains do you
think people should put an effort into
trying to make like you know name it
yeah
yeah it's like
it's like uh
i i think i you know it's it's the
identity of the strain
you know and if you go beyond that and
you go start like you know we're
breeders and you know your job is to
make strains connect with people and you
have to market those strains so you
connect with people and so
you know we really approach it it's it's
a lot like music to us
you know it's like
the
the the the name of the album the name
of the track
has to fit the song
and so it you know in our case as being
breeders for us it's like the name
really has to fit the strain
and uh when it comes to naming you know
it's it's an important aspect of you
know distinguishing yourself as a
breeder or a creator of strains
on what you name your strains it's what
it's it's the it's gonna be the world's
first
um it's gonna be the world's first
experience and interface with your work
they're gonna understand they're gonna
hear the name
they're gonna hear about it before they
even smoke it
you know 99.9 percent of the time so to
me it's the i it's it's it's the true
identity that you're going to give it
for the long term so i think that a lot
of
um a lot of thought a lot of really
careful thought needs to go into what
you're going to name your children right
so it's to me the same thing you said
with with with with what we go naming
strains not really a convention
um
we'll go into breeding a strain
and people will you know we'll go oh
let's call it this
and
you'll finish the strain at the end and
it just doesn't [ __ ] identify with
that name you got to call it something
different it's it's essence
it you know isn't exposed till you're
done making the strain and it's final
and it's fine in the final product
that's what you name you know and the
consistency of of your strands you're
breeding it's it's this is like a really
this is something i'm super passionate
about is is i think it goes often
overlooked because a lot of breeders got
to understand that every single [ __ ]
strain is its own brand it's not about
your company as the [ __ ] seed brand
yeah that's the umbrella you're the
carrier you're the worker bee the plant
is allowing you to take its pollen and
make certain crosses i believe that more
than anything you know but when it comes
to you know naming these things and
giving these things a life
and an identity you know uh it's it's
it's a huge [ __ ] process for us
because that's gonna that's
that's the life of the cookies right
let's say someone took cookies and [ __ ]
said and [ __ ] got lazy and was like oh
this is just f1 derb cross
you know does it [ __ ] taste does it
when you open the bag does it smell like
a plate of fresh cookies [ __ ] no but it
has its own identity you could open a
bag and smell cookies and
that's [ __ ] cookies and the labels
right there and so like our goal as
breeders is to establish that is to
establish something that's easy to
remember
but also inspires a sense of
the name is supposed to instantly
inspire a sense of value
or or or an idea or a myth or or
supposed to um connect with a certain
emotion you know that's what we try to
do when we strains you know it's like
you know who wants
real weed head knows what cat pisses
real weed heads know what cat piss is
but you ask your you know you ask people
hey you want to smoke wedding cake great
pie or cat piss
they'll probably pick the sweeter of the
straights unless they know what cat piss
is so you know the branding is really
important to me
yeah yeah on the money with that one so
a sentiment someone has echoed in the
past was that they were looking up some
names because they wanted to name their
strain this name so they're looking to
see if it's taken and sure enough it is
and then so they think of next in line
and then sure enough that one's taken do
you ever do you have a fear that that
day is going to come when there are
really no names
it's happy [ __ ] right now
there's so many strains
um we've been working on
in
um you know some of these strains take
years you know what i mean some of the
times you know we'll we'll we'll make an
f1 the f1 will just so [ __ ] fire and
it'll do great in testing
and that will just release f once but
when we're we're trying to
um
you know whether we're trying to take
something and back cross it or we're
trying to bring it to like f2 three or
four depending on what we want to
release because people want to you know
a certain modicum of variety um
i'm sorry i got high i lost my [ __ ]
train i thought i'm gonna be real with
you
[Laughter]
not the first time
we were talking about um the uh names
being taken
oh boom so this is my point because that
was yeah
so um
we're having that this year we're we're
looking up different strains that we've
been making you know things that we've
made back in like
2014 and um now those names are taken
you know so there's really a race to
you know this seems like there's this
race for people to [ __ ] you know put
different strains together just so they
could claim a certain brand name on
their strain and you know i don't really
have a beef with that that's just it's
just a phenomenon of the market you
can't [ __ ] about it it's something you
can't control so all you could do is you
know um adjust how you're going to react
and adjust how you're going to approach
strain branding you know when when we
had the creme brulee um uh we were
pretty in you know for the longest time
we were in um mendocino county now we're
based out of lake tahoe um but
mendocino's you know the same thing with
tahoe's it's really insulated um and
this is before you know instagram was
was really huge you know facebook
definitely was a thing but instagram
kind of changed the the landscape and
how people really interface cannabis and
learn about different brands so we
called our we uh we've been working on a
strain since 2012 called creme brulee
and when we the year we dropped it
uh bay exclusives also had a creme
brulee
and um you know it was kind of difficult
for us but i felt you know the best way
to approach that was just to be
respectful you know i wasn't trying to
step on bay exclusives toes you know i
hit him up i was like hey man um you
know you know obviously great minds
think alike i just want i just want you
to know you know i won't try to step on
your toes with this you know so in you
know in other aspects it really is you
know who has the biggest reach and and
what genetic is quality enough to to to
have you know their version of creme
brulee or their version of rose you know
um you know
get a certain exposure where people
recognize your version as as the
definitive you know creme brulee say you
know we got lucky with the creme brulee
because bay excuses crumbly rails was
really [ __ ] good but we had um you
know really good traction with the clone
getting out and uh uh kevin drawdry was
was definitely doing some selections
with with ziggy and they found some
bangers and so that you know that really
you know helped it so
um when it comes to that that's a really
you know
one are we running out of strains and
two what happens if you have a strain
that something's already called
something it's just it's just really
difficult you know we've been working on
the sangria for a while um we've been
working on that for the past two years
two three years
uh last year i believe it was i think it
was either compound
i think it was either compound or i
could be wrong it's one of those really
[ __ ] fire breeders but someone else
had a sangria it was just like a release
um
and so that's kind of the tough decision
we have this year is like are we going
to drop to sangria you know we already
had considerable traction with it in
europe so we're just going to go ahead
and
and drop it you know so it's it's the
risk you play because you could you
could risk as a breeder you could risk
pissing off other breeders you know
which is never a really good idea you
know and um you know and causing a stir
cause you know people have an extreme
attachment to their work and definitely
certain names you know that name if it's
catchy enough uh it's going to take it
you know this really going to put legs
on the strain where the the brand and
the quality itself
is what's going to you know
establish what's going to create the
platform for longevity for any
particular cultivar
so um
yeah that's a
very it's kind of a difficult one you
know because i've noticed this year
we definitely having a hard time
uh like like we've
made a merlot we made a cherry merlot
and we made a merlot
back in
and uh there's another really good
really [ __ ] talented breeder i think
his name is casey out of yerba buena
in uh in oregon
and or i think that's corazon i could be
wrong we might have to erase that i
might be getting people mixed up bro but
there's definitely um i found out
someone bred them alone i was like [ __ ]
it was really good it was really good so
it was like cool we'll just let them
have that you know what i mean like we
won't even try to you know fight for you
know fight for that we'll just you know
find a different name
um but yeah yeah yeah so okay it's hard
to find these days you have to get
really creative and more people are you
know now confectionary base strains are
are are pretty hot you know we get all
credit [ __ ] for being the first guy to
have a confectionary strain you know he
was definitely inspired me to have you
know to name my cookies cross creme
brulee you know before there was a lot
of you know back in 2013 before there
was a lot of this on the market
so
um
yeah what's interesting is i talk to a
lot of people and we often discuss how
you know you can draw a lot of strains
their roots back to chemdog and how
quintessentially you know it's it's
really involved in most everything but
how would you feel about the idea of in
say 10 years from now that same analogy
is being made with the cookie crew
because i can almost see it happening 4
you can see it happening you can see
the lines that um
see junkie jay beezy's working who's
killing it right now you know i don't
know these guys personally don't have a
vested interest in their companies i'm
i'm i love cannabis i'm a fan
you know when i'm doing my work i try to
not focus on what other people but as a
fan i like to follow other people and
see what they're doing because i'm a i'm
[ __ ] generally a big fan of cannabis
so you can see
jbz is killing it and a lot of his stock
is based on um on different og kush um
phenotypes and definitely the cookies
you know as cushman's as wedding cake
you know a lot of this these are these
are cookie derivatives so you know [ __ ]
did something you know pretty amazing
the cookies you know likes to breed true
it likes to mix with things and i think
we're going to see that in 10 years i
think
you know we're going to start seeing
maybe in 10 years a lot of these crosses
are going to come from cats like
compound or symbiotic
you know what i mean i guess it's
whatever is fire at the time but you
know something as definitive as cookies
hell yeah there's so many strains
crossed with but what [ __ ] did with the
cookies
forced people to really look further
into what lions are doing you know what
i mean i think he had he had
the cookie fam had a really good idea
had a really good feel for for what was
hot for the market at that time they had
a really good um
eye for selecting in my opinion uh
because when when i when i'm working
cookies crosses and i'm i'm in breeding
them and i'm out crossing them
i'm using
different parents um that that i'm
assuming that they used i get to see
kind of you know what goes into cookies
and and what's making you know all these
strains so [ __ ] f what's in cookies
that's making these strains so [ __ ]
fire you know
so um
i guess that brings us to the million
dollar question what do you think's in
cookies
uh
i'm not even touched that
what i do know um what i do know is that
there's definitely you know we've i see
a lot of hindu
a lot of hindu tendencies like if you
ever take
mendocino like laytonville in particular
spyroc area um you know kado peak area
is a really good
um example of how you know they've been
holding you know old hindu kush
varieties since you know the early to
late 70s
and so in these you know old hindu kush
varieties which tom hill later bred into
as the br deep chunk we still have
access to these seeds and so a lot of we
were seeing a lot of similarities a lot
of parallels between how the cookies
grows and behaves the frost profile the
noses and and and with and with the uh
uh the hindus so you know that could be
wrong you know what i mean i could you
could be wrong but it's just a general
it was just you know based on years of
observation and and having an
established pattern you know we're not
[ __ ] scientists but we definitely
know that observation is the cornerstone
of evolution so as breeders and and
intuitive breeders because we're all not
scientists we're not [ __ ] doctors we
basically use this observation so we
could see what's in a strain so when it
came to cookies
it really made me look so the cookie fam
has cookies and sherbet
and then there's the big debate about if
skittles
came from sherbert
and so i
i grew cookies next to skittles next to
cherry pie
next to sherbet i grew it next to royal
kush i grew it and i grew all next to an
old school urkel
and to me that urkel was
the most common denominator i found
between a lot of those strains i think a
lot of these really exciting flavors
that mandelbrot got out of out of his
royal cush lines that was was the
[ __ ] i thought it was the sour for
years until i took all these cultivars
and i grew up next to
the urkel and you could see
a striking similarity between all these
cultivars not so much in the cookies but
more in the in in definitely in the
skittles in in the sherbs um i saw a lot
of uh telltale signs um of erko a lot of
these really exciting flavors you know
um uh you know urkel urkel and og are
really the fathers of a lot of these
really exciting fruit flavors um that
have like these really strong grapey you
know almost vineyard kind of floral you
know bouquets so i wish i had my [ __ ]
reading notes with me
because it's really interesting where
you're getting at and so i try to look
at
what's making everything so hot in the
[ __ ] market right now what's the most
common denominator
you know certain you know populations of
strains when i say populations i'm
saying like populations of og
populations of of things that are
crossed either with gdp
or or urkel because you wouldn't have
gdp without the [ __ ] urkel so the
urkel is like one of the original
you know purple that was the original
purple strain that had this [ __ ]
incredible crazy flavor
and and so i've noticed that going back
to the urkel you know the urkels where
you wouldn't have cherry pie without the
urkel you know there were so many uh
similarities between cherry pie and
urkel that was that was unreal to me
same thing with the skittles the
skittles actually you know i don't think
it's directly
a descendant of urkel but you could
definitely see
i'm still trying to [ __ ] figure out
what's in skittles
but you grow it next to
an urkel you can't you can't help it but
to see the similarities
and so that's all we're trying to do
we're just trying to guess and see where
straight where flavors are coming from
but um you know some is definitive as
cookies
that's you know i think that's gonna be
something that you know like every like
now all these strains came from sour or
chem dog or og five to ten years they're
still going to be strands coming from
gelato
cookies and sherbet you know what i mean
it's they're good
yeah totally
and so i guess one of the questions i
wanted to ask quickly do you trust the
fire loss results on skittles
you know um
honestly i
i'm gonna be real since we're on the
podcast the philos results were
was what was what made
the finalist results was provided at the
time it provided the evidence where i
was like
obviously
you know the owners of this whoever
created this strain it's it's really
muddied and it's really foggy but what
philos did was
you can't argue with genetics right
that's a [ __ ] science
right but um also at the same time you
know the whole genome hasn't been
sequenced too and we know that and also
the thing with philos too it's it's at
the discretion of who who who who
you know
it's there's a lot of human error
involved where i work with a lot of
breeders i work with a lot of [ __ ]
nurseries and anybody a lot of people
are going to identify with this where
they get a [ __ ] tray of clones and
some clones are mislabeled or you get
plants from people and some plants from
this label so that's that could be a
possibility where something was
mislabeled and and that happened you
know what i mean and this is just based
on that one skittles test i haven't gone
back to the galaxy and and explored more
because as a geneticist it's hard for me
to reconcile
uh being it's it's hard for me to
reconcile the reality of a lot of people
submitting their their genetic data to
philos and all this data is siloed
and we're seeing this in genomics
companies like 23andme we're seeing this
with the new genomics blockchain company
called nebula where you know you have
you know these geneanomics companies
where data donors and in this case
breeders and growers donate their dna
you know and and that they'll sequence
it for a fee
and then at the same time that data for
a regular human genomics company that
that is going to be bought by a data
buyer that's that's why these business
models are so [ __ ]
successful is because data you know data
buyers that's a huge business
data acquisition for for for research
and especially when it comes to human
genomics is for you know personalized
medicine and so when we see where the
where the industry's going with cannabis
are we going to make personalized
strains for people's individual
cannabinoid systems
how you know what's the evolution of
genetics going to be so when it comes to
someone like philos you know i think
it's really cool i have a lot of respect
for
for what they did um but just to me as a
breeder i think there needs to be a
platform where um all the data is
definitely decentralized and it's still
owned outright by the data donors and
the data donors have a right to say you
know what you can and can't do with that
data
so you know that's you know definitely
how i feel about that
yeah so i think i went down a little
rabbit hole right there but
that's that's perfect i think i i think
what they're what they're they're they
were the first cannabis genomics company
you know so i've you know i have a lot
of you know respect for that but there
is
there is a huge possibility for all this
data to be abused
there is when you have siloed data you
uh the the data is in one particular
place i don't give a [ __ ] how much
security you have that's hackable
i mean this is why blockchain's huge
right now it's because you have things
on thousands of servers
and so you can't hack thousands of
servers but you could [ __ ] hack one
you know and i and
prior to me
you know you know doing cannabis
full-time you know i was kicked out of
the army for smoking weed but while i
was in the army i was i was intelligence
and so these are things that when it
comes to data you know information is
everything so i tell all breeders
protect your [ __ ] data this is nobody
knows how big the genetics market is
going to be nobody knows
how valuable that that is going to be
there's going to be huge pharmaceutical
cannabis companies that are that i can't
wait to buy all this data so they could
you know genetically modify strains or
they could there they could you know do
breeding marker assisted breeding to to
find certain strains and and to go and
patent those flavor profiles and that's
just one scenario
you know so it's to me when it comes to
the breeders work and their in their
data you got to protect that but you
know we definitely got down a rabbit
hole because you know you're the rootier
question was you know uh phyllo
sequencing you know the skittles and
philos work i you know i think that work
was great but at the same time there
just needs to be a platform where um all
the breeders could still control their
data and and who interfaces it
yeah i love it man let's keep going down
this rabbit hole so the next question is
um you know you just touched on like big
companies and like the legal side and
the need for security i totally agree
we we see people trademarking things
within the industry but we don't see
cease and desist being commonplace how
long do you think it is until that does
start to occur and we see what you kind
of predicted
i guess it's going to really depend on
you know my lawyer always tells me who's
who else who has the most money for
litigation
you know so whoever has you know
whatever company hones whatever said
trademark you know if they have a big
enough war chest it won't be a problem
you know sending cease and desist
letters and backing that up you know um
legally backing that up and financially
backing that up you know so i i
definitely see this as
um
it's difficult because it's a lot of
people are worried about exactly what
you're what you're talking about right
now
you know um what if someone goes out and
trademarks our our you know our strain
names or our brand
um and and sends us the cease and desist
so you know i think that when you're you
know mostly cease and desist unless
someone's stealing your brand you know
try a little harder to come up with
something more unique you know what i
mean so
um
you know like we we named the testarossa
you know when ferrari sends me a cease
and desist
it'll be it'll be both a horrible and a
great day
because we've reached that that level of
exposure where ferrari you know so i
think it's a good thing you know like
look at gorilla glue you know they got
beat up by you know by that company you
know they could have called it gg4 but
at the same time man josie wales and the
gorilla glue crew you're [ __ ]
your your your name in his in pot
history is etched in stone now you know
so you could i think you know there's
always you could in those instances you
could kind of turn [ __ ] in the sugar you
know and i think if you know these
trademark things are really difficult
you know trademarking different strain
names how do you you know how do you
you know reinforce that is it first to
file or the first to invent you know
what if someone invents something and
someone goes out and trademarks with it
you know there's this is a really this
is a
trying to navigate cannabis right now in
regulation to me is like playing
three-dimensional chess in a [ __ ]
dark room
you're constantly figuring you're
feeling your way things out you you
learn by making mistakes
you know what i mean and and you're
really just feeling in in in
there's so many dimensions and facets to
it that you're constantly having to
adjust fire and adapt to a new set of
circumstances so right now you used to
be able to call your strains whatever
and now if you're not careful
cert big companies will send you a cease
and desist like matt rise was one of the
first people to get a cease and desist
he had the uh
shatter brothers and the shadow brothers
and this was uh coming out of hopland uh
back in like you know
eleven two 2011
twelve matt ryze was one of the first
guys to popularize you know ice wax
extraction he was one of the he was one
of those guys and he also had a chatter
company and the shadow company had this
depiction of [ __ ] mario and luigi
making shatter
it and nintendo sent those guys a cease
and desist you know so
you know it's definitely you know could
be a bad thing but
damn matt you know
your exposure was to the point where you
got the nintendo's attention
so i don't know this could be turned
into a game by some breeders
but i think it's a slippery slope i
think it's a dangerous one
yeah definitely
well we hear talks about big players
getting involved in the industry even
like you know kind of well-known big
players i cringe to say that that dan
bilzerian guy has been in the news for a
minute what do you think about this type
of move do you think it's just like a
fad thing and do you think overall it's
a good or a bad thing to have rich
people getting involved in the industry
because i've kind of heard arguments on
both sides i guess
i mean here's how i feel about it you
know
um
you know with people like damn dan
bazillion
the guys you could tell by that guy's
[ __ ] ig feed
he's definitely a weak guy you know what
i mean if you're into guns
partying that kind of lifestyle you're
definitely smoking some [ __ ] weed
right so it's like i know a lot of these
guys
that come from that same that similar
worlds dan's world
and they're [ __ ] weed people you know
what i mean but that doesn't necessarily
mean that you understand the industry
you know this is kind of like
i'm not using dana's example he's a
different example i know the [ __ ] guy
um i just know him through his
reputation and he's getting you know
busy investing but a lot of these
corporate guys that are coming into the
industry and they think that it's going
to work out for them just because
they're [ __ ] rich it reminds me a lot
of when paris hilton tried becoming an
edm dj she got laughed off stage laughed
out of the [ __ ] industry there's like
oh that's cute
your money's going to be a panacea for a
lack of talent get the [ __ ] out of here
and so that's that's you know
how we feel about this is you know you
have all these corporate cannabis guys
coming into the game
and they don't know the game
people forget this shit's like [ __ ]
music
you feel me it you know rappers
rappers are like the growers in our
industry you know breeders are like the
producers
you know what i mean and so you have to
and at the same thing with with it being
like music
all the trends in cannabis start at the
street level
you know that was the magic of cookies
that was the magic of you know you take
anybody that's that was big from the
emerald cup you know dying breed mean
gene those [ __ ] guys they're all they
all got hella hill and street credit
you know i mean you you don't get to
that level without having that
connection you know with that street
aspect you know people forget it's like
oh yeah we're growing medicine but
can we all [ __ ] acknowledge for a
minute that california was the largest
producer of cannabis the entire country
growing the country's [ __ ] weed and
it all wasn't medicine guys
you know and so all that pushing
the trends of what's pushed on the
street and what's in demand happens on
the [ __ ] street level and it has to
be co-signed on the street you can't be
a famous rapper without being co-signed
by someone from the hood or being
co-signed by some um og in the industry
like p diddy or jay prince you know from
rap a lot records who you know who
helped create
shape and shift [ __ ] hip-hop as it is
you know right right now so it's like
with corporate guys coming in i think
it's you know i think that there's
something to learn from them when they
have these really really efficient
business process business processes um
and really efficient ways for
understanding markets in ways we guys
can't um you know understand the market
but just because you have those talent
doesn't mean that you could connect
with [ __ ] smokers that's why we say
it's like music you know an artist's
entire [ __ ] job
is to connect with people around the
world is is to put something take
something from nothing put his heart
into the studio and connect with the
world growers do the same exact thing
you know breeder lays the track he he
puts the strain into the grower's hand
and the and the grower is going to
express that strain in a different way
than any other grower
right and and so when that weed leaves
when that quality leaves that usually
goes to the street level or the quality
is going to be acknowledged at the
street level we don't see any corporate
cannabis guys coming in and just killing
the game right now you know selling you
know selling out the top shelf and the
street and everybody collectively
agreeing saying that that corporate
cannabis company is putting out top
shelf it just doesn't exist right now
you know so it's like you could put all
the money you can
but still big al exotics out of [ __ ]
santa rosa they're the first they're the
first company right now with a hundred
dollar eighth
you know what i'm saying it's like so
all these guys are trying to start these
[ __ ] brands and they all want to be
luxury cannabis and put this booth in
these really nice packages but if you
don't have [ __ ] street credit and you
don't have
you don't have the [ __ ] real dna the
passion
you're not willing to [ __ ] sacrifice
everything for your craft you ain't
gonna make it because there's guys out
there who are sacrificing everything for
their [ __ ] craft and that's the fire
that's the fire that's when it's that
good
that's what makes people remember that's
the music that's what connects with
people you know what i mean and so
that's was like as an artist
that's what the cookie fam you know a
lot of people talk [ __ ] i respect the
hustle you know i'm saying it's like i
came from [ __ ] nothing i didn't grow
up in mendo i'm a transplant i came in
mendo with a broken beamer with texas
plates and a broken windshield i was
pulled over all the [ __ ] time and so
to see people and so to interface that
street level and then see people like
the cookie fam use that to their
advantage and create you know make
history
you know connect with people in that way
really follow that music well and
connect people that way that's that
that's that's how you're gonna you know
reach success a lot of these corporate
processes these guys are these guys
don't know what the [ __ ] they're doing
to be quite honest with you some of them
do
but really it's like you're making money
right now but
you know a lot of people in the game
right now the real true believers like
big al and frenchy we're in this for the
rest of our [ __ ] lives
and so
that's who the corporate cannabis guys
got to deal with you know what i mean
just because you have a million dollars
and you like making shoes doesn't mean
that you're going to be christian la
bhutan tomorrow
or f or you're gonna
you know what i mean you're not gonna be
manolo blahnik tomorrow just because you
have [ __ ] money this is art
and that's what these corporate guys
don't get it's not a [ __ ] commodity
if you want to play commodities grow
your big ass outdoors and your
greenhouses and turn that [ __ ] in the
oil that's not our [ __ ] market that's
not the breeders in the growers market
you can't shape you can't create shape
and shift the history of cannabis
through putting boof on the [ __ ]
market
you create shape and shift the history
of cannabis by changing the flavor
profiles again everybody to agree that's
[ __ ] hot
you know what i mean
yeah it's like they don't seem to
understand that like trends and things
are started by creative people and then
people like them more so take over it
but yeah you touched on this perfect
idea right with with big al i had a
question perfectly lined up for that and
so
we've kind of seen in response to that
hundred dollar eighths of mac that cap's
you know capulet hasn't been too happy
and his argument was that he doesn't
want his brand associated with this type
of what he would call price gouging what
do you what are your thoughts on that
you know do you think a breeder gets to
have a say that extends that far out so
to speak
you know let me start from this level
you know cap's probably one of the most
talented guys in the industry right now
he's creating [ __ ] nobody's [ __ ]
creating you know only guys coming close
to cap right now is [ __ ] in-house and
c junkie
jbz
so with like
you know
being a breeder i understand i
understand why he's upset
i understand why he wouldn't want that
because he's the creator that's his baby
you know what i'm saying
but on the flip side i used to have
those those reactions too and then i i
realized that when you when you let
something out on the market it's it's
going to take its own life
um it could either be
a a success
or it could be a failure but as a
breeder you have to accept either one of
those dichotomies
it's up you have to because
control is a [ __ ] illusion and that's
what breeding taught me is that control
is illusion you can't control [ __ ]
especially when you send stuff down
range you send things down the pipeline
seeds clones
they're going to take a life of their
own you know
so
you know with cap being upset yeah i
just had a hard time understanding why
he would
why he why he wasn't so receptive
um to that kind of exposure but at the
same time he's really one of those true
believers like one of those really
down-to-earth dudes that that's not in
the flash and [ __ ] and he's really about
the craft so like i i genuinely see
where he's coming from
and i respect this point and but i also
have another side of me where
um i've always dreamed
of there being a luxury cannabis
component for people to participate in
you know that was why we started
aficionado that way back in 2012
is i was like [ __ ] if mendocino and
humble
can
can establish appellations a form of
prestige right like that you see in wine
then that would stabilize the long-term
price of of cannabis
and so on that same note like like if
you use bordeaux as a model where they
where they created the bordeaux apple
appellation in the mid-1800s and um they
got a premium on their wine it was then
up to the participating brands in
bordeaux
to make bordeaux bordeaux to make it
what it is today so that was the goal
was to make aficionado
this this this this apparatus that
allowed us to to participate in high-end
cannabis when the day came you know what
i'm saying
and so it's like
big owl was the first to do it he's the
first to sell 100.8
and everything isn't binary that's my
that's my thing it's like i'm not mad at
anyone per se but they say [ __ ]
binary
just because it's 100 eight doesn't mean
all samples of max are gonna be go for a
hundred dollars
you know but but we can't ignore that
price demographic you know people who
are students economics the luxury
industry is the only industry that
[ __ ] continues to grow despite
recessions
and so it's like you know if you're a
small guy
you don't have a huge [ __ ] corporate
war chest but what you do is you have
[ __ ] talent and you have quality
man where are these christian la bhutans
going to come from in our industry
where's the john paul gold ta's where's
the real louis vuittons you know this is
this is what's [ __ ] possible right
now so that's why i'm telling people
like stop you know don't don't
necessarily you know resist this new
[ __ ] phenomena this is a great thing
for small people because small people
are the only people who have the
prestige the heritage and the roots to
be considered a luxury brand because if
money and nice branding considered you a
luxury brand
then candescent be a [ __ ] luxury
event but they're not
there this is not so it's like you know
when you have you know what are the
prerequisites for luxury brands all
right well it's a unique know-how in a
particular area of expertise uh
your work has to have an incredible
attention to detail you have to use
different ingredients and and and
techniques and then other people use
it's kind of almost like food too you
know what separates a thousand dollars
you know 300 steak from a 30 steak you
know ingredients technique and timing
and so and also the prestige of the chef
preparing it
and so you need all these things to to
to justify yourself as as being raw
enough to command those [ __ ] prices
you know who knows the longevity of the
hundred dollar eighth but it's a [ __ ]
phenomenon right now and it's amazing
that someone from our community was able
to establish that was able to break that
boundary someone from our neighborhood
broke that boundary and not corporate
cannabis like why can't we just realize
that
because i bet you if it was some
corporate cannabis guys everybody would
be up in arms this would be [ __ ] up oh
corporate cannabis we knew this would
happen blah blah but then the pendulum
swings the other way the small guy with
40 [ __ ] lights selling hundred dollar
eights to migos
they opened that strain up to a wider
more diverse audience just because of
price point alone the laws of economics
did take that too there's an entire
demographic a clientele and customer
that only discerns value based on the
perceived price
if they don't know any better then how
do they know
well well price is one indicator where
it's like okay this obviously has some
extra level prestige but it better
[ __ ] it it it better be good
which is the whole thing and there's
arguments
whether you know was it worth a hundred
dollars an eighth
well [ __ ] millionaires like migos
definitely [ __ ] felt that it was
worth a hundred dollars an eighth and so
that's the trend that needs to happen
is that when you have these different
brands we're able to interface and open
new opportunities for small guys that
got the fire the big guys don't got the
fire it's the small guys
so this is a great this is a great time
for small people man it was like i was
happy as [ __ ] man i called frenchy this
is great
al's getting roasted but it's good
because he he's killing it every every
if you're angry
anger can't exist without fear you know
what i'm saying so it's like a
fear-based emotion if you angry it's
like what are you scared of is what i
want to ask a lot of these people not
necessarily cat i'm not talking to cap
in this
um particular context because i i hunt
hunterly wholeheartedly see where crap's
coming from because he's a creator but
with other people like other peoples
that are really chiming on
on on the subject it's like man why
can't you just be happy for for big al i
mean that yeah that that's capitulator's
beef but
something was done in the industry
that's going to help the small guy
more than anything else you know this is
a huge it's going to be a huge economic
force for for for guys that are at the
top of their game that got the [ __ ]
together and know how to communicate and
sell their strains you know right you
know what i mean and right now a big guy
was able to do that
cap's going to be able to do that too he
doesn't want to count he was going to
gouge people you know so it's like a lot
of these growers are going to come out
you're going to see crazy there's going
to be a price war but there needs to
also be a spectrum of brands
it just can't be
affordable cannabis it just can't be
affordable wine and affordable alcohol
you know people gave me [ __ ] about my
prices for years i'm just like deal with
it i'm sorry like i only make certain
you know so many strains per year you
know i [ __ ] sift through a lot of
strains and so this is like
you know only recently a couple hundred
boxes of each straight anyway so
yeah you know so but it's like it's
really in the eye beholder
yeah i i agree and i've spoken to a lot
of people who have these opinions and
what i find to be the most interesting
part of it all is that these same people
aspire to have you know luxury cars it's
like they're okay with luxury something
else but not in our industry
exactly
exactly and it's like you know
essentially we're
you know there are your people who like
to ball out our industry but you know
the cool thing about the industry which
is you know one of the positives that we
do have a lot of humble people
a lot of humble people that that that
don't need the flash
that don't need to you know when swerve
was blowing up back in the day posting
pictures of his jaguar [ __ ]
getting hated on
that's not necessarily our culture you
know saying it's like if if you're
flossing and you're in the weed game and
you were putting that on instagram you
were wrong because you're basically dry
snitching on yourself you know
like
it's so you know but but i like the fact
that the community has this sense of
humbleness to him because humbleness is
in and and lack of ego is what's needed
to to create true craft um but i think
once you create that craft
there needs to be a mechanism to be able
to open that craft to
what's the highest potential this you
know our market has as boutique
craftsman
we can't do we can't get a [ __ ] price
war with corporate cannabis that's for
damn sure
but you know what there's definitely
this huge underserved demographic
of of of uh you know of
you know upscale oriented customers that
want to indulge in this level of weed
and it [ __ ] exists
you know cats like big owl cats like
[ __ ] you know capulator and [ __ ]
compound these guys are growing the fire
like crazy fire you know and so
but i think that
we are they also
everybody collectively deserves more i
think you spent time in the game
and and you really cut your teeth and
you sacrificed everything i think that
it's a great [ __ ] moment when when
the market could acknowledge that you
know your your stuff is worth you know
you know x amount you know so i think
you could love her to hate it you know
you could sit in front of a rolex shop
you know with the timex on your wrist
and [ __ ] [ __ ] about life all day
saying oh i might watch tell sign better
and you guys are ripping people off but
that's just like that's just like you
guys got to shift your focus your
awareness from that particular
perspective and and broaden your
horizons it's like oh what are the
opportunities in this because if big al
could do it how many other people could
do it
and so like
we don't know what the longevity of
these price points are like first off
but but we do know that the luxury you
know luxury clientele demographic
continues to grow worldwide
you know that that's a fact
yeah so you know we definitely know that
and cannabis is quickly becoming uh
international canada has already taken
international u.s is we're really behind
right now on that you know because we
can have a serious edge but when it does
go international man when it does go
international we have to be cognizant of
this entire spectrum of customer who do
you want to sell to
you know that's cool if you want to be
jack daniels that's cool if you want to
be ever clear you want to be budweiser
we need these people we need those price
points in the ecosystem to differentiate
ourselves you know [ __ ] chateau
montrachet at thirty thousand dollars a
bottle needs box wine to create that
[ __ ] huge chasm of separation
that reminds people this is why you're
paying x amount for this bottle of wine
it's like i want to see that in cannabis
it's always been my dream to do that you
know we've tried doing that you know
we've been doing that with you know we
got really lucky we've been doing that
with seeds you know for the last seven
years but you know when it came to
flowers
anybody could smoke a flower only a few
people could grow seeds you know you
have to really know you know kind of
what aficionado is working with or knows
from back in the day to kind of really
understand our value you know we don't
think that you know we're big players in
the genetics game we're just really
really passionate about what we do
but only so many people could grow seeds
but anybody
anybody could smoke a flower anybody can
smoke hash that's what frenchie's power
is [ __ ] smokes out thousands of
people every month so everybody knows
the frenchie is right so the same thing
is with with with fire ass growers
anybody could experience that and so
it's like if anybody could experience
that
what place in the market do you choose
or wish to participate in
you know why limit yourself if you're
worth that
you know really like is is being aware
better than being humble you know or is
being humble better than being aware you
know which
which of these paths are we gonna choose
as as breeders growers and marketers we
can't
we have awesome to see like just because
you create a craft it's up to you to
[ __ ] now communicate this and market
it to the world it's value
you know so it's like it's it's all
everybody has choices
and big al made a choice and it was a
great choice and i just think it was
really it was i thought it was just
really unfortunate that
you know the tension between you know
big al
and and cap is there you know because
you know the two guys are are genuinely
good people you know i never met cat but
my partner leo you know knows him and he
says you know great everybody i know
that those caps has great things about
him this is nice guys same thing with
big owl he's like the most humble chill
[ __ ] a dude he just loves weed and so
it's like
i think you know
it it's unfortunate but there's also
a really cool potential for for people
to come back
you know to come back full circle and
you know maybe collaborate you know
someday down the future you know because
that's powerful what happened you know
whether you like like that i would have
sent a limo full of [ __ ] women to big
al's house if he did that with my strain
that's just me personally
just to start the thank you process you
know what i mean
because we need that edge small time
guys boutique cultivators
need a distinct edge over corporate
cannabis and this is what's happening
right now
you know like these guys are breaking
down [ __ ] doors so other boutique
cultivators can participate in these
markets interface these higher levels of
society because a lot of people [ __ ]
forget man even though a lot of trends
happen at the street level
trends also
par happen parallel at these really
high-end levels too
you know there's also there's also very
rich trend centers too so we can't
ignore you know if you're really in the
weed and you and your job is to get your
strain and you really want your strain
to connect with people not through hyper
[ __ ] but literally to be shared and
connect with people because your work is
good
that's something magical man
yeah
totally
so i think we might jump out of this
rabbit hole for a moment and go down a
different one
um
i just wanted to
just wanted to loop back on to a point
you made almost at the start of the
interview you mentioned the creme brulee
you had a bit of luck in that the clone
got out there and it brought up this
really interesting point of
what is it like to to have a clone of
yours that's like a really nice one
that's been found selected and it gets
out there is there a good or a bad thing
because on the one hand it's like you
know obviously there's good sides to it
but at the other hand it's like well if
people can get access to the clone
they're probably not going to buy the
seeds so how do you feel about it is it
good or is it bad no
like that's that's that's a that's
whoever's whoever's logic that was this
is wrong like right i mean like look at
all the cookie cross seeds
you know if cookie clone was on the
market you know you wouldn't have you
wouldn't have that the success of those
crosses i think it's i think it's it's
hugely i used to hoard
so this is me talking from experience
and and and somewhat regret that some of
my best work i didn't put into the
market you know you know um and that was
kind of one of the things i learned
working with kevin geodri back in the
day you know who had one of the biggest
nurseries at the time at home bolt
and um
you know in order for your [ __ ] to be on
the market you literally
like in order to be hot in the market
you have to have thousands of growers
growing this [ __ ]
and you have to have thousands of pounds
tens of thousands hundreds of thousands
pounds a year straight
touching people's hands across the
country across the world
you know so that doesn't happen unless
you let the clone out you know so
whatever you lose ownership you know
there's this there's this false
assumption people are going to argue
with me this there's a false assumption
that oh if i'm like the only one with
this cut
i'm going to hoard it and i'm going to
it
it you you limit its growth if you don't
let it out because yeah you can show the
world that you're the best at growing
you know any particular you know this
particular strain
but
growers and breeders we're all
competitive people like by nature like
that's why we compete with ourselves to
get better than ourselves why people get
better but we love showing our [ __ ] to
each other we love that and so
people love to say oh that was your
cookies look at my cookies you know and
that's part of that's part of the
culture too what helps a strain get out
there is when it's a joy to grow and
it's also
it's also it doubles as
it doubles as you know um
an opportunity for you to be able to to
express you know what your best possible
effort is you know so i think if you
have a fire strain you gotta let you
gotta let it out the market's gotta test
it you know because really the market
you could say it's fire all day long but
if people ain't cloning it and pound you
know pounds aren't flowing and the clubs
because people could clone it you could
have a million clones out there but if
the clubs or the or the streets hate
buying that weed again they'll buy it
you know i mean i remember when barry
white came out it's the frostiest strain
that hit mendocino in a long time and at
one year everybody grew it and everybody
bought it but one time you know so it's
like you get repeat buyers you know it's
like people say oh cookies is hype
it's not [ __ ] hype man millions of
people are still buying it they come
back and they buy it again
that's not hype that's that's real
yeah i totally agree so you know to have
that you got to put your strain out
there you got to put the clone out there
which you know i've i've felt i've
fallen i fell short on
you know the past you know five five
years
you know but i learned from you know i
had to learn from my mistakes to go okay
really the right way is to let it out
you know will you lose ownership of it
cool but if you really want to test your
work against the market and see how hot
you are as a breeder you got to put that
[ __ ] out there
yeah good plan so
take us back when did aficionados start
in your mind
like uh 2011
and what was the first project
you know it kind of grew out of um you
know i always had my i was you know i
started growing when i was in germany
and um i went to amsterdam a lot smoked
a lot of weed smoked a lot of hash
always brought seeds back um i just
thought it was cool that you know i
could collect these seeds then i started
hanging out with some german college
students that were growing organic
indoor
and um
they were breeding like they were
crossing their super silver haze to like
um you know straight up land races like
like afghanis and old school like not
not even lyrics but old school like
black dominance like [ __ ] you don't see
you know anymore and you know that was
really my crash course into you know the
next level of growing you know and he
this dude was just having fun he wasn't
like a serious breeder he was like
uh
i hate buying seeds so i just make my
own seeds so to buy seeds and it turns
out good
and i thought that was cool you know so
um after i you know got out of the army
in germany
i uh you know brought my seed collection
back to the states
and um you know met with you know the
guy who became my mentor you know
mendocino mike
and he took me up he took me up but you
know that aficionado kind of you know
was created out of you know when i was
growing
when you're growing the best possible
cannabis it just comes logical that you
have to breed your own strains right so
whether you have a
strain in clone form you know it's going
to come to the time where you have to
start breeding your own strains to have
a unique edge over the market like if
you get to the point where you can read
the market
and and and see what people want you
know that's when i really started taking
breeding seriously was when i was in
mendo with mike and um uh i then i
started on my then i got my own scene
and i did what every other grower does
to make ends meet you gotta
you gotta do business right you got you
gotta help your friends out you gotta
make sure that that that the right
things flow to the right pipelines so
the cool thing about that is you i was
able to like read the market in a way
where i was like okay i think people
want this
and so i'd make a cross not test it out
and i'd grow it out and the buyers would
like it and then it came to the time
where buyers were coming
and they wanted just all sours they
wanted all chem dogs they weren't all
sours but they were buying chem dog too
and this was like the headliners before
you know og you know really hit the
market in in the crazy bulk um up at
humboldt mendoza like chems and sours
were like the biggest thing
and so these repeat guys that were
coming back and making sure that things
were flowing they wanted uh they was
like look man if you could hook our
farmers up
with with with a strain that smells like
this consistently
then we'll we'll buy the whole crop
and so that was really i was like holy
[ __ ] i could probably i could like
because i've seen so much product
flow
you know in mendocino and humble i had a
good idea for like you know who the best
growers were what the hottest genetics
were i knew that even if the the the
buyers weren't coming into town that
even if even if this wasn't what they
were looking for all i had to do was
open the [ __ ] bag so like i've always
i found out early that all you got to do
is exceed expectations
so we created a chem dog strain
and
gave it to our friends we grew it the
buyers bought it all
and um that was we exceeded the
expectations of that chem dog and we
ended up entering that that next year
and so
you know when it came to
aficionados it was kind of like oh this
started seed company you know i was
really inspired to start the sea company
from shiloh massive before he started
dying breed um you know he had this
project called massive seeds that he was
doing like way back in the day
and you know that was like you know that
was really my first interface into like
you know the seed breeders world because
all the breeders i knew like the seed
breeders world that was like the
cannabis industry all the breeders i was
getting my seeds from in mendo you know
if it wasn't from europe were just like
these old these old growers
you know and so i was paying through the
ass for ogcs like that's why we came up
with our particular price point because
i was buying 50
a seed og seeds back in 2010
you know 2000 you know 2011 like that
was a real thing for me because it was
worth the investment so
you know it wouldn't have been without
those strains being an amendo with mike
that aficionado just ended up starting
to happen you know it just came as a
natural process of i was definitely
influenced by shiloh but i was able to
take the strains that i had i collected
you know i made with mike and i had
myself
as an a as a as a way to you know
communicate you know what if we could be
you know one of the best players in
mendocino
and how can we communicate that
and then you know we ended up winning
the cup our first cup in 2012 and that
kind of really
you know really helped you know launch
us into orbit with with people you know
knowing who we were
more buyers came up to us you know more
people that wanted you know a certain
flavor we were really good with gas
i got really lucky with that you know my
og was really good at you know selecting
things for gas crossing things for gas
and you know my later friend you know
alan atkinson who who founded probiotic
farmers alliance and growkashi
uh he was really good at selecting for
gas and selecting for good flavor too
and so you know learning from all these
people
um having that you know um that
you know opportunity to you know to meet
shiloh through allen and to to get my
first glimpse at you know what really
the cannabis industry was like the above
ground cannabis industry that was a
different world for me i was completely
off grid and black
you know for a long time you know i was
kicked out of the army so when i was
kicked out of the army it was like [ __ ]
it's either sink or swim i definitely
ain't getting a job so i had to make it
work you know so you know transitioning
from straight
you know the underworld to seeing this
kind of medical quasi-medical you know
cannabis movement happening cali was was
just [ __ ] mind-blowing
you know it was like it was a different
world for me so that's really you know
what aficionado was born out of
and at what point did you decide to
bring frenchie on board and more
importantly
it was kind of like a bit of a
forethinking thought on your part what
was it about frenchie that you thought
like this is going to bring something
new a twist to the usual
we he met i met him after i got off the
stage
and woke up in
2012. um
because i remember he cut he came out to
me and he was like he gave me this big
hug he didn't even know me and he was
just like
really happy that he was like because a
lot of people when they win the cup you
know they basically pull their dick out
and they flex oh you know and i i never
thought i would was gonna win [ __ ] all i
was like if i get top 20 i'm at least
part of the cool kid crowd you know what
i mean i just wanted to be acknowledged
as a grower that was my thing i just
wanted like my whole you know it wasn't
like i bred so i could keep growing fire
for myself and so i could keep hitting
the highest ticket possible
you know what i mean but when i met
frenchy man
he was just really happy that when i won
i thanked my soil guy
i thank jim rogoff for making me some of
the dankest compost in the world and i
was just you know super humbled you know
just you know to be lucky enough to you
know to be able to express a plant to
that level you know where we got so when
frenchie
you know when i met frenchie
it was just kind of like this instant
connection you know what i mean like you
know when you meet somebody you swear
you've seen him before but you know you
never seen him before but you have a
feeling you've known him before that was
the thing you know i see this guy you
get that feeling then he opens a jar of
hash
i never smelled hash this [ __ ] loud
man it was it looked like
it was some mk ultra from some growers
down in santa cruz
and and i was like dude i've never
spelled hash like this he was like
if your [ __ ] hash doesn't smell as
loud or if louder than your flowers then
you [ __ ] it up
and i was like dude we gotta do it was
right there like really that five-minute
span was like dude you're my hash guy
like forever
and
we've been loyal to each other ever
since man like i've never taken other
people's opportunities to make cash for
them or have other people make hash it
was like you know french is one of those
day ones man
where it's like you know you have a
special connection and it was like
it just ended up it wasn't planned
we we ended up just being
really compatible and we had we ended up
sharing the same vision
you know he's french and he was a he was
a bag designer back in the day and he
has a certain idea for aesthetics and
and for and for refinement and that's
what i always aspired to to have those
sensibilities you know i kind of grew up
in my family wasn't rich you know they
were middle class but you know i had to
earn and work for everything i had as a
child you know nothing was given to me
so
um i have i've always appreciated people
that had that that that that
that
that sense of aesthetic that friendship
has that sense of refinement that we all
wish we could pursue at a higher level
so you know frenchie was the biggest
blessing man he was the he's been the
most solid guy in my life for the past
seven years
like uh he's family
you know so i'm really lucky that you
know we share the same vision on a lot
of things
and you know when it comes to organic
growing
it comes to where the where the company
should go
you know frenchie's definitely you know
he's he's the [ __ ] dude where i'm
like if i make a big move i run up my
friendship first okay french what do you
think about this
yeah for sure i know what it's like to
uh to have a guy like that that's solid
it's good
so i guess kind of leading into the next
question the previous idea of like you
guys are expanding beyond the typical
breeder and i think that people would
commonly identify cookies as doing this
you know expanding into like a lifestyle
type of brand do you feel like this is
the natural progression for all breeders
or and why not yeah why the [ __ ] not so
some breeders are going to choose to
participate at that level and and some
don't
you know so some won't want to and
that's up to them
you know um
[Music]
i think it's cool man like why not man
if your shit's that hot and people want
to support you and hop and hop on your
train then man that's a that's that's a
cool thing man like i respect people's
hustle
a lot of people like to hate on people's
hustle but a lot of people forget that
these are just ideas
one day you know and they and then they
fruited
now they're now it's fruited into a huge
[ __ ] brand that took a lot of work
you know what i mean and so it's like if
a breeder is willing to do that and do
all that work man
um you know
i [ __ ] salute you you know i have my
own plans for how i want to express my
merchandise you know later in the future
but you know it was just to me i wanted
to really you know i really want to
focus on that craft
and not go all right you know because
once you start
i'm a control freak so if i if i did
that i'd have to control the you know
the the merchandising and the branding
of it all but for me it's just as a
breeder i wanted to focus on that craft
so when the time comes
um for me to branch out then
you know hopefully it'll be the right
time and i'll execute it right but i
think breeders i think it's great man
turn it into a huge lifestyle brand
because it is a lifestyle people hate on
everything but this is like the cannabis
lifestyle is [ __ ] amazing and it's a
lifestyle that when you're in it you
never want to leave it and everybody
dreams of being in it and so you know i
don't understand why people you know
hate on these brands you know like you
know jungle voice gets a lot of flack
you know and we and a lot of people
around the globe could talk a lot of
[ __ ] about jungle boys but why is why
are they the only ones making that
hustle work the way they're working it
you know what i mean there's like that
there's magic in that you feel me it's
like you know their whole concept
approach to branding i don't know these
guys frenchie knows them he's really
cool with him but i just respect hustles
in general because all this [ __ ] came
from [ __ ] nothing
you know what i mean and you're able to
to connect with people in this manner
where they want to wear your [ __ ]
clothes and support you communicate to
the world that these are the
[ __ ] i support whether you
agree with it or not
it's like music not everybody listens to
future not everybody listens to to these
new rappers some people choose to listen
to older rappers like biggie and tupac
but that's at your discretion but that
doesn't negate the fact that these
clientele are there and people want to
[ __ ] support these [ __ ]
people want to get behind certain brands
and be like this is this is my identity
i'm a weed person and i identify with
this spectrum in the weed community like
that's [ __ ] cool man i think there
should be more brands that come out and
flex
and and and try to do a lifestyle brand
because if you're raw and it's real
it'll catch on
yeah
certainly what is what's the saying real
real does he's real or whatever god
yeah real like yeah that was like i
didn't learn that one until i came into
industry either like like the above
ground industry like this whole
real recognized real [ __ ] you know what
i mean like i didn't have that when i
was hustling it was like were you on
time and was the money right yeah i mean
it's like not real recognize real is
this [ __ ] does what he says you
know what i mean and so it's like the
whole real record i mean it's like it's
subjective
yeah what's wrong you know what i mean
let's i mean to me to me what's real is
like you know i look at his authenticity
in in the game
yeah you know at least sacrificed it and
you really you were really you know
you you're really in the culture you
know working for you know working to
better your craft and really going to
the shows connecting with people you
know that's the real work that's the
real hustle you know what i mean
yeah yeah i think there's there's
definitely tibbetts of truth you can
draw from it like the idea of are you
doing what's good for you or what's good
for you as well as good for the
community
yeah i mean
it's an interesting one but
yeah that's like [ __ ] it's a good one
it's like you know do you want to do
what's good for the community or do you
want to break boundaries
so it's like if you want to do what's
good for community you wouldn't have
sold 100 eighth
but if you want to break boundaries and
make history you sell 100.8 so it's like
what do you do
i'm the kind of person i'd rather make
history you know what i mean so it's
like
you know uh a lot of people in the
community were against the high prices
of aficionados back in the day but we
wanted to make a point it wasn't because
we you know we thought we were the best
breeders you know because you know i was
working with me and jean back then in
john and q
and um it was about showing the [ __ ]
very best that emerald triangle had to
offer so i think it's like you know how
do you want to communicate
to the world what you do
yeah totally well that brings us to the
next question i was going to say
the pricing of seeds is an interesting
topic and in the past you guys have
copped a bit of flack for the seed
pricing how would you generally answer
someone who was say critical of a more
expensive pricing model in general
it better be good
it better be good that's the only reason
why it works you know some and all you
know let me let me say this straight up
for everybody when you're playing
genetics
it's it's it's a it's a game of
statistics it's just a matter of time
before you release something that's not
good it's it's a there's going to be
some seeds and a fire-ass batch of seeds
that aren't going to work out for people
you know what i'm saying so if you're
going to compete at a certain price
point um your testing better be on point
your selection better be on point or
you're gonna get [ __ ] roasted
you know what i mean you have to have
incredibly high standards and i think
like depending on how you choose to
price your seeds that's the hardest part
what is this worth
you know what i mean just because you
say it's worth something doesn't mean
people are going to buy it
that's the hard part about that
you know it's like you know we got lucky
you know we tend to sell out every year
but
whenever we think about what do we price
this at you know is is is that's like
that's a huge conversation for us every
single [ __ ] year you know things are
changing now
you know back in the day when we first
came out we were
part of part of aficionado was so we
could establish you know one of the
world's first luxury cannabis brands but
really it was
we wanted to sell we wanted to sell to
the kind of guys we were selling packs
to
we wanted to sell people that like
didn't look like weed people but we're
moving a lot of money in the weed
industry a lot of your growers don't
look like wee people that's like regular
people
and those are the kind of guys i wanted
to market to i was like if you were
willing to spend
500 on a box of seeds
you either one would do everything
[ __ ] possible to make sure you're
going to grow the [ __ ] [ __ ] of that
500 box of seeds or two you're raw
enough where you're going damn
i got 10 seeds
worst case scenario i'll get 50 females
that's five plants back in the day the
reasoning was like oh five plants that's
five to eight pounds of plant
you know saying make my investment way
over you know so but those but
that that market dynamic doesn't exist
anymore you know what i mean um you know
now
fire genetics are accessible at all
kinds of price points you know so when
it comes to pricing you know we're
always going to have a high price point
straight because there's things that
we've been working on for a while and
that just stand out but you know um it's
definitely something that needs to
change with the times you know
yeah
we're always going to have our our 500
you know to 800 boxes of strains those
will sell out and people always auction
those we don't have control over that
and that inflates the value too but you
know um
i also know what it's like to not have
the money to spend on like 500 you know
boxes of seeds so you know we definitely
have some more accessible strains coming
out this year for people that you know
want to be able to experience it but
we'll offer at a lower price point is it
going to be like less quality we're
actually like you know some of our best
we're going to put at that lower price
point you know what it means just to
make a point
you know because we understand that but
but you know
it's it's a it's a difficult concept
when you when people talk about pricing
because it also goes like your brand
like what's what's the goal of your
price
you know what i mean like i'm only going
to make these strains once so that's why
we price them that way but i think if
you're going to make them over and over
then they have to not be
then
that level of prestige pricing doesn't
work
you're going to end up frying yourself
and people are going to feel like they
got cheated or you're just you're going
to turn into another doggy's nuts
remember doggies nuts back in the day
they were selling
seed packs and everybody upset with them
yeah they were like that's
come out of the blue selling similar
seed packs you know what i mean so
yeah okay so i that's it brings up a
good question you know what would you
say to someone if they were after one of
your more expensive strains specifically
but they just didn't really have the
financial freedom to get it you know do
you have any kind of creative solutions
um you know
usually we we hear a lot of these
i stay off the gram do i don't do any
business on ig that's my role so
um it kind of sucks i can't interface
with consumers on that level on ig
because when we do have that interface
it's usually on a show
yeah you know i meet all kinds of people
at shows there's like you know they'll
show us a lot of love and they'd be like
yo really i don't have enough money for
this but i have this
i'll hook you up man it's like you know
especially like you know i i give a lot
at the show
like
for a year they didn't want me to sell
seeds at the show because they were like
bro you you hook everybody up
you're too [ __ ] nice you like you
know because i really just want people
to grow you know like aficionado the
brand and the pricing is to show the
world this is the potential in northern
california so i want people to stop
taking it seriously i'm trying to do
something for us so we can you know so
i'm trying to be a part of this
ecosystem so more people could you know
build up this ecosystem to make more
high-end brands across the world
you know
i mean through i mean across california
yeah well i i think you could argue
it'll extend across the world i don't
think a lot of people are familiar with
your refund policy but let's just kind
of put it into question form what would
you say to someone if they said they
were kind of unhappy with a pack of your
seeds or something along those lines and
does that ever really happen
yeah happens all the time i mean it's
genetics you know i'm saying everyone
has different rooms and environments
it's not gonna it's a [ __ ] seed and
so it depends everybody grows
differently um and our seeds are grown
in a certain environment so it
definitely happens but um i try to make
an effort you know if
we've had a few email accounts shut down
um and get hacked over the last past few
years so it's been you know kind of hard
for us to get back to people
but we always try to replace the packs
especially if it's at a show i'll just
hook you up if you're like unhappy and
you show me your certificate like this
was garbage it's like i'll just give you
a pet
like here you go you know but if if you
hold on to the seeds you don't open them
we'll buy it back from you
but you know we'll only pay the
wholesale price because that's what we
get paid we'll pay you what we get paid
you know what i mean and i do that every
year i can't wait till people come up to
the booth can't wait for that [ __ ]
people to [ __ ] sell me back my seeds
because the first three years we sold
everything like everything so
we know we didn't have a whole lot of
white cashmere seeds left we probably
had like 20 30 of those left and so like
when someone came by the booth last year
and they sold me back they wanted to
they wanted
me to buy back two boxes of cashmere i i
gave them you know more than the
wholesale price at that point because i
really wanted those [ __ ] packs
yeah and it is an interesting point and
i think that it might be something which
continues into the future do you think
that's just a part of the the high
kind of prestige and value of the brand
or do you think this might even be
adopted yeah it was
the the function of it was so your
australians always have value
you know if louis vuitton follows a
certain model that's why i never find a
louis vuitton at a [ __ ] thrift store
because if you take a real authentic
louis vuitton perspective louis vuitton
they'll give you cash for it
it always holds the cash value
and i was inspired by that um when doing
aficionados i was like
you know if these things are still
sealed up
and and
the the vials and the boxes are set up
in a way so we can preserve these
[ __ ] things
you know um i'll buy it back we will buy
it back you know we thought that was a
great thing i can't that's that's i'm
stoked every time someone keeps a box
long enough for me to buy back because
chances are i probably don't have boxes
of that strain because we sell
everything
you know it's we sell everything we make
we make we make new stuff every year
and you know um you know that's just how
it is
so over the past say five to ten years
at least as far as i can see there's
been this growing demand for the use of
growing from seed outdoors you know
there's plenty of advantageous region
reasons particularly the taproot and all
the benefits it brings with it with that
in mind do you consider the idea of
catering to these kind of outdoor
growers who are looking for like your 50
or your 100 pack seeds
yeah so um
when you were local in mendocino in
humboldt i had a uh
there was this rule for a long time if
you knew me
if you if you knew me personally or or
you knew me through a friend
you know i get and i'd give you free
seeds if you lived anywhere between
arcata and ukaya
you know so for the longest time i was
you know and that was kind of you know
the thing with you know back in the day
with when i was working with me jeans we
always had the homies come by the booth
and we always gave them seeds because
you know we came from points like you
know even though
like when i was making my own seeds and
doing my own thing before aficionado i
was like just giving them away to people
like hey how does you know see how this
is this is something i made you know
with mike back in the day you know what
i mean like tell me how it is
and so it's like i've always given the
homie seeds so it's like what am i doing
i'm going to charge you now that i have
a company so it's like i always you know
made an effort to show love to the
growers that made all the magic i always
saw the growers in humboldt mendo as the
the key
the key the the key clientele that that
could help are these strains you know
reach a new level you know so when it
came to those guys you know hell yeah
you know but these are mostly on a
personal basis where i'll you know i'll
break you off like 50 to 100 seeds you
know to to sift through
you know but we're seeing that that's
going away now you know the days of
growing big ass outdoor plant patches
you know that's going to get smaller and
smaller because the name of the game now
is clones and tissue culture and getting
that consistent canopy
so
you know the breeding's going to change
the corner that we're always going to
breathe outdoors we're always going to
breathe for outdoor people we're always
going to have those strains because
that's what we are before anything i was
a [ __ ] outdoor grower you know that's
like
that was my passion and so like you know
we'll we'll we'll make some strains
indoors but we'll always make our best
strains outdoors under the sun like
that's that's a rule we just can't
[ __ ] deviate from
and do you believe that seeds produced
organically under the sun give like the
most healthiest and optimal seeds or do
you think that 100
100 people say it doesn't matter and
i'll go okay cool
cool let's take your pregnant wife stick
her in a closet for nine months and feed
her pizza and [ __ ] soda you know put
a light on her should probably survive
but i guarantee that [ __ ] baby ain't
gonna turn out good you know what i mean
yeah and so it's like the the inputs
30 000 genes are in the cannabis plant
every input matters right and so if we
look at that
and we're geneticists where it's like
all right i want to give this dna
everything it needs
to be successful for the next person
that's going to work these lines
i need to give this genetic everything
that it evolved to uptake and have
i mean people forget that this this
phenomenon of of cultivation is wholly
happened in the span of the last
60 years you know what i mean in in big
cannabis cultivation this phenomenon has
only happened you know [ __ ] the last 10
years
and so it's like
people have to also remember like this
plant evolved for millions of years
under sunlight and organic inputs
and and that's just a [ __ ] fact so
when it comes so that's our that's our
that's the our core philosophy
is providing the plant genetics
everything that it needs you know every
everything that it evolved to excel with
you know and then we'll try to
supercharge that aspect
um but i think that nutrition of your
seeds is so important man when i see
people fertilizing seeds but with
salt-based nutrients i'm like it's not
the same it's not the [ __ ] same you
take you take two prize fighters
right you could take two prize fighters
like let's say we take two clones
and and and you [ __ ] make seeds that
are that are inorganic
with salt-based inputs grown on rock
wool and you make seeds that are made in
soil that have a high amino acid content
have you know um a high content of
organic matter have high content of of
of minerals you know because a lot of
the problems isn't an mpk problem in
plants it's a mineral deficiency so it's
like you know in genetics the genetic
building blocks are all built on these
essential minerals and amino acids you
know so it's like it's essential to have
these inputs present in the soil and
present in your regiment just get your
[ __ ] seeds in your babies to have
their very best start so if you take a
prize fighter
and you feed one you know you feed one
the right diet he's supposed to eat and
the other one you feed him vodka and
pizza before a [ __ ] fight you know
you're definitely going to see the
difference you know i see the difference
in people's genetics when they when they
don't when they make seeds without
without organic inputs i see a distinct
difference
yeah totally
so
how would you feel about people making
f2s and f3s of your line for their own
use and i guess in general how do you
feel about people breeding with your
work
that's the biggest
gift you could do for me
it's like it's it's
you know people think that the gift
stops when you buy the seeds and you
grow it out but man when you choose to
to f2 it f3 f4 it
man that's awesome
kill it get it man make that line your
line because at least you're working it
they're doing the work you know what i
mean there's a lot of work that goes
into that [ __ ] and so it's like anybody
who's willing to do that man like
nothing but love and respect man
like [ __ ] let's share some seed stock
give me some ears i'll give you some of
mine you know it's it's all kinds of
opportunities for that man so when i see
people work the genetics man that's just
like the
the greatest gift
it's like the best complete circle to me
it's better than the it's better than
you know than selling the seeds it's
that's that's the to me that's the the
um the validation as a breeder when not
only has it expressed itself good enough
in flower to meet their you know to meet
their expectations
but it's exceeded their expectations to
a point where they choose to continue
working that line
and so that's just the hugest most
humbling gift to me
so in a previous episode we had me and
genon and he said he really enjoyed all
the work he's done with aficionado but
one thing he felt was that it carried a
bit of a labor with it for like being
the absolute best and he said that he
just felt like that was a lot of
pressure do you kind of agree with that
do you feel the pressure sometimes i
remember when gene was talking about
that man
because he would have every year he'd
have something that was crazy fire
and but if they do be the but i don't
think it's good enough for aficionados
like having to meet that bar is pretty
[ __ ] stressful i'll tell you what bro
like
just to keep
doing that and meeting these
expectations is is is uh i think
i was a little short-sighted when i
first came up with that concept but i'm
already all the way in i got to keep
swimming i can't drown now i got to keep
swimming i got to hold that line
and so
i 100 percent feel gene on that and like
you know when you're trying to meet that
level of quality and expectation it's
almost
um unsustainable
really if you really think about if you
want to be hella real like it's it's
almost unsustainable
and so i think it also
it also inhibits you from making other
experiments you wouldn't otherwise
because you're so focused on putting the
best out and you're always so focused on
having the most elite [ __ ] i mean look
at what symbiotic did with larry og and
gdp they created the purple punch you
know [ __ ] what you say that's just not
hype that's beautiful i've sifted it
this year
that's crazy you know what i mean it's
like so you know when you're in this
mindset of like man we only have to put
the most exclusive genetics the best
possible genetics on the market i mean i
think it kind of takes away from the
artistry because you're always trying to
meet a certain expectation you're not
doing it um just for the love of the
game you know and i got to be real you
know when um
when when gene and i kind of went on our
separate ways i think that was a point
in in my game personally when um when we
don't think my head was all the way in
it i think that was that probably that
that was probably one of those that year
i think
based on just how long i've been doing
[ __ ] i got lucky with my selections you
know what i mean i got lucky with the
selections and i was able to to to meet
a certain mark and expectations for
people
but uh it's it's a it's tough
it's tough trying to [ __ ] always hold
that line and do it you know it's like
what gene's doing right now with his
lines is crazy it's really cool you know
he could do anything he [ __ ] wants
you know
like that and that's that's music to me
you know what i mean so you could do
anything you want that's freedom you
know you can really make good music so
that's one of the reasons why we started
a french connection um with my partner
professor q
um was it's a it's an outlet for us to
be able to explore a lot of these more
contemporary flavors
and find new flavors that necessarily
don't fit the aficionado paradigm of
what people expect but
you know are something that can still
exceed all expectations you know what i
mean like you know the the genetics you
know symbiotic and sea junkie are
working with they're not the most
crazy exclusive genetics
but they're incredibly good breeders and
that's why the quality comes out of it
they're able to to select and find
things out of you know normally found
strains you know and some rare strains
and create something entirely [ __ ]
different
in in in pivotal you know so that's the
magic of it so you know going back to
your thing with like
you know uh yeah it was hella [ __ ]
hard i can't blame him you know what i
mean
i can't blame him
yeah so tell us a little more about
professor q i don't think people are as
familiar with him as they are yourself
man
sorry in spanish
two years ago right frenchie goes to
span of this a week before me
and um to do about two classes and i
tell frenchie before i go to spain i'm
like
i'm looking for the [ __ ] skunk
frenchie
at the time you know before duke diamond
released all skunk crosses and stuff you
know we were talking to james you know
there was a bounty you know everybody
had a bounty on skunk right so i was
like i'm gonna find this you know
because you know being a that was
that was the unique edge i had an
aficionado wasn't that not that was the
best breeder i was really able to find
good genetics because i was able to find
the good pounds you know i was a hustler
right so he finally got pounds like
who's a farmer who does this right so
with quentin
um frenchie puts the word out at his
class to all the french cronies and goes
i'm look we're looking for a skunk
and then two weeks passes by we're at
spanibus
and he's two
shady ass looking [ __ ] french
gangsters coming up to the table
with a big ipad
and they're like are you leo
we're looking for leo and i tell my
partner's the booth it's like it's about
to get heavy guys
i don't know what they want but it's
gonna be ugly
and they have these mean mugs mean
mugging ass faces and i look dude looks
at me it's like uh we represent quentin
he's like we heard you looking for the
skunk
and they pull out the ipad and they show
me pictures of the of the skunk
it looks like skunk you know they said
they got it from high pro
um
and you know this the french people been
holding it directly from high pro who
got it from uh flying dutchman so it's
like a verified
flying dutchman cut of the uh roadkill
skunk
and so they show me a sample of the hash
and i'm like well where's this dude at
he's like well he doesn't want to come
and spam it but he wants to meet you at
like
you know he wants to meet you at a
private location so i'm like oh this is
kind of weird
so you know he tells us to meet him we
meet him at this bar
and then uh we go we're at this bar
and
the waitress is super nice to this
[ __ ] guy like you know and he's the
most humble guy he's like he's just some
tall guy he looks kind of he looks like
a gangster but he's like the most humble
you know calm you know soft-spoken dude
you know you'd ever [ __ ] meet you
know and so we were just talking and he
was like yeah i have the skunk and you
know i want to you know i want to offer
it to you guys i want to be able to work
with you guys
and
he was like come up to come up to the
countryside near the french border i
want to show you my place
and so i you know after the cup after
spanish we went to his place man and he
lived in the most beautiful part of of
spain outside this town called girona
which is where they filmed a lot of the
episodes of game of thrones
and so he had this grow there that was
so [ __ ] clean you could eat and off
the floor
and he was so passionate about you know
working with aficionados he was like
i'll give all this up
to have a chance to work with you
and and he left it at that and then for
like the next week he showed us the most
beautiful places of spain and we just
chilled it wasn't any business and i
just had a really good feeling about i
mean this dude could look at any [ __ ]
plant and tell you the scientific name
of it it's like ridiculous
and he went to france's uh
you know their equivalent to mit of
horticulture and it's the university and
teams where he specialized in tissue
culture and um
and breeding
and so it was like it was a it was kind
of like
meeting him
was almost as [ __ ]
magical as meeting frenchie like that
was made to happen and then it just so
happens that
the guy that's kind of quentin's og
from back in the day in nice france
was frenchie's homie they were partying
within goa
it's [ __ ] crazy like how does this
happen
it's like we didn't i was like dude this
is crazy it's like you know and so quinn
had to come you know he came
uh to california and you know we
restructured the company and i was like
bro you know you're my [ __ ] dude
you know i want to like let's let's take
over the world together and so you know
um now he's a full partner in aficionado
and he's like you know he was definitely
you know one of the best breeders
best botanist horticulturist i've ever
met man he's one of the most passionate
people about plants you'd ever [ __ ]
meet one of the most knowledgeable
people about botany it's unreal he's
like how do you know so many scientific
plant names and where they come from
like that's just unreal he's not just a
cannabis person he's a [ __ ] plant
person that's like the magic of
professor q
you know so him having the skunk was
just like an entry into you know under
just scratching the iceberg of like this
guy's potential
you know like me and french he looked at
him we were like you know talking was
like man this guy's gonna be [ __ ]
huge one day
he was gonna be huge
you know so
and he was also generally a good guy so
i was like look man this i want to work
with you you know but i don't want to
make the mistakes i've made with other
breeders where i didn't really play my
cards right so
you know you're so raw you're going to
want to do your own thing one day
so
let's work on aficionado and let's build
a company around you too your own brand
where you could where you could [ __ ]
express yourself and you could be your
own person you know and and it'd just be
kind of like this record label [ __ ] and
he was down and that's how it's been
working you know so we both work on
aficionado and then like you know french
connection is is is our opportunity to
to to do really exciting things in
europe with a lot of really badass
french operators because when frenchie
and i went to spain
it's universal the best [ __ ] growers
in europe are in the uk
and and france i'm sorry all my french
people my spanish people listen to and
alberto i know you're in barcelona right
now yes you're one of the best too
so but but universally man the guys in
france and and uk man they brought some
[ __ ] heat we saw some crazy [ __ ] like
[ __ ] the kind of talent where if you
brought it to cali you could sell it for
cali prices it was that [ __ ] good
they gave cali people run for that money
and so you know that was definitely you
know professor q that was kind of our
whole thing was like man we could make
something bigger than aficionado
and i'm more comfortable on an
international scale anyway i grew up in
japan so i was 20 started my career when
i was in germany so
going to europe with friends with with
quentin
and doing these new exciting things
makes sense while you know we allow
aficionados to be what it always has
been keep it based out of california
keep it pure
you know because we're only going to
release three to five strains a year
anyway for the rest of the rest of this
company's life because you know we have
a very specific focus for what we want
to do but
the music we're going to make with
quentin that's what i'm really excited
about too
sounds exciting are there any other
breeders you plan to do collaborations
with
you know who i just hit up this morning
as i hit up miss jill
i had to miss joe because i've been
breeding a lot of strains
i've been breeding a lot of strains um
more geared towards the female palette
and my sister who's frenchie's
apprentice kind of really inspired me um
she kind of indirectly inspired me on
that because
she liked a certain flavor profile and
her friends liked a certain player
profile and i was like [ __ ] i wonder if
i could breed for that you know what i
mean
so
um i forgot where i was getting to what
was your
any other breeders you want to collab
with yeah yeah so so
my my reason for hitting on miss jill
was um she's
got some of the craziest
flavors that females love like like the
jelly bean the asian orange like these
really incredible exotic
crazy pronounced tones you don't find a
lot of cultivars so she was someone i
hit up this morning i saw she said i
asked if she was down
and she was like yeah man let's rap
later so um another breeder i'm really
looking forward um to doing some work
you know we've kind of really collabed
with a lot of breeders we always kind of
just did our own thing and made our own
music
but that's something that um i
definitely want to change because
there's a lot of talent out there
there's a lot of breeders you know i
want to put off
the the notion that i'm too good to work
with you because it was never like that
i was just always in my own world i'm
pretty reclusive by nature anyway you
know so i was just in my own world
working on my own thing because i tend
to get distracted easy um but you know
being able to work with different
breeders you know i want to work with i
you know in-house in-house is killing it
right now i definitely like to work with
him you know he was someone i like to
work with um
compound
these aren't guys i'm planning to work
with these are just guys i'm fans of
because it works good compounds work is
really good
and you know if i could collab with with
a breeder one day whoever's running
symbiotic
i think it's budologist 420
but i could be wrong but whoever's doing
their breeding is doing some incredible
work like i sipped it through their
their purple punch f2s
and i just can't believe you got that
expression
out of gdp and og like what the [ __ ] did
you select for to get it to look like
that like that's like what he did
was what i always try to do you know
what i mean
so and 303 seeds some cat out of [ __ ]
colorado believe it or not
you know it's like california guys kind
of hate on colorado guys but we just got
to be real man there's some cats in
colorado bringing some flame the 303
seeds was one of them they did the jet
the g6 jet fuel and that was
he was able to get an expression of sour
that i've been trying to get for seven
years
you know he was he he nailed it on the
g6 jet fuel you know what i mean so if i
could work with someone it'd be some
would definitely like that too you know
yeah so on the flip side what are just
some general genetics whether it be land
race or modern that you kind of want to
work into an aficionado strain
well like we're we've been suffering
through the lebanese for a while
that's going to turn into a long-term
project because you know you could cross
things with things that sound exotic but
is the end product going to be exotic
you know so
we're really going to open up um the
urkel we're gonna you know a lot of
these really exciting flavors come from
urkel
so you know
the essence of royal kush
you know i always thought that
you know mandelbrot was trying to go
towards the sour d side of things with
the royal kush until i finally grew his
f1 clone
the magnum opus and the original release
of long valley
directly next to an urkel
and i was like holy [ __ ] and it wasn't
you know it was literally until last
year i saw that observation i was like
holy [ __ ] that's what he was selecting
for
that's where all those crazy flavors in
the original royal cr7 coming from it
wasn't coming from the the ghani it
wasn't coming from the sour i mean it
was complimented by that but man those
that some crazy tense piercing fruit
tones but coming from the urkel
and so i'm definitely going back into
the urkel again um doing some exploring
into there
and um we made a crazy cross last year
with one of the contemporary strains
grape pie
we got one of the cuts of grape pie from
one of our buddies in humboldt
um the cut came from la
and uh we crossed it with the uh the
rose especially
and we just were like we'll see what's
going to happen
and so we didn't really pop the seeds
this year we had uh royal key
josh from royal key organics ran the
seed and he found some crazy [ __ ] he
ended up giving us two males back
we floured the males out and there were
some of the frostiest males we've ever
seen so that's something we're going to
explore that that cultivar a lot more
next year and see what we could select
see if it meets certain expectations and
um you know
i'm really excited about working the
original diesel i met strawberry jerry
from um
god damn i can't remember his [ __ ]
his company name he released strawberry
jerry
he's a super talented beer from the east
coast and he's he's got a back cross
of the original diesel mudder that's
sour diesel original diesel the mom that
made sour diesel so he's got a back
cross of that and that's definitely
something i'm i'm really you know
excited to work in you know i've kind of
been
um
you know collecting pollen and you know
storing a few things uh because uh
capulator gave us uh he gifted leo
from blockchain to give to me a pack of
this uh
orange apricot times mac crossed our
chem dog espresso reserve so
leo ended up keeping the two females out
of that and we ran all the males in our
indoor and the mails are [ __ ] crazy
and so
um we put it
we put the mail on on one of my white
cashmeres to see what happened but like
we're just gonna test that out you know
i have no intention of releasing that i
make
anywhere from like 30 strains a year on
average you know but we only release
like five to six so it's like part of
part of me you know breeding is just
seeing what things happen you know what
i mean and how do they cross you know
how they look you know not everything
that i'm gonna cross i'm gonna i'm gonna
produce or sell you know a lot of this
is for observation just like you know
you're only gonna be a good breeder as
as many strains as you grow and you [ __ ]
with too so that's why i also see the
the virtue and working with other
breeders and collaborating other
breeders getting an extra set of eyes
um getting that extra perspective on
what a certain direction could take you
know what i mean because i'll be i'll be
honest you know like if i don't if i
don't have quentin you know here most of
the time in frenchy i'd probably be full
of [ __ ] you know because you could
believe your own [ __ ] you tell yourself
in your head but if you don't have
another informed breeder going no i
don't think that's the right direction i
think we should go this way
and you can look that objectively and go
yeah you're right bro you know that's
magic you know so you know the you know
these breeders that i'm talking about
that i want to work with you know in
their strains it's because i'm seeing
[ __ ] in their work that they're making
selections they're coming with flavors
that nobody else is making you know
that's magic
yeah totally so i mean on the topic of
creation and whatnot seed testing is
always a topic of interest to me in the
past we used to see people use testers
but we've steered away from that and a
lot of people do in-house testing where
do you guys sit
we've never done testers
ever we've always it's always been our
policy to vigorously test a house
when you're when you're outsourcing
testing it's kind of like the risk of
licensing
you're you're expecting a certain
a certain standard to be met
in your absence and that's always a risk
right especially with breeders breeders
need breeders always need to have things
a certain [ __ ] way and you know and
we're the same way too you know it's
like i vigorously test you know i have
we have a vigorous testing you know
program you know where like the whole
time that we test so when we test this
is like a you know how we test right so
like we'll make a strain
and then we'll test it it's first year
outdoors right we'll test it outdoors
and when we get you know we get a full
six to eight months you know
you know living with this strain seeing
how it works and also we take clutch
cuts during when it's growing we take
cuts of the females we take cuts to the
males
right one for preservation and two for
[ __ ] stress testing you got to see
what's within these strains because you
know when we grow
i'm basically giving the seeds and their
environment the best possible
environment you know it's like you it's
how you want to treat you know your
pregnant wife right you want to give her
just nothing but love and a comfortable
environment and just no stress so that
baby comes out it's best possible self
right and so with
so we need that to happen in the garden
where things are producing or we're
getting a feel for you know cultivating
these things under ideal conditions but
you also have to test things under
unideal conditions
you got to kind of be
a [ __ ] [ __ ] and and and subject
your the girls that you love to you know
a certain degree of pain and especially
the boys we call we you know the
champagne room the reason why we call
our mail room the champagne room is
because it's the final place you go
after you get your ass beat in fight
club like that's initial mail selection
for us it goes through fight club and
that's we have to see what the [ __ ] this
strain can deal with and that's really
where a lot of your testing is going to
come from you know um you know testing
as far as like germination that's
something you should always do in-house
test the [ __ ] germ on your seeds test
the progeny see if they grow out well
you know but you know i think there's
also a lot of value in having other
talented growers test your [ __ ] too i
just think you have to be really um you
have to be really uh
[ __ ] you have to be very decisive on
on who you choose to work with you have
to be a lot of trust and there has to be
you know a set of rules you know in an
agreement that has to be honored between
the breeder and the guy that's testing
it you know because a lot of the reason
people like testers is because you know
things could end up getting stolen you
don't know certain people's security
you know um so you know as a breeder you
just kind of want to control everything
you know best possible
yeah totally
yeah so
aficionado as a brand has a lot of kind
of mystery and kind of mystique around
it in my opinion with that being said
what are the types of things you get up
to on an average basis like are you just
locked away breeding most of the time
yeah
sure yeah
yeah like it's you know um
so basically there's like my day i'm up
at five or
five to six every day
i'm a weed monk
i give a five or six every day i work
out and and i do weed
all the way until i sleep
and you know i think you know you need
that kind of intense focus to be good at
anything you know and it's like you know
i've really butted heads with this guy
in the past and people know that we kind
of don't like each other publicly but
you know
brandon from third gen a lot you could
love him or hate him
there's one thing that i learned from
him was was i never seen somebody work
harder in the industry than that
[ __ ]
and so seeing
you know and a lot of people have you
know you could say whatever you can but
he he earned he earned everything he's
[ __ ] earned through hard [ __ ] work
you know the guy's talented
but hard work beats talent every time
you know what i mean he's any any i
never seen someone work that intense so
you know i've always
you know looked at brandon as someone i
had to kind of keep up with you know and
it was kind of using you know using a
rival to your advantage where you could
find inspiration from someone you don't
get along with you could start you can
kind of see the strengths they have so
it's like you know seeing guys at the
top of their game seeing how many
[ __ ] hours they put into their
business the name of kevin's audrey the
motherfucker's a workaholic he's a
workhorse you know the dude never stops
working
and you know that that inspires me you
know the same thing and i follow the
hip-hop industry you know most some of
your most successful artists don't
[ __ ] sleep i mean they sleep but
they're they work and it takes that
level of focus and attention to detail
to be successful at it and so it's like
i've gotten through times in my life
where i've i've deep m where my focus
and my cognition is deviated from where
it should be
but in but knowing that if i really want
to be in this industry make something i
got to be super [ __ ] disciplined you
know what i mean like this isn't just
because i own you know we have our own
business doesn't mean that we can [ __ ]
off it's like you have to be incredibly
[ __ ] disciplined because no matter
how hard you're working i really feel
that there's other people out there that
are more hungry that are [ __ ] working
harder than you to take away what you
have or to [ __ ] you know get better
that at you in the game
and that's just gonna [ __ ] happen
so it's like
my regular day it's like you know i have
to manage the indoor the outdoor
check on emails check on sales like we
have a really small tight you know tight
family through a small type network
you know and we really like to we
operate like we hustle we don't like to
really share about share a lot about
what we do we just like to show people
the end product we feel that's part of
the magic you know when when you go to a
magic show and someone shows you how the
magic trick is done it kind of loses its
its mystique kind of it loses the magic
and so we figured if we just like
really focus on the [ __ ] craft
and just whenever people see us
we're just communicating some fire
you know that's that that's our goal you
know and so it just takes a certain
lifestyle
um definitely a lot of sacrifice you
know it's definitely sacrificed partying
a lot you know i was parting a lot when
i first started aficionado but you know
now you know just i've learned by being
in the game that if you want to be
relevant you got to work harder than the
guy that's working harder than you to
get in the game right now
so that's what keeps me hungry you know
it's like my normal day is busy as [ __ ]
i'm usually up at five or six done at 11
go to bed at 12 do it all over again
sometimes go to bed at two
yeah wow workaholic by the sounds of it
yeah a little bit you know it's but it's
like
um
you know everybody thinks it's a cool
idea to start their own company until
you're actually doing it and you have to
see
what goes into it and then you know i
have a lot of people i i aspire to kind
of you know get to the level and so i
just kind of emulate their their work
habits and their intensity when they
approach their traffic you know certain
producers i know that i really look up
to and certain businessmen that i know i
would look up to that they have these
these work ethics that man if i want to
get to that level i have to [ __ ] work
that hard or harder
yeah totally it's like a shout out to
brennan from third gen one love
yeah yeah one love you know like we've
you know we've you know we've had
people publicly know we don't get along
but my voice is the thing is like just
because i don't like you doesn't mean i
can't respect you you know what i mean
and just you know like there's always
you know everyone's got something about
their hustle and their intensity that if
you just put us put away your [ __ ]
ego
man you can see you can really see the
value these [ __ ] bring to the
game
you know aside from all the ego [ __ ] on
ig it's like no one worked harder than
that [ __ ] that do work hard as
[ __ ] you know what i mean and same thing
with gene you know no one
makes no one breeds and observes
on a level that gene does
you know what i mean when it comes to
breeding so it's like you know being in
proximity those guys showed me a
standard of of of where we should
operate
you know what i mean
and then not abiding by those and making
my mistakes and [ __ ] ups further
reinforces
how we should emulate how certain guys
like that operate that intensity that
dedication
you know what i mean so
yeah
okay it's definitely like a spiritual
journey
so a little bit unrelated i want to know
what's your prediction on the next big
thing to hit the industry or the next
big wave whatever you want to call it
and how do you plan to ride it
i don't know
that's a good question
that's a good question i think like
the big thing in what context the big
thing in like the flower market genetics
market you know
it's you know next big strain next big
phenomenon
i mean
i really think the next big thing
happened with big al bro
i think that you know
it's
is it is it is it set in stone
we can't tell yet
but but is it happening right now is the
opportunity here right now [ __ ] yeah
that's what that's what real people in
the industry needed so hard
was was to be able to participate at
that level and separate themselves from
the [ __ ] corporate booth squad
you know so like to me that's like you
know some people could say that's not a
big phenomenon [ __ ] is a price
skeleton look that that customer
demographic exists they're underserved
it's the reason why audemars piguet
ferrari and rolex are in business as
customers of this demographic and so
it's like they need to be served you
know what i'm saying it's like and just
because you serve them at that at that
price point doesn't mean you could offer
things at an other price point too you
know it's not binary
you know cannabis isn't binary it's not
just it's not black or white you know so
you know i think that's like the biggest
thing that's happening to the culture
right now that people really aren't
appreciating is that we have this new
opportunity to really be like wine to
really be like craft spirits to really
be like high-end cuban cigars you know
so why resist this opportunity when it's
going to be what's going to save us
later down the line
yeah totally
so one of the questions we received from
a few different fans over the period of
this show is that basically they're
always interested in knowing how is it
you go about sourcing all of the rare
genetics i know before you mentioned
that it was through you know bags and
whatnot but obviously some of the stuff
you have access to which is really old
doesn't come from a bag is it like a
real oh it wasn't from bags it was like
when it came like when i said in that
context
yeah when the person would bring the
packs over i'd be like where's the
farmer at i want to meet the farmer ah
there you go if they if they want to
introduce me to farmer i'd give them
some [ __ ] fire ass seeds or a fire
ass clone
i was like dude introduce me farmer bro
he's gonna want this clone yeah okay so
just in general how do you go about
procuring these more rare and obscure
strains
man all over you know sometimes you know
some people will be talking to frenchie
you know i've met um
you know really it happened it's always
different
you know back in the day
um before before everything went legal
it was really through when i was still
you know when i was still really active
you know uh doing other things is when i
was really collecting the strains
meeting farmers you know driving
thousands of miles putting thousands of
miles on my [ __ ] vehicle every week
just to meet farmers uh making deals
happening so i could find genetics but
now now it's a lot different now it's a
lot now it's the culture changed the the
landscape change so we're getting our
genetics from you know from you know
just random people now like not random
people but like people that we meet
through our network that we never would
have thought would brought this you know
we have to verify these genetics and
grow them out and see if it's really
what they say it's going to be
but a lot of the times you know the
hardest part about obtaining genetics is
getting it from
a rare source that's willing to share it
the game's changed now where
a lot of people really realize the value
and their genetics so it's getting
harder for a lot of breeders to to
obtain you know new gear unless you're
collabing with people or or you're
straight up buying seeds and i've never
been you know
uh uh i've never been a huge like uh see
seed collector in the sense where i i
collect other companies packs it was
like i want the [ __ ] that comes in a
ziploc bag
you know that came from [ __ ] thailand
you know or the stuff that we got from
lebanon like the seeds we got from
lebanon was
uh we could congratulate professor q you
know what i mean it was really hard to
get those they were from they were late
70s stocks that was just opened up a
couple years ago and then um open
pollinated and so and that came directly
from from from lebanon um uh and then we
got that from came from lebanon then it
ended up uh landing in spain where we
were sifting it
and so um i don't know how i [ __ ] got
to spain but quinn calling one day and
he was like dude i got the lebanese
we were so happy you're [ __ ] so happy
oh yeah but you know finding the strain
is is the hardest part
it's it's like when you look at a
producer right when i was mentioning
earlier that you know producer's job is
you know um to create shape and shift
the future music you know then
i have to quote funk master flex was one
who who says that
that producers create shape and shift
the
future music but also what these
producers and djs do is they do
something they have this culture of
digging
where they where they where they go
through and they dig through records so
they can find new sounds
and where you uh where you obtain these
new records in these new tracks and how
you obtain them is always a [ __ ]
secret to djs
you know a lot of people like back in
the day you know
you know [ __ ] always ask other
producer dj hey were you getting these
tracks for where you getting these
samples from that's that's part of their
that's part of their magic and how they
acquired seeds you know like i've always
just had a really
you know that was kind of one of the
weird things i fell into i was just i i
ended up getting really lucky at finding
good genetics because because of
business pipelines
and so i just keep following those
pipelines i just keep you know i keep
you know networking with people
and i share a lot of genetics too so
it's like it's not like i'm just like
look going out looking for [ __ ] i'm like
you know i have a lot of things on my
fault that i'm like hey you know what
are you looking for is there anything
you want
and then you know i'll make that happen
you know you know or to the best of my
ability
it's usually the the best that the best
way we can get strains
yeah for real yeah so you trade them you
know do you feel like breeding with
heirloom or land race strains is able to
help you remove what we would maybe
refer to as the ceiling or that
inability to continue to get more and
more high which doesn't seem to be
occurring in like land race and heirloom
varieties
i don't know man it's it's really
difficult breeding
land rice and heirloom varieties it
sounds exotic until you're actually
doing
it you know and then you have to go out
and you have to make the crosses and
test it you know without these
contemporary strains you could tell from
the mother stock
and what you select that you're going to
have a good probability of getting
something that's going to meet a certain
level of expectation but when you're
working with land race your selection
has to be [ __ ] incredibly on point
there's a lot of really garbage land
race but there's a lot of really good
stuff but it's really difficult to
access
and um so you know for me a lot of these
really difficult ones to access that i
was been searching for years was you
know the the
the broadleaf burmese old-school burmese
the one that looks like og
you know i smoked it i smoked the
burmese
my first trip when i went to when i was
i grew up in japan so i was 20. the
first time i went to thailand i was like
18.
and
my buddies came out it's like hey we
were in the smoke weed at the time
because wheat is expensive as [ __ ] in
japan it was 70 bucks a gram and so we
went to thailand you know it was just
like smoke heaven and i remember having
a burmese
that was rock [ __ ] hard
and
it was one of the craziest highs i've
ever had so i've been kind of chasing
one of those strains it was really
frosty it was like exceedingly frosty
you know some of the weed we were
getting in japan a lot of it was coming
from mexico if it was coming in nug for
him or was getting smuggled in from from
cali from from on the navy ships with
the sailors and then they'd sell it to
kids
and um
but when we went to thailand we were
that was the first time i got to see
like really good wheat i got really
lucky it wasn't it wasn't hydraulically
pressed or anything and so it was
something like that that was the
standard what i wanted to chase you know
same thing with like in afghani like a
real afghani or like a like an
incredible pakistani that has not just
frost
but a nose you know so you see a lot of
these old hash fridays like they'll be
crazy frosty but they won't really have
like a definitive nose something that
you can breed with that you're really
certain that you're gonna get you know a
new and exciting flavor from
you know so it's like it's really i've
learned
through trial and error that when you're
breeding land races it's more of a
long-term project and a lot of it's
going to be more research and
development and recording your
observations because it's going to take
some time to get that land race cross to
express itself in a manner that's going
to meet
the expectations of what strains are
doing these days you know with [ __ ] that
[ __ ] you know symbiotic and see
junkies releasing these crazy frosty
profiles like that's the new standard so
it's like if you want to breed with land
race strains that historically don't
have these exaggerated frost profiles
it's going to be more of a
you know it's it's it you you better
have a [ __ ] good direction you're
going to go if you want to release that
yeah so that's at least my two cents you
know and there's people that work a lot
of land races that have really good work
you know there's ak bean brains
um in the nature farm
on ig these guys um are growing some
crazy [ __ ] land races really rare
[ __ ] and that's cool i think those guys
might end up being some of the next big
guys in the game i've been seeing some
crazy phenotypes and collection coming
out of their [ __ ] feeds that i'm just
like how the [ __ ] did you get that you
know i mean
but it's like that's the magic you know
what i mean
how did you get that the fact is they
got that and it's exotic and they're
going to be able to flex crosses their
land races that are going to hopefully
prove themselves to be just as good if
not better than a lot of these
contemporary polyhybrids we're seeing on
the market
of course
so something i realize i haven't asked
you
what type of cannabis is your personal
favorite are you into stuff that's kind
of like gonna hate more yeah
stimulate stuff i don't
i mean i love gas like you know really
my my first love is gas
i have a really
i i've i i just i get gas plants i get
along with them really well
um as far as growing and smoking them
but man my my love is haze man i love
that
crazy
you know it looks like someone just
plucked your third eye out and just
threw it into outer space like that's
what i want like the first time i smoked
the c5 haze
in spain was a crazy experience it was
like a 16-week flower it didn't look it
looked airy as [ __ ]
it was pretty frosty it didn't really
have
a crazy unique nose that i can remember
right now go oh it's this flavor
i just remember the the high was so
intense i don't remember the flavor bro
and i was sitting
in this house and and great gardener
says to smoke it it's just all the way
up like what do you mean it's just
straight up what the [ __ ] you mean smoke
it straight up
all right so i spoke it and literally it
feels like someone grabs the side of
your head and lifts you straight the
[ __ ] up i haven't had such a visceral
sativa high like that since i was a
little kid in thailand and so it's like
my favorite weeds are always going to be
those old school sativas
that kind of get hated on because they
take a long time to flower out because
to me it's about the high like you know
like yeah everyone says oh this is
medicine yeah it is [ __ ] medicine i
got ptsd i use it medicinally but really
like my form of medicine is getting to
this certain high
so i could i could interface life at a
different frequency you know what i mean
and so to me like
you know the haze height did that and
i'll be real too
with the other straight i love smoking
that [ __ ] love because the high just
makes sense to me skittles
you know what i'm saying some people
either hate that [ __ ] or they love it so
it brought me a similar happy heady high
that i get when i smoke a lot of the you
know the old school and the contemporary
hazes you find in in europe nowadays
you know so um i just i don't like being
really stoned and sleepy because i'm
busy as [ __ ] all day so i like something
that's going to you know really pick me
up
and uh get me going you know almost like
like a proper sour diesel
you know where you could you're
noticeably high but you're not impaired
to the point where it's gonna it's gonna
inhibit you know productivity
yeah so on that note of gassy
we've mentioned it earlier the chem
special reserve it's one of the popular
ones i hear about people from people all
the time from you guys do you plan to
bring it back and work with it and
broadly speaking will you ever rework
any projects again
yeah we're in the middle of reworking
the white cashmere
so
um those packs
yeah those oh no it was yeah those packs
coupled with the last like 30 to 50
seeds we had we went for broke like we
never pop everything we popped
everything this year
so we got we got males in clone form we
saved all the females we got tons of
pawns stocked up but um it depends on
on how good the strain is you know you
know we would really be doing
a lot of our clients
a disservice if we were to release this
to do a re-release of the strain or to
rework it it kind of takes from away
from the allure and the prestige of why
they bought it in the first [ __ ]
place
um unless
it was one of those strains where
because a lot of the times in the first
three years
these strains didn't get saved they were
literally grown as big-ass outdoor
plants and the packs were moved back
east that i mean that's just was the
culture at humboldt and mendo at the
time you know
so
um you know under certain circumstances
like that like the white cashmere was
one of those where a lot of people
really didn't save a cut it kind of
disappeared and if we have enough
evidence that it's disappeared
we'll [ __ ] we'll do a re-release you
know what i mean we'll do an encore
release but we've never
purposely opened up a strain and then
reworked it and released it probably the
only one we've done that with was like
you know the royal lions because every
generation was different from like when
we when i got it as the royal cr7 then
we brought it into eight and nine every
generation was [ __ ] different like
now we have it in twelve
you know we have it as like magnum 12.
and so like and it's completely
different every generation just like
you know there's something unique in
everything so
when we go back and we open things up
it's if only if we could find
an entirely new direction
then it becomes a new thing
yeah
so that's actually a question we got
asked a lot about as well
what was your journey with mandelbrot's
royal and how did it go from being you
know the the royals sorry six to the
long valley to kind of where it is now
so um
i met andelbrot through kevin in in
shiloh
uh at the emerald cup in 2013.
we won in 2012
and then i got fourth place with the
royal
and i remember
on the bree on the card it said
who's the breeder or who bred it i think
there was a thing i was like i remember
writing i don't [ __ ] know
i wanted to
and
because i always heard about him i
didn't know his name was man lebron i
always heard about the guy that bred the
truth
the guy that bred the uh the royal cush
because these are the stain these are
the strains that were going back east
and dave chappelle in common and most
deaf were smoking on you know the the
the story on the street you know when i
heard it fermando brought was that's how
the strain
name got it's true got the name the
truth
is you know chappelle was smoking some
weed with you know this is this is you
know this is you know come this came
from you know sitting in mandelbrot's
cars like you know dave chappelle was
smoking some we were [ __ ] most deaf
and and toled quality most definitely um
in common
and
i guess they called it it they it was
sold to them as like maui super dog
and someone got so high i forgot who it
was he's like nah [ __ ] that's just
called the truth
the truth and so that was like this
whole story and you know that was just
you know and that was the story you know
[ __ ] were also talking about
when
the truth seeds were in mendo the truth
seeds were the first [ __ ] seeds i
ever heard that were eighty dollars a
seed
like they went for eighty dollars a pack
but my our partner sean at the time
who's no longer with us bless your soul
you know he passed away from cancer he
was one of the guys that came up to
mendo in my first years
um he came into the [ __ ] house after
going to uh a club in in san francisco
and he was like you would have [ __ ]
believed this because he was a seed
collector too that was our thing we
collect clones we'd collect seeds we'd
go to any club we could find clones and
seeds and just and go shopping
and um
he came back with these [ __ ] truth
seeds he was like and he and he didn't
pop them he was like bro i paid 80 bucks
a seed for these
i was like bro how many caesar in there
he's like 10. he's like it's it's like
some of the best flour you've ever
smoked and he had some samples of flour
it was [ __ ] crazy
that was probably like 2010
when when i saw those seeds and then
fast forward to like 2013 when i won the
cup i didn't know who had bred the royal
coast so
um
i didn't claim that i've read it so
mandelbrock
shiloh comes up to the booth
kevin's also at the booth too and then
um shadows with this [ __ ] big dude
and he was like hey this is mandelbrot
he bred the royal cush
and and i was like holy [ __ ] because
when i went to go find the seeds of the
wild kush they were they were at this um
they were at
lovin
lovin it at a dispensary in mendocino
and it was the only dispensary in the
entire state of california that had
[ __ ] emerald mountain seeds and they
were all the original seats they were
all the original release seats i
remember buying
tons of packs
and we selected the the winning royal
sauer out of that that's how the royal
sour name came about it was a pheno
from the royal coast seven packs that
was hella sour d dominant it was long
long lanky spaghetti noodle stems and
anybody that grows royal knows it's like
a [ __ ] pine tree it's short stop fat
you know grows like a christmas tree but
this one was like a sour and so that was
the one we entered and i remembered the
seeds were old and they had really bad
germ rates on them and then after i met
uh mandelbrot he was like yeah dude
those are the original you know seeds
those original royal cause seventies i
made
i was like holy [ __ ] and so i remember
after that you know we became you know
he we became friends and you know he
sold me several hundred seeds of you
know the truth the original truth which
i you know some of them i still have
and the royals
and so my goal was like
i was like look man i'm making this
royal and it's it's
it's i want to acclimatize it
to the mendo environment
you know because what we were doing is
you know the royal cush was really
unique was you'd get a [ __ ] nice
you know huge [ __ ] crazy frosty plant
that had gas but no powdery no mold
you know and laytonville is a really
unique environment as far as mendocino
is concerned it's not as dry as places
like like boonville it's not as dry as
places in you know uh east willets like
in hearst
you know laytonville definitely has a
lot more coastal influence
a little more fog so the whole goal of
doing the long valley royal kush was to
select a royal cushrum seed that was
relatively
consistent if anybody remembers popping
the original royal crisp
seven seeds
from brat every single female was was
crazy different
like not in a bad way everything was
[ __ ] fire
but you know some would be long some
would be short some would be purple
someone would have gas some wouldn't
have gas
and so we wanted to get a strain that i
selected the sour deep dominant male and
the sourdy dominant female
um so because we felt that the sour d
tendency sourdy did really well in
leightonville it was uh old faithful you
could grow a ton of it it wouldn't have
a lot of powdery wouldn't have a lot of
botrytis and you could get it to market
so you know just from that observation i
wanted to select you know more of these
smaller leaves noodly branches it was
traits that were definitive to that and
you know and then when i started working
as lines more that when mandelbrot sold
me
um those original seeds that was you
know that was where we really made the
[ __ ] royal christian and he helped me
select
and you know um
you know i was giving him plants up up
until you know when he passed away 2015
you know
it was [ __ ] up you know i gave him
actually gave him the last of my plants
in my greenhouse because he had a
problem on his farms a bunch of his
plants died and
i remember you know i was still with
lady l at the time and amanda brock
comes with this truck and we just we
gave him like a few hundred of our
plants that we had left
and it was all his genetics too so i was
like happy to give him to him he's like
bro you like
you know you helped me you know
create these and i mean not create these
but you help me like [ __ ] grow these
out and select these find you know what
was fire you know it was like the
thing i could at least do is give you
these you know so what was cool about
mandelbrot
was
he opera he vibrated at such a high
[ __ ] level right like
he got me my first account at uh ag
unlimited and like i'm still on his
account
it's like
i'm still on his account before i even
knew
his real name i'd come in i'm like yo
man lebron here sent me it's like who do
you mean mac you know kind of like yeah
whatever that guy big guy you know the
guy came in with
and so he sent my first um like real ag
account up at a ag wholesaler and at the
time i was super into soil science i was
super into compost
um i have just previously worked with
alan atkinson from grokashi who was
doing probiotic farmers alliance
and so that was something that we really
connected on command lebron
was doing emerald mountain organics
he was formulating soil for people he
was actually mixing his own nutrients he
was buying he was getting bio-link
nutrients and he was mixing him and
having ag unlimited do custom mixes for
him and then he would find his own
inputs around
so like really my regimen
i gave to my plants it's like i won the
cup
through the regimen i built with you
know that i learned from mike and that i
helped you know it's like because the
cup soil recipe was jointly created by
um by by lady elle and i you know her
cousin crazy larry had this crazy fire
so makes me use that and then i was you
know i did all the the top end
fertilization and the gene selection but
when it came to
fertilizing that mandelbrot had an
incredible talent for that and that's
where we really bonded on you know what
i mean and
i remember we would be at ariel 101 with
emerald cup tim
and at the time there was man i was
there man lebron was there i think casey
o'neil might have been there
um but this guy named this phd plant
pathologist named chuck schiller who
invented the the micronized 1200
uh the 1200 soybean powder that a lot of
people are using as a foliar that's
[ __ ] crazy he invented that
and
you know he was kind of like him and han
a lot of us growers
but he was genuinely blown the [ __ ] away
by mandelbrot's knowledge
of soil sciences and in general botany
and horticulture he was blown the [ __ ]
away this guy's knowledgeable so
um
you know and i think that was probably
like a year before you know he passed
away
those was when you know they called us
in you know the whole the whole thing it
was is chuck schiller was working for
grower's secret at the time and growers
was like well we're trying to formulate
the best you know bloom formula possible
you know and so like you know me and
amanda about we were really geeking out
on that because we had a beef with bio
links you know phosphorus you know
because their phosphorus was great they
had this great phosphorus nutrient but
it was a colloidal phosphate suspension
so basically it was just [ __ ] water
and soft rock phosphate right so there
was you know and so what we wanted was
we wanted something kind of like what a
biochanner had but they had an exclusive
license on it was like this colloidal
phosphate based phosphorus bloom formula
but that didn't have any sediment that
you could run through a drip line you
know because mandelbrot was really big
on
all right i want to breed these genetics
but also want to create the soil and the
nutrient you know nutrient regimen for
it but i also want it to be scalable and
i want it to be universal so anybody can
use it
and so it's like
really working with mandelbrot goes way
past the genetics the dude taught me so
much about [ __ ] in general you know
general nutrients i still have a a file
box full of like the old catalogs from
emerald mountain organics of what what
what the soil mixes man lebron would
make for people and the different
regimens like he had a 32 part you know
18 part liquid uh
organic liquid regiment and it wasn't
for feeding the plant it was for feeding
the soil like he was onto some next
level [ __ ] man lebron was the first
person
using a calcium magnesium
using a cow mag that was completely
organic it was all from mined car uh
magnesium carbonate and calcium
carbonate and this company
that was working with spinach farmers
back in late 90s they found out that
they could take this calcium carbonate
and this magnesium carbonate they could
put in a vat
of of what's called dextrolactic acid
dextrolactic acid and it's a it's it's a
different salt it's a different sugar
based
or sugar i think i'm saying the right
thing sugar based lactic acid but what
it does is it it attaches a sugar
molecule to the calcium and the
magnesium components and the magnesium
calcium carbonate and allows it to just
hang out in the soil
as as an amino acid based calcium
magnesium you know so what was crazy
about this is like whenever you
generally feed cal mag to a plant it's
chelated with with with with um edta
which is a chemical salt chelating agent
and it gets directly absorbed by the
roots but what mandelbrot was doing he
was like [ __ ] how do i how do i increase
the mobile availability of calcium and
magnesium like so we know that magnesium
is mobile in soil but calcium is it
but with through but but through doing
his [ __ ] homework he was the first
person to use cal magdl
on crops on like cannabis crops like
this and that was like you know like
when when he taught me these things and
i switched to using his inputs man my
[ __ ] soil went through the roof i
remember the first time dirty business
soil came online and i was actually able
to see what my cat ion exchange capacity
is and what people understand they're
listing what a cation exchange capacity
is it's basically a number that
indicates um the rate of how uh how
available nutrients are in your soil and
the breakdown of nature into your soil
so
um i was getting way higher numbers like
with the soil that was using
mandelbrot's inputs versus the soils
that weren't you know so it's like
it goes way more than genetics how i
grow
completely changed because of him
yeah for real as well there's a lot to
take in i'm trying to think i'm trying
to think about a lot of people don't
know the story you know it was a it was
a really it was something that it was
always it was street business back in
the day you know
so it was that was something that you
know no matter what even though that
there was drama between man lebron's
brother and i back in the day it was
something that you know it wasn't my
business to share like it wasn't it
wasn't me it's like people were doubting
that when i worked with man lebron it
wasn't up for me to reinforce that like
i knew what the [ __ ] i don't remember
the right people don't know what that
meant brought
you know what i mean
i was sitting with him in an area 101
helping formulate [ __ ] bloom
nutrients with chuck schiller from
grower's secrets chuck shirley remembers
that [ __ ]
and so it's like
it's a it was like a
it was a it was a bittersweet you know
because i had some drama with with his
family back you know like two years ago
and it was a really hard thing to deal
with you know because i had never met
his family we had us we had a strictly
it was old-school relationship you know
what i'm saying we were based on the
hustle
it's like you know
people that usually are [ __ ] doing
deals together you're not going to
family barbecues together you know what
i'm saying
unless you guys grew up together you
know and i'm a transplant you know i
mean so
i really didn't get to meet most of many
rock's family until i feel like he
really passed away
yeah
that's unfortunate to hear
yeah he was like he was probably you
know he's i
the whole point of working his lines
especially after he passed away was was
so his memory wouldn't die
it was that
a lot of people
you know me and mandela would talk about
this thing about the great breeders that
would breed something
and their [ __ ] got raided by the cops
or they got killed you know and no one's
ever going to hear that story
and and and and that shit's in and those
genetics
are are are forever going to be extinct
you know so it was about
you know i felt that this guy was like
the father of the contemporary you know
of what
he made breeding fuel possible
for a larder for a larger audience that
didn't have access to things like chem
dog or or og bat cross seats you know to
get these kind of crazy real profiles
you know so
i did i you know it was like i'd be
damned if if if [ __ ] forgot
about him you know what i mean but now
his memory lives on through
you know numerous farms and ben still
can you know ben still continuing you
know his brother's work
and so like that's the beautiful thing
you know what i mean
so
yeah for sure
so what type of legacy do you want to
leave on the industry from aficionado
i just want i want to build something
i want to build a company that stand the
test of time
you know and i think it's about
you know finding finding different
talents that could help you take this
vision
and take it somewhere you know what i
mean so
like you look at like i i studied a lot
of fashion companies i grew up in i grew
up in you know yokohama
and you know um i studied fashion when i
was in college in japan before i before
i moved back in the states and so i've
always
been fascinated by how a lot of these
luxury companies were built a lot of how
these fashion companies are built so you
look at you know long after christian
dior passed away he had this guy named
john gagliano you know being his
creative designer you know so you could
have like you know after
if if the brand's good enough and it
could live it could continue to live on
it's still going to need some sort of
creative director to carry that
legacy i don't want to just
sell aficionados and i want to do this
for the rest of my life i want i want i
want my grandkids
to to be able to to sit at the board of
aficionados table and work with whoever
they choose to be the creative director
or whoever is good enough to breathe you
know what i mean so it's like with you
know you saint laurent that's where
that's how tom ford was the creative
director of yves saint laurent and gucci
and all these companies were started by
a guy named [ __ ] east st laurent and
a guy whose last name was gucci
and so like my my vision was like i mean
if we if i could really
if there's a possibility we could build
something to stand the test of time
that will still be here after we die
what's needed to make that happen
you know so i guess we're exploring that
right now and i know french is exploring
that right now you know because
frenchie's building is is a brand
that that we want to to stand the test
of time too you know jack daniels isn't
going to make the whiskey forever but
he's going to continue to spend the test
of time
and so
it's really early in the industry and
it's getting only time in the market and
consistency is going to decide
who reaches that level first you know
because i don't think anyone's reached
that level yet but i think it's worth
trying
yeah i totally agree so i mean if we're
talking means to an end there what are
you gonna release next what can people
look forward to next and tell us what
you're going to have at emerald
so we're
so uh emerald mountain emerald cup
our distributor seeds here now is going
to be representing a fishnet cup i'll be
doing some appearances there but due to
regulation we weren't able to get all
the right permits in time for the
emerald cup this year so james is going
to handle the launch for us
we're also going to be doing an online
uh pre-sale we've never done
a launch online for the emerald cup it's
always that people have always had to
wait after the emerald cup for things to
be available on seeds here now so
what we're doing something different is
since
our market has
magically grown global over the last two
years we're going to offer you know
special online pre-emeral cup release
so people that are fans and have always
supported us they could you know they
have the opportunity to cop what's going
to be at the emerald cup too everybody
has the opportunity to cop it now but
there's not going to be a lot you know
we we we we did a 2000 plant sniff this
year we worked a lot of strains that we
worked last year
we ended up only keeping 80 plants out
of the 2000
and we only pollinated 13
13 plants different we used
some different males on some different
plants
but our production like that's what we
made and so five
five to five of those 13 will probably
make it the fruit tartar turned out
really good the forbidden fruit right in
the pines
across forbidden fruit magnum opus that
turned out hella good oh releasing that
we released six boxes of the f1 of
formula one um and those auctioned for
obscene amounts of money we never
thought they would auction for so much
i guess the fact that they had there was
only six boxes we used some good [ __ ] on
them too
um it went for huge price but we wanted
people we liked it so much it was like
man there just can't be six people with
[ __ ] boxes of formula one so we're
gonna release f2 and we're pretty happy
with how the f2 you know how the f2 is
turning out and we're really excited
about how the f1 turned out in general
so
um we have the sichuan flambe which is
the sangria times cherry noir times
testarossa
that's the one that we're really excited
about and
we have a few that still waiting to be
named we just can't find
the perfect name for him but uh
were we going to be releasing an og
cross this year i did a collab with the
guy who brought me up to mendo's name is
mendocino mike
and we bred his he has this og called we
called the green bomb oh geez his name's
mike greenbaum
so we called the green bomb og and what
that is it's a heirloom bubblegum
crossed with an sfvog that he had from
seed that he's been making his himself
last four years
and so he crossed that with the old
school bubblegum and he got this
bubble gum framed plant that turns
purple but still somewhat smells like oh
gee it's weird it's like you get this
fruity bubble gum but it's there's just
as much og on the contrast in the butt
it's [ __ ] crazy and so we crossed
that with our our versailles which was
like a really good solid og
and um you know we're releasing that
year we're calling you know that that
you know um that's gonna be we're
releasing the miyazaki og and that's
what we're calling that
um
that's from you know my old japan roots
miyazaki was a director who created
films such as totoro
and we always called mike totoro because
he was like a mountain he's like he's
like a forest spirit he's like he's like
this guy's he's like uh you know late
50s
huge white beard
tatted from head to toe
walks barefoot he's a [ __ ]
mountain spirit you know this guy's a
forest spirit you know so
and he taught me a lot about you know
paying respect to plants
and and appreciating nature the way that
miyazaki's films uh did for me when i
was growing up as a kid in japan so we
chose to name that that strained me as
akioji
and um
the next two we just haven't named yet
but they're good
they're good
like
we we came across a flavor and um the
backyard and bcn got some of these seeds
leo got some of these seeds and its
working title was rosso corsa and that
was this offshoot from the the
testarossa line we were working when we
crossed it with the cherry noir
and rose of course is the name
we weren't going to brand it this way
because that's ferrari has that name
trademarked as the color of the paint on
their cars so it was just like i just
called it that just as remember that it
was like oh that's obviously from my
testarossa cross you know what i mean
because the the number the color red on
the testosterone was called rosa corsa
but we're we're we're going through this
thing where we're trying to find
a good identity for it because it
doesn't smell like anything we've ever
worked before
it's gotta completely it literally
smells like
um
like if you were trick-or-treating and
you had a roll of smarties in your
pocket get crushed up and then somehow
someone spilled gasoline you know what i
mean it's it's
insane like crazy we've never been able
we never thought we'd be able to get
terps like this to express
so we wanted something that we could
call it that would give it its justice
and two we wouldn't get a cease and
desist from ferrari
sounds exciting
yeah because tesla roast is like you
know italian for redhead and so like a
lot of the stems and the leaves and the
testarossa would get this red hue and
that's why you know we called it the
testarossa and the rosso corsa was even
more [ __ ] red it was just this
brilliant vibrant red that would
transition to a lavender and then like a
royal purple and then but the nose was
just pure candy shop
pure candy
shop maybe we'll call it shop
sounds really exciting i got a question
though for you and you've got to be
honest here when you do the online
launch do you expect the site to crash
[ __ ]
that would be cool
i mean
the coolest thing that happened to
seeds here now is we crashed their
servers one time
um where the orders came in so fast they
actually
oversold and because the computers
couldn't keep up with them with the with
the frequency of orders going out so
that was like
you know we never expect these kind of
things to happen it's just really
grateful and we're humbled you know
because
we really approach this like as music
you know we could you know if we're in
if we're in the the the garden you know
our version of a studio there's a really
good chance what we what we make won't
connect
so it's like if it connects on the front
end and people like the cross they like
the way it sounds and then it really
expresses itself to exceed their
expectations and that's what we'll know
you know our job is done so it's like
it's really hard for us to get excited
over sales because the sales is the
first part of that that that
relationship with with the grower you
know who's who's the cornerstone of your
[ __ ] brand
you have to get his validation it's not
a good day it's not a good day when you
sell the seeds it's a scary day when you
sell the seeds because you better
[ __ ] hope those seeds come out good
for that grower
so
when when you get the feedback months
later that's when you know you could you
could rest easy
because your testing could be on point
in your friend's gardens that you're
testing other strains too because we
tested our other strains in mendo this
year and they did they did good as usual
because renders were reframing those
contests good but
is it going to hold up in other people's
grows
it's going to express yourselves to you
according to your expectations and their
expectations in their environment
so that's that's the key so i try not to
get too excited about it you know i
think if you get excited about selling
seeds you're in it for the wrong purpose
and that you know
um
you know if you're getting excited too
early
and and then you know
you just can't forecast the [ __ ]
future you know i mean if we could all
forecast the future we wouldn't be in
the weed game we were running headphones
so
that's just the fact
all the testing in the world could be
good but if it doesn't prove itself on
the market you're [ __ ]
so bringing us to kind of the tail end
of things a really interesting question
i pose to a lot of people doesn't seem
to be a very clear answer what's your
recommendations for the small scale
farmers both indoor and out who are kind
of continually dealing with this
conundrum of ever decreasing prices and
ever increasing supply
that's a really difficult problem isn't
it
you know i think the regulations are
changing almost daily
right when people adapt to a certain set
of circumstances the circumstances
change yet again
i'm a long-term thinker i know it's
really painful for a lot of people that
that that are are in the wreck industry
it's not as profitable but it used to be
you got to pay every [ __ ] tax under
the moon um you know uh you know things
are getting spread out regulation makes
it so you know definitely like i said
before we're not making as much money so
i'm a speaking in the sense of long
speaking in light of you know of a
long-term scale
if if if they could just hold on hold on
for another two to four years man keep
grinding as hard as you [ __ ] came for
two to four years because
canada's already made cannabis
international and the amount of [ __ ]
money that government cannabis is going
to dramatically improve canada's gdp
huge and america's not gonna sit back
and watch this happen for too much
longer
a lot of people a lot of people agree
with the sentiment in washington
and um i still talk to a lot of my old
colleagues back in washington that are
still doing it i'm like hey what's hot
right now where do you think politics
are going
you know um and then i'll kind of get a
feel for things i think that
whether you want to [ __ ] acknowledge
it or not cannabis is international
right now so people these small farmers
have to embrace the future and and just
hold the [ __ ] on because once this goes
international these small farms
are overnight going to be big or are
going to be the next big napa wineries
all their products going to [ __ ] sell
out over and over and over and over
smart ones are gonna [ __ ] scale
immediately
and then they're gonna
and they're gonna you know
california right now california wheat is
all over the [ __ ] planet if you go on
instagram
you go on different feeds in the uk you
want different feeds in spain just the
fact of the matter is
there's there's california branded weed
everywhere and it's going for a premium
and that's you know so
a lot of people have to understand so
when we were breeding
we like to read what the black market's
doing and see what trends in the black
market are doing that's the most one of
the most demanding markets as far as
taste and flavor when you're just
dealing with people that that buy things
at the highest ticket possible and so
it's like what the black market's doing
you know worldwide you know you're
seeing a lot of you know somehow a lot
of these packs from cali
are are are going worldwide but they're
going for huge premiums and that should
be indicated to everybody that when this
[ __ ] switch flips guys
when this switch flips everyone's gonna
have it made that that that sacrificed
everything that put their [ __ ] dick
on the line you know put every put
everything on the line their families
their well-being to just keep doing this
dream of cannabis
we kind of stop looking at just the cali
thing even though it's the kali thing
for right now because it's not always
going to be like that the world's global
and the market dynamics are going to
change big time but one thing we've done
it's not going to change
is that consistently the best quality is
going to continue to come out of
california hands down
it's just our culture
what we're known for
that's it right
yeah it starts telling me you're at the
top it's hard right now it's hard to
look at it just hold on guys i believe
in everybody man it's like our [ __ ] was
so fire for years it was going back east
for a for a long time you know what i
mean
and and who else knows where it was
going but when what we know right now if
you if you just surf on instagram a
little hard you see cali weed in
different places in europe it happens
they have a whole import category at
clubs in amsterdam import weed get [ __ ]
out of here really i was like come on
guys that's the highest price point so
it's like people need to start
accepting that our fate as california
for the large part if you're raw at your
[ __ ] game
man it's gonna be like wine or your
shit's gonna go for extremely high
premiums one because your location and
two
because you got roots in the game and
you're able to back that up with your
quality
so it's like if you're at a farm and
you're holding on right now just keep
[ __ ] holding on guys because you know
you're going to do way better you know
you guys are going to be the magic
makers that connect with everybody
breeders can only connect with so many
people but growers connect with
everybody those are the true artists
so
what do you think is the best way to
deal with the dichotomy of you know
needing to use instagram or social media
in general as a breeder to promote your
brand but also you know trying to it's
necessary it's [ __ ] necessary
i think if anybody doesn't think it's
necessarily crazy your [ __ ] better be so
[ __ ] fire other people just naturally
post pictures of it you know what i mean
i think
the the uh
the world's changed
how we interface with people has changed
before it was on threads and it was on
forums it was on icmag
it was on the hustle but now
instagram's changed the game we're so
more connected than we've ever been
people are able to show their grow
methods you know we've seen a huge
exponential increase in raw growers
[ __ ] are put people a lot of
people a lot of hobbyist growers people
just starting out people just in
instagram are growing some good [ __ ]
because they're watching all these pros
on instagram sharing their knowledge man
sharing sharing the tech and so like you
know quality you know qualities you know
continuing to go up and that's because
the phenomena on instagram and more
people globally have been able to
discover aficionados through ig than we
ever have been you know being in
magazines you know being in you know
being a skunk you know and being at high
times you know i mean being in high
times is big for us but consistently
when you have a platform that reaches
everybody in the world and everyone
network you know overlaps to these over
worldwide networks it creates a reach
that we've never been able to see before
so it's like i think everyone's still
adjusting to this new culture of ig it's
absolutely necessary and if it's [ __ ]
up when people get their accounts
deleted because their livelihoods their
followings are dependent
on on on their ig and unfortunately a
lot of people's success is measured upon
their followers because people think
there's a corollary between your
followers and your consistency as being
someone who's a supplier of quality
so
but perception's reality and this is how
people communicate so we can't ignore
reality we got to be real
yeah right now it's on instagram it goes
down the dm
alrighty so just on to the final little
last few questions these are the more
short response ones generally speaking
first one it's a bit of a less harass
one but i have a feeling you have a good
answer what's your favorite tom hill
strain besides deep chunk
it was deep chunk
i know but that's why i said besides
because i heard stories
about him
um on spy rock
having the balls to select their 3 000
plants like nobody was doing that when
tom hill was doing that
[ __ ] nobody
and so the fact that he was able to get
the old blue hindu and the old red hindu
um
and they're
people in town laytonville can actually
trace back who the [ __ ] brought the
hindu back to leightonville and you know
it's not my business to to make you know
who these people are public knowledge
um but definitely you know jackson knows
these people you mean gene knows these
people 100 percent
um and you know these are the people
that originally brought hindu kush back
to spyroc in the 70s and so like when
tom hill was working at the 90s early
2000s nobody was doing that nobody was
putting their balls in the line selector
like that so it was just
the whole
mystique of him having him him being so
devoted to his craft he's willing to
blow it up that much not to sell the
flower but to select a [ __ ] seed oh
he was crazy back in the day to not use
that [ __ ] and to sell all that flour and
he was selecting for like the best
possible [ __ ] like that's passion and so
it's like for that one like he went
through that sacrifice to make deep
chunk bro that's my that's my backup why
it deep chunks my favorite of his it was
the folklore behind that too that really
attracted me yeah no it's a good story
it is a fan favorite so next one what
strain do you wish you had back
oh [ __ ] um
which one did i [ __ ] get rid of which
one have i lost
i lost my original g13 cross
that got lost i got lost in a raid it
was at a buddy's place
it was a g13 across panama
it wasn't anything that was
super special it was something that was
special to me in the terms that it
one it harvested late as [ __ ] you know
hardest is like 20 second week in
november but it didn't get any mold and
it had the craziest high the craze the
craziest high
um
but the one i really regret losing is uh
the really the the bulk of my white
cashmere seats
i think that was one of the strains that
i really could have opened up a lot more
i really could explore that one a lot
more
and um
you know there's a few others that
i've let kind of go out of the window
and i'm like [ __ ] i shouldn't have sold
all those you know because i it was to
me i did i want if i want it to me it
was a personal thing that if if i really
felt my work was good enough i'd let it
all go
you know i'd save like a little bit but
i wanted to see really where i stood
you know would it come back to me would
people keep working it and if people
didn't work it then obviously it wasn't
it didn't meet my expectations for for
what could be a classic you know because
because people weren't inclined to keep
working it and so it was things like
that where i released really small
numbers of it people didn't work it
because i felt like i could have done
better at the breeding
yeah you know
okay
so what is the most memorable or the
best strain you've ever smoked
[Applause]
big sur holy weed
um
we were at the cannabis cup
in in richmond i was with frenchie it
was the first cup i met bam
of when bam was still working with
coastal seeds
and i met mike from coastal seeds and i
had always read about the big sir holy
weed
and i was like dying to try it or i'm a
sativa guy
and i was dabbing all day it was like
when dabs and shatter came out it was
you know cannabis cup
and we were dead we were getting [ __ ]
up man we were dabbing like crazy i
didn't think i'd get any higher
mike pulls out this joint i meet mike
from coastal seeds through our friend
johnny q
and who johnny q runs stinky dink he's
also an emerald cup winner from 2011
and um
and [ __ ] he we light this big sir
holy weed and it cuts clear through all
the dabs
like it was almost like the c5 haze like
the closest thing to c5 hayes for me as
far as like intensity of cerebral high
was was mike's big sir holy weed that
[ __ ] was [ __ ] crazy
it was like it cut through all those
dabs we were smoking og
you know bamf was big at the time we
were smoking a lot of his [ __ ] lemon
oh g hash which was really strong you
know i had a kick
man but that [ __ ] big stroller that
was probably easily
the most that uh and and this too this
too when i won the cup in 2012
um derrick emerald gave me some flowers
of his in the pines
and derrick emerald had won five emerald
cups previous you know to me winning
and
to me i think he's probably one of the
absolute but he's
in my opinion the absolute best grower
to ever compete in the irmo cup circus
derek emerald and when i smoked his
flowers i think i think you know on
point with how blown away i was with
with mike's flowers that was really
memorable as far as like holy [ __ ]
that's big sir holy weed it's exceeded
all expectations it's incredible but
um
derek emerald's flowers and that in the
pines he gave me that year
was the absolute best flower i've ever
[ __ ] smoked you could taste
taste the [ __ ] love
that he put into it you know and then i
think also the first time i met
i met mean jean
is the first time that meen jean was at
the peg house and leggett
and um i meet him online
he's telling me he has some crazy [ __ ]
and he says hey come out to this reggae
show i'm going to be uh performing i'm
like [ __ ] you you do regular that's cool
cool
so i'm like out there i haven't met him
yet i'm waiting to meet jackson at the
peg house and we we see our our homie
he's like this you know oh this is og
guy uh everybody from the neighborhood
knows and i i said
what's up man here's my weed check out
my weed you know i show them this we of
this bud of uh something we selected
from the cantatonic that we called la
dolce vita it was like this 27 percent
thc
uh cantatonic was [ __ ] crazy
and um
then i smell what what what homie's
smoking on what rick was smoking on me
and
and it was like the craziest [ __ ]
flavor i've ever smelled and i'm like
what the [ __ ] are you smoking he goes uh
cherry
cherry cherry crust lime cherry pie
crust lime
and i'm like who grew that he was like
my boy he wouldn't tell me he grew it
you know he's like well boy and then you
know i remember
uh
jackson you know gene goes on stage he
does his thing kills it you know he's a
really good performer if you haven't
heard his music
um but he gets off stage and i'm like
bro you gotta [ __ ]
try this weed bro
he's like and then rick's like oh that's
my boy he's the one who made it and i
was like
you know it was like bro you know if you
would have entered that this year you
would have you would have
[ __ ] beat me like hardcore
like it would have been last line he was
like nah he was really humble about it
like nah your [ __ ] [ __ ] would have
won bro if you entered this and he ended
up [ __ ] getting a breeders cup with
cherry lime a few years later you know
what i mean
and it was like that was like so those
three experiences derek emerald
mike from coastal and then the first
time i met me and gene in 2012
at the peg house that was like the most
memorable pot experiences i had oh and
then one more i have to share one more
one more because it's good um
the first day i get to mendo i'm at
mountain mike's house
and um we had refreshed from san diego
we had just closed the club down uh the
sheriff said shut the club down
and uh but mike had some weed that was
hanging in the house for like literally
six [ __ ] months like the whole time
he was like he was mike when i was
running the club in san diego with mike
he was back and forth you know going
from mendo to san diego all the time
and so like when we finally had the club
shut down we were there
he had this weed that was hanging there
for six months and it was original urkel
it was the first time i had the realest
urkel and that was
that was probably some of the highest
probably the hot
some of the happiest high weed i've ever
smoked in my life was was that original
erko that mike had just sitting there
after months months and months and
months i never tasted a flavor like that
you know his house was like in the trees
and so it was in this place in the
stairs where his house was wood and
there was like a perfect it was always
cool and cold and there's always the
right
temperature so it just cured perfectly
after this last six months but you know
that was like it was my first time in
mendo and my first time smoking mental
weed was like you know that urkel so i
guess
you know those four experiences were
like
definitive to me which which changed how
i looked at weed and how i approached
that weed every single one of those
experiences
pushed me to want to
get to that level i was like wow that
level exists what do i have to do to
just get on that level what kind of
concentration do i need to have what
discipline do i need to have to express
myself in the way these guys are
expressing themselves
you know it came like that for me
yeah what an awesome little backstory so
on to our third last question polar
opposite of the best one what's the
worst weed strength barry white
[ __ ] hate barry white
it's a great plant to grow but it's got
it's just frosty it's got no kick the
hash sucks nobody wants to smoke it
you know it's definitely one strain that
i wasn't really a fan of like
um i'm a big fan of weed you know so
it's like there's one strain of hate
growing i hate growing bubba but i love
smoking that one but this one thing i
just hate smoking is [ __ ]
you know some people say blue dream
train wreck i like smoking all that [ __ ]
you know anyways for some reason
i do not very white yeah i'll always
have a little soft spot for blue dream i
reckon on to the next question
so desert island top three weeds all you
can smoke for the rest of your life what
are you gonna do
i have to go
that's a good one
damn he got me on that one okay okay i
got you i got you
original
it's really hard to find the original
sour d everybody says they have it but
it's not the real sour d even when i was
moving packs 1 out of 20 pounds was a
real sour d any hustler agree with that
yeah [ __ ] right he's probably
being nice too
um but if
i could find the you know the original
just like that [ __ ] crazy sour from
back in the day that would just stink up
your whole car i'd bring that with me
i definitely bring chem dog
yeah chem dog sauer
and c5 hayes
nice little array
yeah
yeah awesome
okay and so lucky last question if you
could go back in time to anywhere any
place to get some land race seeds
presumably where would you go
oh man
i don't know like
marco polo times in like southeast asia
like
you know before like western expansion
you know because with trade
you also saw the trade of certain
cultivars of plants that were being
domesticated by people throughout you
know uh you know europe and in asia
um so you know i always heard these
stories about you know my my favorite
weed just generally since i was in
thailand as a young kid was always been
the tie in the burmese weed and i always
wondered what
weed was like from those villages
because they they purposely cultivated
those flowers in certain parts of this
area just for their flower just for
smoking it you know whereas other places
in the region in the world like you know
like india and in pakistan and
afghanistan there's hash cultures and
other places that were cultivating him
we're cultivating it for fiber but you
know uh southeast asia is one of those
rare places where people you know and
some parts of africa too i won't forget
about that but um you know
[ __ ] thailand burma
1800s before western real real western
industrial you know technocratic
expansion happened where people where
their where their ancient way of life
was
um wasn't allowed anymore you know so i
wanted to you might you know if i had it
if i get a time machine would be what
was what what if they were one of the
only cultures on the [ __ ] planet
you know breeding weed and selecting it
for the taste and the high of the flower
man what the [ __ ] were they smoking on
before you know western before western
idea you know ideal says that this isn't
good for you and we have to outlaw that
or even before when
you know
you know different dramatic changes
happen in certain countries where that
culture is lost because the village is
obliterated due to war
you know that's also a factor too so
um
yeah i've got i got a thing for those
hazes from southeast asia
totally
alrighty so i think that might bring us
to just about the end of it did you have
any comments or shout outs you wanted to
make
man
uh dude big shout out to professor q
you know quentin man
big shout out to to my sister uh cherry
blossom bell who's frenchie's apprentice
big out shout out the frenchie
and uh
big shout out to my brother
who is you know the guy that is
responsible for for
for fighting to get me in the industry
when i got out i got out of the army
on those drug charges
and
and he was able to find me a job with
with mike he's he hooked me up with mike
who brought me up to mendo
and so i owe my brother that you know so
and now he's in mendo running a big ass
form that's so happy for him but big
shout out man i wouldn't be here without
you i love you
and um you know big shout out to big
shout out to me and jean you know he
played a big part in in helping you know
everything where it's at right now and
um how i approach work and learning from
the mistakes and [ __ ] like that you know
and uh
you know yeah big shout out to a big
shout out to me g man
yeah frenchie of course frenchy it's my
smile it's my family frenchie and kim i
love you guys
oh it's in james dude so james from
seeds here now that [ __ ] guy
big shout out not just because he's my
my c distro but he's been a good friend
to me and there was a time
um that that same year that you know the
year after mandelbrot passed away when
things got really rough for aficionado
you know james had a big part in saving
us
and so we could continue doing what we
do so like big shout out to james you
know he really takes care of his people
you know if you're hating on him it's
none of my [ __ ] business he's always
been good to us and make sure that you
know aficionado could continue to like
feed our family you know what i mean so
like big shout out to james
yeah hundred percent i can be right he's
always looked after us here as well
all righty so i think that thanks for
the opportunity bro i really appreciate
it man yeah no worries dude thanks so
much for coming on the show and for
dropping all the knowledge bombs
well yeah it's just some yeah i'm happy
to share bro thanks for the platform and
you know it's really cool to be able to
you know talk to people like you and
then you're really good dude like the
questions were like wow it's a good one
so there you have it family
a big thank you again to leo for taking
the time to join us today
and a big thank you to you guys for
hanging around for the whole show
keeping me company
as always huge shout out to our three
sponsors seeds here now 420 australia
and organic gardening solutions these
are my favorite three go check them out
guys you won't be disappointed
likewise huge shout out to the patreon
game as i say every week lifeblood of
the show blessed with that extra content
if you two want to check it out go see
it for yourself otherwise i'll see you
next time guys
[Music]
la la la la
[Applause]
[Music]
lalalala