[Music]
welcome everyone to the first episode of
the podcast a cannabis breeding and
culture podcast our first episode is
proudly sponsored by 420 Australia your
Premier clothing and lifestyle store as
well as the brothers Grim Seed Company
you know them they're back with the
favorites and More in our first episode
we have Duke Diamond VA of the brothers
Grim who is kind enough to sit down for
the best part of 3 hours as well as
giving us a tour of the brothers grim
facility in Colorado although this show
is a podcast this episode was actually
going to be a video episode However
unfortunately due to a technology
gramlin the video didn't save properly
and we only have the audio however this
doesn't affect the interview at all also
I just quickly wanted to apologize to Mr
Sol and Duke the first 20 seconds of the
interview was cut out and this was when
they were both introducing themselves so
again my apologies but we're just going
to jump right into the interview just
after they've introduce themselves as
we've walked into the first mother room
of the
tour you're looking at the uh this is a
sour diesel uh skunk hybrid here um you
know the original Sour Diesel was a a
skunk that came out of Virginia and it
got crossed with the Kim dog and that
made your Sour Diesel so what I did was
I took the same genetic the the my skunk
is from the same family and we crossed
it to the sour diesel to bring out more
of the skunky side of things there so
you know we have a couple of those right
here um we have
yeah man and then over here we have the
same skunk maale to the Kim dog so
essentially we've made a sour diesel
using uh just using a regular mail
instead of like a hermaphrodite accident
you know so having these two yeah we'll
grow them out you know we'll look at
little different traits you know like
little leaf traits like how thin thick V
uh variegation or the serrations and
branching pattern and things like that
and then we can take these things and
kind of assess them and we could
actually use this like maybe a male from
this to the female sour diesel clone and
maybe outcross back to the sour diesel
skunk depending on what traits we're
looking for whether it be yield or
something cool like that uh so you're
almost doing a s diesel IBL in a way
yeah exactly like we'll put it into a
seed form to where like you you know
everybody chases down that clone and
with that clone they they kind of screw
up you know because there's a lot of
fake ones you know and everybody over
here wants to be a special Little
Snowflake and they're like oh yeah we
got it we got it they ain't got [ __ ] man
they ain't got nothing they got some Bag
seed from something that ain't even sour
right so it's pretty cool that if people
could actually like grow that in seed
for and be able to experience that too
and be able to like sprout seeds and
actually have them come up sour and
Diesel and you know have something good
and just for everyone listening um
you're referring to AJ's Sour Diesel is
the
original yeah like he didn't breed it or
anything but the guys up around Albany
and up in New York City those are the
guys who created her um a friend of mine
on Instagram he goes by Skunk VA he uh
he's the guy who traded him the skunk
for the Kim dog back in 94 and um those
are that's the crew that made the sour
diesel it was an accident really but you
know it got made a that's so interesting
cuz I was wondering how did uh how did
you tie into the whole chem family well
back in uh let's see I think it was uh
2004 um I met uh guy Kim dog everybody
called him back in it was mass G for
Massachusetts and G was his uh initial
of his first name that just kind of
bumped into him I was going and hitting
up like music festivals and things like
that and
um you know we decided like hey let's
hang out and I had a cutting of uh you
know ironically enough right now
Cinderella 99 which is all that stuff
back there yeah it's all Cindy but um so
he really wanted that and I was like
yeah no problem so we get together and
we're smoking and everything and he's
like yeah you know I got this uh this
stuff I grow called Kim dog if you you
know want to try it and I was like yeah
man absolutely so and here we are at
this plant this is the uh Kim dog d
right here um so that's how you got your
c yeah he says uh yeah try this and you
know he's a really big guy too huge
hands big Burly dude and he gives me
this little tiny tiny bong and he's like
yeah hit it so I took I took two hits
off of it and I started to sweat man and
I mean [ __ ] up like a Soup Sandwich
Man like really really high and he's
like you think it's any good and I was
like you damn right it's good I love it
and he's like what do you want it and I
was like absolutely I tooken up some
clones of skunk and white widow and
bunch of bunch of different stuff G13
hybrids and anyway he gives me this and
uh gives me a whole bunch of stuff like
super snow dog and whole bunch of cool
stuff and then uh like over here this is
the original this is the what they call
the 91 uh it also goes by the skunk VA
um my buddy he's uh he's the guy kind of
held her safe for you know what 20s
something years so but that's her she uh
she's a little more viny you know a
little more lanky and everything but uh
man most killer killer weed on Earth
though I mean it's is so so strong and
then like hell everybody's always like
God it's so much like OG and stuff so
here this is the uh triangle cush here
which is actually like the mother of all
what they call OG strains you know a I
see and she's from Florida
1992 but yeah you can kind of get a look
of that structure and like how you know
she's very noty you know and then like
you can look at the Ken dog and you can
kind of see some of those of those same
traits so yeah yeah see I hear a lot
about the uh the history of ogs and you
hear about things like the crippy and uh
obviously triangle Kush quite a bit you
you think it's pretty definitively
triangle
Kush oh yeah um so like uh you you heard
of uh cornbread rookie before right yeah
he's pretty big on
Instagram yeah yeah so he's got Swamp
Boy seeds and stuff so he's the guy who
gave that triangle its name
uh I don't know if y'all know about like
the mysterious things of the world they
have the uh Bermuda Triangle you know
where ailia air heart was flying and got
lost in it and all that so the way I got
that name was you know stuff would [ __ ]
you up so bad
man you yeah you get lost where the hell
you're going so they ended up calling it
The Triangle and like they're from
Florida too so uh you know that name
kind of stuck but me and him have talked
and and you know these these plants uh I
can't really get into it too much but
these plants they're they're very very
very closely related yeah so it all
boils down
to couple of people that were doing some
things kind of running in the same
circles but just uh you know that type
of deal old illegal
world yeah so just stay on that same
point um a lot of your plants they look
so fantastic it's unbelievable how old
some of them are what's your opinions on
how to um keep your clones nice and
vigorous you know not letting them go to
crap over
time well I would say the the number one
thing to do um so I tell you what man
I'm gonna take y'all on a tour to the
mom area here where we keep our old
mother plants and all these good
things awesome probably a little bit
quieter too eh yeah know it's
so like right here this is a master cush
from
1996 oh
wow nice big broad
Le oh yeah man so like the key I would
say is you know you keep a plant healthy
now when my cousins gave me this back in
the day you know we kept things pretty
pretty healthy now I got busted DEA back
back in 2007 and I had some friends you
know keep cuting here and there and my
one friend we used to call him the
butcher because like he'd keep a gray
room 110 degrees he'd have spider mites
he wouldn't feed them right you know
plant look like utter dog [ __ ] so you
know you get a cutting back from them
and I mean just looks terrible you don't
even think this thing's going to live
but if you take the cutting and um I
I'll throw you a little trick so if you
got something really really sick um a
plant cannabis plant they they put off a
it's called Sal aiic acid that's part of
their their immune system so um like to
us like be like me and you getting like
some antibiotics to help us beat an
infection or something so what you do is
you get a aloe vera powder or aloe vera
water okay now that's very high dose of
Sal atic acid you can water it with that
and there's something else called neem
cake that uh is really rich in it's
called Aida
uh all these things help to support the
immune system so if you give it that and
then you're also uh you know like me I'm
a soil guy everything's all organic soil
so if you got a good microbial life in
your dirt here and uh you you got what
it needs to to eat and Thrive and you
got a good light source on it um you can
make that clone look great so if I told
you that you know before you're seeing
this that when I got this clone it
looked like something barely alive well
you treat it good you grow out a big
nice mom like this and then you start
taking good healthy cuting and once you
keep that good healthy cutting long as
you keep it healthy man you know they're
good for for years and years and years
now you'll have to excuse me like some
of these like this one we just got
through taking a whole bunch of clones
man for new breeding program but uh
beautiful don't worry thank you man but
this one here this is from 1984 this is
Durban poisonin yeah but still just as
bigger as this can beig kicking ass over
here we have the Airborne
G13 I forgot the exact year but I think
it's somewhere around like 86 or 88
something along them lines but yeah man
keep them healthy and then over here we
got the 88 G13 hash plant it's been
hacked on a little bit for cuttings and
all but the one and nice yeah man the
one and only man the
thriller so um just kind of looping back
to the uh that other point you made um
especially in terms of talking about
kind of the biochemistry behind it I
love uh the KB cycle post you had on
your Instagram um and I personally know
that uh you're an engineer but I was
wondering did you do any uh like biology
or biochemistry courses at all CU you
seem to have a fairly good grasp of that
as well
yeah they um so the the school I went to
basically they're like you know y'all
are a bunch of country pumpkins and like
you guys you know you better learn how
to work on a car or wire something up or
weld something or you know you kids are
going to be screwed but they also so
where I'm from is big uh big
agricultural area so we grew a lot of
tobacco um soybeans Tomatoes you know
about anything you can think of and we
grow a little weed back in the woods you
know a little supplemental income but um
we we we did have like some pretty
decent little classes in high school now
they weren't like very Advanced but it
was enough to really get my interest
peaked and basically man we cheap
library card I'd do all the researching
I could and anything I could learn man
I'd try to pick it up and then I would
apply it and I'd say okay that's good or
it's bad and I just kept the good things
and left the bad [ __ ] behind and um yeah
it's uh definitely helps if you you know
you get into a little bit of the biology
and that gives you a pretty good
fundamental on you know how plants work
and photosynthesis and chloroplast and
chlorophyll and all these different
things but if you can understand why
something does what it does when it does
it and how you can help facilitate that
that's all the base knowledge you need
need and then like when you start
finding out like oh okay so these plants
when they're stressed out or pissed off
well they they want to start producing
Sal atic acid to help their responses so
like think about what's this plant's
response right like why does it produce
resin well it's horny man it wants
pollen it wants to catch pollen and get
pregnant also man that it's [ __ ]
bright in here man they want to produce
sunscreen as well and also like like you
know hell man like right
now so I just plucked that leaf off
right here right so I pluck that leaf
off it doesn't know I plucked that leaf
off it thinks something's eating it so
right now it's sitting there saying oh
[ __ ] something's eating me what should I
do so all of its responses are you know
putting off resin for sunscreen to get
pregnant or maybe to produce more toxins
or in our case drugs like THC so when
this little rat eats this little leaf
he's going to think twice about it
because he's all [ __ ] up now shaking
and [ __ ] so you just kind of learn how
to stimulate responses and then
facilitate those responses the best that
you can um whether it's Alo water salic
acid you know or coconut water with
enzymes and cycin to help it produce
more you know plant material uh in our
case flowers
um you know and you're just trying to
you know give it everything it needs as
well as kind of teas isn't it like the
horse and the carrot you know you dangle
it in front of the horse and it get gets
you going yeah so more or less man so I
guess this kind of brings us into this
kind of domain of you know how much of
breeding and high quality production is
science versus say an art you know
there's always this debate of science
versus art and you know I frequently
hear of people like your friend JJ myc
of top dog and people talk about how he
has this Knack this hunch for picking
males you know do you think at the end
of the day a good breeder is just mostly
going on a scientific approach or
there's a little something extra
involved so the eye that people speak of
you know like when me and soul walk into
a room and we're looking at plants
what's striking our
eye where we say hey we're looking at a
certain trait in a
plan it's basically that we've done it
so much that it's a learned thing so it
technically it is science like we're
basically piling down to to Gene Pairs
and frequencies of these desirable Jean
pairs things that we like that we want
to see more of so say for instance
um so I make that strain uh Grim right
you seen them big ass buds right oh yeah
so the mother plant the hash plant it
grows buds man like the biggest On's
probably about you know oh man it looks
huge because of the punching my head it
uh it it that's right y'all are
millimeters and centimeters uh so like a
bud would be like the size size of an
ink pen right the longest one yeah now
on the father's side it throws colas
that are the size of a man's forearm now
if I want to see those forearm
buds on that female plant I can say well
in our male we know that hey you know he
uh he looks like this the other male
looks like this other male looks like
this so we could say that male ju has a
thinner Leaf um maybe a particular smell
to the stem rub and say he's uh thin and
sweet say male number two is super wide
leaf and a little more fuy and say male
number three is something in between the
two now if we look at the sisters of
these males we could say that male
number two with the kind of big fat
leaves
his females you know counterparts his
sisters throw big huge colas right so
these two traits could be linked so big
fat Leaf could also be linked to big fat
bud and floral
cluster or it could be the opposite you
know so you would know to say that okay
so the male that I'm wanting to roll
with could be this big fat one if I'm
looking for yield so I take this big fat
wide Leaf thing I pollinate this hash
plant and then we look at the results so
now in the in the progyny man we're
looking at these
children and these kids man we notice
that you know you're still going to see
these thin leafed phenotypes you know
that maybe had the smaller bud and
you're also going to see the other
phenotype with the wider leaf and you
notice hey throwing big huge buds again
so we could refine this a step further
and take like a you know a male same
type deal fale and take it to an F2
generation and then we could do it again
and take it to an F3 and basically what
you're looking to do is if you were only
trying to do that one thing that's cool
but we're not that fortunate you know
our crops we're looking for smell we're
looking for flavor we're looking for
potency yield Vigor all these different
things so you're trying
to up the frequencies of all these
desirable things and
know how to find them by
these like I said these Gene pairs so I
might be looking at a leaf trait on one
with a smell trait I could be looking at
Health even the serration or how many
leaves that it's actually producing on
these fan leaves or a number of
different things there's root mass
there's speed of growth how long did the
males take to get to sexual maturity was
always a big one for me like as far as
potency how fast does it veg does it veg
slow does it veg quick because all the
plants they have this energy in them you
know like so if he's not trying to grow
super quick that means his energy is in
there he's going to do something with it
so maybe it's going to be throwing big
massive guds and flour or maybe all his
energy is going into resin production
right so a lot of it is you know you go
off of these things first then you see
what you come up with at the end and
then you can assess it from there and
move forward um another step would be
instead of the filial generation
breeding we could take these and like
say back cross it you know so let's say
now I'm throwing these big massive huge
buds but I lost a little potency but the
mama hash plant man you know puts your
dick in the dirt so I might say well
I'll find my mail out of that F1
generation look for that big leaf trade
again for those big buds and then back
cross it back to the original mom and
try to regain some potency from there
you know
yeah so with kind of that same topic in
mind we see like Labs these days
offering tests claiming they can you
know tell the sex of males before
they've even got more than a couple
nodes going how do you think this kind
of thing plays into the scene do you
think it's like a fat or do you think
this technology will legitimately find a
use in most breeders
stable I think that what the price of it
and the availability of it coming that I
really do think that it would help if I
could put genetic markers on these
things like these pairs that I'm able to
see with my eye it would help me along
to be able to say well it's definitely
this you know there's sign backing this
up I had these markers put into place
for yield and potency so it would it
would help me along pretty good but I
mean you got to be a rich [ __ ]
to be able to afford all that right now
and you know guys like uh Sol myself
we've done it for so many years without
being able to go to a lab you know or
any of these things to where we can do
it do it by ey and putting it on paper
and recording these things so you know
it does help but on the other to and
like you don't AB absolutely need it it
is a nice thing don't get me wrong but
you know we can still accomplish what
we're looking to do you know without uh
without the labs and everything yeah for
sure so kind of uh how you just
mentioned you've been doing this for
years something I wanted to ask everyone
I interview is uh take me back to uh
when you first started smoking what was
your initial acquaintance with cannabis
you know was it a family affair was it
you and some friends getting up to some
Mischief so uh I had a friend in high
school and ironically enough his last
name is BL I don't know if yall SP once
over in uh over in Australia or not but
um so uh him and this other girl named
Jessica was little punk rock chick and
she had some good weed and we smoked it
and right then and there I loved it you
know it like made me feel real good and
calm and I was always kind of anxious
and I don't know a little uptight and
didn't really like people well I guess I
still don't like people too much it
really it did enhance yeah definitely
enhanced things so from there I'm like
well I'm going to take these seeds out
of this weed and I can grow tomatoes I
can grow everything under the Sun so why
should this be any different so I
started growing it and uh my cousins man
they they saw me you know what I was
doing I was 12 years old and I had all
these seedings sprouted up and they were
like you know look man it is what it is
you're doing what you're doing let's
let's help you do it a little safely so
you don't end up in prison you don't end
up all screwed up and we'll show you how
to do it the right way and basically
that year I turned into a water boy and
I would help him take large amounts of
water through the woods which really
suck because in Virginia summertime
temperatures like 11 Fahrenheit 80 90%
humidity It Feels Like a Jungle and uh
you got snakes man copperheads and water
moccasins and then you got you know uh
Hunters here they have these people
called game wardens that make sure that
you don't kill too many deer or whatever
the hell but they also during the summer
months they help uh help the cops locate
grows so they were showing me how to be
sneaky about it and how to hide it and
all the right things so something of an
apprenticeship and I got to learn yeah
how to make seeds for the next year or
the following years and um you know how
to locate the good plants and how to top
them or pinch them and make them bush
outout and how to feed them and how to
mix soil and uh make use of you know
what's around you and finding water and
such so that's kind of how I got kicked
off and so what was the scene like back
then was it all everyone was kind of
inly doing their own thing amongst their
kind of Hill is the expression I've
heard or was it more kind of people were
just starting to work together and get
the ball
rolling well in those days like in my
area at least it was uh um it was
something that you kept very very quiet
you didn't want to uh you didn't even
want people knowing you smoke weed
because like if that joker man he gets a
DUI even uh which is here it's driving
Under the Influence so you were drinking
beer and driving drunk you know so in
order for them to get out of trouble
they would say oh yeah officer you know
I'm drunk as [ __ ] but this guy up the
Street's growing weed or he smokes weed
or whatever they tell on you then you're
up in the damn uh prison and then
they're free so that there was that and
then other people would just bother you
all the time hey man sell me a little
bag I Just Want To Grim or it just more
trouble than it was worth so you just
kept everything super super super quiet
you damn shed it and let nobody know you
grow uh you uh that was like rule number
one you don't tell nobody nothing you
always keep it Qui it is can be yeah so
on your first couple of grows what were
they like you know what type of
Technology were you using and I think
more kind of interesting to me is what
was the quality
like so ironically like you know my
cousins man they started me off they
bought stuff from the super sativa seed
club that was their main place they like
to get their seed stopped sssc oh
awesome super awesome now now as a kid
I'm like well I'm looking at this
magazine they're like oh yeah bubble gum
blueberry this and that and I'm like oh
wow look at these pictures and that
looks like the [ __ ] man I'm I'm GNA I'm
going to buy this stuff and I'm GNA try
to grow this and then you find out that
it won't that good man it really won't
so genetically I was really started out
on the on the right path um fck far as
technology went in the early years I was
a strictly Outdoors Man um didn't really
want to set anything up
inside and not that I could I was so
young you know I didn't I didn't have a
place to do it but um so when I was 15 I
got kicked out of the house uh mom uh
caught me with a few pounds of weed I I
was stupid I was trying to stashing in
my closet and the whole house smelled
like a dead skunk you know just a few
pants um yeah just a few pounds man I
was just trying to get by you know need
to buy some comic books so um you know
that that happened and then um I went
down to the city which is like Richmond
Virginia and I was able to hook up um a
little apartment with a buddy and I was
like hey man I can grow us some more of
this you know he was like all right so I
got a uh it was actually a Street Lamp
and yeah wired it up and I hooked up a
single bulb with a parabolic reflector
um which is funny because that's how Mr
Souls got his rigged up right now but
he's kicking ass with it like I'll tell
you man these parabolic reflectors they
do a pretty good job so um so I hook up
one of those now growing outside I
mean I was kicking ass you know I do
real good so growing inside it was a big
learning curve because now I don't have
Mother Nature helping me so much man um
now it's kind of all up to me so it's
too hot too humid um I
mean it didn't look good man it I'm i'
been a sham like I wouldn't show show
nobody that [ __ ] it was awful
so so I start uh getting some books and
I'm like man I got to I got to figure
this indoor [ __ ] out so I got uh I think
it was Ed
Rosenthal closet cultivator and then I
had marijuana botney by Robert conel
Clark and the B was more like a college
textbook you know it it it taught me a
lot of
like why this cannabis plant is doing
what it's doing and why it's doing it
but the closet cultivator gave me some
ideas like hey you know you get a little
dehumidifier you know you're looking to
keep it around this temperature or this
temperature and a lot of little tricks
so I took it to heart I really tried you
know and I was like this I not having my
ass whipped by this indoor grow and I
made it happen and it turned out really
really good and then I just kept trying
to refine it a little bit each time you
know so and that's the other thing man
people all keep saying like oh that
guy's a master grower man he's a master
man I'm gonna tell you
the day you think you got that plant
mastered it will show you you don't know
[ __ ] man it will humble your ass so you
never Master it but you get a little bit
better each time you do it and that's
the thing don't ever close your mind you
know just keep it open and keep learning
and you know maybe not trying so many
different things but always be open to
try something different you know and
even if it sounds kind of weird and
crazy like when I started doing like m
and sugar and juice and you know pouring
it on these plants most people are like
dude you're insane man you're going kill
that [ __ ] and but I mean if you
break it down into the science of it and
you look at it you're like oh yeah that
that makes sense and then you know
proofs in the pudding so you know try it
out and you're like yeah it's
good yeah so um just touching back on
how you mentioned uh RC Clark and um a
few others who were the the uh the
people you looked up to in the early
days who were your go-to breeders and
your gurus so to
speak so the first people that I spoke
with so I had a buddy he had a computer
which was awesome I didn't have a
computer never used computers or any of
that so he had internet which was like
who this is cool man you know you can
look at porno and weed and everything
and they had these forums you know and
I'm like okay so like you could see
these other Growers and they're taking
pictures of their weed which I was like
dude man that's sketchy crazy man so uh
some of the first people I talked to was
like Vick High um subcool uh Mr soul and
we got to really you know sharing and
talking about different ways of growing
and um you know just kind of just
sharing back and forth like hey look at
this this is pretty cool or hey I see
what you got there man that looks pretty
cool and you know you kind of pick up
little tidbits and tricks you know like
one guy might have a cool little soil
recipe that you you know you add it to
yours or he might have a different way
of growing or breeding or you never know
and you just take all these little good
tidbits you put them
together and wham bam you know you start
coming up with some real winning winning
recipes you
know so uh sounds like you're in a
pretty fortunate position to be able to
chat to all of these awesome uh breeders
at the time where did the original
Brothers Grim fit into things for you
were they kind of hitting their Peak
popularity when you were getting into
growing like where did you see them in
their initial
Incarnation it was really weird because
like when I when I made my first order
uh in
2000 like they were known but not like
you know super hugely well known um I
don't really think people realized what
they had or how good it was until after
it was gone you know
um people would Overlook things back in
those days you know because you had your
old standby sounds like
today yeah yeah it's exactly like today
but we almost have like the opposite
problem because like like a million of
these guys that are like oh yeah we're
breeders it's like bro because you put
[ __ ] pollen on a on a marijuana
flower don't make you a [ __ ] breeder
man you're a seed maker a glorified seed
maker so you you got all this garbage
out there to try to root through but
back then there weren't that many people
doing it but people were very afraid to
to change you know and like for for good
reason too because there was a lot of
just chicken [ __ ] gentics in too but I
saw the
pictures um and like Soul's descriptions
of the [ __ ] like piak my interest you
know I'm like yeah I want to walk on the
[ __ ] Moon you know yeah I want to you
know smoke some we to make me trip the
[ __ ] out right buddy so you know like I
was like well that sounds real good and
a quick flower time so I'm like all
right I'm going to take me my money I'm
going to get a money order I'm going to
send it on up to Canada the Heaven
Stairway and I'm going to get a pack of
this [ __ ] and see what it's all about
and it was so good that it's
2016 or a DEA raid later and I still got
that same clone had I lost that I would
be so butt hurt man I'd be really mad if
I lost that man yeah so uh yeah I mean
you know they they were they were
getting an in back then but they just
didn't have the uh the recognition yet
and then it was definitely afterwards
everybody's disbanded and long gone
before people were like wow that was the
[ __ ] yeah for sure so how did you
initially get in touch with Mr soul and
kind of broach the idea of bringing
Brothers Grim back or did he come to you
with the
idea well
subcool uh hit me
up what the [ __ ] was
that like uh like a summer summer like
like this time this year wasn't it or a
little earlier yeah yeah so it was
probably yeah around June of last year
and said hey man [ __ ] uh Mr Soul just
gotten told to me and he was like
looking looking to get back in the
industry get a job and I was like Oh
okay that's cool and he's like do you
you know you know any place he could you
know come out and do [ __ ] I was well you
know here in Colorado and you know
there's there's jobs to be had out here
so ended up uh he gives me a call he's
like yeah man I'm ready to ready to rock
and roll man I'm like all right cool so
I'll set you up with this little job
here you can work with me and we got to
you know working around each other we're
like yeah man you know start making some
seeds and we got the genetics we know
what to
do you know why not seems like the right
the Right Mix the right match and we
just said [ __ ] it the world what it
wants resurrect Brothers yeah give them
what they want man that [ __ ] they've
been missing that's it that's it so when
you guys first started uh brainstorming
what were some of the initial ideas you
had for brothers Grim was it initially
let's just re-release some of the
classics and go from there or did you
kind of had some clear goals as to what
you wanted to do in the
future well we uh we definitely knew
that uh right off the bat you got to
have the classics um stuff that like we
were saying people didn't realize what
they had or what was out there until it
was already gone so you know having
Cinderella um um having the Apollos the
Rosetta all these old classics you know
that was a definite you got to have it
you got to have it out there um but we
did realize like hey you know we do have
all this original stock it's only so
much work to to get these done and back
out there but we already know that the
work from back in the 990s into the
2000s I mean it just crushes everything
that that's around today like I can't
believe these Jokers have been working
[ __ ] 15 years years and got this
chicken [ __ ] but
so yeah I'm GNA try to be nice man but I
mean for real [ __ ] man so we know like
that's already G to be good but we
looked at it like okay well where did we
want to go like what what else did we
want to do so we're picking up on some
of his old stuff and you know I had a
lot of my own things that I was looking
to do and things that I did way back
that were like great strange but I
didn't sell seeds you know I'd sell some
to like an outdoor farmer you know in
the northeast or you know just helping
friends out or growing them myself so
it's stuff that I know that the general
public you know they really dig it so we
were looking along the lines of that and
then you kind of look at like what's the
world missing you know like there's not
really any really serious good Haze
hybrids you know the JJ kicks ass with
the Kim dog you know what I mean um but
you know there's you know a lot more
work that can be done with the Kim dog
and stuff you know of course there's
like a million people out there like e
Sour Diesel and Seed form and it ain't
sour and it ain't diesel you know so you
know I thought that was a good one um
the skunk you know that kind of went out
back in the 90s people talk about oh
yeah road kill skunk's real awesome so
you know that was something we know you
have to resurrect that good Haze hybrids
good sativas basically all the things
that people want but it's really not out
there um and you know like a lot of the
Indica stuff too is you know real big a
lot of people are getting Indica stuff
and they're like oh yeah it's Indica but
it's really it's like it's more than a
poly hybrid and it's not really Indica
either you know it's not really that
good narcotic drug traits that we're
looking for you know the stuff that just
makes you melt in the couch like oh I
can't move man I want to get pizza but I
can't move so you know you need these
things back in your life so um and we
got our old genetic collection back it
goes as far back as 1978 some of these
clones so you know we're able to really
kick it off and get things rolling
proper again the way they should be you
know yeah so I've got a bit of a longer
question here but it does tie into those
indicates um so not too long ago I was
watching when Mr Soul was on the uh the
Adam dun show and um and he was speaking
about his former partner Sly and it made
me realize that you and him have a lot
in common in my opinion um and you know
I hope I don't paraphrase Mr Soul wrong
here but um he essentially said you know
not only did he help him with the
breeding but he helped him to kind of
round out the offering in terms of bring
some other strains to the table and it
certainly appears like you uh seem to do
that in terms of the Grim deer and the
hashm in the new release so how do you
feel about this comparison to Sly and uh
do you are these new Inda strains kind
of more your
children yeah man um I definitely I
really really like my indicas um soly
did a great job like uh one of my
favorite ones was called sugar blossoms
and um that was one that really didn't
make it out a lot but man it was really
killer so like on the same token like I
loved like the Cindy I loved the Apollo
but like green GI was was a great one um
the sugar blossoms was great the Grim
Widow was great so SL he was pretty
kickass dude himself man I'd say you'd
agree right bu
yeah got lucky
both yeah got lucky
twice and uh so when we look at the new
uh Brothers Grim offering just recently
put out um we noticed that some of the
strains have been slightly altered in
their genetic composition for re-release
such as the Rosetta Stone which now has
a pure Jack Hera mother as well as the
Apollo 11 which is now sort of a back
cross um why did you guys decide to do
this and how do you think it'll affect
them compared to say the former
editions so with the uh I'll start I
guess with the uh the Rosetta Stone um
so Cafe girl for for one it's it's goner
she's not to be had
anymore yeah even before I broke down
business yeah he was saying he was he
was planning to call her out before
before it even stopped but I would
say yeah it was like one of them things
some people like some people don't um
but the the the girl herself would have
been out of those three seeds the most
uh Jack leaning of the of the group um
me personally I say like the the the
genius is the most of the haze dominant
of the of the group The Princess to me
is more of the nl5 dominant out of the
group um
so when you want to do like like Rosetta
Stone the Jack hair
is just mindblowing what the one that we
use it's the same one that ceny would
have used
um Jack har even selected the selected
the Clone
personal cut very yeah exactly it's very
very very stinky it's got that super
lemon Pine Haze Funk uh yeah sandalwood
and all it doesn't have yeah make
a probably attract other men
unfortunately y there we go we got the
name
man yeah man we're shutting down the
seeds we're going into the yeah colon
and fragrances so um but the structure
of it that sativa Haze dominance out of
it um made a made a better parent than
the cafe girl would have ever made and
um would have given you a better
improved version of Rosetta Stone and
kind of what it was intended to be was a
very you know nice hazy put you put your
mind in the
clouds yeah a lot of Jack influence man
that's what we're looking for yeah nice
um as far as the um so the a11 is
actually going to be just a11 it won't
be a back Cross or anything we just had
to go grow out a literal [ __ ] ton of
Cinderella 999 and find the right mail
to use and we've grown out more than
what I'm even comfortable saying right
now we got
boy and that boy he's lined up back
right in here we're going to make like a
nice little little batch of nothing but
a11 in there so we'll have that Cindy
hitting the um the genius and making a11
from scratch the um the Apollo 13 same
way it's not a back cross it's just made
from just made from scratch the same
same way as it always was p75 the genius
and you got it so everything made the
made the same way but that Rosetta Stone
that would be the one that is that is
different nice but I mean we could
totally argue it it's a bit improved
even
maybe awesome I'm sorry I didn't hear
youor I was going to say I'm sure the
Rosetta Stones
improved oh yeah man I'm gonna uh matter
of fact uh I'll take y'all on a little
tour since we're talking about it man
I'll show you a couple of the different
uh pheno types of the of the old Rosetta
just got to walk upstairs man oh yeah
here there a big ass Cindy Cindy Mom oh
nice while we're talking about Cindy I
got a quick question on it obviously
Cindy is um actually a bx3 you know it's
a it's another word for the princess bx3
um in your ideal world would you want
all Brothers Grim strains to be kind of
true breeding and at that backcross
level or do you think f1s have a good
place in the breeding World little bit
both uh so like uh the Sunday 99 that's
uh four four bat
crosses oh that makes it very breeding
stop certain things I would say yeah so
there's to me uh filial breeding and
backat Crossing they're two different
tools so certain tools work better for
certain jobs so you could say like with
Apollo and Apollo 11 they're way way
better as an F1 just that original F1
hybrid than they are as a backat cross
or F3 F4 you start to lose things so
certain
strains you start to lose things in
Translation you know um certain things
you can you can back cross them Filly
them out um and improve them even you
know make them more potent or better
right but um certain things they they
just don't they don't like it you can
lock found smell flavor structure all
this but sometimes you start to lose
that potency and a lot of that I
attribute to the just that hybrid Vigor
you know having two unrelated things or
even two slightly related things go
together and you you create a monster
but you take it beyond that you might be
able to keep a lot of it but some of it
you know it's not going to be as good as
that F1 so with us we're like you know
it's got to be meet the parent or beat
the parent we don't accept mediocrity
man if it ain't as good or better it
goes right down the [ __ ] man we a we
ain't having it so we we want great not
good you know yeah yeah through here so
I'm not sure if you've noticed but there
seems to be like a a current Trend among
some breeders to just want to take
everything to the F2 or the F3 do you
think that this is a a bit of a the
wrong kind of approach or do you think
maybe they'd be better off maybe back
Crossing things or just keeping them as
f1s um certain things they could um so
when somebody makes an
F2 um a lot of people they don't have
the concept of what's going to happen
they think oh wow you know they took it
to F2 it's going to be stable right but
that's not the case man when you breed
stuff to F2 if like I take um let's say
I take like an indicia plan and a pure
te a plant and I make a F1 and we're
seeing like five phenotypes you know one
should be more like the mom three should
be like a blend of the two and then one
should be more like the daddy so now we
take it to an F2 and I think the ratio
is like the [ __ ] is it man it's like
9335 it so basically what happens is now
you got every color of the rainbow yeah
man it is all over the place you'll see
stuff not only from the mom but [ __ ]
from her mom and her dad and all these
recessive things popping
up yeah before you
stabilize Yeah so basically you know
you're just going to end up with this
big nasty spread now it can be cool like
if me and you are looking for a very
very special
something to use like yeah I mean it it
could be cool but for people that are
like oh well take like Girl Scout
cookies right so you take that garbage
right it's already a poly hybrid you
even if you do make an F1 with something
it's still a poly hybrid so now if you
take that you make an F2 and you got
[ __ ] all over the place and somebody's
going to say hey man it's F2 Girl Scout
cookies and they're going to show you
this picture of a for cut Girl Scout
cookies man you'll be hard pressed to
find that sucker in them f2s you're
going to see stuff all over the place so
you know it it has its place but
normally an F2 is like something that a
you know a good solid breeding program
and you're looking to really refine
something during that F2 search or if I
didn't find what I wanted to use as like
say like a backat cross to Something in
the mom I didn't really see exactly what
I was looking for in my F1 population I
might take it to an F2 to get that big
diversity to find that rare thing that I
am looking forward to where I have more
of these Gene Pairs and one male per se
to take that and then take it back to
the mom then use it um now taking things
to F3 and F4 like I said you do
stabilize them but you some strains like
it some strains don't some of them are
going to say yeah we're going to be
structurally great but the potency is
going to go down the smell is going to
water down some of them get better so
it's kind of a trial and error I guess
from strain to strain to what you know
what you're going to be able to
accomplish I found that cubing like if
you're looking for one specific
phenotype and you're looking to lock
down all the traits of that specific
phenotype you're really hard pressed to
beat beat the cubing meod yeah of course
so uh just touching back on the girls SC
cookies uh what's your general feelings
about kind of these more fad strains you
know your gorilla glues Your Girl Scout
cookies and you know back in the day the
blue dreams you know do you think these
these strains have a place in the
breeding world or would you just never
consider working with them um um I
really wouldn't work with them
um yeah exactly it kind of it is what it
is um if you did want to put it into a
seed form I mean you could go along the
uh yeah that's nice huh um you could uh
you could go along and say yeah man you
know we'll cube out the Girl Scout
cookie clone and uh we'll make it into a
seed form now it could be done but I'm
not trying to work on something that I
don't even really like you know the
thing about Girl Scouts it looks like
super crazy resonance and it looks like
it would hurt you man but it don't like
I barely catch a buzz on the stuff it
tastes real good but hell man I know a
bunch of [ __ ] that tastes good I mean I
go eat some girl scoutt cookies if I
want to taste the [ __ ] you know but you
know that's I guess it's subjective some
people like it I'm just I don't know
I've had better yeah
yeah so uh getting back on to more your
kind of strains we've uh had some talk
about the uh the Durban Tha Cindy 99
possibly being re-released is there
anything you might be a to share with us
about
that yeah we're actually working on it
right now that uh that Durban that you
actually saw so since the T SE club
they're the ones that made the the
Durban to high flyer um we don't we
don't have it anymore sadly um super
kill Str one of the best things I ever
smoked in my wife I mean
just ridiculously potent I mean make you
scared you know you really get freaked
out high so um basically what we got to
do um we had the best outstanding Durban
I've ever ever had ever seen I've never
seen anything come close to this one and
I have a really nice tie and now we have
our Cindy mail so basically what we got
to do we got to make it make it from
scratch man so we are we are currently
working on it the the first F1 outcross
basically step one of it's actually
getting ready to go down in like like 10
days 14 days so it'll be something
you'll see it by next year because we'll
have to make two different sides of it
and we'll probably actually use uh one
filial cross to find what we're really
looking for and then we'll take that
back probably to the tie or depending on
how The Offspring turn out what we're
looking to lock down but yeah DTC 99
will definitely be back out there CU
that shit's killer
man can we uh expect to see any others
from the for menu released or do you
think that might be the last of the
first
edition well we're looking at the um
we're looking at the
um the Green Giant um the Grim
Widow and the D T
c99 um those would be the first things
that we really get to get to working on
um other things that probably see like
something like the sugar blossoms again
you know the White Widow hybrid um what
I'm really looking to do is um so it's
kind of weird the uh the Kim dog D the
smell the structure and a lot of things
about that remind me a lot of the
princess um and the genius actually
reminds me a bit of the 91 in certain
ways but kind of like on opposite ends
of the spectrum um where the Kim dog is
very much just crushes you man for the
genius is so like uplifting so I'm
actually looking to experiment a lot
with the combinations of those two two
different Gene pools and nobody else has
really really messed around with it yet
so that' be pretty pretty cool man
awesome so uh keeping with the kind of
topic of breeding what would be kind of
your number one adice viice for a a
freshly starting out breeder in terms of
what what are they best uh in terms of
what what's their energy best spent
doing should you be trying to grow out
the largest numbers of one strain you
can and trying to get you know your
selection right or maybe a few different
strains and trying to find some unique
things to cross together what would be
your
advice I would
say don't start breeding stuff unless
you're super super super passionate
about the weed like if it's just like H
you know the weed's pretty good you know
I enjoy it you want something that's
really got your attention like wow this
the best weed have ever had in my life
it works for me better than anything
I've ever had this is what I want man
this is all I want you know when you
have that type of feel to like that's
what you what you really want um that's
where it all kind of starts and then you
might might say well I really like it
but you know the structure on it is just
God awful man you know so that might be
your starting point is like hey I really
love this stuff but I want to improve
something or it might have everything
you're looking for all inone and you
just might want to stabilize that um I
would
say if if you know what you're looking
for trait wise and stuff you wouldn't
necess necessarily have to grow out huge
populations but the more you grow the
more opportunities you're going to
see to find things that that that would
go along with this breeding program
better so where you might nail down like
two out of the five traits you're
looking to nail um if you grew out
say 50 of these plants instead you might
find that mail that you could lock down
all these traits with this one male you
know or a good portion of them so so the
more is definitely the better you don't
necessarily have to but it's probably
going to take you longer to to get to
get where you're wanting to go with it
um but I would say definitely have a
vision in mind
um and it's good to have a good diverse
pallet as they would say you know like
uh if you wanted a good Chef I mean if
the son of a [ __ ] has only cooked
barbecue his whole life and ate barbecue
his whole life you know you put him in a
restaurant restaurant with like 50
things on the
menu it probably ain't going to be too
good so it's pretty good to get around
try different things grow different
things and you can start to see things
so like even in a poly hybrid like Girl
Scout cookies right you grow that out
man I don't see Girl Scout cookies man I
smell Durban I taste Durban I'm starting
to taste uh little bits of Lebanese hash
plant you know I can start to pick apart
all these different ingredients into
this stuff because I've grown them all
you know I've grown Northern Lights I've
grown the skunk I've grown the Colombian
and the Northern Lights Haze and pure
Haze and you know anything you can think
of and done grown it already and grown
it in pretty good numbers to say yeah
that's that feno that's that feno this
is showing me this and that and I know
this ain't going to breed worth of damn
because it won't breed true for it and
so on and so forth so I would say you
know definitely make sure you know you
you get well versed growing different
things have a good goal in mind of what
you want to do and make sure that it's
something that you're really really
loving you know like you're passionate
about it so I would say that's the best
advice I could give them and pay
attention to detail like even the
smallest things like uh the the
serration on a leaf um and the the
petales and the colors of of the of the
stem and the flowers and the floral
clusters and
um the length between nodes and how they
get tighter and like the ratio of how
they get tighter and every little
tiniest traits that you can think of
even the lines and the leaves you know
all these things they're all bound to
something it could be something
insignificant or it could be something
big like these serrations might be
potency that's tied to it could be yield
it could be smell hell it could be fiber
production and stock you never know or
it could be something insignificant like
what the the arrangement of these lines
on this Leaf is associated with that you
know serration so keep all those in mind
and as you're growing them out you know
see what happens like if you got notes
saying all right they're thin they got
real Jagged saw serration and they're
tall and lanky you might notice those
are your most potent ones and you might
say the other ones aren't as potent so
you know if you're going to find your
male you might be looking for these
female traits in a male plant might be
okay I'd make sure I get the Sal
serration thin Leaf you know lankier
male is probably going to end up giving
me what I want in my later
generation great advice great advice so
uh keeping on that theme of genetics um
how do you think epigenetics plays into
breeding you know I've heard people talk
about this idea of seeds coming from
really good uh breeding environments you
know good plants that were taken care of
well uh you know they perform better you
know how do you feel about that
idea absolutely man um
so I had some buddies that made seeds
I'm not even going to put put them out
there like that but they um man they're
terrible man they're terrible Growers
and everything so they were making seeds
on unhealthy plants man so now if you
take like human beings for instance
right and you got a mom man she smokes
crack she drinks 40s of malt liquor man
she she's fat and nasty and not healthy
at all eats like [ __ ] man that baby's
probably going to be premature it's
going to be all [ __ ] up and nasty and
you know not what you want now you take
like say like uh some chick that's uh
big into yoga and eating right and she
takes prenatal vitamins and all this and
that well when she gives birth to her
baby it's probably going to be pretty
healthy you know now it also plays a
part in like was Daddy a big Olympian
muscle builder and was she like a
athletic type and you know that plays a
part too but the health the overall
health of her during that that time of
carrying this baby uh definitely see it
you know with the with the plants too if
you got a good healthy plant that is of
a good genetic background and you
facilitate seed growth and like um
keeping these plants as healthy as
possible and feeding them cuz seeded
plant they eat a hell of a lot of food
man so you got to feed them a lot um I
try to facilitate seed growth by adding
a boron any source of boron is super
super crucial to to good seed
development um amino acids derived from
organic
soybean um you know a lot of lot of
extra little perks that I give them that
I don't with say like a normal flowering
plant you know that's like Cy crop or
whatever and I do notice that when I
Sprout my seeds I get a better
germination um they tend to blow through
the ground a lot quicker and I tend to
see like a more vigorous plant more
resistant plant against like disease and
Pest and everything and they typically
just overall bigger in health you know
so I definitely believe that yeah you
want to you want to take real good care
of them when they're pregnant man or
else they they'll let you
know yeah for sure so uh We've seem to
have gone through a few generations of
different lighting technology within say
the past 10 years you know we've gone
from HIDs to LEDs and now we've got
these double-ended gavita bulbs have you
guys moved to gavita as your kind of
gold standard as a lot of the industry
has or do you think the technology is
not quite there yet so um you know like
I was talking about earlier it was on
the old parabolic reflector you know and
there was the HPS air cooled hoods so um
like if you seen some of them pictures I
put up last night of them flowers that's
growing in a basement under old ass HPS
hoods man like garbage wouldn't have
thought
so oh I know right but um so like if
you're growing real good and you give
them what they need like you can still
get good quality and you know good real
good yields from them but I'm going to
tell you these double ended
lamps dude it ain't even fair man like I
was hitting like three of light on HPS
technology and like I'm using these
things right now man I hope I don't
blind you out but yeah no that's good we
can see it
well yeah man so those suckers man
man yeah it it just makes it so much
like the plants just get bigger buds
bigger more dense um so I would say yeah
the double-ended technology I would say
is um very good I will say this say man
y'all in Australia don't buy gavita they
they're own by this company called
Monsanto man Monsanto like the evil
empire man like yeah don't support
suckers at all man they're looking to
take over the world and like not in a
good way we got
Nan nanolux man that's the company I've
been using and I really really like
their stuff um I'm not like paid by them
I ain't sponsored by them or nothing so
like I'm just like you you know I got
money I try to make and
um yeah I'm G I'm GNA spend it well so
with the anals I don't see any failures
with it um there's another brand out
there called papalon ealon and the
Phantom de and I noticed here in this
Warehouse like when we had like
blackouts or brown outs where the
lighting kind of flickers man their
ballast would just fail you know now
with these nanoes man they don't skip a
beat they don't break they're just great
the Design's very streamlined so you can
mount them better the price on them
they're cheaper than gavita or any of
the others and um they have a lot of
really cool technology and features
using like wireless controllers where
they give you like a sunrise function
where it might start off at 400 watts
you know and then after 30 minutes it
goes to 500 and it slowly creeps up over
long you want to set it you can
replicate a sunrise and a sunset um it
has temperature sensing technology to
where it says Okay um you know I know
that this guy wants my temperature to be
you know no hotter than 85 degrees at
this canopy so when it hits 86 or 87 the
light says oh hey man I'm getting it too
hot for this guy so it goes from 1,000
watts and it might go down to 950 Watts
or 921 Watts whatever it needs to do to
satisfy that temperature set point you
know so they're really smart and really
nice and hell man like I can even look
at this [ __ ] on my phone pretty sweet
man yeah yeah sorry for interrupting
before I was just going to say yeah
people in Australia are very aware of
Monsanto and are definitely not fans of
them so thankfully we're up to date on
that good good so the next kind of bunch
of questions are kind of not so breeding
related more kind of uh the scene
related and this is kind of an issue
which is fairly big in Australia because
we're just in the very early stages of
setting up our kind of medical model so
my kind of first question would be how
well do you think the American medical
cannabis model is working for the
patients you know do you think it's it's
been a net positive or I hear claims
about people saying things are going
backwards you know what's your ideas on
all of
this well here uh here recently man I
don't even if I should say it or not but
like I just I just went legit like a
month ago so I never took the medical
thing very lightly there were a lot of
people that were like well you can grow
just go up the street and get this
medical card and to me that was kind of
a lie like I'm not going to pretend to
grow for a sick person like they're not
really sick I mean they got a achy back
the same way as I got a achy back you
know what I mean like we're all sick and
that regard right yeah but they so there
was that that whole thing now there are
sick people who are genuinely really ill
that can use this stuff and those were
the people that I wanted to take care of
so I never in my life had really run
into these really really chronically ill
people um mainly because like I don't I
don't really get out much you know I'm
constantly growing and the way it was in
the old days you don't talk to people
you know you kept it quiet so I came in
contact with some people here and like
they were real sick kids some sick
adults that had uh multiple sclerosis
cancer Crohn all these horrible horrible
things so I just started giving them
weed like yeah man here you go so now
they're like oh man it's so great so
they're like why don't you be our
caregiver and I said you know what I
would love to be your caregiver man that
would be awesome if I could you know
help you out then that makes my day and
then I'm actually doing my job so the
way it went here was there was no like
real legal recreational thing so
everybody was like oh medical medical
medical so these real actual sick people
you know they were you know kind of had
people giving them weed or selling them
weed or they had a dispensary so now in
the states where it went
recreational man and a lot of these
people they got thrown to the Wayside
nobody wants to mess with them no more
because they went and they got that Rec
license and now they're just you know
kind of [ __ ] out of
luck yeah so no one's no one cares about
the medical patients anymore yeah man
sadly enough um there are places where
they still do um and it's kind of Hit
and Miss on an individual basis too so
you know it it's set up pretty good
um I don't know it's just it it really
just comes down to the individual I
guess um if you're good people you know
good things you know you can do good
things for other good people but just
know like if y'all get medical going
there's going to be a lot of rat
bastards out there but they're already
there anyway so just uh guess the best
thing say is just do the right thing do
what's in your heart and try to take
care of sick people because there are a
lot of sick people who do need it and if
you can do a good job you know grow some
good clean organic good quality medicine
for them man that's that's a good thing
you know good thing to do good karma on
you yeah thankfully there are some
people in Australia who kind of uh still
look after six sick people or regardless
of the legal status but uh I guess in
that kind of same idea um for for a
country like Australia that is just you
know about to say kind of legalize
things in the foreseeable future what do
you think is maybe some of the traps or
pitfalls you know some of the ideas that
were presented as a good idea at first
which now in retrospect you realize were
not good things for the
states right so that that's like a big
crucial thing so like a lot of people
they say oh wow you're going to legalize
weed that's great I'm going to vote Yes
for it but really look at what that law
says because like right now in
California they're trying to legalize it
there but legalization with the
California market with the bill that
they're you know trying to push through
basically makes it worse really than it
ever did you know before it was legal so
like now it's like if that were to pass
and you get caught with an ounce of weed
hey you're a felon now man like they're
going to send your ass to prison um so
basically it's set up for like big
corporations to control everything so
like they'll make it to where you're not
allowed to grow your own for yourself
you're not allowed to grow anything for
a sick person they got to go to their
local Monsanto growery and buy their
cheap dog [ __ ] Eagle 20 ridden spider
might infested crap you know so whatever
they do put in front of you just make
sure you y'all read it real good man
because they you know governments are
sneaky I don't know about Australia but
I know in America you got to watch them
suckers man they they'll [ __ ] you any
chance they get man yeah well one of the
uh the major arguments or kind of ideas
put forward is that uh legalization will
be somewhat similar to Tobacco in
Australia in that there would be a few
large companies running it all and very
likely the potential of people not being
able to grow their own medicine how do
you feel about that idea do you think
it's kind of intrinsically important for
people to be able to grow their own
medicines or do you think uh you a big
Monsanto type company is adequately able
to provide for
people yeah so when I worked in Virginia
doing like engineering and
instrumentation and all that good stuff
I used to work for a company y'all got
marbor cigarettes over there don't you I
think you can get them here so I used to
work for those people they're uh called
Philip Morris but um so with the tobacco
industry or any industry for that
matter they're high
volume low quality I highly doubt you
would get anything beneficial from them
um here in the old days we used to have
basically we call it a swag Market you
know it was illegal weed grown in Mexico
mostly coming a brick real cheap
pesticide ridden not very good um to me
those type of places will fill that swag
void if they do produce anything at all
but what you can do for
yourself at your own home is far
superior than anything that you'll be
able to buy in a store so even in this
market like I'm in Colorado right now if
I go to the store looking for weed man
I'm pissed dude like it it's awful
looking man so like what I can just do
in my basement will kill anything you'll
find in a store around here so they're
not going to put the same amount of love
into it as you are and you're not going
to know like what did they spray that
[ __ ] with and did they pull it too early
did they pull it too late do they even
grow what the hell you need you know
like for your for your ailments you know
so if you got Crohn's or whatever and
all they got is Girl Scout cookies you
[ __ ] out of luck man you know you need
something you know more specific for
what you're looking to do so I would say
being able to grow grow your own is huge
you know and my thought has always been
until they consider cannabis the same as
a tomato plant no regulations it's a
plant as any other plant until that
happens I'm not happy I'm still like
[ __ ] them you know I don't like being
regulated at all so [ __ ] these [ __ ]
man they you know plant some PL and
especially it's medically good for
people shame on them for even trying to
regulate it you know yeah so uh
obviously you're an organic fanatic like
myself uh what's your opinion on
Organics versus synthetics in terms of
you know do you think synthetics just
reduce the flavor and the Turin or do
you think it actually reduces the
medicinal value compared to
Organics well that's a good question man
so I've seen a lot of hydro weed some
people can do it good and do it right
and I grew Hydroponics myself even you
know way back in the day when it was a
cash crop thing um you can grow a good
product
hydroponically but I can grow a better
product organically I guess you could
say um it still would have a medicinal
benefit but you would get more medicinal
benefits you know of course from a
better product and that being organic um
I found that growing organically it was
less maintenance it's actually less work
the plants actually grow better and
bigger um that used to be the argument
of a hydro guys that well you know you
might have a better taste or smell or
whatever but hey I yield more well not
not the way I grow organic you don't you
know you might meet it maybe you know
but I'll take the pupsy challenge on
that [ __ ] too so um you know honestly
it's cheaper it's easier um you know
it's better for you that's for sure you
don't have to worry about flushing
[ __ ] plants for 14 days to get [ __ ]
out like you know I'm not going to put
nothing in it that you know I don't want
so I don't know it's just kind of nasty
weed I have one buddy that grows hydro
and he's probably like h the only person
I know of that actually does a good job
that I would actually smoke but if he
were to grow in Organics [ __ ] man it'd
be that much better you know yeah he
only does it out of necessity though
like it's the only way he can grow in
his current current
situation yeah yeah so uh I'm not sure
if the idea is as pre prevalent in
America as it is in Australia but
currently there's this big Trend to kind
of push CBD as the uh the medical
component of weed and to push THC as the
recreational component how do you how do
you feel about this and do you think
it's a bit of a
misrepresentation yeah absolutely um so
like if you look at the research the so
CBD you know prevents like the
metastasizing of cancer cells whereas
THC actually kills the cancer cells so I
actually see them both like you don't
want just one you know one or the other
you would actually you want both um and
then there's like the medicinal benefit
of like Tarpin you know whether it comes
off of a CBD plant or a THC plant like
marine and all that good stuff like they
all have their own their own medicinal
benefit so you know having one without
the other as far as the medicine goes
they're kind of pissing in the wind so
you know you you definitely got to have
both um you know and that not just for
cancer but for anything anything really
pain um nerve nerve damage stuff um
gastrointestinal stuff um depression you
know there's so many different benefits
for the stuff you know so and it's not
as simple as just THC gets you high and
CBD heals you you know yeah even in
recreational Le you want to know call it
that the different canabo profiles
change the different kind of high the
perceived high can be greater
from a plant that has lower overall THC
than another but its profile more CBG
and CBN is we don't know what that code
is yet but there is definitely an
interplay the different cannaboids that
add up to something that's uh greater
than the sum of basically and we don't
understand how it all works yet but it's
certainly not as simple as just pure
thhc just ex that leave everything
behind that's not going to be the
solution neither is getting just pierc y
cuz like you can smoke say like a Thai
plant right 12% THC right I can go get a
Afghan plant 12% THC I smoke that tie
and I'm like oh geez that's strong man
I'm GNA got to go hide um then I could
smoke that 12% s indica and just be like
nodding out so what's the difference THC
is THC it's the whole profile it's the
THC in combination the other canono the
propyl canono you know your thcv and all
that good stuff um in combination with
you know the tpin that's what makes a
tie a tie and a gany aany you know and
an indica and a sativa differences you
know and the different um
medicinal benefits of that like you take
somebody with like ADHD bouncing off the
walls man I could give them a nice
strong sativa and probably chill their
ass out you know whereas I give it to
this other dude or myself and I'm like
oh Jesus man that's too much
man yeah so touching on that Synergy
that kind of uh you and Mr Soul just
mentioned we often hear people talk
about how they will say you know kind of
like your example with that tie or a
haze for example you know these strains
would never test as high as what strains
do today however people would often
claim there's no seiling to them um how
do you think that gets lost you know do
you think that's just a overtime over
hybridizing strains you lose that or you
gain a ceiling in the high because a lot
of people will claim that you know new
strains have a a ceiling you know
whereas some of the older ones don't and
that was why they were so
memorable there is there is that like
there's certain ones that yeah the land
race um there is something pure in those
chemo types that really doesn't have
that ceiling and if you look at a lot of
the old hybrids like say like the derent
Tha high flyer that had no ceiling and
you could get so high you turn white
faced and sweaty and puke um yeah they
they were they were based off of land
races you know deran Pinetown deran
sativa and pure Thai um they didn't
water it down they had two land races
and they stabilized them well they paid
attention to to their breeding program
and they didn't accept mediocrity man
they they made sure it was strong as
[ __ ] every time they did it and yeah so
you can lose
some do doing some bad breeding
practices um the other
thing the the testing so like you guys
over there y'all see uh Girl Scout
cookies or whatever tests 35% THC 40%
THC I'm G tell you that's
[ __ ] the guy that got that tested
probably knows the guy at the lab or the
lab says hey if we keep turning out
these big numbers for these guys they're
going to keep coming to us to get the
testing done right so if the guy at the
corner is giving you a real test on it
and he's like yeah you're like 18% THC
which is a [ __ ] lot by the way um guy
down the street gives you 32 so now in
the market
say like in Oregon for instance that's
probably like the biggest place I see
this problem is that there's guys
they're like going to the dispenser with
weed that says yeah this test at 42%
THC [ __ ] man so now the guy at that
lab is making a killing because
everybody wants to go get tested with
him they get these good numbers now at
the dispensaries the whole Market is
driven by THC percentages so like you
got like un educated public they think
THC is the only thing getting you high
so like we got Apollo 13 at Apollo 13
like on a real actual legit test is like
I think it was like
16% but I'll tell you what man my God
that 16% gets me higher than any
so-called 30% Gorilla Glue that I've
ever had um so you know there there's
quite a bit of [ __ ] part of that
and really I mean on a legit test like
my buddy gets his stuff like
legitimately tested the same Bud that we
could take up and get 35% it's really
only about
22% so you know it's it's a few
different few different factors involved
in that and because something's
resonance doesn't mean that it's very
high in THC like you've seen those
pictures of that 88 G13 hash plant right
yep and you seen how Frosty that is
right covered in snow oh yeah where you
where do you think of test at
THC uh if I had to guess those wild
figures probably 29 or something
30 yeah that's what I used to think
too yeah it's like uh
19% oh
wow yeah I've seen uh pictures of peyote
purple which is a notoriously low th see
percentages but very
frosty yeah man very frosty and it's all
those other things in it like you know
that 88 I don't even like smoking that
[ __ ] man it's too damn strong like I
mean it just I mean it's like a time and
place it's like doing acid or something
man like you there's the right place the
right time around the right people um
and it just makes me eat man like I
can't keep fridge with groceries in it
man I'll be eating pizzas and pudding
man man and chips and dip man it it
ain't no good so it's good for somebody
had stomach problems so you know yeah
yeah so do you think we'll ever get to
the point even with accurate testing and
new technology where we can ever uh
quantitatively put the medical value of
cannabis on a plant or do you think
we're never going to be able to put a
number on it you know there's always
going to be a Synergy and you're just
going to have to try you
know yeah I think uh part of it
part of it I think so like what gets me
just completely blistered man like it
it's just like the best things since
sliced bread for me I could give it to
Mr soul and he would agree like oh yeah
this is very good but something else
works for him so I think a lot of it has
to do with just the uniqueness of like
how our brains are wired and we're all
individuals so I think part of it going
to do with that but I do think that you
know across like a large enough Baseline
I can say like 88 G13 hashplant makes me
starve and hungry everybody I smoke it
with they just want to eat and eat and
eat so certain things like that are you
know they ring true across the board so
as we're starting to kind of like
document these things and you know keep
our records because like in the old days
you couldn't keep records you know um so
now we can uh the lady that was getting
me all hooked up with all these people
that I'm growing for that are real real
sick she's got a person that works with
the University of Colorado and he's very
very interested you know he's master
degree PhD doctor guy right he's very
interested in like recording all this
data that we're coming up with of what
works for what and so it turns out like
I knew all these people were very sick
but it turns out that their illnesses
are kind of like rare illnesses you know
so it's kind of cool to see what's
working for for for these certain things
and then you got more common things like
cancer research and you know neuropathy
you know uh you know you got in a bad
bike accident your nerve endings are all
screwed up and what works for that
versus the next thing and I really do
believe that at the end of the day it's
going to come down to the the tpin the
individual tpin and how they help affect
it because like a lot of people think oh
yeah we're just going to cook you know
we're going to cook this [ __ ] in the
butter yeah we're good
bro yeah yeah I'm gonna take him next
door and show him them [ __ ]
monsters you out of
here yeah yes you thinking
Wendy's all right Bubba I'll see you
yeah I'm sorry about that that's all
good all right Bubba
um so yeah I think it's going to come
down to these tpin and like people say
oh yeah you know I'm going cook some
canabus butter and that's like a cure
all and you know I'm going to give it to
this guy and I'm GNA give it to that guy
well man when you cook
it you got high temperatures man you
going to you going to cook all them
terpins off so by the time we're said
and done we've converted Delta 9 THC to
Delta 11 thc's and we got a whole [ __ ]
ton of CBN now
you know degraded
THC and it's kind of kind of D function
kind of the same whether it's taii or
whether it's an indica or whatever so I
think a lot of it really does boil down
to you know the smells that we're
smelling you know and how these things
help like they just found out like uh
the mercine tpine do you find out a lot
in like your purple strains your indicas
right they work on the same receptors as
opiates do so like I had buddies back
home man they were all hooked on Heroin
and everything right bunch of dope
fiends I could give them good indicas
man get them off that dope one it help
with the stomach so they ain't throwing
up so damn much and two it's acting on
that same receptor as that dope was so
they're not jonesing for the dope so now
they're smoking good indica and then
they able to kick that heroin you know
what I mean so like there's all types of
benefits yeah that's interesting I've
I've heard of people being able to quit
heroin with but then you hear about
other people who say it's not so
effective so maybe it's just a case of
some are getting the right strain for
the
situation
exactly okay so um just kind of on a bit
of a different uh note if someone kind
of asked me to summarize you know the
kind of the current scene I would say
that we're almost having a a bit of a
Renaissance of the past you know if you
look at people like Frenchie canoli
bringing back kind of the old hashish
forms and then furthermore like we could
definitively that there's an organic
Renaissance going on people are really
getting back into it um do you do you
kind of agree with these trends that we
need to go back to the old practices
kind of Back to Basics and look to
master the methodology as opposed to
develop new
technology yeah so so I used to make
hash all back in like 98
99 made it up to like 2003 yeah we used
to call it BHO butane wall AKA hippie
crack so I'd make the [ __ ] out of it man
now I knew damn well that stuff won't be
so good for you man and when I'd smoke
it I mean it gets you gets you good and
good good and big but it won't nowhere
near as good as some good dry SI or
bubble hash that was made
properly um so I think it's it's going
to come down to a good blend because
like there are some pretty cool
technology out there now but if we could
kind of integrate some of those old ways
into a little bit of our new technology
like take like the rosin guys for
instance right they're making the rosin
now hey that's a pretty good little
alternative right there you know you
don't have any solvents there's nothing
to purge out tastes good smells good get
you baked um so I think yeah if people
were to start becoming a little more in
tune with like what what we used to do
back in the day before there was you
know dab rigs and all this [ __ ] you know
you could sit down in your house with
the bubble bags and make all the hash
you wanted and you didn't have to worry
about blowing your house up you know you
didn't have to worry about some cancer
causing damn hydrocarbons up in your
[ __ ] you know and it it tasted great you
know it was awesome that's what you
wanted to do so like me personally man
like I don't I don't smoke no pass oil
man I'm probably in like the dab capital
of the world right now dudes around here
smoking looking like crackheads with
torches and [ __ ] so I don't touch it man
but I will make my own bubble has I will
make my own dry SI I got no problems
with that but I do I only it's kind of
like a rare occasion you know like if
you're into drinking right you know
people drink beers casually you know you
and me after work whatever but hey on
the weekend time to start doing shots of
bourbon or whatever so I kind of think
of it as the same way or if like I'm
really hurting man my back is tweaked or
whatever I can say hey man I'm gonna
load up some bong hits or whatever of uh
you know this draive and really kick my
ass and feel feel like a human
again yeah so it's kind of interesting
you say that because in Australia the
concentrate kind of game is just taking
off and people are really jumping all
over the BHO would your kind of uh
advice be stick to the more solventless
types of concentrates if
possible I would um like I do know some
guys that are very good at making uh
BHO um but they also have a laboratory
and they have a lot of very expensive
equipment yeah man it it ain't like
blowing through like old stainless
turkey basters and some P back on the
back porch right so um I would say you
gotta kind of know where your stuff's
coming from because if you talking to
like Joe around the corner he might not
be purging it too good man and that a
Ain good for your lungs but you might
know a guy you know couple miles down
the road that does do a good job and you
you can enjoy it but I would say try
some
dryv um You probably won't see a lot of
it in your area like it's never been a
big thing even here in America right
like they you don't really go to the
store and say hey there's some
solventless draive because that BHA it's
easier to make but what you can do is is
you can get your grow on grow your own
and then uh you know get you some dry
sing screens and just make your own and
like I mean it's cool little dab rigs
and all that it's too much work for me
but they are cool and if you got one you
like to do it you can do it with the dry
all you got to do man once you got them
heads good and clean and it's nothing
but trike heads you take that you apply
a little heat and some parchment paper
and you pull it off man and it looks
just like shatter and you you can dab it
and it it tastes better and it'll get
you way way way more [ __ ] up man uh
you don't lose any tpin doing dry you
know you don't lose a thing and it's
pure it's clean and it's good for you
too man yeah awesome yeah and you're
right unfortunately I've uh never been
able to try any dry C but uh it's on my
bucket
list um so people often talk about this
idea of returning to land race routes
you know do you think this is the case
and it will get done it seems like it's
been this idea that's been floating
around forever but no one ever really
seems to do it or at least it never
seems to take hold within the community
you know do you think we'll just
continue hybridizing
endlessly well you got so you look at
the mass public you know guys that are
trying to make seeds and this and that
but the thing with them is most of those
guys are chasing a buck they ain't
chasing a passion so there are some guys
over here they're very passionate um
couple friends of mine in California
that's all they do they don't even sell
the seeds they could they could sell
them and probably make a fortune but
their main thing is Preservation you
know everything from old Colombians and
Mexican oh Hawkins taii and Cambodian
anything everything you can think of and
they want to make sure that it remains
pure and it remains safe in a good seed
form and maybe eventually they will sell
but they're more into like you know
giving them to a guy like me and say hey
you want to use it in a hybrid or
whatever and I'm like oh yeah you you
damn right man so I can say that when
you
do like all these guys with the poly
hybrids and stuff I could take something
from them introduce a land race to it
and make it pretty damn potent there is
something to be said for reintroducing a
land race back into a hybrid
that really does does does the trick
like that gria that's a Afghan land race
right there that's been reintroduced to
what you know was a worked hash plant
which is like three different really
really nice
Afghan um from different regions of
Afghanistan that they bred together in a
breeding program at ciny to make the old
hash plant so I'm just reintroducing
land race Vigor back into it and you
know you could can you can definitely do
some damage man yeah great and so do you
think we'll ever see you know the the
new skunk number one type thing or you
know the new Northern Lights 5 or do you
think we're maybe a bit past those
days oh no man I know this dude he's uh
he's working pretty hard Around the
Clock uh working on those um I would say
what month is it man it's uh July July
yeah so I'd say around Christmas time be
looking for uh looking for a roadkill
scun that'll be coming from us we're
growing them out right now like earlier
when I was in that bright ass room
before I got to rambling on bitching
about Girl Scout cookies or whatever I
was in a whole whole room full of uh uh
different stuff uh we had the roadkill
skunk up there we had the Rosetta Stone
some a13 etc etc but yeah like that's
another one of my big ones uh that was
something pretty near and dear to me
like when I was growing up and my
cousins had made it and everything and
it's something that I don't know why it
really isn't around or nobody was on to
the same [ __ ] we were on to back then
but we're going to bring that back and
that's something definitely people hey
do y'all got skunks over there in
Australia um no no like the
animals yeah yeah we don't we don't have
them man they stink so godamn bad man
they will spray and if you hit one on
the road your car will wre I mean really
re heard the St in the region of
Virginia I'm from they're all over the
place man so we could get away with
growing big big big huge grows of it in
the woods because people drive by and go
oh God what do that smell like yeah a
skunk spraying around here I guess man
don't realize in the back 40 we got like
200 300 of them girls growing you know
the perfect cover
story oh yeah it was good that's awesome
yeah so I'm going to have to do it bring
up the dreaded topic for all breeders
feminized
seeds how what's your thoughts on
feminized seeds I could probably guess
but I think that um there is a bit of an
argument to be made that you know a lot
of really good clones have come from
hermaphrodites from feminized seeds you
know so so what's your thoughts do they
have a place or not in your
library well they do um and like
anything like there's uh like we were
talking about filial Crossing or back
Crossing so there's certain tools that
you can use for certain jobs so with
femin see there's a right way to do it
and then there's the wrong way to do it
so the wrong way is like the typical way
of just like hey man
we'll get some collidal silver man we'll
reverse this sucker and make a bunch of
seeds and we'll just throw them out
there um there is a a a right way of
going about it too um which would
basically be like during your first
first uh it's not really an outcross but
during your first selfing where you've
hm this plant onto itself or another
plant um our trick was you know you you
grow out a bunch of them you put them in
a room
and about day 28 a flower you start
doing a disco light effect up in there
where your lights on lights off lights
on lights off and you try to you know
you'll weed them out you'll find the
ones like they'll show pretty quick now
out of like you know hund and something
of these females in there you might find
one that will not Herm out on you not
easily that would be one that you would
probably want to back cross back to the
mother or do it do it like that now when
you're when you're feminized and you're
you're cheating yourself out of a
chromosome um it could be one that's not
not so much affecting what we're looking
for you know it could be a a structural
thing or a color thing or what have you
um a lot of the times guys do it it's
cheating out the potency a lot of it so
I think like you can do it good but you
need to have a lot of numbers and you
need to run these stress tests or else
you're going to be passing that
hermaphroditic trade on and and you're
actually you're going to be cheating
yourself out of a a good chromosome like
potency or something like that so like
you can do it but to me like if you do
it right it's more work and like I'm not
trying to do any more work than I need
to so um you know and there is like you
know I was talking to some guys they're
from Europe and dudes in Spain and down
in South America and like they're not
set up like like an America man like our
service like on a house like electrical
service you got like 200 amps like you
know it's pretty pretty good man you can
you can grow out a lot of weed but say
in Holland man you you're you're getting
ready to like blow your breaker panel by
having one light you know so um it's
very important for these guys to know
for a fact hey I got females man I don't
have much space and like it's worth it
and like I can sympathize with that a
little bit so I could see where a guy
wants to do that um agricultural guys
let's say like we're so legal that we
can grow out fields and Fields and
Fields of weed 100 acres worth of pot um
it would be beneficial that if I could
grow from seed each time and throw out
all these seeds and know for a fact I
don't have any males to call there will
not be any gaps in my rows I'm going to
be good to go that's pretty cool too so
and like you were saying a lot of the
the really good ones came from accidents
man really good accidents
you know but accidents nonetheless from
a hermaphrodite so you know there is
some some things to be said like that
Kim dog man every time like if that
thing gets pissed off and throws out
some pollen everything it hits makes a
legend man but that's just part of the
way it breeds man it it breeds that
chemotype along with that that
hermaphroditic pollen so when it hits
something it's God awful potent just
like the mom was you know so there's
certain ones that will do that but not
all of them do that so just you know
that's the only part to keep in mind I
guess yeah so what's your thoughts on um
people using other breeders genetics you
know do you kind of frown on people
making f2s and then using them for their
own projects or do you think as long as
they kind of ask permission it's all
right yeah the permission thing is is
probably like my my one thing and the
way like we do stuff we actually
encourage enage people to to use our
stuff to to help their breeding program
along our only thing is like just you
know give us a little a little shout out
you know don't be like oh well Sun 99 or
Durban T c99 I'm going to call it
cantaloup pay now or something like that
and I'm G like yeah we just bred that we
made it you know now if they were to be
like oh yeah it's Brothers Grim blah
blah blah we use this in our program
that's that's pretty cool and you know I
like that and like we kind of saw
ourselves as like the Breeders breeder
you know we'll make [ __ ] that you would
want to breed with you know something
that would help you out so Cinderella
99's a good example of that um as far as
like people that make like f2s and
they're like oh yeah I got these grimo
f2s $20 a pack you know what I mean now
that that pissed me off a little bit I'd
be looking to kick that dude's ass yeah
but
um you know um it's
it's I guess like I just see a lot of
like very unui people out there that do
this stuff and I just I guess I would
say like I wish they would like do some
of their own work and not really just
ride off others people's work because
you know it it is a lot of work if you
if you are going the original route
whether you're snatching up land races
from you know different parts of the
world or you know putting a lot of work
into something um it does take work but
that you know some people they they take
that shortcut but when I see a seed
company that say their whole menu is you
know TGA subcool's agent orange cross to
um JJ's starg and then they just throw a
name on it and their whole
menu oh man all over the place man and
like every time I just see it I'm shake
my head man like shame on you you
unoriginal bastards so you know that
part kind of bothers me and they don't
really put in the work either they're
just kind of like sprouted a 10 pack got
two males that one looks good and that
one looks good [ __ ] it make some seeds
make some money you know and then they
just end up polluting the Jean Pool
worse than it already is you know they
didn't improve nothing they didn't
really make nothing new and they just
kind of screwed around now I do have
friends that have like you know they're
like uh what do you call like a closet
you know closet breeders right but the
difference between them and these guys
well they ain't selling them they just
goofing around having fun in the
basement and just growing [ __ ] out for
fun you know that's a different thing
but when you're putting it in a pack and
you're putting a label on it and you
charging people for money and you're
showing you know some picture or
something in a description that ain't
nowhere near like what it is man that's
fugazi bro like that that ain't cool
yeah so kind of on that same topic of
ownership I've been hearing a lot of
talk about uh patenting of strain names
patenting of strains recently you know
are you able to maybe shed some truth on
it there seems to be a lot of rumors um
but from what I've heard it seems like
the end of the Cannabis Community from
what some people are talking it seems a
bit
ridiculous yeah it is man yeah there's
one thing you know about Stoners man
they they paranoid and they like to uh
like to have their little conspiracies
and things so uh a while back uh talked
to a guy that was doing like a Genome
Project and I was giving them all these
samples of all these different things
out of the collection and like okay well
you know tell me something I don't know
like you know I'm going to give you say
this uh triangle cush right here and I'm
going to give you this OG Cush and then
I'm going to give you this Kim dog and I
want you to tell me like are they
related or where do they come from and
I'm going to give you these land race
afghanis do do any of them show hot from
coming from this region and stuff like
that and you know it's pretty pretty
cool stuff and I was like so you know
when you map this this this plant can
you give me a piece of paper saying you
know this is what it
is this is a very unique genotype here
you can't replicate this um you know
when the patent office opens up can I
patent this the answer is no unless you
genetically modify something you can't
patent it so that's how like Monsanto
does what they do they genetically
modify potatoes soybeans and [ __ ] so now
they're able to patent those things
right but they can't patent the
soybean and we can't do it the the same
way with cannabis you know so like my
question was like well what if I get
land races from all parts of the world
can I patent these so that way when
Monsanto does come around hey I done
beat these [ __ ] to the punch and
maybe I'll sue them and we'll we'll have
a big ass bonfire in their office
buildings or something you know so they
were like no it doesn't work that way so
unless you genetically modifi it to make
it unique you can't patent it so that uh
now the the names so the name game yeah
you can you well I don't know about
abroad or nothing but in America you you
can Pat a name you know like a brand
name like Coca-Cola or I heard the the
chem dog name had been patented or
something along those
lines yeah man yeah he ended up doing it
uh us and some buddies man we were
talking like you know a lot of people
use your name and make a lot of money on
you and you're sitting at the house
broke which by the way like if y'all
think like dogs like some big high
roller you know making all this money
you see his weed everywhere nobody gives
him [ __ ] like you know me JJ a few of
the crew you know the Kim family crew
you know we always help out right but a
lot of these guys they're claiming to
breed with Kim dog 99% of them it ain't
it ain't even real Kim dog they're just
using a
name also they they you know even if
they do they don't they don't kick
anything back to the guy so we're like
well you know these guys make all this
money using your
name let's put an end to that you know
because maybe one day soon the time is
going to come to where these patents do
make a make a difference and what
happens if some jack off patents your
name yeah and now we're getting sued for
growing [ __ ] that you know we help you
know get to this point US own name so
yeah man and people hey man I'll tell
you a funny story this dude was on
Instagram man we just chewing his ass he
ended up he he trademarked or patented
uh Kim Fam you believe that [ __ ] what
yeah yeah man and then we were telling
him like bro you can't do that [ __ ] and
he was like oh yeah yeah I can I got the
patent I'm like man you fixing to get
your ass whooped son so everybody's just
like yeah we see you man we're going to
take care of this so anyways uh the guy
gets scared and he's like hey don't want
no problem
I paid like 300 bucks to have this done
give me 300 bucks and it's yours so we
got the money up and made sure that our
our mans got that too but I mean people
are people are crazy man
especially Americans man a bunch of
crooked shyy bastards man that's why I
want to I want to come live over there
with y'all
man yeah I mean you'd have to say
goodbye to all that beautiful clones
N I know how to get them over there that
a that ain't no
problem then you're all set oh yeah yeah
no so um need buy me an Australian
Australian wife or something man she get
me a green card or whatever oh you
wouldn't need a buy don't worry I think
she'd love your accent
sweet game find me one of them Surfers
man them Surfer chicks bro yeah so um I
was about to say if you're willing to
you know would you be willing to talk a
little more about chem dog you know like
he's kind of a really illustrious figure
in the industry you know um as you
pointed out you know a lot of people
probably do assume he gets you know some
kind of kickbacks from people using his
stuff or just you know somehow
intimately tied to some kind of
financial gain from the seeds you think
he's just more of you know a mellow guy
like I know he used to breed is he kind
of stopped doing that yeah so um when I
got out of prison so I went in February
2007 then get out like around uh
November
2009 so like I'm playing it cool you
know like I'm like all right I'm getting
out man DEA they probably still watching
me they don't think they got what they
wanted they think I'm High rolling in
some money which I want but whatever
they want to think so I'm like I'm not
going to contact nobody because if I do
contact somebody and they are watching
I'm going to lead them right to my
friends and my family and I ain't going
to have that I just got through pulling
all that time for not running my mouth
so you know I'm just going to chill yeah
so I get done with my probation and I I
traveled to uh Arizona that's like
middle like the desert out in uh in
America it's like middle South middle
part of the country you know so I get
out there with a old friend from Florida
he was the East Coast guy with me and um
we just got to talk and I'm like yeah
[ __ ] you know how's old G doing you
keeping com
with him and he was like yeah you know
talk to him a little bit I'm like yeah
man we we ought to get a hold of him you
know just you know catch up so we go and
um I mean it's like the next day and we
see the damn news strip popping up he
got
bosted dude snitched on him oh so now I
don't have it on paper and like there's
really not like a whole lot of proof but
you know who res dog is Reservoir seeds
I was kind of avoiding bringing his name
up relation to Kim yeah I know right
[ __ ] do the old [ __ ] yeah [ __ ]
act like a vampire man so that joker he
gets popped and starts running his mouth
man Gypsy Nirvana a bunch of dudes go
down right around the same time he knew
where G lived um you know had had had
hung out with him before anyway now G's
popped you know he he's going away so
we're like [ __ ] me you know so don't uh
don't hear from him you know and like
I'm in Arizona I end up going back to
Virginia and doing my thing there and
I'm just you know staying quiet and then
um so basically you know I hung around
Virginia for my for my parents you know
they were really old when they had me
and uh they weren't doing too good so
anyway when my father passed away I said
you know what I don't like living here
no more I'm tired of get hunted down
like an animal I'm getting the [ __ ] out
of here I'm driving straight to Oregon
so I drove all the way to Oregon man
second I touch down call up subcool I'm
like hey what's up man made it all the
way out here got all my old clones got
the whole [ __ ] Let's do let's do
something cool man so he's like hey man
you want to get a job working with the
Cannabis people you need to start an
Instagram and I'm like an insta what
like I'm not a big technological dude
you know like you can probably tell so
I'm like all right [ __ ] it I'll start up
an Instagram and sure enough old G hits
me up Kim dog glass and I said oh [ __ ]
awesome man I didn't know if he was in
The Joint out of the joint or whatever
so get to talk and he was like yeah you
know everything's all right but they
took my house man they find me like
$700,000 man and ain't got no money so I
started taking up glass blowing again
and back in like 0
056 he tried to give me all of his glass
blowing equipment and I told him no I
said you might end up needing it again
one day and thank God he doesn't because
now he's [ __ ] blowing glass with it
that PR so he's yeah so he's still back
in Massachusetts just blowing glass man
and by the way if y'all want some real
cool old school heavy glass man hit him
up it's uh Kim dog and it's spelled dog
by the way that d o d
AWG that ain't the way to spell it so
it's c h m d
oore
glass and uh yeah he make he makes some
real real nice stuff man yeah everyone
needs to go and pay their respects and
buy some glass from Kem
dog yeah he'll he'll hook it up man and
he he puts a lot of little Millies in it
you know so like y'all y'all got y'all
seen South Park over there right yep the
cartoon
yeah yeah like he's got a bunch of [ __ ]
from that man like he made me a little
bow it's got a tow on it and stuff and
Homer Simpson and you know we were all
big dead heads too so you know a lot of
lot of Grateful Dead stuff on there too
yeah I was about to say I've just uh
organized to get my uh my chem family
shirt through hes and hair heirlooms the
other day so I'm excited to get
it hell yeah dude yeah they're good
they're good shirts too man I got my
peab buug shirt on today oh nice all out
and [ __ ] yeah but uh yeah man yeah
they're they're they're all good people
and we weren't like we're not like
everybody always saw like oh yeah y'all
like some rich [ __ ] like some
real high rollers man at the end of the
day we just a bunch of like broke ass
dirty ass dead heads man they just like
we just love growing weed man this just
like a passion so we're not any famous
star high roller whatever you know we're
just a bunch of farmers that like
growing weed and believe in what we're
doing you know we like to help people
and you know yeah spread the love if you
will there ain't enough love in this
world too much hate yeah I can totally
agree on that one so does Kem kind of
keep out of the Limelight due to his uh
kind of notoriety nowadays and he just
sticks to the glassw work is that kind
of why he stopped breeding because I
know that he made things like you know
the geel and stuff like that yeah he had
the the jel he had the Dog Days um there
was the snow dog um was back in the good
old days man like where we were just
having fun man and um you know the the
the the laws and the the cops man they
they put a they put a quick end to that
and like myself um if they were to come
through the door right now well actually
now I'm all protected so I tell them to
[ __ ] my dick but but like last month if
they were to come through the door I was
looking at like 15 to 20 years man and
same same goes for him I think they got
medical where he's at but you know he's
trying to keep it down low and yeah you
know just kind of mellow out and maybe
you know when some more laws change or
whatever you'll see him see him out and
about a bit more but you know he's a
family man know he's got his kids and
he's got his old lady that tries to keep
him out of trouble and you know that
whole deal so yeah man but real good
dude um like I say he's real real into
his glass blowing too he used to blow
glass on dead tour and sell them out in
the out in the parking lot oh really so
yeah yeah man yeah he's been doing this
[ __ ] long time man that's really cool um
and so I guess my ultimate question
would be have you ever spoken to him
about uh what he plans on doing with
those remaining seeds
oh man the the the DEA took them really
yeah I've never read
that yeah they're in an Evidence room
somewhere man um yeah yeah they they
took them bastards but um I think this
is groundbreaking I don't think this no
one knows about this oh yeah man yeah
that when they come and got him they got
his seed collection as clones and all
but we um collectively you know we've
kept all of our own seed breeding old
seeds clones and we got it all we got it
stored away and he he's uh he's well set
and then um plus you know the the the
mother plant that produced these Kim dog
seeds
um
yeah so all good yeah you could say that
so we um you know [ __ ] them you know
they whatever take man we'll build it
bigger and better than we had it before
you know so they ain't they ain't going
to stop [ __ ] yeah that's a huge thing I
say to anyone as soon as they find
something unique you need to delocalize
it because it's just too risky to hoard
things and you know I I always use the
example of uh the alien technology
strain as much as it might have been a
bit of a fad you know it doesn't exist
anymore because the guy who found it
didn't give any cuts out and then he
lost it
himself yeah man I know that guy too man
I remember when he sprouted SE yeah yeah
that's him um yeah I remember like
they're just land race afghanis man
that's all it that's all it was and he
found a good boy I remember he showed me
pictures of it when I was real little
man had the Cod leadens and like one set
of leaves gr out and had [ __ ] frost
on it like a bud I was like oh [ __ ] and
then that's the one he used called it
the alien Tech and you know it does good
that's why I was saying there's a lot to
be said about you know you introduce
land race to a hybrid right and you can
you can do some pretty cool stuff man
yeah for sure so kind of the last of the
more extended questions uh what do you
think is the best way for a kind of a
community to grow if it's in its infancy
so in in reference to say Australia we
don't really have clones that get passed
around I'm sure there are people with
high quality clones but we don't ever
seen really you know that's something
we're trying to establish what do you
think is the most important do you think
do you think it would be trying to get
you know get people to be passing
genetics around and from their strains
will develop or do you think maybe try
to work on getting the legalization
model and then you've got a bit more
room to work within
there so what what I guess guided us
back in the day is like when everything
was illegal as can be it was the passion
and all that driving us to make
something better or like we find
something cool man we keep hold of it
and then like you know you meet guys you
know you're on Grateful Dead tour you
know these guys a couple years they they
grow killer weed you grow killer weed
you trust each other and you're like hey
man I got this awesome roadkill Skunk
Man you want it you hold on to it for me
in case something happens I can come
back and get that back for me like yeah
cool well I got this really awesome
Afghan do you want this and absolutely
and that's it's like starts off as a
slow Network and then from from that you
know I might have that Afghan and then
call him up in a year and say hey man I
was [ __ ] around grew some roadkill
seeds and pollinated your Afghan here's
some seeds he grows it out finds another
clone then he might have another buddy
here's this clone and it really starts
off slow and clone trading up until I
guess the real legalization was going on
like with the medical and all that it
won't it won't really a whole lot of
people trading a whole lot cuz trust
issues and you and you didn't want to
like let people KN know you grow like so
like the old forums like overgrow and
stuff like that you know we did a little
bit of trading because you could
maintain your anonymousness a little bit
you know yeah so like for the longest
time you know a name like Duke Diamond
you think I probably look like a pimp
you know what I mean gold chains and you
know what I mean so it was an alias I
just trying to make the opposite of what
I look like and who I am so you know
like this to me like years ago this
would have been nuts man like nobody
knew my face nobody knew where I was
from or what I talk like or none of that
so as the things progressed you know
these dispensaries open up they start
selling clones and you know people are
openly trading a little bit more it kind
of starts like a wildfire man it gets
out of control quick but the problem is
you get a lot of uh illegitimate Cuts
Like a guy's like hey man I got this
Sour Diesel right it ain't Sour Diesel
at all you know and but it gets passed
around to 150 people that all swear to
God this is sour diesel I paid $100 for
this cutting or my buddy wouldn't lie to
me you know that whole whole gig so I
would say now like in your in the
infancy of it over there just keep
growing from seed find your really
exceptional stuff and just hang on to
them you know and um as yall get more
and more and you get that more Community
thing where whether it's a forum or
y'all are so far along to where we can
all go down to the park at like some
cannabis Rally or whatever and you meet
people and you know just treat it like
you would anything else like if you grew
tomatoes in your vegetable garden and
your neighbor's cool and he's into it
too you know hang out man and you know
help each other along Yeah man so
basically don't shy away from giving
people you trust things that you want to
hang on
to yeah like I always said it's good to
have a good backup guy now your backup
guy like if you're in like the breeding
world you don't necessarily want to pass
things out because it's like giving out
the Coca-Cola secret you don't want
everybody to have it you know but there
were certain things I made that man I
wanted everybody to have it you know so
you know pick and choose um on kind of
what goes out there but I will say
this um people are people and um if you
don't want something to ever get out
there never give it to a single soul but
be prepared if something happens and you
lose it you done lost it so yeah you
know it's just kind of one of them deals
too yeah for sure so uh for the last
little part I was just uh hoping we
could just do some kind of more
light-hearted short random questions
just maybe novelty interest to people um
so the first one is if you could go back
to I use pant buddy yeah conditioner
it's looking good oh yeah man that's
solid um so if you could go back to one
place and one time in history to get
some land race seeds where would you
pick and you know what
error I'd be in Afghanistan and I'd be
in Lebanon from like the 70s man right
before 1978 when the Russians tried to
invade Afghanistan I'd be all over that
some
[ __ ] huh back when the hippie trial was
open yeah man exactly and I I'd be I'd
be rounding up stuff from there um I
would have probably done that and uh
hell man uh anywhere in Thailand if I if
I knew I won't going to get caught and
like executed by a firing squad for
finding some seeds I'd probably be all
over that place um but yeah primarily
like Lebanon Afghanistan Pakistan right
along that Hindu Kush mountain range
yeah so uh next one what's uh what's the
worst thing to happened to the scene
since you've been involved in it in your
opinion what's the worst thing you said
yeah man where do I start um I don't
know man I would
say [ __ ]
man where to start um you can a few out
if you want I would say um when
legalization happened you had a lot of
rich people with money just looking to
score more money they don't know [ __ ]
about what they're doing the quality
went down the prices go up and they just
screw the whole game up for everybody
they don't know [ __ ] they're like the
number one problem for like
misinformation I went into this one
store just to have a good laugh at what
was in there and had Bubba cush man it
was the shittiest looking weed I ever
seen and they say yes it's Bubba cush
man it's bubblegum Crosser cush I was
like yeah you don't say you know and
like you'll hear yeah Kim dog man that's
some this and this crossed together and
we made it here in our shop like yeah
Okay cool so that that is one um
two I would say uh like High Times
magazine man they're
they're terrible there the it's is
nothing but just [ __ ] long time ago
it used to be full of like a lot of good
grow information and good stuff and now
it's like what's the latest rapper
rapping about and you know bunch of
titties and ass and advertising you know
most of the magazines advertisement for
really shitty Seas at shitty seed banks
that you know it's not good and then if
you do get a little information it's
buried underneath some interview with
some rapper who doesn't give a [ __ ]
about medicine or cannabis Community or
whatever he's just concerned with money
and making songs and they glorify people
like that um there's like certain ones
even they they were informants man they
were snitches these people were like
pieces of [ __ ] and they're sitting there
glorifying this guy in a magazine
and you know and like they they're
killing us and they don't care about us
but you know they're going to they're
going to do that because of the money so
the guys are really just chasing the
money they forgot about the passion and
the real reason why we do what we're
doing you know so that's definitely a
real bad one um and then yeah the
the the the the pollution of the Jean
Pool is a pretty bad one that's been
going on for a while but I'd say in the
last two three years it's just gotten
real ridiculous you know so those those
are probably my top three top three uh
groans and moans y okay um so who's a
breeder who you would love to see the
brothers Grim do a collaboration
with so we got uh we got two that are
coming up oh they're getting ready to
get started yeah man you got one with h
Top Dog
seeds and we have fa
yeah and Swamp Boy seeds too so they're
two uh two friends of mine cornbread
rookie and JJ so we'll we'll definitely
be doing those two for sure um if I had
anybody else
um my mind's kind of going blank but you
you can definitely be sure we'll we'll
be doing some more cool stuff uh with
other people but um yeah those two right
off the top of my head we're definitely
doing that know so we'll have like a
little triangle cush su99 hybrid and a
starg c99 hybrid a awesome so uh what's
your current favorite strain and what's
your favorite strain of all
time damn that's a tough question Bubba
um god
well ah [ __ ] man that's tough dude
that's million dollar question you
you're a tough man man
um I don't know I would
say I can I can give you like a top 10 C
for certain things so I would say like
um for daytime like I need to do work
and [ __ ] like that I'd say like the
Cinderella 99 the Apollos you know this
would be definite favorites um for just
getting stoned as [ __ ] man I would say
Kim dog you know hands down uh without a
doubt
um if I want to feel weird like trippy
weird man like Durban thae high flyer
the DTC 99 stuff along those um flavor
and like just put me out knock me out to
sleep you know I would say uh hash plant
that 88 hash plant those are definite
definite winners and for flavor I have
uh this thing you seen it a local H that
um it's more sour than Sour Diesel so
for flavor and stuff I would say that
like triangle Kush too triangle gets me
[ __ ] up though man I get real high man
I'm not gonna lie I did uh get much
done I did actually spend quite a while
Googling Local H trying to figure out
what it
was so there was a band in America um
like y'all y'all probably heard it that
you know what I'm talking about Local H
they had a song called Eddie butter yeah
I found the B I was trying to find weed
references oh yeah yeah yeah man well
see like I never I never uh really let
that out I had one buddy back home he
was a Hermit he don't leave the house
for nothing and um when I was rounding
my clones back up he was the only guy I
ever gave it to because I know he don't
talk to people man he talks to like
animals and trees and [ __ ] and he don't
leave the house so I know it ain't going
nowhere not off of that property at
least so I give it to him go back years
later man and he's still doing the same
[ __ ] man growing the same strains under
the same equipment and everything's good
and kept and I got her back and um so
back in the day when we when we
originally made it when we were growing
it out we're like wow this [ __ ] is
killer and we were playing that Lo we
had Local H a CD as the As Good As Dead
you know anyway it's playing on Loop you
know we've done dried it and cured it
and smoke it and like there was a line
in the song like you just don't get it
and I was like yeah [ __ ] ain't
going to get this man we keeping this
one in house so they get the bud but
they ain't getting this so we ended up
calling it Local H nice fitting
name yeah so kind of on the opposite end
of the spectrum and feel free to list a
few what is your favorite SL sorry your
most hated uh drain SL what are some of
the worst in your
opinion how long you
[Laughter]
got
um let's see
man man that's the tough one too um I'm
not I'm not real big on Girl Scout
cookies or any of its
hybrids
um all the fake sour all the fake Kim
dog I I hate that
um let me think nastiest weed nastiest
weed I don't know Cy Cy seeds man they
put out some [ __ ] garbage now man
like it ain't like it was in the 90s and
80s um this stuff now man that shit's
atrocious man we had this [ __ ] here in
America uh the Canadians are growing it
it was called beasto man and Beast it
looks like it's thick old wet nugget and
not a damn triome on it it ain't got no
actually does have was smell smells like
hey and um the [ __ ] was Dirt Cheap you
could get it like pounds for cheap sell
it to dumb college kids make a couple
bucks but it was worthless weed it was
so nasty it was so bad we even had
shirts that said friends don't let
friends smoke beasts so that one was
pretty bad so like most of like what Cy
seeds grows out now it reminds me of the
Beast the
Beast [ __ ] that [ __ ] a lot of what you
get commercially available in Australia
is pretty uh similar to the beasters
from what I've heard it's it's not good
at all yeah it looks like uh very orange
looking hair like you got pulled about
two weeks too early super dense but no
resin smells like hey doesn't get you
high yeah maybe one one of our big
problems is uh the use of uh plant
growth Regulators it's uh it's really
predominant and yeah it's just horrible
for the
scene yeah man and the whole like the
whole deal is man is like
like it it it it just starts off real
small like uh what was that [ __ ] uh TS
Elliott the [ __ ] poet you know he had
the whole thing uh it doesn't start with
a bang it starts with the whimp the
slippery SL it really is man so if you
get some good seeds get getting over
there hook y'all up man um and you get
some you get some good uh some good grow
technology and the best way to do it I
used to do this with when I was doing a
solar panel engineering is if you learn
one you do one and you teach one so if
everybody takes that approach like you
learn some good ass soil methodologies
man you grow out some killer weed you
turn on your friend to it and say hey
smoke this [ __ ] and when they're like
man how'd you do that you're like hey
man let me show you how easy it is but
I'm going to show you but in return when
you get done chopping you need to show a
friend and then they turn showel friend
and within a year you'll have a pretty
big organic good killer weed Market
going on there man that just starts with
good genetics and you know a good good
foundation of you know organic growing
skills which I mean it's really easy
it's not even not even that hard man I
you know my dumb ass can do it anybody
can do it you know what I mean yeah I
think that's what's surprising is like
how much easier organic is and yet
somehow it's so like Hy ponic is so much
more
prevalent yeah man like I mean [ __ ] like
these [ __ ] PL man I think I got
enough battery man we going on a tour so
all these plants in here man this dirt
is uh let me think this over a year old
dirt man like I haven't amended it I
ain't done [ __ ] and look at all these
[ __ ] man I mean nice big no
deficiencies man gorgeous nice healthy
and green you know just happy as can be
and I mean simple simple man all I do
you know just give them tea you know
every two weeks and you know there's no
deficiencies in this [ __ ] you know
they're nice and nice and stout and
bushy and there's that 88 right here oh
gorgeous yeah man and I mean super
simple is purple
urle big old bust thing yeah I don't
think I've ever seen one that big
oh yeah that's what she
said sorry dude I had to get you
maning yeah man so yeah this big old
purple clle there's that Jack hair I was
telling you about see how tall and lanky
that [ __ ] is man he's certainly not
IND
car yeah definitely not man but uh man
throws some big buzz so this is the
genius right
here mother of all the Apollos and stuff
do you guys keep
the genius and the princess on fairly
tight
lockdown oh yeah man absolutely like we
never really really got that out there's
a couple of people that uh held on to it
as backup but they're kind of the same
deal they're hermit types they don't
really associate with other other people
so yeah this is the princess right here
right beside the
genius it said I'm sorry they're all
kind of hacked up from taking clones but
I was about to say is it because of the
Clones or do they have quite a different
structure like the uh the princess looks
to be you know more kind of Christmas
tree is yeah exactly man so like that
just goes to show people like you can
take one little Jean Pool Man and man
you could go on infinitely working that
thing you know you don't need a million
strains like we can work [ __ ] probably
50 different variants just off in one
plant even though like this princess and
this genius they're sisters but they
grow totally different man like you said
Christmas tree and then that long kinky
kinky kind of Branch thing going on you
know that shrub I love that shrub
structure yeah man but yeah like and you
know like when when one of these moms
like gets too big like a Sunday we just
took some clones off of we're going to
retire this mom so over
here we got all these clones getting
rooted bro so what'll happen is we'll
take the healthiest one and I'll come
back over here you see that big ass
trunk on that sucker man we'll chop her
off I'll cut a little hole out right
here yep and I'll drop that clone right
back in there and just give it water and
I'll grow another one of these that's
same dirt same pot same everything man
so like this that just happened not too
long ago with this one there's a
gooey
so that's it dropped it right back into
the same pot yeah the gooy is a strain
which uh not not many people seem to
know about her in my opinion yet it's
certainly one which should get more
attention I think what's your opinions
on her oh it's killer dude there ain't
nothing on Earth more pineapple than
that thing and it's like it's really
killer yeah very potent gooey breeder
he's like he's like one of them unknown
breeder Legends man really good dude
knows how to do his thing and um just
gets overlooked by people and I don't
know why but yeah super killer man yeah
and then uh yeah and all these just like
I said they just went right back into
another pot this is a strawberry diesel
coffin cut right here this would be like
one of our new releases uh it's getting
hit with Cindy 99 and we're making it's
called the ice coffee so that be hybrid
coming and we'll have the sour diesel
Bean pole so that's how sour diesel
clone Grows Right There Jesus so anybody
gets those and they look like little
Indica plants they're full of [ __ ] so
yeah it's big old tall Bean pole and
this is uh one of our
males see how thick that is for a mail
man jeez that's such a beautiful
structure yeah man that's our new Cindy
mail one out of a thousand is that the
one I um I saw on the Instagram which is
the uh the kind of the genius
phenotype no that's uh that was another
one um that was our
p75 oh yeah sorry my
mistake yeah man oh you're all good uh
that
one I said we keep them kind of hacked
up so they're not the prettiest but yeah
that was that one it's kind of hard to
see the the whole you can see he's got
great
branching Yeah man so yeah man like we
got we got males and males and males and
and most people throwing them away but
that's another male and there's that
Apollo 11 Mom oh nice sa thing yeah like
I mean you know like if you take like a
a 11 it's genius and then you got uh um
Cinderella 99 is a male so you see this
plant you know see that sativa leaf and
everything and you've seen the buds on
Instagram and yep smells like rip red
grapefruit and tastes like gummy bears
right so then you take over here sounds
this is
Apollo so this Apollo 13 this is uh uh
p75 which is the precursor to
c99 so it's 75% princess whereas c99 is
94% right so that little percentile
difference gives you a totally different
plant this thing smells like skunk's ass
and mango and tastes like
fuel so just you know just from that
slight slight change man
so it's pretty and you can see it's got
a wider Leaf you know it's uh the little
bit coming through from the Shiva skunk
which is skunk and L5 so you know just
off of one little change man you you end
up with a whole lot of difference man
yeah so when you guys um started making
these again and you decided to reuse the
p75 genetics for example was that
because you kind of thought that um the
genetics were proven and it was worth
using them and you know maybe you know
for example the uh I believe it was a
Shiva skunk mail Mr Soul originally used
you know was the kind of idea that you
know like that was a really good male it
was a solid foundation to work from or
was it more so just kind of saving some
time thinking you know like why make p50
again and work it out when we could just
start from
p75 yeah so we know that like the p75
generation that certain things were were
able to happen with that generation it
um it tended to
not overd dominate the mother so much so
it made like more sense to use it in F1
outcrosses like say um you know Rosetta
Stone for instance right we can use that
we had some Speedy nice you know
influences and everything but we don't
like overwhelm what we're really like
and we like the mom that's why we're
using her to make this F1 outcross so if
we like her you know we want to add like
some cool [ __ ] to it you know we'd like
to improve it but we don't want to like
overd dominate it now if we want to
really make something really new and
like overdominant or you know um make
something kind of completely different
we use that Cinderella 99 and then that
actually you know does its thing and the
main reason is just the way that p75
passes its gene pairs along and the
frequencies of those Gene pairs it makes
it like like a real good dad for making
some unique F1 stuff but at the same
time kind of remaining true to mama you
know yeah yeah of course it makes
perfect sense so um I mean just looking
at the Garden I mean I'll obviously
people will get to see when they're
watching this um you know the plants
look fantastic what's kind of the the
biggest thing you notice when you walk
into someone else's Garden what's you
know what's the big mistake most people
seem to be doing or you know just a
common one you kind of come across
they water too much
overwatering um I have to admit I'm a
bit guilty of that
myself yeah the overwatering um is a
real fine line if you're doing Organics
and you got real good microbial life
it's actually really hard to overwater
them to the degree where they're like
adversely affected you know um if you
use Smart pots you know them fabric
fabric pots yep yep yeah man those are
the [ __ ] you get like 30% more yield in
them sock too man and uh you can't
really overw waterer them too much like
they'll they'll dry out pretty good
because they breathe real good but um I
like to you know like I'll water but you
know I feel them out like if I can't
like if I lift that pot up and you know
the weight in the bottom like it looks
dry man but you can feel that weight in
the bottom let her ride another day
until she's kind of whitening up a
little bit and I like to go every two
weeks so like let's say like that room I
just showing y'all um you know this day
one I watered room yesterday so like I
mean they're good and Hefty
right um I'll let them get to where like
I feel that weight in the bottom because
I know like those roots from the
transplant haven't made it all the way
to the bottom but when I water them
again I'm only going to water them about
enough to dampen up that top 2/3 again
right just to keep the plant going and
then like I kind of maintain that for
about 2 weeks and then I let it come to
not totally dry but that pot's pretty
damn light most people are freaked out
but you'll notice man the the leaves
will be up there praying just like that
you know um that lets you know they're
they're happy man so then you you know
you give them water and you repeat that
process and then after two weeks let her
come to a little more of a dry it helps
to tease the roots along it allows them
to breathe some some real serious ious
good breaths of oxygen and um typically
when I let them dry out the next
watering I normally try to make it a
real healthy feed so they kind of uptake
a lot more and I also like to
reintroduce more microbes cuz like by
letting it dry out a little bit if I
lose any microbes you know by letting it
get a little too dry I'm putting them
right back in so they can keep [ __ ]
and getting you know so um you know
every two weeks you know you keep that
schedule you won't get no root rot
problems you won't get no fungus net and
things like that and um actually in
agriculture it's called crop pushing so
like you're kind of starving them almost
to that little bit and then when you do
hit them they it's like me and you man
you starve us for a couple days and then
throw us in like a buffet man me and you
going to eat so we're sick like our guts
are going to be all swole out like oh
[ __ ] they ate that much but they kind of
do the same thing and you'll see them
flowers start to burst and out like
crazy man that's saying like kind of
with a horse in the carrot thing you
know like you you kind of want to
stimulate them to do something but you
also kind of want to reward them with
what they need to respond that way with
it you know so yeah awesome so I don't
know if you've seen it but uh a new kind
of hot thing is uh vapor pressure
deficit um how much are you a believer
in this whole vapor pressure deficit if
you've ever heard of it and uh even kind
of the more General question is um
what's your kind of number one growing
tip for people you know if you could
give someone one growing tip to someone
who already grows you know what do you
think something people kind of do
wrong um
overfeeding um I know it's a lot of
plants man they especially ones that
have more of the sour fely taste they
tend to eat less now like when they're
overfeeding them they think hey man the
plant it ain't burning ain't no burn on
the leav so obviously
you know it's not too much but that's
actually that's wrong man because
sometimes you can feed them too much
they won't burn but they get complacent
like they'll just sit there in limbo
just not really getting any bigger so I
know a lot of people feed too much and
like this fuy strains man like I can
feed like if my one Buddy's doing his
normal thing feeding the [ __ ] out of
this plant I can feed a third of the
amount of what he's feeding it and I'll
yield twice as much as that sucker so
some plants are used to doing a whole
lot with very little and you kind of
look at like their Origins you know if
you're on the top of a mountain in
Afghanistan you really ain't used to
getting a whole lot of rain you ain't
used to getting a whole lot of good food
so when you do get a little bit you can
do a lot with it but you know too much
man they just get complacent on you so I
would say don't overfeed them and try
try different things you know and take
it slow like you can't you can't learn a
strain in one growth I've grown some of
these things 20 years and I still learn
new [ __ ] about them each time and
they're kind of like people I would
say their language is sign language but
it ain't like deff people sign language
it's plant sign language so if you can
learn how to speak their language you
Leaps and Bounds ahead so you learn how
like how do they sign that hey I need
calcium hey I need nitrogen or hey I'm
happy as [ __ ] or whatever you learn
their signs and each pl's going to be a
little little different and it's just
like your close friend that you grew up
with for 20 30 years you know when he's
tired man he's got that certain look
about him you know when he might be
getting a little hungry a little grumpy
and you'll start to pick up on these
things with those plants so get to know
them just like you do any any any person
or friend of yours or whatnot and you
know just take it slow and try a little
bit you know start low and work yourself
up and then you might say okay well you
know I got less yield this time and I
fed just that a little bit more let me
go back to where I was last time that
was about right and play around with
your Harvest States you know like one
day can make a considerable difference I
got one strain it's got a 48 hour window
you're up there at like 28%
THC and if you miss that window by early
a day or two or late a day or two you're
all the way down to 20% so 9% in a 48
hour window so play around with that a
little bit too like I mean the shit'll
blow your head off if you get it right
but it's real good either way but man
you hit it just
right lord it's tough window of
opportunity it sounds like oh man it's
so tough and like if you were to be
around me working man you laugh your ass
off of us sit there pacing back and
forth out of the plant all day like man
should I pull it is it ready I think
it's ready did I [ __ ] up in the
beginning am I off a day am I on a day
am I ahead a day man [ __ ] and I don't
know when to pull it and then I just go
by my gut and say well it seems right
and then I pull it and 99% of the time
I'll I'll get it and sometimes [ __ ]
happens yeah that it does so uh time for
a bit of a random product endorsement
what's uh one product you'd recommend to
everyone
H
H for
for GR lead oh you know what if if
anything if you recommend it it must be
good oh yeah
um I was GNA say something dirty as [ __ ]
but I ain't gonna do it um yeah you know
what I'm GNA recommend uh so I would
definitely recommend for growing I would
say uh dragonfly Earth medicine uh that
is hands down the best product I've
used ever like a lot of that stuff is
like I used to have to make on my own
which you know I never had a problem
with but growing this amount at this
scale it uh does make it a little
difficult for
me and man the results SP spoke for
themselves man I won't I won't go back
to using anything else so I would say
the dragonfly Earth medicine line that
makes organic growing easy as hell man
you take all that you know little secret
knowledge and little tricks and all that
stuff and they've done it all for you
they got it in a little bucket and you
just take a scoop throw it in the water
PH it let it brew and you're good to go
man it's real easy simple and it's real
nice stuff and they're real nice people
too man they're like Buddhists you know
oh nice um so I think that just about
wraps it up to be honest um is there any
uh shout outs or any just general
comments you wanted to
make oh man shout outs time uh to
everybody in Australia man uh uh y'all
are cool ass people and uh I'm glad that
uh you know that y'all can legally do
this thing but uh don't do like America
did and get it all screwed up just do
what's right follow what's in your heart
grow it good grow from your heart and uh
try to help people and uh I've never met
an Australian person I didn't like
everybody seemed all genuine and
good-hearted and wanting to help people
you know so I think y'all are going to
do awesome with that
um if you are uh doing it and you ain't
in the Realms of the law my daddy always
said if you ain't going to be good make
sure you good at it you don't want to
get in trouble with the man and then uh
yeah big shout out to the [ __ ] Kim
family and all my people back in [ __ ]
Virginia and all the cool Growers around
the world man and you know love y'all
very much try to do a good job for y'all
and hopefully you know bump into y'all
one of these days and uh yeah I reckon
that's about it my
friend so there you have it a big thank
you to Duke and Mr Soul again I hope you
enjoyed it if you did subscribe and all
the usual stuff in order to keep up to
date with us and we'll see you next time
[Music]
la la la la la la