[Music]
hello and welcome to another episode of
the podcast the Cannabis podcast for
Buddy
enthusiasts as always you're joined by
your boy heavy days here from the upside
down library and as usual we want to
give a massive shout out to all of our
incredible sponsors who help ensure the
show continues to happen SE here now
number one seed bank in the industry all
the hottest breeders the latest drops
everything you can look for and more
whether you're after indoor outdoor
feminized regular autoflow they've got
everything under the sun to keep you
loaded on all the hottest genetics
producing the most fire Bud you've ever
had I here they've got some incredible
lines from heavy days still in stock if
you want to go check that out make sure
to do it before it's too late
big shout out to CT now we appreciate
you so much likewise if you want to
produce the best bud to date you've got
to make sure your garden is pumping on
all cylinders and for that we recommend
our good friends at Organics alive they
produce the number one powdered organic
products that will ensure your next crop
is the absolute best today people are
picking up cups all around the globe
using their products which is the
highest Accolade you can get hom Growers
just like you producing not only their
best Harvest today but award-winning
Harvest what more could you ask for
they've got Solutions whether you're in
veg transition flour they've got
micronutrients macronutrients absolutely
every product you could want ferments
and more check them out guys Organics
alive your number one stop for all of
the highest quality organic inputs to
make sure your Harvest is
killing likewise you got to make sure
your garden is pest and pathogen-free to
ensure that your plants are happy and
producing the highest quality Harvest
for that we recommend you check out our
good buddies at copit they've partnered
with us for a long time and we have no
doubt that if you use their products you
will find they are the absolute best in
the game you've got to check out the
spidex vital plus breeda sachets these
are an absolute game Cher it's the usual
spidex vital you know and love that's
going to take out any spidermite
problems you have but the breeder sachet
allow a continuous sustained release of
these beneficial Predators into your
garden ensuring that you don't just have
one big bird burst and surge but instead
a consistent rate of release truly a
game changer I expect nothing less from
the experts at copit biological you know
these guys are world leaders they're not
just in America they're all around the
world and for good reason they are the
Pinnacle of the game if you're after
biological Pest Control check out copit
number one thank you so much for the
support the final piece of the puzzle to
ensure that your room is killing it is
our good friends at Pulse their sense
are second to none industry leading and
just recently they announced the pulse
Hub what more could you want an
integrated unit for all of your sensors
to ensure that your garden is automated
and tracking all of the variables you
may not be consciously aware of from VPD
to ppf dupoint temperature humidity so
much more you've got to get yourself a
pulse sensor guys it has revolutionized
the way I grow flower and increased the
turpine content the cannaboid content
the yield so so so much more shout out
as always to our friends at Pulse
sensors likewise if any of you guys have
been listening to the show you know that
I am passionate about helping people
transition to vaporized options if
they're considerate about their
respiratory health and for me dap are
the world leaders in this dnap helped me
to transition from bongs to vaping and I
tell you what I've never looked back
their unit is the most potent the most
highly replicating of a bong hit I've
ever come across and through their
incredible mu unit I was able to
successfully get off bongs a few years
ago now truly one of the most Innovative
and interesting Vapes on the market
using a totally different design to
others you have found please check out
dap I promise you guys if you've tried
vaping before and felt like it didn't
quite cut it check these guys out you
will not be disappointed massive shout
out to dinat thank you so
much and last but not least we want to
give a massive shout out to the
incredible patreon gang without you guys
we could not continue to make it
episodes if you want to get early access
to upcoming episodes exclusive content
just on the patreon including the likes
of mem Jean Bob hemp Hill Bodie triome
jungle so much more be sure to go check
out our patreon we give away genetics
every month to our supporters along with
artwork Vapes sensors so much more
please check out the patreon guys I
promise you you won't regret it you'll
get your money back in swag for helping
supporter show you love thank you so
much to everyone from the patreon we
appreciate you so
[Music]
greatly and on this one we are stoked to
have a humble native a veteran of the
drug war an up and cominging star and an
all around lovely guy John of
Huckleberry Hill
Farms here to talk all
things white Thorn
Rose
breeding plans for the future
so much
more without further
delay let's get into
it all righty gang welcome back for
another episode and on today we are
incredibly grateful to have a Humbolt
native a career grower breeder operator
of Huckleberry Hill Farms and an all
round lovely guy a massive welcome to
John for taking the time to come on the
show
today yeah well thank you so much for
having me I'm looking forward to talking
with you today oh that's lovely to hear
first question we love to ask guests
what have you been smoking on
today you know uh to be completely
honest I usually don't smoke until you
know later on in the afternoon and and
when I do it's it's usually just a few
Puffs here or there but um you know it's
usually a couple hits on the white Thorn
Rose one of our signature strains or um
trying out a few new fenos that we we
tried to create from last year's uh seed
stock and really trying to figure out
which ones uh will be something that we
decide to plant for this year so um
always smoking kind of something
different I love that you're a man after
my own heart I too transitioned from um
from having Brey bongs to just smoking
in the evening usually after the kids
have gone down and um I can certainly
appreciate how much well for me at least
it helped me to appreciate cannabis a
lot more I started getting a lot more
fire which I really enjoyed you
mentioned the white Thorn Rose anyone
who's come across your brand would have
seen the iconic strain that's associated
with you guys let's let's talk a little
bit quickly about the Inception of that
one because it's such a signature strain
for you guys how did that strain first
come to
be um you know when you've grown we've
grown I've been growing for maybe 45
years now and so it's always still
exciting every single year is exciting
every single year is a little bit
different um but what really becomes
very exciting to a lot of us Growers is
the breeding process and and really
trying to find the the next new thing
right um and that's kind of how white
Thorn Rose came to be um and in honor of
my mom who passed away um I really
wanted to make this Farm um about her
and about what she taught me and so all
the different strains that we grow here
are breed to a strain I used to grow
with her when I was 10 so and that
strain was called Froot Loops back then
we didn't did rename it to Paradise
punch and so um whitethorn Rose is a
lemon OG crossed with the paradise punch
and we we named it uh after my
girlfriend Rose and after um the town of
whitethorn which is right down the road
where I consider to be um really the
bullseye of a dartboard where a billion
dooll industry was created and I say
that
because back in the 80s and back in the
90s there was enforcement around you
know they were flying helicopters they
were dropping guys down on wires and
eradicating you know the cannabis plants
and arresting you if they could and um
really hanbul County and whitethorne the
town of whitethorne was really the
epicenter of those enforcement um
dollars that they had and it was pretty
pretty sketchy so I thought white Thorn
Rose was a fitting name for that that
Cult of our so many people like it I
just thought it uh would help tell the
story of the Emerald Triangle small
farmer oh manate that's beautiful like
an homage to your mom your hometown your
partner what a what a brilliant Trifecta
I I realize you have this epic backstory
and let's let's jump into it cuz I know
that you know you you've been in the
beating heart and epicenter of worldwide
cannabis so tell me a little bit first
let's go all the way back to the start
what was your first experience with
cannabis you know um I moved here when I
to this very piece of property that
we're sitting on today and moved here
with my mom and my stepdad when I was
five years old and really from the the
first first two years that we moved here
um cannabis was a part of our life right
it was just a small part of our income
that we had to do to live in the country
so we grew a little bit cannabis we were
part-time loggers we were part-time
commercial fisherman um we cut firewood
in the winter time and sold it to a
local Merchant so you just did a bunch
of different things we had a vegetable
garden we had fruit trees and cannabis
really very quickly for me growing up as
a kid became like growing a tomato plant
I really looked at it as just that it
was just another plant and um my mom
really taught me everything I know about
cannabis and she really taught me that
there's no sop you know stand standard
operating procedure that you could write
down on a piece of paper because every
strain kind of needed its own individual
attention it wasn't like OG and and
white Thorn Rose could be grown exactly
the same and they both could Thrive so
she was the one that really taught me
that they they each needed individual
attention and that they each uh uh
needed to be grown a little bit
differently so it was really from I the
the age of 10 that I started growing
with her and she gave me little chores
like checking the emitters the drippers
you know checking the water tank and it
didn't really take that long before um I
really wanted to experiment around and
see what these different cultivars or
these different strains responded to we
were uh we were already doing some stuff
together like you know putting Rusty
Nails in the planter box you know for
the iron um at Harvest time we were
using birth control pills because
neighbor had told us that that would
help the flowers harden up um we would
sometimes pull the big plants out of the
ground with the roots and everything and
we'd stick those roots in boiling water
before we hung them upside down because
somebody said that all the resin would
go to the the flower if we did that so
you know I don't do any of that stuff
today but I still experiment around in
my own little ways um not so extreme I
guess um to really find out what these
plants really respond to
and uh well I'll just keep going a
little bit unless you want me to stop
but I love it keep going so it it's it
really took like four or five six years
before you know I could talk my mom into
giving me my own plants and really that
was you know my goal is to have my own
plants to grow them the own way the way
I wanted to grow them and you know she
struggled as being a parent you know to
let your kid grow something that was
technically illegal right like how do I
let him do that I'm not a good mom blah
blah blah but after I nagged enough I
think she gave in and she said okay well
these are the conditions I'll give you
10 plants and given none of these plants
were ever grown in our front yard these
were plants that we had to like make
trails and hide to Trails and Hike into
the woods and hide them from aerial
surveillance and airplanes and
helicopters and enforcement team so it
wasn't as easy as it is today and uh
part of the condition was any of the
money that if I were to make it to
harvest any of the money that I were to
make it had to go to like a college
education or I had to invest it in
something something for my future I
couldn't go out and buy a motorcycle or
something that was fun and and frivolous
so that first year I remember I made 12
pounds and I think uh the price back
then was like $1,200 a pound or
something like that which sounds good
now um
but and so she ended up taking the
product after it was dried and and
trimmed and she sold it for me and I put
uh I put $10,000 down on a a piece of
property along the Eel River you know at
the age of 15 and so um I then started
growing there during the summertimes and
uh yeah just really fell in love with
this plant and and growing with my
friends and my buddies and it was like
okay let's go work on the gardens in the
morning and then let's go surfing or
let's go fishing or hiking or something
like that so Humble County is an amazing
place to to grow up at there's redwoods
everywhere the ocean's right 15 minutes
over the hill um there's plenty of
hiking trails and it's just a very
beautiful clean place and so I feel
pretty fortunate growing up here as a
kid I'll let you get a couple words
in what an incredible story that's
that's beautiful I love it a very
admirable upbringing that I think
everyone can can when they hear that
they'll think man that sounds awesome I
guess I'd be interested given you know
you and your parents were in the the
Beating Heart of cannabis for all those
years first question were there any old
genetics that were ever grown by
yourself or your parents that left a
really lasting memory on
you yeah actually uh this one genetic
that I ended up breeding with um the
lemon OG to create the white Thorn Rose
was a um strain my mom bred with a
really good friend of mine's mother um
she she had a
blueberry uh blueberry cush that she
crossed with u my friend's mom's
lavender cush and together they they
ended up calling that Froot Loops at the
time and one of the reasons we used to
grow that strain not only because it was
really fruity and it tasted amazing but
it it harvested really early it
harvested you know early September the
first week of September so if you were
on top of your game you had the ability
to dry cure it trim it and sell it
before the big Harvest of humbo County
came in and dropped the price so we
always got2 or $300 more a pound um
whatever we trimed because it was an
early
Harvester and it also really allowed you
to get your harvest in before maybe some
of the enforcement teams might you know
eradicate you and and and just to
reflect a little bit back to those
eradication teams sometimes especially
after 1985 Ronald re had declared the
war on drugs and enforcement got bad the
government was supplementing the
counties with Monies to flly do
overflights and drop guys in and cut the
weed down and um that got really really
really bad and really scary you'd wake
up some mornings you know right at
sunlight and there'd be like a a
Blackhawk helicopter sitting over your
house with guys and AR15s I mean it was
only a plant but they took it seriously
like we were doing something bad and you
know growing with my best friend it was
always our opinion that well we live in
Humble County every single person we
knew was growing pot back then and so
the the few people that we knew that got
caught or got in trouble just got
probation so that was kind of our game
plan well if we get caught and we get in
trouble um we'll get probation and then
we can decide how to go forward with our
life but um enforcement was really bad
sometimes there was four or five
helicopters in the air at a time and
that's really when my parents decided
excuse me to to move out and they bought
a commercial fishing boat and really
sailed around the world to China to uh
excuse me to the South Pacific to China
to uh Alaska and really fish for albore
11 months out of the year and I stayed
back here with my best friend and we
just kept growing and we were just
loving it loving everything and uh long
story short
we were pretty naive as as Hill kids
right we we knew about redwood trees we
knew about growing Po and fishing and
all those kind of things but really
worldly we were pretty naive you know we
didn't know there was a difference
between you know state law and federal
law and all these different things and
then kind of got an eye opener one day
at the age of uh
24 um this old man down our road ended
up turning Us in to the cops and they
like I said Ronald Reagan had declared
the war on drugs and he really wanted to
make an uh an impression on people in
humbal and really attempt to stop people
from growing weed and I had 30 federal
agents drive up my driveway one morning
at 6 o'clock and um really from that
point forward my life was never the same
um I was now uh you know getting
searched um at the end of that day they
searched my place they eradicated all
the
weed and um then at the end of the day
they left they gave me a little yellow
speeding ticket and they said if we want
to contact you we will and it uh you
know then I'm I'm starting to learn the
difference between state and federal and
how they operate and a year and a half
later they came back with a federal
arrest warrant um I went down to San
Francisco courthouse building was
arraigned and uh retained an attorney
and now was being made aware that there
was something called the mandatory
minimums and the mandatory minimums
don't clear so much if you're a
firsttime nonviolent offender the
mandatory minimums don't care if you
would never hurt anybody if you're nice
if you're bad the mandatory minimums
really was looking me straight in the
face with a 10year to life in prison for
a firsttime nonviolent offender and I
really refus to and my best friend um so
together for the next three and a half
years we went to court we went to court
telling the judge you know we were
growing the the the tomato plant or we
were growing the weed plant whatever you
want to call it and um we would never
hurt anybody and you know at the end of
three years of going to court he stood
up and he said you know because I'm
Bound by the law you know I I'm going to
sentence you to the lower end of the
mandatory minimums and he ended up
giving us 10 years in jail um and in
federal prison you do 85% of your time
so I did um eight years in prison six
years in Lao and then another two years
at Nellis Air Force Base you know all
for this plant and ironically full
circle now I'm a permitted Farm in humbo
county and permitted by the state of
California so you know still to this day
their rules and their regulations and
their laws don't really make a whole lot
of sense to me but um I really like to
look at the positive side of everything
and um it's just a uh it was just a
story in my life that um that I had an
experience that I feel pretty fortunate
that a lot of people didn't have that
gives me a different perspective on the
reality of of our government and the
reality of some of the really cool
people that are in jail for really a uh
a harmless crime and so um I'm okay with
it wow look first of all thank you so
much for you know I I I for lack of a
better words for your service you know
what you've contributed to the scene
with your sacrifice that's that's
incredible that sadly someone as
successful as yourself was a victim of
of the drug war I think that we we need
to talk about that a little more because
we often on the show talk about the
people who' have come before us who have
say for example like yourself had to
serve sentences to help progress the
scene I think we really need to give a
bit of homage to that the first question
that comes to mind is what what why did
the old man tip you off why was he upset
you know he was he was about 90 years
old he had lived in that um area for his
whole life and he just wasn't really
keen on having somebody new move in I
don't I'm really not sure unfortunately
while we were gone he passed away and
like you know I never had a chance to
ask him or talk to him or um it really I
guess doesn't matter at this time but
you know sometimes uh people are stuck
in their way and maybe he didn't agree
with cannabis or whatever his reasoning
was um you know sure sure and then so
you mentioned that they came initially
and then they sort of left at the end of
the day and then there was a year in
between the visits what was that year
like were you sort of walking on
eggshells or did you just get back to it
or well I kind of knew I was in trouble
but you know it was a year and a half
before they came back with the the
arrest warrant and you know it was about
a year where I didn't do a whole lot and
I was like after a year went by I was
like well you know maybe they just
messed up maybe they just came here and
they realized that you know I am
somebody that would never hurt anybody
and it was just some plants and blah
blah blah whatever it was and so I
started growing again and uh long story
short they were following me and so um
yeah I got lucky not to get in trouble
again while I was um about to get
arrested again um but yeah so I guess
they still never learned my lesson I'm
here now still doing the same thing that
I was doing back then but now it's legal
so yeah no look I'm glad you're still
doing it and I I think everyone can
relate to that after a year of waiting I
think it's safe everyone would basically
assume similar to yourself that maybe
something else has happened so you know
that that's a bummer they they came back
after a year and a half so um when you
eventually ended up going to the the
Federal prism what was that experience
like any memorable characters did you
meet any other growers in
there yeah well I was fortunate enough
to go to Lao which is one of the they
say the cushier the easier prisons um
out there um my mom and my dad drove me
to prison um where you selfs surrender
you self surrender at the USP which is
the United States Penitentiary where
people have life in prison with the
razor wire and they check you in there
they fingerprint you in there and they
process you in there before they take
you over to where I finally ended up
which was the camp which was a a cattle
ranch which was a dairy which was a uh
had some Farmland where we grew corn and
beans for the the cows um so I got to go
out every day and work in the fields and
um make 11 cents an hour and um at least
be outside and get to work out and play
some softball and really after I uh
after the first year when you're you
know kind of done missing the things
that are on the outside like good food
and you know your family and your
friends and you kind of get into a
routine in there and it's not like you
forgot what's on the outside but I think
we're pretty strong as as humans and we
learn to adapt to the situation and you
get into your routines and you start
looking forward to hey on the weekend I
get to play softball and hey I'm playing
volleyball and basketball and you know
you just occupy your time with doing
things that you like to do even in there
and so um I do remember walking over to
the camp and I had uh the maximum time
you can have to go to the prison camp is
10 years so when I got there I had the
longest prison sentence out of anybody
there for a first time non-violent
offender and people were looking at me
going what what you you grew weed wait
you had to have done something else or
how you can't just be here for a plant
and and so because of that they knew I
wasn't a rat they knew I didn't
cooperate and and rat off one of my
friends and really gained a lot of
respect from all ethnic groups blacks
whites Hispanics um Asians all of them
really accepted me with open arms and
and really gave me a lot of respect very
quickly because of solely that um and uh
so I felt pretty at home and you know
they brought me over toothpaste and
toothbrushes and kind of welcomed me
there and made it as as really as good
as could
be that's that's nice to hear that you
were able to sort of make the most of it
I guess the question that I always think
about whenever I'm contemplating either
myself theoretically in jail or someone
else as you describe I have to imagine
that there were points where you were
sitting there going I can't wait to get
out I'm going to light up some fruit
loop like what was the strain that you
were thinking about like what what were
you having the The Mirage dreams about
smoking when you first got out and as a
followup tell me about as you got closer
to getting out how did that all pan
out so
um because I was in a camp you had the
ability to get whatever you wanted in
there like visitors could drop it off in
the visiting room that prison system was
pretty corrupt it was it was pretty
awful actually and
um but you were really in command of
your own destiny if you get in trouble
there you would have to go to a higher
security facility so I didn't mess
around too much and uh really was just
playing sports trying to get in the best
shape I could um back then it was all
about OG and Sour Diesel and so we
didn't have and it I didn't look forward
to the fro Loop so much you know I
remember growing it with my mom and um
thought it was cool but really there was
a time in the the 80s and early 90s
where was all about OG and sour d and we
were getting $5,800 a pound um right
before I went to jail so um yeah I guess
I was thinking about that I was hearing
stories of my friends really doing
pretty well in the Cannabis industry out
out here which was a little bit hard to
hear at times and you know we were in
there um but uh yeah time went pretty
fast after a while I mean 3,000 days the
first year was slow the next little bit
went fairly quick and then six months
before I got out like all of a sudden
every day was like forever and it just
slowed down because I could finally see
the light at the end of the tunnel and I
was like wow I'm G to make it out of
here and uh so it really got really
tense and really slow and stressful and
you know finally made it out went to a
halfway house and got home and um really
didn't smoke for for quite a while and
didn't grow because I still was on I got
five years federal probation which
didn't allow for you to grow at the time
and did get released a little bit early
from that and then immediately started
growing my 215 but one thing I I want to
share is what was very odd to me at the
time was I love fishing I was a fishing
guide on the river for years I
commercial fished with my my parents for
Sam and albacore and crab and I love the
water and I love the outdoors and when I
got back
I didn't have that drive that I
remembered that I used to have to want
to go do those things because when you
don't do those things for so long you
forget about what it is about those
things that really made you get up in
the morning and want to do them and so
it really took me a minute even with
growing pot I didn't realize what it was
so much about growing a plant that I
love so much until I put a few in and I
was like whoa and then all of a sudden
you know we had the 215 era and so I was
able to you know grow a certain amount
once I was off probation and really just
fell in love with that and then um very
quickly you know California was going to
legalize cannabis and allow you to get
permits and ended up falling all back
into that and was the fourth existing
Farm to get a permit in Humble County so
um yeah ironically now I'm here I'm one
of three farms in Humble County to get a
tourism permit so I take people here and
I really it's not so much about the
money for me it's about creating these
strains honoring my mom that passed away
when I was in jail um telling stories
about not Huckleberry Hill Farm so much
but all the Emerald Triangle small
farmers that have families and kids that
are exactly like me that could have
ended up exactly like me and there's
thousands of those people that really
just want to grow the best possible
product they can and and feel like just
energized and amazed to be able to share
it with these consumers for the first
time in our lives like to have somebody
after 45 years say to you excuse
me say to you hey the white Thorn Rose
made me feel amazing you know I slept
really good last night thank you so
much like that
validation is the reason why we're doing
what
doing 100% excuse me no that take your
time that's such a powerful statement to
be able to give someone relief you know
if if nothing else in this world to to
not have pain is a is a noble thing you
can grant someone and and it's just so
sad that we've been lagging behind for
so many years and that has you know sort
of been on the table but for so many
people not accessible so it's it's
beautiful to see you know native
passionate people like yourself bringing
that to the table and there's so many
things you you referen you know we'll
have to loop back on so many of them but
I guess the first question I'd love to
ask is you started growing again what
was the progression from planting those
few seeds finding that spark again to
then starting your own breeding
Journey um really it was dictated by my
ability to get my County permit because
once you were in the the permitting
process you know The Regulators would
come here frequently and do their
inspections like they were supposed to
make sure you have rainwater catchment
ponds make sure that all the the the
sediment wasn't flowing into the
tributaries and um there was all these
rules and regulations that now that we
entered into the system we had to follow
and we were getting checked up on all
the time so um kind of started off slow
but my farm here is permitted for 5,000
square fet um one of the smallest
permitted farms in the state of
California like one of the bigger ones
is 2.2 million square feet and I'm 5,000
square feet so that's like 500 5,000 I
don't even know how many times bigger
than mine maybe 10,000 times I don't
know but um yeah so it's just my
girlfriend and I that are really here
and um I was saying before having grown
so long um really found a a big interest
in breing and creating different strains
and found that
maybe a pathway forward for the small
farmer wasn't ever going to be to
compete with big a with all these gush
mins and sour diesels and all these um
commercialized strains that they could
easily get at commercial nurseries but
maybe it was highlighting our Legacy
strains that nobody else in the world
had and so I really just focused on you
know breeding different strains which
hundreds of them turned out to be
failures that I didn't do I really
valuated them myself and what I liked
then that's what I really presented to
the consumer and then um once the
consumer got it in their hands then they
really uh determined whether or not I
would ever grow It Again by their
feedback and so I Rely a lot on their
feedback to to dictate what I grow and
today we grow 90% of our farm is
whitethorn Rose and I just because I
won't give up the other 10% because I
want to experiment around and grow some
of these little pheno hunts that I'm
running around trying and doing and um
gotten a lot of attention doing so um
yeah feel pretty blessed being able to
do something I love and wake up every
single morning and run on my front door
with a cup of coffee and uh tend the
plants beautiful it sounds like you're
living the dream I love that and
specifically in terms of the the white
Thorn Rose let's let's delve into that a
bit we we love to focus on genetics and
breeding here on the show and so I guess
the first question is it's made using
some of those Legacy strains you just
referenced that are you know native to
yourself in the area were you working
with seed stock did someone retain some
clones was the first creation of white
Thorn Rose a fem or a regular cross that
that was that's a very good question and
um I guess a very important point that I
think I always leave out on most of the
stories
for there's just so much information
when I share that Journey that a lot of
stuff gets uh left out and and that's
one thing that I I leave out but when I
was gone and you know I told you I
didn't rat on any of my friends which if
I would have I would have got no time I
didn't have to do any time and they
wanted me to cooperate with them and
that's how the federal government worked
but it was the single most important
decision I ever made in my life not to
to cooperate with the federal government
and really ensure assure the people that
I grew up with that I am who I said I
was and you know in Humble County we
were like one big family we trusted one
another with his with our lives so if
you break that trust you never get it
back so I did never broke that trust
even when I got in trouble and so when I
showed back up here um after being gone
for eight years I had 50 people from
this community here to welcome me back
to bring me silverware to bring me
plates and toothpaste and all those
simple things that we took for granted
that had gotten stolen when I was gone
and you know they all were here to
celebrate me in my return and um just
was really grateful for that and some
people brought me over barbecues and
just brought me over everyday living
stuff but there was this one friend in
particular his name was
trell um trell was a really super good
friend of mine and he was the friend
that I was telling you that my mom bred
um her blueberry cush to the lavend
berry cush and so trell came over and
after being that gone uh for that long
he had kept Froot Loops alive in his
garage underneath a light for me for
eight years and he brought that mother
plant back to me after that long and
instead of giving me a barbecue he gave
me this plant back that really was a
reflection of my mom and what we created
so um he really enabled this Farm to be
what it is today um by that kind of
thoughtfulness and that kind of
generosity and um just we'll never
forget that ever and um just to Circle
back a little bit I you know we're
always talking about growing and and
smoking different strains and that
amazingness of with all that but um one
of the little projects when you and I
first met a couple years ago with the
weed in the jar and the little uh peep
Puck on the top really was trying to
find a way to share with people the
validation that I felt from growing I
wanted people to understand that
starting a seed growing it throughout
its life cycle harvesting it drying it
curing it and then sharing it with your
good friends and watching them smile and
alleviating their pain or their stress
was really where all the magic H happens
and so this breeding that I do here is
is as much to find a new strain but is
is is also part of trying to encourage
people to grow their own like nobody
really needs to buy pot from the retail
shop and and pay this ridiculous amount
of money like on a jar that you saw
there which was a quarter ounce I make
$3 they sell it for 65 at the retail
store so like it's ridiculous and I just
want people to experience growing their
own because that's where the true magic
is so many incredible points there I
think we got to say shout out to tr for
hanging on to that clone that's
absolutely beautiful I've I've held on
to a clone for a bu for one year and
that felt like a lifetime I can't
imagine eight that's shout out to him
that's a that's a good homie yeah for
sure yeah look so many incredible points
you you touched on then um I guess the
first question is tell me about when you
so you've made the uh the white Thorn
Rose was was that a regular pollination
and and tell me about when you popped
those seeds and and started to realize
what magic you'd stumbled
upon yeah so I think that was in
2018 was the first year I had grown the
seeds I created those seeds the lemon OG
to the paradise punch um in 2017 and
then in 2018 was the first year I grew
them and at that time I was putting some
of my product in the willly reserve jar
the Willie Nelson jar and um really
having fun participating with that crew
and learning about Willie Nelson and and
having our stuff in his jar and
um ended up with maybe 15 different
plants all a different variation at that
time we were still growing from seed and
the marketplace was a little hesitant
because what happened was growing from
seed every plant is a little bit
different right they're not identical
like growing from a clone eventually the
industry pushed back so hard on that
that many of us grow from clone now we
make we do feno hunts we make mother
plants and then if we like those we we
grow like a bed of that or or 10 plants
of that so at least the product looks
exactly the same that's going to be
going in the jar that I'm calling white
Thorn Rose and so what came about those
15 different phenos of the white Thorn
Rose was another strain that we renamed
called mom's weed so people ask me well
you got Mom's weed and you got white
Thorn Rose and they both say it's a
lemon OG crossed with um Paradise punch
like you must have made a mistake but
really it was just a different pheno of
the same cross and so we liked them both
so much that we kept them both and what
you'll notice really quickly is that all
the names here are from seeds that we
named ourselves are strains we named
ourselves and so they we have strains
like a MF because we went to Italy and
went to the mfi coast we named one after
my girlfriend's mom that passed away
when she was 48 called Margie's magic
her name was Margie um we had one that
was called sweet Marlene my mother was
marleene you know we just named them
what we wanted to name them right and
and then we really tried to educate the
consumer why we did that instead of
really trying to let them dictate what
names were popular or whatever we just
did what we wanted to do we grew what we
wanted to grow and then we shared it
with them and and really found a a
little niche in in what they liked so
yeah I don't know no that's that's
beautiful and I too do the same thing
you know I've I've actually got a few
phenotypes of the same cross and I give
them slightly different names and people
always ask me they're like can't you
just like col it down to the one that's
better and you're like no they're
different like that's that's why they're
different and some PE and some people
love moms weed better than they do white
Thorn Rose and vice versa and it's truly
amazing to have watched since 2018
whitethorn Rose to its Evolution to
today it's really taken a life of its
own it's won like 20 different Awards in
the emerald cup and um you know with
different products with hash holes and
vape pens and rosin and resin and bubble
has and all the different things and and
manufacturers are really having a fun
time experimenting around and creating
different products with a strain they've
never seen before and um really is given
a leg given us a leg up in the
marketplace and the newest and the
latest um I guess momentum that we've
gotten with the right uh whitethorn Rose
was when somebody that had came and
visited my farm here took that white
Thorn Rose back and shared it with a a
comedian named Bert Cher and he's a
pretty famous comedian out of LA and um
he took it on one of his podcasts that
has like three million viewers and you
know he started yelling this is the best
Trin in the world and like hundreds of
people reached out to me where can I get
it where can I get it and you know next
thing you know Tony Hawk smoking it and
Tom sagira and all these famous people
that I never even had heard about until
then and um and then we got invited to
his podcast me myself in in Ridgeline
Farms Jason another award-winning farm
that I I really work very closely with
and grew up with and um it's kind of
mutated since then and now we have done
a across between his award-winning Lance
and we cross it to the white Thorn Rose
and Bert ker is going to feno hunt
this year at his his house in LA and we
actually did a mockup jar and we hope
that he's going to accept our proposal
to sell a Bert ker pheno hunt of a
strain that we're going to name after
his nickname the machine and so we're
having fun doing what we're doing we
don't know if any of it makes any sense
or anything but as long as we're having
fun and enjoying life and um living
every day to the fullest I think you
know that that's what life's all about
wow you I feel like you must have a copy
of my questions cuz you just answered
about 10 of them in one go that was like
no you you did it you're a mind reader
look a huge fan of your mom's house
Network and um you know anyone who
watches it would be aware burnt Chrysler
serial alcoholic funny guy though um is
uh hugely involved in the mainstream
comedian scene I guess I guess I was
interested how did that connection
initially happen who gave him the
whitethorn rose that started it all
so um Bert's
sister's um boyfriend had come here with
the
ganier um program and for a tour and at
the end of every tour I always save a
bunch of product and and one of my
highlights is sharing a bunch of product
with people that got to hear my story
got to hear you know stories of people
that are on um the
property and uh he went back and he
actually shared it with bertt and Bert
fell in love with it and then he started
seeking it out and then when we went
down to his podcast you know we bought
him we brought tons of weed down to him
and really hoping that um kind of have
it on the schedule he's going to come up
here um this summer and do a podcast on
the farm um so just yeah just kind of
riding the wave and got to go to the
Chelsea Handler um comedy show a couple
weeks ago and I passed her off a bunch
of white Thorn Rose so she hasn't said
anything about it but kind of exploring
the comedian World there and getting a
chance to share um our story and our
Legacy sungrown strains with a whole
different group of consumers so really
stoked about that and um yeah yeah
hugely hugely like the the amount of
overlap between the Cannabis and the
comedian scene is huge and when you
think about it not that surprising I
guess the question I thought when I was
thinking about this appearance on
bertcast and I'd encourage everyone to
to go check it out it's a it's a great
episode um what do you feel like this is
a sign that we're becoming more and more
mainstream or do you think it was just a
lucky
coincidence I I want to say it's a lucky
coincidence but I am a firm believer
that everything happens for a reason and
um I've always
felt from the very beginning that that
we were going to do something amazing
and amazing I don't mean by making a a
whole bunch of money because money I
know doesn't make people happy I was
taught that from the age of 10 like
never chase money because you'll never
have enough there's always somebody that
has more it will never make you happy it
always make you feel hollow and yeah it
does make you know paying the rent
easier and it does make you know going
to the grocery store yeah but it's
really friends family and community that
make you feel real and make you feel
whole and um I still feel that same way
today I don't know what part or what
role Bert ker is playing in really
uplifting our community um or sharing
with the world the story of the Emerald
Triangle small farmer and where a
multi-billion dollar industry was
created um but I I do feel like he has
and he is going to play a bigger role in
in really helping share our story and um
really Greatful for
him he's yelled out a couple times you
know Ridgeline farms and Huckleberry
Hill Farms on some of his comedy shows
and um when he does that the response
from people is always to reach out and
DM us through Instagram and um so just
really grateful that he even remembers
to say it and that he's still smoking
our weed and really want to uh give him
something really special and and cool to
um have fun with himself and let him
grow his own yeah that that would be
epic to see what comes from from his
little hom grow earlier on in the answer
you you mentioned you were uh involved
with the Willie Nelson crew and I had
seen on your Instagram there was a
number of photos and before I'd figured
out sort of what was going on I was like
what's with the Willie Nelson Obsession
so tell me a little bit about how you
got involved with that crew and how your
work ended up being in some of the jars
of his brand so I started working really
early with uh a company that thought
they were going to be the world's
largest sungrown cannabis company and uh
really went out and started building
their brand by representing small
farmers of the Emerald Triangle they had
five people in their company um when
they first started in uh when they
finally went out of business they had
300 people in their company and so they
ended up raising $300 million and along
that um four years before they lost it
all um they brought on
Brands like the Willies Reserve which uh
really Incorporated Willie Nelson and is
his ideals in there and you know that
team would come up here not Willie
himself but his Willie The the Reserve
team and they would look at all the
flour and then the different Farms that
they went to they would decide what flow
they wanted Willie Nelson to actually
taste and then they would bring a little
bit back to him Willie would taste it
and he was the chief tasting officer so
at the end of the day he would decide
what flower ended up going into his jar
and the first year we grew legally he
picked three out of our four strains and
um you know got to go to some of his
concert got to go backstage and just
really admire that man for kind of the
little bit that I know of him and what
he went through and just his life
Journey really was just truly amazing
and hearing some of his stories and what
he's been through and um just really
respect that person a very lot and was
happy to participate in the the small
amount of time that I was with him our
product also was introduced uh first
year in 2018 at the
Oscars so some of the biggest stars in
the world it was in the gift bags the
Huckleberry Hill joint and you know
Denzel Washington Merill Street and all
them got to smoke a a huckleberry joint
um they never admitted it and they never
showed it but it was in their gift bag
so maybe they gave it away it was
definitely uh a strain that was bred to
the paradise punch I'm I'm not exactly
sure which one it was I think we called
it huckleberries but um it was it was
definitely bread to Paradise punch yeah
pretty cool that that's incredible while
we're on the topic of awards you know
you you touched on it a little bit
earlier you've been picking up Awards
left right and center and I tried to go
over it last night quickly and I might
have missed a few but you've won awards
for your flower your bubble hash your
concentrates your pre-rolls your Vapes
you said many of these but I just wanted
to verify you weren't you weren't being
factious you've actually want awards for
all of those categories I guess the
question is what's the key like some
people can pick up Awards in flour cuz
maybe the strain is good as a flower but
it's often not as good as a concentrate
but it seems like your stuff is just
nailing it across the board like how do
you rationale it's been so successful is
it the genetics is it the grow style
what do you attribute it to
that's a a good thing to recognize um
because a lot of times either a strain
is really good for for rosin or it's
really good for flour and very rarely
I've been told that you find something
that's good for both and and and that
happens to be what white Thorn Rose
really does fulfill is is being both um
demand huge demand for flow and rosin
and all the other different byproducts
that are made from it um I want to say
it it has a to do with the the cultivar
and those Legacy strains for sure but I
I don't also want to take away um
anything from the way a farmer
grows um that flower um you know it's
all about the TLC we don't dump liquid
fertilizer into a into a a tank and and
water it in usually it's all stuff
really from the forest around us if it's
not you know white Thorn or white thorn
Bush mulch or uh Manzanita mulch or um
you know I do a lot of top dressing with
Dr Earth 444 you know everything's
organic everything is kind of natural
but I really like the idea of top
dressing on a plant with you know like a
dry Amendment so pretty much every time
and I I I do have drippers on all the
plants but I hand water every morning
usually in the middle of the summer just
because some need more water and some
need less water and I want to have that
ability not just to turn the water on
and everything gets the same I want to
have the ability to say okay this one
looks pretty wet I might want to skip
this one this time and let it dry out
and so but anyways every time you water
really um you're watering in just a
small amount of of fertilizer so it's
not getting this huge concentration of
this big
green synthetic fertilizer it's getting
all natural consistent every time and I
think the plants just respond to that
better and I really want my
flower good or bad to really taste like
the place that it's grown in like I've
I've shared some of my genetics like
Mom's weed um moonmaid Farms over on the
east side of the county who is somebody
that I respect a lot excuse me
um her mom's weed tastes totally
different than my's mom's weed it looks
fairly similar but it does definitely
taste different and you know ridg line
grows a few of my strains in can of
country and hogwash farms and they're
all really good Growers it's just it
tastes different from the places I get a
little influence a little fog from the
ocean that comes over the hills where
maybe the east side of the county
doesn't and so all these different you
know things that really are attributed
to the Tera is what really affects the
taste along with you know the way you
nurture and take care of the plant and
so um forgot what your question was but
um it's really a combination of the
farmer and that's why I always tell the
consumer know your farmer know how
they're
cultivating really know who they are
inside know if they support to Veterans
and donate to Compassionate Care because
I mean if you're looking for something
that's going to make you feel amazing
that's going to be good for you that
maybe has some healing properties that
can make an ailment that you have go
away you kind of want to know the doctor
that's working on your you right you
want to know who's farming your stuff if
you want to feel the the best possible
way so knowing your farmer is the most
and the best advice I can give to any
consumer yeah 100% if you if you know
where it's coming from it'll it'll make
every follow-up question all that much
easier and I just realized you know
we're talking so much about the white
Thorn Rose but there's probably some
people out there especially those
outside of the USA who have probably
never had a chance to uh try it
themselves just yet so just as a as a
general sort of example how how would
you describe it for someone who's never
never had it I remember when I first
smelt it I thought oh this is like a a
much more complex version of forbidden
fruit like real tropical fruit explosion
really gorgeous sort of fruity smells
how would you describe it to someone who
hasn't encountered it
yet um I would agree with that and uh
you know it's been explained to me like
words like kind of grapefruity like um a
tinge of grapefruit or um the one the I
guess one of the things that I know
noticed right off when I smoked white
Thorn Rose and really went whoa this is
this is something cool is really the
flavor of that joint all the way down to
the very last hit tasted amazing it
wasn't like oh half the joint tasted
good and then the rest tasted sort of
shabby it just tasted really good really
fruity you could put it down and pick it
up and it still tasted amazing and
that's kind of what's lingered with me
and um and most people describe it as
something just that they haven't
experienced before something so unique
and different and just uh in combination
with hearing the story of this place and
how it came to be maybe affects the way
people really enjoy it too and so
knowing the story really before you
smoke it really enables you after you
smoked a little bit to really imagine
the journey that we've been on to get to
this
point certainly so certainly and look we
we've heard a lot about how it really
thrives Outdoors uh the majority of our
listeners I think are probably more
indoor orientated how does it perform
indoors never tried it I love that I
don't know anybody that's ever tried it
inside and so that that's curious there
was there was several indoor operators
that have reached out to me there's been
some big giant companies that have
reached out to me to want to license it
um most of them want to license it so
they can take it down to Southern
California grow it more commercially
like with tractors and and you know I
always tried to explain to these bigger
companies that it won't be the same it's
not going to taste the same the thing
that you think you love about it and the
reason you want it so much won't be
there and you'll probably be
disappointed
so and that's a little bit of a
hindrance as a as a such a small farm
there's really a limited amount of it
that we're growing and yeah I just it
and let uh hogwash farms grow it on his
farm we grow really similar same inputs
he's always coming over here I'm going
over there you know it's like an
extension of Huckleberry Hill over there
and um he's another grower that really
just is very passionate about what he
does so I felt okay doing that and I've
even smoked his and I can't tell the
difference between his or mine so um
yeah so we're just trying to figure out
how to navigate this business and really
make it work for a lot of people and get
it into as many consumers hands as
possible yeah certainly look the
challenges of scaling up is something we
talk with many guests about you've
referenced a few different um you know
really fantastically reputable uh
collaborators in the area and the one I
wanted to touch on for sure is Ridgeline
as you mentioned you know they're
extremely well known in the industry I
think almost every time I've been to the
emerald cup they've come first second or
third in multiple categories they
absolutely C rush it how did this uh
friendship first start and how did it
evolve into the collaboration you're
moving into
now I grew up with Jason who's Ridgeline
and uh it was always kind of a little
battle between we're on the west side of
the county and he's on the east side of
the county so it was kind of the west
side of this Hill Country versus the
east side and who could grow more and
who had the better strain so it was
always a friendly competition not only
drawing weed but with fishing like when
we had our boats out in the ocean who
caught the biggest fish or who caught
the most fish and um once we went legal
and we got a little bit older um we just
really
started relying on one another to try to
navigate the legal market and how to to
run a business and um he's just a really
kind person good heart um good human
being um and our value system is the
same and he just isn't really about
excuse me he's not really about the
money he's about you know making people
happy and and you know having fun doing
it because we only go around once and so
we we're very fortunate to to work
really closely with together we're very
fortunate to have won a lot of awards
and um I'm just as happy for him to win
an award as I am for myself to win one
and um I think it's vice versa too
so um yeah really cool guy you should
definitely try some of his legacy
strains and he's a second generation
cannabis farmer he grew with his dad and
his dad was was hauled off one year in a
a camp helicopter during a raid and he
was coming home on a school bus and you
know he watched his dad he heard his
house was getting raid and his dad you
know was hauled away in a in a
helicopter with you know AR-15s and so
that kind of stuff is traumatized and at
the same time very um bonding to those
people that are um that that have gone
through that with you and so um we have
that much in common and um really trust
each other yeah wow that's that's so
interesting to hear you have that common
sort of experience as a as a young
person being really affected by those
those raids that's that's really
powerful and I guess just to follow up
you know you've got this new collab
that's going down with the Lance and the
white Thorn Rose tell us a little bit
about what sort of things people might
expect to find in those seeds if they're
interested in grabbing
some well um they're they're going to
need to know that it might be a while
because we haven't offered those
particular seeds to the public yet um
you know we we both work with the same
seed company that Tangled Roots
store.com um he has released you know
some award-winning genetics like the
green Lantern um I think his ridg line
runs that one Emerald cup um are on that
site you know and I have a couple
Creations that I released um but really
we want to grow and experiment around
with all these new strains for multiple
years before we you know torture
somebody's Harvest by giving them
something that turns out terrible so
it's still in the evolution process
Bert's going to be part of that process
in pheno hunting
and there's four or five different
phenos of the machine of the Lance white
Thorn rose that we're trying to evaluate
to see which one we like and ultimately
at the end of the day if if Bert wants
to participate he's going to be the one
that really chooses the one that's going
to go in the jar um there'll be a
limited amount of jars and um yeah it'll
be something special it's it's it's
really purple um it's really fruity um
yeah have we haven't tested it you know
in the California labs yet to to really
know how it tests
out but uh yeah pretty excited and
having fun with it
nonetheless yeah hugely we'll we'll all
have to watch and keep an eye on it to
see when it becomes available and you
just mentioned something which really uh
got my brain going which is you
mentioned you know it's fruity it's
purple it's what people like and I'm I'm
interested to hear the thoughts of our
guests about what they feel are some of
the necessary components to make a
strain popular these days and some of
the most recent guests we've had on have
all pretty unanimously said that they
feel like uh for something to be really
commercially popular at the moment has
to have a degree of purple to it whereas
in the past that had fallen off you know
we went through the purple age in the
early 2000s feels like it's coming back
a bit in your mind what are some of the
components that you think need to be
there to hit that current popular
Market um definitely needs to be purple
like purple is in like it could be gone
next year but this year it is like is it
purple that's almost the first question
um you know purple and gassy is really a
popular thing um even though I most of
my strains aren't gassy a lot of
Ridgeline strains are a little bit more
on the gassy side um but what what what
to be honest what has really happened
over the last six seven eight years with
both Ridgeline and and Huckleberry Hill
and even Cana country and hogwash Farms
is those consumers have really built a
trust system with us and so it almost
doesn't matter if it's green purple
gassy fruity whatever we put in their
jars they know has really gone through
our evaluation system or techniques that
they have resonated with and maybe liked
if they continue to purchase our product
so it's doesn't matter what we put in in
our jars so much and what what is really
important for consumers to know is it's
at the end of the day really up to them
what makes them feel good so if you ever
run into a farmer that says I grow the
best that's when you want to run because
what makes me feel good might not make
you feel good our endoc canabo system is
made up differently so Tarpin and
cannabinoids of the cannabis plants are
going to affect each one of us totally
different so I can never say hey White
Thorn Rose is the best but I can say
white Thorn Rose a lot of people have
had amazing experience you should try it
and if that doesn't work maybe pick up
some ridgel line because we're circling
back to knowing your farmer and really
the most important thing to know is how
they cultivated the product that you're
about to put in your body and so really
that's the most important thing yeah
100% you you got to know how it's grown
and uh you know I forgot to mention
earlier I'm a DI hard organic Sky myself
as well so so it's beautiful to hear
that's how you do it out of curiosity
when when Brands like yourself are just
so highly prized by the consumer base it
can actually be almost hard for people
to get their hands on the product what
sort of reach does your product have at
the moment is it fairly limited because
there is such high demand in the local
area or what's your thoughts on your
reach at the moment it it is very it is
very limited in how far south that it it
kind of able to reach um more so just
because I work with a a kid Chris
Anderson with redwood Roots who um
started a Distribution Company and the
state of California makes us go through
distribution companies to sell to retail
right so um I wanted to work with
somebody that I trusted somebody that
you know I grew up with and um Chris is
that that person and he has like three
people in his company he only has the
ability to you know drive the van down
to to La once in a while so it doesn't
even really make it to San Diego there
are companies like Nabis that give the
farmer the ability to you know pay
monthly fees and to do this and they'll
deliver anywhere in California within a
couple days and and that's an option um
but I'm trying to give Chris with
redwood Ruth the opportunity to to
figure it all out and to kind of be on
the journey with us and or us be on the
journey with him and and figure it out
together um yeah so it's we we sell out
all of our product
all luckily every year unfortunately a
lot of people in San Diego and a little
bit in in La don't get a chance to get
it unless they come
north yeah fair enough but you know what
like it's it's a testament and it's
almost like uh good for brand promotion
because you know I'm sure you've learned
this yourself if if people have to work
hard to get it they're going to Value it
more someone from La driving up your way
I'm sure they're just going to be riding
High the whole way home because it just
makes it that little bit extra sweet
that they put the effort in but I want
to loop back to your breeding just for a
moment um and just talk a little bit
about like the future you know we've
mentioned the the collaboration with
Ridgeline runs but I wanted to know
what's what's your sort of um Vision
moving forward with the genetics and as
a quick followup is there any new
genetics or just things that you've seen
recently that you're thinking oh I
wouldn't mind in incorporating that into
some of my
lines yeah I you know I did a this last
year I did a few different
collaborations like the one with
Ridgeline I also did a project with you
know everybody wants to participate
luckily with the white Thorn Rose and so
I'm pretty selective on you know who
those people are and you know it's
usually people that I grew up with and
um one of those peoples is is Ted Blair
with Cana country farms um who also has
a lot of award-winning cultivars some of
them that only test 16% like the Cana
country 26 that won quite a few Awards
too and so I had smoked some of his Cana
country 38 and all his are numbers right
because he doesn't want to give them
names until he pheno hunts the ones out
that are amazing and then he'll name
them different
So currently we're all just on numbers
but um Cana country 38 was one that I
tried last year something that he bred
at his place that I don't even actually
know the cross with but it was so
amazing and so he brought me over some
pauland last year and we BR it to the
whitethorn the whitethorn rose and uh I
did a little feno hunt in my garage this
this winter with along with Ridgeline
and um that's a really amazing one and I
think we're going to call that Country
Rose um kind of like the Sun or the song
and then you know can of country country
Rose and thought that was an amazing
name and if if Bert doesn't end up
naming uh or want to participate with
the machine we're going to name that
Ridgeline Rose and just put the same
product in a different you know with a
different name um because we think it's
amazing and so yeah for this year um I I
don't have any big plans this year yet I
would love to cross the white Thorn rose
with the Cana country
um and yeah I guess we'll see we always
we always kind of midseason after we get
everything planted then focus our
attention on okay what am I going to get
and what am I going to breed to and um
there was a lot of uh demand for the
white Thorn rose that we cross with
rs1 I I sold out on all those seeds
within a like three or four days I never
even grew any of them like I don't even
know they could all be winners um so uh
probably I'll do that one again maybe
keep a few for myself to grow um but
yeah I don't I don't I'm not yet I
haven't pivoted to to being in that
mental state yet to to figure out what
I'm going to cross but going to
definitely do it no that that's awesome
and as like a bit of an extension of
that and referencing what you just
mentioned I I noticed on sites that that
sell your uh seeds there was actually a
nice variation of crosses there and
there was ones like you know that used
the mom's weed um and and a few other of
those Legacy strains but as you just
referenced there was also some really
modern stuff like some rs1 cross white
Thorn Rose I was wondering is this a
conscious decision to do a bit of both
or does it just happen to work out that
way that you do a bit of the hype stuff
a bit of the Legacy stuff I was doing a
little bit of the hype stuff because I
got some of those um those clones from
friends of mine that were growing those
commercial strains and so they always
had extras and I said hey give me one of
those RS 11s or give me one of this or
give me one of that um and then I also
had you know some leftover mom's weed
that I was able to breed with kind of
was second guessing myself on was that
the right move to let the the mom's weed
cross with Paradise P like there's a
winner in there somebody's gonna have to
find it somebody's gonna have to hunt it
and I'm am really having a great time um
sharing that journey of other people
that I don't even know phenoh hunting my
strains that I haven't even grown before
like um there is one that we found we
did a little pheno hunt last year of the
paradise Pine that we did release too
and I've been watching this guy that I
don't even know he he's been showing me
all the different fenos that he has
growing indoor and there's some just
amazing ones and and we actually Cherry
Picked a couple really good amazing
Paradise Pine here that we're doing some
um rosin with entered it into the
emerald Cup this year with a company
named iy who that really takes a lot of
pride in what they do and they always
use a lot of our white Thorn Rose too so
um keep an eye out for Paradise Pine I
think that's a sneaker that's going to
be another staple uh cultivar here that
we grow at Huckleberry and in hogwash
farms and this year uh I actually am
sharing some of those genetics with
another really really really good farmer
called uh mat sunr and uh mat Valley
sunr and that's Dylan mat he's been out
at um over the mountain for 50 years on
that same piece of property so should
check him out too he grows amazing stuff
and um really good guy too yeah that
that's awesome to hear Paradise Pine
everyone keep your eyes out for it it's
it's going to creep up while we're on
the topic of genetics I wanted to just
quickly throw it out there are you much
of a sativa guy yourself or you more
just into the indicas no I I prefer
actually like a you know most of the the
strains that we're doing nowadays are
like hybrids so you know there's a
little this and a little that and but um
the Margie magic is a a really cool um
strain it's more of like a a sativa
hybrid and I really enjoy that from time
to time it's you know got that really
cool um after taste it's it's more of a
like a jack herrer um blue dreamy um and
I either find that people really love
Margie's magic or they're just like
really burnt out on it like that was a
strain that was more in the 80s that was
really something that we just we did so
much of that it just kind of overwhelmed
people they didn't even want it any more
so a lot of my friends say oh that's the
charity no we don't we're don't we don't
want any of that but um a a lot of uh
the Reta the consumers at the retail
level really love Margie's magic and we
grow uh we grow 15 pounds of that a year
we put it in a thousand different
quarter jars and that's all we do a year
and that's what we're going to do we
don't do too much we don't do too little
we just that that's a staple thousand
jars that's that's brilliant You' you've
just reminded me because you know you
you referenced how that one's been
around for quite a while I wanted to
just quickly loop back to when you were
younger you you mentioned your early
experiences with cannabis helping your
parents in the garden and sort of having
that really organic introduction to it
all I forgot to ask you what was the
first strain you ever actually smoked
was it one of the ones you're working
with now or just one of the ones back
then it was uh it was one called Fruit
Loops that my original the one you know
um my mom was Catholic and so she was a
even though we grew pot it she was her
her her parents were really straight and
you know really strict
and even though she wasn't super strict
and we moved up to the country and did
our own thing um you know I didn't
really drink in front of her and I
didn't smoke in front of her but you
know every so often maybe I you know if
a bud fell off one of the plants into my
hand and you know I took it and to a
party or something um you know that's
what I first experim experimented around
with was was the Froot Loop strain wow
that that's so cool that you you're
still smoking on you know the The Strain
that you first ever puffed on I guess as
a out of curiosity we we talk about this
idea of like genetic deterioration over
the years have you noticed any
difference in it yeah I was just going
you read my mind um because yeah I think
um there was one point that I did notice
a little deterioration I don't know if
maybe you know there's things called
russed mites and Broad mites and now
they have uh ex hop Lon vir vroid and
you
know even though I've been able to avoid
a lot of that stuff because all the Gen
I don't really take genetics in here
except maybe an rs11 and um there was
one year I took one strain in that I did
some breeding with that maybe I
introduced something that maybe affected
some of my plants and so I I did start I
had some Paradise punch seeds and I did
restart a whole bunch and I pheno hunted
one that I thought was exactly the same
and kind of started over and I think I
think I ended up with the better end of
the deal I think that after that long of
cutting off those this the not the same
mother because I'm always making new
mothers but I do think there was some
kind of deterioration and I haven't ex
explored too much around with doing like
tissue cultures which I heard can
Revitalize that and and help with that
and don't know a whole lot about that
kind of stuff and um but I'm I'm really
happy with where they're at and I feel
like the genetics are still really
strong and um maybe I'll have to explore
that another time but I I always have
these seeds of of kind of those genetics
and I could always reeno hunt something
real similar or something that I really
like so yeah yeah certainly no we we've
spoke to many guests who have done
similar things maybe they make some s1s
and rehunt something from there and it's
certainly an issue people encounter when
you when you're maintaining genetics for
such a long period of time I I was a
little bit curious and you may not know
the answer did your parents ever talk to
you about where they got the genetics
from because they must have been getting
some of the early stuff I imagine
right yeah that's funny um yeah so when
we moved here um you know we got some of
those genetics um from our neighbors and
stuff and um you know there was all this
variation of different there was like so
many different phenos and basically my
mom found one that she liked and don't
exactly really know where it kind of
came from or who our neighbor got it
from but ended up with that and it ended
up being pretty stable and we kind of
utilized that and then named kind of
considered it ours after a while and
there is um one other genetic we called
it the uh the number 21 and um it was
one when my dad was out partying pretty
hard and I was a really young kid he had
taken me to a friend of his place and
they were rolling up a joint and a seed
had rolled out of the Rolling tray into
the bottom of this box and I was really
I think I was like nine or 10 or
whatever and I had picked up that seed
and put it in my pocket and took it home
and then we started it and my mom said
oh yeah we'll try that and it ended up
being amazing and so we made a bunch of
seeds out of it and long story short I
still have like um trell ended up
remodeling his house and in the wall of
his house he found a bunch of those 21
seeds that I had given him 40 years ago
and so he gave those back to me I've
tried every different technique to try
to get one to pop get one to sprout I
can't do it I have like maybe 15 of
those left not wanting to keep trying
because I had so many failures of so
many like waiting for somebody to have
some kind of new advanced technology
that can scoop the tissue out of it and
and Revitalize it but I remember that as
a kid just being another amazing just
great strain so I'm hoping somebody
either has some knowledge that I don't
yet or can steer me in the right
direction or something develops
so yeah 100% I think there's a there's a
lot of people waiting for that sort of
what do they call it the uh the
artificial embryo to sort of come out
and to to help bring back some of this
killer old stuff and you know Kudos Fe
to recognizing that we just need to hang
on to these last ones and wait till we
get the right Tech at hand if we fast
forward back to sort of the modern era
from you know having a bit of a
reflection on the past I'd love to ask
you a lot of the guests who come on the
show talk about how over the past say
five or more years there's been a big
Market shift for people wanting almost
exclusively feminized seeds when you
talk to Growers do you notice any clear
preference over regular versus feminized
and you yourself do you have any
preference so I do you know with the SE
with the little seed business do see a
greater demand for feminized seeds just
because typically I think people that
don't have um a lot of experience it
just eliminates a step for them from
making a mistake right you know they
know it's a female they can do it but it
also for my friends none of us grow
femin seeds like they they're a little
bit um it can I should let me say this
differently it can they can be a little
bit unstable and you know they can shoot
out a little you know male flower here
or there or I've had some little
disasters happen um with femin seeds
before so none of us really grow our
whole crop we might grow one or two
feminized seeds and there are some you
know breeders like humble seed company
that really has done a lot of
experimenting Nat and and hie um have
done experiments with that a lot more
and have refined it to really isolate
some of those staer genetics where they
they're pretty successful at it um I
don't think I've graduated to that point
and I would really hate to to ruin ruin
somebody's crop so the only feminized
seeds that I do are ones that you know
I've played around with that I feel very
comfortable with but I still don't
really grow those or too many of those
on my farm now that's understandable and
um as as a follow-up i' love to ask all
of our guests without being able to know
anything about the grower because I know
that the intuitive answer is oh I'd want
to talk to them a bit but if you could
only recommend one of your strains to
someone and just think look this is an
allrounder most people are going to be
really happy with it what would you
recommend to grow yeah to grow Paradise
Pine there you go you're you're solid
Paradise Pine there's a 100% not even I
mean I'm growing two of the the very
exact seeds that I'm selling on the
there is I I I'm I'm I'm almost I'm not
greedy I want people to grow amazing
strains there's a winner there's
something that's better than white Thorn
Rose in those Paradise Pine seeds I I
know it I feel it I when I smoked the
rosin that was made out of the paradise
Pine um I had believed and because the
emerald cup got pushed back that um
Paradise pine rosin from ippy was going
to Dethrone the white Thorn Rose and um
I I still believe it it is a very unique
flavor um and I have pheno hunted the
very one that I like it does it is a
pretty good yielder for the the
manufacturer so they're pretty happy
with it and um I got really high host
for it white Thorn Rose seems like it
will always have a place here on this
Farm it is unique it's it's some
people's favorite strain ever and they
have said such kind words to me that I
would never not want to have it here to
offer to them um and it's really just a
reflection of my mother and her kindness
and really who she was as a person and
so um I feel very honored to have that
and feel lucky that I stumbled upon it
and I probably don't really truly
deserve
it oh look I I think you deserve it you
you put in the hard yards you've you
know sacrificed part of your life for
the community I I think there's there's
no doubt you deserve that but just to
follow up you mentioned you know that
you you smoked the rosin and and it just
signified to you that we're rering in a
new era almost uh I love how how you
know how memorable that was for you I
get the growing feeling that
concentrates are going to continue to
dominate the market in terms of what
people are looking to consume my
question for you is is that something
you're thinking and will you be
considerate of that going forward or do
you think I'm just going to keep
breeding the way I'm doing now if it
happens to work well for concentrates
that's great but you know not the
primary focus where do you sit on
that I'm really truly breeding for
concentrates now um 90% % of my farm
goes to concentrates but 90% of my farm
is split up between 8 to 10
manufacturers next year it'll be split
up between 10 to 15 because I like to
see their different techniques and I
like the um what that creates for me the
ability to get it to more people and um
the flower that I do grow here will be
flower that I put in my jar and so where
I fear for most people with concentrates
is
that um I think the industry as a whole
is kind of utilizing concentrates to
really get rid of their subpar product
because you can transform it into uh
product that maybe's not uh well formed
into a flower that can be put into a jar
you can put it into make it into a
concentrate and it kind of all looks the
same right um when when we do
concentrate especially with the white
Thorn Rose here we do Whole plant
concentrate so when I'm selling um our
fresh frozen to uh manufacturer like I
harvest the whole plant they get
everything they get the tops they get
everything um because I want that rosin
or that bubble hash or whatever to be
the best that it can be and um I don't
know what truly affects that so I don't
want to take the chance and and have any
kind of negative effect so they get
everything they get the tops they get
everything I don't go and top all my
plants and then give all the the lower
stuff to the manufacturer they get the
whole plant and and they can take part
in it they can be here and do it with me
however they want or they see it when
you know they're washing it and stuff so
um I think they all appreciate it and I
think it does end up being a better
product So eventually I I don't know if
the consumer how well the consumer can
tell the difference but I think there's
a fine line
between really good flow and and flow
that's okay and and the same with rosin
and um I know a lot of Manufacturers are
trying to drive that price point down
you know we keep the white Thorn Rose at
135 flat rate per pound and I think a
lot of you know companies are trying to
you know there there slim margins out
there so if they can find some subar
stuff for $50 a pound or $40 a pound you
know it maybe that more beneficial for
them and um I just I just haven't worked
with those kind of people because that
can't you know help my farm survive so
we just are the higher end
right yes sure and I want to loop back
and and talk about the pricing but
before we go there I just want to
quickly ask the discussion around indoor
versus outdoor cannabis has evolved and
for the longest time it was always
indoor Supreme it's the best um more
recently I feel like there's a lot lot
more Credence given to the idea that
outdoor can produce a much more shelf
stable product in the long run as well
as arguably a superior tpine profile how
do you rationalize the difference how
would you explain it if someone who said
oh I don't really know all that much
about cannabis what's the difference
between indoor and outdoor what would
your answer
be um I think the same reason you don't
buy your vegetables that are grown
underneath artificial light is the same
reason you shouldn't buy your cannabis
grown underneath artificial light I've
grown a lot of indoor in the the the
traditional days um when I was younger
to avoid the helicopters and invoid uh
avoid um enforcement um and I think
there was some amazing indoor back then
um but what I know now is from doing
experiments with Columbia University and
really
identifying um the different tpine
profiles from indoor and outdoor um
really
understanding that the the heads are a
lot thicker um grown outdoor because
they're subjected to the the wind the
the rain the weather and um because of
that um influence from the weather those
tpen are able to um last longer in a jar
they're they're they have a thicker wall
around them I don't know what that I
forgot the name of the actual wall
around the tpine head and so I just
learned a lot about uh the difference
between Sun grown and outdoor through
Columbia University and the different
cannaboids and learned that you know a
lot of us are relying on these testing
Labs that test for maybe 20 or 25 tpin
because that's what the standards are
that's all they have to test for by the
states standards and through Columbia
University I learned that white Thorn
Rose had 444 different cannabinoids you
know never even knew of them had um over
60 different tpin so there was there was
35 to 40 different chin that were never
tested for and what we figur found out
was that I kept wondering how white
Thorn Rose can be so amazing and smell
and taste so amazing and then the
turpine um percentages was always coming
back 1.5 1.5 well because they're only
testing for certain CH pins well white
Thorn Rose has certain tpin um that
aren't even tested for and so that that
works negatively against with the
California labs and um once I found out
it had 60 different chir Pines um
especially one called Selena dying um
that really has some ability to cure a
lot of different ailments um really made
a lot of sense to me and so if you have
smoked a lot of cannabis and now we're
hearing people like burner from cookies
who is was strictly about you know
indoor cannabis starting to really
highlight and work with Legacy Farmers
without door and you know he works with
Ridgeline now with his Lance um and
really just had him here at my farm and
you know had him not on video saying it
but he said sungrown way better you know
the Entourage effect um the amount of
how long that um Entourage effects last
last a lot longer smoking outdoor um and
you know it'll affect each one of us a
lot differently but um I think like you
were saying before the consumer is slow
starting to figure out that even though
it's not this rock hard tight OG Bud
that we were always educated that that's
what determins it being the best um and
it looks a little fluffier and it might
be a little bit um shaggier or looks a
little different it can still make you
feel amazing so um I always encourage
people to smoke
both hugely that's that's really cool to
hear that uh as the kids say uncle burn
was around the farm that's it's good to
hear um I was just going to ask you know
cuz you mentioned talking about the labs
giving you these uh tpine readings of
like 1.5% and tpine percentages have
become such a focal point of what buyers
base their purchasing decisions off
these days and um you know likewise the
same is said for THC percentages what's
your thoughts on the future of that I
feel like although it hasn't started yet
I feel like we're getting close to a
point where people are going to start to
accept that that the numbers they see
for tpin or THC content is not
necessarily the entire story where do
you see us in regards to
that yeah I think I think they're
figuring that out and I think they're
also figuring out that the labs are are
pretty inaccurate and you know you're
seeing stuff like 710 Labs tested um
from the same batch their flower did you
see that and like I think it the THC
levels varied from 14 % to like 25 or
26% um and that's how inconsistent the
labs are because what happens is that
the labs really only have the ability to
make their business work if they
generate you know test from the
Distributors and so if they continually
give low THC scores it really makes it
hard for those Farmers to survive so
you'll switch Labs so it it's
really it behooves the labs to those
Farmers higher THC scores because then
you go back to them and you use them
again and so you can generate a lot of
business by continually just turning the
dial up a little bit and at the end of
the day probably 90% of the people can't
tell the difference anyways and um you
know it's my belief that the consumer
starting to understand that the tpine
profile and the tpen and the THC and the
cannabinoids together really um give you
different Entourage effects and it's a
little bit more complicated than reading
you know a number on a jar and um I
think once they experiment around with
enough strains and come back to knowing
your farmer again um they're figuring it
out it's probably not as fast as I had
hoped but um yeah they're figuring out
they're pretty
smart that's yeah look that's awesome to
hear cuz I know certainly some of the
the older strains may not produce quite
as high numbers as some of the more
modern ones but are still able to stand
up side by side not to interrupt you but
what really ends up hurting the uh the
educational process are things like the
state fair and and I'm Ambassador with
the state fair and so I'm going to try
not to say anything too negatively about
the the way they're going about it but
as they're developing and trying to
educate people they're they're not
really helping the cause because um you
they're they're basing their Awards on a
co-a test that's done by a lab and
they're saying things like um this is
these are the best growers in California
or this is the best flower in California
and you're you're coming up with that
conclusion by a lab test that we already
know is completely
inaccurate so like I've been pushing
back to them I think you know any
Contest out there has to be you know
they have to touch and feel and and
experience the flower or the rosin or
the gummy or whatever they're they're
they're ex you know entering the contest
with um and so I don't know um I'm
having a little issue with that yeah no
look I I too would take issue especially
as we just said you know given the
variation that 710 pointed out is it
even within their own metric of how
they're grading things is it even
accurate it by the way they think
they're marking it which may not
necessarily be the case you know and and
then you get into the the more minute
details of like well let's just say it
all is getting tested by the one company
so there's some amount of
standardization there's it usually comes
down to the way the individual
technician processes the bud sample and
then loads it into the hlc so it really
is like you know a bit of a quagmire to
to wander into but I think I think we
are we're both pretty much on the same
page that it's should be more about
effect and um how it makes you feel than
than any of the numbers but you said
something really quite profound a little
earlier on and I have to loop back and I
wanted to talk a little bit about you
within the marketplace as you know a a
medium/ small to medium siiz farm and
how you're able to still be profitable
and so I I guess the first thing I'd say
is you know you mentioned earlier you
were the fourth existing Farm in hanbul
County to be fully permitted uh what was
that process like you know was it was it
really difficult and how many Hoops did
you have to jump through excuse my
language but it was hell um and it's
it's hell for a lot of uh my fellow
Farmers too um you know you're talking
about a bunch of regulators that know
nothing about weed that really are
trying to capitalize on um the
marketplace that we built in the
traditional era and as they're learning
as they're going um it's been brutally
painful for many of us um compliance
wise to to to bow down to some of the
things they're asking us to do like
weigh every plant wet and then weigh
every plant um dry and then keep track
of all the waste on that plant and then
reway the flour and then keep track of
the trim off of that flour and like
they're making us do so much work
because they think they have the ability
to keep track of
something we can waste out in one one
click of a key on the keyboard and say
it molded um they have no ability to
control what we're doing and they should
really give into working with us instead
of trying to control us and I think
that's where they're making a mistake
and and we do take do some Educational
Tours with the DCC who's a regulating
body of of this industry and um you know
they always are very nice people that
work in the industry and they seem
genuine and want to help but
um man it's just so slow everything they
do and yeah they agree with us but they
just take years before they actually act
on what they know to be true and
um I just try to take it with the grain
of Sal we're a small enough Farm where
tagging every plant isn't a huge
deal
um yeah I don't know there it it cost a
you know cost a fortune you know for
many of us to put in rainwater catchment
ponds to fix our roads to fix our
ditches to change out coverts um and to
do a lot of things that they were
thinking was helpful um that now they
think isn't help didn't need to be done
and you know they have uh like moonmaid
Farms I was talking about her Farm was
logged in the 80s and when part of her
permitting process she has to change out
25 coverts on a piece of property that
was um that she bought in the 2000s that
really was logged in the 80s that all
these coverts were put in so like these
are roads that are never used but since
they have the ability to kind of
control the properties once they're in
the process they're really trying to I
don't know punish us still or I'm not
sure what what they're gaining or what
the benefits are they they're really
destroying the whole cannabis the
California Cannabis industry is quickly
failing and they're starting to realize
that now most of the small farmers are
are really struggling and you know
they're they're not making money they're
you know if they're if they're still
around they're maybe breaking even or
surviving and you know a lot of my
friends are going going away
unfortunately
let's touch on that in just a second but
you you actually made a really profound
comment there about how the regulatory
bodies are worried you're going to make
you know a bunch of the crop disappear
and say it molded and it's really
interesting to hear that because I think
a lot of the discussion around that
issue is actually far more targeted
towards the massive like multi-state
operations and the people I talk to have
the suspicion that um a lot of the
flower that is subpar or is just excess
from some of these big like multi-state
operations ends up in these black market
you know New York little um Bodega being
sold on the corner sort of thing like
that's what they think is where all that
Supply is coming from do you have any
suspicions about that and do you feel
like the regulatory bodies are targeting
the wrong people if they're worried
about you doing it when really there's
10 million hectare farms and seemingly
all their product just you know it's not
left over well they're absolutely right
that's where 90% of the weed goes I mean
you if if you're not participating in
that market and I'm not saying anybody
does but if if you're not you're not
making it in California so it's it's
it's in my opinion that they understand
that it's happening since there's only
enough retail stores that they've given
licenses to to Really distribute two to
three million pounds in packaging but
yet they've permitted enough Farms to
produce 15 million pounds this year so
where do they think the other 13 12 or
13 million pounds are going to go they
know there's nowhere it can't go
anywhere and you can't lose that much as
a business or you would be out of
business so I think they understand that
it's happening and I think they're being
very lenient about that now because if
they enforce too hard on it the whole
industry goes away and then what it
makes them all look really bad that's my
opinion I could be way off base and
could be wrong but I would put a lot of
money on that I'm absolutely 100%
right yeah you're right and God wouldn't
that be egg on their face if they
regulated their own industry out of
existence I never thought of it that way
but that's it and right they have so
many they they've created so many
different sub businesses like the
regulators and uh you know the retail
shop inspectors and they have they've
created this huge industry enforcement
and as farmers are going away they still
have this many people right so if
they're not generating that money all of
a sudden now California is running at a
deficit and with the Cannabis industry
that they created now is costing them a
fortune and like at one point or another
they might not even be able to have
enough people to actually run it they're
in a they're in a pickle right
now yeah and and it loop back to the
point you made just a question or two
ago about how you were saying you know
many of your friends are finding it
really difficult to remain in the market
the the the comment you made that's
really lasted with me is
um how you said that you keep the price
firm of the the white Thorn Rose for 135
a pound and so you hear someone and just
to clarify I'm talking about 135 for a
wet pound so it's really a five to one
conversion right so um it ends up being
like maybe seven or $800 dried trimmed
pounds go for about 500 so so to put
that in perspective I guess the the
reason why I bring that up is it does
beg the question you know how how do
people stay in businesses when the
prices are so low and and the price you
just reflected is one of high quality
where there's a bit of Premium sech
charge you know you also referenced a
$50 wet pound you know is it like is it
is it even financially possible to stay
in business if that's the prices you're
able to fetch um only if you're
avoiding paying their
taxes okay so it's not sustainable if
you're diverting no it's not yeah that's
the answer it's not sustainable unless
you maybe flirt around with the gray
areas I'll put it I'll put it like that
that's crazy so I guess what do you
think is the future of sort of the mum
and pop businesses is is the entire
model under threat the I think the
entire model is definitely under threat
unless you're pivoting and really
building your small business model with
the only pathway forward I see and I
don't know everything I'm not a great
business person I'm just a farmer but um
really found a lot of momentum with the
white Thorn Rose and really think that
most small farmers should highlight
those Legacy strains that strains no one
else in the world has and I and I always
say that and it sounds redundant but
just the sound of it creates a little
mini demand for for it whether or not
it's great or not um you know they just
think that we can't compete with the
commercialized strains or will'll never
make it and um if you know you're not
going to make it you know you want to
Pivot earlier than later and trying to
make something and then if it's not
going to work then you can become a
fisherman or
something yeah look it's sad because
there's a lot of you know incredibly
talented cultivators who probably will
end up taking up an alternative
profession and just all of that
knowledge and wisdom will sadly be lost
for the most part I guess with that in
mind what do you think would be the most
important sort of message you could give
to someone who's just trying to get into
the market or maybe is in the market but
struggling a bit what should they focus
on or or what do you think people could
do a bit better that would help their
brand um well what we did and I think
maybe not even purposely but what
benefited us the most was you know our
farm is small enough it's those in
between Farms that um your farm too big
to work yourself or work with your a
family member that you need to have
employees which then requires you to
have workman's comp and all these other
expenditures that really eats at the
bottom line you know it it's uh it's
really up to me and Rose my girlfriend
we do all the work you know I'm out here
at five o'clock at night I'm planting
flowers I'm you know work cutting clones
I'm doing all the stuff so um you know
it's a little bit harder on having any
kind of freedom but um I think you have
to limit the amount of your expenses um
your overhead really um you know I don't
have uh I don't have high-tech automated
depth things I don't have you know all
these high-tech expensive things I kind
of limited my overhead and and it's
really allowed me to produce a pound
that maybe I sell for $500 maybe it cost
me $250 $300 to produce like I know
moonm made Farm was telling me it costs
her $600 to $700 a pound that she can
only sell for $500 so that doesn't make
any sense right but she had to have she
had a big enough she had like a half an
acre so she needed employees and they
were doing depths and so I do one crop a
year um I have 65 outdoor plants and
then I have two green houses which you
know I don't have too many plants in
they get so it's it's all manageable for
me and my overhead isn't that big and if
uh if yeah it's just really up to me and
Rose so um keeping your overhead low is
I think key and not trying to B expand
you don't want to be too big now there's
no reason none of those bigger companies
are making it you know they're all
failing you can't you can't more isn't
more less is more and then just focus on
educating people about who you are and
your story and um that's the where the
real value is I
think yeah 100% And and that's some some
great words there more is not always
more I like that so I think that just
about brings us to our our tail end of
it where we do our five quickfire
questions we love to ask all guests so
the first question I'll ask is what's
the single most memorable experience
with cannabis you've ever had it doesn't
have to be like the most potent dab hit
you've ever done but like you know maybe
you're at a concert the music was just
hitting right like what's the most
memorable experience for you most
memorable experience or the most
impactful experience I think I ever had
was um several years ago I got an email
from the warden and from the guard of
the prison that I was um housed at for
over six years and they reached out to
me and um they felt so bad that somebody
that was growing a plant would get that
much time and they learned who I was and
they they knew I would never heard
anybody and they asked to come to my
farm and they came up to my farm spent
two days here and at the end of those
two days um of showing them around of
watching them you know federal prison
guards and wardens in playing with the
plants they each took six of my plants
my my unique cultivars home and today to
this day they still grow those cultivars
at their their house in in Lomo and they
they already called me this year and
just even last week I just sent them
seeds of the paradise Pine and so um to
realize that all of us no matter who we
are can make a difference in somebody's
life whether or not it's a prison Garden
a pot grower um or whatever um I think
that's
really really an amazing thing and it's
just always on my mind and he calls to
check in on me to make sure I'm okay and
that's just it just seemed so farfetched
and not even real that it just it just
impressed me that they could come full
circle like
that yeah compl completely full circle
and and at the core a message of love
which is absolutely beautiful on the
other end of the spectrum what's a
strain where everyone around you was
hyping it up telling you oh man you got
to try it and you finally try it and
you're like ah is that all gush
Ms not the first one to say that yeah I
bet yeah um yeah you know it lasted a
year or two around here and then it was
over like they just rotate through
strains that are hype strains and um
gush minz was one of them and I was not
impressed there you go okay next
question is I'm going to drop you off on
a desert island you've got the resources
to grow plants for the rest of your life
but you can only take three genetics
with you can be either three clones or
three packs of seeds if you prefer seeds
maybe do a bit of breeding what three
things are you going to take with you
I'm going to take Paradise Pine I'm
going to take white Thorn Rin I'm going
to take Mom's weed oh brilliant there
was no hesitation I love that that's
good no absolutely yeah perfect okay
look we might already have the answer to
this one but I want to ask you anyway
this is one of our new ones we've been
doing let's say under crazy
unpredictable circumstances your your
house burns down but as you're going
through the rubble you see one pack of
seeds preserved perfectly in the dust to
restart the company with what pack would
you hope that would be what would you
want to restart the company with if you
could only pick one pack I would have to
to say Paradise punch my original strain
I used to go with my
mom that was what I was thinking okay
cool yeah there you go there you go
brilliant okay final
question I have a time machine for you
you can go back anywhere any place to
presumably collect a clone or some seeds
where you going to go what are you going
to
get you
know I don't think I I I do anything
different and maybe I go back in time
and and maybe save some of those
original 21 seeds that I was talking
about that trell found in his wall and
and maybe try to breed with those and
and preserve those because I believe
there's some magic in there somewhere
and I feel like that is something that
I'm yearning to to to restart or to
refigure out so um yeah I'm going back
in time I'm getting some of those 21
seeds and I'm I'm keeping them alive and
I'm keeping them around that's
absolutely brilliant I love that answer
I have to imagine as a killer strain uh
we we'll all have to wait for the
artificial embryos to see what's inside
those last few you got so I think that
just about brings us to the end of it
for things today was there any comments
or shoutouts you wanted to
make nope I just uh want to tell the
consumer you know really
ironically coming full circle from you
know the War on Drugs to now it it's
it's really in the hands of the
consumers whether or not the small
farmer makes it or or not and not to put
any pressure on anybody but when you
walk into your real your retail store
please ask for small sungrown cannabis
and you know that you're supporting a
family farm like mine many of those
families have kids and many of those
people care about you more than you'll
ever know beautiful I love that message
so again a massive massive thank you to
a humbal native career grower breeder
operator of Huckleberry Hill Farms a
massive thank you John taking the time
to come on the show today well thank you
so
[Applause]
[Music]
much so what do you think guys a massive
shout out to John for taking the time to
come on the show and a massive shout out
to you guys for supporting
us if you love this episode please
consider supporting both the patreon as
well as Mr ni seeds check out the new
website shanyar seeds.com as well as the
websites of our incredible sponsors if
you're looking to transition from
combustion to vaping check out our good
friends at D aath you will not be
disappointed cheap affordable and
Incredibly efficient units likewise
check out our friends at Pulse sensors
if you want to make sure that your
garden is dialed in and you are tracking
all of the variables that are going to
ensure your next Harvest is the best to
date you got to get yourself a pulse
guys it's a
no-brainer in order to ensure that your
garden is pest and page and free please
check out our friends at copit they are
the number one in bior predatory
technology the spyx vital sachet have
been Game Changer the slow release of
spider spider will make sure that your
garden is spiderm free copit thank you
so so so much for your
support likewise a big shout out to our
friends at Organics alive for all the
most incredible powdered organic
products usable in all systems both
organic and hybrid people winning cups
around the globe with their products
it's no surprise because the quality is
second to none a huge thank you to
Organics alive we recommend them highly
please check them out if you want to
take your organic game to the next level
finally massive shout out to our good
friends at seeds here now they got heavy
days beans go check them out guys I
promise you will not be disappointed
they' got all the latest drops the
hottest breeders fem Auto photo period
CBD whatever you need they're here to
help you out a massive thank you to our
friends at CT
now and big love to the patreon gang we
love you so much thank you for
supporting the show they got Early
Access to this episode over a month ago
you want to get extra content please
consider supporting the show you'll
score yourself genetics a whole bunch of
swags from our sponsors and so much
more so that just about brings us to the
end of it for this
one big thank you to you for getting to
the end yet again and for the
support Big Love is always from your boy
heavy
days signing
off see you
[Music]
w