[Music]
hello and welcome to another episode of
the podcast the Cannabis podcast for
Buddy
enthusiasts as always you're joined by
your boy heavy days here from the upside
down library and as usual we want to
give a massive shout out to all of our
incredible sponsors who help ensure the
show continues to happen seeds here now
number one seed bank in the industry all
the hottest breeders the latest drops
everything you can look for and more
whether you're after indoor outdoor
feminized regular autoflow they've got
everything under the sun to keep you
loaded on all the hottest genetics
producing the most fire Bud you've ever
had I hear they've got some incredible
lines from heavy days still in stock if
you want to go check that out make sure
to do it before it's too
late big shout out to ctnl we appreciate
you you so much likewise if you want to
produce the best bud to date you've got
to make sure your garden is pumping on
all cylinders and for that we recommend
our good friends at Organics alive they
produce the number one powdered organic
products that will ensure your next crop
is the absolute best to date people are
picking up cups all around the globe
using their products which is the
highest Accolade you can get hom Growers
just like you producing W winning
Harvest what more could you ask for
they've got Solutions whether you're in
veg transition flour they've got
micronutrients macronutrients absolutely
every product you could want ferment and
more check them out guys Organics alive
your number one stop for all of the
highest quality organic inputs to make
sure your Harvest is killing
it likewise you got to make sure your
garden is pest and pathogen free to
ensure that your plants are happy and
producing the highest quality Harvest
for that we recommend you check out our
good buddies at copit they've partnered
with us for a long time and we have no
doubt that if you use their product you
will find they are the absolute best in
the game you've got to check out the
spidex vital plus breeda sachet these
are an absolute game Cher it's the usual
spidex vital you know and love that's
going to take out any spidermite
problems you have but the breeda sachet
allow a continuous sustained release of
these beneficial Predators into your
garden ensuring that you don't just have
one big burst and surge but instead a
consistent rate of release truly a game
changer I expect nothing less from the
experts at copit biological you know
these guys are world leaders they're not
just in America they're all around the
world and for good reason they are the
Pinnacle of the game if you're after
biological Pest Control check out copit
number one thank you so much for the
support the final piece of the puzzle to
ensure that your room is killing it is
our good friends at Pulse their sensors
are second to none industry leading and
just recently they announced the pulse
hub what more could you want an
integrated unit for all of your sensors
to ensure that your garden is automated
and tracking all of the variables you
may not be consciously aware of from VPD
to ppf dupoint temperature humidity so
much more you've got to get yourself a
pulse sensor guys it has revolutionized
the way I grow flour and increased the
tpping content the cannaboid content the
yield so so so much more shout out as
always to our friends at Pulse sensors
likewise if any of you guys have been
listening to the show you know that I am
passionate about helping people
transition to vaporized options if
they're considerate about their
respiratory health and for me dap are
the world leaders in this dap helped me
to transition from bongs to vaping and I
tell you what I've never look back their
unit is the most potent the most highly
replicating of a bong hit I've ever come
across and through their incredible
munit I was able to successfully get off
bongs a few years ago now truly one of
the most Innovative and interesting
Vapes on the market using a totally
different design to others you have
found please check out dap I promise you
guys if you've tried vaping before and
felt like it didn't quite cut it check
these guys out you will not be
disappointed massive shout out to dinat
thank you so much and last but not least
we want to give a massive shout out to
the incredible patreon gang without you
guys we could not continue to make
episodes if you want to get early access
to upcoming episodes exclusive content
just on the p patreon including the
likes of mean Jean Bob hemp Bodie Tricom
jungle so much more be sure to go check
out our patreon we give away genetics
every month to our supporters along with
artwork Vapes sensors so much more
please check out at the patreon guys I
promise you you won't regret it you'll
get your money back in swag to helping
supporter show you love thank you so
much to everyone from the patreon we
appreciate you so
[Music]
greatly and on today we have a true OG
of the scene an early contributor to
numerous magazines winner of High Times
best Garden of all time award as well as
having contributed some incredible
genetics to the scene that you've no
doubt heard of the likes of ultraviolet
purple kush I'm sure you've heard of
that one a massive welcome to K of
triome Technologies for taking the time
to join us today share a whole bunch of
his knowledge and boy does it span a
long period this guy's probably
forgotten more than I know I'm
incredibly grateful to have him on the
show today so without further
delay let's get into it all righty gang
we're back for another episode and on
today we are grateful to be joined by
one of the ogs of the scene a prolific
author an incredible cultivator a
fantastic breeder and truly a head's
head a massive massive thank you to Ken
Morrow of triome Technologies for coming
on the show today how you doing
very well sir thank you very much
appreciate you uh inviting me and having
me as a guest uh the pleasure is all
mine I I appreciate you having you on
and I guess the question I'd love to ask
you is we do all guests what have you
been smoking on
recently um let's see so I live in
Northern California so I've got quite a
um uh a laundry list of uh
availabilities so to speak uh friend of
mine runs a company called yosity
cannabis company and he grows all
organic outdoor cannabis and
so I enjoy getting pot from him so
that's what I'm smoking at the
moment Ah that's incredible are you more
of an indo or is Tava
guy um depends on the time of day you
know what I mean is uh uh more than
sativa or indicia normac clature
classifications uh I I have uh uh you
know uh I like high cannab uh cannaboid
contents at night low cannaboids in the
middle of the day in the in in the early
parts of the morning and um then you
know getting into my favorite uh tpine
so to speak I like beta careline I love
black pepper and there's certain Tarpin
that I kind of seek out in the cultivar
so more so than the sativa indicia
references I I I look for chemical
ratios you know that's incredible I I
love the the breakdown even just as you
said you know high cannaboid in the
evening lower in the day I just want to
quickly follow up that comment about the
turpins first do you feel like you
gravitate more towards W tpine profiles
than say any other individual
aspect um yeah because the flavor and
the smell is uh
probably I'll even say 50% of the
pleasure I gain from Cannabis or hashish
either one um so I've always you know
besides just the high I enjoyed the
different flavors and nuances and smells
and that that part of it fascinates me
and that gets into the chemical ratios
and differences of Tarpin that's really
what differentiates one from another as
well as you know sulfur based thols and
a few other
chemicals yeah certainly and look let's
let's uh pause the th there for a second
cuz I want to come back but I want to
quickly ask you first cuz I was talking
to a few grower friends the other day
and they asked me they were like you
know you hear people talking about tpin
bit of caropine you know smells like
Peppers you mentioned things like that
and they sort of said I don't know if
I've got like my base palette down in a
sense they were like people talk about
mirene for example and you can often
hear quite widely varying descriptions
of what it smells like and you know I
think in a sense it sort of for some
people it can just come down to you need
someone to like put a plant in front of
your face and say this is what a merine
dominant plant smells like or something
like that so my question to you is how
would you advise people to try to
develop their nose if for example they
don't have someone who can be like
here's this PL and it smells exactly
like talene or you know how can people
start to get that reference
down so I recently wrote an article that
basically addressed that subject and and
so more so than you know saying buy
buying a a bottle of pure uh pinene
limine or whatever have you um you know
what is your favorite cannabis and and
go Analyze That send that to a lab or
you know there's there's so many um um
lab reports available in other countries
where it's legalized that that try to
find a lab report that tells you what
what is the turpine ratio in your
favorite cultivar and you might find
that that there is dominant tpine and or
a few and and that would be a good place
to start I I explained to people that
you know there's something called like a
wine journal or a wine diary if you were
to go to a famous wine region and buy a
given bottle of wine you know maybe
there was uh uh something that
fascinated you or or or or made you
prefer that and and you would write it
in your journal and then when you got
home after a while you would start
seeing some similarities you know maybe
it was a certain mixture of Mero and
Cabernet or maybe it was French Oak
maybe it was American oak or those
outside influences that really make up
the totality of that wine after a while
you'll find a preference you know what I
mean something that you prefer uh uh you
know a 6040 ratio of a Cabernet to Mero
or again French oak versus American oak
or you know you you'll you'll probably
find that there's characteristics that
you prefer and I believe that's to be
the same in cannabis uh you know so so
so find the Cannabis that you find the
most appealing and then try to find the
characteristics that are in the contents
of that cannabis what's the dominant
tpine and what's the T the the the the
can cannaboid ratios does it have CBC or
thcv or you know what what what are the
nuances figure out the nuances and then
try to find similar and like strains or
cultivars if you will and and and
perhaps that's that's the path
yeah that sounds fantastic you know like
follow what you're interested in and
that's going to give you some answers
and there's so many little Avenues you
just you spoke about that we need to
follow up on but I guess the one that
I'm most interested in talking to you
about is you referenced wine a few times
in that answer and I wanted to ask you
to what degree do you think we will see
a mirroring of say elements of the wine
industry and the Cannabis industry you
know people often talk about they want
to establish these production appalaches
and um really promoting the Terre of
certain regions I think at this point we
sadly aren't there yet you know like the
majority of a lot of uh the highest
quality production is generally
considered indoors though there are a
vocal group of people who is very you
know um big about supporting outdoor
what do you think we'll come to see in
uh the coming 15 to 20 years that will
mirror the wine industry in
cannabis um well there's there's a lot
of misconceptions there and and you know
where will where will it end up up I I
believe it'll end up just where I said
uh people will have preferential uh
cultivars ratios be it you know similar
to CBD and THC ratios akin to Cabernet
and Mero levels or something like that I
want seen a uh a comic and and and it
depicted a a gentleman on the phone to
his local grow store and he was placing
his order so to speak and and he ordered
one bag of Humble County Tera and one
bag of Menino Tera and I just I still
find that funny as hell because if you
really get into Tera and and and you
know there's
appalation um there there's uh you know
other things that denote where a wine is
produced but when you get into Tera a
wine grape in a given Appalachian there
there's no outside influence there's no
nutrient application there's no uh you
know uh the influences that the the
Cannabis has cannabis has nutrient
applications a wine grape doesn't so you
know to to to truly say that you are
extoling the the properties of an
appalation of a given region of a
cannabis plant would be to plant it in
the dirt water only and never give it
food and that's never going to happen
you know what I mean so you know then
then you get into the uh environmental
aspects of it you know is it a a cool
region a foggy region is it a rocky
region uh iron rich and those other uh
outside environmental
influences uh are are are really what
makes up the characteristics of the
final product more so than um a a a
so-called Tera you know what I mean
because because it terat isn't really
appropriate term the second you add
nutrients or amendments to the soil
because that's not what happens in
grapes you
know yeah certainly certainly and I
think I have come across a few farms at
least on Instagram on face value who say
they're trying to do that even a few who
go so far as to say they're trying to do
like dry farming and you know like just
natural rain only but it does remain to
be seen if it's like actually a viable
option and then uh maybe you could start
to assess if there is some degree of TOA
there you you mentioned in the last
answer that your friend was growing some
organic outdoor I love to ask all the
guests what's your preferred style of
growing if you have your choice are you
like an indoor cocoa and salt Sky you an
outdoor organic what's your preferred
setup if you had your
choice
uh hybrid uh supplemental Lighting in a
greenhouse um I have uh been fortunate
enough to meet some of the largest uh
commercial tomato growers in the world
that do so with uh no compromise of
quality so to speak you know what I mean
so they're just not spitting out
flavorless to tomatoes and and in fact
he handed me a tomato from his
Greenhouse one time and I kid you not to
this day it is the best damn tomato I
ever taste it you know what I mean and
it's not just because he's my friend or
I I prefer his methodologies but it's a
fact and and you know it's uh you know
he's in um not really using supplemental
lighting because he's in a preferential
location but if I was going to be in a
preferential location um I would use
supplemental lighting for cultivating
cannabis in a greenhouse large scale
commercial yeah I wanted to ask you
about that because you know you're
you're well known especially you know in
a in sort of 10 uh 15 years ago for
being a pioneer of like scaling up
commercial cultivation tell me a little
bit about what it's like to grow on the
sort of scale you're referring to
because I think both myself and many of
our listeners um probably you know for
better or worse uh kid ourselves at
times and think oh you know I've I've
got Mastery of this tent I could do a
greenhouse you know what are some of the
issues you come across on scale that
just simply aren't present on the the
smaller hobby level well keep in mind
when I was uh doing those commercial
cultivations that you were talking about
that were so famous and fluid in those
magazines I was facing a 20 to5 to life
sentence because prop 215 wasn't even
enacted let alone prop 64 so it was just
all illegal you know activity um you
know even going back as far as when I
did 60 Minutes television show in 1996 I
I had already been arrested in 1993 and
was facing 25 to life if I got caught
doing that interview so there was the
mindset you know um it wasn't I didn't
go large and and do those commercial
levels out of um you know uh money or
you know uh what what what ended up was
uh to to get a lot of data you have to
do a lot of plants and when especially
when you're breeding I bred over 200
different cultivars so when you start
breeding that much and and and taking
that many clones by default your plant
go count just skyrockets you end up with
2,000 4,000 and then if you got 4,000
what's six you know what I mean there's
no really you know 25 years or 50 what's
the difference you know what I mean so
you know but then after a while it was
like you know the the cultivation
techniques and the information available
you know especially when there was no
real internet so to speak um I mean
there was but there there there wasn't
as free and open as it is today um as
far as marijuana cultivation information
or anything else so it was still books
and papers and and magazines
Etc so you know um you know it was just
uh to to to answer my own questions uh
you know what happens if and scaling up
and and you know those nft systems that
I built and then you know okay well nft
does this that and the other thing with
rock well then what about fog ponics
what about you know organ organic
amendments uh you know because uh you
know you mentioned salts versus uh
Organics it's it's you know very hard to
get Organics to go through a drip system
and not end up clogging it you know so
so then inevitably you end up with two
if you're you know um trying to
incorporate organic uh amendments you
end up with the drip system and hand
watering over the top with your organic
amendments so you can get include those
Etc but I think I went off track with my
answers but no I love it it gives such
colorful context to your your story and
we're certainly going to loop back and
and cover you know chronologically your
journey because it's so interesting but
I guess one thing I still wanted to hunt
down from that last question was what
are some of the challenges you face on
scale when you're growing thousands of
plants versus say maybe you know 80 to
100 at home in a room skilled labor and
time you know what I mean being able to
manage everything especially you know if
if you're the one uh paying the bills
you know physically going down to pay
the pg&amp; bill etc etc uh if you're the
one physically doing deliveries of the
product to The Dispensary if you're the
one procuring materials uh to you know
uh uh continue the process you know uh
if you're a Onan Shan there's onean show
there's only so many hours in the day so
when it was illegal activity um you know
you had to watch who be very mindful of
who you trusted um now that it's legal
you there's there there's you know
there's unions there's there's you know
there's uh you know legitimate places to
hire skilled labor yeah there's there's
college courses being given now at AR
you know multiple colleges in the United
States so it's it's much easier to get
labor um skilled labor should I say and
and and much easier to deal with than an
illegal
entity yeah certainly I mean did you
were you able to get any help back in
the day or was it the case that you just
had to do everything yourself no I had a
handful of very good friends I I
wouldn't be where I am today without all
of those friends and and you know there
were some of them that are just aren't
here today that were you know invaluable
and stuff I had a Japanese gentleman
named nooro zaha that is uh passed away
from kidney disease not too long ago
that was you know basically you know he
was a tried true Soldier you know I mean
you know there was a little bit of a
language barrier but one time he asked
me so I you know I I should shoot at him
if they come in here and I'm like shoot
at who what are you talking about and
he's like if the police if the police
comes here I should shoot at him and I
was like no no you do not shoot at him
don't have a gun don't do any of that
stuff you know it was like but yeah um
the level of dedication was very
impressive but yeah I had I had a
handful of friends uh actually a big
handful of friends I'm I'm
I'm uh 59 years old and throughout my
life I've had a lot of
friends wow that's that's incredible and
it must speak to your own character to
have had so many friends over your time
and and shout out to your your friend
who passed away recently sounds like a a
real OG the sort of guy you'd want on
your team so let's let's go back a
little bit and uh and roll this out in a
bit of order so tell me you know what
was your first grow when did you first
start
growing I first started growing when I
was uh just turned 13 years old um a
friend across the street his dad was a
dealer so I just caught the tail end of
say uh the the hippie era the the the
the the the hash trails and stuff I
caught the very end of the red lebanes
and the blonde levian and the the the
the Panamanian and and you know just
started you know the 80s began the uh
influx of the uh black Afghanistan hash
that was lower quality but I got to
experience a lot of the end of the the
era so to speak and it kind of
fascinated me that you know people went
to prison and and and put their lives on
the line for this plant and stuff and I
I grew up I was born and raised in Napa
Valley and wine country and then lived
in other agricultural based communities
so I knew you know plant production and
plant growth and stuff and new kids that
you know Liv their life off farming and
so you know my mom had cutting and the
the the the the the kitchen window like
anybody else that rooted and stuff and
things and you my parents work for the
government and they didn't really want
me out and about um doing you know
illegal grows in in the the the the the
surrounding areas so they preferred that
I do it at home so I was able to at a
very young age grow in the backyard so
you know I was able to you know get
Colombian marijuana seeds and plant them
and see them grow and fail and fall over
and not enough life trials and
tribulations there was no books there
was no information and if there was no
one could sell it to a little kid you
know and then I seen an ad in High Times
that offered something called a hydrop
poot and it sounded magic so you know so
I bought that um and it was basically a
bus boy tray uh it's in my book there's
a picture of me standing there next to
it a bus boy tray with a lava rock in it
with the AirStone bubbler and it came
with a little packet of um Miracle Grow
and uh yeah it worked it grew and and
that as a 13-year-old kid sparked my
fascination with Hydroponics and
cannabis growth and everything related
um and then you know I was telling some
the other day I can distinctly remember
and could take you to today the exact
spot where I was standing when I seen
seedless cannabis uh what we would know
today is um it just it completely
fascinated me um as well as the first
time I seen a concentrate in 1980 a has
soil concentrate that was of part
today uh tell me about both of those you
know what was that first herb you saw
that was Sensei did it have a name or
I'm guessing it was just back at the
time where it was just like the kind or
something and also tell us about that
concentrate and it was uh well both
happened about 1980 a new guy moved into
town um and he brought this cannabis and
showed it to me and it had these it had
a when it did have a seed it was huge it
was like you know to me it looked like a
a watermelon you know what I mean it was
absolutely huge with these Jagged black
uh lines it was completely different
than any kind of um sativa or thin Leaf
cultivar uh seed that I had ever seen it
was just this gargantuan seed um but you
you very rarely got one um the G the the
the person that sold us the pot ended up
telling us he'll give us 25 a seed to
buy them back so anyway um I asked that
guy where'd you get that and he you know
and can you get more and he said yeah he
could get more and because when I was
young um I I I was a TR have always been
trustworthy so older yeah and and and
kind of um hung out with older uh kids
uh uh one of my best friends was you
know almost twice my age and and so my
mom would let me go hang out with them
and stay as long as I stand out of
trouble you know what I mean uh and so
you know uh so knowing him um I I was
you know afforded the luxury of seeing
lots of different cannabis and stuff
like that so when the new kid came to
town and I asked him if he could get
more of it I I knew adults that sold
cannabis so I knew if he could get more
that those adults would want that
cannabis so he said yes he could get
more and there was a a school program a
occupational program for auto mechanics
and and it took you like three towns
away and you went to their auto shop and
you learned all day and then you came
back to town and so that town was the
same town that he could get the
marijuana so I said well let's get on
that bus and let's go to that town and
let's get that marijuana and we went
there and we got a pound and this is in
what ninth grade and or grade nine
whatever you want to say and then from
there we went to uh uh you know got got
front at a pound took it to my friend
bod's house and said here look and he
went how much for that we said $2,200
and he said okay boom and so we got it
for 2,000 we kept 200 each
100 each and and brought the the the
main guy the money back and started
doing that at like n ninth grade um you
know and none of the adults knew where
this stuff was coming from but it was
just from me and him and his connection
to his dad's
friend and then one day a guy named rust
armmer came over my house and he had
some what he called hash
oil and he said do you want to buy some
of this for $25 a grand which which was
a very high price back then then again
1980 and before that sorry this is a
three four P part story um I had a
childhood friend and and maybe he didn't
tell the truth all the time he stretched
the truth quite a bit um about fishing
and all kinds of stuff and he came over
one day and he's got a brown paper bag
full of marijuana and it was like hey
Phil where'd you get the marijuana he
was like it was by my trash and it was
like so and we lived in a small again
agricultural town and
so the probability of someone sneaking
marijuana on your trash back in 1980
when that could be a felony a felony
amount of marijuana on your trash it
just didn't make sense so it was like
yeah sure so you know rolled a joint of
this and smoked it and got nothing but a
headache it was like wow this is
terrible and it was like maybe if you
smoke a bunch more of it it'll be okay
and and it wasn't and so we didn't smoke
more more of that and so a couple weeks
later he came back with another round
paper bag and it's like you know it
wasn't buds it was just all all ground
up and it was like what's with this you
know didn't couldn't couldn't figure it
out and then his older brother one day
was sleeping and uh there was a banging
on the door and he went to the door and
it was the neighbor and the neighbor
said can I put something in your garage
and he said I don't care and went back
to bed and then a couple hours later
there was more banging on the door he
went to the door flung the door open and
the local police department are sitting
there and he's like I didn't do nothing
and they're like we know you didn't do
anything Randall uh get your get your
pants on and come outside so he went
outside and he could see Dolly marks
from the neighbor's house going to his
house and then he looked over at the
neighbor's house and the neighbor's
house is on fire and they're they're
they're cutting a hole in the roof and
putting that out and the firemen are
there and stuff so he opens his garage
door and inside is a wooden crates full
of siloc cybin mushrooms and the other
wooden crates are full of honey oil and
he said thought that's not mine and they
they said yeah we know that's not yours
Randall but anyway so apparently the
hash oil that I got um and the horrible
marijuana by the trash came from the
neighbors that were making honey oil
back in the day um I sitting right next
to me I can tell you what year what
address exactly where this was I someday
want to go find a police report so I can
go and this is an odd tale um so I was
told that the person was out of
Australia so um yeah um a guy named Phil
or Phillip and supposedly Australian and
again why would he be doing this in that
location way back then it didn't make
sense but um when I first sampled that
first concentrate I mean it it wasn't a
chlorophyl nasty hash oil it was a
golden you could read through it Amber
flavorful strong as hell for a kid uh uh
hash oil that was every bit worth of $25
a gram and I spent I spent 25 to 30
years trying to find something of that
quality and never found it until today's
modern uh extracts became available so
to
speak wow I mean what a what a testament
to the quality of the extract that was
being produced in like the ' 80s like
how why do you think and how do you
think he got the knowledge to be so
ahead of the
curve I think it was just you know it
wasn't a super knowledge or anything
else with the basic chemistry degree and
and availability of the chemical I
believe probably what he was doing was a
quick wash with with ether and and then
just doing the evaporation of The Ether
out in the backyard you know and and and
hence that's where the fire came from
and when it all went to hell but I I
don't think it was anything
sophisticated there was no no glass
square no lab or anything else I think
it was just take marijuana soak it in
ether and evaporate The Ether real quick
without you know um letting it soak too
long and pick up any um any kind of
chlorophylls or sugars or fats or waxes
and da da da da da I think it was just a
quick
wash wow that's cool to hear and I I
guess you know the natural followup is a
lot of people uh very reminiscently
remember their first dab or concentrate
hit was that the experience you had it
went straight to my pleasure Center you
hear people in in in in addicts in
Rehabilitation talking about their drugs
of of choice and how it just went to
their their their core their their their
nerve center their brain it was again it
wasn't just the the the high it was the
flavor and the smell and and everything
about it you just that that it resonated
with me and that became my drug of
choice even though I I had no
availability of
it yeah wow look I I certainly as you
were saying that I went back to the
first dab I ever took and it it does
right it hits you in that uh that
primordial part of our lizard brain as
they say but um while we're on the topic
we had a a fan submit a question which
was that they said oh look I'd love to
hear a little bit about the evolution of
extraction from K and maybe a little bit
of a rundown on his current methodology
of how he makes
extracts so I I can give my perspective
from my bubble in Northern California
let's start there so you know there
there was a book called cannabis Alchemy
or or marijuana chemistry um by Starks
or David Hoy um that talked about
isomerization it was the same book with
different covers and you know slight
different
um and and that was the first book I
ever seen that talked about concentrates
and and before there that there was a a
red oil comic book that talked about uh
and I still have these things um um that
talked about a red oil that the
government had made and then I got the
the the government brochure on their red
oil which is basically just you know raw
dirty black hash oils um so uh uh I I
got the book and the book said you know
um to basically get cannabis grinded up
put it through a
a a cheesecloth and press it into a
apply heat and next to a fire and and
and twist it in a ball it was obviously
from someone looking over the shoulder
of someone that didn't speak the
language didn't know the questions to
ask or didn't know what was taking place
there so so it was convoluted all I got
was a ground up ball of marijuana you
know what I mean so it certainly wasn't
H and so but I I didn't understand
anything about like res glands Etc you
know it was just dipping into the um era
of the mid 80s where you know uh
Northern California was reading good
genetics with high resin contents before
that it was imported pressed you know
you never seen a triome kind of sort of
thing you know so on once I started
producing high resin content plants and
then started breeding and then as I said
the numbers climbed exponentially
with with with a rise in the amount of
cannabis there was a rise in the amount
of waste and you're looking at this trim
with all this good resin on it and
asking yourself well you know what do I
do with this you know and so you know
after a while I started taking it put it
in the you know not drying it trimming
it wet putting it in the freezer and
then uh getting silk screens on a big
big bowl and then just slightly slightly
swirling them before they would defrost
and then dumping it and doing that like
for 12 hours straight and and the
resulting powder that I got was the most
incredible dry sift that I had
personally ever had in my life so that
right there became a fascination of mine
was you know how to make dry SE hash and
you know that was probably in um
1989 um you know and then I started you
know trying to automate it with
vibrating boxes and things trying to
scale it up and things but it never
really came out as well as I could get
with a fresh frozen hand trim you know
so that that became my focus for quite
some time then um let's see so uh then a
after that uh you know I just started
you know again bigger screens more
cannabis uh you know scaling up scaling
up and at that point you were just doing
hand pressing and stuff and things later
on they like uh mil Jensen produced a
pollinator which automated things uh but
only had one size working screen you had
to refine and clean the resulting
product after that and then so you know
that that I wrapped my head and you know
got fairly good at at dry seing and and
um uh me I I wrote an article and um it
was edited and uh cleaned up so to speak
and co-authored by Mel Frank one of my
Heroes and and someone I respect
immensely um and so that was prob that
was in the year 2000 um and it basically
that they told how to do dry seeve um
and that was for High Times magazine and
then also I had gotten a piece of paper
in
from someone that got let's see so the
piece of paper I got from Ed Rosenthal
who got from Neville sh and mocker from
from Super City the seed club and
and uh he got that document from uh sadu
Sam or Sam the skunkman and basically
this document onepage document it's on
my Instagram page you can see the the
the original document there and it was
originally sold in High Times magazine
as an
instruction and so it basically said
take cannabis put it in a blender uh
blend it gently quickly and then
uh SE out the the floating part and
collect the uh sinking part in a coffee
filter and basically that was the the
early stage information and early stage
of water has uh
technology and so from there I I I you
know uh try to scale it up then you know
did did you know ridiculous stupid
things you know what I mean like you
know um used a a a a a paint stir to try
to you know uh you know so you got a a
uh a chiller instead of using ice to
drop your temperature of your water you
got fresh frozen material in there and
you're trying to keep it uh the resin
gland solidified but trying to separate
it without um using the bulk of ice and
also the damage of ice so you know it
made sense to like try a a painer which
was far too aggressive and and put far
too much particulate into the into the
the final product etc etc but yeah you
know I had no sources of information and
and so this is how I you know went
through the process of elimination of
what worked and what didn't you know in
the in the end you would just uh use the
water chiller no ice and hand or that
you know and and so but I was doing
fresh frozen you know way before it was
a term or or being utilized um and so
that article also went into the same
article with Mel Frank it taught you how
to dry seeve and it also taught you how
water hash but and the year 2000 um and
those are both uh on my Instagram page
you know you can see what what year what
uh issue you know uh everything I say
I've got publish proof kind of sort of
thing um and at that point there wasn't
um uh water bags or or you know any of
those products so I just told how to do
it without those products and those
products came out very soon after and
you know took off and and exploded um
from from there you know I I was still
fascinated by those those I loved dry
seeve hash don't get me wrong water hash
uh
secondary but I but I absolutely loved
that original oil and I wanted to get
back to that I had had oil since but it
was all chlorophilia dirty black some
nasty extraction and and and certainly
wasn't close to the original that I had
so then I started asking myself how to
do that da d d d da so you know that
gets into you know fairly you know Roto
Vapes in chemistry I had the the luxury
of meeting a gentleman that was um doing
Roto Vapes with ether on the hillsides
of Kabul Afghanistan in
1983 wow and boy that's some some hair
raising stuff oh funny story there that
they were kids they were from Berkeley
um and and one of them had a chemistry
degree so they they they went to Kabul
and they were shipping all their their
materials there their rot of Vapes their
their ether ET
Etc and they said one time that um the
the winter times get very very cold
there and so their ether was in the
basement and and so someone went down to
the basement and somehow they sparked
off a the the the the cans of ether had
condensed because of the cold and Vapors
had filled the basement so when they
went down to the basement they sparked
off this explosion and it blew you know
all the windows out started a fire and
stuff so everybody rushed down the hill
and they went to the local um um the
coffee restaurant down in the Flatlands
so they could sit there and stare at
their house burning after a while it
went out and nothing really happened but
they noticed like people were walking by
and staring at them and stuff until they
finally stared at each other and they
realized all their hair was singed and
their eyebrows and and everybody had
soot looked like they had been burned up
so pretty dangerous but yeah the Soviets
C the Soviets came in and they stopped
doing that um another funny story they
told me was like uh on on one side of
the valley they had their lab and and so
and on the other side they they had
their their source so one day the source
shows up at at at their spot and and
he's kind of watching what's going on
and he's kind of dismayed and they're
like what's wrong and he was like see
your guys there and he's like yeah and
he's like they they've got these huge
bricks of hash and they're they're
they're scraping them over screens so
they could particulate it you know what
I mean and expose the surface area for
extraction for ether you know and he's
like you see on the other side of the
valley and he like yeah and he's like I
have my guys over there pressing it into
those into those blocks he's like he's
like you mean you could just give it to
us in in in gunny sacks so just raw
resin he was like yeah yeah yeah save us
both a bunch of time so I found that
amusing but but I I didn't want to do
ether you know um at that time early in
the days ether was a um very forbidden
um substance because it was used
utilized in the the the manufacturing of
methamphetamine so in California it
probably wouldn't be a good idea to go
out there running around trying to buy
ether so and and plus I'm not I'm not a
fan of the flammability of it and etc
etc so that wasn't the path I wanted to
take um or or even ethanol and Roto
Vapes it just seems so backwards you
know and and and the the distillate that
that It produced just really did nothing
to fancy me the turpine content was
destroyed etc etc by the heat so from
there um a friend was talking about the
the petrochemical companies um how they
utilize something called a cracker and
how they utilize that to to to make um
petroleum and basically what he
explained was a tube um that you push uh
butane through and then very quickly
after that you started seeing stuff in
the Bay Area called wax uh from ear wax
because it was all brown and looked like
ear wax and it was all sticky and nasty
what a horrible term but that stuck you
know um later on um well that but uh so
so then people started making the the
the butane extracts and stuff and um
pushing it through you know they didn't
know any better uh I wrote an article
for rede magazine called uh Captain
butane I didn't write it I told Nick how
to write it but but it basically you
know told you know how to do the nasty
process of pushing butane through a PVC
pipe you know which was revolutionary
for the time you know um you know later
we learned that you know that's a bomb
and it's poison and you shouldn't do
that but
until then it made some fancy product um
so you know people started doing that
but very quickly it started getting into
closed loop systems and and and the
industry shifted gears before this the
glass bong makers were about to go out
of business because nobody wanted a
glass bong with the invent of dabs and
the dab rig it reinvigorated so many
Industries the Cannabis industry it it
it it it took off like I've never seen
before I remember the first time showing
Mel Frank a a Cannabis Cup in Los
Angeles and you know one day they were
smoking weed the next day they were
smoking dabs it was just that fast and
they've got blowtorches and it was just
like what in the [__] is going on here
he was just blown away as well as I
remember in Richmond California walking
through into the cranway Pavilion with
Mila Johnson the first time she seen the
whole dab Scene It just blew her mind
you know what I mean it was just you
know it was just it was overnight you
know it just it just just
exploded um
then uh the but before that I I started
in um cannabis culture with Dana Larson
and and Mark Emory I read a small little
quote about somebody making something in
Canada called butter bu u d d r i later
learned his name um and spoke with the
gentleman he was fascinating he uh was
very kind and and told me everything
that I answered all my questions and
told me exactly what he was doing at the
time and basically he was doing a quick
uh um wa alcohol wash and then
collecting the um residual and and um
evaporating the alcohol and whipping the
uh final concentrate into something that
he termed butter and it was bright
colored not dark in color it was
absolutely fascinating
um and and
so uh combined that uh butter um with
also um a um
a let's call it open blast article that
I wrote for High Times was called The
Art and Science cleaning concentrates
part one and part two part one was all
about the quick wash and how to make
butter part two was all about you know
how to do you know I introduced the term
uh thin layer evaporation winterization
and uh vacuum drying oven to the
industry in that article you know nobody
was talking about these terms but you
know from from you know they were just
open blasting but now you take the open
blast you e you add ethanol then you
wait for the uh butane to dissipate then
then you're able to now take that put it
in a freezer winterize it solidify any
of the undesirables the lipids the fats
the waxes and all that kind of stuff
then you're able to filter it through a
coffee filter and get a much cleaner
purified concentrate and so then after
that I seen a ad for a video um that um
was called medicinal alchemy.com and it
offered a video and I later was
introduced met the the person
responsible for it and it was an
interesting little video and an
interesting little method but it it it
basically showed you how to take a 2 L
bottle uh take the top roduce a um uh a
valve to be able to introduce butane put
your product in the 2 L plastic bottle
introduce your butane shake it around
then then filter that out into a another
vessel glass vessel um and then
introduce your your ethanol and then
winterize and then he was spreading it
out on a glass sheet and and letting it
slowly evaporate and then scraping it
with the methodically scraping it with
the razor blade and and coming up with a
you know a almost clear concentrate what
fascinated me most was when I heard him
drop that that piece of concentrate onto
a glass dish it made a pinging sound
telling me it was hard like it wasn't
sticky it wasn't anything like that it
wasn't gooey it was hard like a glass so
then this video said that it could show
show you how to make butter and glass
and shatter and things and so it was
fascinating to me but you know once I
got behind the curtain and seen the the
the rudimentary
methodologies then it made sense so was
like oh wait a minute there there's got
to be ways to scale this up so you know
basically with a Clos Loop then then you
get into the winterization aspect of it
and then you know um the utilization of
a uh vacuum drying oven you know instead
of uh drying it on a piece of glass and
you know then then I taught myself all
these things then I contacted AC cross
international who made the the vacuum
drying oven and said hey I uh uh you
know I'm contaminating my oil and things
are going arai and then and got one of
their technicians who was about to quit
on the phone and he said oh what you
want to do is you want to upgrade your
plumbing you want to do this you want to
do that blah blah blah blah blah and
then I said well in your literature
somewhere it mentions this thing you
know and he was like oh we don't sell
those and he's like but here's where to
get one you know so you know I went and
got this apparatus and I attached it to
my vacuum drying oven in between the
oven and the pump and uh you it would it
would build up with ice and then so when
I tried to because of the moisture um
and so the the residual moisture from
the alcohol left in the the the the
concentrate from the winterization
process so when I tried to get that out
um it would contaminate my pump oil so I
put this uh device in and when I went to
to drain the device I got hit in the
face with the smell of tping so very
very strong and it was like oh wait wait
wait maybe you don't want to throw that
away so I started methodically
collecting it over and over and over and
over and over again and then after that
I put it into the The Ice I let it melt
and then I put it into graduated
cylinders and so um I was able to with
the the the graduated cylinders let a
layer thin layer of essence oil float to
the top and separate the essence oil
from the top from the hydrosols and SE
separate the two and so you know um I
basically taught myself how to do um uh
turpine isolation and then it made sense
that it's like well I could do that with
a fresh frozen flow and capture all the
tpin or or or hops or any other uh plant
material uh I could uh take that and
collect the Essences that are typically
lost to the drying process or that are
lost during um the the the recapture of
the um hydrocarbon in a closed loop
system and so I I could capture all
those those tpin um and so and you know
put them in a bottle unlike ever before
and so that that that kind of fascinated
me right there and then so then you know
looping back in today I just finished an
article I write for cannabis business
times and uh somebody wrote a question
saying that they expected a much larger
Harvest this year than they have room to
dry it and so there's you know
technology and apparatuses that some
don't know about that are available
right now like uh something called a
Cyro Mass it's a um liquid nitrogen
freezes the Cannabis the Cannabis goes
into a uh uh vibrating seeve and the
seeve separates the resin gland from act
the active ingredients from the
undesirable green vegetative material
call it biomass so it can do this by the
ton you know what I mean so so it
eliminates you don't have to dry the
Canabis don't have to cure the Cannabis
don't have to hand trim the Cannabis
don't have to have a place to store it
buy a whole bunch of dehumidifiers or
any of this stuff or employ the hundred
people to trim this or anything else you
take the the wet fresh frozen plant
material and you separate the desirable
material from the undesirable material
and then after that you put it through a
static apparatus that separates
the uh any kind of particulate that went
through or any kind of uh
uh triome stocks or immature glands um
it separates the undesirable resin from
the desirable resin but it it does so
the desirable resin still has multiple
sizes so after the the static separation
you'll go back into a vort with multiple
screens and then you can separate by
size and and so then you've got whatever
size desired you know uh triome size
separated that you want so that that
right there is how I believe because now
you've got the the the resin gland in a
55 gallon drum and that you can press it
into rosin you can do hydrocarbon you
can do ethanol extract you can use it as
just an active ingredient and a product
that you're trying to develop you know
so you know I I I advise like you know
someone that wants to take down 20 acres
you know take the the the desirable
cream of the crop the whatever you
destined to be hand trimmed as flower
the 10 15% the best of the best the rest
of it should go immediately into uh uh
storage and be it fresh frozen and then
taken out as needed and and separated uh
as as active ingredients to to
manufacture whatever you know from your
baked goods to your your Vape carts to
to anything in
between wow what a what an incredibly
comprehensive rundown of both the
progression over the years as well as
you know that technology I have to admit
even I haven't heard of that and it
sounds like it's almost like an
all-in-one automated process in terms of
taking fresh cannabis and ending with
highly refined and segregated sized uh
glands there's so many things we'll have
to touch on I'll have to give you like
four or five questions but I guess the
first one is do you foresee that as the
the future of um the production of
concentrates in that you've got this
process like do you think that type of
um Machinery will become common place
and as a quick follow-up what would be
in your opinion the best use of those
glands what's your preferred method of
consuming uh concentrate well it just
stands the reason that that's the way
the the industry has to shift because
already it's flooded you know um the the
the the retail Market is basically
flooded um so so know you you you can
lower your cost of production but
typically that's done at a compromise of
quality this is a way of of of of of
minimizing cost without compromising
quality you're taking fresh frozen
cannabis the best of the best of the
best um uh and and taking those resin
glands off without losing uh Tarpin to
drying losing tpin to to to hydrocarbon
extractor uh to the Roto Vape or or
ethanol or you know so you're collecting
all the the the the best of the best um
for the lowest cost of production and
able to pass that on to Consumers um so
it just stands to reason that that will
be the future um there's there's
facilities that are you know um multiple
facilities in in the state of California
that are over 20 acres and so how do you
take down 20 acres every two weeks you
know it's impossible to dry it and cure
it and and and all that other stuff
especially when in a flooded Market when
nobody really wants the B and C grade so
you know to take the a grade as flowers
present your customers with the best of
the best of the best and all B andc
grade gets turned into top quality
flowers again you don't lose tpin by
drying and curing um you know you don't
have to to pay for those services and
and the equipment that do so so that
that affects your overall cost of
production so in the end you're able to
produce Superior Products for a superior
price and pass those those on to
Consumers um without compromising
quality um the second part of your
question was it was just in terms of
what's your preferred method of
consumption in regards to say like high
quality resin heads where would you just
want to do it as dry Si would you
convert it to Rosen like what's your
preferred method of
consumption kind of old school like with
Rob Clark I really like my favorite is
just like you know
unadulterated high quality fresh frozen
dry seed um but I do appreciate a really
nice rosin too um and and I got to admit
some hydrocarbons are really fascinating
too they're they're still very flavorful
and I like them very much not too much
on a distillate um that's kind of like
uh I'll pass on that I was going to say
what's your thoughts on the prevalence
of CRC do you think it's going to like
fade away or it's just going to continue
to become more and more um around no no
it produces great ibles you know it's
it's fascinating you know it's it's it's
a you know distillation CRC all of it is
is great for producing raw ingredients
for uh gummies and the plethora of I
also um consult for an a company called
uh uh deeper they produce a product
called deeper green now you can see more
about the company on my Instagram page
that talks about them if you want to
contact them but uh I I so after you
after you have all the raw ingredients
the cannaboids and the chapines and all
this stuff separated in the raws form
how do you formulate them right so that
get in got into bioavailability
solubility you know how how do you take
a distillate and make it water soluble
um you know or how do you make it past
the brain blood barrier or you know
stuff like that those things fascinate
me as well so you know then I started
teaching myself how to formulate
products and I help formulate a product
called damper green for a believe
they're called essential Origins uh and
and so the relevance being is like yes I
can take a distillate and make it water
soluble and put it into any of the
drinks uh beverage uh but also also they
make a U bioavailable white powder for
say if you are a outside company and you
have a chocolate or you have a gummy or
you have all this whatever um that you
can buy their product as an active
ingredient no different than flour sugar
or salt the the relevance being is like
it's it's measured it's it's it's uh
it's um
if if they give
you
uh their final product they they can
give it to you in a form that if you
require 10 milligrams per unit they can
tell you exactly how much of their
product will yield that 10 milligram and
how many pieces you will get so you know
if you say you know I I do a thousand
pieces at a time they'll tell you
exactly how much of their product to use
to to make your thousand that are going
to be exactly 10 milligrams
the the with no hotpots or any of that
kind of stuff the also the relevance
being is it's it's got Superior
bioavailability be it that um some of
the
microemulsions will not really
process or or become uh available to
your system because your only body is
only capable of processing maybe six to
8 milligrams of a a micro Emulsion as
opposed to this uh um process that you
will get um you will metabolize the the
whole 10 milligrams um which when you're
say in California and you could you're
you're subject to only a 10 milligram
gummy you would prefer to be able to
metabolize the whole 10 milligrams
rather than six to eight so it it
delivers a superior experience but the
company provides an active ingredient
you can buy a 55 gallon drum of deeper
Green from them if and and never grow
pot extract pot or formulate pot or do
anything else it's just another active
ingredients for your product so I see a
lot of that going to happen especially
with the changes just made to the farm
bill combined with rescheduling you know
will will that allow some of the larger
pharmaceutical companies to start buying
um active ingredients because again you
know they're not they're they're not
going to compete with the Cannabis
Market they're going to make true
Pharmaceuticals hopefully um the you
know
don't uh involve inhalation or
combustion or any of that kind of stuff
so I I believe that just even starting
on the research that they're they're not
going to want to grow yeah it certainly
paves an interesting uh picture of the
future where you can be totally
uninvolved in the production yet have it
as a central feature of your product if
you were say an Edibles company for
example given your you know extensive
knowledge within tpin I did want to ask
you because you mentioned you I mean
we've been talking about concentrates in
general right and dab pens for the Youth
are all the craze as we know my question
though is a lot of the heads complain
they're unsatisfied compared to flower
the dab pens don't quite hit the spot my
question is do you think that it's
possible for us one day to get to a
point where the uh say addition of the
correct Turpin and maybe the right
extraction process creates dab pens that
truly are um you know satisfying to say
people who prefer flour or do you think
it'll just always inherently be a
different
experience uh I think that's a cause and
effect based on illegality illegality so
the the the the the the comments that
you're you're referencing from the dab
pens uh and the
majority of the dab pens and especially
the the popular commercial grade ones so
like um you know like stizzy and those
sorts of really popular brands that the
youth are very into um don't seem to
quite be uh the same hit the same spot
yeah no there there there's a like
anything else you have to look between
the the the the the products there
there's Superior Products out there
there's uh both hydrocarbon and um rosin
pens that are just um delicious
absolutely delicious that are you know
they're not distillates they're not
artificial uh non-cannabis Drive Tarpin
and Etc and they don't they don't have
glycol or glycerin or any of that kind
of stuff they're not distillates at all
you know so a lot of those those
unsatisfactory pens that you're talking
about are you know most of them are are
are distillates with with some kind of
artificial flavoring or you know
something else cutting agents or
something to lower viscosity there's
some other you know adulterant in there
as opposed to you know some of the I I
don't want to give out brand names and
stuff like that but you know I certainly
there's there there's a couple pens that
I certainly like you know what I mean or
if I you know if you're not satisfied
with one don't buy that one again find
one that you will or or or or you know
ask your friends what what ones they
prefer and what ones they
haven't enjoyed no certainly I've
noticed huge variation in the quality
and I've had some that have been
incredible so certainly a test to that I
wanted to actually loop back to
something you mentioned a few answers
ago you know you you you've met a wide
variety of uh how shall we say like
industry movers and shakers over the
years and you mentioned that photo on
your Instagram that comes from Sam the
skunkman and I'd love to ask you this
because you've been around long enough
to have a perspective but I feel like
for years um Dave Watson has at times
been painted as a bit of a shady
character but in terms of my analysis I
think it stands to reason that he's one
of the biggest players in the overall
modern scene and you could make a strong
argument you know he's certainly up
there on the rout the Mount Rushmore so
to speak what's your thoughts on Dave
Watson what's your interactions with him
being like he's a very mysterious figure
it's hard to get much info on him he's a
beautiful man and
uh I I'll say his name is Sam the
skunkman or sadu Sam I'm not saying the
other words I'll get in
trouble he he he he is uh yeah he's an
absolute beautiful individual um he he
is way ahead of his time his
accomplishments uh are are are Head and
Shoulders uh above many of today um you
know any of the the I I agree with your
assessment um there there's much to do
about nothing I've I've met him in
person multiple times I consider him a
friend um he he's never done anything
malicious that I know of um if if if any
if half of those things that are said
about him were true that uh Rob Clark
would not associate or participate with
him um so you know without getting you
know a whole lot of backlash going you
know oh he he created Terminator seeds
he sold to GW he did this he did that he
did this he did that you know and you
know I I don't I don't see any malicious
activity I I I've only seen good things
that David has done you know uh you know
skunk number one help helping preserve
and bring the haze to light so many
different things uh you know most people
aren't even aware of his contributions
you know yeah hugely I can certainly
attest that the more I've leared over
the years the more and especially like
the stuff that's sort of a bit more hush
hush on the back end not not for any um
other reason than like you know I
suspect he's just not looking for more
praise so to speak but yeah that's
that's incredible to hear here that um
that's your experience cuz that's
obviously you know what my
interpretation has been and while we're
on the topic I guess just as a general
question you know you've met an amazing
array of characters throughout your life
any memorable stories or standout
interactions ah dozens you know what I
mean it's like you know uh you know one
time I seen the movie Blow um I I I I'm
highly allergic to alkaloids so I don't
do cocaine or you know or or or
recommend it or or Advocate it or
anything like that but when I seen that
money that that movie that movie really
tugged on my heartstrings as it did
millions of others you know what I mean
but you know I I uh was fascinated with
the trafficking of the the the material
not really the material in itself so I I
started uh uh back we're talking over 20
years ago now um started um uh
conversing with George Young from the
movie um you know because he was in
Northern California
he he likes aircraft I like aircraft uh
there's a lot of common denominators
there you know and as he said it could
have been moon rocks you know what I
mean he was he was just moving stuff
from from one point A to point B across
an imaginary line you know so meeting
George Young was fascinating to me uh
meeting Freer Ray Ricky Ross was
fascinating to me um you know but also
you know the the people I consider my
older brothers my brethren like Rob
Clark like like uh you know George
santes like Ed Rosenthal um you know the
list goes on you know I I I am the the
ultimately the the the product of all
those men and stand on all their
shoulders and have have no one to thank
but all of them you know um they they
all came before I did and and and you
know they say never meet your Heroes you
know what I mean um true to some sense
but but and and and and and that bunch I
I I don't regret any interaction you
know and and and
love each one of them in their own ways
dearly yeah that's so awesome to hear
because you know you do hear people
often express that sentiment around you
know don't meet your Heroes but it's
awesome to hear that that that all of
those guys are stand up and I got to
admit I uh I saw Rob Clark on a plane
for 5 seconds I walked past him I said
you're Rob Clark and he said yes I am as
I was ke I had to keep walking cuz
everyone was exiting the plane um but
yeah he seemed like a very nice guy in
that brief interaction so there you go
times 10 times 10 he's got a heart of
cold he's just he's just a beautiful
person he he is he has always been there
for me he you know if I ask him to write
for Canabis business times or something
him and Mojave Richmond produced
Superior wonderful articles for that
magazine and you know so so yeah Rob is
absolutely golden yeah that's awesome to
hear that's awesome to hear I want to go
back because we we sort of brushed over
it very early on but there's so much
history I'm I'm just going to have to
try to take us back and we'll steer
forward from there but you mentioned
earlier on you know you you had a 60
Minutes segment that featured you and I
actually tried to look up that clip and
uh I couldn't find it unfortunately so I
wanted to ask you what were you talking
about and give us the backstory as to
how you found yourself in that position
because I think some people are probably
not aware of your
backstory some people over there do do
do you even get 60 Minutes TV show in
Australia yeah definitely it's uh I
think it's probably bigger in Australia
for the Australian audience the what
itties in America like it was a real
focal part of Australian journalism for
the past 30 plus years interesting so um
I was arrested in 1993 and one of the uh
the the expert Witnesses I hired to uh
deal with an aspect of my case was Ed
rosenvall so I met Ed rosenville in 1993
under adverse conditions so after I had
dealt with that I immediately I I
harvested within one year of my date of
arrest so you know I I was not going to
allow them to um win so to speak so uh I
already had a garden and so um and knew
Ed and he one day said here come to my
house and you know they're going to do
this interview and so I was you know
fascinated wanted to see how interviews
were done and stuff and things so you
know there was no notable note there was
just producers and cameraman and stuff
and asking questions and stuff and
things and so that went down then later
on we went to San Francisco and they did
the same with Dennis Peron and they
asked all kinds of questions and stuff
and things and stuff and it was a
fascinating process and that's all I
wanted out of it you know and then me
and Ed were dropping the the producer
guy off at the airport and he kind of
turned and looked at me and he was like
what's what's your taking all this and I
was like what do you mean he was like
well you were around all day like you
know what are you at bodyguard I'm like
no not at bodyguard I'm I'm a grower and
he was like really he was like you know
would it be okay if we came back and you
know took some footage and stuff and
things and I was like if Ed says okay I
don't care you know so you know about a
week later Ed calls and he was like Hey
that guy wants to talk to you so I I you
know got him on the phone he was like
you know who morle safer is and I'm like
look I'm not an idiot yes I know who
morle safer is and he was like okay we'd
like to come out and interview you and
stuff and things and blah blah blah so
it was kind of fascinating I I it was
done up in sowa California I told him
where to go where to stay Etc and they
came in and Morley came in he was you
know kind of like talking to your
grandpa you know what I mean he was
really kind and you know he was positive
and believed it should be legalized and
stuff and he was you know pretty cool so
that was kind of a a neat interaction
and I believe you know either either you
can Google Kenneth Marl UH 60 Minutes
interview or triome Technologies uh uh
60 Minutes interview or something like
that it's up there it's on YouTube
actually
the one of the funnier interactions I
had uh was um I got a call from Chris
simic uh from High Times magazine he
says uh you want to talk to Heraldo
Rivera I'm like you know what's that
about he was like I don't know you'd
have to ask them so I was like all right
I'll entertain the conversation so I'm
standing in a coffee shop standing in
line and I get this producer on the
phone he's like look you know uh you we
want to do this TV show and you know
it's a you know the opening segment
there they want to stand in front of
this this you know big pot garden and
pretty much tell people this could be in
your neighborhood in any any
neighborhood you know any house in your
neighborhood you know and I was like
that's not really a positive light you
know I mean that's that's that's not
kind of the hysteria I want to be
responsible for bringing on you know
what I mean you know that sounds like
you're going to be getting people in
trouble that way and he was like no no
no no and and then all a sudden like
uh Heraldo pipes in he's like look if
it's a security thing you can take me
which I thought was pretty nefarious
that he was on the phone call and didn't
announce himself you know but he was
like look you you can you can blindfold
me you can put me in the trunk and stuff
and you my mind immediately went to like
wow what a blast that would be to to go
put Heraldo Rivera in your trunk and and
drive around town with them and you know
pull up the people and open it up and be
like look I got a Heraldo AR in my trunk
you know so that was fascinating but you
know in the end I was not going to
participate in something like that
because you know that again all it was
going to do was put it in the negative
life sure thing look big ups for for not
participating in it but I agree it would
have been uh certainly a fun story to be
able to just at least do it and know
that um you're not going to get in
trouble so I guess the next question I
wanted to ask you was in your mind what
was the first big break you had in terms
of getting Community attention you know
do you was it like when you first
started to appear in magazines when did
you start to appear on other people's
radar in your own mind
uh so I was arrested
1993 and then Ed started writing
articles about me um because I
immediately went back into you know
cultivation so you know uh you know
every once in a while he'd be like hey
could you try doing this for me like you
know uh try this gibberelic acid and see
if it makes me flowers and so I do
little experiments here and there and
stuff for him and you know was also a
photo source for him so you know did
that for a couple years and then
um uh there came a time where there was
um you know uh let's say um an
opportunity just to present my work from
myself so you know I I contacted uh the
the editor at High Times magazine and
said look you know um you know you
you've featured my work multiple times
and here it is um but at the same time I
sent him some samples of hash oil and a
whole a whole Christmas uh bag of treats
so uh I knew that he had probably
received his bag of treats and was
staring at his bag of treats uh upon my
phone call so you know he was very very
pleased about the treats but begged me
never to do that again which started a
lifelong friend friendship and at that
time he was uh his name is Chris simic
he was a editor of High High Times
magazine that that ended up being
editor-in chief of high times before
they uh changed ownership and stuff like
that um but I'm still friends with him
today etc etc and so you know from there
you know I said look you I've got a new
project you should come you know shoot
some photos so you know he came out and
you know it was beyond his expectations
so he quickly scheduled another uh photo
shoot and that brought um uh keny or or
Andre Gman and they came out with uh
real proper hustle bomb cameras with 4x5
uh uh negatives and stuff like that and
so that fascinated me right there being
able to see uh a legitimate photographer
do really high quality photos and you
know those ended up being Centerfolds
and covers of from High Times to a lot
of the
also those ended up being covers of a
red ey Magazine from in England or um
also submitted them to burst high in
Japan or some of the uh Centerfolds and
magazine inclusions in Cano in Spain so
it kind of went all over the world you
know um but also those articles were
pretty revolutionary because you know
the the the cultivation setups were you
know there was you know that three
three4 of a million dollar nft systems
put together you know so you know
obviously these Gardens weren't just
about making money or profit you know
what I mean it was their their
legitimate research and development
facilities for breeding you know so
that's that's kind of what it it you
know took off and ended up being you
know it wasn't for glamour it wasn't for
profit it wasn't for selling products or
hacking products or you know no no no no
disingenuous intent it was it was about
uh any of the articles I wrote any of
the things I did I never got paid for I
never got compensated for it wasn't the
purpose the purpose was to disseminate
that information as fast as possible so
the industry could take it grab it and
Rise you know so that that was always my
focus yeah that's incredible and and so
many topics I want to touch on like
first of all you know you wrote for red
eye and for people who aren't aware this
is truly like one of the most like heady
cannabis magazines that was ever around
often regarded as the greatest magazine
of all time in the sense that it was
like free from you know sort of the
commercial influence that you see on a
lot of cannabis magazines these days and
it was just like totally powered on the
passion and the enthusiasm of the
contributors such as yourself what was
it like to be a part of that incredible
magazine you know it was it's it's
remembered by so many as such like an
epic
contribution readers can still I I see
copies pop up on on uh eBay and stuff
like that so I highly encourage people
to buy you know any of the magazines
that they can because every one of
them's a gem every one of them's got
great reads and stuff like that um like
I said uh well so I I I first seen uh
Redeye Magazine on probably issue two or
three um and and could quickly Garner
that it was a one-man show so I you know
back in the day you know no in no no
emails or any of that stuff I hand wrote
a letter to the editor and and you know
said how can I help how can I
participate I've got photos I can
provide you know I know lots of
different people that would love to
participate and you say pabis magazine
it was actually a hash lovers magazine
Nick loved hash his name was Nick
Cranston he he produced the magazine
himself he whatever proceeds he got from
the magazine he bought a plane ticket
and he went to Nepal he went to uh
Gambia to sagol to to to you know
Pakistan he you know went to the
mountaintops he meant the gangsters that
were making the tons of hash to smuggle
back to England you know it was just
just fascinating the stories he he he
wrote uh a a Side Story uh so
he back in the day you know a CD uh
music CD there there's when you open the
packet there's a little dead space uh on
the left so to speak uh
so when he went someplace he would take
a gram and he would put the gram in that
little dead space of a CD and he would
mail that to me separately from the new
magazine so when I got the magazine I
would also get this CD and I would pull
out a gram of the hash and I would get
to read the article and smoke the hash
and take the journey with them so it was
our our private little thing and it was
very very special to me but until one
day he goes to to to Nepal and you know
when you're a hash lover you want you
want to the five cents is kind of sort
of the smell the the flavor the the the
touch the you know so inevitably you
want to put some in your mouth and kind
of like between your teeth and see how
sticky it is and if it's got any
contaminant be it dirt or debris or
whatever you know what I mean so as I'm
getting to the bottom of the article I'm
about to to do the last five last thing
which is put it in my mouth but as I'm
reading it says oh but when you go to
this region never consume uh the the
Cannabis edibly because there's a lot of
tuberculosis uh in this region and and
some of the the the pressors utilize
saliva to to to get the the resin uh
moist and and make it easier to get off
your hands you know what I mean so you
know just as I'm about to bite this I'm
I'm I'm I'm figuring out that I'm just
about to give myself tuberculosis so I I
didn't eat the hash but you know uh
great great Journeys we did did that
probably four or five times and and and
it was just an incredible experience I I
wish every reader of the magazine got a
grandma hashed in their magazine to take
the journey you know what I mean if in a
per perfect world but Nick was amazing
like I said said each I think he he did
22 of the
magazines um I've I've got issue 22 but
I never read issue 22 it's in my
collection
um because it's very personal to me
because if I read issue 22 it'll mean
that uh that's the the the last issue
that I'll ever read so maybe even though
Nick's dead if I don't read the issue
maybe it's not the last I'll ever read
kind of sort of thing so I've got I've
the last issue I've got all the issues
but I've never personally opened or read
number 22 but it was great because I got
to bring again George Young from the
movie Blow he wrote All Kinds what
people don't understand is like you know
that movie glorified cocaine etc etc etc
George was a weed Smuggler you know what
I mean George Geor George liked weed um
so did so did Escobar you know um uh so
so in the end uh people think that
George did like 22 years uh uh for uh
cocaine smuggling he he didn't he did 22
years for 400 lbs of of Mexican
cannabis that's what he did his largest
stretch F so you know the you know
smuggling and trafficking cannabis back
in the day was you know what what drew
me to him um but I got to you know uh
get him to write for the magazine and
then the magazine paid him $800 while he
was in federal prison so you know and
and you know uh other people
participated again Mel Frank uh the
great photographer Andre grman you know
many others and it was you know kind of
a
neat um again a hash lovers Club you
know what I
mean yeah look that sounds truly epic
and quickly while we're on the topic you
mentioned that you're involved in burst
High you know the Japanese cannabis
magazine that's a really cool and quite
a niche one how did you get involved in
the Japanese cannabis
as I said uh I had a worker that was
Japanese so he spoke fluent Japanese um
and so I could converse with them that
way and so once I learned that they
existed I asked him to contact them and
um provided them like with a whole photo
library I knew that they were you know
probably in a basement somewhere didn't
have funding you know in a in a highly
illegal situation so to dump a bunch of
free content on them was was you know I
I I felt the appropriate thing to do
which ended up you know they printed
them as copies of uh you
know Centerfolds and covers and stuff
and we took all kinds of Japanese toys
and took photos with big piles apart it
was it was a
blast that's really cool do you know how
much about the active scene is still
alive today because I mean a lot of the
world what I've noticed a lot of the
world is online like you can even find
like you know um a handful of like
Afghan proper land race farmers who are
on Instagram just doing their thing you
know but I have yet to really come
across anyone in um Japan or the Asia
scene obviously probably implications
about the penalties do you know is it
still pretty active over
there uh no that magazine doesn't exist
and you know there there's some
incredible glass blowers and dabri uh
producers that are Japanese um that you
know rose rose and and and you know just
some not fluid in in the the the glass
Community but I've seen their work and
they're absolutely incredible but you
know they you know they have nothing to
put in their pipe kind of sort of thing
so you know it's you know besides the
you know the Thailand situation who
would have predicted that that's kind of
an interesting thing but apparently now
they're trying to put that gen back in
the bottle and and go back to uh uh
medical and not recreational which is I
don't think is going to be possible but
you know they could do you know
something Draconian like in the
Philippines and you know say you
know uh recreational drug use is
a crime punishable by that you know what
I mean the Indonesia style who knows
what the what what what could happen but
you know but yeah so that's a an unusual
thing I never would have seen Thailand
do that which I think is pretty
Progressive and I wish they would just
leave it the way it is it seem to be
working in fantastic fashion yeah it
certainly remains to be seen what's
going to happen over there in Thailand
but I you know I I think I think the
world worldwide the Genie's out of the
model you know what I mean when you
start talking about rescheduling in the
United States mo mo most times you know
with treaties and stuff it was the
United States putting pressure on
Lebanon to stop hash production or you
know uh you know India or or you know
any of the other you know hash producing
countries in the 70s you know stomped
production based on you know pressure
from the United States so when the
United States stops pressuring those
foreign countries and you know you see
you know slight change Germany legal
legalizing and you know you know I think
the world is going to progress and I
think I think very quickly cannabis is
going to be the least of the world's
problems yeah I I certainly hope so that
would be a beautiful future for sure I
want to quickly loop back before I lose
my train of thought to uh High Times for
a moment because you're famous for
having been chosen as having had the
best grow room in 25 years history of
the magazine can you describe the setup
that won that for you and uh maybe just
give us a few little pointers about how
people might be able to improve their
home setup in the context of you know
you are a Titan according to High
Times uh yeah bless up to Danny Denko
for writing that article and giving me
him and Chris cinic for giving me that
title and credit that's very kind to
them but you know I think there was you
know many bests but um you
know in a nutshell like I said it was it
was never about profit it was about
research and development so you know um
you know filling pots with dirt to to
grow indoors and urban settings got to
be problematic but also it got to be it
seemed like environmental wasteful so
you know the to to to migrate to a a 3in
rock wo cube in an nft system seemed
like a a logical thing to do um maybe I
wouldn't do that today because of a
legality I wouldn't have to um maximize
every aspect of of of the production you
know um maybe uh I I would have them
spaced a little bit farther etc etc etc
but in that we we we you know spent the
company spent 3/4 of a million dollars
to develop the nft systems that were a
drip from the top but also allowed again
for a handw waterer uh uh augmentation
um but you know it would drain we run
the waste we didn't recycle because of
uh contamination and and you know
pythium and all kinds of disease and
stuff and you know to sterilize we
didn't have the ability to sterilize
reuse capture 15,000 gallons of water
and reuse every day back and forth back
and forth so you know but to develop
that system and and literally have a
plank go from a 1-in clone into a 3 and
1 half inch rockle Cube and finish its
life in a three and 1 half inch rockle
cube with a 4 to six inch plant but then
at the end of harvest I could take you
know uh what was it 400 and something
3inch Rock hoal cubes squeeze the water
out and walk out of my facility with a
with a all of my medium waste medium and
and and a garbage bag over my shoulder
you know as opposed to getting rid of
you know 400 dirt pots and root balls
and all this other stuff uh again just
wasn't conducive to a Urban
situation so you know a lot of things
were were necessity by not by Design but
by default you know sure and what are
some general pointers you might be able
to give to people in terms of like
common issues or aspects that you feel
people maybe Overlook or aren't paying
enough attention to that would help
Elevate their their
game well moving forward and stuff in
today's you know Brave New World you
know if if if I only would have known um
then would I know now uh be it uh the
potential for for virus uh transmission
into the cannabis plants and the
proliferation of hop Laden vroid disease
um I can't say enough about keeping
mothers sterile and clean with UV light
um to eliminate the possibility of of of
of hop Laden vroid disease transmission
to a clone from one generation to
another I started noticing this uh over
15 years ago I started noticing I was
hired by by an individual that said that
they thought they had a virus and a
problem and stuff and they would like me
to prove or disprove and so there was no
way to get um anything analyzed back
then you know uh you know it just wasn't
possible there was no legal Labs there
no legal Avenue um so you know I put the
garden together ran it you know uh very
quickly it went sideways but it was like
there was no way to confirm what it was
but then once I started Consulting Once
Denver went legal I had seen symptoms
and signs at multiple locations
throughout California but once I started
going to other states I started knowing
Sim similarities of of of cooking and
curling up leaves and yellow streaks and
the plants you know stopped producing
you know uh resin uh or or Aroma and you
know resin content was garbage yield was
garbage you know but there was no you
know you look back at you know good
quality records keeping and you know
three
four previous uh uh Generations or
harvest you know same food same
environment same everything but there so
so no rhyme nor reason for it so I
moving forward I think you know I can't
say enough about you know
um utilizing sterile genetics meaning
going to a quality source to get your
clones that will give you a report that
says that your genetics do not have hot
Laden thyroid disease um because if it
does then you're
just
spreading the the disease but but also
just causing yourself problem s so you
know um but if you're utilizing mothers
to produce your own clones it's in your
best interest to keep those clone or
those mothers as clean as possible so so
you don't end up
proliferating a vroid and and and so
that brings me back to uh Sam the skunk
man or sadu Sam you know he he pointed
out to me because you know his work at
HOA farm and his association with GW
Pharmaceuticals afforded him the luxury
of identifying
many different viruses that cannabis is
susceptible to as well as you know Rob's
work with uh cannabis ethnobotany etc
etc I I can't I can't stress enough the
the importance of some of of of the new
generations you know buy a book buy buy
Rob CL Clark's marijuana botney uh it
there's still stuff in that book that I
don't understand today you know what I
mean it was it was his thesis in college
it it was an amazing work um you know as
well as uh you know his book hashish um
that that book just changed my world you
know to to to to to tell me certain it
answered so many questions you know
because uh you know Rob Trav traveled
the world and and in the end I was
afforded the luxury of being uh included
in his second revised Edition for the
article that I previously mentioned that
I co-authored and wrote with Mel Frank
about water separation you know uh so I
was lucky to be included in Rob's book
but that that book hashish is absolutely
incredible I you know it deserves to be
on everybody's shelf as well as as uh
you know hemp Pest and disease as well
as ethnobotany like every every
everything he's ever touched everything
he's written is is is just beyond
Priceless um and and that gets into the
viruses and and
as Sam the skunkman pointed out that
there's multiple viruses that that
cannabis is susceptible to I read a
report that the relevance being that
that 90% of of the the Cannabis in
California it could be polluted with
that virus which
is
uh a billion dollar at least a billion
dollar
catastrophe especially when you consider
that once a legal another legal Market
opens
up in whatever state in the United
States people want the newest latest
hottest trendiest cultivars um which
typically um come from existing um
markets so those genetics are going to
migrate from existing markets to the new
markets and the potential of the those
genetics from
the Old Market to the New Market of
being polluted with the virus is very
high it's so interesting that you
mention that because just last week
there was uh a lot of scuttlebug and
articles coming out about how uh some
plants in the relatively newly
established Australian medical scene uh
plants in those facilities had tested
positive for a hopl and virus which is
interesting because most of the
facilities are working with seed um but
there are still a few that have brought
over some clones so it's certainly doing
exactly what you just said so we'll have
to you know hope we're able to get on
top of this virus just to clarify but
but but the virus is transmittable from
a mother to a seed so it doesn't matter
if the Clones were the source or the
seed was the source yeah you know uh
infected mothers produce infected seed
yes certainly certainly I just wanted to
loop back one last time to wrap up on
the old high times because you've you've
had so many um you know articles being
featured about you and I wanted to ask
what's your thoughts on high these days
because it was just a week or two ago
the news came out sadly that they've put
out the announcement that they're going
into receivership indicating that their
their finances are maybe not once what
they were where do you think High Times
went
wrong um it's hard to roll with progress
in the in the industry I I I know the
old guard and um you know uh every print
magazine is having troubles you know the
new generation you know isn't drinking
alcohol and they're not reading
magazines you know so hard hard to to
to uh exist in that um Arena but also
like in you know red eyee the demise of
red eye was the the demise of the
advertiser you know um with a downturn
in economies uh advertisers stop paying
their bills and stop as uh advertising
and and periodicals or or what have you
and so that's what you know that's how
they pay their bills and that's how they
drive it so um you know I was you know
privileged to to to to you know know
Michael Kennedy the owner of high times
as well as again multiple staff members
from the old guard and you know um you
know when it sold to the new owners um I
believe that
that what the new owners bought was uh a
name was a brand and was was was a hard
drive with with uh 200 million or I mean
with 2 million followers or or or
whatever you know what I mean whatever
their social Med media presence was you
know um you know the brand just didn't
didn't didn't progress it didn't carry
the the weight the the the the
merchandise wasn't you know going to
going to carry it through
the you know it just it it just it
reached it reached the end you know and
so you know sad because because I was a
you know from from from a you know 12
and 13 year old child a a consumer of
the magazine let's say you know um I it
taught me a lot and and they allowed me
to parti participate and
I from what their archives has has shown
as as on my Instagram page my
contributions are as an independent uh
contributor to the magazine uh was
probably the number one contributor to
that magazine in the history of the
magazine so I lament the loss but but
but you know I it doesn't surprise me
its progress you know yeah look all good
things must come to an end and and I
think an aspect of it certainly has to
be attributed to the uh changing
landscape of the way people are
consuming informations and you know
Instagram certainly seems to be the more
prevalent than magazines these days but
I wanted to talk about you as a breeder
it's sort of surprising it hasn't come
up already but we've got a lot of stuff
on it so I guess the first thing I
wanted to say was that you know there's
a number of strains that have been
associated with you but the one that
comes up the most consistently has to be
you know the Purple Kush and
specifically your one that's known as
the ultraviolet I've seen this cut
talked about on the forums for years I
know a few breeders who use it first of
all give us a bit of a backstory where
does this cut come from what's the
Genesis story on
it well living in Northern California
one of my best friends from high school
who I'm still friends with today had an
uncle and an aunt that were in Redway
California um in Humble County and so we
from ninth grade on uh after I started
trafficking for the other uh with the
other friend I started trafficking with
this friend and so every week we'd go up
and back up and back and bring you know
15 to 30 pounds of outdoor Northern
California bud and they you know since
there was so so much of it being
produced Outdoors it wasn't um unheard
of to get common bag seeds here and
there as well as you know um you know
they would have uh on Black's Beach
there would be Fourth of July parties
and you know fireworks etc etc and and
there was you know trading up seeds
there and so I was afforded the luxury
of being part of this community as you
know a fairly young man um with my
friend and his family um and so I would
collect everything that I possibly could
and so uh you know inevitably I ended up
getting a just a basically a purple
Afghani and a pure Afghani but they they
more
were you
know let's let let's Callin had had
string stringy traits to them and stuff
they weren't like short Squat and
so you know and and you know the the the
color was fairly inconsistent so I I I
took the two I bred the two but then
after that I started reproducing them so
I could pheno hunt pheno hunt pheno hunt
feno hunt and and in search of the the
darker color the darker color the darker
color you know had no idea what anthos
cyanin was uh didn't know why I was
doing what I was doing but but besides
the purple color it it had this great
Kool-Aid flavor and and and you know it
was only like a 16% THC but it was you
know to me it was a a beautiful midday
uh cultivar um so you know but also
since I'm working with High Times the
they started shooting lots of photos of
it and and because it was unusual they
started featuring it on their covers and
Centerfolds and and throughout the
Articles and stuff and so then it
started you know taking hold then um
Berkeley Patients Group uh dispensary
and uh a Blue Sky Coffee shop or or
SR71 um Richard Lee and a friend of mine
work there asked if he could uh
distribute it through there um I kind of
wanted to see what it what one of my
Cult of Arts would do on the o Open
Market because I really didn't sell
things or or or have a seed company or
anything like that so just out of
curiosity you know I I I released it
through both of those dispensaries um
and it kind of exploded you know um so
much so that you know it was at a time
where you know um URL and Granddaddy
Purple started coming out and some
friends of mine were running a club in
Hayward called CCAC or CCDC um they
ended up getting shut down by the feds
because I was Consulting for them and
stuff um they they it's when
dispensaries were few and far between
and they were one of the few in the East
Bay and then the year they got arrested
they ended up doing 53 million in sales
in 52 weeks they one of the first to pay
State uh sales taxs and when the feds
figured out uh what they were doing um
they pretty much came after him and and
you know G gave each brother that was
running it you know well over 60
felonies um but you know
uh sorry why did I go into that um oh uh
uh so so you know once they started
running their dispensary um you started
noticing
um you know okay purple's trendy um you
know but you know one day I was in there
and and their buyer walked into their
their buying room with the wet paper
towel and I was like what's with the wet
paper towel he was like we're starting
to get people rolling their pot in dye
um so we've got to roll the pot in a wet
paper towel to see if the Dy comes off
and if so then we don't buy the pot and
I'm like wow that's that's how much the
the purple has in influen the market and
and that's when I first started noticing
that like oh no this is this is going to
be problematic um you know ultimately
answer your question um so so you know a
purple afghan and a pure Afghani you
know called it purple kush but pretty
pretty soon it BEC so popularized that
people started bootlegging the name so I
had to change the name to ultraviolet um
and and hence they're the same cultivar
I just changed that name
um um and the problematic part was I I
started seeing how Trend driven the IND
industry was going to become and and so
the one day the the the purple was was
was very hot and the most desirable once
the market got flooded with purple then
everybody started going to Kush the LA
Kush the the then then Kush was on it
was kush everything and and the the more
popular it became the less popular some
of those lad races and those old school
cultivars became and desirable those
became because they weren't marketable
because the the the market wanted the
Kush so it's it's interesting how you
know I started noticing let's call it um
species Extinction driven by Trend you
know what I mean um there you know there
there there's C of ours out there you
know the found on the side of the road
Dead Skunk that everybody romanticizes
about everybody laments the loss of that
that I do too it did like a skunk not a
a skunk that was just sprayed but a
3-day old side of the road Dead Skunk
which was you know to me a beautiful
smell you know I love the smell and and
you know to me that brings me back to
1983 School Bus everybody rolling joints
on the way to school you know the whole
damn thing smelled like a skunk that c
bar is gone you know uh and you know I I
I I blame trends for that you know um
now it's all candy flavors and gelato
and da d da you know so it's interesting
to see the the es and flows of popular
cultivars but the the the purple um i'
I've still got um a small amount of
seeds um right now trying
to uh raise Capital to put together uh a
seed company because me and my friends
lament the loss of multiple cultivars
that I used to have
and so we're trying to put something
together so I can restart those so just
just so we could have those flavors
again not really for
um marketability or not for profit or
something like that but you know the the
main focus is just because we we want
that again we're we're kind of tired of
today's availability so to speak yeah
certainly look that that would be cool
to see that get off the ground my um my
my immediate follow-up question would be
so are you saying that the uh your your
purple cush is in fact the Blue Sky
SR71 Purple Kush and correct but but you
know again if you go to my Instagram
account you can see an SR71 catalog that
says exactly that you know what I mean
that it's from triome Technologies da d
d so you know it's not a secret that
that that they're uh ultraviolet slurple
Co came from triome Technologies they've
admitted that for many many years sure
sure there's lots of stuff on the
internet but it's all wild speculation
and people saying you know uh you know
the G13 was a cavar that was uh grown by
the government that you know someone
liberated and all this other stuff and
it's like that's hogwash you know what I
mean uh you know I'm someone one of the
rare individuals you meet that has read
something called the rips papers and
it's like rips papers what the hell is
that and it's like so it's the Research
Institute of pharmaceutical Sciences
papers it comes from the University of
Mississippi it comes from the University
of Mississippi's cannabis cultivation
program because it's a
a public
uh a a public paid for uh subsidiary or
company or college um and and the data
that was comes out of University of
Mississippi and the grants everything
associated with they they were forced to
put a bibliography together each and
every year so if you again go to my
Instagram page you can see both the
catalog from SR71 but you can also in
one of my posts see some of these books
from the Research Institute of
pharmaceutical sciences and so every
year that they did research they had to
document their research that they did
regarding cannabis each and every year
so there's like 25 volumes starting in
like 1982 or something like that that
started with like you know stapled
together hand hand uh uh assembled
little leaflets to you know actual bound
books that you know they you go through
pages and pages and Pages it's all the
research all the stuff they ever ever
did in that you can see what Muhammad
ooli and Carlton Turner and the
University of Mississippi what cultivars
they actually researched and and and
worked with you know some some will say
that oh this is a university in
Washington or Maine or you know that's
where the G13 came from you know I don't
know nothing about that I I can say that
I've read the documentation of the
cultivars that they did utilize at the
University of Mississippi and and you
know towards the very very end of the
the the program did they they start even
investigating or working with any kind
of wide Leaf call it Indica cultivars um
it was it was mostly thin uh Leaf uh
sativa said cultivars from seized
product that they ever researched with
so the G13 is I I don't know if I find
that whole story you know the internet's
a crazy thing I noticed on your
Instagram you had a few photos of both
the uh the nl5 and the G13 uh in
magazines and I wanted to ask you like
how do they stand up to today's cultivar
and what was your experience with the
G13 it seems to be one that's largely
been lost
mostly let's say that the C you know I
got it and it was very leggy and gang I
started breeding it and rebreeding it
and inbreeding it and and and you know
it's just an inbred line that I kept
doing over and over and over until I got
something that I I I found
fascinating and when I say fascinating I
can say just breaking up a joint It
produced more resin on my fingers than
anything else I had ever ever run across
so that's that's what sparked my
curiosity it was finicky it it was the
first to to to get bugs it was the first
to die it was it it yielded like crap
you know what I mean it was a nightmare
but the flavor the flavor was like just
smoking pure hat and then the stickiness
pretty much proved that it was high THC
content but there was no way of testing
then I was afforded the luxury of uh
working with uh after uh 215 passed uh I
was afforded the luxury through uh
General Hydroponics they had an
individual that was working there that
was putting together a study with
California normal and that product was
going to go to uh drug detection
Laboratories in Sacramento and they had
a
gcms that they were going to do testing
on all the Cannabis and including
mother's milk I've still got these
documents to prove all this uh you know
uh so they they I long story short 11 of
my cultivars went to this drug detection
laboratory you know besides like Mel
Frank and a couple others that were able
to get uh THC uh testing done at the
University of Mississippi um I'm
probably the second private individual
that got those government entities to
test their cultivars but it was a
roundabout way because it went to drug
detection Laboratories and and some of
the cult of ours tested unusually high
so uh it was uh brought to question so
Muhammad Ali Who provided the standards
for the gcms was sent those samples with
a the DEA license uh from drug detection
Laboratories so my samples went from me
to Sacramento Sacramento to University
of Mississippi where Muhammad Ali tested
them and Quantified them and said that
the G13 tested at a 20 and and said yes
it was true that the G13 tested at a 272
per THC and that was in
1996 and so those in the photos you see
in the magazines it's got THC levels
down below
yeah certainly cuz I mean it's so it's
so like interesting that you were one of
the first people to get actual tests and
that the numbers came back so high
because the common Mantra you hear is
that you know stuff was like sub 20% in
the '90s it begs the question do you
think we've really improved cannabis as
much as we might like to think if those
are truly the
values yeah yeah because you know you
know let's let's go back to 1996 there
was you know there was a handful of Mees
you know what I mean let's go to today
there's dozens of Mees you know what I
mean there's there there's there's an
army of Mees out there creating the
newest latest hottest genetics there's
companies out there that trading you
know uh seeds like trading cards you
know what I mean there's there's uh
there's amazing genetics out there that
just you know every day I look at
Instagram or something like that and it
blows my mind to see these resin coed
Cult of ours that are just like awesome
just so awesome and then there's you
know there's a
a couple companies out there that do
high resolution um uh photography uh
schale and uh sorry the name escap me I
just met him not too long ago he gave me
a decal I can dig out his decal
um but just amazing uh close-up
photographies and stuff like that that
just like you know give you such a such
a an incredible closeup view of the the
resin
but yeah some of the some of the he was
in the the last one of the last
published issues of High Times magazine
um damn what is it uh yeah the wellness
issue
um yeah he's one of the people I follow
on Instagram and stuff but yeah schale
and him both do the the best high high
quality high resolution photography um
of resin Clans that I've ever seen in my
life um but yeah so so you know do it do
I think you
know well you know you've got polyploids
and stuff like that out there today um
and and and and you know some some so
very good genetics very good breeders
then Poly on top and it's like do I
believe the 35% thc's
absolutely there's an army of breeders
out there producing incredible things
back and forth back and forth back and
forth yeah you read my mind that was
going to be my next question do you
believe the 35% well look that's good to
hear the answer there um I want to loop
back because I I realized I forgot to
ask you when you were talking about the
G13 you mentioned that you did the
breeding project with it and I wanted to
ask you a little bit about that because
I'd read online that you said you know
the goals were to reduce the height the
internodal length and improve the
potency which all sounds like fantastic
stuff what was the initial male you used
to get that cross going and to do that
line breeding and what do you look for
when you select
males no I I started with the G13 and
just inbred the the the the jurny itself
with with SCS so I I just start got it
to produce pollen and just started you
know reproducing it reproducing it
reproducing it oh wow that's incredible
so you just did consequential uh self so
what what uh generation did you
eventually get it
to easy 15 easy 15 because it it was
like I said it was just it was the first
to die it was finicky it was you know
gangly um
um you know it was uh yeah there there
it was just it was like just a sickly
anemic plant that that that hated to
live you know what I mean so it took
everything I I I and even the final
version is like ick you know kind of
sort of except for the finished except
for the finished
product wow I mean when when you hear
common um rhetoric around doing multiple
uh selfing projects you hear people
citing that they're concerned about like
loss of vigor but it sounds like part of
your goal was to improve it would you
say that you know when you get into like
those higher numbers of the self um
Generations that you you notice any
decline in the genetics or not
necessarily no uh the the main my main
focus was to produce as many seeds as I
could so I could increase the variables
by having as many options to feno hunt
as I possibly could you know that that
was the key and and and again that's it
wasn't by by by Design all the the high
numbers and the commercialization and
scaling up and all that stuff you know
it was it wasn't a want to it was a have
to you know to to to you know especially
when you're breeding like that to have
as many options as possible so you know
if you can get you know
uh a 36 inch plant to produce 200 seeds
so you can in turn pop those 200 seeds
to try to get you know 900 seeds but but
but but also you know find you know
preferential desirable traits within the
the the the genus and and and you know
look for Superior phenotypes of the
genotype yeah that's that's beautiful
information and I guess something I've
wondered for a while now is how much
were you able to achieve those goals
like you know you described The Strain
as quite lanky and um not not compact at
all how much were you able to improve
that while being within the confines of
just selfing it and using just purely
selections we able to achieve that in
your
mind no no you're hamper I mean to to do
a you know as as as Sam the skunk man
says look a you know a proper pheno Hunt
is 20,000 plants you know what I mean
and and in a GW Pharmaceuticals or a ho
of farm situation you know back in the
day ho of farm got to do some or
participate in some very large
Greenhouse operations you know and and
so you know that's that's that's who
educated me to that fact that like look
you know you're you're not going to
you're not feno hunting you know I mean
you are you know but you're stifled if
you only have 10 copies of a given
cultivar to choose from or or or you
know those are your only representations
as opposed to you know
thousands I I I see some seed companies
that you know are and this is the the
the benefit of legalization or or or you
know um whatever you want to call
today's um situation uh I've seen you
know some you know very reputable seed
companies you know out there doing you
know uh you know a 100,000 uh plants to
to to go through and do their genetic
selection you know what I mean and that
that's really the proper way to do it
you know because then you get full
expressions of you know far and Far Far
you know ends of the spectrum both
positive and negative you
know there's there there's some
companies out there doing incred
incredible fenal hunts just just I'm in
awe when I see some of them just it's
you
know some of them are producing so so
much that they they they can't even you
know they've got to have teams of of S
of Samplers and note takers because you
know you're you're you're you
know eight hours of of of sniffing
cannabis you're burnt you know what I
mean you you just can't do a 12h hour
day that's almost like a uh like a first
world problem like I got old factory
fatigue I love that but you're right
they they certainly do produce enough
that that's the case and it's a it's an
evolving landscape for sure I wanted to
ask you've given us such an awesome
rundown of the
G13 you also had a number of many other
notable strains I wanted to touch on but
I guess first off the nl5 you know what
I've certainly noticed over the years of
running this podcast is that many of the
guests have like a notable nl5 cutting
they had or M smoking but the
interesting part is that it seems to me
like most of these cuttings they
referenc were different from the other
ones what was your nl5 like how would
you describe it and again do you feel
like it stands up to today's
stuff yeah well that's that's why to
clarify I I did an nl6 uh which was was
a you know an nl5 that I got that I
ended up like you know back Crossing in
[__] withd like six times so there
hence the name and and that's all it is
but you know uh it it it was certainly
Head and Shoulders above most that I I
ever encountered and and you know and
certainly made a name for itself and
stood on its own um you know uh I I
found it you know very pleasurable very
unique very very um very uniquely
aromatic was was my
nl6 wow yeah cuz a lot of the people
we've had on historically say that uh
you know the nose was probably lacking
to be honest and it was really like the
resin um that and maybe some of the
potency to a lesser extent that really
sold them so I guess you you improved it
and you read my mind I was going to ask
you what's the
nl6 yeah no and that's you know like I
like I said long ago the the the the
aromatic and flavorful qualities is like
50% you know I I used to say you know
it's 25% High
uh you know uh you
[Music]
know you know easily 35 flavor and 35
smell you know what I mean is is is you
know well yeah more so than the high I
enjoy the flavor and smell is is what I
I guess I can say um so in in my
breeding that's that's what I kind of
focus on is is you know the most
aromatic and flavorful
but that that that's hard when you know
when you're not using STS when you're
using you know pure lines when you're
using mail breeders you know trying to
find a preferential male that's Superior
to others without testing at your at
your disposal as well as you know I
always wished that I had a a large
enough facility to where I could
completely finish out all my male
candidates and do lab work on those and
find Superior traits in the finished
product of the males and then go back
with clones that I took off those males
and then use those clones as my my basis
of breeding I I always lament that I
wasn't able to do that afforded that
luxury because you know other than that
we you know your thumb and your
forefinger and rubbing it on the stem
and trying to find a superior smelling
male is basically how you chose your
males back in the day if you did use
males and didn't use you know STS or
something gibberelic
whatever yeah certainly and and you
touched on an interesting point which is
that over the past few years we've seen
a huge increase in the number of people
demanding feminized seeds over regular
sex and I think part of it is due to
what you said that so few if any people
have the ability to truly run out their
males fully do you feel like in the
future we're going to see that Trend
continue and we'll eventually just get
to almost totally fem
Market uh I I believe that would you
know that would hinder that would be a
hindered s would bottleneck I I I
believe all most of this and I've talked
to interviewed
most of the seed companies and and they
would you know they they they would like
something for everybody so yes they will
uh continue to produce uh uh feminis yes
they will continue to produce regulars
um as well as uh uh autof flowers you
know uh but you know possibly in the
future uh polyploids um you know we'll
see how that's embraced um or not
you know so so you know um yeah you know
because there's going to be some
companies that are out there producing
not for for the general public they're
not producing for uh consumables as
flowers or even concentrates you know
they're going to be for pharmaceuticals
they're going to be for you know uh you
know commercial products of the
beverages whatever you know what I mean
you know I've heard that you know you
know cannabis beverages could
potentially you know e Eclipse uh uh
alcohol consumption in the distant
future you know as as the next
Generations drink less and less so you
know um those those those genetics will
produce those things so you know anybody
it's like I don't want some poly Ploy
blah blah blah and it's like it's it's
it's not to be consumed by you it's to
be consumed in a pharmaceutical that's
put in a pill or whatever have you
yeah that's an interesting perspective
that I actually haven't given much
thought to I'll have to I'll have to
ponder that one actually and you know
there is some uh some poly ployed
controversy in the community at the
moment but yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah we
can leave that be for the moment I
wanted to quickly ask you before I
forget you also in um some of the
magazines you've posted on your
Instagram by the way in case people
haven't uh clued in yet if you haven't
uh gone over to K's Instagram already
please do so it's like a a treasure
Trove of awesome old School photos and
info just yeah just track on
Technologies yes yes um these two other
strains keep popping up that I wanted to
ask you about the Juicy Fruit and the
cryptonite where'd you get those you
know we've heard about them in from
other guests but um I'd love to hear
from you juicy fruit was
fascinating you know if you produced it
today and called it that you'd get sued
by rley you know what I mean but but it
genuinely did smell like that and it was
just again a cultivar that I stumbled
across coming from Northern California
um you know and and bettered it and
refined it you know most of the
cultivars I was getting at that time
were all bred for outdoor production so
it took a lot of work to get them to to
size down and and get a little bit more
manageable for indoor production because
they were you know they were used to be
in you
know very distant internodal lengths uh
up up to you know 9 to 12 feet Outdoors
you know so that's that's what I started
with and and and the best I could given
my limited resource ability and
bandwidth and space and you know uh you
can only have so many plants in a given
rotation so you know yeah I I did the
best I did I could with what I had but
you know some people would say well you
started with other people's material and
it's like well didn't everybody um you
know the which came first the chicken or
the egg but I I certainly believe that
like the the juu fruit the the the D13
the all all the apps were mentioned uh I
I definitely left them better than I
received them the uh I first encountered
the uh Kryptonite in 198
1995 at Dennis peron's uh cup in the
upper Castro that I went to with Ed
rosenal um and if you look at my
Instagram again there's there's
brochures from that cup you know what I
mean I think there was five cvars ENT
uh but a gentleman named Brian
jeul jwl is the breeder of the
Kryptonite he is the
original person that brought it to that
cup and won that cup and I became
fascinated with it because had a very
unique flavor you know what I I and and
if you look at my photos in my articles
that were taken at that time and compare
them to what other people call crippy
and this and that whatever they've
mutated it into they look nothing alike
so you know I don't I don't
know you know I I can only assume that
the name's been appropriated and and and
given to other cultivars Etc because
it's not the same fortunately I do have
a lot of uh genetics left of that so uh
along with the purple Kish I hope to to
re in introduce
that uh if possible but uh so uh yeah my
my my friend is the one who BR that um
Brian
Jewel that's that's awesome to hear and
I was going to ask you know any relation
to the crippy so good to get that
clarification I think I also saw two
other strains pop up uh maybe one called
Washington another called
Yoshi yeah yeah uh yeah again uh I I
responsible for over 200 so there
there's a plethora of them and and I
believe in those mag magazine articles
those were some of them that also have
the THC uh levels and stuff at that
point I think most of those were around
the 16 or something like that they were
mid-levels you know they were hybrids
so-called sativa indicia
hybrids yeah okay look yeah 200 God we
be here all day right it's uh it's
interesting to see how many of them um
are notable names I wanted to ask you've
won a numerous amount of awards over the
years and one of the stories that
grabbed me the most was how in uh in one
of the first cups you entered you you
won first second and third place all in
the same cup that was h a pretty funny
story tell me a little bit about what
that experience was like it was done uh
by a man named Bob at the Hayward hempy
and it was put on by a very dear friend
named Debbie goldsbury from an
organization called cabis Action Network
Ed rosenball asked me to go and you know
at that point I you know had 11
different C of ours and I was just out
of curiosity you know I I I don't really
uh play in the sandbox with other kids
so to speak I don't go out and about I
stay to myself I keep my head down I I
I've you know never been to a a
Amsterdam Cannabis Cup back in the day I
I you know I I just uh yeah I'd rather
just stay home and work you know what I
mean so you know um I I didn't go out
much so Ed was like hey just for fun you
should enter this thing and I was like
okay so you know I put 11 different
cultivar in and stuff and you know it
was interesting I mean it was very Neal
it was like you know watching watching
the general public grab samples of your
pot and tear it apart on on paper plates
literally you know and then they smoked
it and stuff and I was like okay we see
what happens here and then you know they
started to give Awards and they like
okay you know this this Cult of art blah
blah blah third place and I was like oh
okay kind of disappointed that I got
third place but okay I never done this
before you know and so then I went and
sat down and they were like okay well
second place and blah blah blah and you
know then they said by cultivar and so I
was like okay well that's not too bad
you know what I mean and you know got a
second and a third first time out you
know what I mean and then the guy just
looked at me he was like don't even sit
down and I was like what do you mean he
was like oh you got first place too and
I was like oh but it was kind of
uncomfortable because then there started
being like grumblings in the room you
know what I mean it was like oh that at
the point you know I I I wish I wasn't
still there so I don't know it felt
uncomfortable and you know at that point
I decided that I really don't like being
a so-called you know mo most people
don't know what I look like you know
what I mean so I can walk through most
events and nobody's points or stares or
you know says anything you know what I
mean so I I I enjoy my anonymity so to
speak you know so at that point I felt
kind of uncomfortable having the general
public uh displeased that I took first
second and third so
There He
Go yeah that's an interesting
perspective I I certainly wasn't
expecting to hear that but I can I can
appreciate your point of you you know
certainly being uh a little bit more
introverted than extroverted myself I
can appreciate that I guess from a more
theoretical point of view that's just
one of a numerous amount of awards and
just high placings in general you've had
over the years what do you think has
allowed you to be so successful in
competitions what made your samples
stand
out just hard work you know what I mean
just uh attention to detail and
dedication you know what I mean and
again the people that came before me uh
you know being H having the luxury of of
you know having good quality genetics
provided to me to to to breed and
improve with you know what I mean so you
know can't even really take the credit
myself it was you know the the
generation before me that that that gave
me the tools to work with you know so
you know I I I just paid attention and
fortunately I had books like marijuana
botney from Rob Clark and you know I I
know I paid attention you know
um yeah
so hugely look and uh I think no one
needs to hear it because if you've been
paying attention throughout this
interview you've heard just the the
numerous amounts of Articles you've
written it's no surprise that you ended
up writing your own book marijuana
Horticultural fundamentals a
comprehensive guide to cannabis
cultivation it's highly regarded by many
in the industry I wanted to ask you what
was the process of writing the book like
and what are some things people can
expect to get out of it if they grab
themselves a
copy uh it was a nightmare and probably
one of the hardest things I ever did
trying to put all the the the content
you know there there was so much more
that I wanted to include you had to
limit it to 400 pages so what what was
the best and you know um I've got I've
been critized for for for kind of
favoring the commercial scale even you
know back then but that was my focus
that was my Fascination you know but I
tried to include everybody and and and
even the small little handw watered
Gardens etc etc I tried to produce and
and provide something for everybody you
know uh keeping in mind that 60% of the
photos in that book are minded are are
are the are are my work I didn't Source
photos from other people there is 40%
that other people that the publisher
took and sourced from other people but
the gardens the you know the the setups
and all that kind of stuff you know 60%
of it is all my work and and stuff so
you know um the the hard part was what
to include and what not to but even then
that that was you know between the time
that it was written the time that it was
published was five years so even when it
was published there's things that now I
wish weren't in there that I would love
to change some of the product
recommendations Etc Etc you know for
instance you know a lot of the lights
and you know uh other products that I
recommend um other corporations turned
around and bought those companies and
and now I wish that I didn't recommend
those companies because they're bought
by corporations you know what I mean so
in the revised next Edition I'll be
taking that out you know so that was
kind of a an interesting perspective but
you know um yeah the hardest part was
probably you know what to include and
what not
to yeah yeah look certainly I don't
think anyone's going to hold it against
you as time goes on you know things
change but that's great to hear that
you're still trying to keep it relevant
with subsequent updates and I wanted to
ask you know you have notably been one
of the first if not the first to write
about dryv extraction in common magazine
as well as large scale water hash
extraction and even some of the first
articles describing BHO I feel like
you've always been ahead of the curb in
that regard so I wanted to ask you what
do you think
on the future what's your prediction for
the next big
thing like I said uh taking 20 acres and
and turning it into a 55 gallon drum of
dry seeve of from fresh frozen material
within uh eight hours that fascinates me
you know what I mean uh you know you did
not compromise the final product to
final product is sitting there it's from
a fresh frozen product the highest
Turing content available um you know
know uh and and then to be able to
separate those cannaboids from tpin all
organically for the lowest cost of
production that fascinates me as well so
you know it starts with the cry Mass cry
Mass separates uh the the the the
biomass from the active ingredients then
then like I said a a static electricity
separator separates and this equipments
available so you've got one equipment
the the cry Mass second equipment is the
the the the static separator then you've
got a vorticy a vorticy will separate
the the the the the material that comes
off the the the static separator uh in
multiple sizes the vorticy the second
vorticy will separate by size you know
so so being able to do that with a fresh
frozen material that hasn't been dried
hasn't been cured hasn't been trimmed
and all the equipment and equip uh the
the space and everything that goes with
that process to eliminate all that stuff
take a 20 acre BAS from a greenhouse and
and on it put you know so I I say one
team walks in De lefs the pro the the
the plants second team behind them takes
uh uh all the the branches off the main
stocks puts them in a bin does a 1880
rotation puts that b onto a conveyor
belt that conveyor belt goes to a
bucking team bucking team uh takes all
that material off the stem with the
Bucking puts it in seals containers and
goes into subzero minus 20 uh uh
storage until needed and whatever is is
is able to be processed that day goes
into something AK to a uh a a chomas
separator that will you know take fresh
frozen biomass and and turn it separate
the green vegetated material uh from
from the active ingredient and then
you've got again the the the static
separator uh that's available so then
you'll go into that from that you'll go
into the VY again and separate to your
final size and and those are your active
ingredients I mean yeah that that will
enable companies to engage with that 20
acre facility and be like look I'm just
a a vapen company I'm a rosin company
and I I don't want to grow don't want to
extract don't want to do any of those
things don't want to hydrocarbon don't
want to blow up they want you know I'm
just going to take your 55 gallon drum
put it in bags got a got a got a vacuum
seal them um then GNA
uh should I say freeze dry them then
vacuum seal them then press them and
then you know gonna get crash it out
make my diamonds do whatever I'm going
to do uh hdfb High turpine whatever blah
blah blah and make my VAP carts or you
know so you know to be able to take uh
20 acres and turn it into active
ingredients all organically for the
lowest cost of production again so I can
pass those savings and and and and you
know again a superior product for a
superior price to customers all organic
that's that's that's something that
fascinates
me that that sounds incredible and it's
absolutely going to be a game changer
the more it rolls out and I guess I'd
love to follow that up by asking what do
you think is going to be the future of
tpin in the context that we're seeing a
massive rise in the popularity of tped
infused cannabis it's it's almost its
own entity I'm sure you've seen it what
do you think the future of
turpins H turpins are a fascinating
thing to me um especially being someone
that you know I mean uh was one of the
very first to enter a I separated
cannaboids from tpin and entered them
into a cannabis cff but they wouldn't
accept them because they didn't have a
category for them and didn't know what
to do with them but there is people out
there that remember that and if you look
on my Instagram it shows pictures of it
and the time and place etc etc so you
know i' I've definitely pioneered the
field of tpine isolation and application
uh I I the the trend that you say of of
of utilizing non-cannabis derived tpes
on cannabis I'm not in favor of uh
non-derived cannabis uh tpes into Vape
carts I'm also not a fan of um you know
I've I've pioneered and and and and
established processes and procedures for
all organic tpine isolation and and I
think you know take the Cannabis
separate the active ingredients then
separate the the the tpin all
organically from from fresh frozen
material that hasn't been dried so you
haven't lost any of the the the monot
tanes ETC put those in a bottle then
separate your cannaboids and then after
that you've got the raw ingredients to
mix them back the way you want to you
know and and for or VAP pens or you know
uh I believe those separated Tarpin are
going to be utilized for for that next
generation of Pharmaceutical
applications as well you know um
where're just at the tip of the iceberg
of understanding the medical benefits of
the Entourage effect combined with the
endocannabinoid system on the human body
to be able to formulate the next
generation of cannaboid and turpine
based Pharmaceuticals or wellness
products if you
will yeah it's such a a Big Field that's
unfolding it's almost hard to like
articulate what products are going to
exist in 10 15 years time and as you
said it's going to be
incredible we don't don't know we're
still in our infancy because of you know
Draconian laws and and legalization or
you know illegalization should I say you
know uh I explain to to to you know
sometimes I I deal with you know
pharmacologists or or doctors Etc and
you know they they'll ask me about the
pharmacology of this the whole thing and
I I have to explain to them how how
primitive and how in the infancy we are
meaning
that right now if if if I ask you what
is responsible as some people have given
credit for for cannabinoids in reducing
a a tumor a brain tumor so to speak um
you know so what what is responsible for
that is that uh uh thca or is that a
decarbox Delta
9 and and some people would say well
what's the relevance and the relevance
is is let's let's take for instance a
pediatric cancer patient I could give a
pediatric cancer patient a smoothie with
a th000 milligrams of thca with no
euphoric effects so to speak you know no
uncomfortable effect where the same
can't be said about the decarbox Delta 9
you know you you can give less than a
grain of rice to that pediatric cancer
patient and and they're definitely going
to experience a uncomfortable euphoric
effect so to speak you know so so there
there's there's major relevance there
you know you know I could give you know
10,000 milligrams of thca smoothie to
someone you know without a euphoric
effect I don't know if that'd be healthy
otherwise but you
know too much of a good thing I don't
know but but so you know until just that
basic Foundation can be answered the the
the there's there's you know you've got
to start from point A you know what I
mean there is no answers to any of of
this and today if you go to most modern
doctors and ask them about you know hey
you've got a lymphatic system right
they'll be yeah and it's like you got a
circulatory system and it's like yeah
and it's like do you know anything about
the endocannabinoid system they'll look
at you sideways it's like what I don't
know what you're talking about that
doesn't exist and it's like yes it does
you know it's medically proven da d d d
da and it's like you know yeah so so you
know they don't even teach the
endocannabinoid system in medical school
you know it's interesting to see the new
Awakening of cannabis cannabis as a
medicine as well as the Synergy of
psychedelics uh in here in you know my
local area in uh Northern California
some of the politicians are are you know
wanting to and have in some small
enclaves in Denver Colorado as well you
know started hinting at legal legalizing
certain psychedelics for uh you know
medical purposes for research and Etc a
friend of mine is named Rick doblin runs
something called the multi-disciplinary
association for psychedelic studies as
well as another friend of mine Paul Dy
runs something called the Alexander
research Alexander Shogun Research
Institute um and both of them are at the
Forefront of psychedelic studies for all
psychedelics from you know MDMA to iasa
to ketamine to this that the other thing
and you know um Alexander schan is
responsible for you know tyo and F two
books on you know uh psychedelics that
you know basically you know was uh
instrumental and and identifying and and
and and cataloging you know hundreds and
hundreds of different psychedelic
compounds and amazing and amazing
individual yeah absolutely shout out to
shulan I remember discovering his books
at probably 18 or 19 years old and just
having my mind blown so yeah I was
fortunate enough to meet him at the
Twilight of his career so to speak uhh
Rick dolin I had contacted Rick and told
him that I had isolated cannabis tpin
not mixed with with with with cannaboids
but pure tpine themselves and he was
like wow that's fascinating and the only
person I know that you could really
probably work with in your area would be
Paul Daly from Alexander shulan Research
Institute I was like okay so I contacted
him and he was like here come to the
farm so I went there and didn't realize
who what I
was stepping into where I was going and
how privileged I was to be able to be
invited to go there especially when
Sasha was alive um and in that I've got
photos that you know of the first day
that me and Paul started you know
injecting the torpin into the gcms and
hplt and you know Sasha was there and
you know I got to talk to him about one
of the early early early early papers he
did about uh tpin and Catabus and stuff
and he's said uh I wrote A B book about
tpin and I said sir you've forgotten
more than I'll ever know you know so
it's just it was a sweet T toay and I'm
just privileged that Paul enabled me to
have that experience to know Sasha at
his end wow there you go well look
earlier on when I asked you you know any
notable encounters or stories you said
too many so I think you just proved it
with that answer right there that's uh
incredible that you got to have that
experience I've been very fortunate very
fortunate to meet a lot of really really
incredible people wow okay well look
let's keep it on a positive note I
wanted to ask you what strains have you
been impressed by
recently oh boy
um yeah there's there's too many to
count I mean I I I don't even know him
by name again I know him by photo on on
Instagram you know I just see these
these Cult of ours that are you know uh
and I I explain an anunt could walk
across and never touched biomass it it
could only touch resin glands they're
just covering this product I mean and
and it's hard to keep up with every
every every month there's a new one you
know so you know uh you know don't even
know the names of them don't even take
note of what the names are you know
there's
just every week There's a new latest
hotest product here in the United States
especially since there's so many new uh
legal markets you know I mean I've Got
Friends that let's say uh are purveyors
of the gray market and they uh keep very
much AB breast of the trends so to speak
and you know here in uh California
Northern California I'm sure from many
other places there is uh something
called seses which are uh Black Market
farmers markets where uh your local
grower can show up pay pay to rent a
table and uh people can pay to come
enter and then they go shopping like a
regular farmers market for the latest
newest latest hottest
genetics but as far as like do I have
you know any any super duper favorites
and it's like no because uh you know I
try one then I try another then I try
another then I try another so um you
know between two friends that that work
at the seses uh my friend uh big up
Teddy at the Yus uh can this company um
you know I I I get to see you know the
the best and brightest and newest and
latest and hottest I I I haven't been
judging competitions lately because uh
um it's
uh it's kind of
um I don't know a little bit too
demanding as far as like uh you know a
major amount of samples in a short
amount of time and uh um you know you're
really determining someone's fate kind
of sort of thing so I I I felt
uncomfortable in that position but I
used to judge competitions and found it
kind of
fascinating yeah look that's such an
interesting point which we don't really
talk about much and I'd heard the
sentiment articulated in the context of
of wine judging but haven't heard it in
cannabis as much if at all where you
know you do have to acknowledge the uh
the role of influence and power that
comes with judging and uh for some
people it can really make or break a
business depending on how well they
score um I guess I'd be interested in
asking we've sort of alluded to it and
lightly touched on the topic throughout
the episode but what's your thoughts on
the Modern genan Pool cuz there are many
people who are critical that you know
we're sort of
bottlenecking uh the the genan pool
that's sort of largely driven by cookies
gelato Skittles backbone you see that
common in many strains to today do you
have any thoughts on this do you see it
as a negative where do you think we're
going to go
next my barometer on cultivars is is the
emerald cup because that that is the
heart of Northern California and it is
uh the premier
of competition that where where the real
true Growers of of of Northern
California enter and so the the last cup
I entered I mean last cup I attended you
know there there was literally hundreds
I mean you know I think they stopped at
300 different cultivars of just cannabis
and and and better yet even more
mind-blowing is is the California State
Fair like everybody has a state fair
right in California the state fair not
only acknowledges cannabis but now just
like you a pi competition the the the
California State Fair now has a cannabis
competition that just finished enters
entries I think just this week or
something like that from last year's
Harvest so to speak you know um which
which is to me is just revolutionary I
never ever ever ever someone that you
know was arrested for cultivation and uh
of cannabis ever saw a day where where
cannabis would be judged at a county
fair so you know that's that's about as
mainstream accept acceptable as you can
get at this point and you know so so I
think you know competition both those
competitions uh you know they're they're
blind
competitions th those are are pretty
much going to you know Drive help Drive
the trends of the Next Generation so to
speak you know what I mean will will
will it be sweet will it be Savory will
it be you know your candy flavors of
gelato etc etc or you know what will it
be you know so I I find that fascinating
as well but but a lot of it as you said
is hype driven it's uh you know you know
somebody out there r about it you know
they they they happen to be a rapper
they happen to own multiple dispensaries
they happen to also be associated with
the group that produced major amounts of
genetics and now they're able to march
from City to City talking about how
great their cultivars is and how great
their store is etc etc um you know I I I
I believe that that will probably um
Garner interest let's say you know um
and and help Drive their agenda and
their Trend and there's multiples of
that you know as as well as you know you
see the celebrity Brands you know what I
mean um you know from Willie Nelson to
Snoop Dog to Jim balushi to Martha
Stewart dipping into the the game to you
know I heard I heard at one point the
number one celebrity brand is W palro go
figure more more more so than Whiz
Khalifa or Snoop dogs wow or or Seth Ro
or Seth Rogan's Health plant
I think Seth Rogan's brand gets a
surprising amount of backlash because he
really overprices all his stuff and uh
it seems to seems to not work for him
but the gwenneth ptro one that's
interesting that's kind of funny she's
uh she's had a few funny products she's
released I guess while we're on the
topic of like existing in the modern
Market do you feel that there is a
future for mum and pop businesses in the
market and do you feel there are any
legal changes that might need to occur
to help ensure they ongoing
survival H so yeah I I I I I you know I
write for periodical that would would
would prefer that I don't name names and
and because it's not good for them or me
or anybody else but but but there had
but there was a rise of let's call it
corporations that were funded by
publicly traded Canadian money let's say
that right there's a there's dozens of
them so there's there's no throw in
stock stones at anyone a lot of those
are are now one was just delisted from
the stock exchange uh one has sold the
majority of their millions of dollars of
Assets in cultivation aspects uh Assets
in favor of it's a buyer's market we'd
rather just buy it than produce it
ourselves so um I I see I see a lot of
people that didn't belong in the
industry seized the industry they took
over the industry and they pushed out a
lot of Mom and Pops a lot of people that
deserve to be in this industry that
built this industry H and help get the
laws passed the way they are um but but
I I I hope that with the demise of some
of these corporate entities that didn't
belong in the industry in the first
place it will create a vacuum that will
allow those mom and Pops that were
pushed out to reenter the the industry I
I I know people that that pay $400 an
ounce for marijuana today in California
and and they're happy to do so because
they go to their favorite grower who has
eight lights who who does not cut
corners does all the right things for
all the right reasons and and and and
works their ass off as that past
generation did as those
uh Legacy Growers did for lack of a
better term um For the Love of doing it
not for the love of cash you know um and
and and so you know I've got multiple
friends that would much rather go to
that small mom and pop and spend their
money with them and and I I do as well
and and so um you know and I do proudly
you know and so I I I look forward and
hope that with the demise of of of some
of these corporate entities that that
that it will reinvigorate some of the um
the the mom and pops but more
importantly I I hope that that that the
the investors the people that are
funding those Bad actors uh have have
um now come to realize that the that the
the the the true deserving people to
invest in is is the the the the Legacy
Growers and the people who who got us
where we are today and more so than the
corporates that don't don't deserve and
there can end up burning your cash
getting delisted and and going under you
know as many of them are today yeah 100%
uh support the uh the organic the
passionate the mom and pop businesses
those who deserve to be involved I love
that
sentiment I think that brings us to our
quickfire questions before we wrap
things up so the first one I wanted to
ask you was what's the single most
memorable experience with cannabis
you've had you know it doesn't have to
be the most insanely potent dab but just
the most memorable experience that comes
to mind where cannabis was
involved uh I I think like I told you
that day I consumed my first uh uh
quality con concentrate um that that
right there was you know that you talked
uh or hear interviews with with uh
people about their drug of choice or
something that just went to the Cor
their brain and that right there was you
know a significant moment to
me yeah certainly I can I can understand
your reasoning for that one on the other
end of the spectrum what's a strain that
was really popular all your friends were
hyping it up you were really Keen to try
and then when you finally did you were
left a little bit
disappointed some of the bubble gums
mostly you know what I mean it was just
a I I suspect that most of the bubble
gums I ever tried that smelled like
bubble gum were were artificially
enhanced so to speak with some kind of
uh you know bubble gum essence or
something like that that's probably the
my most disappointing because it smelled
so good it smelled like you want to eat
it it smelled like just like bubble gum
and then like the smoke it was like so
disappointing it was a w w w moment yeah
sure everyone's got their own sort of
stories that's interesting to hear yours
um I'm going to drop you off on a desert
island you can take three strains or
three packs of seeds with you for the
rest of Life what are you going to be
growing three what three strains in the
form of seed yeah like you could you
could take three clones or you could
take three packs of seeds or any sort of
mix I'm going to start with my G13
um geez uh I guess I would try the
spound on the side of the road Dead
Skunk as number
two um I really like Old School
California orange or or Tangi that it
morphed into or you know they say
they're not related but you know a
cultivar that really smells like a
really nice fresh orange I really
enjoyed that
cultivar yeah that's gorgeous to hear
like you hear a lot of um you know
sentiment at times from the American
audience about being burnt out on say
Tang or train wreck or blue dream but i'
like to remind everyone that uh for
pretty much everyone outside of
California they're not burnt out on
those flavors and Tangi I agree
incredible stuff I love
it next question is if you had to start
a seed company with just one pack of
seeds could be your seeds could be
another company's seeds what are you
going to throw your weight behind which
pack you going to
choose uh it's either the G13 or the
purple kush one of the other both of
those have really defined my my breing
so
that's
beautiful all right well look on to the
final question for our interview today
I've got a time machine for you you can
go back anywhere anytime any place get
seeds clone whatever you want where are
you going what are you
getting uh
1983 approx to get that found on the
side of the road Dead Skunk cultivar I I
absolutely loved it the roadkill the one
the original one incredible a lot of
people speculate it's like an Afghan do
you have any ideas um in my conversation
with h sadu Sam Sam the skunk man um who
created skunk number one he told a tale
how his while during breeding there came
a crossroad where his wife preferred the
sweeter cultivar as opposed to the
more skunkie cultivar so he chose to
take a right and go with the site and
forsake the uh more skunky cultivar um
and then
that is how that went but then as far as
the the the consumers I believe that you
know it was Trend driven that you know a
new a new fancy thing came to town and
less and less people started growing
that original skunk and it just faded
away yeah there we go I think hopefully
in time it'll reemerge and we can all
enjoy it again fingers crossed and with
that I think that just about brings us
to the end of it for this one did you
have any comments or shoutouts you
wanted to give just do you Havey it was
a pleasure to meet you and thank you
very much for your time and having me on
and I hope your audience uh enjoys our
conversation and I didn't bore them too
much no no the thanks is all mine it's
been incredible so look I'm grateful to
be joined by one of the industry Legends
no G of the scene a prolific author an
incredible cultivator and truly a heads
head a massive thank you to K of triome
Technologies for joining me today thank
you very much and everybody hit me up on
Instagram I'd love to hear from people
out and about in the
world and there you go friends a massive
shout out to K for taking the time to
join us today and a massive shout out
for you guys supporting the show what do
you think
think I loved
it if you love this episode please
consider supporting both the patreon as
well as the websites of our incredible
sponsors if you're looking to transition
from combustion to vaping check out our
good friends at dap you will not be
disappointed cheap affordable and
Incredibly efficient units likewise
check out our friends at Pulse sensors
if you want to make sure that your
garden is dialed in and you are tracking
all of the variables that are going to
ensure your next Harvest is the best to
date you got to get yourself a pulse
guys it's a
no-brainer in order to ensure that your
garden is pest and pathogen free please
check out our friends at copit they are
the number one in bior predatory
technology the spidex vital sachet have
been a game changer the slow release of
SPID x v will make sure that your garden
is spiderm might free copit thank you so
so so much for your
support likewise a big shout out to our
friends at Organics alive for all the
most incredible powdered organic
products usable in all systems both
organic and hybrid people winning cups
around the globe with their products
it's no surprise because the quality is
second to none a huge thank you to
Organics alive we recommend them highly
please check them out if you want to
take your organic game to the next
level finally massive shout out to our
good friends at seeds here now they got
heavy days beans go check them out guys
I promise you will not be disappointed
they've got all the latest drops the
hottest breeders fem Auto photo period
CBD whatever you need they're here to
help you out a massive thank you to our
friends at seeds here
now and big love to the patreon gang we
love you so much thank you for
supporting the show they got Early
Access to this episode over a month ago
if you want to get extra content please
consider supporting the show you'll
score yourself genetics a whole bunch of
swag from our sponsors and so much
more so that just about brings us to the
end of it for this
one a big thank you to you for getting
to the end yet again and for the
support Big Love is always from your boy
heavy
days signing
off see you