hello welcome to the next episode of the
podcast a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts
as always this episode was brought to
you by our amazing sponsors
420 australia your premier store for
lifestyle and apparel
organic gardening solutions your
one-stop shop for organic gardening
needs to grow that top shelf
and last but not least seeds here now
your number one seed bank guarantee on
satisfaction as well as germination best
breeders there are
check them out
on this episode we're joined by mass
medical strands chat all things genetics
mass medical scene
and more
let's get into it
alrighty so a big thank you and welcome
to one of the fresh faces on the block
mass medical strains thanks so much for
joining us today
cool thank you so much for having me i'm
very excited to be here
so our deviant question from the first
question which is kind of becoming our
new first question what are you smoking
on at the moment
oh i actually just smoked on some star
people
that i grew
a couple months ago so it's really
really cute now
and it's a couple of my last mugs
because i
took a break from perpetual harvest so
i'm just like trying to make my last
stash last me until my next stuff but
yeah some star people i chopped in a
little bit early like eight weeks
instead of nine weeks so it was a little
bit racy but
really really tasty it's pretty much
been my favorite for the last
five years or so at least
and do you find that she kind of comes
into her prime at that point of curing
or it just happens to be where you're at
um i like it after about a month
month and a half yeah probably closer to
a month is like when it starts getting
like really really
really good um
but it's pretty tasty right off the bat
just because like
i don't know maybe because there's not
much chlorophyll it's like so purple
that like it it's got a unique flavor
pretty much when it's smokeable you know
yeah okay
and so you mentioned that you know you
took her eight weeks instead of nine
what is the range of the harvest window
for her like is it like somewhere
between eight and ten or just eight and
nine
um i pretty much always go nine weeks
with her because that's just what i
found is a sweet spot and i think that's
what pretty much everybody agrees is
like
right on nine weeks is perfect but
i don't know she was going a little bit
faster under the cobs so i chopped her
literally and it seems
pretty [ __ ] strong too so sometimes
under led i'll go just over eight weeks
and the cops seem to go even faster than
like the purples
and are you fully
sorry i was going to say are you
converted to the leds now or are you
just still toying around with it before
you transition
um i switched over most of my lights to
leds
and um
i've got a couple
uh i got cmhs and i got the ceramic hbs
from ortlocks that i'm testing out but
mostly led and i've been growing
for
years under different leds and stuff and
i've just always liked them a little bit
better than my hids
yeah okay
so
now if we jump back to our normal first
question what was your first experience
with cannabis
yeah this is a fun one so
um the first time i smoked was with a
friend from new york and
basically me and him were both thinking
about smoking weed because
um
at least for me i grew up
in kind of that mindset where like oh
you know weed is a drug and it's bad and
they taught you in school like
that it's a gateway drug and all that
crap so
initially i didn't think weed was like
anything i would ever touch and actually
one of my best friends like started
smoking weed when we were like
13 or 14 and then i didn't really like
hang out with him much after that
because i was like oh [ __ ] like he's a
bad person now and whatever and then a
few years later
i realized like damn a couple of my
older friends that i look up to that are
really smart and they're successful like
they smoke weed almost every single day
and they're awesome people like i
genuinely respect everything about them
like there's no way that wheat is bad
so i you know eventually i figured out
like weed is not that crazy ass drug
that they tell you like in
middle school and [ __ ] you know um
so
anyways
me and my friend
he came from new york to visit me for
like a week and he brought some weed and
he's like dude let's smoke i just smoked
last week for the first time and it's
awesome
so like we rolled up this joint it was
scentsy star he said and
i just remember like
we went deep into the woods because we
were all scared of getting caught and we
smoked it and
we came out of the woods and i was just
like waiting and i was like dude i'm not
seeing anything like where's the dragons
and [ __ ] flying around in my vision
he just started laughing he was like
you don't
see things it's not like that it's just
a feeling
and
so
i don't know i didn't feel anything
i wasn't
like i didn't know what the hell to
expect but i wasn't experiencing what i
expected and then
um
smoked a bunch of times after that
and i hadn't really been taught how to
inhale properly and then
um
actually i went to europe and i smoked a
few times there and still like you know
nothing really happened but i was like
yeah i like smoking you know it's chill
and it doesn't really do anything it's
fine
so i just smoked my friend and then
this is awesome my friend that i was
staying with in germany he gave me this
dvd and he was like dude you gotta watch
this video it's [ __ ] awesome and i
was like all right sure like i'll get to
it eventually and i never ended up
watching it and you kept asking me to
watch it and i was just like
yeah i forgot like i'll watch it
tomorrow
and then so i get home and i brought the
video home and i open it up
and there's like 2 grams of wheat in
there and i flew back with it not even
knowing
so
um and then this was awesome this is
where i actually got high for the first
time so i just learned how to properly
inhale and i rolled up two joints of it
and
i it was night time i just smoked both
of them to my face by myself and all of
a sudden it [ __ ] hit me like a train
and it just felt like
this feeling watch over me and i
immediately just thought i was going to
die and i was just freaking out like the
whole entire night i was just by myself
and then
like i thought i was giving myself
surgery at one point like it was
ridiculous because i just smoked way too
much and like
it just hit me super hard
and
that was a crazy memorable time just
because like the music that i listened
to that night just like stuck with me in
this special way and like i just
realized like damn this is some powerful
[ __ ] like
i stopped i didn't smoke after that for
a couple weeks and i don't know why i
even tried again but i ended up liking
it a lot after that
and so would you say that was the point
when you kind of really got into it or
like were you still sporadic in your
usage for a while
it was about it was a gradual thing like
i probably smoked once a week or once
every
couple weeks or something and then
just gradually got more into it like
when i started realizing there's
different strains and stuff and like ooh
this weed i like and the sweet i don't
like and like
this one has a different taste and stuff
like that like it started getting pretty
interesting
and
i don't know i didn't really think too
much about it because i was young but i
guess i just liked it for whatever
reason so
just kept smoking it
more and more
and so outside of the uh the scentsy
star you mentioned initially what were
some of the other strains that were
going around in that earliest times like
most notably you mentioned some of them
were catching your attention do you
remember specifically or was it just
kind of like the kind bud type of thing
yeah i remember a few different times um
like the best one that one of the best
smokes i've had in my life was way back
then it was this blueberry
and i got it twice
and i never ever got it again after that
but i remember it so distinctly
it just had this amazing like everything
about it the fur the texture like it was
cured really nice and i don't even know
like
anything about curing but i just knew
like damn the consistency of this it's
like juicy but it's not wet and it's
sticky as hell and it's like so
delicious and i was so good
and i've been growing blueberry plants
all the time looking for the hispino and
just never finding it but
whatever that was i'm still searching
that was
one of my favorites and then smaller i
mean
we got like cushion haze which were just
called kush and haze like there there
wasn't much of a name to it i remember
like my dealer was like yeah kush is
when it's good and haze is when it's not
so good and so i bought the haze and i
was like dude i love the haze
and turns out now like i'm really big
into cedivas
and back then i didn't even know there
was like different
indicas and sativas and the facts i just
knew there was like different names to
it and i never believed the name because
i didn't know if he was making it up but
that haze was pretty good stuff
yeah um
some ak-47
yeah okay
i mean that blueberry comment you made
is one we hear a lot it's almost like
you know blueberry is so prolific but
it's also like it's no one can really
find that one cut at the same time
yeah it's elusive for sure and um
i've noticed i've grown
blueberry from a few different breeders
and
i got one where it had that high and
maybe even had a better high
it was like one of the best highs ever
and it was every single time you smoked
it you just felt like how you felt when
you were like
10 years old like so pure and so amazed
and everything's so perfect and fun and
interesting like just the best mood ever
and super nostalgic
and
but the flavor was [ __ ] horrible and
it wasn't blueberry it was just like
something really good but it wasn't the
plant that i'm looking for
and
now i'm digging into
some clones from different people
so there's this one from new york which
i'm hoping is the one because a lot of
bud from new york comes up here but
we really know as we'll see
yeah okay
that's interesting you say that because
i often have thought to myself when dj
first made blueberry
how how long did it sit there before
they realized it was blueberry because i
can only imagine they didn't find the
insane blueberry fino in the first
couple of seeds they popped and so i
wouldn't be surprised you know what i
mean like i i think that more likely
than not they didn't know there was the
blueberry phenos in there for a while
yeah that's a good point i'm not really
sure like
um
i don't know how consistent his stock
was back then there is now or like
if his goal was the blueberry or if he
just found the blueberry and then kept
going with it or whatever like he said
there could have been all kinds of other
stuff in there too
yeah okay
so
obviously topic near and dear to the
heart of this show chem dog you know
you're in mass did you ever see it
dude so actually i'm not that into chem
personally but i've smoked something
grown by him apparently
and it was [ __ ] really strong because
i smoked one hit and i forgot i even
smoked and i was like what the [ __ ] is
happening to me
and then like i remembered that i smoked
it was just like it was such an
experience
um
and
one of my
kind of friends more of just an
acquaintance like a friend of a friend
apparently his dad is best friends with
captain dog and i was like [ __ ]
i can't tell this dude that i grow
because i don't really tell anybody
locally that i grow especially if i
don't know them well or like i think
they're baby and this kid is kind of
shady so i was like
i can't tell him that i grow like how
how do i get to meet kem without
dropping the fact that i'm a breeder and
stuff because i was just liking it so i
haven't
uh ran into him personally yet but i'm
growing a few different chemicals right
now so
we'll see what's what but i don't know
i'm
it's good wheat for sure but it's not
exactly my taste
so
i've never been super duper into it
personally
yeah no it's interesting it's a very
polarizing type of weed isn't it like
what is it about it that you're not a
fan of i think the most common thing
people say is it's just so
non-functional in many respects
all right yeah i'd probably agree with
that it's not very
functional it just kind of [ __ ] you up
and i don't know there's a lot of weed
that has that effect for me where it
just feels like damn i'm [ __ ] up like
and that's not what i'm looking for i
don't smoke to get [ __ ] up i smoke to
feel good i smoke to
relax i smoke to focus i smoke to feel
better whatever it is but i don't really
smoke to feel like i'm on drugs
specifically i mean sometimes like a
real nice trippy high is nice but
i don't know
i'm not trying to just feel like
debilitated
yeah i know what you mean it can be a
bit full on
so last one i've gotta ask about did you
ever see the mass super skunk grown up
i have not personally no
i wish
oh that's a bummer it's still like such
a small kind of select period an area
when it was around i think
yeah
i'll have to ask a few people about that
but yeah i haven't came across it i
don't know if anybody has it around here
if it's long gone
yeah i mean people say it's around but i
haven't seen it so i'd love to see it
anyway we kind of get back on track for
a second when did you kind of start to
grow yourself you know and more
importantly what were the first strains
you were growing out
yeah so
basically i always like like i told you
how i used to have the impression that
weed was like this really bad thing so
i also thought like if you grow you're
just the worst like you don't grow
you're gonna go to prison like growing
is very bad like it's it's a lot worse
than smoking so for a while i never even
thought about it
and then
one time it was funny it was actually my
mom she was like
she knows that i smoke and she's fine
with it but she was like scared i was
gonna get some lace sweet or something
and she was like you should grow i was
like
you think i should grow really like i've
been thinking about it but i thought it
was like
so dangerous and she's like now just
grow it's safer for you and blah blah
blah
i ended up growing because of that like
that was the final push
and basically
let's see well the first plants i grew
was
the seeds that actually led to star
pupil
and my friends had given me a bunch of
seeds and
basically they were thai and afghani
and he didn't really know anything about
him at all and i didn't know anything
about
anything really like
i just like i'll plant them in some solo
cups like you said to do and i put them
on my windowsill
and then
eventually like they were getting all
stringy and my friend was like dude you
gotta get that under light or put it
outside
and i was like
all right i went to a grocery store and
they were like are you a badger flower
and i was like i don't know man i just
need a light like i i did so much
reading and nothing made any sense to me
but i was just like
you know they're in they're in the cups
and they're
five inches tall but they're not doing
they're not growing fast and i had them
for like almost two months and they're
like
they look like two-week old season
so i got a light
put them in a closet and
i only had six plants so
um i ended up putting one of them
planting it out in the woods and the
rest of them that flowered out indoors
and
one of them was a male and by this point
i was obsessed like by the time they
were actually
getting to flower i was reading every
single day about growing and asking my
friends and learning stuff like
my friend told me um
that you could put fan on them to make
them stronger like you know because the
wind and stuff
and that just blew my mind because i was
like
people know [ __ ] about growing weed like
it was i didn't realize that there was
knowledge up there
and then
i just started getting obsessed and i
would like talk to people every day and
read and learn
and then so i was like all right i'm
even going to make some seeds it seems
easy enough so
each plant i just may see like one
bottom branch but i was mainly just
focusing on growing the plants because
like i said i had one male
and then
yeah so
one of the plants i actually named it
star pupil because it was super
symmetrical and it just looked so
awesome
and then so i just named each plant
something they just had funny names and
stuff and
um
basically i grew those out they were
awesome
the star pupil was like this half purple
half green kind of it's not the exact
star people i have now but it's the
mother to it
um but anyways it was
really nice it finished in 52 days and i
remember reading
that everything had to go eight weeks
that's just what i thought was like why
is it done sooner and why is this tall
one not finished yet and i had to let it
go longer and like
i was reading every day but there was
just so much to learn
and
so i harvested those and i smoked them
and cured them and saved the seeds off
each one labeled separately and all that
and then
my next run i was like all right autumn
flowers i've been reading autoflowers
are the best i can't wait to grow a song
and i ordered some
and i grew them and i was just like
what the [ __ ] is this
i was so disappointed with the
autoflowers in comparison to like the
first plants that i grew that was like
so amazing and super strong and they all
had their own unique character and then
i grew like four different strands of
autos that i purchased so i knew the
strain names and i was like
is blue dream and northern lights
the same as blueberry bliss like i don't
get it they're all the same
and i was like
i don't know if it's the autos or
strange or [ __ ] or what but i was
just figuring [ __ ] out so i was like all
right
i really like that star people playing
i'm just gonna grow a bunch of seeds
that i made off of that and then one of
them ended up being my star people and
i've been keeping the clone of her ever
since
so the the star people that you offer
now is that like an f2 of the initial
strain you made or where's it at
so that's actually an s1 the seeds that
i released and um
the thing is
i had this star people clone and i've
been growing it and it was super good
and i was like what if my clones don't
make it and what if i [ __ ] up and lose
it like i better make some seeds and
so i was like how do i get it
what's what's the best way to make seeds
of this like i just want this plant i
don't want to cross with anything else
because it might be worse or better or
different but i want this like this is
awesome
so i learned about like making feminized
seeds and how you could trust the plant
to themselves
and so basically
i made us ones of it and some people are
saying like if you grow out s once
they're going to be the exact same as
the mom
and other people were saying no they're
going to be all over the place and
they're going to hurt them and they're
going to suck i was like [ __ ] it i'll
just try it
and honestly i got really lucky that
for whatever reason when you s1 the star
pupil every single plant is like spot on
to the star pupils super super close to
the mother so
that's what um that's what the star
pupil seats are and then
since then obviously i got into actual
breeding and making regular seeds and
doing some line work and stuff like that
but starter pupil seeds they're always
just s ones because it's like
the most perfect representation of the
bomb
yeah that's awesome and so are you
considering doing like a back cross or
even like a cubing process down the line
yeah i'm actually working on some right
now and they're all
in seedling stage right now so i'm just
waiting to see what they do basically
and go from there um
i've done a lot of different outcrosses
and stuff and i'm working on some back
crosses and some femme back crosses with
a nice s1 that i found
and
just messing around with different
things to see what i can come up with
and so if you were to kind of think long
term about it and you were going to do
maybe an extended back crossing project
with the idea that the initial mail you
use is probably not going to be really
present after a few back crosses but
maybe some of the characteristics from
it could be like maybe things you could
improve on the star pupil with that in
mind what type of things would you be
looking for to bring you know if you
were going to do say a cube project you
know what is something maybe a male
could bring to the table that would be
an improvement
yeah definitely um
something that i like about a lot of the
other plants that i've created is that
um like for example the pu tang has a
really really nice stretch where you can
veg that thing to be like four and a
half tall and then you flower it and
it's like four and a half feet tall with
like
a [ __ ] ton of branches and it's just
like this monster plant where you don't
really have to veg it that long so
i would probably put something like that
into it just like some more vigor
um shorten up the veg time a little just
because that's the style that i usually
agree with for other stuff
um and then
it yields pretty good but you could i
mean i probably try to add a little bit
of yield to it
is yield something you consider when
you're breeding or is it really like a
peripheral consideration
um yield is
not too important but
i don't want to say i don't care about
it because if something yields really
low i'm gonna toss it unless it's just
super super special um
like the rick's pupil is my low sealing
strain which i don't even offer anymore
but it's such a
really good smoke so
um
it was worth you've been around for a
while
and then i kind of made things that i
think
were a little bit better and yielded a
lot better so it's like all right
um you know rick's people like
people who want it they can get it like
i'll make more as freebies but
i like everything to at least have like
a medium to high yield depending on what
it is but
the main thing that i really breed for
is like the vibe implant
how it is when you smoke it like what
you've
what you feel when you smoke it what you
experience how you feel after you smoked
it like you know some stuff you can
smoke it you feel great and then
afterwards you feel super drained and
shitty and
i don't even like that
i like something where you can smoke it
you enjoy it
and then you come down and you can
you know like
exist you don't have to smoke again to
feel good like you can you might even
feel better
after you've smoked it like you might
have a nice experience where you're like
life is [ __ ] awesome like i feel
uplifted now
even after you're not high anymore like
that's the kind of stuff i like stuff
that just leaves you feeling really good
and so out of your lineup what do you
think best represents that
um
probably the star pupil especially from
the feedback that i've been getting from
people lately like
it kind of blows my mind because
i really like it as a plant but i know
that everyone's different so every time
somebody else likes it as much as i do
it's like really really cool
um
besides the star pupil
i have
a couple of sativas like the deadly
sativa is really really powerful
and
that one's too much for local but if you
smoke a very small amount of it super
super uplifting and refreshing
and then
the prayer pupil for sure like i still
remember the first time that i smoked
that 33 vino that i got
and that was just such an uplifting
experience and like actually the old
timer's hey zoo it was a great night i
was up all night and smoked it at 10 and
probably stayed up till like six in the
morning from that [ __ ] and it was like
i like the stuff where you smoke it and
you make memories you know like you
remember when you smoked that strain
because it was so unique or such a good
time whatever not just like
something that blends in with the rest
and you fell asleep on couch or
something like that's not fun
old time is haze that's an interesting
one we don't hear about too much do you
plan on releasing any crosses with that
um i'm not sure so i made the cross just
to see what would happen because it was
a crazy plant you know like
took them 17 weeks of flower and then 19
for the green peanut
and i really like that 17-week purple
female
um
so
i made a few different beans on them and
i wasn't really thinking of releasing
them because i was just like these are
gonna be wacky or people aren't gonna
want this like you know the saying how
everyone says oh i want a really gnarly
sativa and then the other dude says no
you actually don't you just think you
want that it's always true like
when you get to that point where you're
like here these seeds will take 17 weeks
to flower you want to grow them
everybody says no even though they ask
for it until that point so
it's kind of like
people
people think they want it and i don't
know if they actually do
but
i made them kind for myself and for my
friends to dig through and see what
happens but i ended up getting a lot of
beans off them
off the magoo cross because that was a
pretty big plant so
maybe i mean i've only seen a few of
them grown out i'd like to see more of
them grown out and i got to grow some
myself
um because my friends have been growing
them so
yeah i want to see what those do and
then we'll go from there
they might become available i gave out
some as freebies so we'll see and then
the star people ultimate days those are
just for me and friends so
i've got some of those uh just starting
to flower now and i'm hoping to find
some cool clone only purple haze kind of
pupil haze whatever we'll see what
happens really
yeah that sounds interesting i mean just
out of curiosity with those old-timer
blue magoo crosses what did the
flowering time work out to be because
something i've noticed from toying
around with the magoo myself is it's
such a consistent eight week plan and so
when you pair it with that 17 weaker
does it just meet in the middle or do
you get some that just fall all over the
spectrum
um well like i said i've only seen a few
of them so far
and
basically it seems like there's a magoo
dominant fino that goes a little faster
but it's probably some kind of 10 12
weekish thing
and then the haze one
seems to be like
i think it's around 14 weeks or
something so it is a little bit shorter
but it's still super long so we kind of
met in the middle a little bit
yeah but i don't know how much variation
is going to actually be in those
okay and so if we just loop back to a
point you made a moment ago you
mentioned you enjoyed professor p's
photography are you into photography
slash would you want to get into it more
so eventually
yeah i'm definitely super into
photography
and
um he's definitely an inspiration of
mine
when it comes to photographing cannabis
plants and flowers and all that
um i've just always been drawn to the
way that he captures the flower
and the lighting like it's really hard
to get good lighting compared to just
like
average lighting like if you want to
make it look like one of his photos
you got to take 100 shots and got to be
moving two or three flashes around and
really like
trying hard and like that i like just
when you see a flower and then you try
to portray it the best way you possibly
can
that's really cool
and it's a lot of fun to me i'm usually
taking pictures in the garden almost
every day and i post way too much on
instagram
but
i don't know a lot of times i have asked
it because
i'm just trying to show the plant and i
don't take the plant out and put it in
front of a black background every single
day but i like the changes day to day
and flowers i'm always
shooting photos of everything i think
yeah so do you think there's a
really strong kind of link between
having good photos and like sales
because one might assume so but you also
might think oh there's some pretty big
name guys who don't really take good
photos so to speak
oh you know what's crazy is that a lot
of my half-assed cell phone pictures
that i post will end up getting like one
or two thousand likes and then i'll take
a photo that took me an hour to get the
perfect shot and it will get like 190
likes and like zero comments so
i don't know like i don't know what
people are looking for because i think
they're looking for some different
things in the photos compared to what
i'm looking for but
um that's why
i've been posting like
whatever photos
i take like some of them are just shitty
phone pictures
and
people love them for whatever reason
maybe because it's even more real it's
more of a real experience they feel like
damn that's what it would look like in
my garden
if i was looking at it like that's not
some
crazy high-def camera and photoshop and
unreal expectations like
like the modeling industry you know how
everything's like fake so maybe they
like seeing the real stuff more
and so i mean if we look at the opposite
end of what you were just talking about
how do you feel about breeders who
outright photoshop i mean do you think
like if whatever people want to do with
their photos that's cool by you or do
you think it should really kind of be a
true representation
nobody should photoshop their photos
um obviously people are putting filters
like instagram filters you got to
sharpen and the contrast and whatever
and
i think
most people i would hope and tell the
difference between like a realistic
photo versus like
when they put it in photoshop and they
change the hue and then you got this
these overly red pistols not like the
natural pink ones you can find like
sometimes you just see really really red
hairs with like a brownish tinge to the
bud and the leaves are like
they're not even red anymore they're
like
super just like
blown out and there's pixels in the
colors like if you see stuff like that
is photoshop and it's just complete
garbage
in my opinion you should be posting like
realistic photos
um
yeah and i like
professor p's photography and like team
terpene does a really nice job
especially with like his studio shots
and
a few other guys like
i like to see the stuff where they take
the time to put on a good lens and put
some nice fleshes in there
and get the angle right
but
you shouldn't really be photoshopping or
artificially modifying anything
unless it's just like light levels to
just you know make the background a
little darker or something like that's
fine but that's about it i don't want to
see modified colors i want to see what
it really looks like
yeah i know what you mean and i mean a
quick little shout out to uh photos i
love i was noticing the other days uh
green dot dave he does some really nice
photos yeah
that's actually i was thinking of him in
my head but i couldn't remember the name
while i was saying those other two
people yeah it was only this morning i
was like yeah he does some good photos
so
something i wanted to quickly jump on
what is your general growth style
because you mentioned you're into the
leds and the cobs but you know are you
organic are you bottled nutrients give
us the rundown
oh yeah i love to talk about this
because to me it's so so important to
grow organically
so to answer your question i grow
organically in soil
and
in my opinion that's the best way to
grow period for a lot of reasons the
first reason being
for beginners
and i actually
learned this at the grow store they told
me why they push organics to beginners
because i was like every other grow
store i go to
they always try and sell you chemicals
but the one that i shop at which is
green harvest hydroponics they're
awesome and
they
teach a lot of people to grow
organically even when they're a first
time grower
and
it's because it's just easier
plain and simple you're not going to
[ __ ] up if you
are growing synthetically there's a good
chance you can kill a plant by
over fertilizing it or getting your
whatever your chemicals all [ __ ] up
whatever the hell they do um i mean i
i think it's all kind of
really
i don't know since that growing is not
my style i very very rarely smoke
anything grown with nutrients at all
because i'm super sensitive to it
and i feel it in my body and i've met
other people that are the same way and
some people are way more sensitive than
i am
[Music]
i met some people that are like i can't
smoke weed because and then they'll name
like
something like oh it [ __ ] with my
thyroid or it [ __ ] with my lungs or my
throat and i feel it for the next two
days
and then i'm like try organic and i give
them something organic just a little
nugget and smoking and they're like i
didn't have that problem i always have
and i'm like yeah because you're
probably reacting chemicals that are in
the bud whether you know it or not
99 of the wheat out there is grown with
chemicals
um
and
99 of the growers are taught that that's
how you grow weed
and when i had my first plants that i
believed out they were in soil from my
backyard which i put into pots and then
they were under led lights
and
at one point i was having an issue
and it turned out that my light was too
close so it was like bleaching them
and so i went to a grocery store a
different store and i showed the photos
and they were like
dude bro you got to be hitting it with
some newts bro your place is going to
die and so they gave me some nudes and i
poured them in and i fried the hell out
of my plants
and i lost like probably almost 50 of
the leaves on them just within a few
hours were totally like
crinkled and crunched in yellow and
white like super gnarly and that was the
one and only time that i felt them any
nutrients because i was like that's not
natural what the hell did i just do
and luckily they didn't die and i was
able to keep growing but
there's just so many things like that
um so if you're a beginner or if you're
learning
it's just easier to go with organic but
that's
it's healthier too but i would say my
favorite reason for growing organic is
just getting the best expression out of
the plant
um
and doing it first try doing a second
try if you [ __ ] up a little bit um i see
a lot of nutrient growers that are like
yeah i'm on my six to run with this cut
and i finally got dialed down
and
usually with organic the plant dials
itself in because the plants choosing
what it wants to take in from
the soil
and the roots are interacting with whole
the living stuff in your soil those
little microbes and whatever
and
you know plants do really well in
organic and
pretty consistently so um
sometimes you run into an issue but
usually it's straightforward you can get
a plant whether it's a cedar a clone you
put it in some good dirt and you grow it
and it's incredibly simple
and
it takes 5-10 minutes a day you go water
your plant you make sure your air is
moving around you check all your basic
things like temperature and humidity
and
it it's just foolproof so
and you can scale it up i actually went
to this giant
operation in maine where it was
no-till and it was like 99 lights or
something like that
and every single planet was organic just
fed nothing but water
and they were huge and they were doing
major major production here they had a
huge crew of people working every single
day there so
when people say you can't scale it up
it's [ __ ] it's just that they don't
know
how to do it they haven't tried
they haven't looked into it enough but
yeah to me organic is just the best way
to do it
i 100 agree just to uh clarify does that
mean that you're pretty much mostly like
an amended soil and you just water only
for the most part
yeah exactly so
my basic growing style is this um
i get a super soil that's called mission
mix
and i've also used other soils that are
similar and they all do about the same
thing this is just the one that i like
the most but
um and brand works as long as it's
specifically super soil versus not just
like
regular potting soil that's not going to
have enough stuff it's not going to be
tailored for the cannabis plant it's
just kind of for growing so
you want to get something that's made
for growing weed
plant it in there
and
basically
if it's an indico plant
i'm going to transplant it into its
final container one or two weeks before
i flip to flower
and if it's a sativa plant where
uh
the roots will grow a lot more when you
flip it into flower you can kind of
transplant it right before flip like on
the day of flip and then just
put it into flour right there
and that's just the basic technique for
growing plants in super soil which
always seems to work good for me
and i've also got a bunch of no-till
pots where
i'm on a bunch of them are just second
round right now but then i've got some
better third fourth and fifth round
and i'll just add some amendments to
them each time they have worms living in
them and they're bigger sized pots and
they're awesome and then you don't have
to throw away soil without binding soil
oh yeah
and so have you found that on those pots
where you're on the
fourth or the fifth cycle for example
that it's kind of getting better with
time because that's something which is
commonly uh you know spouted by the
organic uh preachers basically
um
a little i don't really know it kind of
depends because some plants like them
more than others and sometimes you run
into a little issue where all of a
sudden your plants aren't in a yellow
and then next week looks good again so
it's definitely kind of shifting around
and
constantly adjusting and stuff but
everything ends up doing really well
regardless of if it's like first round
or fifth round they've all been doing
pretty good
yeah
so when you do grow out those more
sativa i mean that's pretty much all you
grow do you find that they are a little
more sensitive than say the odd indica
that you run
um
sensitive maybe doesn't like
hermaphroditic or
oh um
the only
challenge i've had recently was those
old timers hazes
um they all got super deficient
somewhere in week
10 or 12 a flower and they were in a
second round
no-till pot
and i was like all right i'm gonna save
these then so i fed them with some
um some teas like dragonfly earth
medicine and i put some amendments into
the soil
and then they got way over fed right
away and they just started frying and
they like
it totally went the opposite direction
and i was like oh [ __ ] this is not going
to go well and then a couple weeks later
they bounced back and they started
flowering more and putting out new
flowers because it was just flowers
forever so
um that was definitely the most finicky
thing that i've grown in a while most
things are fairly simple
the only
way that i've [ __ ] up upon a sativa is
not enough root space
or not enough soil really
um then it might get deficient before it
finishes because if it's flowering 12
weeks versus eight might need a little
bit more nutrition to carry it that far
yeah so
i thought i've been pondering over for a
while is
every now and again i'll talk to a
newbie and they'll be like oh and a
group purple haze or like you know
clearly like they haven't looked into
the specifics at all and you kind of
like no that's not a beginner's plan at
all and then you're not even going to
find the thing you're looking for but
anyway i digress
when you do grow out these haze plants
or you know something akin to the purple
haze so to speak these 17 weeks and
whatnot i was trying to think what is it
about these plants which specifically
makes them hard to grow
and i was thinking about it and i think
the the best way i could pinpoint it is
that it's kind of what you mentioned
about if you give them extra nutrients
they just start to bloom more growth and
it can almost just stretch it out
indefinitely do you think that is the
primary challenge with these longer
growing plants or do you think it's just
a variety of other things as well
um
so the common thing that i hear from
people
is
the first concern is always space
they're like i have x amount of height i
got five feet of height i can't grow
sativas or
i don't want to another thing is just
the bloom times people don't have the
actual patience to go that long which i
do understand but
the thing is you can put one of those in
the corner and have the rest of your
tent be like
an eight week indica and then
when those are done you rhyme and your
old timer's haze is still going for
another cycle or two of your next
harvest and then those will finish up
and then your haze is almost done
so
i mean the patience thing is like just
dedicate a little corner to it and get
used to it
and for me when i'm growing long time
satives i'm not really thinking about
like when's it gonna be done
it's a really really nice plant to be in
the moment with and just appreciate that
plant every day or whenever you feel
like spending some time with it
um just spread it and enjoy it and smell
it
because
i don't know a lot of growing it's
always like oh what am i gonna grow next
what's what's coming down what's going
in and you're always focusing on later
and i always try to remind myself to
like focus on the present how beautiful
everything is like right now that i have
so
the sativas really teach you to do that
because
if you think about what's coming down
you're just gonna stress out because
it's not anytime soon but if you're
looking at it and
you're just appreciating it
it's almost like a blast well it is a
blast to the past but
it's it's like a step backwards in
cannabis evolution really because you
see these they're not even bugs they're
barely buds they're just strings of
calyxes but they're all near each other
and you can imagine like if you squish
them next to each other it almost
becomes like a modern bud
and
i don't know just stuff like that but i
got a lot of topic from the question so
what was the question again
no that that's that's awesome let's keep
going with this because that's like you
just summarized exactly how i feel i was
talking to a friend just the other day
about how i was saying to them i don't
even get excited about what i'm going to
harvest because i've been thinking about
that already for so long and now i'm
already thinking about what's going in
next and so by the time i'm actually
harvesting the crop i'm already like i'm
really excited for the seeds i'm
germinating but what you said is
essentially just kind of like
mindfulness for cannabis growers right
like live in the moment not in your head
right
yeah absolutely and that's actually why
i took a break from doing perpetual
because i've been perpetual since my
third
row ever and
i just took my first perpetual break
and that was the [ __ ] worst idea but
i thought it would be awesome because i
was like yeah really well it was a good
idea because it made me appreciate
everything a little more and slow down
which was the goal of it but
the problem was i didn't have stuff to
smoke and i'm like trying to make these
grams last a couple months but anyways
it's
you're always in the cycle of like
you have stuff midway through bloom and
then you've got this new
bunch of strains that you're popping
seeds of and you have stuff that's
almost ready to go into flower that
you're not even excited about anymore
because you're more excited about your
ceilings and you're just waiting for
your flower to come down and that that's
not a good place to be i've seen a lot
of people that are in that kind of
zone perpetually and
it's it's more awesome to just
treat every plant as something special
that it is like when you're in flower go
appreciate those flowers when you're in
your drying or curing stage
appreciate your work right there and
don't give up like
keep focusing on that as if it was your
only plan because in that moment it is
the plan in front of you is
all you have
so
just kind of paying attention to every
single stage and then you go into your
bedroom
and like you know don't just water them
and be like all right boring you gotta
really
look at the structure and
give them some stem rubs and smell them
look at what kind of different funny
leaves are on different plants and who's
praying and who's grouping and
like when you got a whole bunch of the
same strain be like all right this one's
a little stretchier and this one's
shorter like
just spend more time staring at your
plants like
all of them and be excited for them all
because
if you have a plant that you're not
excited about you shouldn't be growing
it
and that's something i learned when i
was like growing a really really lot of
weed
and half of it was stuff that i was just
growing because i had it
i didn't even want to smoke it because i
didn't like it
and then i learned like
there's
no room for those plants like just get
them out of there give them away or
if you have to just compost them and dry
them out and put them back into your
soil but
don't grow something
if the vibe isn't right don't grow it
just
because you have it grow because you
want it and because you're excited about
it and you'll have a lot more fun
yeah definitely in the words of uh mr
bob hemphill
not library status
but uh
so then that brings me to the point then
pheno hunting this is something near and
dear to my heart because it loops back
to something you just mentioned with
organics it's it's so easy to finna hunt
because as you said you do things right
the plan presents itself to you
so with that being said you know are you
pretty ruthless with the pheno hunting
things have to be pretty good to make
the library status and then as a
follow-up for people out there who are
in that boat that you just mentioned
where maybe they grow on some things
they're not that keen about do you push
people to fino hunt more like or do you
think just find a few plants you like
and then stick with them for a while or
what's your gig
yeah so
when i'm clean one thing um i'm super
super picky
because
um even if i'm not female hunting and
i'm just trying to grow like
one or two plants or something i'm still
picky as hell but
um the point is like a lot of people i
understand because seats are expensive
and whatever but
a lot of people they won't throw away
anything because they're just like oh
you know like i paid for that or like
it's a plant and i used to like never
even want to buck a leaf off a plant in
the first place because i was like i
don't want to hurt it it's so special
and now it's more of like
i don't know i guess i call a lot of
[ __ ] plants a lot of times if i'm
pheno hunting something and i know i
only have room to flower 20
i'll start 250 beans anyways and weed
them out through beds
even if i'm just going to flower 10
because like
the more of the selection you have the
better plant you're going to find unless
you just get lucky you can also plant
one single seed and get lucky find
something really awesome and it don't
happen but
if you pop a whole bunch of seeds if you
have the ability to whether you're gonna
grow out all of them or maybe give some
away friends like if i can't flower
everything i'll give away a few nice
looking ones to friends and be like hey
if this is any good just get me a cup
pack
and it never ends up being anything good
but
uh
usually
at least with my own lens when i'm
reading
um i know what i'm looking for so
i can weed out a lot in veg and then
i know pretty good idea like
which females i want to grow about just
based on their growth patterns and then
see if i find the flower
on flower qualities that i'm looking for
after that but there is a lot to be said
in stem rub
people don't really realize that
um a stem rub on one specific day
doesn't tell you much but if you stem
rob every plant maybe every week let's
say you got like 50 plants
stem rub all of them every week and take
notes on every single one because
they're going to change
and some of them will give you that hint
that you're looking for like for example
when i was looking for my prayer tower
male i had grown prayer tower a few
different times before and i knew which
vino i liked i was trying to find a male
that had that feel which is you know a
little bit difficult
and i was stem rubbing all the plants
and on one specific day
the male that ended up being the one had
the smell i was looking for but it never
had it again but none of the other
plants ever had it
and so i went with that one that was
like this has to be the one it has this
soapy hashy
smell that i'm
looking for it's like this creamy so i
don't even know how to explain it but
it ended up being the one and then
it passed on the exact tricks i'm
looking for
in the flower department and i mean it
checked all the other boxes too but
that's just one example of how like the
stem up can tell you a lot but it won't
just tell you every day you gotta really
check them out on different days
stuff like that
yeah i agree and something i've noticed
and i'd love to run by you is
you can actually get different uh smells
whether you rub the stem at the new
growth where you know the shoot is
rather green versus say you know a
little bit more woody harden growth down
low do you take note of the differences
or do that at all
yeah i usually rub probably three
quarters of the planet just by habit and
then
i don't know sometimes i'll check
different parts of it and if i find
something interesting i'll
i'll take another figure and rub a
different part of the plant like really
look into it and then
if there's no smell
or not much smell i'll try and rub like
a different part of it so
definitely i think it's almost like how
if you have a big clone or a big mom and
you're taking clones
and like one round all the top clones
root and the bottoms don't poop that
well and then the next round it's the
other way around it's kind of like how
the plant has different levels of
hormones in different areas at different
times so
i guess it's similar to that where like
one day the bottom might smell more one
day the top might smell more or they
might smell differently at different
times
just things moving around with the plant
maybe it has to do with day and night
too i don't really know
yeah and i understand and so do you
generally take clones from the top and
the bottom or just wherever it seems to
work at the time and what do you use to
stimulate rooting given that you're
organic
oh yeah so clones on um
i always used to take from the bottom
because i learned that from the internet
or from whoever it's like bottom clones
root faster because they're closer to
the roots
and then the last year or two people
like when i started telling people about
that they're like dude you gotta take
them from the top so you get way better
clones so now i've been doing a bit of
both because i've always had great
plants from taking roots
uh taking cuts from the bottom
so i don't know you can do either way i
don't even think it matters i mean i
guess the next step would be to take a
bottom clone and a top clone and flower
them side by side and see if there's a
difference but i really don't think
there's gonna be as long as it's a
healthy clone
a healthy mother plant and it stays
pretty healthy while rooting and going
through that transformation or being a
branch to an implant as long as it
doesn't like almost die or something
like it's it's gonna be fine um
you know a clone is a clone as long as
it's healthy and happy so
yeah what i do for clones is very simple
um
just take an arrow cloner like it's a
bucket full of water and there's an air
stone and an air pump and
the water is bubbling around
and just takes some cuts like i don't
know
i used to take really small cards i
didn't know any better and now i take a
little bigger ones but
at least
probably
six seven inches or something is good
and like maybe ten inch cut is be nice
usually the big ones are stronger plants
from the get-go so
um
you know whatever it doesn't really
matter that much but basically just cut
off a branch and stick it in the water
and then two or three weeks later as
rooted it's really really easy you don't
have to do anything
one time
i dipped them all in aloe and they'll
die so it's like all right none of that
like going back to straight water it
works for me like i'm not gonna change
anything
and then one time
um i had some really difficult cuts that
i couldn't root i forget what strains
they were but somebody was like yeah
just pretend it's a deep water culture
just throwing all the nuts in there like
super diluted and i did that and they
[ __ ] rooted like monsters and they
were growing in the cloner and they had
like these huge like
unbelievable overkill roots so
if you need a boost you can put [ __ ] in
there but
i never do because it's not organic like
i did it that one time and i just
couldn't get something to root or
survive or whatever but
um
the only thing that i help them with
sometimes i don't even do it every time
but when i remember is i'll spray them
with a foliar spray like the first four
days or so
and that'll just feed them a little bit
but you don't even have to do that like
i usually
i just have like
a separate layer like underneath one of
the tables in my bedroom and i just have
like lights under there and i put my
corners under there and just fill them
up and then
you just have to remember to
check the water maybe
once a week like put some
you know empty it out clean it out put
some water in or just top it off once in
a while
and it's it's just waiting and basically
forgetting and then remembering then
they're done
yeah and heck you can't get much more
organic than plain water right
do you generally like to push people to
constantly be popping new seeds and
pheno hunting or are you kind of okay
with the idea that people just run the
same thing for a while
um
luckily most of the people that i know
not all of them but most of them are
pretty into popping seeds and
that's cool because i love giving them
seeds and watching them grow them out
but
in general
i definitely tell people
never stop popping seeds um similar to
like
what bodhi said
just every seed is its own
plant and it's it's like
such a special thing inside there
and like yeah all these elite clones and
popular clones are most of them are
pretty good some of them
whatever but
i mean they're great plants but it's not
that hard to find your own
plants that are just as good or better
or different and
um in my opinion when you plant a seed
that plant you know is really your plant
it has an emotional bond with you and
you have one with it
and
that plant is it's just going to be
closer to you than the clone that you
got from someone else no matter what
you can love a clone too but
when you watch a plant grow up from seed
i mean
you're tearing it like from birth you're
literally giving it life and that plant
is gonna work with you
and
um i forget where i heard it but
somewhere in africa where they grow
cannabis
they say
you have to grow your own cannabis for
it to be the best for you and if
somebody else grows it or if you steal
it from someone or you take it or get it
from someone it's not going to help you
the same way as if you grow the plant
for you
because that plant is working for you
and you are working for it and it's just
a special bond
but
um anyways yeah so popping seeds is like
you're gonna find all these unique
plants every single plant you grow is
gonna be something that nobody else has
grown even though it's yeah it's the
same strain and maybe something
stabilizing whatever but
you have
that individual child
that's
your own plan and it's going to adapt to
your environment immediately start
expressing itself based on what you give
it
um including emotions actually but even
just down to environment and all that
and you're gonna find some really
special plants and i never really
thought it was that fun growing other
clones because
i was like
you know why do i want to grow
the same thing that the next guy has and
the next guy and the next guy and
5 000 people also had this
like
now i'm a little bit more open to it
because i think it's cool to see what
that plant is the same as seeing what
any seed is it's like very cool it is
another plant like let's see what's so
good about it or like looks awesome
smells awesome whenever i want to smoke
it there's plenty of reasons to grow a
clone for sure
but
growing seeds is just like
that's
that's how all those clones came to be
obviously they came from seed that
someone popped and you never know you
might be the next person that pops a
seed whether it's you under 500 you
might pop that next elite clone only
blah blah amazing plant that everyone
wants to grow and smoke
and
if you don't pop seeds you'll never know
that's exactly it
so
again looping back to a point you made
earlier on you said that you know it's
really important to you like the the
vibe of if you're going to use someone
else's work like their vibe things like
that i guess that means that there's
maybe certain people's work who you
wouldn't want to work with but the flip
side of that is how would you feel if
someone who you didn't really vibe with
they fell into that category of you
wouldn't work with their gear because
you don't agree with maybe personal
aspects or whatever how would you feel
if they then started to incorporate your
work into their gear is that you know
would that take you off or is it kind of
just a part of the game
um
i mean i would have to be okay with it
because
honestly i believe anybody should be
able to do whatever they want with
whatever plan is in their possession so
if somebody wanted to breed with my
stuff luckily everybody that's bred with
my strength so far has been friendly
with me was really really nice and
they've done some amazing work there's a
stellar collision with demand seeds and
that was something we agreed upon like
hey grow these and breed with them and
we'll do this collab kind of thing and
whatever so
that's just one of them there's a few
others out there too and then there's
some
people that read with some of my stuff
that
like you know they didn't ask me but i
saw it and i was just like holy [ __ ]
that looks amazing like that's really
cool i'm happy to see that like
thanks for choosing my strain versus
someone else's like that means a lot to
me i think it's really cool
um
so i don't know i mean if somebody that
i didn't like
bread with one of my plants
i'd probably like them a little more i
don't really know like
i i wouldn't be mad like it's fine i'd
probably still be honored because it's
just like
you know they like that plant it works
for them
and
they're gonna put their own twist to it
maybe they'll even make something that i
don't like like maybe they'll put
cookies into it and i [ __ ] hate
cookies but like if somebody
you know they want to make their own
version
of whatever
like let's say somebody wants to make a
pupil hybrid with some
with like an og or cookies or something
it's like cool do it like i want to see
what it comes out like i probably still
grow it out even if i don't really like
you i normally wouldn't grow plants from
people i don't like but if there's like
something really cool about it i can put
things aside
because
i don't i try not to have problems with
people like if they have a problem with
me then maybe i'm not gonna like them so
much but
it's pretty
i don't know there's a lot of love in
scene so i try to focus on all the
positives all the time
yeah of course and so in general where
do you sit on the issue of
say permission or good grace i mean i
know you mentioned earlier that you had
the conversation with professor p
is that kind of ideally how you would
like it to go down
with if you were going to use someone
else's work or like for example let's
just say you couldn't really get in
contact with them would you just kind of
go ahead like what would you be your
protocol
yeah so
basically
the best case scenario of course is one
like that where you can talk to the
person who's bred the client you want to
work with and be like hey do you mind if
i do this and then when i talk to them
they even say like yeah these are going
to be for sale at some point they might
be sold as an f1 they might be work
whatever it is i'll explain them what i
want to do
and then if they say that's okay then
that's like the best case scenario and
if they said it wasn't okay i wouldn't
even do it at all
but there's other cases where you just
can't get in contact
with the people or maybe it's something
that's so used already that you're like
[ __ ] it it's fine like gorilla glue 4 is
the only like elite clone that i've read
with and
i was kind of like
all right
i don't think they'll get mad at me like
there's 700 different glue hives out
there already and like i actually feel
like i can make something unique with it
so i'm just gonna go for it like i think
it's fine
um
and like
puting was another i made a pupil tangy
hybrid and i was like i can't get in
contact with the tangy dudes and people
who don't even know what the hell tangy
is because maybe they
took california orange and renamed it or
you know there's that whole tangy drama
nobody knows the exact truth behind
what they did and if they really made it
or if they just have it so i'm like all
right tangies kind of free range
everyone's breathing with that too like
a time but
um i definitely prefer a lot
to breed with anything from somebody
that i can talk to that i know
personally um
or that says like it's okay definitely
the coolest way to do it because i need
to know that like
there's there's more good vibes in it
that way like a lot of my words with
some of d-man and stuff
which i'm friends with him and i got to
go to his place in canada which is
really cool
and
he taught me so so much like a lot of my
breeding knowledge comes from him over
the years so
it's really really cool to read with
each other's stuff and it just puts like
an extra
piece of excitement in there every time
you grow those plants it's like you have
a little bit of the connection with that
person too like even if it's just in
your head or it's in the plant like
i don't know right now i'm throwing some
mr e pupils and so mr e is a cut from
east coaster dam that he gave me breed
with
and growing those is so cool because
it's like
that's a super special plant that my
friend held for 10 plus years
and then he gifted it to me that i could
breed with it because he wanted it to be
available to other people
and
i don't know it's just that much more
exciting to see like my plants come
together with his plants when we're both
friends and we both like our own plants
in each other's plants like
there's
there's a lot of good vibes bouncing
back and forth when you're
collaborating like that
yeah of course
and so
just kind of in line with what you just
mentioned what are some genetics you
don't currently have access to that
you'd love to work with and why
um
i want to check out some colombian golds
because i've never grown or smoked that
specifically i mean i've had it like
in hybridized whatever but i haven't had
this pure colombian gold yet
um vietnam black like
just some different land races um
i don't know if i would necessarily
breed with them or not it depends like
how outrageously finicky they are
or not
but
um because usually i tend to try to
breed with something that's like
pretty stable off the bat is because
it's available like why would you
not use something that you like that's
already pretty damn good but
um
i believe everybody should try and grow
out the craziest plants that they heard
of through their like
old ass uncle or whoever the hell is
just like back in my day we smoke this
and this and we came off a boat like
when you hear a story like that and it
speaks to you or it just sounds cool
like
seek out that plan because it's not as
long gone as you might think like
there's somebody preserving
every single land race strain so
that stuff is just awesome and sometimes
it can be really good reading too
uh what else what else
uh
as cheesy as it sounds i'm finally
getting triangle kush because i've never
had that going before
and like i said i don't usually grow i
don't usually breed with clones but
that's one that i'm really excited to
explore the possibilities because every
single tk hybrid that i've smoked has
been so so good and i've grown a few and
seen a whole bunch of them growing and
i don't know man like
it's a classic and maybe it's a little
overused but i think the star people put
like a unique touch to it and i think
um
that'll be really cool so that's coming
up soon well i don't want to tell people
that but that's coming in a year or two
if it works out well you know
yeah i mean i don't think anyone's going
to look down on you for liking tk it's
it's easily my favorite of all the
kush's and it it's just so solid i can
when i when you smoke it you can
understand why it's stood up but with
that in mind are there any other ultra
clone only you know almost even
borderline hype strains that you would
consider working with
um i'm checking a few out at the moment
like i said um
how i got some clones i'm kind of doing
a run of like a ton of clones just to
see what i
like actually at all like these elites
and stuff
just because i recently ran into like a
few different people that are big on
like having all these elite clones and
stuff and they're just yeah you can have
whatever the [ __ ] you want so
i'm just like all right let's take in a
whole bunch and i don't want to like
tell people that i'm going to breed with
them or not because chances are i'm not
gonna unless something really vibes with
me but i'm sure something will really
fine with me so
um
i'm gonna be checking out
i got like so much lavender i got tempty
i got
supposed to be 1091 but it's not so i'm
still looking for 1091 a real one but
that one cool
but
um
looking through some blueberry clones
uh
purple punch i mean i don't think it's
supposed to be very strong but it smells
really good and it looks awesome so
maybe one day i'll hit that with some
heavy hitters but i don't know probably
not
i don't i don't think i need to
because
usually
when i'm breeding i like to find stuff
from seed from strains that i really
like already and then work with that
just because it's more unique like i
don't want to create the same thing that
somebody next door can create like
or create something similar to like but
i don't want to make the next purple
part if there's already 30 different
purple charges out there i'd rather like
sprout a bunch of seeds of like
anything and then find something i like
and i'd rather oxidize with that just
because nobody else has that pheno that
strain because i grew it from seed
and i liked it because of
whatever reasons i liked it for versus
like oh it's that clone that you can
pick up at the shop for 20 bucks
so with that being said are you somewhat
kind of uh
guard full of your clones given that you
know you have gone through work to find
the individual ones are you kind of of
the mindset that you know to keep your
work unique and
in that regard you know still valuable
in the consumer's eyes you want to
somewhat limit the availability of the
parents
um so actually
the only clone that i'm like that with
is the star pupil
because it's just such an amazing
breeding cut like is it's just the world
to me like
it's it's an amazing amazing plant and
so nobody has that um
family members have that so in case i
lose it i can get it back but nobody
else has that
no matter how much i trust them they
just don't get it because then it's
gonna get out um everything else i like
to share
because
i'm really excited when i make a strain
and then i find a really nice cut of it
and it just represents exactly what it's
going for i'm happy for people to grow
that like especially if they don't want
to dig through seeds i'll be like here
try this cut like this is the thing on
the front page of my
catalog like this is that grow it out
it's gonna look just like that and it's
gonna smoke amazing
you don't have to like you don't even
have to dig through a pack of seeds like
it's just here so i'm happy to share
those really awesome plants that i get
and
some of them are actually going to be
available soon through a few different
clone exchanges so if
you're lucky enough you'll be able to
pick up a cut of like putang and ninja
people rick's pupil
um and then others in the future as i
let him out slowly but
usually like a few of my friends will
get just about everything like even when
i'm throwing other trains of whatever
like looking for moms and female hunting
stuff
i definitely pass them off to friends so
that if i want to get them back later i
can or just
like i know they're not going to get
that far and if they do it's fine like
if i don't want something out there i'm
not going to let it out like the star
people clone nobody has that so i don't
have to worry about it and then i can't
get mad because nothing you know nobody
can do the wrong thing because it's just
i believe everything
is
for every human everything is your own
fault so whatever you do what
circumstances you are you're in like
it's because of something did or that
you're doing or
whatever like to an extent so
yeah if you want people to grow your own
let people grow your clone i don't want
people to breathe with your clone don't
let people have it and that's it
yeah i think that's one of the most
universal truths i've learned from all
the interviews is that when you give
something out even just to one friend
it's out
well yeah because i've been given clones
by people that are like hey i'm not
allowed to give you this like i'm gonna
die if anyone finds out so just don't
tell anyone that you have this
and then i'm like alright cool thanks
and then like all right don't trust that
person with my clothes
yeah no no
i mean i would trust them with a clone
to the extent that i know they might
give it to somebody else usually that's
fine with me but if it wasn't like
that's your lesson right there you just
learned that like
you can't you can't trust people because
every single person's gonna give you
some kind of secret or like you know
when you tell somebody a secret they
tell one other person so
every person you tell a secret to you're
telling 10 people or like if you tell
someone that you grow like 10 people
find out
it's along the same lines of that and
it's fine like it's it's not even a bad
thing it's just life it's like a lesson
that everybody should just know about
and
you can compensate for it and good
decisions
yeah i agree
so if we just loot back to a point you
made you said uh you'd actually learnt a
lot of things from d-man over the years
d-man's well-known breeder for anyone
who hasn't heard of him he's actually a
little
he's well recognized within the scene
but i think he's a little lesser known
which is a little bit of a shame because
he's been around for ages but here's
where the question is actually going was
that initially when you were learning
stuff from him was that via like online
forums and stuff like were you around
back then or was this much more of like
a personal contact
um
no it was a little bit more recent i am
on his forums
but
uh we started talking
um basically i saw that he had
acapulco gold
which was like one of the strands that
my mom had talked about
from her day so
it was a little before me like i never
got to smoke it like
fresh off the
truck or wherever the hell it came from
in a brick you know but
um
anyways i saw that he had that and i
started talking to him and like
somehow we just started talking to
boston and
now we just like text and stuff so
anyways like he taught me a whole bunch
of stuff because he was like dude what
the hell like you're a little bit
younger and you're interested in like
these strains the land races like that's
really cool like everybody these days
just wants like
og bush and stuff and you're here asking
me about acapulco gold and like growing
my panama's now
anyways like
we just got off to like
we're like
straight on the same foot right away and
just like
vibe super well
and
i was already like you know i was
growing and making seeds a little and
telling him about those and i sent him
some of my star pupil swans
and he was like dude i hate purple weed
and i was like you do not understand i
have something special here and like
i'm not wasting time this [ __ ] is really
strong and it's really enjoyable like
it's not the same as most of the purple
[ __ ] that's just purple and that's it
like
this is this is something i want you to
try he tried it and he was like that's
one of the first purples that i've
really liked and he ended up asking me
if he could breed with it because he
liked it that much so
it was cool like he gave me stuff that i
really liked i gave him stuff that he
ended up really liking too
and uh one of my favorite strains of all
time is hispanic powerhouse
which is a panama red land race crossed
with the
f6
g13 black widow
and
holy [ __ ] just
i can't say enough about how [ __ ]
amazing that strain is
yeah wow i mean it's certainly been
around for a long time
raises an interesting question in my
mind
although you just mentioned you got the
panama from d-man where do you go
generally if you are looking to source
these older genetics do you look to seed
or just to kind of acquisition of clone
um definitely to seeds
because
i don't usually take in many clones like
i said um
and when i do it's very rare for
somebody to be like
hey i got this clone of like
i don't know 1980s like thai stick or
something like i never see that in clone
if i did i would take it for sure so if
anybody's listening who has some
you know
hit me up but
um yeah i'm usually digging through
seeds
and just
getting them from random ass like
sometimes there's like a random website
in uh
in denmark that has like all these cool
land races and stuff
and some of them are recent and some of
them are really old they got like
some jamaicans that are 1960 cross of
1985 and pollination
jamaican sativa they're like 14 to 20
week flower
so
it was just like somebody sent me a link
they're just like hey check out this
website we have like all these cool
things so i think the seeds are really
really amazing because then if you don't
find a good plant you can open pollinate
and then eventually
find something that's like
a little bit reasonable to work with and
go from there
yeah for sure i mean it it it almost
seems like you would never get offered a
clone of tie right
yeah
i mean i wonder if anybody has like
people definitely have some but i don't
think it's that common like yeah you
gotta remember most of these people are
on the internet
yeah oh yeah especially in europe
there's a huge i think i was actually
talking to kagu and he said there's in
europe there's and spain specifically
there's people who have like some of the
best land races on earth and they hoard
it and they do not want it to get out
yeah i bet especially like
i always wonder
when all that [ __ ] went from
here to the netherlands and then it all
became like the same [ __ ]
like
all those breeders like they must have
original
parental stock that's actually a little
bit more unique than the watertown dutch
hybrids of today you know like
there's got to be a lot of unique stuff
still floating around
yeah well like i mean the easiest
example you can point to is that
uh neville has said in interviews he's
still got lots of stock
yeah i bet he has some amazing things
i know and i know there's there's like
groups in california preservationists
that have all these land races
and they have clones and seeds and
everything and they just don't give it
out to anybody
and on one hand it's awesome that
they're preserving it but i'm a little
like
why wouldn't you share it like you know
how much this means to people and like
it could be kind of a fresh start for a
gene pool for tons of people that want
to [ __ ] around with it and try breeding
a little or just preserve themselves too
like
i don't really i don't know i understand
hoarding but
it gets tricky when it's like dude
you're hoarding like the last [ __ ]
seeds of this strain that like yeah you
could just let out people and it's like
especially in seed forms like why
wouldn't you
yeah the last pure building blocks
yeah exactly because it's so hard to
find anything
really like pure these days
yeah so something i did wanted to ask is
like much of your work it draws on
strains which might broadly be
considered old school in general things
like even flow evelyn amnesia panama was
this an intentional decision or is it
just kind of how it worked out
um i guess it's just the plants that
vibe with me really
i don't like a lot of the new school
kind of stuff that much and
like i grow a lot of plants and a lot of
them never get to see the light of day
because i'm just like
[ __ ] this plant it sucks like i was
smoking a few times and be like nope not
my vibe next like
um
and it's mostly newer stuff that tends
to
blend together as like the strains you
don't even remember growing after a year
because they just weren't anything stand
out and then a lot of these standout
plants that i find
tend to be like
a haze or a panama or like
you know just something a little bit
older
a little bit less common for sure
um
and it's usually because they have
unique effects or unique flavors or a
combination of those
yeah
so
do you think that it's possible to
through breeding with these old land
races to kind of create the next sliced
bread like something that's really
unique really different it's gonna kind
of spur off its own
tree of lineage and whatnot or do you
think that you can create something
unique but it's not gonna have like the
same impact as
you know if you created like skunk back
in the day or something like that
um no you definitely you can change the
world with the single hundred for sure
it doesn't matter what year you're in
you could do it right now you could do
it ten years from now you can do it ten
years ago
um like
i don't know for me
like one example would be girl scout
cookies which is a strain that i really
don't like
but
if you think about it
it's in so many things right now there's
i could name tons of companies that
exist solely because of girl scout
cookies because their entire line is
girl scout cookies crosses something
across to something so
for example whoever
popped that girl's got a cookie seed and
who knows what the real story is but
there was a plan people liked it people
read with it that's plain and simple so
you know if i make something with a
couple land races in it and somebody
really really likes it or maybe it's a
phone that gets out that's like super
exceptional or maybe it's just seed
stock that people agreed with like
it doesn't really matter
if you make something good or special
that people like
then it's gonna get used in hybrids just
like
you know chem dog is in a ton of things
too
and that's it's just because people
liked it and that's about all there is
to it
and like with cookies it's not even
stable and people still like it like you
get so many herms off it but
people like something about it and
it made a big dent
for there
so with that in mind would you let a
plant which was the next sliced bread to
you but it happened to throw some nana's
would that be like a red flag or would
you just still go with it keeping in
mind what we just said about cookies
um
in what regard because for example when
i release seeds i make sure that they're
pretty damn stable that they're not
going to earn all over the place
and i test them and i have other people
test them in their environments and hear
back from them like
you know i did this and this and this
and it survived it and whatever anyways
um i believe first of all everybody
should
do some solid testing before releasing
seeds
unless you're saying that they're
testers which is different like freebies
whatever you can say like untested
freebies
but
um if i'm releasing seeds i want to see
it stable
it's a clone
i pretty much also want to see it be
really stable because
i don't want to give somebody a clone
and then it turns their garden and like
you know somebody's garden is sometimes
they're livelihood and all they're just
seated and
they can't make rent the next month
because they had to toss everything like
that's
not a good
thing to happen so i mean you try to
really minimize
the possibility of like permanent [ __ ]
and i guess the exception would be like
sterile mandarins if you prove that the
nanners have no viable pollen every
single time
and you try using that pollen to make a
seed and make sure
then like maybe in a clone only kind of
thing it might be fine like i think
chem d
i was deported is gonna do that like
it'll probably hurt but there won't be
viable calling so don't worry about that
kind of thing
so
i mean in that case it's totally fine i
guess
well i mean it certainly feels like the
devil's kind of in the details and i was
talking to me and gene about this at the
emerald cup and
he kind of raised this interesting
question you know he said what if you
create australian as a breeder and it's
fire like dead set the best thing ever
but like 50 you don't it's only like 50
percent of the phenoes and the other 50
percent like wilhelm and even if you
work on it for a generation or two or
reselect the parents it just seems to be
the inevitable outcome like what do you
do in that situation
um
i mean how much better is this strain
than the next best strain that you have
you know like really really good
yeah i don't know i mean
like once one solution that got thrown
around was like you offer it with that
information out there and maybe at a
reduced price that was just one solution
that got thrown around
i usually see him at triple price with
no warning but knocking it into that
i see a lot of breeders putting out
current packs for 300 bucks and they
don't even have the warning on them but
you hear it through people and then you
try it and you see it's true but anyways
yeah i think the right thing to do
is either
you don't release it or you release it
with that warning
and
probably as a freebie with the warning
like i don't know even if it's really
[ __ ] good
[Music]
you don't have to sell it if it's if
it's gonna cause problems
and
yeah i don't know i would
i would probably say don't sell hermes
stuff
uh even if you haven't warned me it's
probably just better not to because
somebody is going to trade that pack and
they're going to lose the warning the
next person is going to get [ __ ] over
and he's gonna be mad at you the breeder
i don't know it's too much there's so
many other good plants that
you don't need to worry about crazy
hermes
yeah of course it's kind of like as
we're having this conversation it dawns
on me how like kind of funny it is like
yeah you probably shouldn't sell hermes
seeds
so
what do you think about this idea of
breeders who release lions with new
parents each cycle whether it be due to
laziness or due to the fact that there
could be some advantages to doing so do
you think any potential advantages are
offset by potential disadvantages or
what do you think of that idea in
general um if you're going to do that
you just have to tell people
and you have to test each generation
before you release it so let's say
you're first you make this new strain
and then you release it and it's the f1s
and then the next year you run out of
those so you make some f2s like just
tell people that it's f2s and then test
those f2s and see like okay maybe
there's a little bit different things
coming out of here like explain that but
the problem i have with a lot of seeds
is that there's zero information when
you buy them from a lot of breeders
there's just a name and the cross and
that's it
and
that kind of sucks because
i don't know i try to give out the
information on my strains that i would
want to see if i was buying it from
somebody else so like i'll put out as
much information as i can think of and
then if people ask me questions
i'll even add that to my description
where i can like on my website and stuff
like try to be super thorough
and
i don't know just so people know what
they're getting like if if you're buying
a certain strain and then it's totally
different from what you bought last year
but it's from a breeder
and it's because they use different
parents like
i don't know i would want to know that
it's version two or version five like
some some readers have like a couple
versions of the same strain and they're
labeled that and maybe there's not much
info but at least you know like okay i
grew e3 last year now i'm throwing v5
versus like
just expecting the same thing when it's
not because no two parents are going to
combine the same
ever they might be close but
definitely not the same
yeah okay and how do you feel about f2s
that get sold which then a kind of you
know
crazy high pricing because something i
hear people which they say to me is is
there's a bit of a question mark over
the f2s in the sense that from a
breeding point of view it could be more
ideal but from a consumer point of view
it's probably less ideal because as you
loosely reference you're gonna get
things popping up which probably not
intended like i mean when you make an f1
i don't think many people think about
yeah so when i eventually make some f2s
like i definitely want people to have
one of these grandparent phenos popping
up like i just think it's a totally not
a thought that goes through your mind
and so
the the the criticism i hear is that you
know effectively you're going to get
less phenotypes which you would see in
the f1 which is probably what you're
looking for right and um and then
likewise it's kind of like
sometimes f2s can be done quite
improperly with small selection pools
and whatnot like how do you feel about
the f2 offering in general
i never understood why people
asked for more money for an f2
i always thought it should be the
opposite i have two is like okay you got
lazy you didn't keep your parents and
you can't recreate the same seat so
you're doing the next best thing you can
or you can look at it the other way and
say you're taking into generation
forward and doing more work and more
selections which is also true
but
in that case it kind of evens out it's
like a plus and a minus but it really
depends
what your style is what you're trying to
offer
um
like d-man likes to release f2s
for
almost a preservation type
reason where it's like you have
more phenos that are coming out and
there's a little more variety
than the solid f1 where there's just
like say two phenols and four females
that are very tight
maybe your f2 will open it up a little
bit and
offer more diversity
which in some cases is really important
and in other cases it is your worst
enemy it just depends what you want to
grow and why so
i think there's room for everything
there's room for like
super work lines there's room for solid
f1s that can be reproduced by the
breeder with the same pairs every time
there's room for f2s and f3s and
i like to use f2 sometimes like
in
an f1 hybrid you know like make
something take it to f2 and then cross
that f2 like find what you're looking
for in f2 and just process it
to another mother or something like that
and sometimes you can pull out some
really unique stuff that way
um
so i don't know there's there's
there's just a reason for everything so
it just depends what you're going for
and why
so i mean you referenced the the 300
packs of seeds and i'm sure many people
can think of even more expensive ones
than that what's your position on seed
pricing do you think that it should just
be like a capitalist thing where you
know people set their own prices and the
market determines supply and demand or
do you think that there should be some
sort of i don't want to say like pricing
structure but like essentially you know
you can't just go ripping people off
with f1s versus maybe some other project
which has got a lot of work being put
into it where do you sit on it
yeah pricing is always tricky
because like you said like you can price
something and then just see people buy
it or not but like
in my opinion the best thing to do is
like price fairly so whatever fair is to
you
and obviously everybody has different uh
image of like what fare means like for
me my prices had to go up like a year or
two ago because
it just wasn't cutting it i was working
way too hard for what i was getting and
it wasn't quite adding up so i just had
to change it a little and i felt bad
even raising it so i was like we'll see
how it goes and i'll put it a little
higher and
that will allow me to do everything that
i need to do and bring out some awesome
stuff and hopefully people will be happy
with it and then i saw people charging
three or five times as much as i was
charging anyways i was like all right i
don't feel that bad like this is what's
fair to me this works for me
this will hopefully work for the people
that want to grow my strains at least
most of them can afford it um i don't
know i think
that's just me though like every breeder
has their own five and some people's
vibe is like let me charge 500 for this
pack and only
the people that really want it can have
it and like i understand that like
sometimes if i have something more
limited
it's almost on that kind of it's not
going to be 500 bucks but it's going to
be a little more expensive because
there's so little amount of packs that
it's like
this is only going to exist one time and
whoever can get this is like your only
little chance and then it's just gone
but
for whatever reason like sometimes
there's a mom that you can grow or a
giant and you still get a very low
amount of seeds off of it and then it's
just like
that this is what you're left with and
like or maybe you lost the clone and it
gets more rare because of that you never
make the seeds again or
you lost both parents and it's super out
of the question or whatever like if
something's rare
maybe charge more or something
super like if you put a [ __ ] ton of work
into something and you can improve it
and it's really really awesome like
charge whatever you want for it but
the only problem i have with c pricing
is when stuff is expensive and it's bad
or it's unstable like there's a couple
pretty
well-known breeders out there that are
charging anywhere from 100 to a few
hundred bucks
and
their stuff is very loaded with hermes
all over the place and undesirable
phenotypes and
you know there's there's certain ones
that people just know i mean a lot of
people don't know but people that know
know that you're gonna pop five packs
and you find that one keeper that looks
like the photo and then
that's gonna be your one that doesn't
hurt and then hopefully from there it's
good smoke if you're lucky and it's like
why go through that [ __ ] when you
like
spend 70 bucks on like a body pack and
just you know
it's almost always something good
yeah i can definitely attest to that and
you you're kind of hitting on a point
which i really wanted to bring up
because something that i've noticed
happens more often than not is that
there are people
maybe shady's not the right word but as
you describe
charging a lot for things which
shouldn't be priced that high especially
given there may be hermes or things like
that and there are certainly lots of
people within the scene and the
community who are aware of this and
aware of the the types of results you're
going to get but more often than not
nothing gets said because people don't
want to rock the boat do you think that
it's a bit of a mistake that we're in
this mindset because
so often you know it just seems like
that's the case where people know the
shady things that are going on but just
no one says anything
dude that's such a good point and it's
really tough because as a breeder myself
i don't want to make enemies and even
just as a grower as a person who likes
to plant i don't want to make enemies
and i know that if i go call someone out
on their [ __ ] that really quickly is
going to be
like all right this person doesn't like
you but guess what all his friends
[ __ ] hate you too and then you know
it becomes a war
and there's there's no time for that
like
i
i don't know it's really tricky because
the best thing that i can do is just do
my best and try to encourage people like
to see that but
hey here's what i stand for and this is
how i think things should be and if
somebody asked me directly like do you
have experience with so and so breeder
or some strain i can tell i'm like yeah
yeah it's all hermes unfortunately but
whatever like
i don't know it's pretty
tricky
just
i don't know i don't think everyone
should be as quiet about it as they are
i do see people commenting once in a
while that most people do stay quiet and
i think it's just because
people are scared of getting enemies and
then like the more popular you get the
more you don't want to have enemies
like i don't know i totally stay out of
drama whenever possible
but at the same time i feel really bad
for like the people who just don't know
that they're about to waste their money
on someone else's ear but like
i don't know as as my own self i can't
be like hey don't buy that strain by my
string like mine stabilizes and like
that just looks shitty so i'm not gonna
do that
yeah
it's a tough one to navigate so i mean
in general how do you feel about the
state of our community in general i
think at the moment
we're kind of at a bit of a low point in
terms of the internal drama like i think
if you look back a couple months ago
there was a lot of drama going on it
seems like we're kind of you know things
are all pretty chill at the moment do
you think this is things are better this
way or did you think like that the drama
generates necessary conversation how do
you feel about it
um
[Music]
i don't know i probably missed whatever
drama you're talking about because i
think there's certain people that need
to be called out that maybe haven't but
i'm not going to do it um especially
because i have no personal problems with
them it's more of just seeing what's
what people are doing whatever
i don't know i i think dramas is
not good but at the same time people
need to
know what's going on
like
um
i don't know everybody's in their own
kind of circles in their own zones and
whatever
and some people
have a really wide scope and view of
like
what's going on with everyone and other
people are like yeah i only follow like
this guy this guy in this guy and that's
all i know and i'm cool with it and
that's fine too so
there's like
i don't i don't really know what's
the big picture because i kind of stick
like
who i vibe with specifically
and i usually ignore the drama just
because like when there's drama i do
know there's always two sides to it like
even if one of them is your friend and
one of them's your enemy like they both
have partial truths and you don't know
where to sit so it's like
i'm gonna stay out of that personally
and just go by like how that person's
affected me directly or what i see
directly from them and just
take it from there
yeah
so one of the topics we love to chat
about on this show the roadkill skunk
you know very elusive origins hard to
pin down everyone's got some cool
stories about it do you have any
experiences with the roadkill skunk by
any chance
yeah um
my opinion on this going is that
basically like there's
everybody's searching for this strain
that smells just like a skunk and i've
had it a couple times
um i mean i've had different trains that
have that quality whether one of them
was actually called skunk and a couple
others were just other strains
and something interesting that i noticed
that i wanted to talk about with that
was um
a lot of times you could get a bag of
wheat and it just smells like a skunk
but that's like before you even open it
and it smells super skunky through the
bag
and then when you open it and you smell
it sometimes it's totally different
which would also mean that when you're
growing in the plant it might totally
not really smell like a skunk at the
moment but then when you get in the
right conditions whether it's
in a bag or maybe in a certain
temperature or something like that then
the skunkiness comes out more
and it seems like
a lot of times that skunk smell
experience is like smelling it through a
bag or smelling it
from a distance or something like that
um because recently
somebody gave me some blood and i
smelled it like i just smelled the bag
that he gave me i didn't even open it
because it smelled so strong through and
it was straight skunk and i was like
dude this smells so skunky and he looked
at me like i was an idiot
like i didn't know what i was talking
about and he's like what and then he's
like dude take it out and smell it like
it's totally butter it's creamy it's og
it's not skunky at all
and i opened it and i cracked it a
little bit and he was so right it was
completely different than when the bag
was sealed and it was just like
only those skunk turps were
permeating through the bag or whatever
so
that's definitely a thing with the skunk
i think it's certain terpenes that will
come out
in certain conditions and
they can definitely be masked by other
ones where you're actually like up close
with the pod
yeah see that's really interesting it's
like
i you know never had anyone really
suggest that so that's some good food
for thought but the first thing that
jumps to mind for me is that it would
almost indicate that maybe this skunky
profile that people are chasing is
actually
a more simplistic one so to speak and as
you said the bag is kind of filtering
certain maybe more complex just for
whatever reason terpenes that aren't
making it through and and what we're
looking for is actually more of a simple
profile than a super complex one per se
yeah definitely and it could be just a
terpene that's
like one single terpene or maybe a
certain combination that really
permeates through the bag and then like
you said it's holding in all the finer
more complex ones
which may actually
smell stronger once you do get to them
by opening bags
yeah okay that's yeah that's definitely
some food for thought so did you ever
smoke any growing up or do you have any
cool stories about anything you smoked
while growing up
yeah um i mean i got
skunked one time
i don't know what skunk it was it was
just skunk when i got it from the dude
and it was just
straight up
that one smelled like a skunk even
without the bag but especially through
the bag like i was trying to hide this
well i didn't know about glass jars yet
because i was just starting to smoke and
my whole everywhere everywhere i went
with that thing just smelled like a
skunk behind me
but um
yeah i got
some cool stories um
oh yeah this is a phone so
one of the first few times that i smoked
it was back when like smoking was still
an adventure it was like not casual yet
for me and my friend so it was like
dude i know this spot we can get some
weed i was in um albany with a couple of
friends like staying for a weekend with
them
and he was like you're not even to
believe this but i know where we can get
this weed in the city there's like
this house that you have to go to
there's like kind of an apartment
building and then
you walk down this hall and then there's
a door and you
like
knock on the door and it's called the
knock knock house and the dude sticks
his fingers through the thing and then
he asks you what you want and i'm like
dude that's so [ __ ] that's not a
real thing
and basically
we went and
it was like i know what street it's on
we just got to find the right house like
we'll just try it and so like give us a
win
and uh
we went into those
buildings like yes this red one here and
we we go in and then we knock on this
door nothing happens so he opens the
door and we just walk in
and we're just this dude's kitchen and
he's just like smoking a bong
and so we're like all right yeah this
must be it
so now we just like walked in some
random person's apartment that was like
not the right thing at all
and he just happened to be smoking weed
too
and then
we're just like oh sorry i think we're
at the wrong place
and we went back in the hall and then we
went down the hall and found the actual
one
and i'm dead serious it was like my
friend knocked on the door and this dude
stuck his fingers through the mail slot
like you know those like horizontal
mailbot things yeah
and he's like yo look inside here's the
menu and it was like three things i
don't remember what the first one was
but it was
it was like
miz and then there was green crack and
the miz was 10 a gram and the green
crack was 25 which is the highest that
i've ever paid for anything
and
my buddy was just like dude i hear the
myths they spray with windex like we
can't get the bids you gotta get the the
good stuff and i was like holy [ __ ] all
right so
we we just got into the screen crack it
was 25 bucks and i just remembered it so
distinctly because it was like some of
the strongest smelling stuff ever
it was green with like these purple
streaks in it
and
basically we put it in his car and we
went around the city and stuff and then
like when we were going back to his car
we could smell it across the street and
all his windows were up and everything
it was a single gram in there so it was
just like
i don't know i wish
somehow i could get that cut because
like
the intensity of the smell was so crazy
and then when we smoked it like
we all just started freaking out and we
all thought it was laced and like they
had smoked many many times more than i
had at that point and they were just
like i think this just lays dude like i
feel the blood rushing through my like
veins through my whole body and [ __ ]
it was just wild but i've had a few
different times like that in new york
just getting like the most ridiculous
ever
and to this day i mean i don't know if
it was laced or not but
probably not
because usually
[Music]
yeah so something i wanted to bring up
because i know that you do dabble in it
is like cobb led lightings could you
give us a little bit of a rundown with
your experience and any information you
have to share
oh yeah so
um basically cobb is a chip on board
it's like these whole spectrum leds with
the white light you can see everything
like real color and all that and
i saw these videos on youtube where this
guy was like yeah i get like 1.8 1.9
grams per watt with these
and you have to build them yourself but
they're better than any lights you can
get out there and i'm just like
what like that's crazy built like
yourself i don't
i don't get it it was super technical
and all that but eventually i took the
time to
figure out what he was
talking about and how it all worked and
stuff and
um
basically studied
everything he was saying and all kinds
of things about life spectrum for a
couple weeks with my brother
and
we developed like a really good spectrum
by like combining different chips and i
built this light
and i just
started using it i was so blown away
because i've always
been at least like the last few years
i've been using leds just because i like
them a lot more
than hps i always find like
better more unique terpenes and
just like less generic but i feel like
the plant can express itself better
under leds
but then when i switch to the cobs it
was like again it was like a whole
nother level
of like
just the plants expressing to their
fullest potential indoors i mean you
would see stuff like outdoors you see
pink hairs on some strains and then
indoors you almost never see that and
then under the cause i started seeing
that like everything was praying and
flowering like a little bit faster and
super healthy
and then
yeah i'm just super hooked on the cob
lighting because basically i chopped
down a few plants under it and i'm like
yeah you know this looks like
x amount of blood like i don't know 100
grams let's say for example and then
like
turns out to be like 200 like every
single time it's like double what it
looks like it's just like super dense
super
heavy yields and like
the same or better quality than i'm used
to
so
i recommend to people try out the cob
lights they're just super crazy
um
and i switched like almost all my
fixtures over to cobbs in the last
year or so
after using that one for
maybe a year or something like that
yeah okay
um
i recommend to people if they're growing
under cobs make sure or even out any
leds keep your temperatures at like 82
degrees
because
if you go lower than that you're going
to have like some nutrient deficiencies
that are basically
in short it's related to the leaf
temperature
um it has to do with the whole spectrum
and what nutrients the plant needs a
little bit more of because of the
spectrum
and anyways if you keep your
temperatures like at least in the low
80s you won't have any issues but if you
keep them like 75 like
hps temperatures
you're gonna get like magnesium
deficiencies and stuff so
something to consider just for like
really good results
yeah that's awesome info have you
fiddled around at all with the far red
uv initiators at all
yeah those are crazy actually so
i put those in too
and
basically when i started um
flowering with those they would go on
for like 15 minutes right the lights go
out and it
simulates on like the sunset outside and
it puts his plants to sleep faster and
essentially gives them two hours more
darkness
according to whoever developed it
and
i was pretty skeptical but it was
scientifically proven by all kinds of
whoever the hell studies it and
so
sure enough it makes your plants flower
really fast and i noticed that basically
i think it was like day 14 looked like
day 21 on like every play in the room
and i did a whole bunch of different
strains in there and just everything
flowered super fast
um it's basically the initiation of
flower the first few weeks that go a lot
faster like you really notice in a few
days like damn these things are already
flowering and then like a week later
it's like really really flowering so
um i recommend those if you're trying to
speed up your cycle by like
five to seven days or so
yeah wow that's some awesome info as
well
yeah and definitely for sativas because
some sativas
like um you know 11 hours of light or 10
hours of light and i know a lot of
growers just want to use 12 so
if you do that and you're basically
giving them you're still getting another
12 hours of life then you're giving them
the equivalent to like 14 hours of dark
or something like that
just because they process the fact that
it's nighttime sooner
yeah
a lot more flowers
killer
so
in regards to your flowering cycle then
besides the cobs and the far red
initiator chip do you do anything
outside of the norm when you're in
flower
yeah definitely so
um
i've always
for the last few years i've been
flowering under 11 hours of light and
then 13 hours of dark
and
i heard it from dj short who said like
yeah we'll kind of make your plans to be
a little bit more sativa in
characteristics even if you're growing
indicas it will kind of
give them a little energy a little kick
to them and i thought that was
interesting because it's kind of more of
a tropical light cycle and that's where
the plants evolved to these more
sativa phenotypic expressions so i
basically tried to side by side with a
couple clones and
one really cool thing was that
this um his viper city og moxie which i
only heard a couple times but
under 12 hours of light and these are
both under the same temperatures
under 12 hours of light it was totally
green
and it smelled like super generic i
don't like nothing memorable whatever
and then like
under 11 it went totally purple with
like just
insane like really really nice smell and
color and everything and i was like damn
that's the same clone
in like the same just about the same
environment just a different light cycle
and it like really really improved the
plant and it went a few days faster and
flowered so it was like the same kind of
ripeness on the tricones and all that so
that was like my first
um first time seeing that like damn this
life cycle thing makes a difference and
they both yield it very similar like
a lot of people are scared they're like
oh am i gonna lose yield and
i think that might depend on what you're
growing like maybe some plants will like
it more and some won't but
i've been flowering under 11 hours and
combined with the cos i've seen over 2
grams per watt
type of yield so i don't think it really
reduces yield
um but i definitely noticed that a lot
of
what i grow is very like uplifting even
when i grow into because it's pretty
functional and stuff like that so
um i do like growing and breeding under
11 hours and then i veg under 17 because
the best cycle has the same effect it's
kind of it's going to kind of like
make your plant evolve over time you
know whatever conditions you keep a
clone in especially if it's for many
many years
um
like if you're doing 24 hours versus 18
or 17 it's just gonna the plant's gonna
shift ever so slightly
just from being in a different
environment
yeah so
outside of that legendary green crack
did you ever have any other cuts which
left a lasting impression in your mind
yeah there was um
this one time i smoked a spliff of white
widow and i don't usually
mix with typical but once in a while i
would back then and
actually i like the thing that bodhi
said about
mixing cannabis and taco where it kind
of gives you that grounding effect and
like that masculinizing effect towards
like a feminine plant so
once in a great while if you smoke a
split it can be super super
therapeutic but anyways it was this
white widow
smoked into a spliff and i just remember
like as soon as we were done smoking it
or in the woods we just sat down on the
ground
didn't talk for like
half an hour
and it was just like the one of the most
psychedelic smokes that ever had
and
it's funny because you know white widow
is like the pretty common strain
i guess like in the commercial
uh
field whatever you want to call it and
but it's never really that good these
days
and this white widow i smoked it a
couple times but this first time i
smoked it especially it was always so
good but
like i just remember
like not being able to read like letters
and [ __ ] because it was just like
i don't know it's just like this whole
different headspace that was so foreign
and like
it wasn't even uncomfortable that i
couldn't read anything it was just like
every letter was a picture and like
super super trippy so
i don't know like i've grown white widow
and i've smoked white moves since then
from plenty of places and plenty of
different seasons or whatever
and
i just never found a white widow that
came close to that one
and that was it wasn't that long ago
that white widow i don't know probably
eight years ago or something
maybe nine years ago i don't know
but
yeah i don't know where's the white
where's a good white widow
yeah i'd like to know that too
yeah all the other ones i've sold lately
either
put you to sleep or they're super bland
and like
not really much flavor or much effect
just like regular
speed i smoked some white rhino a while
back like not that long back probably
about a year ago
and um
[ __ ] it was good man it like
wasn't the same in a lot of ways but
there was a lot of aspects of it that
reminded me of smoking skelly in the
states and it was just such a
mind-blowing thing i was like what no
way
oh that's awesome i love when you just
get something that's like even if it's
not the same it's like close to
something you had in the past that was
so reminiscent and that's like
just amazing no matter what it is
yeah just bring it back
so if we kind of jump to a slightly
related topic but a little bit off field
living in massachusetts what's it like
with the medical laws there i mean i
know things have changed recently but
for the longest period of time
people had always said that it was you
know it wasn't the most friendly state
to be and how have you found it and how
does it look for you going forward
um
it's interesting it's definitely
less chill than some places and it's a
lot better than a lot of places and i'm
super super grateful to be where i am
and at this time
um
like it's a relatively safe environment
to do what i do
sometimes it's a little scary and
there's always
you know it's definitely not perfect
like at our weed events you can't have
weed you can
there's seeds and stuff but like
we're doing a
event at canacon which is like this
event in boston
and they're like yeah you can't bring
flower to display like i wanted to bring
a little
branch of star pupil flowering and
putting water so people could smell it
and see
what it's like and they're just like you
absolutely cannot do that you can't give
away what you can't display like no thc
allowed
and i'm like okay fine like whatever you
know it's not the end of the world but
in in that kind of sense it's a serious
environment here
but it makes sense because to me
massachusetts at least the area i'm in
it's a lot of people that don't like
weed and it's a miracle that have we've
legalized here so
i'm pretty grateful for the whole thing
and our medical programs like
better than some places although it's
not the best it's definitely not the
worst so
to me it's like wherever in the world
you are you you adapt
you either move or you adapt so whatever
works for you
you you work with it or you find a way
and uh
our whole
legalization thing is like a huge mess
here
and so
something i wanted to ask you was that
we don't see you at a stack of events
however you know obviously you just
mentioned the cannacon is this more of a
geographical location issue or are you
just not so into like the high times and
all that stuff
um actually i've been to a bunch of
events but i don't usually i don't want
to join my face like
as i don't know i'm the overly paranoid
person because i learned from people
that grew in like total prohibition and
i learned from the books that teach you
like the craziest ass way of staying
safe so you don't get caught and so even
like meeting people from online i never
met anyone until a couple years ago
because i was so scared that like the
first person i mean it's just gonna be
that agent that's gonna take me away
forever from my family and possessions
just like [ __ ] up my life so
it's still a transition of being like
realizing like things are okay you can
talk to people like i was scared as hell
to do this interview but i so badly want
to like talk about all these things that
i loved so
like
i don't know things are
things are safer than i thought but at
the same time there's always
that risk because it's like
everything in massachusetts and in this
country is just gray area so
all like you know everything on
instagram you see these people posting
selfies with like 5 000 clients behind
them they're like
this is my full name and i'm growing 5
000 cannabis plants and look how awesome
i am and it's like
only so many people can do that before
one of them just gets like
taken to jail you know like i'm like
what the [ __ ] are you guys doing like
this shit's a little sketchy don't you
think so i don't know
that's kind of why i've been more
private the whole time
just because i've been a little
uncomfortable with the whole like
how public can you really go before like
something bad happens to you
and so moving forward do you think you
will be a bit more out in the open or
are you just kind of gonna still kind of
take care of yourself
um i mean i'm pretty private myself i
have a pretty small circle of people and
then
um
i'd like to be at more events and stuff
like that
i usually when i go to events it's
usually just like there's a couple
specific people i want to meet that are
either at the event or going to the
event as like a
person going to the event so it's like
you know like someone on instagram is
like yeah we've been talking for a year
like we should link up
going to this event
um so i'll usually go to events and do
that like in private but i'm not like
wearing a huge red flag that's like hey
i'm mass medical strength and
the last couple events like some people
started coming up to me and be like hey
mass medical strands and i'm like oh
[ __ ] people are learning who i am
i'm scared but it's i don't know we'll
see we'll see where it goes i definitely
would like to be
more public because
i like talking about plants and sharing
all these good things and stuff like
that so there's like a lot of good stuff
but just gotta stay safe at the same
time
yeah okay
and so the last question about
massachusetts do you have access to labs
and the testing facilities that people
in say california or colorado have
access to and do you utilize them do you
see the value in it
yeah really awesome um
so like
you can just go to a lab and bring your
weed there and they test it for you like
within a few days and you don't have to
tell them who you even are like you can
i put mass medical strains i don't have
to give an id or my real name or
anything and then
you know they just put it online and
they email it to you or whatever you
want them to do but it's super relaxed
in that sense
you can learn a lot about your growing
and your strains and
the effects a little bit i mean
effects are more subjective and
experiential but you can still get some
interesting numbers out of everything
and then
you know like
you grow something you're like why does
this smell like this okay it has this
terpene and then you're like
what does this terpene do
medicinally
and then you're like oh [ __ ] it boosts
memory no no wonder like this strain
always like really helps me when i need
to think or remember [ __ ] it's like
that's why
and
you can kind of
learn a little bit more about the plant
through the lab results
sometimes but then other times i mean
i've had really strong [ __ ] test out at
like 10 to 15 on occasion so that's thc
so
you know there's more to it than lab
results at the same time but they're
really really awesome in general
yeah okay
so something i'd love to talk to
everyone about clone deterioration or
genetic drift however you want to term
it
do you believe in it or do you think
it's just uh it's just poor maintenance
um
so all my clones pretty much get treated
the same and i treat them pretty well
overall like you know keeping them
healthy and then
i always take extra clones and just keep
the healthiest rooted one and you know
some pretty good cloning practices and
keeping it in a nice environment as best
as i can
and i've noticed
most clones stay the same and then you
know when you grow a clone differently
you're going to get slightly different
expressions off of it
and sometimes you can
get really something different off it if
you change something drastically but
then if you go back to what you're doing
before it goes back to how it grew
before so you're not really changing
anything you're just flowering
differently
and then
on the other hand
i had a cut of the evelyn and every
single time i grew it it was a
completely different plant one time it
was
almost entirely green
one time it was like
totally black one time it was red and
one time it was purple and there was
little different smells coming out and
it's like
every generation that i grew it it just
changed and it wasn't the environment
changing it was just
maybe getting older or something
and then a friend of mine said oh yeah
like all the stuff i've grown from that
breeder does the same thing that genetic
line like they just change over time as
clones
and
um so i think genetically there's
certain plants that may drift over times
because they're not expecting to live
for multiple years because usually
cannabis outside will die in the winter
so especially like
i don't know i would assume something
that
originates from like a more tropical uh
not tropical like
a more like cold ass climate
uh where it would never have the chance
to live a year and then it lives a year
and might start doing some weird [ __ ]
versus
other plants so they don't really care
um but then if you keep a clone in cheap
condition
unhealthy whatever problems like
it can deteriorate but i think you can
also revive it for sure it's pretty easy
i mean if you know how to grow
organically it's pretty easy to bring it
back
you just grow it healthy for a while you
can put it outside in the sun for like a
month or two and then take clones off it
and bring it back inside and obviously
make sure it doesn't have any bugs that
you're going to bring in but
the sun really does wonders for
rejuvenating cuts when you need to
and
really like if i get a clone and it's
grown synthetically
and like let's say it comes in
some soil or whatever and i know there's
salts in there like
i'll grow it for a bit i'll transplant
it up to like some organic soil but
the salts are already in there to me so
i'm like i'm gonna grow it big and then
take some new clones grow those totally
organically and then i'll flower it so
that it's
kind of cleaning up and kind of getting
towards my growing style a little bit
more and like at the same time it's
adapting to my led and my little bit
more grow rooms and all that stuff
yeah makes sense so you reference not
bringing any bugs inside if that were to
happen what would your ipm treatment or
go-to regime be
um
pretty much beneficial predators have
been the best thing that i've ever used
um
like i used to use azamax and edge
because it was supposed to be organic
and then
now they're they came out
saying like yeah there's also these
banned pesticides secretly in here so
you know stopped using that real quick
and i was like [ __ ] but luckily i had
only used that veg because
in flour you never want to spray
anything like even foliar sprays and
flowers like you're going to smoke at
the end and people don't realize that
but anyways um
basically
my number one ipm is like i generally
don't take in clones and i don't go in
my room unless i'm clean like i usually
take care of the gardens in the morning
so i'll just take a shower before i go
in and i'll leave you have like a garden
outfit that i'll wear for like a couple
weeks at a time like just when i go in
there and then i'll change out a bit
like keep it clean
or you know just don't go in there like
if if you've been in a grow or if you've
been outside even like if you've touched
any plants like dude there's gotta be
some
some eggs on your skin or some [ __ ]
that's gonna like [ __ ] up your grow so i
just stay super clean when i go in there
so that i don't have to spray anything
and i don't have to constantly buy
predator bugs to take care of issues
and then you know sometimes something
will come in i'll get like some thrips
or aphids or whatever and you can get
these predator bugs that will eat them
all and they literally eat all of them
till they're super gone and you won't
see them again
and that's just the best because
there's no chemicals involved at all and
it's the most natural way it's the same
thing that happens outside
yeah i agree and just as a little point
i wanted to add in there i've heard a
few people like
i guess like the undertone in their
voices they've been critical of predator
mites and they're like yeah but what
about like the predator mites pooing and
stuff like that
and uh the the thing i wanted to quickly
point out is that
the predator mites largely are not on
the buds they're on the leaves and you
don't you don't smoke those really and
the amount they poo is minimal because
they bio-convert into like recreating
babies instead of pooping heaps so yeah
just a little fyi for anyone out there
who's wondering because that's something
i always hear they're like aren't you
just like solving one problem but it's
like causing the same problem in a way
and it's like well not really but um
anyway just to jump to a bit of a
different topic
what do you think will be some of the
future varieties and or flavors that are
going to storm the scene and do you try
to predict that to a certain extent like
i mean imagine if you had made putang
back when tanji had first came out you
know you can only assume that it would
have rid that wave of popularity a
little more do you actively think about
that at all
no because honestly like even though i
really see it's for people to grow and
stuff i'm pretty much just breeding for
myself for what i want to make and what
i like and think is good
and
um
i don't really know what's out there
sometimes for weed like there was
a lot of times like i'll go like half a
year or a year without smoking like
anybody else's weed and then at one
point i'm like what is weed supposed to
be like like let me get some weed from
somewhere else just like make sure i'm
still doing a good job like i don't even
know anymore like what
other people's weed is like so a lot of
times i'm in my own world with that just
because there's not that many organic
growers out here
um that i know personally at least so
um
and then like with the scene and all
that what they want i don't really know
what the [ __ ] they want because i feel
like the people
uh
seek out my like really unique strains
or their kind of land race base like
they're people that are looking for
something different than the norm
and then
i mean people that are looking for star
people they just want to believe that
gets them high and that's tasty and all
that so
like
i don't know i feel like i have
something for just about everyone like
that's part of why i read with the glue
at one point was because like
i knew i had a way to improve it and a
way to kind of
use something popular and good that
people want to like put my own twist to
it so
usually i just kind of make what i want
to see because i don't know like
when i go to a dispensary is all this
like
most of the menu is stuff that i don't
want to smoke so i just don't go there
and just like this is [ __ ]
everything's gas i don't really like gas
everything's cookies i can't smoke
cookies because it just has a bad
reaction with
my physiology i just freak out when even
if it's in a cross like my body's just
like no don't soak that so i learned
after 15
you know different cookies crosses that
like okay
it just doesn't buy with you just don't
smoke that so
a big variety of what's out there i just
don't smoke and i just smoke what i want
to smoke and then like if i hear
something cool like oh [ __ ] like this
grower just grew like an old school haze
or like
some
wacky hybrid of like nigerian something
i'm like dude hell yeah like i'll try
some of that but i'm not gonna go try
like
a wedding cake or something like
something something like that you know
it's just not
for me so
even though it's the trendy stuff right
now but most of the trendy stuff is like
not what i'm into
and so i don't know why but this just
springs to mind just kind of loosely
referencing earlier on when you were
talking to d-man and saying this you
know star people's not like other purple
weed would you ever consider doing like
a star purple a star people sorry
cross two like a purple strand like you
know an urkel or a granddaddy purple
like just for the lols
yeah um i actually have
a little thing in the works right now
with that
because i found a purple that i really
liked
um from inspector he sent me a bunch of
his mendo f1 to work with and
it's a mendo purse cross with his
pakistani
and um
they were really really unique because
to me at least they did not smell like a
purple i also grew like some endo perps
test ones just to get an idea of like
the mango prayers because i hadn't grown
the clone but
i got an idea for that but then i grew
up
the f ones which were the regular seeds
with the the [ __ ] cross
and i really liked them i was like damn
this is another purple that like
you know it gets you actually high it
had a really unique effect for me i
couldn't go in the grow room when i
smoked it which kind of sucked but
what would happen is the life is [ __ ]
through the strobing thing in my vision
whenever i would smoke it
and
that's you know it was uncomfortable but
at the same time like dude give that to
people that want to party and they're
going to love you you know if it really
like [ __ ] your vision that's like a
unique effect versus just like
a normal high it's like if there's
something more to it
and the flavor was really really cool
i was having so much trouble describing
it but
it was a really really bright it wasn't
much of a purple smell until i cured it
for like two months
but it was really bright and like
i don't know creamy vanilla was a little
tiny dash of lemon in the background and
like
i don't know it smelled like the color
white for whatever reason it was like
didn't smell like the color purple
and
those are really really cool plants so
it's like this
and they're beautiful they look a little
like star pupil although the flower
structure was very different it had the
same
kind of purple that starts in the center
and it's just purple the whole time it
looked pretty similar
um and it had its own unique leaf
structure that i hadn't seen in other
stuff so just like this is unique enough
to cross with the star pupil
and just see what purple craziness comes
out so
right now i'm flowering a few of those
out and somebody's hunting like a
hundred of them so i'm gonna see what
comes out of there
and
throw a few more of them and hopefully
that'll be a release in the future i
want to call it the valedictorian if
it's as good as i expect
that's a good name
so
what would be your advice for an
aspiring breeder
oh yeah that's a fun one so
i love when people want to breed because
like breeding is a huge part of growing
for me it always has been just because
like
i always end up just like making a
little two seeds on the side while i was
growing stuff for smoke and i think it's
a really important part of growing
um
if you want to read i think
you should have a goal to start with
like
that goal just has to be a vision of
like what type of plant you want or what
you want to see happen let's say you
have like
two strains you like and you just think
like what if the combine is like that's
a goal already like you're thinking
you're getting somewhere like you have
to have a reason to do what you do not
just like all right i picked up these
ten clones and like i popped one seed
out of a packet bought and it's a male
so i'll just hit everything like that's
not the way to do it
um you gotta have a little bit of a goal
and then a little bit of plan how you're
gonna like do decent job versus doing a
shitty job you know
and to me i tell people like
usually
like grow some plants that you know you
like let's say you buy a pack of seeds
from breeder
and you like that strain you let's say
even you pop half the pack
and you like them
you've found that they're they're all
pretty similar and they smell good and
whatever
and you're like damn this is awesome
and then i have like this female of this
other strain that i really like and like
i see them matching up nicely like
this one has this trade and this one is
that trade and i think it'll combine
good
and you know maybe revisit those seats
maybe buy another couple
buy another couple packs if you can
afford it
um
and like look through all the mails and
find a male that you can cross with your
other female of a different strain that
you think will work well
and then
don't just be like all right i'm done
like growing out don't just grow one
grow like as many as you can
and give them the people to grow because
you're not gonna be able to grow
probably all of them you know you're
probably gonna be able to grow
however many fit in grow room but if you
can pass them out to 10 friends
you're going to start seeing what's
really in there what you created
and to me there's like nothing more
beautiful than combining two plants and
then growing them out and seeing that
combination like that you did and seeing
like oh [ __ ] like there's the benching
in the smell from the star pupil but
then there's
like the overwhelming sativa effect from
the amnesia haze and the
flowers are purple but they now they're
smelling like haze but the stem road
smells like pupils
it's like super [ __ ] exciting when
you're growing out your crosses
and you're just seeing the best traits
of all plants that you found and put
into that cross itself
and
another thing i would say is like
research the genetic background of your
strains and take some time to learn
which strains have hermes tendencies and
which don't
because
sometimes like i don't know you might
find something that you like as a plant
and you don't realize like three
generations back it has cookies in it
just because the f1 cross you got
was stable when you grew it doesn't mean
that there's hermey disasters waiting to
happen in your next outcross because
chances are that's what's going to
happen
if you work with sketchy things
sometimes so i don't know do some
research behind everything like
learning the lineage really helps you
get a feel for the plant and kind of
expect what you might find
especially if you dive deeper into more
generations and stuff like that and i
like to look at like seed finder is a
pretty good website like i know some
people say like they're not that
accurate but
a lot of their stuff's accurate and then
go you know go to a second or a third
source and see if it matches up and if
you know the real lineage of your strain
based on like how many people say what
and
hopefully you know what's in it at least
maybe it's all wrong but usually you can
get a good idea
and
find the planets that vibe with you
don't create what you think people want
to see create what you want to see
because
i don't know people sometimes people
maybe even lack the confidence to know
that like
their opinion matters
just as much as like some famous
attitudes opinion like you're equal
people dude
if you want something
do it and create it and
it's gonna be awesome like if you're the
only one that likes some weird ass treat
read for that weird-ass trade and make
it
and you're gonna find people that love
it too and they're gonna be really happy
because they thought the only ones that
wanted that
yeah sounds like some good plans so
what's your thoughts on breeding with a
mother
that was originally a feminized seed
oh yeah this is a fun one so
i'll tell you right now it does not
matter if your plant came from ephemera
reg seed it matters
that exact pheno that plant that you're
dealing with
how stable it is and how stable it is in
a cross
and it's plain and simple
you could have a really nice mom from a
regular seed and depending whatever
genetics are in that it might not be
good for breeding or it might be awesome
for breeding and the same goes for femme
seed
it could be super stable when you breed
with it or it could be super harmy but
i tell people do a run with your moms or
stress test the hell out of them and see
who croaks you know like [ __ ] with your
lights in the middle of the night turn
them on for a little for like half an
hour like every couple weeks during
flower like
if you can [ __ ] with your temperatures
like just shot your heat off or shut off
your ac and let it go wild for like a
few days and like
i don't know maybe let them almost die
for like not watering them and then
water them like just enough that they
bounce back i do all kinds of weird [ __ ]
like
just as a test to see how stable your
plants are
and
usually once you've done that like you
have at least a much better chance that
they're gonna outcross well because they
seem to be stable although it's not
always the case you definitely just have
to grow up whatever cross you make but
um it's no secret that you need a pupil
the amnesia haze came from them seed
from royal queen seeds and i was not
planning on breeding with it but i just
found some amazing pheno and i was like
[ __ ] it let's see what happens and
i was totally expecting it to be like
some sketchy-ass hermit cross because it
was a fence seed but
they all came out super stable and super
amazing
and
that mom was a really really good plant
and it was so so vigorous didn't matter
that it was from the fmc it was insanely
vigorous so
i don't know i i see a lot of things
come from fantasies and see a lot of
good things come from egg seeds too
yeah i can definitely attest to that
so in regards to being more of a
well-established breeder these days do
you find that there's any difficulty in
dealing with multiple seed banks is
there at times where you wish you were
just going through one or do you kind of
like being able to spread your work out
a bit
um i like being able to spread it out
because for whatever reason like
customers seem to have their own
preference like some some growers are
just like when's it coming to neptune
and i'm like dude it's a seed bank and
this seed bank like if you want it go
get it before it's gone because it's
limited and they're like i'm gonna wait
till neptune gets it or like i'm gonna
wait till the east coast gets it and
sometimes they're not even like locally
from that area it's just like where they
prefer to shop for whatever reason so
it's kind of cool to
spread them out to different places and
different people and like
you know some of the seed banks are
close friends of mine so it's like they
in my book they come first like it first
dibs on whatever
and then the people who take like a
month to answer me like it's their fault
if they miss a drop or something but
people are just going to get them
like it's kind of first come first serve
like i reach out to everybody and tell
them like all right these are coming
next and then
get them if you want them don't get them
if you don't but this is what's
happening i try to like tag the seed
banks that only have this train when
it's
available and stuff it's hard to keep
track obviously so sometimes i just have
them all and i'm like just look through
them see if you can find it
yeah but yeah i like it
so
on to our last question before the short
fire ones
who is someone because you mentioned
earlier you've done some collabs before
but who are some breeders who you would
love to do a collab with going forward
and more importantly how would you
logistically envision the project go
down would you want it to be like you
select one parent they select the other
or how would you want to do it
um
definitely would love to do a collab
with bobotie
just because
i find that he vibes i vibe with him
like with his whole philosophy and his
way of doing things
from his vision of the planet and
kind of
yet pretty much he's one of my favorite
readers so
i would like to do something with him if
he was down for it like i mean i've read
with some of his work before so i would
love to see him read some of mine and it
could go any way that works you know
like send him a cut or something uh send
him seeds to hunt through and
you know maybe hit it with one of his
males on in his own program or whatever
or maybe he send me something special to
work with um
and then you know same with any other
reader if i was going to collab like
something like that like right now um
i didn't even really realize how it was
a collab but i sent dragon's flame
um affino of d-man's panama powerhouse
and then d-man was like yeah he can
breathe with it and i was like yeah you
can breed with it and then all of a
sudden i was like oh [ __ ] we're we're
collaborating aren't we cool hell yeah
and i talked to him a lot he's a cool
dude with like some really unique
paintings going on
and he does really really large humps so
um he's got some awesome selections for
sure so
now he's he released this pan dragon
which is
basically it's a cool out of the three
of us because i hunted
the pen with a powerhouse that demand
bread
and dragon flame across it with his
dragon stash mail so
stuff like that's really cool and then
who else would i want to work with
definitely more stuff with d-man i was
really impressed with his stellar
collision which was
a star pupil cross with power load
and
that [ __ ] was a power load dude it was
[ __ ] strong i was so surprised that
just like how ridiculous those plants
were like these huge baseball bats but
then it was potent too and i was like
damn you nailed it
really really nice so
collab is always fun i'm always open to
it like any breeder that
vibes with me like
if i don't know they pretty much have to
not like cookies and then they're in
i think
all right
i like people that grow organically and
like have a decent sense for the planet
and
pretty respectful and like
i don't know
i i think the vibe just has a lot to do
with everything and the breeding
practices too
yeah of course it all follows through
so on to our last set of questions the
quick fire ones
firstly what is your favorite strain at
the moment
damn
um
it totally depends on my mood it's
either star pupil panama powerhouse
uh
mr e is a go-to because it's always
comfortable
if i'm like super anxious i'll just
smoke mr d
and i never get too i'm always just like
perfectly grounded but at the same time
it's pretty damn strong so that's a
really special plant too those are like
my top three at the moment
yeah okay and so now to get a bit more
specific favorite strain of all time
only one
damn
i gotta go with my baby star pupil
because that thing is it's just too
special i don't know it's brought me on
so many journeys and brought me so much
happiness and
to so many other people too it's just
like
super good vibes all around and somehow
i never get bored of it growing it like
so many times so i guess the one but
there's a lot of close seconds for sure
so conversely on the other end of the
spectrum what's the strain which just
least jived with you
oh it's definitely girl scout cookies
and i'll elaborate on that because i
don't want people to just like not
understand
um
basically
it's like the strain that to me when you
hit something with the girl scout
cookies
it just becomes cookies
and obviously we'll have like different
expressions based on what you process
with a little bit but like i always can
pick out the cookies like in one toke i
can just taste it or just smelling the
bud like it's just
the cookies are very dominating strain
to me
um even when it seems not to be like i
can just pick it out and
it's it's not just that it hurts and all
that is like i physically
can't smoke it personally because like
it gives me this crazy depression
anxiety like bad head
and it comes through in the crosses too
so whatever reason like i don't like
that strain and then
to make it worse like everybody started
breeding with it and putting it in
everything and
i swear it's like every other plant i
see in my explore page is like hey that
looks good but it kind of looks like
cookie i wonder what it is and then i
click on it and it's like
something something cookies or something
else with something across the cookies
in the background there's so many
breeders using it and it makes it so
that i can't smoke half the weed that's
out there and i try to be open-minded so
i always smoke it and then
i have a bad time every [ __ ] time and
there was two cookies
there was two cookies crosses that i
liked out of
i've documented at least 15 that i've
tried but i've probably tried more than
that because i don't usually write down
when i smoke [ __ ] but
i've smoked a lot of cookies and i only
like to go ever
and they were like pretty far out
crossed and the ones that i liked
yeah um and yeah i don't know it's just
like [ __ ] up the g pool really bad
because
i don't know cross anything into
everything and then you lose diversity
and you can never
get it
back fully because it's in there it's
like
i don't know imagine there was a gmo
strain and everyone was like [ __ ] gmos
and then like
if every other strain had that in there
it would be a huge issue so
to me is contamination
and it's simply a strain that i don't
like and i appreciate i respect the fact
that people do like it because for a lot
of people the girl scout cookies is like
good medicine or it's a good plan or
whatever they like about it and i
completely respect that because whatever
my favorite might be could be their
least favorite i don't know like
everybody has their own body and
everything works differently for them so
i respect the plant but i feel like it's
way way overused and it's really causing
problems in breeding and then
diversity and like when you go to
dispensary and restraint is like the
same thing
when it's
three quarters of them are just a
cookie's cross and then the one you
think isn't a cookie's cross you look it
up and it is
that's a thorough answer i like that
so
if you could only grow one land race
strain for the rest of your life which
one would it be
oh [ __ ]
um
[Music]
see that's tricky because first i went
to panama and then i was like dude
sometimes panama's way too [ __ ]
strong like it's for my whole life
i'm just going to go crazy if i only
smoke that so
i mean
can i grow the strains on the side
to balance it out
okay
um damn
that's super tricky
because like that's a favorite of mine
but that's too strong
honestly like i need something more
mellow that i can chill with so that i
can smoke it
like whenever i need to what's smoothing
probably like
some purple type of packs to any land
race just because like they're not that
strong
and i love strong weed but
if i was stuck with something forever
i would have to go with something that's
a little bit mellower just
like for my own sandy because a lot of
the stuff that i breed i can't smoke it
every day it's like when i want an
experience or like whenever when i'm in
the right mindset i can smoke them days
and days in a row but then other times
like give me something mellow like this
shit's too strong the land races are
pretty wild sometimes
yeah that's that's a good pick i was
kind of thinking in my mind the [ __ ]
because of those reasons you mentioned
plus you can even find some like uh
narrow leaf packies as well so you know
goes both ways sometimes yeah
so definitely
next question what's the biggest mistake
you see people making when they're
starting to breed
um
[Music]
not
using enough selection because i see so
many people
that they pop two pack two seeds out of
like one pack let's say like they're
growing a few different strains but each
one they only pop like one or two seeds
and then like
something gives them a mail and they're
just like that's my mail and while that
can work that's just a crapshoot like if
you're lucky that won't work but
nine out of ten times if you select a
male out of like
even ten males instead of one male
you can look for something that you're
looking for rather than just using what
you have
and the same goes for females too
actually i mean i really love hunting
males and i could get into that little
what i like to look for but
first i want to say that
people uh
i don't know i see a lot of beginner
breeders like
they pop one or a few seeds and they got
like one staple female and they just
like go and breed with it
and it's not like the worst i did
because like you could for sure make
something good and if you're just doing
it for yourself and your friends it's
cool but
there's so much more
potential and more fun really if you can
do a larger gene pool
and
people always say like they don't have
the space and blah blah blah but just
grow smaller plants and grow more of
them and
look for like
something special like i think you have
to know this planet a little bit more
like you can start breeding when you
start growing for sure but you have to
keep an eye on the plant
as a species and see what variations are
in there and what you like and what you
don't like
and that's how you're going to create
something a little bit better
is by weeding out the bad ones and like
a lot of people will say like yeah i
have this one plant and it's pretty it's
not strong but it has all these other
traits and the flavor sucks and then
i'll cross over this and try to make it
better and i'm like dude if you have a
bigger selection you'd probably find a
stronger one to work with to begin with
that has maybe a better flavor and then
like work with a good plant and another
good plant make those better don't work
with a sheep plant and a decent plant
and try to make cold because you
certainly can but it's just more work
and like at this point there's so much
good stuff out there like just pick a
good one
like find a good one take the time to
find special plants and then you'll
create some really cool stuff
yeah for sure and i mean you just kind
of said yourself you'd love to talk
about some our selection stuff why don't
we do it before we wrap it up
okay so mail selection right yeah
yeah so
basically
i try to look at the male plants as if
they were female plants and for kind of
the same things you would look for
the only thing is that you can't smoke
it i mean people say you can try to
smoke it but
there's no buds to smoke it's plain and
simple you're not going to go smoking
your nails really
to get high so
um my first piece of advice is like
generally grow
hunt milk of the strain that you've
already grown before and smoke the
females or at least if you haven't run
it you've smoked a female of it and you
know what it's like
and
um
pay attention to like the pheno of the
female in that strain that you're
looking for especially if it's like a
polyhybrid that may have a few different
phenoes
you might want to select male that kind
of seems to match up with the female
that you like
um
and you have to do all of this
with all your other senses you can't
smoke it but the male plant is just as
much of a cannabis plant as the female
plant and
when you first start flowering males
like a lot of people just like okay well
there's pollen that's uses it but
i don't know that's kind of early to
make your decision because
the male flowers develop over time and
sometimes they'll start dropping a
little pollen but they're not fully
grown yet you haven't seen like
how it really stacks and how
if it gets
resonance and trichomes and
what it
you know like there's a lot more to see
so
i recommend first of all get like
a strain you like start a bunch of seeds
of it you can even call the females if
you don't have time for that or give
them away or whatever but like you want
a lot of males to look through and you
can do it you have to like squeeze them
in a two by four or four by four or
whatever like small areas fine small
plants are fine but like the more plants
the better like flower in a two or three
gallon if you can like to keep them
small but still get a decent expression
off of them
you could flower them in a soiled bed if
you want then you can do way more plants
that way like
in a 4x4 bed i like to start 250 seeds
and then narrow it down to like 30 to 50
final plants to hit flower with
um and then you can really look through
the phenos as they're flowering and you
can clone off of whatever you need and
you can re-veg a male clone too you just
gotta keep picking off the pollen sacks
but it works usually
um
and let's see so flour a whole bunch of
those find
you gotta stem rub them like i said
earlier stem rub them like probably
every week or so
um
starting pretty early you know when
they're a few notes tall and they start
smelling pretty good
i love
to hunt males under full spectrum
lighting especially as cmh because
you can really smell
the turbines a lot more with that kind
of lighting maybe it's the uv maybe it's
the full spectrum but
when you get really really stinky plants
you get a really good clue to like
what what if you know that maybe or like
the intensity of you is big with the
male that that can help a lot to pass on
to the next generation and get you
something really really
um
and
let's see
there's a lot of growth
characteristics and veg that are pretty
important when you're going through big
selections like if you're starting a few
hundred in solo cups
and they're ready for transplant this is
where you're gonna throw half of them
out because you're gonna look at the
root development as you take them out of
the cup
and
everything that has half-assed roots
doesn't matter how good the plant is
it's not perfect to get rid of it you
gotta call it a lot of plants so that
you're just ending up with the best one
so
even if each stage of transplant you
have to weed out half the plants just to
fit your space like that's good because
you're only gonna keep the best and
um yeah root development is big just
because you want the best plant you can
get in like every aspect and something
that grows roots fast probably going to
grow above ground faster too
um
let's see
the first males that show sex i always
kill those no matter what
like when you're just in veg and
everybody's showing female male like
there's usually one day where like you
know maybe a few of the mail show like
it doesn't matter just get rid of those
um
and
usually the later showing males
are better or more recessive
um all of these things by the way you
have to test in your cross because they
can be totally wrong sometimes the male
will not pass on what you think it will
um and it depends on the cross across it
with a few different things and see what
happens and grow those all out but these
tips will help you get like at least
one of the best males of your stock that
you're working with and you might want
to try a few different ones on like a
few different branches and label
everything and keep the clones but
then going into flower you want to see
like does a stack hard like a female
does it stretch super shitty lanky and
weak or does it have like a little more
better structure like more branching for
the same size plants
usually a good thing like i don't know
there's a certain structure i'd like to
look for but
it's
you know look for a good planet don't
just take one male that you have because
you have two seeds go through a lot of
males whatever you can afford to do
and like just find that awesome plant
like almost every mail that i've ever
used has been super resinous and i've
heard other breeds breeders saying that
they've never seen a residence male and
i'm like how i see them all the time
like
they're out there they're
maybe it depends what
jeans you're working with because some
strands may just have one but
i think the bigger selection the better
things you're gonna find so
go for big selection look for female
qualities um the smell is super
important the intensity of the smell
and just the growth habits maybe i don't
pick the very tallest male either but
something in the middle
a little vigorous is nice
yeah wow that was a really comprehensive
little run down do you think that maybe
some of the reason a lot of people
uh don't see those resinous males is
because
maybe they might claim to but they just
don't really let the flowers bloom that
long because that's something i noticed
you know a lot of people as you
mentioned will be pretty quick to cull
the mail off
yeah um well like
when i did the blue magoo mails and i
had like 23 22 males there was three
resonant ones that are straight up
frosty veg so i knew right off the bat
and then i was flowering those three and
a few others and just those three were
like
pretty caked on some areas like really
frosty before pollen even came out
um and that might have been kind of an
exception for like early early frosty
ones but
um
definitely
some of the males that i thought were
like that's good but oh well it's not
frosty like then they turned out to be
frosty leader flower too so that's
definitely a good point like people
might make their selections to her just
because it started dropping pollen but
you just gotta keep it somewhere
separate and like bring it in when
you're ready to use it when you know
it's the right choice
yeah solid advice
so we'll jump back now to the actual
last question of our interview
and it is if you could go back to any
one place any moment in time presumably
to collect seeds or maybe a clone
where would you go and why
oh i like that the clone part i never
thought about that
but uh yeah
probably like i don't know india always
seemed to vibe with me maybe it's just
the imagery that i've been exposed to
but it just seems like such a beautiful
place where like some
beautiful plants with amazing vibes have
to come from so probably like the
mountains in india
and when
probably
i don't know how long they've been
cultivating there but i know they've
been for a while so like
i would want to go
before like
white people started breeding i guess
before we like [ __ ] everything up with
our poly hybrids so anytime before
i don't know even the early 1900s i'm
sure like there was some great like
locally bred stuff that wasn't like
super hybridized but just like nice
selections that came from land race in
the area
like you know like a good air like a
family heirloom somewhere in the 100
years ago that would be really really
really cool
yeah for sure i think there's a lot of
stuff locked away in india that we
haven't seen yet so to speak
yeah definitely there's all these people
living in the mountains that have their
strains that they grow there and there's
a lot of wild strains and
there's there's like remote locations
and
really really
interesting things that are hiding from
civilization which
probably is for the best so we don't
ruin it
like by bringing our own seeds in there
and stuff
yeah right
so i think that one um that might bring
us about to the end of it was there any
shout outs or comments you wanted to
make
um
yeah shout out to everybody that's
growing organically
because
it's like the single most important
thing
um
and
grow for like grow with good vibes and
good intentions really
um
it's like
i don't know organic and good vibes like
so some people it's just gonna sound
like hippie trash whatever but
seriously think about it it's the
healthiest way like
people are gonna be smoking your product
like there doesn't have to be any
bottled stuff in there and then the
vibes you put in
that goes along with you like what
you're doing
it's really gonna show and you're gonna
create some amazing vibes and just like
do what you love don't do it to impress
people do it like for yourself maybe
impress yourself but
um just have fun and like
shout outs dangerous because i don't
want to miss anybody
but
um
definitely a huge thank you to everybody
who's helped me in any way like
with growing teaching me things or like
teaching others um everybody who wrote
those books that made me so paranoid
like you're the reason i'm not in jail
so thank you for that too
uh
like
everybody
does
doing good things for the cannabis
community um there's so many people
working their asses off like in politics
and [ __ ] like that just to like
try to get wheat to be a little bit more
legal and safe for like a few more
people and that stuff really really goes
a long way like
those are the people that are changing
lives by making so like less people get
in trouble for such like
and
it's a basic human right to a planet so
like thank you to all those warriors out
there that like doing really awesome
things because
it makes a big impact and then i feel
like everybody that's ever bred anything
that i've grown because
most of it is a hell of a lot easier to
grow than like gnarly ass land races for
sure so
even
you know every all the strains that
we're all growing they're super special
and
people definitely need to respect even
like there's there's a few things you
can say about them but they're
they're a lot of work that goes into
everything so just thank you to like
everybody in community that's doing
anything good because
it's pretty much all good there's so
many good things going on
yeah i totally agree
so again a big thank you for coming on
the show and for sharing all your wisdom
with this mass medical strands
cool thank you so much for having me
that was a blast
[Music]
so there you have it crew
a big thank you to mass medical strains
for taking the time to chat with us
again and a big thank you for you guys
for sitting through until the end
our sponsors as always 420 australia
organic gardening solutions seeds here
now
best in the game what they do
check them out you will not be
disappointed
and the patreon gang as always you guys
get the biggest shout out we love you
thanks so much for donating something
cool is in the works guys all the
patreon fans will get a shot at being on
a future episode keep that one in your
cap
anyway i'll check you guys next time
we'll see you
[Music]
la la la la
[Applause]
[Music]
la la la la
[Applause]
[Music]
you