hello and welcome to another episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts this episode as
always was brought to you by our amazing
sponsors 420 Australia your number one
store for 420 lifestyle and apparel
organic gardening Solutions your
One-Stop shop for all your organic
gardening needs and finally number one C
Bank in the game seeds here now you know
them you trust them you love them
guarantee on
satisfaction why go out something which
you then might be pissed off about and
there's just nothing you can do
guarantee is there for a reason y'all
hit them up on this episode we're joined
by the one and only shud of 707 seed
[Music]
bank really excited to bring this one to
you it was a whole bunch of fun let's
jump into
it
all righty I'd like to extend a big
thank you and welcome to shabbat of 707
Seedbank thanks so much for joining us
today thanks for having me bud totally
excited so first question we've been
doing recently what are you currently
smoking
on uh I'm I still love my OG the uh sfv
Cut's been my favorite for 15 plus years
now um can't get enough of it so been
smoking a little bit of that little bit
of lemon tree um doing some blends of
the two give give that lemon tree a
little extra
kick wow there's a lot to go into so
first of all the sfv thing that's
interesting I've noticed a lot of the
chem fam seems to favor sfv do you think
that a lot of people just like don't
really maybe have the real cut and so
they don't think it's the best like why
do you think that most I guess what I'm
trying to say is why do you think most
people don't regard it as the best while
a lot of the real heads do
I think the majority of the people that
have sfv now have some kind of fake cut
they bought from the club and was just
called
SF uh a lot of the dispensaries out here
um I know they pass off a Cali
Connection cut of the San Fernando
Valley as the real cut you know um so
it's it's just a lot of
mislabeling and you know they they
probably just don't have the real deal
is what's going going
on and out of curiosity do you think all
of the calicon hybrids are made with the
real
one uh swerve
uh who knows about that guy um I'm sure
he's just throwing names on stuff here
and there uh he got me he got me for a
few packs of seeds maybe 10 plus years
ago
and worst seeds I've ever grown in my
life I mean even even worse than Sensei
seed now oh yeah see he got me for a few
packs too but here's what I do have to
say about swer because I know swerve he
listens to the show and he doesn't like
me because I've said some things about
him in the past but what I think is true
and I don't say this as a criticism is I
like to describe swerve gear as like a
glass Cannon I think if you run like six
F seeds from him probably going to find
four Hermes but one of them could well
be a really nice keeper and that was my
experience I I ran like three of his
packs I think out of the three packs I
found two keepers which is you know like
I hope to find at least one from one
pack so you know I was hoping for three
got two so maybe a little low but you
know those Keepers were nice but the
fact that the others were Hermes that
was a bit like you know i' maybe just
prefer they weren't Keepers
but oh well I guess that's yeah sry were
they were they uh feminized seeds or
regular seeds feminized but here's how
we can add more to the story one of the
p one of the ones that I was
particularly Blown Away by was the it
was Bubba Kush feminize like but it was
from like a BX line and then I heard
that he actually purchased that line
from someone else and hadn't really done
it himself so I was like oh well I like
that one so H nice nice yeah he got me
for uh i' had bought 10 packs of the of
his sfv OG you know and went back and
forth talking to him and and you know he
sold himself pretty good anyhow that 10
pack of seeds or yeah the 10 packs um I
ended up throwing most of it
away yeah well I knew that he definitely
had some issues with the sfv line in
particular a few years ago and I think
ultimately the reason he came out and
said that there was some pollen
contamination
issues oh really yeah but I think he
also I mean I could be totally wrong but
I think he also said that like it was a
he had outsourced that crop and so yeah
I think that's maybe had happened could
be totally wrong if so feel free to come
on the show swerve
um I asked him he said no um anyway so
he sold me pretty good on those seeds
like I kept on asking him I was like you
know uh they need to be consistent what
did I think he said like they were work
to F6 or F7 or something like that yeah
yeah see seed finder says that they they
were consistent but it was it was
consistent crap is what it ended up
being all right well that that means
that like I got no idea of what sfv is
cuz that's my only real experience with
it is is the Cali Connection sfb yeah oh
okay all right I I grew out uh all the
ogs side by side one year um everything
I could get my hands on uh I did the sfv
the ghost the fire the triangle the
Tahoe uh what else was there there was a
y uh
white WiFi number three I think I had
gotten from uh from cornbread Ricky or I
forget what his name goes by big Ricky
from Swamp boys and uh there were my my
favorite out of all of them was
SF even to this day there's just
uh it works great for my body
chemistry it it it uh never lets me down
it's always just uh takes me to a higher
level doesn't matter how much of it I
smoke it gets me higher and higher each
time just just one and I mean it's been
a good solid shoot since you know the
early
2000s that uh I've been smoking on it
almost on a daily basis and I I still
haven't gotten tired of it yeah okay so
where do you think it sits in regards to
the ogs do you think it's one of the
originals or where do you think it it
spurts off in the lineage so to speak I
think it's just say uh a S1 maybe off
the triangle cush
um yeah probably probably just an S1 off
the triangle you know I'm not too sure
and and uh I I I stopped paying
attention to a lot of the uh the history
and the background of strains a while
ago it just seems like people were
making up a lot of [ __ ]
and yeah the truth would never really
came out so but
okay well I'm going to have to push you
for one more then because this is the
one I'm most interested in I got the
suspicion like most people that triangle
is the first but no one can really seem
to elucidate where ghost fits into
things cuz it's like I guess ghost could
maybe be an S1 of triangle and it's kind
of very triangle leaning and that it's
not like lemony like sfv but then I've
heard other people say that maybe it
went like triangled to ghost and then
from there ghost SL um you know cuz
obviously Oregon kid had it and he did
that famous S1 project and then someone
was like what if all of the sfv and the
face off and all of that just came from
that S1 series and I was like that's
that's plausible you know I mean I guess
right right I I know the face off
definitely came off of those uh I
remember when Fletch got those
originally um he kicked down a couple of
cuts and uh yeah I'm pretty sure he he
even said there were s1's from uh the
ghost or or maybe it was the cross uh
it's been so long it's hard to
remember but you know I I I hear people
say lemony with
sfv and I when I grew them all out side
by side I mean it it was really hard to
tell a difference between them like The
Ghost and the Tahoe are almost
identical uh you know even the triangle
there I mean there was just slight
slight little difference is when growing
them all out but just the the high from
the sfv and and I mean even the the
flavor just seemed to come out better
for me you know every grower is
different so I I don't know if I just
have a connection with that plant or
what but yeah okay and then what do you
think about the idea I don't know if it
was an actual grow or if it was a Fus
thing but someone basically put the idea
forward that they did a similar thing
too they collected them all and they
were like most of them are just the same
cut
yeah I seen that with the phos I was
just actually just on there a couple
days ago and noticed that there were all
but you know with phos who who knows
who's sending what cut in there and and
you know did did they were they able to
trace it back to the you know to the
original person you know so I'm not I'm
not
too until phos gets a a uh legit cut of
everything to to you know like a a
baseline for their Galaxy it's it's
still a little up in the
air yeah well what do you how far off do
you think they are because I I was of
the same mindset and then I was talking
to someone a few days ago and they
listed a whole bunch of cuts that we had
on record had been sent in like for
example uh you know CSI has said that he
sent in the chem 91 and purple urle meno
perss and then Noto dog uh sorry yeah
Noto dog is um sent in a few things and
you know what I mean like if you go
through all the Instagram posts online
you can kind of draw up a list of what's
been gathered and when I looked at the
list I was like that's actually pretty
comprehensive and I'm pretty confident
most of these guys have got the real
ones so I guess it kind of raises the
question at what point would you feel
comfortable with the Galaxy cuz I do
share that same concern but I I now
start to question like it it's looking
kind of complete to me right well you
just you just said the two names that I
I uh I I trust in those guys um they've
done their their homework both CSI and
not so dog they they've uh you know
they've tracked down their their cuts to
the to the original Source you know so
those guys I I totally trust um totally
you know believe in their judgment um
and their opinions uh but majority of
the
folks it's hard to say yeah true because
there's a lot of other stuff being sent
in that's just not correct yeah
absolutely absolutely I kind of blanked
on that one all right well let's jump
back for a moment all the way back to
the beginning what was your first
experience with
cannabis um I grew my my old man smoked
I got an older brother older sister uh
so my whole life it's always just been
there um the smell like I I remember
that from it's like one of my earliest
memories uh and then I was a latchy kid
both my parents worked um so at a young
age and the place I I grew up in the in
San Francisco area and it it was you
know uh low-income
housing um so there was a lot of
everything around it was we didn't
called the ghetto we called it the
get-go because there was just like every
other house was cooking meth in this
neighborhood um it never slept always
Sirens going off so there there was
pretty much just about anything and
everything you can imagine
at your fingertips in this
neighborhood so my first experience with
cannabis I was pretty
young um probably like nine or 10 with
the neighborhood kids uh smoked it a
couple times never really did
anything and then uh
my eighth grade
year someone had broughten some uh some
some nice green nuggets to school and we
all smoked out and that was the first
time I ever got really high and I
remember walking uh down the hallway of
the school and like just every step I
took just felt like I was climbing
higher and higher like floating in the
air
um kind it was you know I went to class
that day and and that that was a that
was a mistake I should have just cut and
never went
but it rocked my world and then uh fell
in love with it it just um put my mind
to ease uh they had put me on like you
know riddlin addd medicine all that
stuff at a young age so the the herbo
has always just been uh I never knew it
at the time but I always self-medicated
with it and it calm me down brought me
back to normal my my brain wouldn't race
you know a th000 miles per
hour and
then let's see here when I when I was uh
about 10 or 11 I ended up moving with my
uncle and
then my my uh I had an older cousin who
wanted to go to a dead show and then my
uncle was like you know if you want to
go you got to take me with him I was
pretty young I think I was like 13 or
something like that go to the dead show
with my cousin and uh was I got to
experience
LSD and that Chang my whole world around
I mean I was I was a pretty rambunctious
kid always getting into trouble and then
I remember these doses there were uh it
was like a a a pig dressed in a cops
uniform and and wow that it just it
changed my whole world even to this day
it's like pretty wild and then
um let's see from
there I ended up moving uh I was 14 now
I ended up moving uh with my sister in
New York City and lived there for a year
and I got a job uh it was under the
table job at this coffee shop it's
called The Sweetheart Cafe and then uh
there was a liquor store right next door
to the uh coffee shop
and uh every day like after work with my
tip money I would the liquor store had
this whole wall of of High Time
magazines uh and and they were like you
know from like 3 4 years before uh you
know backdated or what not so every day
with my tip money I would go in there
buy buy High Times and then from there
i' would walk to Washington Square par
Park and uh buy a little dime sack off
The rosters in there and then from there
I had another job where I was walking
dogs for my uh brother-in-law's boss so
I'd go uptown pick up the dogs go to
Central Park let the dogs loose and I
just roll up a blunt and read the high
times and and just get Stony over there
and I was like man as soon as I get back
to Cali you know every time I was like
this is what I'm going to do this is
this is my way out of the ghetto
so that was pretty much uh my herb like
I you know the beginning of it and then
um came back to California when I was
almost
16 and uh just jumped right into it I uh
would there was a a little Park well I'm
not a little park but it's called
bionis and uh I rode my bike you would
ride BMX down there and hiked down you
know I didn't really know what I was
doing but had some seeds I hiked down
into the creek then I grew him in the
shade nothing much really ever came out
of it and then uh one you know the few
that I did Harvest I ended up drying
them in the trees and turned brown and
moldy and nasty but you know this is the
early early 90s it didn't matter it was
uh me being you know 15 16 with some
herb it was pretty nice I was pretty
stoked hell yeah yeah
so what I just wanted to ask before we
move too far past it is when you were
getting that stuff from The rosters was
it ever anything
good no it wasn't and they would always
pass it off as like oh Humble County or
this that or the other and what it would
be would be it would be like a little
Grand baggie and the outside of it would
be you know brick weed and then in the
middle of it they would pack it full of
stem and Seed like I mean it must have
taken a good 30 minutes to package each
one of these things [ __ ] but you know I
just grind it all down and roll it up in
a tobacco leaf and a blunt back then it
was the only way I can handle the taste
and you know coming from Cali it was uh
you know where I grew up it it was all
just pretty much like the roadkill skunk
or cat piss uh we we' barely ever saw
Mexican
weed and so going traveling America and
going to like the East Coast I spent
some time in the South a little bit and
that's all they had it was all just uh
the brown
frown damn that sucks so yeah so when
did you first start growing properly was
it when you got back to Cali uh properly
so I got back to Cali uh I was about 16
I lived with my folks
for few months and then I took off again
and then I moved in with uh my pot
dealer at the time uh he let me uh C
couch Surf and all I pretty much had to
do was just answer his phone while he
went to work and you know take care of
his business while he was gone he let me
stay there for it's probably a good
solid year and then from there I moved
in with this uh old ha family they took
me in for about a year and you know I
was doing my thing always uh you know
hustling on the side and working odd
jobs here and there and
then when I turned
18 I was living with this with this girl
and my dealer at the time his name was
his name was Rick we called him tweaker
Rick you know you got early 90s in
California everyone uh all the old
cokeheads from the 80s turned to meth in
the 90s so it it was It was kind of
chaotic but anyhow my my pot dealer at
the time he was a tweak so we called him
tweaker Rick and he would do like weird
[ __ ] like he would come over
unannounced you know and be like hey man
I need to talk to you and then he would
take me out to his car turn up the music
like as loud as he could and then like
whisper in my ear like you know
everyone's listening to him anyhow uh
tweaker Rick ended up he was getting
herbf fronted as well from another guy
out in Santa Cruz mountains and uh
tweaker Rick ended up getting the great
idea of using this guy
all this guy pot money that he had owed
him to buy Elton John tickets right and
thinking he was going to scalp these
tickets in the parking lot and make all
his money back and double it up anyhow
he didn't sell a single ticket took you
know everybody he knew to see Elton John
and then you know ended up stiff in the
sky in Santa
Cruz so his way to pay back the guy in
Santa Cruz was he had introduced him to
me and and you know I I was still paying
the tweaker Rick price but now to you
know the source you know so he had
gotten his money back that way and after
a while uh we had built a relationship
he got some trust you know in me and he
was like you
know then that's when he told me that he
was grown he invited me over up to the
hills once and I started trimming for
them and so at this point I'm
18 and then uh he asked me one day he
was like you want to come help you know
you want you want to move out here and
help me out and I was like yeah
absolutely and and they were doing a
hydro setup and you know I I didn't know
much I didn't know anything back then to
be honest and they were doing a a rock
wool they were growing in rockwool uh
4-in Rockwall cubes on Rockwall
slabs and uh you know like this is
before carbon filters or anything like
that in Northern California we had three
Hydra Hydra stores there was one
Berkeley we had one in San Jose and then
we had one in in Santa not Santa Cruz in
Sacramento uh I think the only kind of
products were out was maybe uh Earth
Juice and General
Hydroponics I don't think there was
anything else out at that
time so uh ended up moving to Santa Cruz
was working uh for this
guy um like I said in rock wall on the
slabs and they had a cycling system so
the nugs never like filled out really
good uh you know the climate wasn't all
like gr but it's it's the early 90s so
as long as it didn't have seeds or if it
was brown you know it was going and you
getting top top dollar for it back then
so the guy I was working with they ended
up opening up a hydro store in the Santa
Cruz mountains and so this is yeah early
'90s
um no this is mid 90s uh n probably
[Music]
907 96 or 97 and my boss man uh had a
set up another house with this couple
living inside of it and they had just
opened up a Hydra store in the Santa
Cruz mountains in
sakel and the uh the DEA or I don't
think it was yeah maybe it was a DEA
they ended up following everybody uh
home
that would go to the Hydra store oh no
so it was called operation green fire
and they did it to you know I think it
was every Hydra store we had here in
Northern California so I mean it wasn't
too many but uh they were following
people home and ended up doing massive
raids and whatnot so at that time uh I
was at the grow house um early in the
morning my boss man wasn't there and you
know the door gets kicked down and and
you know here comes all these guys
hooting and hollering and whatnot and uh
so ended up getting busted then um my
boss man ended up getting uh six months
of work release in the Santa Cruz area
back then which you know for for the
amount that there he was growing I mean
if you were probably like you know in
Southern California or Eastern
California they would have thrown the
book at you and given you like five to
10 years but is you know out here you
got to know your laws and out here if
you live in the Northern District the
judge back then was very lenient with
the herb where you know the the judge in
the eastern district would would have
just thrown the book at you and you
would have been locked up for a long
long
time [ __ ] so that was my first Growing
Experience uh real like growing uh
Perpetual Harvest you know they taught
me how to clone
um uh so after we got busted there I
ended up going back to San Francisco
area um was doing my thing there
uh and back then I was getting some
really really good herb a indoor herb
from Santa Cruz mountains um like I
remember we had some awesome big bud and
Mongolian
indicia what else was there there was
one called The Asthma that I've been
looking for but no one's ever heard of
it um
since uh what else was there uh anyhow
so I was doing my thing in the bay um I
had some of the best herb in the bay
during the time and then the the
Canadian the Canadian the BC herb
started coming through and prices of
herb went from you know uh quality
indoor like wholesale was 4,000 bucks
and then this BC herb started flooding
in and it was going for
$2,000 so now no one wanted the quality
stuff they wanted the cheap cheap cheap
and uh that pretty much ended it for me
out there and then I moved to the Sierra
mountains and that's where I started
pursuing my grow uh much more and not
only that I had I had a a uh I had my
first kid then as well so that kind of
pushed me into it um I went back to
school uh got a couple jobs you know I
was working full-time and going to
school fulltime and uh was growing a
little herb in the backyard had a eight
lighter inside um help you know help get
bu and whatnot and at that time so you
know I learned with the rock wools so
that I was growing I I started with the
rock wool and you know just it would
just never turn out the way I wanted it
and you know I was taught with a
recycling system so the only thing I did
different was I ended up uh ditching the
recycling system and going to a drain to
waste and and that just changed the
whole setup I mean it it was night and
day just it all a sudden just turned out
amazing thick buds you know super Frost
I was growing train wreck back then and
uh nothing but train wreck for like a
good solid three years
and and then uh
man a lost track world no that that's
that's amazing so far so the question I
want to ask first off is were there any
uh like kind of prominent breeders back
then or was everyone still super Hush
Hush about everything super super super
Hush Hush super Hush Hush no one ever
knew what you were doing uh you didn't
tell anybody definitely didn't like you
know bring any girlfriends or anything
like that around um very very hush hush
you know uh and you know the only thing
you could learn from were the books back
then I mean I had all these high times
and all that stuff ask Ed but uh you
know there was there was nobody to talk
to about about it you know and you know
I had I had friends that were growing
also but they didn't know I was growing
and I didn't know they were growing at
the time it was always you know it was
really really Hush Hush back then and so
what what was the progression into your
first breeding project and what was like
the first cross you
made my first cross I ever made was uh
it was LE leato Uno or something like
that um I forget the name of the seed
leato Uno yeah I think it was leato Uno
or something like that I forget the seed
bank and I had uh there was a string
going around it was called the Blue Dot
um in
California and someone had told me it
was this lato Uno you know and that's it
was just a feno out of that and so
bought a pack of seeds popped them out
um didn't know you know really what I
was doing I was just playing and ended
up T dusting a train wreck with a mail
of that and I remember the seeds just
being these tiny tiny tiny little seeds
um which is is a normal characteristics
when you cross anything to train rank
but I thought I [ __ ] it up somehow you
know uh so that that was my first real
Cross or not real cross but me just
playing around and then um I ended up
getting the
[Music]
strain in about it was probably like
2000 maybe 2002 it was my old high
school strain cat piss and you know back
in when I was going to high school
everything was either catpiss or skunk
there was uh we didn't really have names
to it at all it was green or brown they
called it schwag or dank you know
kbud uh KGB killer
greenbud um so I ended up getting this
cat
piss uh founded in my hometown um
getting that and and I always thought
the cat piss was related to the roadkill
skunk back in you know in the uh in the
90s we the skunk we would always get
would be uh it would just be this really
light green barely any hairs and it
would always have these really fat uh uh
Sugar Leaf that would just coat like
cocoon the whole bud you know and and uh
so the cat piss is what kind of got me
going really into the breeding thinking
that I could find the roadkill inside of
it um but it wasn't in there at all it's
just all cat
piss so that that's what uh kind of got
me going into it and it was just uh it's
just labor love for
me man that's that's going to become a
sound bite just so you know that was so
good it's just all cat piss so
then so you know I've uh I was blowing
glass for a long time I've always liked
I've always enjoyed creating
uh things it's it's the breeding is is
like my art now it's
uh you know sort of just creating making
your own strain um digging through
digging through the seeds you know not
knowing what's going to pop up it's it's
super I I love it it's just uh really
exciting I love the gamble of it
um I love everything about
it yeah no I agree and I think that's
why we should pop more seeds and we're
going to talk about that soon but just
to quickly jump back to the cat piss I
noticed uh strains like the cat piss and
including cat piss pop up somewhat
commonly on your Instagram and more
importantly a lot of people you know
generally speak quite highly of it yet
it's hard to find and almost no one
really breeds with it why do you think
it fell off if it is kind of getting a
bit of a Resurgence right
now uh it's it's the same thing with
like the roadkill skunk
um well well back then so
mid90s uh like the cat piss that I'm
working with and you got the name
catpiss was just uh Loosely thrown on
anything that had that smell so the ciss
that I have now is a pure Indica but
like in in high school we would uh we
would get like a we would either name
the catus from the city we bought it
from or from the deal dealer so like we
we had the Nate dog piss we would get
cat piss from the girlr CLA so we called
it the CLA piss uh the cat piss that I
hold right now we would get it from this
town called Pittsburgh so we called it
the Pittsburgh piss um there was another
one called the Danville piss uh Tom the
bomb piss you know uh so and now after
you know growing for so many years I've
kind of you know like we the one we'd
get from this guy Nate um it had to be
like a super silver haze or some kind of
haze it was always really Airy really
you know really uh skinny um sugar
leaves where like you know a lot of the
other ones would be uh now you know
looking back at it I could tell it they
had to be you know indicas of some sort
just because of how fat the Sugar Leaf
would cocoon you know just be like one
leaf uh one blade would like cocoon the
whole entire
nugget yeah wow so I've always had like
a similar suspicion about cuz I noticed
that on your feed uh purple Inda pops up
and I've always figured that was another
cat piss type thing where it was just
like a broad term for many strains do
you think that is the case or it was
always referring to one cut the the
purple Indo has always been the one
cut ah see it's almost
counterintuitive yeah um came from the
Pacific
Northwest uh now I I have seen the
purple Inda here in
California but labeled purple
kush yeah so you know I I don't know if
the if it's the Garberville Purple Kush
from a long time
ago um I don't know if you know if it
started in Garberville made its way to
the Pacific
Northwest uh what what other names they
call they call it the ultraviolet as
well the purple
Indica um I think it might even have
another name but I just can't can't
remember off the top of my
head yeah it's so funny you mentioned
that cuz I remember the the first strain
to ever really kind of proper Captivate
my attention was indeed the Purple Kush
that was like the the mislabeled purple
Inda and I remember it was the second
time I'd ever smoked like proper good
American weed and there was something so
special about it and looking back on it
one of the first things I think of is
why don't people breed with these or
more importantly why don't you see like
s1's of these surely there'd be a demand
you'd
think you'd think you know and back in
the day before uh Instagram and I guess
before you know the oil craze there
there was you know this because uh you
know 100% of the market was all buying
flowers now it's like you know 50% of
the Market's buying flour and the other
50% is buying oils now so we lost a lot
of that and then now it's also big uh
you know it's it's what ever the jungle
boys is grown it's what people want and
and uh whatever is all hyped up or
whoever's rapping about what is is just
what the market wants now and and so
like a lot of these good Classics are
are going extinct and uh people are
missing out there's there's a there's a
lot of great weed but you know they just
want that picture picture perfect uh
herb that's on Instagram that
everybody's you know hyping about and
and you know they're they're going to
miss out on a lot of these good stuff
these good Classics that we had also
that that that purple Indica is uh it's
a real finicky plant and it's it's kind
of a pain to grow so I think that's that
was another reason why it never really
picked up like a lot of other strains
did yeah okay so in regards to
concentrates do you feel like the the
growing demand of consumers wanting
things like say Vape cartridges and just
you know dabs whatnot distillates in
general is going to have a negative
impact ultimately on the growing
culture yeah absolutely I absolutely I
think uh I know I know a lot of
Old-Timers you know they have been
smoking their whole lives and they don't
even smoke flour anymore they just go to
the cartridges now on the pens it's just
uh it doesn't smell for them they could
keep it in their pocket they could puff
it
anywhere uh it it's it's changing it's
changing really really fast the whole
the whole uh the whole ganja culture
that we had out here it's uh it's it's
definitely going to be a thing in the
past I feel like in the next 10 20
years and so how can we raise kind of
this issue in the broader mindset of the
the consumers Community I guess because
I think something which is kind of
implied in this whole discussion is that
a lot of the people buying these
cartridges are probably just blow and
they probably you know don't know much
about the majority of this do you think
we should try to put some information
out there or do you think like it's you
know like you can't force someone to be
like into something so to speak yeah I
don't think you could force people into
you know they people like what they like
and and uh they like things that are
easy and those cartridges are easy like
I said I mean people that have smoken
their whole lives or or uh smoking you
know flower their whole life or or just
switching over to the pens it blows me
away like and I've tried a couple pens
here and there I've tried some that
where they add the fake flavoring and
whatnot and you know I ain't gonna lie
they tastes good you know it's it's it
tastes like candy some of them and it
does kind of work but it's for me it's
it's not my thing you know I I don't
like the dabs I don't like the pens uh
you know I like to roll up a big fatty
and kick back and I like to enjoy it you
know I I I eat I like to eat my food
slow I like to smoke my you know I like
to relax with my
weed um so the the oil thing in the pens
has never been my jam but even even the
younger generation now um like I know my
my kids friends they always tell me that
they say like you know they've never
smoked herb before they've only taken
dabs which just blows me away you
know wow yeah with that in mind do you
have to keep this top this type of uh
consumer demand in mind when you breed
do you kind of reluctantly make plants
which might be more inclined to
concentrate production or is it an
afterthought no it's uh I breed for
myself I always have it's it's uh the
weed that I breed is the weed that I
enjoy smoking um and I mean I guess I
guess the real reason why I started was
you know I don't want to lose these like
like you know the roadkill skunk is
completely G gone for the most part and
and you know I I don't want to lose the
OG I don't want it you know 20 years
from now it just be completely gone so
pre
everything is uh has been I guess the
majority of stuff has been what I enjoy
smoking um I like I like uh it's got to
make my mouth water if it doesn't make
my mouth water I don't want anything to
do with it uh and it's got getting high
you
know yeah two two very good criteria so
going to get into some serious good
stuff here but the first thing I wanted
to throw out I wanted to put you a
little bit off foot here and say that
chem 4 has got to easily be my least
favorite of the chams so it's your job
it's your job to change my
mind
well I got a thing that I do with like
the sour the sour d and the chem where
uh I I lose half my yield but I I I
rootbound them um and when I do that uh
you know as long as you can get your as
long as you keep it healthy and and root
bound so I'll grow them out in a one
gallon pot and I'll leave it inside
there you know a veg for a month and
then I'll flower them out and what I
find is with with both the sourd and the
chem4 uh is the buds become much smaller
but much tighter and uh like the the I
don't know if it's just like the the
potency goes up or what but for my body
chemistry that chem 4 works really well
I had gotten the um the chem 91
originally before I got the chem 4 and
uh that came straight from skunk V I met
him he was uh doing some work over at my
neighbor's house one day and uh I went
over there and we just started talking
and then you know he had mentioned uh
the the chem
91 um the first time I had heard about
the chem 91 was from I think maybe I
read it in High Times or something like
that it was going like for $600 an ounce
in New York City uh you know the best
weed ever and then the second time I
heard about it was I was at a harvest
party and um Noto dog was there who else
Jack herrer was there um Kyle
kushman Eddie LEP always at these things
too and um at that party talking to Nato
dog he had also mentioned the chem 91
you know and I'm already intrigued now
I'm hearing $600 an ounce in New York
it's the best weed the strongest you
know this that and the other and uh you
know I begged him for a cut he was like
no it's you know him and his crew had a
pack it wasn't going anywhere so uh you
know fast forward to a year or two later
I met skunk VA over at my neighbor's
house and you know he's telling me the
story and then you know similar stories
as as Noto dog told me so I knew it was
legit uh and you know he had also told
me he was like you know I've never given
out a cut of this and you know I told
him I was like you know you know I'm
breeding um you know playing around I
was like you know let let me work it and
you know I'll give you back every step
of seeds that I make from
it um
so
so he he ended up uh giving kicking me
down a cut uh I grew it out a bunch um
my first cross with it was uh I had uh
back cross three the Bubba
cush and then used the mail of that and
hit the chem
991 and then from that I think I did
another back Cross of the cham
91 and then at this point I was parting
a lot during these days so one day I I
took off for like two days and I left my
seeds out um out of the jar well I left
the jar the lid open and when I came
back home the jar was completely emptied
all all the uh the packages of seeds had
a little holes in them and there was a
bunch of R uh mouse or rat [ __ ] all over
it they had eaten like a good like six
seven years of breeding work um [ __ ]
yeah yeah it totally sucks
but you know I I shared I shared a [ __ ]
ton of seats a lot of people and you
know tracked everybody down was like you
know can I get those back can I get
those back and slowly you know gathered
as much as I could um and then uh
inspecta got
the chem you know one two 3
4 and he had kicked those down and I
grew those out and and
uh the chem 91 to me reminds me a lot of
OG so when I had a jar um and this is
just me this is my my flavor you know my
my taste bud so it's it's not going to
be the same for everybody for but to me
it reminds me a lot of of OG and so when
I had a jar of you know like chem 91 or
an
sfv I always found myself going towards
the OG the sfv uh I just found the taste
better and then and then I got the chem
4 and all those ones and and the chem
4 and like the chem CIS have a real
similar flavor the chem D has a similar
flavor to the chem 4 and the and the
chem CIS but it's more has more of a
fuel to it and then the chem 91 just to
me doesn't smell like any of the other
ones I mean to me it smells and tastes
like
OG so that's when I stopped uh working
with the chem 91 and actually I started
with my sfv project at that point and
ended up going with the chem 4 I didn't
have the CIS or the D at that time um
and so I started working the chem 4 and
I I don't know what it is about it it's
just one of those ones that it when you
when you get it right it it uh I mean
I've seen a lot of shitty examples uh of
it and a lot of people like uh I don't
know the buds just get real fluffy or
they burn it you know it's um but when
you get it right man for for me it's
just I love that taste I don't know
yeah okay so the first thing we have to
loop back to you said uh inspector
kicked you some cuts of the chem one
through to four and you grew him
out uh yeah I I
remember I remember the
three maybe I didn't get the one and the
two or maybe I did I it's been so long
um but I all I remember I think the I
you know I can't remember the the ones
but the the four was the one I like the
best out of all of
them I remember one being more OG style
it grew more of a Vine um do you
remember it being sativa cuz that's the
commonly said thing that like one of
them was quite sativa I think it was
either one or two I don't remember I I
can't remember at all it's been so long
ago okay so you you mentioned that um at
that point you started working on the
sfv line as well as you know having that
in with skunk VA that's really
interesting cuz I wanted to ask cuz um
he's he's not the type of guy who like
you know often says people's names
unless like you know he knows you're
cool but he had he had kind of told me
that same story you had told me but just
without actually saying names so I guess
that would mean that uh you are the kind
friend who donated the uh the sfv BX
line that he's started his backcross
project with yeah yeah yeah I gave him
uh so he gave me the cut um we chilled
for you know hang out with him for about
a year after that and then uh you know
life just got busy he got busy and we
lost contact for several years and then
probably about four years ago we had met
up at the emerald cup um and at that
point you know I had uh I had I had I
think I was pretty much done with my
chem 4 line at that point right so I
gave him every step of the breeding
process of of all the chems that I had
made um you know I had lost a lot of the
chem 91 stuff early stuff from the mice
but uh G gave them what I could and at
that same time um I had just finished
making uh sfv back cross 2os and I also
had did a uh back cross one uh f2s as
well
um and you know I hadn't I hadn't grown
him out but I just gave it to him um to
see what he had thought and then uh yeah
but I think the the sfv backcross twos
that he's working with were uh from the
seeds that I had given
him yeah fantastic and I remember
initially when skunk VA said to me that
he felt the sfv or maybe broadly
speaking the OG was a good partner to
complement the chem 91 in terms of like
starting a back Crossing project
it was something that I hadn't really
heard expressed at the time you know
especially because in the past a lot of
Cam back cross projects like if you look
at uh JJ or even Rez they just use land
race afghanis so I was almost expecting
him to say something like that would be
what he would use so when he said oh no
I've gone with this sfv OG BX it was a
little it threw me off kilter a little
bit but I guess at the same time it's
exactly the same thing you've been
saying this whole interview of like how
OG and kemma really quite similar and
complimentary
right right right yeah you know like I
said uh I think they're totally related
um you know I I I've always felt the OG
came from the uh the
91 you know maybe from a bag seed
or yeah or or something like that but uh
yeah I think they complement each other
very well um you know to the sfv by far
is probably my favorite strain of all
times but uh so you can't can't really
go wrong with that at all and then
everything you know even that when I
cross uh to the sfv the actual clone um
it it's similar to the 91 it packs a
punch it brings the potency way up on on
anything you uh pollinate it
with yeah for sure that's that's
something we definitely hear commonly
spoken about so one thing I do have to
kind of ask and get it out of the way
why is South folk seeds using your chem
for IBL as
well uh not only there's been uh quite a
few seed companies that uh I've given
seeds to before they even had a seed
company and you know um it it breeds
well I I I put my you know I put my
heart and soul into these seeds and and
uh you know I try everything out if if
it does you know if the cross didn't
work I go back you know I start over
until until I'm happy with the
results uh I'm very selective with my
with my breeding I know a lot of people
disagree with it but I'm I'm one male
one female um you know I reverse I
reverse all my males so I can see what
kind of turps they got um when I was
able to go to the labs I could get them
tested and and like so you know if I
select like out of a run you know let's
I I'll select like four or five males
that I find that you know has got what I
like and and then I'll cross each male
to its own female of the you know the
same exact clone so let's just say the
chem 4 line uh so i' pick you know you
know four or five of the chem4 males
that I liked and then I would cross each
male to its own chem4 clone and then I
would grow all those out and that now I
can pinpoint like you know what male did
what and and you know like uh my my the
sfv I've been working on um that OG's is
probably one of the hardest strains I've
worked on trying to get that that flavor
out of it and and there's been times
where you know I found a full-blown OG
mail smells um just like OG but when I
back cross it it comes out this like
water like watered down OG almost like a
wet cardboard taste and smell to it um
so you know not always does it work out
but uh for the most part I'm able to cut
out all the guess work when reversing
the males
yeah and uh so I mean the line's very
stable you know every seed comes out uh
chem dog with that chem 4 um and then
you know for breeding purposes it's uh
you know depending on what your goal is
uh it's it's a it's a good start you
know the the seeds are totally stable so
you're not going to get you know a bunch
of different variation throughout the
seeds and and uh
you know I I never I never wanted to the
seed making has always just been for
myself it's it's my hobby it's it's what
I enjoyed doing I I never intended to
come out with a seed company and then
seeing all these people
uh using my seeds to start up a seed
company um kind of you know a little
fire in my ass and and push me to uh uh
you know come out with my own seeds you
know I'm spending th tens of thousands
of dollarss on
electricity um you know making these
lines and whatnot and then I'm seeing
all these other guys profiting off of
off my work and some of them give me
credit some of them don't um you know
the this whole breeding world it's kind
of a shady industry to be honest with
you I'm not a a big fan and and I don't
know how much longer I got it in me uh
some of the things these people are
doing is just just so unethical and just
downright
Shady um so I don't know South Fork uh
you know they must like the stuff and
they went with
it yeah and so is that the Diplomatic
answer or like you don't mind if
someone's using kind of like the same
mail that you're using at the same time
uh you know they're not using the same
exact male I I gave them a handful of
seeds but uh you know the seed Line's
totally consistent so it's like any
knucklehead can pop out 10 of these
seeds and and you're going to find chem
dog they're all going to be chem dog
males so it's not like uh yeah no I get
you definitely so you know so at what
point did you decide to start 707 seed
bank um I think it was
uh ins inspector and little Hill
Farms were just kept on pushing me they
were just like you know uh all all these
guys that you they were like stop giving
out your seeds because everybody had
been giving the seeds out uh to had
started up a seed company you know
there's South Fork
um uh you know who else uh skunk VA with
that with the uh with the
SF um I know I know uh uh Swamp Boy
seeds use uh some white diesel seeds I
had given them in some of their in one
of their
crosses um who else is there there's a
couple uh guy in
Oregon uh what has he
got chronic culture or something like
that um I know he used the uh the cat or
the um the chem dogs in his
line uh there's another guy I don't want
to mention their name but um I had
traded seeds to him he's you know he
gave me the whole oh I got the roadkill
skunk it came from you know menes you
know Joe this that or the other traded
him seeds and uh you know I grew out all
of his seeds they must have been um from
some brick weed that he had picked out
it was just crazy long sativas and
whatnot and that guy ended up coming out
with this uh a seed company and using my
chems using the chem 4 but he had
switched the name to like chem deer
something like that but um if you look
at the guy the guy's pictures were
obviously km for and not only that like
I'd given them the breakdown of how I
made the seed line and instead of uh uh
you know using the Bubba back cross 3
chem
91 as my first uh as the first donor he
had switched up the name from Bubba back
cross 3 to uh heirloom Afghan cross to
chem 91 cross to uh Kem and then he's
changed the chem 4 to chem but um so
that was just kind of I mean it's it's
very flattering I'm I'm I'm really
honored that these people uh like to you
know think think the seeds are good
enough to use and uh breeding projects
but at that point I was just like you
know um maybe I got something here you
know my so that that's when I decided to
come out and do my own thing you know
I'm I'm My Own I'm my worst critic
uh so everything uh I mean I got I got a
a refrigerator full of seeds that uh you
know won't ever release or uh you know I
just give them out um but it just they
just didn't reach my standard or or you
know and there's a lot of strains where
you know like like the cat piss uh uh I
I tried Crossing males to the actual
clone but the uh the traits that I was
looking for like the ciss flavor and the
smell would have never transfer through
it was more the structure so then that's
when I was like okay I got to make this
cat piss into a male form and then try
to hit these other clones to you know
boost the potency up on it um you got to
remember the weed back in like you know
late 80s early 90s uh doesn't compare to
the weed that we have now just like you
know the really oldtimers where they're
always like uh oh the aapco gold or the
Panama Red or you know this side or the
other oh it was the best weed ever back
in the day you know I mean if you grow
it out now it's like you know you smoke
a couple joints and you try to give it
away to people and then they don't want
it and it ends up getting thrown
away you know it just doesn't compare to
the weed nowadays and
so yeah for sure so one of the strains
that I think is possibly most well known
from your Work Cush cleaner give us a
little bit of a background on it uh the
Kush cleaner actually um
the the original cross was made by
somebody else it was is by this really
great guy his name is Lauren really
sweet guy um uh and he was breeding for
motor Rebel for a while and uh he when
he gave me the seeds um he called it
long bottom
leaf and uh it was just an awesome
awesome producer outside uh finished
fairly early middle of October huge huge
light green buds almost had an indoor
but it it's really high in like merine
um kind of that train wrecky flavor and
like I was saying I had grown that train
wreck for so many years straight and
smoked it for so many years uh you know
nothing but it that that flavor um and
that smell that tarpine profile just
kind of makes me
cringe but everybody else loved the uh
long bottom Leaf but they hated the name
and every year you know I'd go back to
Lauren I'd be like hey you know I need I
need a few more hundred seeds you know
so he he was just like take the mail
make your own um so he gave me the cut
of uh he's a Jax cleaner
male um so he gave me the cut of the
mail uh ended up making my own
seeds and um hit you know hit the sfv
with it uh I also hit this Blockhead
that I had grown out for years and years
actually the blockhead is what I had
grown before I started growing the Kush
cleaner as as a a major outdoor
crop um potent potent potent this the
the male was just a stud anything he
touched just became huge uh but it also
gave off that that Jack mercing um
flavor and smell to everything attached
so uh yeah anyhow Lauren gave me the
mail I ended up making my own seeds uh
the name long bottom Leaf wasn't really
flying so a bunch of my trimmers you
know they were like call a Kush cleaner
and then that's when the name stuck to
it uh but but not it's not my uh you
know I I just recreated uh the seeds but
um not my you know it wasn't my work at
all it was it definitely all came from
Lauren and then maybe a good 10 years
ago uh Lauren had lost the mail and then
um my I had also lost the mail so he uh
he then got some more Jack cleaner seeds
and recreated it um but calls it now
just uh calls it long bottom rather than
the long bottom Leaf so you know it's
not uh The Identical or anything like
that as as the original one but um still
I'm sure it's it's pretty
good yeah wow that's that's a really
cool story as a bit of a side note I um
I think I tried that newer one cuz I
think could be wrong here but I think he
had to use the ja cleaner 2 instead of
the original one just due to what TJ is
releasing yeah yeah yeah that's exactly
what had happened yeah man that's such a
small world because I actually he ended
up making a little freebie project where
it was that new one he made that male uh
cross to Gorilla Glue it's just like a
freebie because you know like little
hype thing I got some yeah I got some of
those seeds grew them out found an all
right leaning female and then crossed it
to this choba but oh my God it tapped
into that long bottom and it's just
amazing so it was so funny just hearing
you talk all about that oh right on
right on yeah and then I don't know if
Lauren still breeds with uh is still
breeding for motor Rebel but I I know he
he had also used uh uh the chem4 the my
seed line of chem4 in some of his lines
and he had also used uh a pineapple
tie in some of his in some of his work
there but I'm not too sure if he had
released him with motor Rebel or
not yeah okay well I mean either way
interesting we'll have to dive into it
later I want to ask you about the
pineapple tie because this is on the
website and it's so interesting to me
because you don't often hear about
pineapple tie you know like I mean
chocolate cherry Thai stick these are
all the commonly spoke about ones was
pineapple a rare one or is there a bit
more of a story behind it than it's just
simply a pineapple TI land
race uh I I'm the I got the Clone um
it's it's a cut that's been going around
Menino for quite a few years
now um so it came to me as a clone only
string and uh but work working through I
mean it it smells and tastes just like
pineapples it's I mean a strong order
odor of pineapple but when I was uh
working it into seed
line there's definitely uh some Haze
inside there um that that you know that
just that
spicy uh I don't know how to describe
the Haze but just that classic Haze
smell like uh have you ever tried the
nl5 haze back in the day or the cough or
yeah see the dog [ __ ] um I don't know
some people disagree with me and I could
totally be wrong but I I've always
thought like the Colorado cough and the
Pacific Northwest dog [ __ ] it were all
just Northern Light five haze just you
know
renamed um but there was definitely some
of that inside there uh big plant um
indoors it's real light green uh but
just like I said a strong strong ripe
pineapple um with with a slight hazy you
know aftertaste to it um makes my mouth
water every time just even talking about
it right now I'm starting to salivate a
little
bit that's how you know it's a good
herb so just some of the other strains
which kind of caught my eye off you you
know that were on the front page of the
site the UK cheese this is one which
doesn't get a mention anymore for the
most part and most people are aware you
know it kind of comes from the skunk
number one stock and I think some people
may be regarded as a bit weaker imp
potency like kind of like a bit of a
strain of yester year as DJ Short would
say do you think do you think people are
missing the boat with this
one uh you know again it's it it isn't
as potent as the weed is today um but
man that you know that flavor to it is
just unreal I mean some some people are
really turned off on it and some people
really like it I myself um really like
it and uh so that that one um actually
came out really turned out really good
with that chem dog because the chem dog
uh gave it a little bit uh an extra kick
to it added some potency and lightened
up the color color a little bit on it
but for the most part it it's uh it ret
it retained all that cheese flavor and
even the structure of the plant is is uh
mostly cheese but with the chem dog just
it did add some um potency which was
definitely needed in it but like I don't
know that that the taste of that cheese
I mean I love it I love it I can't get
enough of it so this might sound like a
bit of a silly question but
the the exact source of the skunk that
the UK cheese comes from a little bit
ambiguity because obviously you know
skunk's been offered by a lot of
different seed banks at a lot of
different times do you think it was from
the uh you know widely regarded as less
ideal sweeter skunk stock or probably
from the earlier
stuff I think it was from the earlier
stuff um the the the the later stuff of
skunk number one to me always had a uh
perfumey smell to it a sweeter
perfume um where where this one is just
uh I mean I've never tasted herb like
this from anything else it's so
um I don't know I don't know it's just
it's it's special it's special that the
tur profile off of it is just
unreal yeah for sure I remember I had a
a cheese S one before that was insane so
I can only imagine the original was just
the icing on the cake with that so
something I did want to run by I noticed
not only on the website but also on my
Instagram a fair few times I've seen
lava cake pop up and what I wanted to
ask was obviously give us a bit of a
rundown on lava cake but more
importantly what do you think it is
about the cookies and chem combo that's
so alluring to people do you think it's
purely a hype thing cuz I think it's
beyond that cuz I you know I think
there's too many cookie and chem hybrids
that work for people to just be doing it
for like a market reason you know do you
think it works well and what about them
do you think Blends well together it it
works well the um the chem male that I
use uh is a blank male um meaning the uh
the females completely take over the
cross uh rarely do I get in any of like
the uh the chem crosses um will you get
that chem uh flavor or structure or
anything with with the mail that I have
I've been
using um so with the lava cake uh I used
the thin mint with that cross and when
when I grew all those out like I got
every single feno of uh cookies
imaginable I got that short little
Indico which is like the
ogkb um I got like you know the the
lanky one like the Forum and then I got
the you know a nice big yielding um like
the like the thin mint and then a few
others I think out of uh I did a big run
of them inside of a greenhouse and out
of all of them there was only one that
ended up being a light green like
something I hadn't seen before but um
there's definitely some interesting
stuff in that lava cake and and uh you
know the the name uh I I just uh had
somebody on Instagram pick out the name
for me um did like a you know a little
contest but I know there's quite a few
different breeders now that actually use
that uh the lava cake name um I don't
know if if I don't know if they use it
first or I did it's it's there's so many
breeders out there it's hard to keep
track of now of all the different names
oh it's it's almost easier just to go
with h instead of naming a strain just
just write down the lineage of what it
is and let it be that yeah yeah know I
know what you
mean the last thing I wanted to kind of
probe into in regards to the lava with
was you say it uses the thin mint cut
this is of curiosity to me because you
know of all the people we've asked on
the show we still can't really get a
solid ruling on what the thinman is if
it was the original how does it differ
to The Forum really and you know overall
what do you think cookies
is uh definitely OG definitely has some
kind of OG I think um I think
any you know my I think any new strain
out
now um to to meet the
uh you know modern day criteria of you
know their potency and all this stuff I
think it all need all has to have a
little OG mixed into it to to get that
that potency up to to
today's you know um up to par to today's
weed so uh defin definitely
some o cookie or OG inside there the
whole uh Durban thing thing um yeah I
don't buy that one bit uh I don't see
any bit of Durban inside there at all
I've grown out every single Seed Company
there was that had Durban and they all
have a very strong uh what is it
trolene um fluffy buds you know Out
outdoors they would always finish
extremely early but uh yeah I I don't
know and I I've talked to these the
cookie guys before
and each one kind of gives me a
different story so I don't even think
they know oh man that was the other
question can we trust anything that
comes at a camp cookie
fam yeah yeah yeah you know um I I I
trust CSI humble I trust not so dog
that's about it uh you know I don't know
and you know I I don't know I don't keep
track to all these people out now or or
anything like that
so I've been uh I've been fed a lot of
[ __ ] I've been fed a lot of fake
cuts uh and a lot of fake ass seeds so
it's kind of just left me to this point
where uh I do my thing um I I enjoy
talking to inspecta about breeding and
this that and the other uh you know we
have we have different taste buds in
herb uh but you know it works out well
um I I can run stuff off of him and uh
you you know he he does he does the
homework and finds out you know about
this that and the other so it's it's
always nice to pick his brain and and
see what's what but you know grow
growing out all the durans the yeah I
don't I don't see that one bit inside
the
cookies um yeah you know I I've grown
strains in the past uh uh some Dutch
stuff that had cookies profile you know
little buds lanky l
uh
plants
um but as as for the
uh the genetic makeup of of the cookies
I couldn't tell
you yeah I I'd have to agree with like
everything you said there especially the
durb and having been able to smoke a bit
of it myself and see the growth
structure of it and whatnot I think it's
totally overrated like the the
percentage of what people say it could
be in there and another little funny
little side note like when you said uh
you enjoy talking to Prof inspector you
know he does his homework I was like
that's that I remember I made that exact
comment to him at um Emerald cup and he
just looks at me and goes do you ever
wonder why they call me inspector he
just walks
off laugh so
hard yeah he does his homework so I
guess to summarize it all up you know
we've speculated on the genetics of
cookies and we were talking about
cookies and cam what is your speculation
on the genetics of
chem the the
chem yeah what do what do you
reckon uh definitely you know after
growing out those Hermes seeds that I
had gotten from skunk VA uh you know I
think some kind of it's definitely HJ
pod of
stuff um definitely see that like a
Pakistani style something in there some
kind of
indicia uh but
you know who knows who
knows okay so another strain from kind
of the old school which no one can
really give me too much info on but I
got a hunch you're going to be the one
to do it old Betsy can you give us any
story on
her uh old Betsy came from uh a buddy of
mine from overgrow he went by
budel uh he had broughten the Betsy up
to Humble back in the early
2000s um from what information I
gathered it's the same guy that did the
Hogs breath and the bull
rider who also did the uh the old Betsy
and you know I've asked around um and
just like you know breeding with it
seeing the different stuff that pops up
I kind of believe the White Widow maybe
Super Skunk Cross or something like that
uh but again you know this is all
speculation but I think um for sure the
White Widow I've grown out quite a few
white widows in the past and kind of see
that in
it um but again uh I think whoever was
growing a long time ago is long gone and
and uh it's going to be another one of
those mystery plants that you know maybe
when phos gets enough uh stuff gathered
up they'll be able to tell us in the
future
yeah okay and what's it like as a as a
smoke you know what's the flavor what's
the
high um so a lot of the uh a lot of my
breeding um the past 10 years has been
for commercial
outdoor uh so the Betsy um very pungent
this like rotten mango or maybe like a
baby eight a ton of mangoes and then
[ __ ] them out you know it it's funky and
and the smell it's it's got a really
really strong uh uh tur profile to it uh
the thing I really liked about it was um
how quick how fast it finished outside
it's usually about October 5th for us
over here uh October 5th to like uh you
know if you wanted to I guess maybe
October 15th latest latest no uh October
oer 5th about October 8th is usually
when I cut it um big big big yielder
very Hardy and and just the uh the the
the tur profile on it um that stuff can
sit for a solid year and when you open
it up it's just going to stink like it
did from day one uh I've had people you
know take that over
OG um they they loved it they love it um
it's a good it's a good daytime smoke uh
pretty pretty pretty heavy
duty um what
else but again more more for the
outdoor uh is is what I started working
it's got you know for for
outdoor there's certain types of herb
that um when done right outside has an
indoor look to it uh Betsy being one of
those um a lot of breeder Steve stuff
from back in the day uh had some really
nice uh would would have a really nice
like indoor look to it there there's one
uh a blockhead that I've been working
for several several years now from him
um that that I mean for the longest
times like when the dispensaries first
started opening up out here I was taking
it in and passing it off as indor and
they were loving it and they were taking
it giving me top dollar all the time for
it uh so so the Betsy is another one
like that it's just it's just got that
that look um to it um it's got the it's
got the nose to it and it's got the
structure to it um so it was one you
know I I couldn't let it pass up so I
worked that into uh back uh inbred line
I guess um just kept on back Crossing it
and uh it's it's a winner for sure it's
a winner the the name of it um turns a
lot of people off so most most times uh
I've seen it being passed off as Oregon
blueberry or Mango
Kush
[Music]
um there a couple other names but again
it was just it was a cash Cropper back
then for the indoor and it's a cash
Cropper now for the outdoor and I mean
and it does great insight as well but
that's cool so when you kind of take a
look over 707 offerings as a seed bank
seems to me on face value it's pretty
evenly split down the middle in terms of
kind of like sativa and indicas I mean I
guess you could argue a little more into
cening with you know some of the cham
hybrids but overall you know was that
kind of intentional did you look to
cater to both sides of the market or is
it really just about
you it's uh yeah I hate to say it but
all it's just what I like and I I tend
to go more towards the indicas but you
know I do like a little bit of sativa
here and there not not anything super
heavy sativa like um what was it like
the genius from Brother Grims actual
genius clone I mean that thing just
makes my head spin I start hearing
things in the walls and that's like all
I want to
smoke the P sativas huh oh genius I
remember when I got to smoke genius I
just exhaled and just within about 5
seconds I just looked at soul and was
just like this is my new favorite plant
yeah yeah I remember the the first time
I I grew the genius and flattered it out
I I uh I had harvested it had it in my
garage and then uh left came back a
couple hours later and I I had thought
somebody had thrown up in my house and
like didn't paint it up that smell was
just like wow it was something else I
love that smell and the taste of it but
uh it just makes my head spin yeah it's
just too much and my head already go um
you know I already go a thousand miles
per per minute here and uh I I don't
need anything else to increase that you
know I need something to calm me down
yeah okay so I guess it would be safe to
say overall you're definitely more into
your indicas than sativas more more
indicia hybrids yeah I definitely like
the blend you know pure pure indicas of
course you know they lay me out um I got
an army of kids so it's it's pretty hard
to function if I if I smoke too much of
those things so uh I like uh a nice
blend nice hybrids of uh I guess but
more I guess I guess more
into yeah for sure so a little while
back you mentioned that you were
reversing the males and in fact you did
it for all of your males that you were
going to like kind of greenl light we've
had people talk about this process but
no one's ever really you know said that
they've actually really done it would
you be able to give us a bit of a run
through of what it's like and more
importantly what's the bud like when you
smoke it and does it give like a real
true representation of the male or is it
more just kind of hinting things to you
uh it it uh I I've never smoked it
before it it's the the stuff I use is
called florel and um it's a bare product
so it it's it's definitely really
toxic uh so yeah like I mean when I
spray the plants um you know I'll spray
him outside and then I I won even touch
the plant um for a good while so it's
one of those things I really like
telling people use it because uh you
know most people are stoners and they're
just going to spray it without any kind
of covering or or respirator or anything
like that and it you know I don't know
what it could do to you but I know it's
toxic I know uh it's ban in Europe so I
mean that that says a lot right there
you know uh but what what you get off of
it is uh the tur profiles you can
definitely you know since I'm always
after you know a certain tur profile
this I could weed out all the [ __ ] that
I don't want anymore you know uh and
then when I was able to take them to the
labs uh you know you could get it tested
for potency and whatnot it gives you you
know a slight little idea but when you
reverse it it just it just produces I
mean I guess I've had some strains that
actually produce a nugget but most times
it's just like a little seed
CX and uh you know just and it just goes
up to stem kind of like that uh what's
that string Green Spoon Grim spoon or
something like that yeah Dr grein spoon
yeah it turns out similar to that uh in
structure but you you can get the tur
profile which is what I'm after all the
time and uh you know it cuts out all the
guests work and breeding um there was
just recently a uh post by Mr Bob
Hill where he has I think it was just
yesterday actually um where he had
posted a thing where he had gotten some
ohaw Hawkin seeds or something like that
and he only ended up with one male uh so
in that you know in that case he could
he could reverse that male pollinate
itself and now you're able to get both
male when you when you reverse a male
and make male US ones most people would
think you're getting all male seeds but
the uh the male carries both chromosomes
the X and Y so you get both male and
female
seeds so you know in that case you know
since he wasn't able to get any females
or anything like that now you're able to
he can reverse the
male pollinate itself and you know go
through the seeds and now you have both
male and female seeds and uh I've done
that with like the cat piss before where
I made uh you know male s1's I guess
you'd call it
and uh grew those seeds out and I read a
thing on uh where Sam the skunkman said
you know do you get a certain percentage
of male certain percentage of female
this that and the other but
uh I ended up pretty much no I ended up
with a pretty much a 5050 split you know
the same amount of females as males when
I did it um yeah I remember that article
he said it was uh 25% male 25% female
50% home
yeah yeah and then again I think that's
uh strain dependent are are you working
with the hermy or or not the uh the cat
piss that I have it's it's stable it's
strong uh I've never seen any kind of
intersects with it or anything and even
with the seeds there there was no Herms
whatsoever uh when I had did the male S1
project and and uh again it was it was a
good split you know
5050 I mean everything sounds great in
theory but
man you don't really know what you're
going to get until you grow them out you
know not not all males cross the same
you know that's why you know when I pick
out all my males I do one male to one
female you know and now I can grow all
those out and and pinpoint exactly what
Mal is doing what uh like and like I was
saying with like the OG thing you know I
found a few males that smelled like OG
you know completely like OG but when I
would cross it back to the sfv it would
get this watered down carb a lot of them
turn out like the Fire OG really really
Frosty but just not much flavor and
taste to it at
all yeah okay so I guess the thing which
comes to mind then is
um uh with in regards to these seeds do
you think there is anything valuable to
be gained in them like these M seeds or
do you think it's more of just a novelty
thing
uh if
you're wanting to go deep inside you
know inside of what it is to see what uh
you know what what kind of Heritage it
might have had or or something like that
sure I think it could be valuable or you
know and and in like Mr Bob Hamp Hill's
situation where he only has one male and
that's it and no other
seeds uh yeah absolutely you know
reverse that sucker and and uh you know
you're going to get both male and female
seeds out of out of it and and now
you're able you know go deeper inside of
it see what's going on in there um yeah
the sorry go on the reversing of the
males it it it it cuts out all the guess
work for for the most part you
know there's no more questioning you
know what is this going to do I mean you
never know what it's going to do but you
can always pick out the uh the uh the
tpping profile or here here's a great
example um a few years back uh I want to
do a CBD line so I had bought a bunch of
uh seeds online CBD I remember there's
some like reer man stuff and and some
other people's stuff so I grew them all
out um reversed all the Maes took all
the males to the lab to see you know
what kind of percentage what things had
none of the seeds that I had bought had
any CBD they all came back THC
huh right so I mean like situations like
that you know it saved me uh quite a few
quite a bit of time yeah wow that's
that's questionable so uh I noticed when
you reverse a female the female plan
itself tends to not really want to
accept the pollen and and form any s1's
on itself but I'm pretty confident I
noticed when I was looking a little
closer at some of your photos of the
males that it looked like it it was
making seeds on itself is that the case
and and why do you think there is this
difference um well when reversing the
females I guess a lot of times when
you're when you're spraying it with the
silver nitrate or whatever uh you know
you're burning up the uh the
pistols so
[Music]
um you know I I I don't know I don't
know I I thinking about it but uh I
don't know uh with with the males it's
every time I reverse them it seeds
itself uh and and that's one of like the
downfalls of when I would take it to the
lab because the the seeds and and the
stem and all that bring the testing way
down so people are always asking me like
you know what what kind of numbers are
you getting from your males and I'm like
you know it's only like 12 to
14% but you know most of that sample is
is seed and stem you know know there's
there's very little cxes or to to test
off of yeah okay and so with the male
traits that you're assessing when you
reverse it let's just say you know you
you're smelling the turpine profile have
you found that what it Expresses in the
female reverse trait is what it will
pass on in its
pollen most times yeah yeah the ma the
majority of the time yeah cool well
that's pretty
reassuring yeah yeah absolutely I mean
not in every case
but but most times yeah it it does pass
off uh you know the traits the pass off
to the female most
males in in my case I guess have uh
usually take over the cross um you know
when when you find a blank male uh it's
it's really something special and hold
on that sucker tight when you know the
females completely take over the cross
uh th those are the real special ones
that um and I I don't I out of thousands
and thousands of males I've only found
like one or two in my life that do
that yeah of course and it kind of plays
into the idea of I've been thinking
about this for a while that people buy
strains predominantly for the
female yeah absolutely absolutely um you
know when I was buying uh seeds you know
the description sold me uh and you know
n out of the 10 times uh you might find
one seed out of the pack that would
actually be what the description
is so that that's that's why I like the
back Crossing and
stabilizing uh you know if if you're
reading my description that's what
you're going to get you're not going to
get one out of 10 you know every single
seed of the heavily worked lines that I
have is coming out exactly what I say
it's going to be you know like the
betsies they're all turning out how uh
it's Des cribed you know cat piss every
single one comes out these short little
Indica uh cat piss you know um no
variation and so like uh for doing
commercial outdoor it was uh you know I
wanted to be able to grow out um let's
say like you know 10 10
seeds and every single one turn out
exactly the same to where uh you know
you can mix the different plants
together and no one's going to know
difference you know uh if if like if I'm
buying a pack of seeds from somebody
else uh and you know I'm growing them
out I got three or four different kind
of
fenos uh the end user isn't going to be
happy if I call it all one thing when
there's three different you know flavors
out of it so that that was uh the big
driving force behind the uh making
outdoor seeds is just having that
consistency um you know obviously the
seeds going to get twice sealed as a
clone is and uh you know a lot more
resistant to pests and mold and whatnot
so yeah
100% so I mean just kind of slotting
this one in there would you ever
consider offering any feminize
work uh I I love feminize seeds I love
feminize seeds um I make them for myself
uh I I do it more for preservation of of
clones that I want to let go
you know a feminize make
s1's and put them in the
vault the thing I found with you know a
lot of the you know when you're making
an S1 of one strain
[Music]
um it doesn't generally turn out as well
as if you uh make a hybrid with s you
know U make feminized hybrids those
usually turn out much better than actual
the uh when when make the
S1
but uh you know I got them in the vault
so in 20 years from now if I want to
grow you know this that or the other I
can always just bust them out and Sprout
them and uh I'm sure you know out of out
of 10 or 20 seeds you're going to find
exactly what you're looking
for but uh as of offering them to the
public I don't even know I don't even
know what the future of 707 Seedbank has
uh the uh I said this it breeding has
always been my passion it's been my
hobby and uh now kind of bringing it
into a into the market Zone you know I'm
always scared it's going to uh cloud my
judgment a little bit like you know uh
everyone wants this purple punch or or
wedding cake or this that or the other
you know I've smoked purple punch a few
times and uh there was no punch to it
you know what I'm saying it was just
purple it tasted good but there was
definitely no punch so but that's that's
what it seems like the market wants they
all want these uh whatever jungle boys
is growing is what what they
want the reason why
I is because I noticed that lemon do you
breed with lemon and soig if you're will
to
[Music]
sure sure yeah that that uh the the
lemon tree
S1 um I have a buddy who was uh the
lemon tree guys' distributor when they
first came out and you know as as he was
moving the packs he would always find a
couple seeds inside each pack and saved
them and he wasn't he wasn't growing at
the time he he does now but uh he gave
me um all all the lemon tree Hermes
seeds he had
found and uh I grew them all out uh you
know like like I said with the s1's you
know a good half of them turn out to be
like Duds or just really weak grown or
whatnot uh that lemon
tree it's you know it's got that citrusy
kind of Calo uh
uh you know tur
profile um and and you know most those
tangies and stuff like that for me uh
doesn't get me all that high tastes
great you know a couple joints are good
but after that it's just like uh it
doesn't do nothing so the the lemon tree
you
know seems to be a little bit more
potent than uh the majority of the
citrusy string trins that that I've
worked but it's that flavor on it is
just so mouthwatering so flavorful and
and uh it it does pack a good good punch
uh but you know like like uh most s1's
it's it's it's kind of a [ __ ] to grow
has a real weak weak uh root system to
it um same thing with the I use a
snowman um S1 which is from the cookie
guys is uh one of the ones that they've
kind of held down more on a uh uh they
they've held that one down pretty good
they didn't let it go at all but
uh again with like the snowman also weak
Roots very finicky to grow but a lot of
these uh s1s you know like like the SF I
I wouldn't be surprised that if that
wasn't a hermy seed even though I've
never seen OG hermy on me any of them
indoors but uh I imagine you know that's
where most of all these Cuts came out
from but uh you know weak weak root
system but awesome flavorful flavorful
herb you know I can't I can't let that
stuff pass up when it when it's that
good is this the same lemonry S1 which I
think swamp boys have used in a hybrid
or
two uh not the same cut no uh
most the the lemon tree guy stopped by
my booth at the emerald cup uh last year
and and I've heard this from other
people
before uh and they said that they've
never given out the actual clone and
everybody that does have a lemon tree uh
cut is comes from you know a seed that
they found uh inside inside their bag so
uh the Swamp Boy guys also uh uh they
found their own seed
um and and uh grew theirs out I haven't
seen uh I haven't seen or smoked their
lemon tree at all but uh different so
everybody's got a different one I I've
I've shared my cutout with a few people
I know I gave it to Archive uh and a
couple other folks but not not too many
so it's definitely not out there at all
ah is that the one he used in the
creation of the lemon peel
line who used lemon peel or what's lemon
peel I think it's uh lemon tree cross
something from
archive oh okay yeah yeah if if archive
have it it was the cut of lemon tree
that I gave them cool cool cool yeah
know I've tried um I think it was called
lemon drop or something one of the
hybrids he made so he made a hybrid with
lemon tree and then crossed that to
other things and so I got to try the end
product one of them and it was really
good it was really good did that citrusy
fun come Mountain to the Cross or um
well I don't know cuz I also tried lemon
tree at U Mr Bob hemp's place and that
sounds much more like what you're
talking about whereas the one I trade
from archive was just a really nice
lemon hybrid and I could definitely see
that lemon tree was in there I could
believe it I should say but um kind of
what you're talking about is definitely
like what I tried at Bob Hill's house oh
right on so what did you think of the
lemon tree I really liked it but I found
there was something a little bit
obnoxious about it it was like obnoxious
lemon like it was um and it's not like
the way he grewed or anything I think
it's just a my personal preference thing
but I definitely see what you mean when
you say like there's a Calo vibe to it
cuz it's almost like not a bang on Lemon
it's like a very tart
lemon right right right yeah I I I
personally don't get any lemon out of it
yeah it's it's not like the way some
OG's a bang on Lemon it's not like that
lemon in my opinion at
all right right yeah I feel I feel the
same way to me it's more uh uh like a
orangey but um Everyone likes a lemon
now I guess the name's uh pretty popular
yeah it's an interesting cut nonetheless
so it Spurs the question to mind for me
though I've seen people breeding with
S2s is that something you interested in
like not necessarily breeding with an S2
but like digging to that generation and
doing that type of thing or not
necessarily oh oh absolutely um I don't
I don't think there's
you know there's no right or wrong way
in in
breeding uh if you if you have a goal in
mind uh you know just go for it try it
out if it doesn't work try a different
way you know not not all strains are
going to breed the same not you know
what might work with one strain might
not work with another so uh any kind of
tool that I could use I use it uh s1's
S2s reversing males uh you know the the
one one one one thing uh I've noticed
with reversing males and it's it's
something that I I still do to this day
is uh the stem rub you know before I
reverse a mail I'll go through all my
males and I'll rub the stem and you know
I I'll I'll pick out what I think is
going to be the killer stud of the group
and you know I'll label
those not once has one of those males
been the the the keeper stud It's
usually the one off in the far corner so
with that stem rub
thing uh I've noticed
maybe 5% of plants that stem rub
actually comes through to the flower but
for the most part that stem robe doesn't
mean [ __ ] uh whatever smell you're
getting off that stem robe it's going to
come out completely different to the
flower
uh so that that's you know another cool
thing with the reversing of the males
just finding these little little things
but whatever any kind of
tool um whatever I could do to reach my
end goal is you know I'll use it the uh
I don't have uh any problems with with
s1's S2s and actually I think uh to make
a strain Tighter and to breed like to
breed a pure you know a real
F1 I think you do need to go to S2 S3 S4
um you know and then cross that to
something else that has also been taken
that far and and you know to get that
true that true hybrid figure and that
was another reason why I did the uh I
like the back Crossing um to you know
back cross the hell out of it to where
every seed comes out the exactly the
same and then I'll cross those back to
you know a different strain that I did
the same thing with in hopes to get a
true you know full-on Vigor you know
hybrid yeah wow I mean the first thing I
kind of think of is what are some other
little tips and tricks you may have for
uh selecting a
male the reversing of the mail I I I
pick out everything from there uh you I
like when I sprouting my seeds and stuff
like that I I'll automatically uh call
off anything that's weak or are uh
doesn't doesn't fit my bill uh growing
wise so I just keep all the best ones
and then from there I'll start reversing
and and and then pick it that way yeah
wow interesting I think the thing which
comes to mind most when you mentioned
that the you know the how should we say
the interreliability of the stem rub is
um our most recent guest Mass strains he
said that something he had noticed which
wasn't exactly what you said but it very
much was following that train of thought
was that
he said uh don't put too much stock in a
single stem rub because if you do the
stem rubs consistently over a long
period of time it changes wildly and so
yeah if you just stem rub on any old day
like who knows what that really
means right right like I said only uh
like the cat piss will actually the the
smell will come off on the on the stem
rub and a lot of those uh that Tangi
like the lemon tree and that those
citrus
strains uh the stem rub will actually
translate to the flower you know but the
the every other strain I've ever tried
um not even close nowhere near
close so this is maybe a bit of a weird
kind of farfetch concept but I really
like the idea of it where basically an
old idea DJ Short put forward was that
he always said he found crosses worked a
little better when the more sativa of
the two plants was the mother have you
ever found anything like that or found
any of your own little kind of of weird
rules that seem to work like that um no
uh you know like not not all not all
strains are going to mix a match the
same uh you know some sometimes like
like uh sfv if if you cross uh anything
to the actual xfv clone it's almost
guaranteed the potency goes up uh if you
cross anything to my cat piss clone um
that cat piss smell just does not go
through it just doesn't it just doesn't
translate to the crosses uh and I I just
uh maybe about a year or two ago I made
a bunch of cat piss crosses where I
actually use uh a mail for my cat piss
and and cross it to a bunch of stuff and
it was kind of weird anything that like
had hermy
Tendencies um it it it just brought it
right out like anything uhh the chem 91
her hella bad the the Girl Scout cookies
her really bad uh but strains that
didn't really have any hermy Tendencies
we we're perfectly fine which is totally
weird uh I I I stress all my males out
for a good long time usually just
because I'm not home and able to use
them but uh I I'll be gone for like you
know a good season and then finally come
back and get to them and you know
they're kept in little tiny cups uh you
know half dead and and if some of them
sometimes will start spitting out hairs
and crystals and at that point uh you
know off to the mulch pile they go but
you know if if they if they can survive
me being absent for that long then I
know I got to keep her you
know so there's some strong genetics in
there so what are some of the next
crosses you're looking at working
on uh I'm I'm still working on my
SF uh currently got a um a seed run
going on that uh I've been working that
uh spice of life Blockhead clone for
quite a few years but more more of an
outdoor uh project so when I breed for
outdoors uh vers indoors I I do
completely different things for my for
outdoor breeding uh I I'll leave all my
males outside until the very end uh see
you know what's going to flower first
under the natural light
uh grow structure this that or the other
and you know for for outside uh like
right now I'm working I'm trying to
finish out my Blockhead this year it uh
the blockhead I used the same Jacks
cleaner for the cush cleaner for my
original cross uh I back crossed it
twice to the Clone but the Clone would
do this thing outside to where like the
very tip of the plant would would die
off or just one branch would die off on
it and without fail like it you know it
did it every year just the Clone and
when I started back Crossing it I
started noticing it was actually going
through into the uh into the seed I
don't know I I still don't know what it
is so then I started uh you know making
f2s f3s f4s with it uh breeding that
part of it out so for for you know
outdoor seed uh especially with this
Blockhead you know picked my this year I
took clones off all the males and just
let them all do their thing outside and
then I picked out uh several of the
earliest ones to start
flowering um got those you know set
aside and then uh you know take cuts off
of the females that are the earliest um
that are the ones that are starting to
flower
first so that's where I'm at right now I
got clones of every everybody set aside
the males uh a reverse them come this
winter inside to see you know which
one's got the tur profile I want and uh
from there then next season you know
during during winter hopefully I'll have
enough time to uh you know cross the
males to the females that I like and
then I'll test them out next year and
and see what see what happens or you
know which stud worked the best and
Carry On from there doing it that way
sounds yeah after the blockhead uh you
know I've wanted the roadkill skunk but
I I just think that thing is
goner
um I've spent tens of thousands of
dollars on fake seeds Cuts uh driven All
Over America to fine Cuts people say
they have the cuts you know usually
they're just trying to trade for the
stuff that I got and they give me
something you know completely off and uh
but I I don't uh I'd like to work CBD
I'd like to make some CBD lines but I'm
just uh I got a bunch of these Panama
CBD that Mr Bob Hill gave me I like to
work those but as of right now the uh
the labs are all cut off to me they
won't let me take anything in to get
tested
so until I can find a testing facility
I'm kind of put on hold with the
CBDs uh I was even thinking about you
know doing some hemp lines
um I think that might be a thing in the
future but uh really after the the
sfv if I can ever get that thing right
I've I've been going back to it um for
years and years just uh thinking I got
it right grew out the seeds it's not
what I've been looking for so I start
over and we'll see what happens with
that one but I don't really have uh
much more in the works than what I've
already done
um I think uh yeah well one one thing I
wanted to ask in relation to the seed
thing quickly was when you do your feno
hunting or maybe more specifically when
you're testing lines you create how many
seeds do you like to pop at any one
time as many as I can as uh uh let's
just put it this way I got chased out of
Trinity County by the police
and when they came over to my property
they said that they were they would have
loved to arrest me but they didn't have
the manpower to cut down my
Gardens so as much as I can that's a
good answer and so in general how
important is it do you think that people
do engage in the whole kind of art of
pheno
hunting absolutely uh uh 100% you know
just
what what you want to find the new new
or or something that you know is special
to your heart or to your to your taste
buds uh got to pop seeds or we're just
going to be stuck with this purple punch
forever you
know yeah yeah I understand that so
something I surprisingly haven't asked
yet you mentioned earlier you know you
did the whole rock wool slab thing do
you grow organically now and what style
of growing do you use in general uh I
grow uh I do everything um for
outdoor I'm not I'm not 100% uh organic
I keep my soil completely organic like
no no liquid bottles nothing in the
plastic ever will touch my soil but I do
foler spray with uh you know certain
bottle nutrients so that that's uh but
for you know head stash um I was doing
uh Oran Organics mixing all my
amendments uh but then I found a a super
soil that they make out of out of out in
organ and I think they use the dragonfly
Earth medicine is that the name of those
guys I think they use their stuff inside
the soil uh works great I just dump a
bag you know a bag of it inside of a pot
and plant and I'm good to go just
straight water uh but you know that term
organic uh you know I use drip lines so
I know a lot of people will tell me it's
not organic because I'm using plastic
drip lines or whatnot and and uh but and
then for indoor um I I I learned with
General Hydroponics and
rockol and then uh later in life I did
go to all soil um I I had done Organics
I I tried uh aquaponics before with the
Guppies and
uh ended up just killing all these fish
over and over again so I stopped that
that was pretty hard I've done nft I've
done
aeroponics
uh for and really I'll just use whatever
is free to me uh there was a a company
growth science um they sent me like a
good like six Monon of of fertilizer so
I used that for indoor uh the past year
and then um
yeah it just depends on the situation
where I'm at and what I'm after pretty
much yeah okay I mean it makes sense
right so do you ultimately prefer
organic I mean you kind of alluded when
you said head
stash yeah yeah definitely for smoke
like uh herb grown in rock wool has a
certain look to it and like always has
that same kind of certain look to it and
a certain flavor to it it it definitely
sticks out to me I could I could pick it
out like night and day uh
Organics By far for head stash always
turns out the nicest ta the tastiest for
me um but for outdoor you know like
outdoor production it's just not cost
efficient it it just doesn't work out
it's it's not like uh you you don't get
that extra Buck because it's organic and
not only that most times uh your yield
will go down just a slight bit but for
the most uh I like to do that Tom Hill
mix uh out outside and then you know
I'll also as as a base it's really good
chicken [ __ ] bone meal um oyster can't
really go wrong with it solid it's been
proven um it's proven test of time with
with those old school humble Growers
they've been they've been using that
stutsman
forever yeah yeah 100% And it even flows
through into a lot of the no toil
recipes today
so something I get asked a lot of
questions about but sadly I don't really
have a lot of answers for is when in
regards to being an outdoor grow what
are some of your tips for getting the
plants big do you like to veg them
indoors do you do like some light depth
thing or how do you get him nice and big
in
vegge uh start from a
seed SE seed
always um I I start my
seeds about the middle of March I'll get
them big inside and then from there I'll
put them into a greenhouse and then from
there they go outside so by the time
they're actually reach their hole or
their pot or you know whatever style
it's going in uh they're already like a
good 3 to four
feet you know and then from there then
you just uh just let it do its thing
give it water give it sunshine it's good
to go I mean it's a PL you know it's a
weed that stuff just grows like crazy
and so do you have a dedicated IPM
regime or how do you deal with pests
when they
arise uh I don't don't really uh deal
with much pest I'm I'm everything is
pretty clean
inside uh before they even go
outside
uh so I mean I I don't do much uh spring
for anything like that and if uh I I
have been battling um what is it
scales for for a while now uh I try
ladybugs this that the other but I just
I just can't shake them right now I
don't know what the deal is with those
things for kind of a pain in the
ass yeah yeah for
sure so one thing you may or may not be
experienced with how do you feel about
reving cuts and more specifically do you
feel like it causes any damage to the
cutting uh so when I was
growing train wreck I didn't keep
mothers of it I just went uh I I just
took Cuts as right when uh the plant
would flip I would take cuts off of off
the clones and I did that for about a
three for three years straight with that
train wreck and I I never really noticed
a difference and then with reving plants
uh I rev my seeds all the time um just
to save space if I don't have enough
space to take clones off of
Everybody uh even with the females you
know I I'll just grow them out if I like
one of them uh you know I just cut cut
half of it down and then put the rest of
it in back in the vegro and let it you
know reveg back out but I I'm sure if
you kept doing it over and over and over
again for years and years yeah you you
notice a difference but I I've never
noticed a difference off of uh doing a
myself yeah okay so it's going to seem a
little weird question but I definitely
want to run this one by especially in
light of our purple punch comments you
know a lot of people in general when
they talk about purple strains there's
kind of this undertone of like how you
know purple weed is always weak and it
seems to be you know an idea that comes
up again and again do you kind of agree
with that in general or do you just
think it's the purple strains that are
currently around are just maybe not the
most
potent uh no I I think uh purple weed
and that like Calo type uh that citrusy
kind of herb has always been
weak there's there's a a certain few
that pop out every now and then that
that are really good like the purple
urle I mean that thing's potent it's
strong it knocks me
out uh but then again purple urle is is
one of those purple strains where you
need the cold to make it really purple
out um
but I think generally I you know most
purple her uh is generally on the weaker
side yeah
understandable so a few little legal
questions before we get into the tail
end of things how do you feel that the
industry is going to evolve in light of
the legal changes that came to pass with
uh prop 64 and do you feel that it is
the impending death of the m pop
business yeah yeah I hate to say it but
yeah I I think it's it's the end of
quality herb quality
genetics uh there's going to be a lot of
I I don't I don't I don't see people
smoking weed really in 20 years I I feel
like they're all just going to go to the
pen I I think uh the flowers is just
going to be a thing in the past but you
know that that's just my personal
opinion I think there'll always be that
little uh uh you know connoisseur group
like like the micr
Brew but for the most part uh I I think
the whole cannabis culture and the mom
and pop thing uh California has
definitely killed it and are is trying
very very hard to uh end it and just
pretty much let this uh a massive
corporate takeover pretty much
yeah yeah so do you think that uh with
those changes all of the kind of
cultural events like the cups and um you
know Harvest parties and things like
that will kind of forever be different
or it'll still
survive the the events are done I feel
like I think they they're going to be
completely finished uh you know the the
the uh humble counties DND in away I
mean even property values out there you
know land that was selling for a million
or two million a few years ago isn't
even selling for 300,000
now it's uh you know they killed it
Humble County is doing this thing if if
you're growing without a permit right
now they send you a letter and they'll
give you a couple days to cut down your
garden and if you don't cut it down
within those days you're going to get a
fine for $10,000 a day that every day
your garden up so I mean 10 grand a day
it it made a lot of people shut down and
and a lot of people got those letters
already up up over there so that that's
you
know they're they're going to turn
Humble County into a ghost town I mean
the whole the whole Emerald Triangle is
probably going to become a ghost town in
a while property valleys are just
completely plummeting
uh the the harvest parties uh you know
that's well always be around there's
always going to be that small group of
people you know who's all stoked you
want to share your flowers at the end of
the year you know so you smoke mine I
want to smoke some of yours let's you
know let's talk see what's good you
know so I don't see that ever going away
but uh the whole cannabis culture thing
I think is uh definitely dying out very
fast yeah so I mean in the previous
question you alluded to you know the
coniss Market do you think that'll
almost become synonymous with the black
market yeah I mean you know just like
Colorado uh and all the other states
that had legalized beforehand the laws
are going to are going to you know
they're working it out so they're
constantly going to be changing so who
knows maybe uh they they'll throw us
little guys a bone here and uh not make
it so rough uh maybe they'll they'll cut
down down on the on these crazy
taxes uh maybe some of these landlords
that are trying to charge ridiculous
prices for where houses are going to
realize you know they're just wasting
people's times a lot of a lot of these
uh a lot of these poor investors that
are throwing in millions and millions of
dollars to hear some like you know
20-year-old talking about oh I could do
this make you rich rich rich you know
they're all going to go belly up in a
couple of years um the same thing it
happened in Colorado it happened in
Washington it's going to happen
here yeah so if you could make say one
change to the legislation that in your
mind at least would hopefully ensure
that the canine kind of continues in a
healthy direction what sort of change
would you want to make or do you feel
that no change needs to be made uh they
just need to lower the taxes it's just
too much there there's nothing left
there's nothing left you're you're going
to be working your ass off just trying
to break even
uh you know each each city has its own
tax and then you got the state tax and
it's it's just it's just ridiculous for
for a little grow I mean you know for a
yearly license some of uh some of these
cities you know want anywhere from 40 to
$100,000 every year and then and then
you got you know employees you got to
pay for electricity you got to pay for
rent uh warehouse space that would
normally go for 80 cents to a dollar per
square foot is not anywhere from3 to4 do
per square foot uh there's just there's
just nothing left over you know
yeah so I guess as a more International
based question and just one that
obviously bit relevant to home here in
Australia do you think countries should
give up their right to be able to have a
personal grow if it means that they can
get access to Legal cannabis but it's
being done through say a big Corporation
I mean if that's all you got then yeah
but I mean if there's any other options
like uh you know I mean for the for the
every day or guess just you know it's
not the prop 64 is not all that horrible
you know everybody can grow a few plants
so that I mean that's cool you know
you're not getting thrown in jail
anymore for well I I guess now you would
be able to or they're going to start
throwing people in jail I get anything
over six plants again is a felony out
here which is
ridiculous
but uh you know if that's all you got
then yeah you know there's there's uh
nothing wrong with it it's better than
uh you know as a kid growing up in the
bay I mean I had a I had a friend that
got some guy unloaded the clip in him
for a quarter pound of weed you know it
was uh 1,200 bucks back then in the
early 90s and and they killed them for
it so you know get getting rid of that
element yeah I'm all about the uh
legalization get rid of that whole
criminal um gangster whatever but you
know the way they're they're going
around with uh these crazy taxes the
crazy
regulations um you know they you should
be able to use whatever they're using on
our food on on cannabis which you can't
you can't even use that uh uh safer so
BT for you know the caterpillars
anymore yeah yeah that's that's a bummer
isn't it cuz that's a good product yeah
it's a great product now you know I'm
stuck out there with tweezers picking
off caterpillars all day long it's uh
it's not fun so I guess on the flip side
question what are you excited for in
regards to the can scene you know is
there any kind of interesting develops
that have really caught your eye and
you're a bit optimistic
about no no nothing I'm uh I'm looking
for a new place to move to uh some place
a little bit more lenient not as
expensive ensive uh you know if if uh
some corporate dude wants to hire me I'd
probably take a job at this
point yeah
bu yeah yeah it's uh I mean we had a
good ride for a good solid 20 years it
was uh it was pretty damn good like I
mean I had uh I had uh some weed taken
from me by the sheriff's before and then
they sent me a letter and they're like
come pick it up and they kept it for
about a good six months and then uh when
I picked it up out of the sheriff's
office they when I was there they're
like inspect it I was like what they're
like you know take a look make sure it's
still good and they they kept it better
than I could have they kept it in a nice
like you know consistent like 60 degree
room all all climate controlled and I
mean I was pretty shocked how well they
kept it that's pretty
neat um cool all right so onto the tail
and questions these are just our little
quick fire questions so first one old
school strain you wish you still
had uh roadkill skunk bud roadkill skunk
and I
know I know I sound like the old-timers
now with the AA Poco gold oh the best
stuff you know but that that old
roadkill is my childhood weed and uh you
know I I I hear what all the old school
Growers are saying about it and you know
why it's not around anymore but it's uh
I miss that flavor I miss that flavor I
miss that I miss having that you know
one butt in my pocket and it's going to
stink up the whole grocery store
wherever I am you
know yeah it's uh definitely one which
makes the uh the list almost every
interview
actually right right you know what the
oldtimers tell
me is uh it's
sucked they they say you know it was a
small little Afghan plant um you know
the same time uh when the roadkill came
out is when uh is when uh you know the
the states were allowing a lot of uh the
Afghan Freedom Fighters into the country
you know it was what the Soviet uh went
to Afghanistan like 79 to like the late
80s or something like that and uh you
know when the CIA got involved you know
helping the freed The Afghani Freedom
Fighters a lot of them got uh you know
were getting Refugee or play Refugee out
out here and with a lot of them you know
they they brought the seeds and uh so
you know there were short little indicas
and even when I was getting the the
skunk back in in like my high school
days you could you knowing what I know
now it was definitely indicas because of
how fat the little sugar leaves were
that were cocoon the buds and um so you
know the Oldtimer is telling me that uh
that the the old roadkill skunk sucked
and I'm like what what do you mean it
sucked that stuff was great but you know
that's when I first started kind of
smoking herb it was uh uh you know
pretty pretty much anything back then
would have gotten me high you know but
uh they say you know it was it was it
was short little plant it was a pain in
the ass to trim and it didn't get him
high after you know they they smoked it
a while and then like you know all all
the fruits and a lot of the Dutch stuff
came through that grew big was you know
a lot more stronger and and uh easy to
trim you know so that that uh that old
roadkill just want extinct from uh from
you know uh just people not Desiring the
uh the the the traits from it well at
least old school Growers that were
growing
it yeah okay so what in your opinion is
your favorite strin of all
time OG Kush can't get enough of
it hell yeah that that SF it's uh tried
and true it works every time even to to
this day you
know so on the opposite end of the
spectrum what is the strain that's least
jive with
you
uh man you know I I I really like the
flavors of a lot of the the hazes and
stuff like that but there the heavy
sativas get me oh you know what there's
a couple other strands I like to throw
in they're the old school ones that I
miss um yeah in the Taho
area uh we used to get this one called
Afghan queen that was is really amazing
and from the same guy we were getting
one called the
club uh and both of them were were just
just um head twisting and then in the
early 90s there was one called the
asthma in the Santa Cruz mountains that
it used to get um and I missed that
one what else was there uh there was a
Romulan uh not the we had two romulans
floating around we had one that was a
short little indica
piny real piny tasting to it and then we
had another one that was more sativa
that had this like
grapy um like a creamy grape taste to it
that was that was really really good
miss that one yeah oh man yeah
yeah starting to think about it I could
probably name off a few dozen strains
that I wish were still around but so
yeah what I was going to say is to jump
back to the question do we do we get a
worse
strain a worst strain
uh I can't really think of anything um I
love it all bud it's all I love it all I
love how they grow I love the
flavors um what would be one that I
didn't really
like I can't think of a single one it's
a good problem to have yeah it's not too
bad so if you could go back to one place
in history and in time to collect some
land R seeds where would you
go uh you know I'm a I love my indic car
so so probably uh the the Kush mountain
ranges would have to be
it that's a good answer yeah um you know
Afghanistan Pakistan
um you know nowadays it's uh I don't
know where you'd be able to find any
true land races almost every uh country
has been watered down with either Dutch
or you know American genetics by now
but yeah I would I would probably say
you know uh late
70s about the late 70s in the Afghan
region or somewhere out over there where
where things weren uh didn't get all
dutchified yet and and uh remain true
that you know things that they've
probably been breeding for thousands of
years yeah that pure
pure so lucky last question what is your
biggest hope for the Cannabis scene in
general oh go back how it
was did you know um no I think things
are good things are good uh you know
long as people aren't going getting
thrown in jail for for little amounts of
weed and and uh you're able you know
grow a few plants in your backyard it's
it's not terrible at
all that's it the Sun keeps shining so
at the end of it all do you have any
shout outs or comments you'd like to
make um no man I I appreciate you having
me I guess uh
give a shout out to all those activ
activists that got us to this point and
uh you know did put in some jail time so
we can have our
freedom and
[Music]
uh I guess I guess uh everybody that's
helped me along the way um CSI Fletcher
with archive they've both been a huge
help we we've always uh you know if I if
I lost strains I can always count on
them and uh you know vice versa
you know when they need something I
always got their backs too and uh yeah
that's about it I
guess yeah I'm sure I'm sure I'm I'm
sure I'm forgetting a ton of folks but
uh yeah you know just everybody that's
ever helped me along this journey um
super appreciative you know can't thank
everybody enough awesome thanks so much
for coming on the show Shabad and uh for
dropping all the history and setting the
record straight on a few things right on
you and thanks for for having me I
really enjoyed
[Music]
it so there we have it a big thank you
to my buddy shud for taking the time to
talk with us
again and for all you guys for hanging
out till the end a big thank you to the
patreon supporters you guys I love
you I'll see you guys soon but first
first thank you to our sponsors seeds
here now 420 Australia organic gardening
Solutions you guys and me you know
together forever I like that
idea see yall next time see
[Music]
you
la la la la la
[Music]
[Applause]
la
[Music]
la la la la
la