hey there gang this is your boy heavy
days
giving you a big thank you for coming
and checking out this episode
i just wanted to let you all know that
we have a patreon over at
www.patreon.com
forward slash the podcast if you enjoy
the show and would like to continue to
help make it happen
head on over and get access to a whole
range of goodies
including early access to episodes bonus
patreon exclusive episodes
and extra goodies like shirts stickers
giveaways and a whole lot more
thank you so much to everyone who helps
support the show you are truly the
lifeblood of it and you help us to keep
the wheels turning so that we can
continue to bring you the content
you enjoy now let's get into the episode
[Music]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts
this episode as always was brought to
you by 420 australia
your premier store for all things
lifestyle and apparel as well as team
ogs
your stop shop for all things organic
garden
on this episode we're really excited to
have bananamen
all the way from spain to talk about all
things eu as well as the breeding scene
and some history stay tuned for an
awesome episode
here we go
[Music]
all righty a big thank you and welcome
to banana man of trichome jungle our
first guest from across the pond in the
eu
thanks for joining us nice to be here
thank you for having me so first
question as always you probably know
what it is
what was your introduction to cannabis
right probably about um
14 uh smoking with friends
um would have been some moroccan hush
mixed with tobacco um
that's the sort of way that a lot of
people in the uk
sort of smoked it at that time
so yeah that was the first experience
didn't really get
high from it and probably too much
tobacco
mixed with it but probably
two weeks three weeks after that and
same group of friends we got together
and we smoked it in a bong and
i definitely got high anyway i couldn't
move off that couch for a while
i don't suppose you remember what
strains were going around back then was
it just
just whatever i mean back in the days of
hash there kind of wasn't really strains
but i don't know
what was it no we had we had a lot of
like import
like thai steak coming in and also
like brickweed from
africa and places like this um
very seeded but um the first time i ever
smoked the african
like i got a high that was unlike
anything i'd experienced from hash
the feeling in my legs the tingling
feelings
almost like psychedelic to some extent
and from that day i just
always ask the guy can can you get more
of this this this is the stuff that i
want to smoke i don't want to be smoking
the hash anymore
um so that's what i've tried to find
more of
um but at the time there wasn't really
any skunk or anything like this
so that's interesting there's like a few
points in that one i guess it goes
without saying your favorite land race
is african
um yes because of the memories it being
brings back definitely and the high
the high that it has it has something
special about the african wheats
the thing which is really interesting
about the africans is there's actually a
fair bit of diversity within the african
land races but
you know obviously durban poison just
gets the main wrap
do you think it was durban poison that
you smoked as a kid or something else
because the thing which people often
mention about durban poison is
it's not all that potent so based off
your story i would almost
tend to think it probably wasn't what do
you think
no i'm gonna say it was probably
something like
like a malawi interesting and you think
it was like the full-on
cobb type thing or just some malawi
um well because of the color of it
um it had this like almost golden edge
to it
so from
looking into it a little bit more i'd
say it could have been some sort of
malawi cobb type thing
okay interesting have you ever toyed
around with doing that yourself with any
modern stuff
like you doing the cobb method we did me
and a friend
a friend of mine grew out of malawi gold
and he vegeta outside in the uk
or for most of the season and brought it
in to flower it at the end
and flowered it for like almost 22 weeks
and the plant was huge it was just one
plant growing under four or four hundred
and yeah again the high off that was
amazing
and we tried to make some cobs out of
that and bury him in the ground
so yeah that was that was a fun
experience that's full on
and so have you ever considered trying
to find that stuff and breed with it or
is it just considered
gone in your mind um i do have some
malawi seeds that a friend collected
while he was
out in malawi um i'm yet to start them
they're they're still in the collection
um hope to pop them maybe one day soon
and so if we rewind back what was your
first grow like you know what strains
were you running and what type of
technology were you using
okay um so the first strain
would have been okay okay this is how it
uh
it came my friend was growing out the
strain we did we got a light
we'd set it up in his room and we were
growing a
tight some thai seeds but at this time
we hadn't really figured out the whole
12 thing and if the plant was just
growing
and we sort of scrapped the idea after
that
later on i got some hindu cush seeds
and i found a book um
in an old little bookstore and
this book like said in it about the
whole 12 12 light regime
and it was just like a light bulb moment
i got my plant i got the hindu kush
seeds planted them
and set up the light and away i went and
i was basically just feeding it basic
stuff here it's like
i got some chicken poo i got some wood
ash
and that's what i was basically feeding
the plant it was very basic
and so just to fast forward for a quick
second
what's your growth style now you know
are you organic bottled synthetic
um i've pretty much grown every single
way
and for the last couple years i've been
doing a lot of cocoa growing
um using bottled feeds and
also did a bit of hydro but this was
more to do with like really
testing my plants and seeing
what did well in certain situations um
with a hydra i could do a lot of tests
about removing certain nutrients and
seeing which plants drink more um
which plants take up more nutrients
stuff like this
but now i'm actually going back to my
original
way of growing which i've always grown
which is organic
but without the bottle feed and making
more of my
own ferments and teas and
stuff like this which i do outdoors so
i'm bringing
my outdoor organic methods now indoors
so you've got some pretty insane photos
of
your strains not necessarily all of them
from your garden but
you know some really full-on photos just
towering colas things like that
do you feel like when that level of
quantity is being produced
from a single plant it is at the
detriment of other qualities like you
know
quality yes i've noticed in the past
with a lot of strains that are big
yielding
they tend to lack quality but obviously
through selection and
the gene pools that we are using now you
can achieve both
yeah um but saying that
my the plans that i prefer the most
are on the more medium side of yield
but the new that the jungle juice
which uh i'm smoking today that has both
the quality and the yield the yields are
like outstanding
and people just keep picking this over
everything at the moment
so um yeah you can get both definitely
so if we just go back now for a moment
how was it that you decided to get into
breeding
was it like a eureka moment on your own
was it
you thought you could improve on what
was already there or was it just a bit
of an accident
the first one was a bit of an accident
it was
um a blueberry that hermed and
pollinated some of the
stuff the stuff in the room that me and
a friend were growing which at the time
was
a white widow um a hemp star
bubble gum we had a skunk number one
i missed a nice hash plant we were
growing a lot of hash plant at the time
as well
and a lot of casey brains things so a
few things got pollinated by the
blueberry
and i started germinating the seeds and
that's when i realized like we're not
getting any males
they're all feminized seeds that's when
i realized that we've made like
feminized seeds um
it was probably a few years later from
that point
that i was growing a lot of like dutch
seed companies out
and just found them being quite lacking
and that's when i thought right i think
i can actually make something a little
bit better than this
so i already had a plant that we call
nap which was like a hindu kush type
plant
which was like super resinous
um like knockout sleepy type of high
and but the the flavor was maybe lacking
it had this slight like aniseed
hashy type taste and
so i thought i can improve on that and i
crossed the
santa maria hayes mail onto that
and this is what later on went to makes
the
mantis which is one of my like first
main breeding project where i had i had
a goal at the end
yeah and so i mean if we look at the
mantis for a quick moment
online the genetics listed is knapp
cross to
santa maria hayes was it a santa maria
hayes hybrid or just santa maria
no santa maria hayes i found it in some
haze uh flowers that i was smoking in
holland
and i found like five seeds in it
so i spoke to the guy in the coffee shop
and
he told me that he had a santa maria
male
that probably pollinated it so i took
those seeds home
thinking uh they might be feminized
we'll see if he's telling the truth
and i got two females and
three males and did the selection from
them
so mantis went on to do a few different
projects the one i'm interested in
is the cali schnapple kush now kelly
schnapple
clone from sonic there's also another
one in the states from dynasty just so
everyone knows not talking about that
one talking about the one from sonic
what is it about the mantis og hybrid
you know you found the one you're after
what was it about that that you were
thinking this is going to pair really
well with the cali schnapple
um it was mainly to uh i wanted to add a
little bit more
of that oh gee sort of flavor into the
curry snapple because the cabbage napple
has an amazing flavor but i just wanted
to
bring something more to it so that's
adding that mail was
the idea of that um but the cali snapple
on its own is an
amazing plant like super tropical sort
of
flavors that come off it amazing
and the yield's huge yeah and the
biggest plants i've grown
full on so just looking back at a
comment you made before about
getting those seeds from amsterdam
almost some parallels with the uh
mr soul story from brothers grimm what
did the females turn out like from that
because you know you used the mantis
males or females was it the males
yeah i used a male from them onto the
female nap here
so the the females that came from those
seeds uh
one of them was like a haze but with a
little bit more structure to it
um and the other one had this sort of
lime terp which is what you get in the
mantis
and so would you ever consider like
f2ing and
just further line breeding it or is it
just more of like a breeding i have done
the month is now i've taken i'm made the
f2 line which i did release
um who cannabis did a nice article
on them there's a little bit of
variation but
so so much less variation than i would
expect you
and then i took it to f3
i've made two batches of f3
and released one of them and then
this year i'm going to take you to f4
what do you expect out of the f4s i mean
given the f2s didn't show all that much
variation as one might expect you'd
similarly think the f4s would be pretty
limited in their variation as well right
yeah and i'm going to do the f4s from a
much larger population as well um
so i'm going to probably use like five
females or maybe two
two or three males from a selection of
maybe 50 or 100
and then that will be the the f4 that
i'll finally release again
and so that's interesting i've been
talking to a few people about this idea
would you then want to release those
seeds as labeled like
just just a mixture from all of them and
that's just you know it all just comes
from one batch or would you want to
isolate
individual females and be like you're
buying a packet from this female
because a few breeders have done that
before like dungeon vault he does that
with a few different phenotypes of a few
different strains but
i think it'd be interesting if more
people got on board or do you just think
for
in terms of like not bottlenecking
things you just want to mix it all
together and release it like that
yeah for that reason so it doesn't
bottleneck to the
the genetics um but i would definitely
use
the five females i would use would all
be five females
that all resemble each other still
i wouldn't want it to be too varied the
main thing i go for with the
with the mantis is that the the lime the
lime
like opal fruits do you know opal fruits
no no okay we had like opal fruits i
think they're called starbursts now
but um you get you get the green ones
and
it just just reminds me of having them
as a kid
so that's the main thing i go for with
the mantis
and so if we look at some of the other
lines you've lime breaded the
i'm going to say this wrong is it the
pure sang or the purse
okay the person yeah that that's that
was a
sonic thing um he selected
that from seeds from barney's
um coffee shop and he got them from
from derry and i remember seeing it in
the
canner bible jason king's canon bible
and he mentions it in there the person
hayes
but i think sonic was the only guy who
who like she kept those seeds going
and bred that line so it's
he he line bred it i just took it to f4
um later on um so it's mainly his work
um but yeah he he uses a purse sang in a
lot of his crosses
and i've used that breeding male as well
and yeah it's a it's a great male and
great plant to use as a super like
like i won't want to compare it to
amnesia but it has that similar terp to
amnesia but much more sativa and much
more fruity almost like bubble gum
fruity
like an old super silver haze or
something
it's interesting i was gonna ask what do
you like about it but you just kind of
banged it out
so something that's been kind of popped
up in a few of the answers is
you know this underlying theme of
dutch genetics and you know things
coming from holland
how do you feel holland influenced the
landscape of
the uk breeding scene because i think
like for me personally from the outside
point of view it seemed like for a while
when holland first started to stagnate
and say the early 2000s
kind of felt like that rippled a bit to
the uk
how do you feel about that yeah and i
think this is when you've seen
a influx of more people actually
selecting things and keeping more clones
and actually making their own seeds
around this sort of time
um yeah definitely
like uh the one main strain that i think
played a big role in the uk is the uk
cheese
which also came from dutch seeds
you know skunk number one
yeah i mean it's almost like synonymous
in the uk
like good weed is just called skunk in
many places i remember at least when i
was there in 2010
like hydro was called skunk like you
know like like good indoor
quality high quality weed was skunk and
the other stuff was just
import do you feel like there were some
kind of unsung heroes in terms of
strains
that did help build the scene like i've
only recently become aware of it through
a few friends um
shout out to vic firth but uh psychosis
you know that's from like the same the
exodus crew those same guys who did the
cheese
are there any other ones that you know
of that you feel like did really help
build the scene but maybe didn't get
that spotlight because
cheese was like the poster child
yeah um there's a couple of strains that
there was about there was one that we
kept coming across
uh called i just it was just called i
it was i'm almost along those same sort
of like fruity skunk lines
that like typical dutch skunk but on
that fruity side
um and
yeah that was one that stood out for me
um
yeah definitely it was it was later on
that like the nap
that clone that i passed around to quite
a few people
um and yeah i suppose
psychosis was always a nice standout
strain it's very similar into in terms
of with cheese
like if you put them both in there in
the same jar
i think you'd struggle to pick them out
yeah it all comes down to who grows it
and
yeah i think that plays a big role
and so how do you feel about the way
things are now in the uk
where you know at least for the masses
cali is king
and seems like you know those import
packs are like
the be all end-all do you think this is
a healthy culture or it's maybe
detracting from what's
a really blooming scene at the moment
yeah um i
i yeah the whole the the cali packs and
stuff like this
it's all gone a bit crazy the whole the
prices and stuff like that
i've heard of these things go for is
just
unbelievable um
i've not tried a lot of these sort of
like
new cali elites yeah
but from what i hear from a lot of my
friends
again it all depends on who's grown it
and
i think a lot of these things are coming
over to the uk
are probably stuff that they can't sell
in a lot of places
that probably would fail a lot of tasks
it's certainly interesting the idea if
we don't go to clones
what do you feel about clones it seems
like you know with
the uh advent of clone shippers existing
the number of clones in different
countries particularly the uk has just
gone through the roof
i've seen people in the uk with clones
that i would almost swear
would still be incredibly hard to get in
in the usa you know like they seem so
tightly held
do you think that a lot of the stuff
that is being flaunted around
is real i almost get the impression that
maybe
people are just getting s ones or you
know because like
for example if you say i've got sour
diesel you're probably familiar with the
situation it's like
is it the real sour diesel and so you
know what i mean do you feel like a lot
of the stuff that's coming in is the
real deal or maybe people
are just a bit optimistic or maybe
getting swindled or you know somewhere
in the middle
yeah i think there's a lot of clones of
each thing and
people will find a bag seed and whatever
they find in that's what they'll name it
so yeah i imagine that a lot of these
clones aren't the original ones
um yeah i'd agree i'd agree
to say that yeah so how do you go about
sourcing your clones if there's
something kind of
in the us and maybe you're not really
sorry and um and maybe you know without
obviously talking about getting it to
spain like
do you find it's hard to source things
or does
spain got plenty to offer where's that
stand for you as a breeder
yeah i i tend to work with a lot more
seeds to be honest now
i used to work more with clones and
elite clones like the sfv the bubba
i've just got the bubba back from a
friend um
so i'll definitely be working with that
more but the rest of the us elite things
um i'm not too bothered about getting as
the original clone
like i've got crosses where i know the
originals have been used
people like from colorado and people
like that
um so yeah i i prefer to do that i think
a lot of the problems come from sharing
clones you see
and with america having a big problem
with like russet mites
pm um i'd rather not take in clones from
places like that
do you feel like you can almost stand
behind your work more
when you're using both mother and father
that you've found from seed
yes because then it is fully your
selection on both sides
um i think we can select our own elites
i think most people can even select
elites from packets of seeds mine
so i think a lot of it is hype
and i think it i i could select a plant
and give it to a certain person if they
hyped it the way they typed over strains
it would become just as popular um
so yeah i think that plays a big role i
find a lot of these elites that
have spoken to friends they say that
some and not even that stand out
compared to other stuff that
they've selected or tried for me so
um yeah interesting you bring that up
because
i've kind of been having thoughts like
that myself i pop a lot of seeds pretty
regularly and i guess i just
commonly think to myself like geez i'm
finding a lot of keepers
and then like i look at the numbers and
it seems pretty proportional
but um yeah that's always made me think
like
is the barlow or what so here's the
question
how often is it you come across a plant
you pop from a seed
and you're thinking to yourself wow this
this is really like you know a notch
above what i would normally consider a
good plant this is like
you know like definitely clone only
possibly one of the best plants i've
ever grown you know how often does that
happen
quite regular to be honest um especially
if you're growing things
from if the person sent you a packet
of something like i've recently grew up
the the bodhi
uh soulmate um he sent me a few packets
of different things
and like there was a little bit of
variation but there's two females from
the song me
that could easily both be elite strings
but the smells of them the growth on
them is amazing
i'm yet to try them both but i know
that's going to come through on the
flavor
so yeah um both of them
both standout plants and i see this a
lot i've just grown out some stuff from
colorado
amazing plants again so this is what i
i work towards this is what i want
everybody else to have they grow a
packet of my
of my seeds and they find
out with a 10-pack five plants that
they're gonna struggle to
pick a keeper from yeah it's always a
good problem to have when you've got to
uh pick your keeper isn't it too many to
choose from
yes yeah this is what everybody should
be getting from their seats
yeah we have such a gene pool to choose
from
nowadays it's not like it was like 10
years ago
um so everything that people
are breeding um people should be able to
find
uh keepers in every packet especially if
people are putting the work in as well i
see a lot of just people
releasing a lot of f1s but i would like
to go
down that line myself more just because
i can get through
more strains in a shorter amount of time
and i think that's the
the line i'm going to be going more
towards because
i like popping seeds all the time making
new things all the time
so yeah definitely go along those lines
so interestingly mandarin is one of the
ones i knew from you
before i'd ever done any serious kind of
research you know i always do some
good research before every interview so
after i kind of looked into it a little
more seriously
quickly noticed one half of its age in
orange
and the thing which kind of jumped to
minded that is is
you probably haven't heard it but we
recently did an interview with james
bean
and he actually posed the
you know the proposition that tangi is
possibly just an agent orange offspring
or
s1 or maybe just a cut of it saying that
he had done some filos testing and that
was what it indicated
surely you've grown tangy it's big all
around the world did you see any
similarities between the age and orange
you use for mandarina
and tangies would you feel like there's
maybe any similarities between them
there are some similarities um i always
said that tanji was a
nyc diesel uh that's what i always
thought it was
because they have a nyc diesel
clone that i found found out recently
that goes around spain
and they call this the mandarina cut and
when i found that i was like that that's
that's that's like tangy
so that just reinforced the force i sort
of already had that tangi was a
nyc diesel but it could easily be a
agent orange because i find these same
when i've crossed the mandarina with
other things like the sour diesel
i get those same turps coming out like
the nyc diesel with tangy type things
whereas mandarina is a lot more sweeter
fizzy sherbet type orange smells
well what's interesting to me is like
you made mandarina a few years ago now
however as far as i can tell from the
timeline
you made it just kind of before right
when the whole hype around the citrus
terpene was just taking off and
obviously
tangy was a big proponent of that but
did you have any idea that was going to
come about like did you
have a sense that this kind of you know
orangey mandarin
terpene profile was about to just take
the scene by storm or
was it a bit of a fluke like seems like
it came out at a perfect time
yeah like we really enjoyed the agent
orange
from subcool that that was just a
standout plant
we passed that clone around so many
people um
so working with that was just
we were gonna do it anyway because it
was such a nice plant
um i thought the orange thing was
fizzling out to be honest
because so many people were getting
tired of that orange turp
but i think the new generation and how
things come around in circles
like with fashion and everything else um
things make a comeback and i think that
it was perfect timing
that they saw yeah that came back as i
was working the mandarina line
and what was it about the you know the
male you used in that cross
that was right the uk pineapples some
shiva in there and even dynamite
what was it about that which you thought
just paired well with it because
essentially it seems like it's imparted
how would you put it
kind of mellowed a bit of the sugariness
at least i'm
the asian orange i'm familiar with like
a sweet orange
so like mandarina you know it's added
like a bit of sourness taking a bit of
sugariness
what do you think the male brought to
the table yeah the
the pine of my shiva mail um
i mainly was putting that onto the
cheese
and the pineapples to do like almost
like a pineapple back cross
and also to cross it with the cheese
because of that skunkiness
um at the time i had a pot of gold
there was also a nice like sweet skunky
apple sort of terp going on with that
one i thought i crossed that without so
i was going for a skunky type thing this
is what i was working
but then i had the agent orange i had
the crowberry
i had the bubba kush and also the jack's
cleaner clone from subcool
so at the time i thought okay well i'll
pollinate them at the same time
so they were all just real experimental
whereas
that's why it sort of took a back burner
for a while
but then after a few people trying it
and saying it was really nice
i thought okay i'll definitely work that
line in the future
and when i came to spain that's when i
started to finish the line
so it was quite a few years it was a big
gap from start to finish
yeah well are there any other lines like
that which you've been working over you
know many years
uh the jungle kush
that's something that i've done so the
original cross was
sfv the clone
the bubba kush clone and the hawaiian
the hawaiian was added to add like a
little bit more vigor
to to those to those strains um
and then from those seeds i work that
line
crossing them together and doing a
little bit of selection
and then that's what i release as the
actual jungle push then later on
so the mantis the mandarina
and the jungle kush are the
three lines that i've worked really
everything else is
mainly f1 after that okay and was the
first release of the jungle kush
labelled like f2 f3 or
did you just call it jungle kush just
jungle kush
yeah same with the mandarina even though
i worked the line in that
it's because it's never sort of released
so the original ones
just go between maybe a few friends that
are testing it and stuff like that
and then what i actually release will be
the worst line and that is
what i release because that's as close
to the mother that i
most people have tried as well would you
consider
kind of adding those generations onto
future packets just in the fact that
these days it seems almost standard that
the more generations a line has
put into it you know you can almost
charge a bit more
for each generation because you know you
have put work in for each generation
or would you still just always want to
keep it you know just simply
jungle push for example no i definitely
want to put like i
haven't got a catalog or anything like
that at the moment
so i'd like to put catalog together and
maybe in there put a little bit more
of the history and the actual breeding
work of each string
i think that would be a good option just
because if nothing else
potentially other breeders you know like
they're always looking
for you know potentially more work
stocks
more stable more predictable generally
and also
you know hopefully you haven't wasted
your time working a line that was a dud
so you know kind of a good indication if
you've bothered to work it's probably
pretty good
yeah no definitely and you you like the
mandarina is so
stable for for that for that smell that
it has on it
anything that you cross it with i mean
so many people have uh i've even seen
some small little breeders that are on
my instagram and that they've used
the mail of it i reversed it made a few
lines for
karma and stuff like that so um
and it's it's a very dominant trait now
because of how it's been bred
so you've mentioned a few uk breeders
and you know i've mentioned one or two
why do you think it is that a lot of the
uk breeders don't get as much notoriety
as some of the us breeders do you think
it's
the fact that just the culture is a bit
different or do you think there's
not as many breeders per capita type
thing in the uk
what do you think the situation is
i think it definitely comes down to
location and
the whole scene the american scene is
totally different
to the uk scene yeah
the outdoor scene that they have there
as well yeah i think
the selections that they've been able to
do
even since the 60s and stuff like this
in america
they have a a good genetic pool of
plants
yeah and so did people
not really keep seeds from those early
import hash because it seems like
that's kind of the most valuable stuff
going around at the moment
no yeah i think like even
the old like hippie types that i knew
and stuff like that
like they never even kept hash even
though they brought back all sorts of
different things from
india and places it's because
we haven't got that outdoor scenery
whereas people
when they came back from their travels
back to america those seeds could be
planted straight in the ground and
people could grow them out
yeah that's interesting and so do you
think overall
the ability to have an outdoor season in
general just really benefits the
community
like the scene so to speak yes yes
definitely
definitely i even see it here in spain
and
visiting like older growers and stuff
like that they have some
strains that they've kept for years and
they're things that i've never like even
smelt before
some of the smiles that come from these
old sativas
and stuff that they've kept uh yeah very
impressive
um i grew a few out last year
and um yeah some of the
terps he had one that was an afghan
cross
and it smelled like straight up
chocolate from dna genetics
like straight up chocolate so that was
quite impressive
um but yeah so definitely the outdoor
scene definitely uh
improves those genetics i think
and so you just touched on it you're now
in spain what's the spanish seem like
you know you're our first person from
the
spanish region who's given able to give
us the rundown which is obviously
in my opinion the kind of hot place to
be in the eu right now would you agree
and what's it like from your perspective
um yeah i think how it's portrayed on
the
internet and is is totally different to
how it is in reality
um in catalonia now
um some of the clubs are starting to be
recognized and
they're going down that line of sort of
legality
but how they're going to actually
regulate it and stuff like that i
i really don't know um the rest of spain
no if you you can't take any any
cannabis on your personal self outside
um if you're in your own house doing it
you're
you you are permitted to do that growing
it
is is a big gray area really so
um but barcelona sense is is the place
where
it is changing and going towards the
right way
where you have a lot of clubs now um
they have the span of this every year
which is a really big event
um so yeah it's going in the right
direction
this is a much more relaxed than the uk
how the general public view it here as
well
is is a lot more relaxed and so how do
you feel about spanish you know
a lot of people in the states uh have
mixed feelings about cops for a variety
of reasons do you think like
the spanish cup's pretty good you know
it's not
not really any whispers of corruption or
any people who
are you know causing any mishaps
so far i i've seen none of that and it
seems to be
like the the best flower or the best
extract
does win um a group of friends of mine
and a deborah tree fabulous
which like a extract company they
entered the sour mandarina extract and
they got second place
so um there's there's definitely no
uh it can't be sort of bought how they
judge it
as well is quite fair in the way
they do it um i'd like to see the actual
the actual voting to show that
afterwards
that would be interesting i like how
they do that on
the ic mag cup i think that's a very
sort of
uh transparent good one
nice and so how do you
interact with all the other breeders in
spain you know there's a few notable
ones like
charlie garcia and the guys from canada
biogen are the first ones to jump to
mind
do you have a lot of interaction with
those guys or is it everyone's just kind
of doing their own thing at the moment
yeah i don't tend to sort of uh
get into the whole scene out here too
much i'm quite far from barcelona
and i'm like out in the sticks in the
country
um so yeah i i i'm not
sort of i don't get involved in that
side of things too much out here
and when i go to spannabis um
i meet up with some of the breeders
there and stuff like that and
yeah it's a good event for that even
though
they have a cup and stuff it's more
about
going seeing old friends new people
seeing what people have
seen how the the blood has changed over
the last few years is get just getting
better and better and better so
i can only see it in the next two three
years
um it's going to be some amazing stuff
available in all of these places and so
what's the coolest thing you've ever
seen at the cup in terms of budweis
um there's a few places that have some
nice stuff
um right but the most like place that
i'll actually like to chill out
is like there's a place called um our
backyard
um that has a nice vibe about it and
they
always tend to have some nice stuff in
there um one place i haven't checked out
yet but they tend to stock a lot of my
things and that is the plug
um that's another place seems to have
like a nice vibe about it um
but yeah like i see i also see like a
price
increase as the i've
i think the bud can be cheaper i think
the prices need to be brought down
definitely
i think that will happen as things go
more towards the legal side of things
okay and do you think
that the development of a scene
is largely dependent on the number of
people
popping seeds because i've got this
theory that
if everyone stops popping seeds
essentially
everything will come to a standstill in
terms of progression
do you think that's the case 100
yes because nothing new will be found
everyone grows the same stuff
everyone grows the same clone i see it
happen in holland
where everyone just wants to grow clones
even in the uk
but this the feminist seed market
i think this is where most people
in europe and the uk want to go down the
lines of feminized seeds
um but i think in the future i think
even people are going to come away from
that
who who are more serious about it and be
popping
regular seeds and going through more
regular seeds doing their own breeding
doing their certain selection
because i love to see other people's
work because everybody selects something
totally different
i can give the same packages as seeds
three different people
and tell them to do some breeding work
and what they end up with will be
three totally different things totally
and so we've mentioned a lot of breeders
so far
who are some of the ones who you really
look up to or you you know you're really
fond of the work they do
[Music]
okay um bodhi at the moment i'm
very impressed with his work i've always
been a like
enjoyed talking to him and seeing his
stuff online
and breathe but he used to do a lot of
good threads and when he used to do his
trips just like south america and stuff
like this yeah
and uh nepal so yeah i i admire bodhi
definitely
he's a he's he's a good guy
would there be anyone you'd want to do a
collaboration with
um i'd probably like to do
a couple more things with sonic because
um
in the past me and him used to do a lot
of work together in that
and i like the lines that he's worked
with
so yeah maybe some of him i'd love to do
one with bodhi that would be amazing
yeah and so to kind of be devil's
advocate
what strain you know if the kind of the
proposed idea is you're each going to
bring
one side of the strain to the table
which strain and you can even choose
which whether it's the male or the
female what would you want to bring to
the table
uh well from both those people well no
on your part
if you were say to do a cross with bodhi
don't worry about him for the moment
what would you want to bring to the
table on your half you can pick male or
female but one of your strains
you know what would you most kind of
want to stand behind or what do you
think would work the best with one of
his lines
i think the jungle kush or the mandarina
just those two lines just because of how
they breed and how strong they are
bigger
everything yeah turps yeah those two
so i've had this interesting theory for
a little bit now basically that
a long time ago i used to get pretty bad
anxiety with certain sativas generally
you know like the more stronger ones
pretty typical with what most people
would describe and then as time went by
i kind of didn't really get
that anxiety anymore for a long time i
was thinking to myself
oh you know like i've just had like a
tolerance
build up to sativas in general and i'm
now able to have these more racy ones
because you know like i've worked my way
up to a type thing
but then thinking back on in general i
was like you know what like
back when i was getting anxiety from the
sativas i had anxiety in general
and nowadays when i can smoke them i
don't actually get anxiety anymore i
haven't in a very long time
and so it makes me think do you think
like a lot of that
even with weed for example is down to
where you're at
personally because like a lot of people
will say oh you know don't do a dmt trip
if
for example you really you're depressed
or you're anxious because
that type of stuff can be aggravated and
come out do you think that even applies
to weed as well
i think it like we'll go to we'll say
answer the dmt one first and say like
look
if you are feeling like anxious or
depressed than that i want to say
not to take it i think to do it with the
right person
yeah in the right space is definitely
more to do with it than anything else
obviously the mindset
comes with it like the better mindset
you're in but then
you're going for an experience so
sometimes it can help with different
mindsets
so with cannabis
um i would say
yeah like one of my friends he gets a
bit anxious with the sativas and that
and still does but as he's got
older he's been able to handle it a
little bit better definitely
um i think does that answer your
question i hope
yeah no for sure it's interesting it's
one i want to kind of think more about
myself contemplate and see where we get
to
so a quick little question i wanted to
ask where does the name banana man come
from
uh-huh that's a funny or not um
right at the time i i was the only one
just growing regular seeds all the time
all my friends were growing feminized
seeds and
i was going today grows and i'm just
picking up bananas everywhere
so i'm thinking like i'll use a bit of a
joke i'm like telling them i'm more of a
banana farm i keep coming here just
picking up bananas all day
so when i went online i thought okay
banana farmer and then
and i thought no actually banana man i
like the cartoon
so yeah and that's how the name came
about really
that's awesome what stuff are you
testing out at the moment
uh like my friends just done like a big
like grow over orange soda so i'm
testing out some of them and i've just
done a new
jungle kush times jungle push again like
a
v2 version so he's giving me a load of
different phoenix of that
i've got a little bit of gorilla glue
for the clone
so he's giving me a bit of that try some
jungle dog venus
which was a star dog across with the
jungle kush
again though limited i only released so
many i think there's like a couple of
packets still available at so
other places but i probably won't make
that one again
how do you feel about the common hype
strains you mentioned the gorilla glue
a lot of people you know kind of hate on
the hype strains but at the same time
they love them
where do you sit um
no i i like a lot of them like there's
the gt4 it it makes some real nice hash
and yeah it's a good all-round strain
like the ones that stood the test of
time like like the og's
and sours and stuff like that they're
amazing the newer things like the
cookies i do like the cookies
i haven't tried like the gelato and a
lot of these new
ones from like and what else was there
the sunset shirt
things like this i'm yet to try them so
and do you like to breed with the
cookies i mean i know you have
yes um i think it's good for breeding
and
from breeding with it i see so many
fennels are so similar to like bubba
when i breed with bubba as well
definitely like those cherry pie type
phenos are
popping up as well so it's quite
interesting when you breed a bit
whatever the f1 durbin is
if he's quite interested to find out
what that actually is i don't think
anybody actually knows to be honest
that's my opinion on it
yeah do you think it's the case that no
one knows what the f1 derby is or that
maybe it's just something completely
i think they probably found it in a bag
seed or something
and they don't actually know what the
parents is just like
so many other things that have been
found in backseat and people
don't really know what the full parent
is
is yeah and so
how do you feel about the idea of
breeding with s-ones
okay um i've just done a cross with an
s1
i'm testing it out now uh it's an
s1 from a fruity purple og
cross with og kb line so i've just
crossed that with my jungle
and i'm gonna see how that comes out but
my s1 of my mandarina
i wasn't happy enough to release them as
a feminized line
um i've grown other s ones out in the
past of like some chem strains and stuff
like this
i've not really been impressed uh
compared to the actual clone so
yeah and so how do you feel about fem
lines in general is it something we can
expect from you in the future um yeah
i'm definitely going to be making more
phone lines in the future
i made some mandarina phone lines
and also some sour diesel phone lines
last year and they've come out with some
good results
um the jungle juice and the orange soda
was made with my jungle kush
with the sour diesel reverse and also
with the
mandarina with the sour diesel reverse
to make the orange
soda but i did it the other way around
as well
i reversed the mandarina onto the sour
diesel
i also did the jungle push onto the
mandarina and the mandarina onto the
jungle kush
and i've definitely seen that the
dominant
plan is the plant that you reverse
like all the ones that i reverse with
the sour diesel of that like slightly
cyber diesel stretch and have more sour
diesel
taste with the mandarina whereas when
you reverse the mandarina
you get those more short sativa phenos
and more mandarina taste coming out
so it's been quite interesting insanely
of way around with the jungle
um i've seen some quite interesting
things with like reversing and stuff
like even
reversing like i've had a male
that produced pistols this was somebody
else's clone
and i use
i've got seeds from it so i've floured
it fully out
collected the seeds from the mail
and grew those seeds out and i'm getting
50 50 male and female from them which i
didn't expect
so that's been quite interesting as well
have you finished flaring them out
yeah yeah yeah i got 50 50 male and
female from the seeds
but this was this was that was a couple
years ago that one happened
and were the females stable yeah
the female was like a female from that
liner
so would you consider further using
those seeds or they just weren't that
good in general
no they just went in the stash yeah
nice so one thing i noticed is that
you've used c99 in a few year strains
and
a lot of these strains came out before
brothers grim came back
would you consider re-releasing some of
these strains with the new c99
or what's your plans for that
um no because they're back now
um i probably won't work with that line
anymore um
at the time they weren't around the
cindy 99 was an amazing plant
that was a line worked by a friend of
mine
from greed bay and he worked the line
for many years from the original bros
grim and then
i continued working that line to
f4 um and i've just used
a female that i've selected from those
f4 seeds and
pollinated that with the jungle kush and
that's like i just named it jungle jane
at the moment
but i'm testing them out at the moment
to see what they come out like
but cindy 99 is a real special plant and
uh that that pineappley
uh fruity turp that something special so
yeah i'll probably i won't work with
that like now it's back
it'd be interesting to see what they
make
so have you had a chance to try the new
one and has your
f4s you know has it varied over the
generations compared to
what the original is essentially
no everything that you grow from the
f-4s
are just pure cindy's they're just all
coming out so similar
and there's not much variation and
it was already almost like a stable line
to work with anyway
so um it was i think it's quite easy
my friend worked the line over the years
just just on high
and then i worked it on those pineapple
things so yeah
it's come out amazing so
where do you rank different attributes
in kind of your hierarchy of breeding so
in your mind is it the case that you
don't care if it's big or small yielding
if it's just really good smoke like
that's the goal or
do you try to have you know a bit of a
compromise between you know
like commercial value or
where where do you sit on that are you
breeding entirely ahead stash what's the
go
no i i think like one of the main things
for me
is like the vigor of the plant and
how well it can handle like
mites is it resistant to powdery mildew
these are some of the main things for me
at the moment i think this is what
most of the market needs to start
looking towards because of how things
are going
so um yeah definitely that rent is quite
high for me
and flavor is is the main thing but the
high
that's that's down to different
different lines that i work each line
that i work has a different height about
it and i think that comes with turps as
well then
i'm finding that certain turps like the
orange things for instance
the orangey things are on those lower
thc sides the people that extract it
get a little bit less return so that
comes from like those
orangey sort of things and but yeah
so it's interesting have you done any
work with the whole
you know the the how should i say newly
discovered
land of terps in that people are adding
you know like
food grade terps back to concentrates
and stuff now and
the overwhelming feedback i've heard is
that it's it's not quite the same and
it's definitely not as good as if it was
like
natural terps in there do you know much
about this and how do you feel about the
turp scene do you feel it's like the new
flavor of the month thing
um yeah i think for the future i think
it's going to hold a lot of benefits the
terps
um i think breeding point of view as
well
certain terps are definitely
stock mites certain terps encourage mice
to come to the plant so i think that
side of things but the whole thing about
adding other plant tips to
cannabis extract and all that i don't
agree with that to be honest
i think tips are quite a volatile sort
of solvent anyway
to be smoking a lot of
um but yeah i think it's going to be
interesting what
all this testing and stuff like that
brings to the table
and so do you feel like the same testing
requirements that exist in the states
should be
you know in spain as well yes
um but like
the whole how it's going legal in the
states and
what they're going to implement and
stuff like that i don't know if i agree
with all of it totally
and it just opens up the market for
big companies basically like you've got
scott's miracle girl that's brought out
gavir
and general hydroponics and all these
these other companies
um they're not good companies and these
are the people
that will end up um taking control
like monsanto and bayer taking control
of
other parts of the fruit and vegetable
market and seed market as well
um and then you mix plant poisons into
that and
yeah it's not it's not good i think it's
going to go in the future
i think it's going to be very controlled
so what's the concentrate seem like in
general
in the uk you know in the states it's
seems like it's completely overtaken the
flower scene for the you know the
general consumer
do you feel like that's the progression
that's happening for the eu in general
or
maybe in the uk but not spain or maybe
vice versa
what do you think it's what do you think
is happening sorry
yeah um i think like
the extract scene is becoming more
popular
it seems to be a younger generation
thing as well
with the whole dabbing and stuff like
this um
i'm getting into it a little bit um
but like yeah i think in
the future i think smoking will be
looked as like an old school way of
doing it
um but the scene
here in spain yeah dabbing is very
popular it's getting more and more
popular
barcelona yeah there's a big scene for
it there's
lots and lots of extract artists now
over in spain
and the uk um and they're bringing some
beautiful tasting stuff to the table so
yeah
i'm competing with some of the americans
even so yeah
it's interesting to see what's what
it'll bring
so would you ever consider breeding
specifically for terps or for
concentrates so to speak
yeah well i've sort of done that anyway
by
by breeding for uh trichome production
and
terps in general um like the jungle
kush and the jungle juice they produce
some crazy returns
um so yeah
people are people loving that is like an
extract artist dream those two plants
um so yeah i think that comes hand in
hand with breeding
good flower you breed
good extract strains and because
if you're breeding for flavor i think
that's one of the main things
try complexion obviously you select for
the plants with
big big trichome production that can
produce
lots of terpenes the terpenes that you
choose that you like so
yeah okay
and so a question i was thinking about
is how often do you think it's the case
that someone grows out a pack of maybe
yours maybe anyone's seeds
and they think to themselves oh this
finna is not so good
and then like maybe they ditch it but
the truth is maybe they just didn't grow
out that well because recently
i've grown a few things again that i
initially thought were bunk
but they're from people i really respect
i was like you know what i'll give it
another go
lo and behold completely different way
better totally worth keeping
do you think that's like something which
happens a lot because you mentioned
earlier you're like yeah there's you
know there's winners in every packet
do you think maybe there's a bit of that
going on for people who maybe disagree
with that
um yeah i think that just comes down to
selection
like when i first started breeding
i seen this more with the plants like
the plants that i was selecting and
using
i would see this variation where you
were getting some really nice plants and
some plants
not so nice but as
you know that's progressed i don't see
that so much
in my lines um and even lines from other
people
i've grown bodies things this year i've
grown some stuff from colorado
i've grown some stuff from south fork
seeds yeah their stuff does really well
outdoors
um and i've all amazing work from
each one of them so yeah
so the interesting thing i just took
away from that is all of those are us
breeders as well as many of the other
breeders you've mentioned so far
what do you think is the go with there
not being that many breeders
in the eu scene despite there being a
really big market
do you think that more people from you
know
uk for example need to you know pick up
their game and start releasing things or
why do you think it is you know there
aren't that many eu breeders
um i think there's lots of them
um i think there's a good one there's a
lot of yeah there's a lot of [__]
companies out there
like just producing i
i don't even know what they're producing
now i see some
so like yeah like there's so many of
these little spanish companies and dutch
companies popping up all the time
and a lot of spanish people grow these
seeds they like cheap
feminized seeds and when you see the
results everything's just
sub standard uh weed
it's just yeah it's just shame to see
because
if they were actually growing uh
plants that were actually starting from
good seeds they could produce some
amazing flower out here
so this is where it comes down to
genetics again
these these these [__] seed companies
that use
uh not very good genetics that are just
making feminized seeds because
that particular plant produces a lot of
pollen
yeah and it's good for making feminized
seeds
it's just polluting the the market with
um substandard uh genetics
so something you may or may not have an
opinion on
how do you feel about the way strain
hunters notably
you know kind of went to
other countries and just diluted or
polluted i should say
the genetic gene pools you know with
their stock in exchange for land races
because it's almost kind of like
what you're describing in a way like
just coming and giving inferior stuff to
the locals and
they just don't know yeah i think that
whole thing was crazy when i seen that
um well elite he he's got a nice genetic
library now of all the nice land races
and he's polluted it for anybody else to
go back to but
these people like you tell these people
that uh
you can get twice as many uh
twice as much yield and you don't have
to pick up males
and these people are going to go with
that this is how
uh monsanto has taken over parts of
africa with certain
uh things that they've produced so it's
just the same thing as that really
like going around to these places and
polluting
uh and it's not even like he's given a
few seeds to one little farmer and say
keep that little patch or something like
that he's literally gone there with
kilos of seeds
and taking kilos of their seeds it's all
crazy to be honest
yeah the immediate thing i thought of
it's almost like a crude way of like
copyrighting it you know because as you
said it's like
you've got your library no one else does
yeah that's what he'll be doing in the
future um i think unless
this yeah he's he's looking to the
future
where he can pay in certain strains or
stuff like that
yeah definitely yeah it'll be
interesting to see what aryan's game
plan is now that
the main workhorse there is no longer
there
yeah franco was a good guy he had a true
passion for the plan now
yeah shame he's gone yeah i totally
agree with you franco
in my opinion did all the work and it
was so pretentious the way aryan
named everything after himself when he
almost openly admitted he didn't do any
of the work
yeah it's a shame to see
oh well hopefully some good new dutch
companies can take their place
an interesting idea i wanted to ask you
about though is do you think that people
who are aspiring breeders throughout the
eu
should move to spain for example to help
get things going
i guess the underlying idea is is it
better to try to
have one more person you know like doing
the right thing
being a good breeder but in spain
or to stay in the illegal country kind
of you know
fight the hard fight but not be able to
reach your full potential and you know
offer what you could maybe
yeah i think even in spain it's hard
like i can't achieve my full potential
out here
this is why i'm looking towards maybe
working with somebody in america
to sort of get a lot more of my genetic
lines over there
maybe work some of the lines on a on a
bigger scale
larger selections um because that can't
be done here
it's still a very big gray area i think
anyone who's thinking about coming to
spain
should definitely look at all the laws
come out here first speak to people that
are already living here
um and judge it for themselves
yeah so do you think it's possible for
the average person
to make a living like let's let's let's
be actually really optimistic about it
let's say you live in america and so
and you're a really good grower like
you've got validation of it like you
know dispensaries will pay top dollar
for your type stuff and it's it's really
good
so you're thinking to yourself yeah if i
moved to spain i could definitely grow
stuff it's real good
sell it to dispensaries you know yadda
yadda
do you think that that's actually
possible or do you think like no like
you
you know you're not gonna get enough
money for it you need to have other
stuff going on
like how do you see it
um because i'm not really in that scene
in barcelona
i don't know how that would work there i
don't know how it really works there
um but with it going sort of
more legal and they're going to sort of
regulate the grow rooms and that
maybe i think maybe maybe they might
even go towards that way
yeah so another thing that's going to be
interesting to see over the next year or
so
yeah well interesting if we were going
to talk about
some of the traits that you look at in
males
and think that that indicates a superior
male
what are the sum of things you like on
males that you think indicate you know
this is going to be
my breeding male okay
uh resistance you know how how well it
copes with things number one
um the growth
um i like to tend to go for like
like a slightly shorter time mail
because when they do go into flower they
tend to stretch out a lot more
um short internodes
between the spacing um the smell of the
stem was something i
always used to go by and when it dropped
pollen
as well not those males that dropped too
early you know um
and obviously resin like the the males
that you can
get resin from and smell them uh
they are the special meals yeah
and do you find that that flavor or that
smell correlates
yes yeah i'd like to actually start
reversing some of my males
and turning them female to actually see
uh how they end up
that's something i'd like to i haven't
done that i'd like to start doing
it just as a bit of a random side
question would you ever consider doing a
pollen release
yes yeah but you know i've actually uh
um got some pots here at the moment
and i was thinking of doing a little
giveaway of
just uh three
[Music]
three packs of seeds and one little
tube of pollen to someone someone that's
already grown out my strains as a little
giveaway
so yeah i definitely look towards doing
something i like in the future
yeah and what would be some of the
strains you'd want to do for the pollen
release because obviously
as a breeder you could do it
strategically because you can think all
right
what is something i would want to get
out there because you know best case no
someone breeds with it makes something
amazing and you know whenever something
amazing is around people always look at
the parents and think
you know i'd like to try that type thing
yeah i it would be the mandarina
and uh the mantis uh because of the two
sort of turps
it does pass over it's quite a dominant
both of them are quite dominant
uh mantis passes over this lime
zest and the mandarina passes over
that orangey citrus turp so
they would be the two pollens i would
actually uh probably look towards giving
out
okay and so if we just jump back to what
we're talking about before with the
breeding
an idea commonly brought up and i think
notably i've heard this from sub cool is
he says that he believes the males
particularly
bring the flavor do you find that is an
accurate rule of thumb or it really just
varies
the male brings flavor let me think so i
guess if you wanted me to like elaborate
a little bit more
you know your selection of the male
that's what brings the flavor so for
example you could have a female which is
really nice
got really good flavor but if the male
you pick if if what his
profile is is not good you know that's
going to dominate more so so do you feel
like the male you're using crosses
dominates them
yeah yeah i think that plays a big role
if you're if you're selecting a male
um the outcome from that cross can be
varied and this is where you get
some plants that are amazing and other
plants that you just look at i think oh
i just wouldn't even smoke that
so yeah i think that plays a big role in
so what about this idea i've been
thinking about right
is the best female for breeding a
dominant one
in that a lot of people i feel
buy seeds more so for
the mother than the father because
there's a lot of people out there
notably say
sub cool who a lot of the strains use
the same father
again and again and so it's like the
people buying these seeds
obviously interested in the mother what
it brings to the table so with that
being said is the best mother
not one that's very dominant so that
people can ideally find a good replica
of it in the 10-pack
yeah like even males that are
non-dominant so
when you cross a male everything that
comes is more like the mother i find
some males are like this like a
non-dominant male
so it doesn't matter what you cross that
male 2
so many of the females are coming out
like the mother that you cross it to
so i think that plays a big role as well
and that comes down to selection again
okay and so how do you find you select
that
do you just have to do it the
old-fashioned way and you know make some
seeds grow them out
and test them and test yeah yeah time
time consuming
so use multiple males on the same female
all of different on different females
though so you don't mix the pollen
and then test those seeds out and see
which males pass over what traits so
yeah only way it can be done
so how many seeds do you like to pop
when you're popping one of your strains
to get a bit of an idea of you know if
it's a good line if it's worth releasing
okay um i'll pop a couple of packets
myself and i'll give
out a few packets to friends that will
grow straight away
and then give out a few to maybe a few
selected people from online or something
like this
and then see the results from that and
that's how i tend to do it now um
just with this new one i've done so many
new crosses with the jungle kush
but i've just started so many seeds
outside and
they've vegeta for a few weeks and
they've gone into flowers they're all
very short but i'll get a good idea
of which ones i want to continue working
with or test more
so um yeah like from
each strain i you i want to be seeing
like
from 50 i can get a bit of a percentage
from 50
females
and would you ever consider providing a
little bit
more kind of detailed information on
number of phenotypes what you could
expect from each phenotype that type of
thing because we have seen more breeders
switch over to providing you know these
more kind of
thyroid analysis particularly on f1
where it's you know there is a bit more
variation
yeah if you go on breed bay we used to
have to fill out a form
and then you can see it all there and it
says how many phoenix of each type and
everything
so i used to do this a lot more but i
see that
so many people are just like not even
interested they just want to know what
the mother is
and what the fire is and what is crossed
with and
it's all about the name it seems
nowadays but
i always tend to jot all these things
down i've got notebooks and
everything so maybe i'll put that in the
catalogue as well
but if you go on breed by a lot of my
older strains and the mantis and stuff
like that
you can actually see and it says there
you know
the parents how many phenas of each type
and
explains everything yeah so something
i've noticed over the past kind of
year or so that i've been doing the show
is i've been keeping tight tracks on
which seed values are stocking who and
things like that for various reasons and
something i've noticed is
your seeds have been increasingly
getting to more seed banks getting out
there more and more
have you found that it's been like an
easy thing or it's been a bit of an
uphill battle and what should people
expect if they're looking to get their
seeds out there into the market
um yeah it's hard
hard to sort of maybe crack america a
little bit more
but i think i've had quite a few people
buying from america and canada
since i sort of started on breed bay so
we had a lot of american people on there
and at the time
so cool was on there um bodhi was on
there
gooey breeder sun simulator quite a few
people so
like there was it was a a good little
uh community so a lot of people came
there bought seeds
so i've had quite a
american-based market for a while but
it all comes with time and
i think now that it's all about seems
about all about cups and
what you've crossed it with that seems
to be the
how you sell seeds now more than
how much work's actually gone behind it
i think that's more for the connoisseur
type grower and so like with that being
said
do you not feel like it's really
important for you to try to
win as many cups as possible assuming
they are based on merit
because you know it is going to have a
flow-on effect of sales
um yeah um i'd like to
enter the ic markup again just because
of how
transparent it is and you you get to see
everything
um i wasn't really into cups in the past
um but recently i've entered a few and
we've got a few cups so that's that's
been that's been good
but yeah i think it's always good to um
enter one every now and again
yeah but maybe in the future i'll
probably stay away from most of them
just stick with the
ic mag ones or maybe any new ones that
pop up which are a little bit more
transparent
yeah so overall what would be your
advice
to you know a new aspiring breeder
what's
what's the best way for them to get into
the market should they look to develop a
library first
what should they do before they try to
start getting their work out there to
the masses
grow as many different genetics as you
can create a library
um selection
do your selection make your seeds pass
them to people give out so many seeds
for free
i've given up so many seeds for free
just give out your seizure
and um i think
the seeds will speak for themselves and
um yeah i think that's the best advice
really
so what point did you make the jump from
just you know
like making some seats for yourself to
thinking you know what
i'm gonna sell this yeah um
i was making a few um
different strains uh making a few
different crosses and stuff like that
and people would show an interest like
asking well when are you going to put
them on breed breedway
so i sent out a lot and people were
putting up pictures and growing them
this was around 2007 2008 and then
that's when i sort of created trichome
jungle seeds
and yeah uh it went from there really
but it's only more recently that i've
had
a bit more of a influx of
uh interest and sales and stuff like
that is
from the whole american market i would
say yeah
how it's going over there
okay interesting and so what do you
think is going to be the next big thing
to hit the american market and are you
already working on something for that to
cater to it
um yeah i'm working on a few things at
the moment and
mainly the jungle cush crosses so
i've crossed so many different things
with jungle kush i think the main ones
are going to be like the
the tahoe tk across with the jungle kush
the sfv tk with the jungle kush
um the girl scout cookie crossed with a
cherry pie across with the jungle kush
so
those three um are in testing at the
moment which i think are gonna be like
yeah well the parents i've selected are
amazing so
we'll see how all the testing goes so
they're going to be the main ones i'm
going to be
releasing soon um i released two
recently
which was uh the hadoo ken which is the
sunset sherbert
cos cross with a cookie crisp from
colorado
and i crossed that with the jungle kush
and the jungle rose which is a cross of
from motive 303 of
uh fruity pebble oh g with you dub
and i found this uh like fennel that has
this like
rose water turp so that's the one that i
selected
and crossed with the jungle kush as well
so
yeah and everything's coming out amazing
so we've just finished testing that and
just done a release on both of them
crystal ship is a strain that caught my
eye
because it uses kodiak gold which is not
a well-known strain from reefer man
um how do you feel about it you know
would you consider using it again or is
it one of those ones that's kind of long
gone
um yeah i used it at the time and
it was a nice selection but
now from the gene pool i've got
it it's not a standout plant
and plus i probably i wouldn't want to
work with reef man stuff anyway
um yeah i do go on
um i don't like some of his
uh views he's had in the past i know
people changing that but yeah
i i'll probably stay away from his
genetics from now on
yeah no worries and so if we then jump a
generation forward galactic smurf you
know you use crystal ship
you crossed it to an australian pony boy
i always love
unknown strains tell us about this one
what was the go with him
okay ponyboy um these seeds came to me
a high times cup one year uh
from coyote seeds yeah
there's some like mad american guy
um and he had like this picture of all
that little smurfs everywhere
and like he put them all in his birth
and some seeds and he had all these
different crosses with the smurfs and
stuff
and that's where i got those seeds from
but i can't find
any information about this guy at all i
don't know if you've ever heard of
coyote seeds no
okay so that's that's where it came from
yeah
okey-dokey so we mentioned the jungle
kush a few times
do you think that this is kind of gonna
be your masterpiece so to speak or do
you envision
envision there ever being a masterpiece
or do you think
you'll just continue on with strains and
just keep working things until you find
a new thing to work on
um yeah like every year i'm finding just
new things and
like it's unbelievable how
how many different um
smells that this plant can produce like
okay so
ev every couple of years i'm i'm finding
something that stands out
that i might i've never smelled anything
like this before
so i don't think i think creating
con we're always creating we're always
learning
throughout life so yeah i think
that's how i'll take my breathing yeah
and
constantly learning from this plant and
constantly creating new things all the
time but the
jungle kush at the moment
amongst everybody that's uh growing it
and
extracting from it is one of the
standard strains
alongside the jungle juice um
i think the jungle juice will probably
become almost an elite like
because there's not many seeds of that
left now
in circulation so it'd be interesting
i haven't got the sour diesel um
uh it's like a res dog sour diesel but
karma selected it so i reversed that
to make that and also the orange soda so
i haven't got that anymore
so um we'll see how i work that line
further in the future maybe we'll see
so it's interesting you mentioned karma
i had a question you know you've used
some of karma's strains in a whole bunch
of
different strains of your own is there
any other breeders out there besides the
ones already mentioned you know
colorado got a bunch of big ups is there
any other breeders who
you would consider using their work
see karma stuff i like his og lines
is his cush biker kush
and that was a real nice plan uh
i even liked his headbanger that was a
good one
um me and him don't work too much
together anymore
he used my mandarina on a few crosses uh
i made a few mandarina crosses for him
and
see working with other breeders in the
future
um maybe some collabs or something like
that maybe some limited things
that have been quite interesting with
some people yeah we'll see how things go
okay so just to clarify things went sour
because he made the mandarina cushions
or you made them for him
um do you know what that was
uh that was yeah
somebody else actually made them right i
i gave someone a mandarina clone
um and they just pollinated a plant
so he ended up with some seeds from some
some guy that he was using to make some
seeds for him
so that's where they came from and then
he's used the same name put the same
name on it and
releasing his freebies now yeah that is
probably down to
the things going sour between me and him
um
but yeah some it happens a lot in this
game and
i see a lot of breeders they they fall
over certain things
um but yeah
it's uh how things go sometimes and so
how do you feel about the idea of
asking for permission to use someone's
work you know is like mandatory or just
respectful
no i think it's respectful to ask
someone
it depends it depends like what your
intentions are with the seeds if you're
going to be making a lot of money from
it or not then
yeah i think the people need to be asked
um
if you're going to be doing a little
limited drop
or giving them out for freebies or
something like this
um i don't see it as too much of a big
problem
um people are welcome to use anything
from any of my seeds
i say always you know select a male
select a female make things cross things
it's how we all start so um
yeah i don't have a problem with it
myself
uh a few people have used my things and
not asked
and it doesn't really bother me to be
honest
and so if we jump back to that uh
african land race idea for a while
will we be seeing any african crosses in
the future
notably i see you have the caribbean
crush you know
guess not africa most people are
thinking of but
nevertheless an african strain
yeah well that was a a solution
and me and sonic went to saint lucia
i'm trying to come and it was probably
about 2000 and
nine or something like this and we went
to a field there
we uh the the variation was unbelievable
you had like 12 foot sativas and you had
like
tiny little two-foot plants next to it
so
like because of the season there um
so we went round we collected some
flowers with the things that taste
smell the nicest took them back dried
them
tasted them selected some seeds from
and a lot of them hummed when grown
indoors
yeah a lot of them uh hurt when grown
indoors and delights
and but then out in spain
i found a nice one and i pollinated that
with the
month with the uh i had the mantis
and i had the some lucian and i
pollinated them both with the headbanger
so i made like the sour mantis and the
caribbean crush at the same time
so but that was a real nice strain as
well
like it had that almost tropical
but zesty
going on with it but yeah it was a nice
one
we selected from that field an idea i've
had for a little bit now is
do you think that the most memorable
crosses are ones that produce really
unexpected but awesome flavors like for
example
if you cross a chocolate strain with a
strawberry strain and you think you know
i'll get like you know chocolate stories
or whatever
and then it comes out and it's like
rotten meat and like maybe it's like
phenomenal you know like something like
that was just like you know totally
doesn't really add up
do you feel like those are often the
most memorable ones or
sometimes the predictable ones are the
best as well
yeah no i think the ones that really
like for me when i grow
things and someone says it's a cross of
this and this
and then i grow it and it's it produces
a smell that's nothing like any of the
parents
and really unique and unusual
that for me is something special and
and i've come across that a couple of
times this year with a few things
and they've become part of the library
so people will see a lot more from those
things and a little history on each one
soon in the future so yeah
and so just as a bit of a random
question
how important do you rate aesthetics
within
your whole breeding operation do you
value it highly would you ever
knock a strain back from market if you
thought oh it doesn't really look good
but it was like really good smoke
um no probably not
but like i'd sort of uh
explain it a little bit like you get
some like varied phenos and
some a small yielding and something
large yielding or maybe
like you get something like with like
even i'd consider some
cookie crosses like they they have these
like almost freaky
um stunted almost vino's where the buds
don't want to grow too big and stuff
like this
so yeah i'd explain all that
and so just as another bit of a random
question if you were going to enter a
cup
would you want to enter something which
you thought was just really well grown
or like would you also want to have like
a bit of that real wild card
factor of like throwing some real unique
flavor or terpene profile out there
what would be your kind of aim um
most of the time i'd like to enter a
strain that i've got in seed form
and athena that represents the strain
that he so uh
if it does win people can have the seeds
and a good representation of what has
actually won
i think that's a good thing to go for
and so do you have any kind of old
school
genetics or any kind of wild cards
you're looking to breed within the near
future or you know pop in the near
future
potentially work with um
definitely a few of the land race
collection is definitely going to be
coming out
i have some hunza pakistani strains
uh was becky uh
some african australians again yeah so
i'm interested in fluffing some of them
because i haven't grown any of that for
a long time
um what else uh
yeah i think more of the laundry because
i've i've been
starting a lot of seeds from other
breeders a lot of my own stuff
um i think it's time to do
a little uh landry selection and
see what comes about how would you want
to work now let's just say you did pop
it in you got some good numbers of
let's just say just one would you want
to cross it with a certain strain or
would you want to
breed it a few generations yeah i've got
already got like brazilian and
thai so i'd probably look for something
in there
us becky strange or the citral strain
or even the hunza and find
something a little bit more on the
indica side
and cross that with the uh the
um mexican time
and so what type of like you know let's
say you do have this crazy hybrid what
type of work would you want to do with
it then would you want to
keep working it to the point where it's
stable or be offering something like you
know it's a bit more wild kind of like
what bode
is doing now what's kind of the end goal
for the the land races
um it'd be nice to create something
totally from scratch uh
from the well the originals um
and then uh work that line yeah
uh even work it outside would be nice
each year maybe do a little patch
so yeah that would be quite interesting
and let's just say worst case scenario
you got the seeds to the top
but they were all showing herm traits
would you try to line breed it and weed
them out or would that type of thing
just indicate too much effort for you
yeah i try and work away from that and
especially outdoors
i'd expect not to see it as much with
a lot of these strains i know it's
they're prone to it and
it's natural but i try and work away
from that
yeah you can breed it out
how many generations would you expect it
might take because i mean
something i noticed is in the earliest
ssc magazines for example they would
often say
bread for generations shows some
hermaphroditic traits still
and so that was something you know the
best stock there was so
to me it makes me think well obviously
it's not worth just throwing in the
tower immediately but
it might take a few generations and to
me four sounded like they maybe got
lucky like i would almost expect it to
have taken more to really
taking a good step away from those
trades especially because they're
recessive if like they're all herming on
the first generation
right yeah i'm gonna say
you could do it in four or five
generations i reckon
interesting and depend depending on what
you're starting with
yeah yeah yeah and so
i guess if we jump back to strain
hunters for a moment do you think there
is
there is any real pure land races left
or they've just
all been diluted in one form or another
i think a lot of places have been
diluted for a long time
um other small
islands and maybe hard to get to
places have still got things and
even if it's only one or two
packets that have been brought to these
places
and then introduced natural selection
again will get rid of them
and they'll revert back to their sort of
almost natural sort of stuff anyway
so um i think there are still some
places out there with
some uh land race strains
what places would you like to go and
search for some land races
i think maybe some uh indian genetics
would be nice to
add yeah i think india would be maybe a
nice place to go and
collect some seeds is that just because
you're into hash
um yeah i think the whole hash thing
um the culture
yeah it'd be interesting to see it all
and uh
collect some seeds from that next on the
list after that would probably be uh
south america and just to see some of
the stuff there
um yeah
okay how do you feel about strains that
throw nana's at like the end of the
cycle
you know the ones that do it rather
predictably do you feel like that's a
negative trait or it's just kind of like
something you deal with yeah i don't see
it as a problem
um i find that sometimes
i see it from the agent orange before
but they were always unfertile um
and never ever made seeds you could even
pick them out and try and make a seed
from them and they just wouldn't
pollinate so
um and it's almost like a natural
defense if you've pushed a plant out and
you get a few nana's at the top and that
i i i don't see it as a
as a huge problem yeah another one i
wanted to run by you is
i myself have seen a bunch of plants be
revedged before and when i say revenge i
mean
they've been taken more or less full
flower
and just trying to re-veg from that
point do you feel like when you do that
often it's kind of detrimental to the
plant in that the plants may be
not quite the same as when it was first
flowered out do you like do you tend to
lose any traits from re-veging or do you
find that's not the case
um i think that depends on the genetics
um i've seen
like things where uh me or a friend was
veg stuff out
uh re-badged and um taking clones again
growing those plants out and they've
been identical
so um i think genetic drift
in general can happen
down to genetics and the health of the
plant in general
so if you can reverse that plant and get
it healthy
nice clones coming off of it
then i think you'll get good results
back again
so do you agree with the idea expressed
by many of our guests
in that a poor clone room in terms of
the quality
results in a degradation of quality over
time
yeah if you're taking clones of poor
mothers
then yeah i've seen it with the cheese
clone
in the uk and people taking clones off
it clones off it and when they start
taking clones off
poor mothers i start seeing
um the outcome
like the plants don't bubble up like
they normally do they don't fill out
like they normally do
maybe the buds are a little bit smaller
um
even down to like taste and smell can be
lacking
so it can happen over time so
keeping your mothers uh healthy
is key definitely and so you mentioned
earlier that you're organics and you're
really into that now what type of
growing
style do you use specifically you know
what are you feeding your plants what
are you feeding your mothers to keep
them healthy what are you
giving them in all regards okay
um before i was doing it mainly with a
cocoa and bottled nutrients
um but uh now
i'm back to organics i'm using a lot of
like uh
slow release um powdered
organic sort of amendments um
making like some ferments
uh aloe vera i use that a lot in coconut
water
um bean ferments
uh what else if i can get nettles
that depends on time of year um make
some nettle tea
comfrey tea stuff like this um
but yeah um going on
those along those lines now um
outdoors i've always done it organic and
always indoors i've always done organic
until i
come out to spain really so it's only
been the last couple of years i did the
coco
um but also a
good way to test test plants yeah
just quickly touch on the outdoors are
you enjoying the outdoors more
i mean given you're into your hat i
imagine you would that's something i've
always seemed to notice
people say that the outdoor hash is
unbeatable because even though you know
maybe the bud doesn't look quite as good
as indoor because you know there's a bit
of dirt a bit of wind and all that
that you know the trichome heads are
still perfect and you know the sun
spectrum is number one
so how do you feel about it or where
does the outdoors sit for you
yeah i think the sun
light depth weed is uh
by far the best that you can get
the sun produces like
terpenes that you just don't get when
you do it indoors
i think indoors
organic you can achieve similar outcomes
but still not like like the sun
um i think
um chemical fertilizers or like
mineral salts or whatever and they can
produce like maybe
a little bit stronger weed but the turps
outdoor under the sun
is the way forward um i've been getting
into a couple of books from uh
jeff lowenfels and
uh what's the other guy called something
lewis
um but they're like the teaming with
microbes
and teaming with fungi teaming with
nutrients
and they've been uh really good books
um putting into practice a lot of
knowledge i've gained over the years
through like sort of growing like a
permaculture
type garden vegetables in that sort of
style a lot of companion planting anyway
so
it's good to put all this into practice
now with cannabis outside
and the garden outdoors this year is
just looking amazing
yeah so that's something you mentioned
to me earlier that you do grow a lot of
food and stuff and i think you even said
you keep some bees you know
how does all that play into things do
you think that people do grow
organically should try to make an effort
to grow their own food and things like
that seeing as
they've got the skills and often a lot
of the uh the inputs as well
um yeah like bees i used to keep bees
when i was living in the uk
and now that i've moved to spain i i've
stopped keeping bees
um but growing food i think everybody
should grow their own food
um or try it like what it comes down to
is where you live
and land a lot of people don't have the
land a lot of people don't have the time
to do it um but if you have the time and
you've got the land there
definitely gross grow some food
you've got the skills so put it put it
put it into practice yeah
and a lot of people grow organic but
then they don't eat organic food so
you know going along those lines as well
when you're growing your own food
and you know everything that's gone into
it
do you feel like you do have like a
better
view on the whole plant now that you do
do it organically like i guess what i'm
trying to say is
a lot of people say to me when they grow
organically they feel kind of more in
tune with their plants
not in necessarily like this weird hokey
pokey spiritual way
but in a sense of like you know they
really understand the cycle they
understand how it's all working whereas
the stuff in bottles can still be a bit
smoke and mirrors at times
do you feel like you have that better
link with your plants in
either way whether it be spiritual or
just like you know a more fundamental
understanding of the cogs and wheels
yeah like organically it teaches you
everything about
how that soil works how that plant works
um and when you're actually making all
these things yourself
this is what so many people are missing
out on on is the actual understanding of
what they're feeding their plants
so many people grow and don't even know
what mpk is
and it's just like yeah you need to be
understanding it
all of this stuff and organic really
teaches you that
and yeah being around your plants
all the time making these things feeding
it too and that's
that's another connection with with
nature and that whole cycle
i think it was jeremy from builder soil
who said there's a certain
romance about the end quality product of
organics do you feel the same
um yeah definitely definitely it has
something special about it
when it's organic sun grown
it it it's at its most natural way of
how it should be
um you're getting everything
yeah it it's just the perfect way
basically
so you mentioned earlier that you do a
lot of your own ferments and things like
that now
do you get much into the whole knf type
of thing or you just kind of starting to
dip your water
dip your toes sorry into the whole water
of all the various ferments and how that
interacts with it all
yeah i'm just like this is what i'm
looking into
more because before i came out to spain
when i was doing organics before
a lot of it was a lot of bottled feeds
yeah i'd like
use some slow release powdered
amendments and stuff like that
but this way of doing it is is is
well i used to do nettle teas with the
garden and comfrey teas and stuff like
that
but then this whole uh
fermenting and stuff like that this is
all new
definitely so i'm looking into all this
now
and what some of the uh the newest
products or
ideas you're looking to delve into or
implement in your own garden
um yeah like you were saying then build
the soil and stuff like that i've been
looking into a few of these other
companies
that do these uh amendments and
definitely trying to use a few
uh broader variety of things in in my
feeds and soil mixes
uh and even composting uh
i'm starting to do a lot more composting
and
i used to have worm farm and stuff like
that like in the uk
quite a few bins of worms and i think i
need to get
more into that so yeah definitely
look towards that does the
spanish scene have you know like a build
a soil equivalent is there a place where
you can get all of the amendments you're
after or is it still a bit of a struggle
no there's nothing like that this is
what i've sort of
it definitely needs uh it's lacking on
that side
but as progression happens more of these
stores will start to get these products
i'd like to see a store that only stocks
organic products i've not seen that so
far i think that would be a
a really good thing to do out here in
spain yeah because all of these products
are hard to get
and it's quite a big agricultural
industry over here
um but they like to spray a lot of
chemicals and chemical fertilizers on
everything
so yeah i love how your voice just like
trailed off
so how would you describe the scene in
general in spain is it mostly people
growing organic outdoors given there's
the availability or is it pretty well
infiltrated by that
commercial scene as you referenced with
the synthetics
no like any of the commercial
um standard of spanish
uh cannabis is is quite
low really i don't know how they're
growing it but everything has a certain
smell or taste to it when i see it so
i'm not too sure what some of these
people do use
um but yeah
not organic but then everybody that
grows for themselves
on a personal level tends to go down the
organic line
um which is good a bit of a weird
political question
what would you rather do would you
rather live in a situation where
it's illegal but you're growing your own
or it's legal but the only people
supplying it are like you know big
corporations and there's a lot of
question marks over the quality
and you know kind of safety checks in
the whole process
if it has to be legalized to be
normalized
and not be felt like a criminal
then that's the line we have to go down
but
decriminalizing it is the way forward
um but then yeah i just
it's it's a it's a hard question that
but
yeah i think it needs to go legal and uh
be um
i don't think he should be put in the
government's hands like i think there's
enough people out there that can there's
ways of regulating it in different ways
yeah that's not how it will go well i
mean just touching on the idea of
regulation you referenced earlier that
you think the price of weed should go
down let's just move that idea over to
seeds though we're seeing
a general increase in the price of seeds
as time goes by
some say it's in accordance with
inflation
others say it's getting out of hand in
some
in some respects how do you feel about
that and you know do you think there
should be some regulation on the price
of seeds ultimately
um the seeds are worth what what people
can sell them for
yeah um my seeds i think in general are
quite
cheap um i think i could even maybe
lower the price a little bit
um depending on how much work was
involved in each strain
um some feminized strains don't produce
many seeds
so you have to charge a bit more and
but then uh i think it's gone crazy with
like when people are
charging 300 400 500
a packet but then
it's the market that people pay this
um and then people think if something's
and something's 50 the 500 one's got to
be better
so people buy by price
i think so many people we do it in the
shops we do it with food
we do it with clothes and
so people do it with seeds
and so do you think that there are
or should i say do you think that there
is a max price which no one should go
over
or do you think it's just really like
you know if you want it and you'll need
to pay
go for it um
i'd pay uh a high amount for a special
packet
um of something old maybe
so this place wasn't about anymore well
yeah if i play devil's advocate do you
remember
uh starfighter you know that that there
was some auctions for a while and that
got
you know very expensive very quickly um
you know do you think that was out of
hand or like that's the type of thing
which merits
what you're talking about um
yeah auctions are different and i
remember when the
it was i think it was the alien
technology went on to auction
and that it was like when it was crazy
prices for a packet
but people have used that in the future
for breeding stock
i had a good little story behind it um
so yeah um certain things sell
um but to have a release
of and if you've got thousands of
packets
and you're charging a huge amount for
each
packet and i think that's down to morals
isn't it
a topic you just briefly touched on
auctions
we've seen a dramatic rise in the number
of auctions especially on instagram
recently
how do you feel about this does it feel
like we have too many auctions er
auction's a bad thing
i guess the thing i noticed mostly is
that people will often discredit really
expensive purchases and say oh yeah but
it was for an auction so you know it's
kind of like different rules or it's in
play right now
but i mean if they're just constantly
happening is it not the new norm
are you talking like charity auctions or
is it like
yeah the majority of them are charity
auctions i mean i
i don't think i've really seen that okay
yeah for charity but yeah it seems like
they're just
non-stop now on instagram wherever you
look
right i remember a couple popping up and
i
donated some seeds and stuff like this
and i remember checking and go for like
crazy price for one packet um
but then it's for a good cause and
if there's more and more and more of
them popping up
maybe people need to look into it a
little bit more about
you know but yeah i don't see it as a
bad thing
if it's the charity and it's for a good
cause
and people do it all the time with other
other other industries
and people who hold options and parties
and stuff like that
and so uh
yeah why not do it with some seeds as
well if it goes to a good cause
yeah no worries all righty last question
for the extended response
is breeding an art or a science you know
do you think that you could pass all
your knowledge onto someone or at the
end of the day you need to have a
certain
something within you you know like a
sense or a knack
whatever it may be you want to call it
do you think that yeah
it's it's an art or it's a science
um i'd say it's a mix of both yeah
um it's just things that you've learned
along the way and some things can't even
be explained it's just through
things that you've seen um but
definitely you can
teach people a lot and save them a lot
of time
by telling them what you know um
so i'd say it's a it's a mix of both
definitely
it's a bit of art and a bit of science
all mixed in
okay awesome so now for our last little
quick
fire segment first question
if you go back to one place in time in
history anywhere you want
where would you go and what land race
seeds would you be after
okay um
[Music]
oh the 60s yeah
um afghanistan um
[Music]
and maybe some old persian seeds would
be nice
yeah oh exotic that sounds good
okay what's the worst thing to happen
to the eu scene since you've been active
in it you know so not just since you
moved to spain
since you've you know been essentially
online or even just talking to people
down the block
um
[__] feminized seeds
ones that just don't even smell and
taste good
and so what's your current favorite
strain
um from i'll say from this year out of
my things
jungle juice and
jungle kush out of other people's stuff
i like baldi's soul mate this year
and south fork seeds cherry chem
they're the things that are standing out
this year from outdoors
and what's your favorite of all time
oh i'm really happy to have the bubba
kush back
just had that back so i'm looking
forward to that at the moment
um yeah
the list is too long just to pick one
but i'm happy to get the bubba back
and i think uh
sfvog cushion yeah
sfv and bubba yeah yeah a lot of people
love the sfv don't they
so next question though what is the
worst strain
you've ever had the privilege of trying
or growing
um oh
i've grown a few packets of uh
greenhouse stuff that a friend gave me
that it weren't very good
um what else
something that i bought okay i bought a
packet of
soma seeds nyc diesel expecting a nice
nyc
diesel thing and didn't find
[Music]
the nyc diesel i was looking for that
was a little bit disappointing i suppose
um but yeah
um i think
random seeds that people give you and
you think okay i'll try it out
years ago and you just find a lot of
[__] stuff from that as well
yeah so what's the biggest mistake
you see people making when they're
growing
um
over feeding yeah um
giving the plant too many bottled feeds
thinking that
this is gonna do this this is gonna do
that that's gonna do that
and they end up with weed that's had a
build-up
doesn't burn very well um
yeah so i think
people that add too much to the plant
and what's a little breeding tip for all
the aspiring breeders out there
um pick your favorite female
one that you've worked with a while um
any packet of seeds that you've grown
out that you find in
a lot of females you like collect a
little bit of pollen
dust it on something and grow those
seeds out
give them out for free you know um
yeah i think that's the best best tip
awesome so i think that one just about
wraps it up for us
thanks so much bananame coming on the
show and dropping all the knowledge on
us is there any shout outs or comments
you wanted to make
um no i'd just like to yeah thank you
for having me on the show
um there's too many people to mention
uh i'd like to thank anyone that's grown
up my
strains uh over the last couple years
sent me pictures posted pictures up
online
and entered into cups all of these
people these people make a difference um
yeah thank you for growing my stuff
awesome thanks so much for coming on
again nice one thank you
[Music]
alrighty so a big big big big thank you
to banana man
thanks for stopping by chatting
a big big big thank you to 420 australia
and ogs
two companies that are the lifeblood of
this show as well as our patreon fans
these guys contribute in more ways than
you'll ever know and they're all getting
great prizes for it feel free to check
it out if you're interested or if you
need an extra fix of the podcast
otherwise we'll see you
[Music]
lalalala
lala
[Music]
you