foreign
[Music]
podcast for budding enthusiasts
as always you're joined by your host
heavy days here from the upside down
library and we want to give thanks to
our amazing sponsors who helped make the
show happen stay tuned now your number
one seed bank in the game all the
hottest drops the latest hits if it's
fire breeding they got it they offer a
guarantee not only on germination but
also satisfaction so if you're unhappy
at the end of your growth shoot him a
message they'll sort you out what more
could you want
likewise huge shout out to our other
fantastic sponsors coppet biological
systems these guys have all the best
Predators feeds beneficial microbes to
keep your garden happy and healthy I've
got issues with mites check out their
spydex vital good issue with asses check
out the appy param all of them are
industry-leading predators proof of
predation technology and we'll work
together to help ensure your next
Harvest is the best today check out
copper biological systems guys they're
my pick for all your beneficial
Predators bugs feeds and more
likewise huge shout out to our friends
at Top Shelf seed bank in Australia if
you're looking for seeds in Australia
check out talktel seed bank number one
in the game customer service on point I
stock my seeds there check them out
[Music]
and last but not least huge shout out to
the patreon gang you are the lifeblood
of the show you helped to ensure
episodes keep happening thank you so
much for your ongoing support and I hope
you enjoy getting access to early
content additional episodes giveaways
Discord so much more
on this episode we're joined by the
Australian local Legend Wally Ducks who
made up one half of the Wizards of Oz a
breed of collaboration based out of
Australia as well as being a mod on the
IC mag forums for years a very
well-known figure in the Australian
cannabis scene and worldwide for
bringing strains such as z99 Ducks foot
Zoid fuel hybrids and so many more we
are incredibly grateful to have Wally on
this episode to chat all things history
Australian politics
[Music]
law
equatorial settings
and so much more
let's get into it
alrighty gang we're back for another one
and on this episode we're joined by one
of the true ogs from the Australian
cannabis scene one half of The Wizard of
Oz and a very highly requested guest
indeed a big welcome to Wally duck for
coming on the show thanks for joining us
yeah thanks for having me on
no worries my friend uh question we
normally ask people to start off is what
have you been smoking on recently
um nothing I I gave up about two years
ago and
um I share a lot of weed still but and I
enjoy seeing people's reactions to it
but yeah I don't I don't hope at all
myself anymore uh 40 Years of bonging
took its toll
oh God I love it that's that's some
serious passion there and I it's
interesting you bring that up because I
think there's some people in the
community who would probably really
struggle to um to sort of identify with
how that must feel like as you said you
know to 40 years to be so involved and
to sort of give it up did you find that
like really real like you know is that
like the hardest thing you've ever had
to do or is just one of those things
that you know you sort of got on with
and did
oh no it was really hard after so long
of doing something you know I go I was I
was awaken bike guy too I was up at 5 30
every morning having a few bombs cutting
my head off and
oh yeah well you got me curious now you
know what what was the uh the rocket
fuel for the day I'm hoping it was
something sativa if it was early in the
morning oh almost always almost always
yeah that's that's my go-to for sure
uh I love it was there was there
anything specific that was like the
go-to morning smoke or it just sort of
varied with what was on offer in terms
of harvest yeah exactly with the Harvest
but I tell you what I really like I had
some Lao uh that I grew for a while
before I stopped and um that was by far
my favorite uh it did it didn't it
wasn't like zero to a hundred and three
seconds it gently took you there you
know uh and it let you down gently there
was no lag afterwards it was uh
you still got us high but um you know it
was easy on you and uh definitely the
way to start the morning
wow you've uh you've caught me out I'm
not familiar with loud I've just quickly
tapped away on Google is it is it the
one from loud seeds
no we got it from uh one of our friends
from the forums uh he Loops out in uh
food on Tani in Thailand beside Lao and
uh he wrote it as some of the best
sativa he'd had so
yeah he sent me some seeds I grew it and
um I grew a fair bit of it I I kept a
cutting and uh we just kept pumping it
out for a while
uh amazing and and now I have to own up
for being a real Goose I thought you
said loud with like a d on the end if
you meant Lao like yeah yeah the the
Southeast Asian variety go duh sorry of
course
that's that's cool to hear okay and uh
and and what was the variety like was it
like more like what people might think
of like a typical Southeast Asian like a
Thai Cambodian sort of thing or how
would you describe it in like flavor and
effect
oh yeah it reminded me a lot of Ty it
just didn't seem as potent off the bat
you know what I mean it did instant
smash you uh but um like I said it was a
bit gentle on you and that's what I
enjoyed about it I was getting older I
didn't need that you know zero to 103
second kind of gear uh
yeah for sure look you know no one needs
to be smoking like A5 or C5 first thing
in the morning I bet that's cool that's
cool and something I've always been
interested in is I've always heard
speculations around the true lineage of
Cali Miss and I've heard people even
throw like Lao and Cambodian sort of
names in the mix have you ever had any
experience with the the infamous Cali
mist and any sort of ideas around what
the genetics might be
oh yeah we tried it we grew some here
and um I really liked it it was strong
good good weed
um the the lineage I no idea but um it
was familiar to me that's for sure it
quite quite likely did have some
Southeast Asian in there
nice okay well I mean before I forget
out of all the sort of Southeast Asian
varieties you've tried what are what are
some of the most memorable ones to you
oh I'd have to be Thai yeah
I grew up on that I that was the first
weed I ever smoked and we smoked a fair
bit of it and um there was uh just Thai
sticks when I started and um they
actually made me sick the first time I
smoked bombs I was throwing up but I
went back for more
I love it so it's funny you mentioned
that because before you even said it I
was sort of thinking to myself you know
you hear these stories of people getting
sick off the Thai sticks and some have
even gone so far as to throw the idea
out there that like maybe they had some
sort of opium on them or you know
whether it's wives tale or not have you
ever heard or thought anything about
those rumors yeah yeah we've had big
debates about that I I don't I don't
think so uh I I think for uh you know
inexperienced people that are not used
to that that sort of weed it was really
strong and um
yeah I threw up a fair bit but uh no I
went back again
I love that I love that real men go back
okay that's cool that's cool and I mean
before I forget I just wanted to ask you
I heard from someone I can't remember
who it was so apologies whoever told me
this but they said that when you're
dealing with people who have lots of
pain a lot of people think oh you know
give them an Indica that's pain killing
but then they were like that's actually
not true you're probably actually better
to give them like something really
sativa because the way it like is
stimulating and creative it's actually
better to be distracted from the pain
than to sort of have something that's
like an analgesic for the pain have you
ever thought anything along those lines
have you ever thought like maybe sativas
are actually better for pain killing
properties than people sort of let on or
what's your thoughts
my mum she had um pretty severe um
lung problems and um I used to give a
harsh a lot to make Cups of Tea with and
coffee and she ended up biting it too
but
um it was mostly sativa because that's
that's what I like and uh yeah she said
just the way it makes you feel the
happiness the Euphoria you know what I
mean that that's what was getting her
along she said oh there was nothing else
to live for apart from do you know I
don't know being a bit happy uh I don't
think Indica would have done that for
him might have helped her with the pain
but um as far as uh you know your
well-being you
your sense of happiness that sort of
thing I I totally agree so type is
great for that iron
yeah yeah that's cool to hear and you
know uh thanks for sharing that sort of
personal story just to loop back a
question you mentioned you know the
first thing you smoke was Ty the other
question we normally ask people first is
tell me about your first experience with
cannabis you know like paint me a
picture how did it go down
um
joints with my brother-in-law I was
about 14 and um I was just sitting here
I
my sister said I wasn't allowed to smoke
any weed till I was 16. but uh my
brother-in-law obviously had other ideas
and uh he passed me the joint I smoked
the whole thing I didn't even do
anything to me and um I smoked too and I
was still
sober you know and uh he said he wasn't
going to give me any more
he said I better get up and go and do
something you know to activate myself
then get get it going you know and
um I stepped into the kitchen which was
a step down and it hit me then and it
was just I was in a different place
altogether it was uh fantastic actually
I I had the most delicious lamb roast
I'd ever eaten that night
[Laughter]
oh my God please for all of our
International listeners I've been told
on good authority not many people eat
lamb outside of Australia eat some lamb
it's so bloody good oh you can't go
wrong can you it's my favorite meat you
know my my partner will kill me because
she swears up and down pork's better but
I'm like no lamb for life
okay and so
um at that time was there still like a
commercial Thai stick input being
brought in yes
I think it did it kind of uh it stopped
not long after that but um we had
another like up to about I think it was
like 84 or early 85 we had some um stuff
they call Golden Buddha it was golden
Thai and uh
oh that was beautiful lovely but I
remember clearly uh
super strong I'd say it was strong in
the Thai sticks yeah
wow that yeah that's that's seriously
strong and I mean there's been ongoing
discussion for forever but I'm you know
you've grown a lot of these sort of
Southeast Asian varieties yourself do
you feel like you were ever able to
replicate the flavor and effect you got
from the input or like the terroir just
really can't be replicated in that sense
uh not not that I lived in Melbourne
back then so we didn't have much chance
of trying to replicate you know a
tropical variety outdoors and we were
growing Outdoors so
um up here though
up in Queensland North Queensland there
was stuff that was very similar to those
Thai sticks uh I had some a few years
after I'd first tried weed
um that my mum sent me actually and um I
remember riding my push bike and I think
it was the fastest I'd ever gotten from
A to B you know
[Laughter]
Little Wally duck just fanging it down
the road
that's awesome okay cool cool cool well
yeah I mean up north in like far North
Queensland do you feel like the
conditions are similar enough that you
can essentially replicate sort of you
know those Thai varieties
oh where I live is exactly the same
latitude as where they grow a lot of
that Thai stick it's like 17 degrees
which is the same as udontani which is
where a lot of that stuff around those
provinces came from so
yeah you can definitely replicate it
down the road there's a climate that's
exactly the same as Thailand it's dry a
little bit arid uh hot uh I think the
average temperature is like about 29 All
Year lovely
yeah it's not like that where I live I
get a bit too much Coastal sort of
influence where I am sometimes it's good
you know sometimes we have a nice end to
the monsoon season but others keep
drizzling on and on and uh yeah the
weight doesn't like it
interesting and I mean before we go too
much into the Australian medicinal scene
out of curiosity are there any
operations up there that you're aware of
taking advantage of these conditions
no there was a bit of hemp being grown
but it was pretty haphazard the way they
were doing it so I don't know whether
much was well it might have been just
trial crops I don't know I know they
tried some hemp up here I think it was
just for fiber it did very well but um
otherwise now I I'm not aware of any any
weed being grown up here for any legal
stuff anyway
yeah it's interesting because uh I think
it yeah like as much as it might be sort
of left of field and maybe not
marketably viable at the moment there is
a huge demand internationally for uh
these Southeast Asian varieties grown in
that actual sort of latitude as near as
close to the actual origin as you can
get and I was thinking maybe that's the
answer I mean unless unless Thailand
steamrolls ahead with all their sort of
plans and actually starts exporting
yeah they probably will they like a few
dollars those guys yeah yeah I mean I I
think you'd mentioned to me in a in a
prior conversation that you you were
keeping an eye on the Thai scene do you
have any predictions or hopes for how
that turns out
I'd love to see it return to what it was
but I think it's going to take a bit of
searching for them to get that original
stuff back again it's it's been over 40
years so
I I don't hold out hope that they can
find exactly the same stuff initially
they're going to have to do a bit of
selection
yeah wow I mean it's such a you just
made me realize that like of course the
Thai government doesn't have really sick
Thai seeds in a seed bank somewhere like
yeah you're right they're just gonna go
there and assume that what they've got
is probably the real deal
um it makes me wonder you know do you
think that those varieties were lost
just like over the years and just
non-selective breeding or do you think
it was more like the sort of Strain
Hunters going in and giving out
feminized seeds sort of thing that
caused it to be lost
nah I think it was just time I don't I
don't think that that I've seen people
on like Facebook Thai people they they
grow all sorts of different weed but I
think they know to keep do you know what
I mean keep them separated a bit I I
know they probably crossed them in that
but they're not silly you know they know
that they've got something special in
that stuff so I think they do keep it
separate uh but there's lots of
different word there but the bulk of it
seems to be um
the uh the stuff available on the street
for instance is is I think Lao everyone
seems to agree uh it's it's compressed
brick sort of stuff and
um everyone seems to agree that it's
likely from Lao it's it's quite some of
it's quite good
foreign
it's interesting because when you talk
to a lot of Australians I guess you know
the ones I'm talking to aren't
necessarily super plugged into the
Cannabis scene but they smoke weed at
least every now and again and my friends
who have been over there would sort of
say like oh you know like you can score
it at a pub or whatever but it's not
it's nothing good I'm guessing that's
not the stuff you're talking about
I think I think it varies with quality
do you know what I mean some some that's
good so we had some that was so sticky
that it when you poured it into the bowl
or where it still moved around by it by
itself you've seen stuff do that before
yeah well like static or something yeah
that's cool they call it dancing Thai
they call them and um yeah it was pretty
potent stuff I I don't think it compared
with the tie stick but uh it was still
quite good weed
yeah well okay and I mean just as a
purely hypothetical if if you had been
contracted by the Thai government to go
over there and to just get it all sorted
for them would you be like thinking I
need to go around to different farms and
collect some different stock or instead
would you be like you know what probably
gonna have better chance just asking
some like old Forum heads for like their
Thai seed stock instead
uh uh probably some of the aisle to say
but it it's probably probably growing in
Lao as well uh it's it's only next door
the seed would have absolutely ended up
there too and they still grow plenty of
weed there so
I think you can run your backyard like
always have been able to and Lao there's
been no restriction you know you can
grow a few plants no one cares so yeah
that's cool and I mean I'd heard some
people say that like some of the parts
of like that whole Golden Triangle in
that area
um because they like over the years were
so heavily populated by like militia and
stuff that they probably were less
polluted the genetics so to speak that
were there because you know they were
probably focusing on on like you know
opium and stuff but I'd always got told
that they were still [ __ ] with
cannabis around those areas as well do
you know anything about that or not
specifically no not really I know that
where I go I I visited on Tani quite a
bit whenever I can and um the people I
hang out with they don't like cannabis
a lot of tires they they really frown
upon it uh it's just like the the farmer
types the you know that that get into a
bit of weed the the hard-working guy do
you know what I mean he finishes his day
he goes home he relaxes with a few bongs
and um yeah that's so interesting to
hear yeah because I I mean not like it's
a revolutionary statement but yeah like
a lot of a lot of Asian cultures in
general sort of view weed as like you
know it makes you lazy it's not good we
don't like it
I think they'd think it's a bit
low-class to do that you know what I
mean that's you're just a low-class
farmer you sort of worker guy and
ah okay yeah that that makes sense
doesn't it
that that's interesting impression I get
from the ties I I hang out with I talk
to them about and they said no you're
not coming here and doing that not not
around us
wow would you say that in general
they're sort of more into stimulants or
just like alcohol or like nothing
no nothing they're pretty straight yeah
yeah okay well there you go I mean I
guess it must be an interesting
experience for you to go over there now
when you're not smoking or consuming
compared to back in the day like you're
probably seeing and doing different
things
yeah absolutely
um I I go there for the food you've
eaten Thai food yeah yeah I can only
imagine how good the food you've had is
yeah and the lifestyle it's really nice
I enjoy it there it's a great place even
without weed
yeah yeah that's awesome to hear okay
cool well let's get back on track
because we had a nice little little
detour there tell me a little bit about
your first grow do you remember the
strain you were growing or do you
remember like what sort of Technology
you were using was it outdoor tell me a
little bit about it
yeah it was outdoor and it was just bag
seed that my my older brother-in-law had
collected and um it was light harvesting
so I guess it was probably more sativa a
bit of purple stuff amongst it a bit of
hermaphrodite
and um
really tall they grew up huge there was
a what about uh Ash Wednesday fires in
in around Melbourne there it was just
after that so
1984 I guess uh
and um
it was long time harvesting I took it
took forever yeah so I I it wasn't
really the correct stuff and um it's not
like we we could pick and choose back
then like we can now you know
yeah yeah wow like the the OG trim jail
took forever
and we mustn't Trend much of it to like
we do now that's for sure we must have
been a bit lazy with it because I don't
remember lots and lots of trimming then
you know what I feel like maybe I'm
maybe I was meant for back then because
I feel like as time goes by I trim less
like I'm just like I'm smoking it
whatever I'll do it at the time like
there you go okay and then so what was
the progression then from like you know
sort of first grow to like being really
in the thick of it and being like yeah
like I really like doing this
uh I I just did hobby growing because I
liked smoking so it wasn't until
probably
um
oh the late 90s early 2000s that I got
fairly serious about it and started to
grow a fair bit of weed
yeah at night and were you still down in
Victoria or had you moved up north by
then I was up north by then yeah
and I was always worried about the laws
here the laws have always been so strict
you know but um
tell me a bit about it because uh I'm
sure there's a lot of people who aren't
aware like what was the legal climate
like say in the mid to late 90s for a
cannabis grower
I think it had improved at that point
but earlier on I guess probably in the
80s when Joe Bugatti Peterson was the
premier they were they were giving you
life in jail for uh production of
cannabis it was really serious you know
I don't know why they did that but uh
so you didn't want to get caught even
with just a few ounces of weed you'd go
to jail for a fair while
and um yeah it did change and I think at
some point I know I got caught so a
number of times in fact so I think
eventually it actually lessened then you
know it was less than down south and I
don't know why but uh
the party a political party of the day
the laws changed whatever but um
it's not so bad these days uh I think a
fair bit of weed and um I'm still here
that's that's good if if you can make it
through we're all gonna make it
okay so at the time let's say like let's
let's start at like you know the late
80s early 90s when it was like you know
quite illegal I'm guessing you weren't
looking online for a friend you were
like I'm just keeping to myself and
staying out of jail or what was it like
I never even came online until
um
oh it must have been
early 2000 2001 2000 2001 something like
that and um
I found this uh actually a lady in
Africa and
um she was selling weed online which I
never thought had happened you know I
didn't think we could buy it you know
but she said look it's so cheap why not
give it a go and you might get it I'll
see all right I'll give it a go and it
arrived and um so I I did a little bit
of business with her I traded Sage with
her and uh she sent me hash and weed and
and it all got here yeah
oh yeah it was it was good stuff because
I mean you know outside of Durban you
don't really hear about a lot of South
African weed
I I can't remember I think she was in
Cape Town maybe but um
and she had a variety of weight the way
yeah it was a bit average but the stuff
I Grew From it was pretty nice I grew
some decentness and swazi uh it was
beautiful such a really nice high on it
uh euphoric and you know that feel good
stuff which is actually my go-to I love
that sort of stuff you know
yeah wow pure swazi back in the day what
a treat damn jealous okay
um so before but let's let's wind back
to just before you got online you know
let's say it's year 2000. did you know
anyone else who was growing or you were
really sort of like on your own doing
your own thing
oh it was just locals uh there's there's
always been a growing scene up here
where I live
um
it's been pretty popular for a long time
uh so Local's just sharing knowledge and
sharing seeds and um
it was just bag scene too mostly
whatever we could get you know it was a
bit of a hit and miss thing
yeah okay and I mean out of curiosity
was there ever a sort of a definitive
point where you feel like indicas were
introduced because you know you hear the
Californian guys talk about like they
were like you know it was all Mexican
and sativa and then the hippies brought
the afghanis in in like the late 70s or
something like that do you ever remember
that happening for Far North Queensland
now I would have been down south but
when I was a young fella I um I would
have been I don't know about 15 or
whatever I remember um we we grew that
Chicago like I said and I hadn't seen
any short fast flowering sorts of stuff
at that time but um
there was a news report
from Mildura where they found a whole
bunch of uh weed and the plants were
three or four foot tall and just one
huge bud no branching uh I'd say that
was indica
that I guess yeah yeah yeah well and I I
guess you probably hadn't really seen
anything like that no I was really
surprised actually but then we we grew
like after that you know bits and pieces
and uh there was definitely hybrids
amongst it uh it wasn't all sativa I
started growing indoors and we were
successful and some with it was taller
stuff they were shorter stuff you know
there was a variety of and I'm certain
that quite a bit of it would have been
hybrid stuff hybrids of those indicas
and the survivors we had so
uh but there I don't remember any
specific point where that happened I I
was probably too young
yeah sure so sounds like you're sorted
with that generation that bridged you
know like the old and the new world sort
of stuff which is really cool to get
your perspective on
um out of curiosity were you aware of
any of the international seed banks you
know I'm sure like
the the seed bank and Scentsy seeds and
stuff in the mid 90s were doing their
thing did you know about them or you
were like just like now we just work
with what we got
oh yeah we we got scum when I guess it
was
would have been the 90s early 90s and um
people started growing indoors they've
been a a real drought between the uh
imported stuff and you know
um Australia having to look after their
own sales with the with weed and um the
price of weed went to like 750 an ounce
at one point
it was ridiculous and that was like
probably for about a year before
you know everyone got lights I guess and
decided [ __ ] we gotta get our gear
together here
yeah
you know so
um and yeah that not long after that
that's when we saw our first skunks and
uh and Northern Lights I I bought a fair
bit of it because uh
I might have some Colombian pride of
that some Colombian gold and to be
honest the the look of the skunk
reminded me of that the high didn't the
the look of it it was golden looking you
know it was really nice looking stuff it
stunk
was it that you know because there's
obviously that never-ending debate about
roadkill skunk and I guess I'm wondering
do you remember there being like a
particularly acrid skunkiness to it or
was it more the sweet stuff that you
hear about
well I've never smelled a skunk but um
that first stuff we got it it it
permeated it's it really you couldn't
keep it in your pocket in the car you
couldn't take it anywhere it was strong
smelling and um I don't know whether it
came from seeds from Neville I I'm
actually certain the first stuff we've
tried called uh it was called kalska in
California then and that didn't come
from any seed bank I'm pretty sure they
had friends in California that they got
the and that was a little bit different
to be honest but um
yeah the smell and like I don't I don't
know about roadkill skunk I I'd have to
smell it to know that you know so uh
yeah yeah look I when I was in the
states a few years ago I uh I managed to
to drive past the Dead one and pull over
and smell it and it's large it's largely
like just a really acrid rotten garlic
smell like like ammonia and garlic like
makes your nostrils flare and that you
know like sometimes how you'd smoke a
strain you'd exhale and it really coats
your mouth and your nostrils flare and
you get like a bit almost like you've
got like something sour in your mouth
yeah like that's sort of what the skunk
thing does but that's interesting to
hear you know it sounds like you had
some pretty OG stuff
um especially if you could really see
that Colombian in it which is which is
neat right
um what was your thoughts on the NL you
know we've had such a Resurgence of NL
over the past 15 20 years do you look
back fondly on it or do you just think
oh you know it's just another one of the
strains at the time
yeah I I didn't write it that I really
like the scarf to be honest I didn't
think the Northern Lights was just nice
so I bought a fair bit of it but um
no I didn't uh I prefer the skunk to be
honest yeah
there was a novel for us just to have
those sorts of things after what we had
had you know
for sure for sure so continuing on right
you've you've just come online what was
the first thing that happened online was
it discovering one of the big forums and
you're like oh wow like there's this
whole Community or or was it more like
you discovered some local people via
some other means how did it all go down
online
I think I met a guy on
um I think there's a forum called Sweet
Leaf or something like that that's where
I'm at that
um African lady and um and I had I had
Oxford Shades and I wanted to know more
about
uh where they come from because I'd
never seen cannabis like that before and
that that's the reason I went on the
forums and
um then when a few of them saw they said
they'd never seen it either obviously so
uh one thing led to another and um
I was on overgrowth
that's what I learned yeah let me pull
you back before we jump into overgrow
because everyone's so fond about it we
we had a lot of viewers ask about your
Ducks foot and I guess you know you
could boil it down to one or two sort of
questions everyone's asking in different
forms but it was sort of like you know
first off how did you get access to the
Ducks footer originally
oh a friend showed it to me he described
it a couple of times to me not very well
uh he just said it was a a strain with
three fingered leaves on it which I I've
seen that before so it really didn't
Peak my attention very much but then
when I saw it I thought whoa it doesn't
it didn't even look like cannabis
particularly the first stuff we grew and
um it took him a fair bit to get it off
the guy that had it and uh I think the
guy ran into trouble had to give away a
box of seedlings and that's how we ended
up with some and um from that we only
had a few seeds
and what we grew we only ended up one
ducks for a plan and um
I think though the the other ones the
the non-dux foot ones the the they'd
already had some they'd been crossed
with that already I'm pretty sure
because we just crossed by the miles
with the Ducks foot and we ended up with
more Ducks foot and normal normal leaf
cannabis and um
that's where it stem from initially and
um I just thought it was so novel that
uh
and I I didn't want to lose it I I just
saw it us you know Silly Aussie
backyarder guys we're going to probably
lose it if we're not careful so I'm best
to try and spread it around so that that
doesn't happen you know
yeah wow man for the people I love it I
love it and I guess sort of uh as a
follow-up to that what percentage of
those Offspring were coming out with the
Ducks foot phenotype
oh it's probably about 50 percent close
enough too it took a few generations to
get it you know completely old Ducks
foot and
um I neglected the other trade so I was
no you know I didn't know much about
breeding cannabis at the time and I I
still regard myself as just a hobby
breeder I I just do it for a bit of fun
and to make ourselves some seeds do you
know that
there's no no interest in
selling seeds to be honest
um just share a bit of cannabis might
make ourselves some seeds and um so you
took a few Generations by the time I
made something that ended up on the
market I was a bit embarrassed to be
honest how that I'd lost some of the
important parts of it you know by that
do you mean like the like the flavor or
the effect
exactly that the flyra the buds look
better to me some people did say they
got some stuff that was more similar to
what we had started with but we saved a
bunch of the seed or I I got my friend
to and I thought that was safe I'd asked
him you know make sure you keep that and
uh he had a stash in his freezer
and um he ended up giving it away which
I just I couldn't believe it I when I I
thought oh look I've probably messed
this up a bit I'll go back and get the
originals and we'll try again no they're
gone
heartbreaking yeah yeah I was pretty
disappointed he gave them to his
ex-wife's boyfriend and who does that
the guy banging your wife your ex-wife
I know that a bit
oh god oh wow what a turn of events who
would have thought okay well
um interesting stuff so in terms of the
original
um what what sort of flavor and effect
did it have
oh it was it varied a little bit this
kind of coffee sometimes a little bit
hashy
it's really strong aroma and that's
super strong uh I would have rated it up
there with um skunk permeation you know
what I mean it's really really you can
smell the plant from a long long way
away
yeah
and we I got some other web stuff from
uh from Hawaii
nah Hawaiian webbed Indica as well I
made a trade with a Hawaiian guy because
um it seemed like his stuff
uh was lacking the traits that mine had
and a big vice versa you know so we
thought we'd trade and and see what we
come up with and um
he didn't say his stuff was Indica but
it was uh it grew completely different
than mine there was no branching small
fat stemmed uh pungent little plant and
um super potent and I made a cross with
that in Ducks but and that smelled even
stronger that that stuff was
now you couldn't hide it there was no
chance I've heard I heard of people
getting busted with little tiny buds in
their car because it just stuck yeah
wow that's that sounds really cool and I
mean you sort of like I mean you gave me
the perfect segue into the next question
which was that one of our listeners had
asked do you know anything about whether
the Ducks foot originally comes from
Hawaii because a lot of people have sort
of said that over the years do you think
that it comes from one spot or maybe
different places simultaneously and it's
just a common mutation
well I think it's just a common mutation
and they're not necessarily related yeah
I wasn't sure for a while but I asked
Sam about it too and he said he found
some 20 years before I was doing uh when
he started initially reversing cannabis
they found some webbed Leaf stuff but uh
he said he didn't really see a use for
it so they never kept it but um I I
think it's just a trade in cannabis that
can appear sometimes
sure and I mean I think that sometimes
the duck's foot can get grouped into
this category as because I'm not sure if
you've been following closely but
there's sort of two other well-known
plants now that have like you know sort
of these very altered phenotypical
appearances being the Australian bastard
cannabis which you're probably very
familiar with
um as well as the super freak which is a
more sort of New Creation
um it's got like a very hyper serrated
Leaf which makes it look essentially
like a fern and uh I guess I'm sort of
interested because those two strands I
just mentioned ABC and super freak
they're not regarded as necessarily the
be-alls in terms of smoke quality and
effect it's more of like a tool to help
like try to hide the crop but what I've
heard from you sounds like the Ducks
foot really did sort of stand on its own
in terms of the effect and the flavor is
that sort of your impression
oh yeah particularly that hybrid we made
that was amazing stuff the smell was so
strong that pruning it would make you
nauseous after a while you couldn't
really trim a lot of it it made you feel
sick it was like fumes coming off the
stuff yeah I'd still rate it as some of
the strongest weed I've ever had it was
really really potent stuff yeah wow did
that one ever make it out into the
masses at all
no I just I've lost it through getting
busted and I I did try and back some up
but that was lost as well too just some
things are just not meant to be I think
oh no well there you go there you go
okay well the uh Australian bastard
cannabis recently and and that freak
stuff and
um
I don't know I didn't smoke any of the
the bars and stuff but my friends smoked
the freak and they said it was quite
good but uh it was just a little bit low
yielding but um amazing looking plan
yeah well hey I'd be curious to know did
you ever smoke it back in the day
because people always used to say that
back in the day it was like it gave it
was like the worst high gave you like a
headache and did you ever experience
that the Boston cannabis remain yeah no
I never smoked any of it they seem to
think it was hammer and uh by what
people report it sounds like
um yeah I I remember just reading the
word Bindi or something like that and
they would call it Bindi and it was like
I guess it was like the old equivalent
of like you know the Beast is like you
know like the shitty rayquaid or
whatever but um yeah there you go I
guess I'm I'm glad you haven't uh you
know had to smoke that in the words of
skunk yeah I've only got so many breaths
in this life to fill my lungs with and
I'm not going to waste it on something
[ __ ]
uh okay so sort of jumping back to the
timeline what was the first strain you
ever bred and was it intentional or was
it an accident
we used to make seeds for ourselves out
of the bank seed we got if any of it was
any good we because we needed more seed
every year so we'd you'd just like
filial breed at most times like just pop
the bag seed and breed the brothers to
the sisters or you sort of out Crossing
it to different stuff
with whatever we had at the time yeah
and um just a bit of pardon the pun but
just potluck what we came up with yeah
you know what this would be perfect
because I was talking to a friend the
other day and because he had just
recently started taking clones of like
everything and I was like this is the
way to do it man like it's it's annoying
and it takes space but trust me it's
good to have the clone of it and I was
sort of saying to him you know think of
all these legendary clones throughout
history you know whatever you know chem
dog OG Kush whatever you want to think
of and uh and I'd always say think about
how many chem dogs have existed
throughout history but we're just never
cloned or we're just you know
haphazardly made through sort of you
know breeding one thing to another and
like I guess what I'm sort of getting is
are there any plants you remember from
your like you know from the history
where you're like man I I remember this
one plant we grew it was so special and
like you know we didn't keep a clone but
like it if if I had it it would stand up
to Modern Elites like oh yeah there was
a few of them I had some pretty cool
African stuff from that see that girl
sent me someone somewhere one was that
it smelled so disgusting uh that I
actually I killed it
I couldn't even give it away it was that
disco it's not like the stink bug you
know stink bugs yeah yeah
I couldn't even give it away so I
thought I'd uh I just chucked it in a
box and threw it on top of the cupboard
and I thought one day when we're out of
weed we might want to smoke there and uh
months down the track we got it out and
it was actually quite good the smell had
dissipated and
I gave some to the guy that I'd offered
it to him for nothing and he wouldn't
take it and he
came back later and anyway he said it
was some of the best way to he'd have he
said to me and uh he uh I said so you
could have had the whole lot for nothing
but you wouldn't take it
no I'm Gonna Keep it I love it oh that's
that's brilliant that's that's cool to
hear yeah I like that I remember because
a lot of people might hear that and
think how could you like consider giving
it away it's still weed or whatever but
it's like I remember one time I was at
Bodie's house and he's like oh smell
this it's called ass I'm like really and
he's like yeah he's like American skunk
selection but like smell it and it
proper smelled like an [ __ ] and I had
some in this bong and I'm going to smoke
it and like I'm like hesitantly bringing
and I'm like am I about to like vomit
like because if this tastes like it
smells I'm going to vomit and thank [ __ ]
it didn't translate the first smell at
all
but I can only imagine what you went
through it would have been fun
definitely not licking your lips type of
stuff eh
that's it that's it right okay well
um I guess sort of at the point when the
duck's foot that you said you know you
felt like you'd lost some traits but it
was sort of going out to Market I think
a lot of people still really viewed that
as like a really worthwhile tool people
still looking for that seed stock did
you have any idea at the time that it
was going to go on to become this sort
of legendary stock that like people are
hunting for like you know wild right now
no but um so I see a few people still
sell it uh I've I've seen it around I
see it on um some
um some Facebook pages and that sort of
thing so it's definitely still out there
yeah I mean that's what that's what I
think is really interesting is like
people are really looking for it like
it's sort of funny because it'll it'll
tie into when we talk about some of your
strains later on with like the MBS and
stuff but I feel like there's a
similarity between your ducks for and a
lot of Tom Hills lines it's like it's
these old lines that people are really
hunting for now because they're like
they recognize the value some of these
older lines how just inherently within
them but I guess you're sort of saying
at the time you weren't really aware it
was going to have this ripple effect it
did
no like I said I was just trying to save
the stuff because I just thought there
was some importance with that leaf and
um it might be useful to people you know
trying to hide their their plants and
stuff like that so
um
and I'm sure it probably helped a few a
few people probably grew stuff where
they weren't able to before
stench yeah yeah yeah yeah right the
camouflage aspect's undeniable yeah take
me a little bit forward now I mean maybe
it was happening at the time how did you
first meet Moon Unit and what sort of
got you first thinking about the idea of
you know the Wizards of Oz
I was just on the forums on um I see mag
and he posted some stuff uh Zoid field
I'm pretty sure it was his his side feel
you hear you've heard of Sword feel oh
yeah yeah so I'll contact him and um
with him being an Aussie you know I want
to know more about it looked awesome and
um
so I I got some seed out off of him and
I I grew some it was amazing stuff I
can't believe that uh
just an average Aussie guy could make
something so good out of a few land
roses that was an excellent effort yeah
not many of the people that breed
cannabis actually do that you know what
I mean they always start with someone
else's stuff whereas he made it himself
so yeah and with uh non-european or
American genetics yeah it's just like
Aussie bushweed PNG gold and some of
that uh Chinese Indica stuff so
incredible stuff okay and so I guess you
guys just sort of hit it off from there
yeah and so well we we decided we'd try
and make a few things that people might
like and uh he did it all and it wasn't
me I just sent him some seeds and spoke
with him on the phone and that sort of
thing so
it was more his work than mine you know
oh look I feel like you know you
contributed pretty well so that's that's
great to hear and um and and how do you
how did you feel about it all you know
when you're releasing the seeds do you
were you sort of thinking like it's
going pretty well maybe we should keep
doing this or like yeah what was your
thoughts at the time
oh we were pretty excited we had a few
dramas though that the MBS that had
Hermes in it and we weren't able to
shake them and
um was lovely stuff so we we gave it
some additional patients back then
because even though medicinal cannabis
wasn't a big thing then it was starting
to take off and um
it gave you the munchies severely so uh
this this guy he was he was dying of
AIDS apparently and uh he'd lost the
will to live he wasn't eating anymore
you know he was down to like 90 pounds
or something like that and um one of the
guys that we gave the stuff to he uh he
gave him some MBS and he he reported he
put on like 30 pounds in two weeks and
um and like eight ten years later he was
still alive he was he reckons it saved
his life that that week
hey I I believe you that's incredible
that and I mean you know without excuse
me um you know without trying to get too
sentimental like gosh that must make you
feel like it's all sort of worth it
right oh absolutely yeah well I said
maybe this one the word was new I I just
thought that was a bit fanciful
um additional weight it was just a way
for our stoners to generate to
legitimize what we were doing
hahaha yeah I get what you mean yeah and
and that's the thing what you sort of
just touched on is a concept that I
actually uh first heard from uh our
buddy Todd
um and he I don't know if he coined the
term but I sort of looked into it
afterwards and he he said this term
hippie guilt and it's like what you just
touched on like this guilt we feel
around the fact that like we just like
this plant and we you know as you said
you know like we give it the name
medicinal to sort of try to legitimize
what we're doing and it's like the
reason why we do that is because we
inherently feel a bit guilty because
we're made to feel that what we're doing
is bad and uh so if we can say it's
medicinal well now it's actually good
it's interesting did you ever feel like
that did you ever feel like because I
certainly feel that way at times like as
in like on the one hand I know that
clearly what I'm doing is fine it's a
plan the laws are wrong but they don't
determine what's right or wrong
ethically and I know that growing a
plant is not inherently wrong but at the
same time you do feel a bit bad because
there is like this stigma in society and
culturally it's not as accepted as we
might like how have you wrestled that
sort of dynamic of you know being
essentially a real famous guy in a scene
that you can't tell any of your friends
about for the most part
oh no I've felt the same thing but I I
tell you what I read something recently
or heard someone say that um all
cannabis usually is medicinal and when I
thought about that I thought well yeah
it is even if we just you know lifting
your spirits do you know what I mean
like like I said my mother was doing you
know that that's medicinal and so we're
all using it for a medicinal reason uh
and like I said when I stopped smoking
the and the realization that I I have
been using it medicinally for a whole
bunch of things that I I didn't even
know I had uh so
yeah absolutely all cannabis use is
medicinal in my opinion too
yeah yeah look I tend to agree you know
like um I think it's somewhat Vogue for
people to have reasons for why they're
using cannabis and like yourself at a
certain point I just tried to move away
from that and it's like I'm not going to
say I'm using it for X condition or why
condition I'm just going to say I'm
using it it's just improving my quality
of life and that's all that needs to be
said really yeah I I agree 100 100 yeah
yeah Okay cool so just to jump back on
to the topic you know you're talking
about some of the work you did with Moon
Unit and the MBS and stuff
how how did those strains get received
domestically did you feel like you were
getting any traction within the Aussie
community at all or it was mostly going
to overseas people
oh there was never really an official
release of The Siege we generally just
shared them to be honest so um
and I do recall
uh some some American people came down
to the Mardi grass and someone shared it
with them there and that that reported
it to be pretty well they liked it so it
was well received
um we smoked a lot of it
that's that's always a good Testament so
I mean was there like a a somewhat
active Australian scene or did you
really feel like it was just the two of
you out on an island doing your own
thing like no one else was really on the
same level so to speak
no we even I went to a Sydney Cannabis
Cup at one point uh there was I think it
was two years in a row
um so I went to one of them this
red-headed guy he was crazy guy and um
when I went first visit him was uh on
our way to the Mardi Gras and
um
so the goal was to to visit him and
we're all going to hook up and then then
we'd go to the Mardi Gras from there and
he wanted to enter a whole bunch of his
stuff he grew in this Factory and
um I I'd no long been busted and so I
was a little bit cautious I didn't know
that I was heading there to go and spend
two nights in a
cannabis Factory
yeah and um
he didn't end up going we went to the me
and his friend uh Rodwell went to the uh
the Mardi Gras on our own and um we
entered these staff I entered some hash
uh there wasn't a a section for hash and
um
I'm not sure they said it spoiled it
poor on some of the people because they
smoked the hash and then the rest of the
weed didn't do anything for them
[Laughter]
I didn't care if we won or not that
wasn't the you know it was just about
entering you know what I mean that
that's what that might be about it's
it's a celebration of cannabis and it's
not to be taken seriously the Lord we
won you know that that's not what it's
about yeah
it was actually it was a really great
weekend it was we had a great time
cool and like did you did you bump into
any other Growers while you're in nimbin
for example
oh I'm sure I did it was it's a bit of a
blur though
okay okay so I guess sort of the picture
I'm getting is that like it wasn't like
you bumped into another Wally duck
equivalent where you're like oh hey you
you're like sort of doing your own thing
in the way that we are no I did meet on
the second time um I told um
a couple of American guys about it and
one of them met me there he was like I
end up being the um
uh one of the IC uh Tech guys uh you
know he did the forums and um
but I thought it was great they ended up
and coming and staying in Australia for
at least six months
because it was a bit of an eye-opener
for them they thought we had a great
kind of Lifestyle a good outlook on life
and and that sort of so
yeah yeah definitely any of our uh
American listeners who are wondering if
life in Australia would be good the
answer is yes
I've invited heaps of people and they've
all really enjoyed it and
um some of them are particularly a
Finnish guy said it spoiled them forever
they want to come back and they're not
satisfied living in Finland anymore
yeah look I can't comment on Finland but
I can definitely say as much as I enjoy
spending time in the states
um I'm always very happy when I touch
back down on Australian soil I feel like
when I see the Australian native plants
I'm like yeah all right I'm home I feel
good
um so moving the story along you know
was there a definitive moment where sort
of you and Moon Unit sort of split ways
or was it just sort of like a slow
fizzle and you both just sort of went
your different Pathways in life how did
that progress
are we kept in touch but he got busted
and
um I haven't spoken I think might have
spoken to him after that that I can't I
don't know what happened and I've got a
phone number for him somewhere I keep
meaning to try it to see what he's doing
whether it works or not I don't know but
um he's in New South Wales so I gather
the being busted there wasn't very good
for him I don't know whether he went to
jail or
or what happened but um
and uh so yeah that was basically the
end of that I'd like to get in touch
with him again he's a good guy
yeah I mean not that I've looked
particularly hard but I I guess it's
probably safe to assume he dropped off
after that for just obvious legal
reasons yeah him him and and Ken Kang
achiever
uh I I think sometimes
um you lose interest after you get in
that much trouble you know what I mean
and you you figure you better put your
energy in another Direction and I think
that's possibly what both those guys
have done I still speak to Kanga a
little bit and um I think he's lost
interest in
way after being in jail for a couple of
years it really tainted it for him yeah
yeah I can I can imagine I mean while
we're on the topic of Kanga like I'm
guessing you were around when he was
pretty active and during the time when
he was bastard
yes yeah we were going to do a
collaboration together but um
yeah that
quickly ended
yeah wow and I mean
um did you have any thoughts because you
know there's a lot of rumors around the
Kanga bust and people link it to Gypsy
Nirvana and various other people did you
have any thoughts on how that went down
or you just think it was probably just
you know like a loose lips sort of thing
oh I think someone found their plans I
think that's what happened I don't know
how but uh
that's what I seem to recall I don't
think he thinks anyone got him in either
I think it was just
luck of the draw yeah bad luck
yeah sure sure I mean while we're on the
topic of candy you know the strain that
always gets referenced is the the Mullen
Bibby Madness I I feel like it's one of
those strains where it's just got you
know so much mythology attributed to it
and it's just so hard to find verifiable
information about it what are your
thoughts on mother Madness did you ever
try it do you think it is as good as
people sometimes make it out to be where
do you stand
I I heard about that stuff when I was
like 15 and uh a guy was a
brother-in-law's friend was heading up
north from where we were in Melbourne to
get some I gave him a hundred dollars so
yeah get me some and a hundred dollars
for me when I was 15 was a fair bit of
money
he didn't come back
it must have been pretty good weed but
uh
everyone seems to think that everything
from Mal and bimby ended up being called
or nimb in the area
ended up being called that do you know
what I mean and uh would the plea would
the real uh Marlin madness please stand
up sort of scenario yeah
I I had heard that as well and the story
made sense right like as soon as the
name came out every dealer in Muslims
calling their weed Mull and bimby
Madness I guess
um from what you saw of what Kanga was
doing you must have sort of thought oh
well I guess given how much he's messing
with it like it must be pretty alright
yeah and he sent some to Neville and
Neville said to him that it was as good
as the highs he had had so I gather it
was pretty good gear I didn't I didn't
smoke any of Kangas pot but um
it seemed to have a pretty good
reputation
yeah look I'm sure it was just you know
killer outdoor sativa like largely like
what you were probably growing for the
most part was probably and that's the
other thing I try to remind myself is
like you hear all these stories but back
in the day like good weed was hard to
find so people probably remember things
like you know really well is like yo
that was the best way to had him forever
like sort of thing yeah yeah I'd agree
with
um that Nostalgia thing people say that
a lot of a lot of the weed we were
getting was [ __ ] and then suddenly we'd
have something good and it would waste
us you know I mean because our tolerance
was down we hadn't had anything good for
a while and
um I think there's a lot of Truth to
that
yeah certainly well I mean while we're
on the topic of melon Madness I've
always wondered myself and maybe you can
chime in to some degree maybe not all
good if you can't do you think mum baby
Madness is different to Old Mother
sativa because I feel like as much as
people maybe try to talk about them as
different different they they maybe are
just the same
I I don't know to comment on that really
I've seen both of them and they're
obviously both the titles but uh
relationship I don't know there seems to
be uh
rumors that Mullen bimby was tied across
with Colombian but um I'd heard that
yeah I don't know
yeah interesting okay
um yeah I I definitely heard that and I
thought because that's also one of the
rumored genetic combinations of uh
uh Cali mist and so I was like well that
would make sense because that was meant
to be a really good sativa so like it
would make sense a similar genetic
combination could make a good good
sativa but uh interesting interesting
stuff
um and I I don't know if you know the
answer to this but when we were talking
about the Zoid Fuel and um the Aussie
bushweed was that like old mother sativa
or like a different Aussie bushweed
oh it was just sativa as far as I know
there was a fair bit of that around Moon
seemed to think that it was uh
a bit it was must have been strong
because he said it was a bit paranoid in
inducing you know a bit scary and he
said that's that's what he liked about
uh the China is indicatively added to it
because he said that was like
anti-anxiety sort of stuff and uh it
leveled it leveled the high out a lot
and I I tend to agree that uh Zoid view
was real uh you know feel good weed and
uh you know gave you that nice uh
buzzing in the head actually I would
write it similar to
um MDMA actually it was similar to that
yeah yeah like it was a really
psychoactive and
um
I don't know just a buzz in the head and
a Euphoria you know uh I'd say it was
quite similar to that sort of stuff
wow that's a testament to the power of
the old world strains right absolutely
that was strong you know people say and
unless you unless you were smoking with
stuff that was scary and paranoid it
wasn't that strong I I disagree
fun you know and happy and uplifting and
be very very strong you know yeah
certainly certainly okay
um and in terms of like the z99 across
you guys made with um your c99 can you
tell us a little bit about that did you
just send the seeds over the Moon Unit
how'd that one go down
yeah I sent uh some I was F5 c99 I think
something like that and um and then he
just uh he sent me back samples of
different females that he'd used
and um we must had a similar taste in
weed because we both selected the same
one without talking to one another yeah
it actually uh it was similar to the
Zoid fuel it must have taken trades from
that because it had that nice little
buzzing sort of in your head
type of High and um we we still grow it
I've still got z99 uh we still grow that
stuff
you read my mind because the next
question was a question from one of the
listeners who said uh please pass on my
thanks to Wally huge fan of his work he
sent me some z99 to test out years ago
and I got to be honest I did a pretty
pitiful job of doing it Outdoors at the
time but I'm really curious to know if
he has any more maybe I can do a better
job this time around
sure yeah I win I have a bunch of say 99
cents
and um I still make seeds because
there's still a people are still growing
cannabis out there so
well we gotta we've got to use this
opportunity now if anyone was interested
in getting some of your seeds what's
what's the best Avenue for them to make
contact
well I haven't really solved any on on
that guy that has trouble receiving
funds and that was my always my problem
you know I don't know how but um and I
did was going to do a collaboration with
another Aussie guy recently uh Mr dots
and um he had the same trouble how was
he going to receive the funds without
disclosing his address or do you know
what I mean that sort of thing so
um
interesting stuff interesting stuff
maybe I'll put you in touch with uh some
friends of mine who who run a seed bank
in Australia they might be able to help
you out there you go
there you go this chat just became
worthwhile
uh okay cool cool cool so um in terms of
your seeds would you largely say that
you know knowingly or unknowingly
they're sort of bred for Aussie
conditions because I know that like you
know being Queensland native myself a
lot of strains really struggle with the
heat you know do you think these might
be good candidates for people in those
environments where like heat is a factor
yeah sure we're definitely testing that
out by just growing them here ourselves
that's largely why we make them for our
local friends to grow
um because you know there's never enough
good weed around us there so and we've
got a great climate and when I didn't
have any weed I'd I'd want I'd want to
go and find some and it was always just
[ __ ] so uh I thought well if I could
make enough seed to share with the
locals uh then when I run out of weed
there's going to be something decent
just like you know around right with any
luck anyway so um
that's what I've been doing and it's
I get a lot of paper resume these days
for that very thing and um we you know I
do benefit from it
that's great to hear that's great to
hear you know what it's so funny you
mentioned that because I always said
that was uh that was my initial
motivation for making seeds as well was
I just thought if there ever came a time
where I wasn't able to grow for myself I
just want to be able to know that I
could buy some decent quality of someone
and uh I think I think it does sort of
help you get there you know
absolutely it's it's definitely a foot
in the door if you had shared some seeds
with someone and they've grown some good
stuff the chances of you being able to
acquire some often it's pretty good
isn't it yeah that's it it's like a
business proposition I love it
okay and out of curiosity uh you know
because I I think that Instagram and the
internet in general has done a lot for
the Cannabis Community undoubtedly and
it feels like in Australia there's a
newly emerging sort of scene that's a
bit more how shall you say online not
just in like the internet sense but as
in like we're coming online we're all
linking up like we're all nodes in a
network and we're linking with each
other and I feel like there is slowly
beginning to emerge a clone sharing
scene and I don't think it's really
there just yet but I think in the next
few years we'll really see it come to
fruition where you know because often
people come on the show and they say oh
you know what like what's you know UK
has cheese what does Australia have and
I'm like oh there isn't really a one
thing that Australia has that gets
passed around per se
but I feel like in time that might
happen as clones get traded have you
noticed the development of like a sort
of cannabis scene or a clone sharing
scene per se
um I hope that's beginning I've got to
say we're probably like the last cab off
the rank using the internet for these
sorts of things a lot of Aussies are
very paranoid people and and they're shy
away from technology you know I've Got
Friends that don't even have phones and
half of them don't know how to use them
and they've never dared to go on a
cannabis site you know
it's a bit funny even you know people
like you and I and you know we're out
there on there and nothing much happens
to us and in fact it increases our
knowledge and our Network basing and
friends and you know I don't know it's
been beneficial and these guys are
missing out on that you know yeah yeah
yeah hugely hugely I've the amount of
messages I've had over the years from
people who are like oh you know I want
to grow but I don't want to get busted
but I was sort of thinking if they were
going to be busting someone like they'd
probably go for like a big fish uh
what's your secrets to not being busted
and I was just like oh just like don't
sell hard drugs or like associate with
people who do hard drugs that's sort of
My Only Rule it's like if you do or sell
hard drugs I probably won't really want
to hang out with you and that's always
kept me really safe you know because I
pretty much just hang around with other
Growers
now that's a good rule
yeah right while we're on the topic
what's your thoughts on the Australian
legal climate you know obviously in the
past few years we've seen the ACT
legalize two plants per person per
household uh with an upper limit of six
plants per household so you know three
people pulling their plants together do
you feel like that's a step in the right
direction or are you uh sort of thinking
like it's you know it's a Band-Aid for a
bullet wound what can you do with two
plants
yeah it might be a star you know they
they're not allowed to possess seeds
though seeds are still illegal for them
they can have two plans but where are
they going to get the seeds
that's a very good question
crazy isn't it
yeah well you know so I got an uncle who
lives in Canberra and uh and it was when
I was talking to him he sort of painted
how logistically challenging it is
because I was like oh you know I'll send
you down this sick clone I've got he's
like oh nah and I'm like why it's like
it's definitely better than whatever you
got and he's like oh yeah but like then
I can't keep a clone of the current one
I'm running like I can flower one out
and keep one clone and that's that's all
I can do and so I realized very quickly
I was like you can't like you can't grow
anything new because if you even pop one
new seed you can't keep a clone of the
other thing you're running and then so
that's gone and like it it really does
paint you in a corner doesn't it
yeah if you're law abiding like that guy
I've never really been like that so
oh look I I only ever abide the law
myself
[Laughter]
no I think I think uh I think that I'm
maybe a couple of plants over the count
at the moment
um so I guess the question then needs to
be asked what to you would be an
acceptable medical system I know that in
an Ideal World you know we can grow as
many plants as we want and we can go
nuts and have fun what do you think
would be like
a realistic proposition that you would
be able to get on board with while also
recognizing like you know like they're
not going to give us infinite plans like
what's a happy medium in your opinion
oh just what they did in Thailand
recently is a bit of an example of what
they you know six plants you can grow at
home treat yourself you know I think
Australia is crazy where
um only the doctor's allowed to give you
medicine because you have no idea
because you're an idiot you know you
have an idea it's your body you should
be able to whack in it what you it's not
as it's not harming you you know what I
mean and um bit of home remedy sort of
stuff why not what's wrong with that you
shouldn't you don't have to pay anyone
to do that why should we have to go to a
doctor and get a bloody script to get
stuff do you know what I mean when we
know we've studied it we know what's
wrong we know how to treat it we know
where to get the staff why can't we
I that's what I'd like to be able to see
people doing you know what I mean
they're not idiots they're they know
what's good for them a lot of people you
know
that's the sort of thing I'd like to say
I'm worried that
um to be honest with legality here that
we could end up in a situation where
growing a few plants is worse than it is
now you know because that could happen
it's a real real issue where you know
the government's mates are all making
money selling pot but you can't even
grow a few of yourself because you're in
bloody big trouble you know
yeah I remembered when they legalized
those two plants in act I I said to my
buddies I said you watch they're going
to come out now and say now that we've
legalized it anyone who's genuinely
needing cannabis will do that and anyone
who grows more than that is a dirty
Criminal
exactly exactly you know you can't grow
tobacco obviously because that's really
frowned upon and
um possession of large amounts of
tobacco that that's a federal offense
you're in big trouble you're in worse
trouble than if they found you with a
pound of weed you know yeah and that's
what I'm worried about what might happen
with weed in the future if you let's say
you want to grow for everybody else but
you don't have a license and you get
caught doing it then you're indeed [ __ ]
you know
yeah it look it would be it would be
super concerning if that happened didn't
it especially because yeah Australia's
got such a hard on for like tightly
regulated pharmaceutical dispensing like
I mean on the one hand it's good I think
that Australia has that grip on the
pharmaceutical dispensing because it
stops pharmaceutical industries from
like bribing doctors and stuff like that
but on the other hand it's it rate gives
that point you said where it's like
there's so many checks and hurdles that
you like you have to go to a doctor to
grow a plant that you know is safe yeah
we're so tight with some things so I
understand that they want to do things
properly but when the rest of the
world's done 350 studies and they've
come up with something and then we've
got a you know we've got to do exactly
the same study and we come up with the
same thing it's a bit ridiculous isn't
it yeah yeah gosh I wish we could go
back to like back in California when
they had the 215 days like I think that
model is the dream but I'm sadly I'm not
convinced it'll ever happen in Australia
but like yeah where people can just like
grow at their house and go to a
dispensary and sell their product to a
dispensary and then like like what
medical was for the longest time in sort
of California that would be the dream
but um but yeah who knows whether it'll
actually happen and um I mean on on the
tail end of the legalities side Yeah you
mentioned earlier you you got busted is
is there any chance you'd be willing to
tell us a little bit about what happened
or what sort of punishment you faced
I I broke that rule that you mentioned
earlier
with people that were doing some I
didn't know that's what they were doing
but um that's that led to me getting
busted and um twice quite a lot quite a
large amounts both times
and um yeah I'm I'm still in trouble
so even as far as like um
legal growing and that went I I probably
wouldn't be able to do that for quite a
while yeah I think they shut us down for
quite a while at least five years maybe
I might be 10 years I don't know but uh
I mentioned that to someone the other
day who's got some legal stuff going on
down south and said that uh I probably
wouldn't be even allowed into one of
those facilities and he said well
they're not guard they're not carding
you on the way through the door there's
no one checking your idea or anything
absolutely you can go in you'll have a
look around
but yeah I don't think I'll be a
candidate to grow legally for quite some
time
yeah look I was thinking about it myself
when you mentioned that to me and I
thought maybe in the future it'll become
more possible I know I've I've
interacted with a few of the legal grows
in Australia and I know that the
majority of them are being operated by
people with virtually zero cannabis
experience but just have been able to
get the financial backing and so
and and a lot of those companies are
producing very lackluster results that
even they themselves are acknowledging
is like not good and so I think maybe in
a few years once they've lost enough
money they'll be like maybe we should
get someone in here who can actually
grow weed yeah you want you you'd think
they would eventually come to that
conclusion you know it's frustrating
isn't it yeah look and I'm talking about
this for you you know like I'm hoping
that you get a call because
um it would be a shame for your talents
to go to waste like in that respect
yeah I definitely do it but there'd want
to be some reasonable money in it though
well they make pretty good money you've
seen the price of medicinal weed hey oh
God I remember when it first came out
and it was like 900 an ounce from the
pharmacy I think now you can get
reasonably good quality for about 500 an
ounce from the pharmacy but you're sort
of like for a legal system I was hoping
the price point might have
especially since you can go down the
road and get something better cheaper
and black market yeah that's it okay so
the next question I had for you and this
was something I was really interested to
ask you was
I'm always asking myself more than
anything I would like to be regarded as
someone who helped progress the
Australian scene in some form or another
and so I thought I should ask you that
exact question what to you do you think
is the most impactful thing the average
person can do
to help progress the scene do you think
that maybe for example it's like getting
online and networking and just like just
trying to like you know like build that
Network or do you think like for example
for a long time I've always told people
just keep Fino hunting trust me like
when you finish hunt you find new
special plants and it makes the scene
interesting like what do you think is
the best thing someone can do
God that that's not easy everyone's got
different skills don't they so they've
got different stuff to give some people
are way better at talking than others
some people are just gardeners and they
want to be left alone
whatever they're good at I guess
that's that's a good answer that's
that's actually a lot more uh you know
wide spectrum than I expected and that's
really good so I guess maybe I can make
it a bit more specific
for you what do you think is the most
impactful thing you did for the scene
oh just become involved I think
mainly yeah I've I've shared a lot of
seeds and um
uh connected people together that sort
of thing all that helps
you know definitely definitely
definitely definitely and I mean as a
curiosity what's your thoughts on Fino
hunting are you the sort of person who's
like always Keen to crack some new seeds
or are you pretty content just running
from clone where do you sit
oh I think it's exciting cracking new
stuff all the time don't you yeah yeah
this is twice alive
yeah like and it's an interesting one
because it then goes next into this
conversation of like some people don't
like the fact I say this but in
Australia at least I always say that I
recommend people have a day job and
don't grow for a living because I feel
like
whenever I meet someone who's like oh
you know I would really love to grow
something new but I've got this strain I
grow and I have to yield 4p in order to
pay the bills and
you know etc etc and I'm like oh you've
sort of backed yourself into a corner
with your hobby because it's no longer
your hobby it's now paying your bills
and thus you don't have that freedom to
maybe pop some Zoid fuel or something
new that maybe doesn't quite yield as
much but in the long term could be like
really cool and
um I've always felt like that's been a
good bit of advice because the people I
know who do really good Fino hunting and
really have fun with cannabis it's it
doesn't pay their bills for the most
part like maybe it gives them a bit of
pocket money but like it's not the
primary income Source what's your
thoughts on that sentiment feel free to
totally shoot it down if you don't agree
no maybe we need some guy that just does
that you know and he gets some some
money out of it everyone pays him for
his uh you know his success his
additions to to everything because he's
doing a job too so he's looking for
something for all these guys that are
doing you know the big jobs and
um he should be included as well maybe
that's another job you know like being a
uh paying breeders to find us better
stuff stuff like that so there's the the
Fino Hunter guy and uh he should do well
too
yeah yeah I actually I say that to
people all the time I say look just for
simple numbers if you grow a crop and
you make ten thousand dollars off it and
I pop new seeds and because I'm like
Fino hunting and some of the Finos are
[ __ ] and don't yield much like maybe I
only get like five thousand dollars
worth of crop but I get a few new plants
that are special like could you not make
the argument that whatever plants I
found are sort of worth five thousand
like that was the opportunity cost for
me to find those plants was like
foregoing that crop and a lot of people
get really uptight when they hear that
because they're like oh you're implying
that a clone's worth five grand and I
don't know if I'm saying a clone's worth
five grand per se but I'm definitely
saying in that theoretical situation
someone foregoed a bunch of yield to
find that new plant which maybe wasn't
optimized in the setup
um yeah what's your thoughts about that
can't he get a percentage of what the
guys that are growing it are making you
know five percent or something
they could you know cut him in on the
deal
yeah it seems like a reasonable sort of
like middle ground right well I do that
with the guys with seed we have an
arrangement
you know some like to pay
straight up front some like to give a
percentage of what they get or whatever
and uh it works as long as we're all
getting something and we're all happy
that guy should be cut in as well
yeah that's actually a really sort of uh
even killed Middle Ground I like that I
like that I hadn't hadn't thought about
that too much but yeah that would be
good and I guess it inherently sort of
promotes like unity and uh like
collaboration just by virtue of how
you're doing the transaction exactly
we're all working together toward you
know the guy at the end who's
smoking his stuff saying wow I'm glad
they chose this one but then that goes
back to your final Hunter mate isn't it
yeah definitely and and you know what
you've said is really true you know I've
been thinking about this a lot recently
and I've I've decided to give out some
of my closer guarded clones because I
thought it's all well and good for me to
think this is the best [ __ ] on Earth but
if I'm only cropping a couple of ounces
of it every few months like who's ever
going to get to taste it yeah exactly
yeah I'm all about that too I I we've
got some cuttings years ago from
overseas which we never thought was
possible and um
at first I thought we should Garden
tightly do you know what I mean but uh
eventually I thought well I I'm going to
lose them like like I thought with the
the Ducks but I'm going to lose this if
I do do that if I share and let other
people reap the rewards the benefits or
whatever then
when when I lose mine which I will I can
get it back of somebody and that's
exactly what happened and
um that way we met I managed to keep one
oh I think it must have been at least
six years ago that we got those cuttings
and uh the one I got I I it's still
running
and everyone's really happy and I can
get it anytime do you know what I mean
it'd be pretty selfish just to keep it
to yourself no no I've got it and you
can't have them uh you know cannabis is
supposed to be about sharing as far as I
remember when I first started
um
yeah definitely definitely I I'm I feel
like I'm I'm slowly treading the same
path you did years ago so that's that's
cool to hear I'd be interested to hear
what's your thoughts on the Australian
cannabis scene in general I'm not sure
if you're on Instagram much but I guess
from sort of what you see on the forums
I would largely describe the Australian
cannabis seen as quite similar to the
American in terms of like the trends you
know like OG and cookies and all that
it's you know sort of popular over here
nowadays with the younger Growers what's
your thoughts on the scene from what you
see
yeah I've seen that too I I not long got
on Instagram it took me a minute to work
out how to use the darn thing though
it wasn't like Facebook where you join a
group and there it all is you know but
um
yeah they like a bunch of kids with new
toys aren't they I I've noted at the
moment they're all trying those new
things and you know I've got Bruce
Banner or I've got cookies or and um I
think it's it's cool to see but um I'd
like to see more of them growing some
stuff from like ice seeds for instance
uh those survivors of those guys bring
out oh they're awesome I love that sort
of stuff I'm so glad there's someone
doing that that there's a market that
they can you know make some money out of
and and produce stuff like that
hell yeah I remember when I spoke to him
he he sold me a Lewis uh he sold me on
the Cali China I was like oh send me
some now
[Laughter]
yeah with a few of those I did grow some
crosses a guy made with some of their
stuff and uh that was awesome I loved it
it's great to see that on and that
there's enough people around you know
growing that sort of stuff that uh
it's it's becoming more popular at even
things
yeah hugely I feel like Hayes you know
someone said it the other day and it
made sense like they said whether it's
related or not seems like since
Neville's passing the the demand for
Hayes is definitely feels more apparent
yeah yeah there's been a re-emergence
lately hasn't there
I I think there's a lot of discussion on
the forums where I go about it so it's a
little bit heated mind you but
I love it
so when you talk to Australians about or
you know what I'm gonna actually
rephrase this when you talk to
Internationals about Australian weed a
lot of them talk about you know uh
nimbin the Emerald Triangle do you think
of fun do you think of far Northern
Rivers New South Wales as the Emerald
Triangle of Australia or do you feel
like there's actually a lot of other
areas that produce a lot and just don't
really have the namesake and I guess I
will add the caveat that you know I
haven't been to nimbin in a number of
years but whenever I do go there I'm
largely unimpressed
um slash disappointed you know where
where do you stand on it and do you
think nimbin gets hyped
yeah I do I I agree with you I I was
pretty disappointed with the stuff they
had they need some more input more more
seed you know better stuff they've got a
not bad climate there uh and I'm I'm
sure they've got a name for a reason
initially but
yeah I think those days are gone and
they really need to step up a bit and
when I was a kid uh up here where I live
was pretty famous for the best weed in
Australia North Queensland heads
everyone loved them it's you if you had
a bag of that you'd sell out in minutes
sort of thing you know it was pretty
popular stuff and um
strong
you know but I I think because of the uh
lack of imports you know when the import
market died and no one could make any
decent seed they couldn't inbreed it
well or whatever happened they um the
market kind of collapsed a bit
and they end up with a whole bunch of
Hamp it seems like and maybe that's
what's going on down nimbin too they
need new input you know
yeah well that's interesting and uh I
definitely agree they need some new seed
they're uh it's pretty stagnant yeah
yeah we used to have some friends around
here locally that um they grew some
stuff from India and uh it was kind of
like brown buds it wasn't Brown from
being ruined it was just Brown and um
around there and they smoked out of a
big Chillum it was bloody awesome
actually but he put a lot of weed in
there chill I must have been like seven
grams or something in there wow
oh fire came out of the top of that
thing when you popped on it was huge and
uh I was sitting on a chair I had to go
and sit on against the wall because I
felt like I was going to fall off my
chair I was at smashed you know
and I asked them about uh seed and they
said they had to go back to India every
year uh because they tried making their
own and they failed every time they said
they couldn't do it and it was just
better to go back to the source and uh I
guess uh inbreeding some of those things
just unless you're knowledgeable or
whatever or you've got enough
plants or it just doesn't seem to work
very well
a lot of it's not a lot of people I
guess
yeah certainly
I think uh we might move on to some of
the fan submitted questions at this
point so uh from a fellow Aussie bin
chicken he asks uh for the z99 would you
consider giving it a modern twist in
like a sort of a hybrid reformed or
would you just want to bring it back as
you have it now
I did I did recreate it and I also gave
it a modern twist and crossed it with uh
East Coast Sour Diesel so sours at 99
and that was pretty well received by the
guys that have grown up
yeah killer that's like you're ahead of
the game on that one oh yeah I knew you
haven't I knew that question was coming
oh that's like that's the perfect cross
as well like sour to the z99 is perfect
yeah I did use that shower a little bit
I I had some xaml too you've heard of
Miles yeah the mythical LSD effect it's
a pretty good pot I really liked it and
um
it had a really weird smell it was kind
of like tea tree oil Clarity tea tree
oil strong wow pretty robust sort of
Aroma and I did the same I posted with
sour diesel because why not use that
thing when you've cut it out and um
it was super potent uh it was it was a
great price I I crossed it again so I've
got like a double showers ammo and um
I've had some guys send me pictures of
these huge big colas they've grown with
it and so they're reasonably happy too
it seems
hell yeah that's that's a good answer to
that question
um so the next question we got was from
my buddy goody garden and he wanted to
know as far as you know is there any
difference between Duck's foot and
another strain that they call Monkey
Madness
I Thought Monkey was ABC
maybe I I think I might have heard that
term used as well so maybe it is ABC I
think it's one of the guys I think he
said he originally was the guy that
bounded off some old people I've seen a
recall reading and he hey I think he did
a bunch of crosses with it because I
think he said it was wasn't very potent
but I I recall him saying he did up the
potency whether that happened or not I
don't know uh I wrote to him once
because there seemed to be an interest
in it and I wanted to get some to spread
it around but I think he was concerned
with people making money out of
something that he hadn't made anything
out of or something I I wouldn't have
done that you know I would have just
given it away but I can understand where
he was at but uh why couldn't he just do
it and make some money out of it do you
know what I mean
yeah yeah exactly right like I remember
mean Jane you know a famous breeder
who's been on the show said you know
just like just get one or two steps of a
project under your belt and then you can
let it go and then if like your fear of
someone trying to rush to mark it
happens you're already one or two steps
ahead of him you know like so or do a
deal with them over it talk to them and
say look you want to give us a little
bit of something or another
yeah that's it collab's the way to go
for sure okay
table salt that's what and I don't
you know I don't have a foot in there
door at all I don't care I actually gave
that stuff away I never even made any
money out of it but uh and I see people
spelling and making money good on them
you know they're sharing something and
they they need something for the work
they're doing it puts you know food on
their table whatever I'm okay with that
yeah yeah definitely but they can send
me some money if they wanted to
of course I love that so the next
question we got was from a patreon
listener Felix he says it would be great
to hear Wally talk a little bit about
the Grail Hayes yeah let's start there
what's your thoughts on the Grail Haze
what was that was that something that
Neville was doing with kangaroo or yeah
exactly okay yeah I I don't know
I don't know what steps he ended up with
I I think someone sells some of that
that seed still
um but and I'm sure it must be good I I
tried some
um across with uh was it mullum
cross with tie and there's a dispute
over what tie it was so I won't get into
that but uh it was pretty good it did
remind me a lot of time
that golden tie that I mentioned earlier
uh it reminded me of that it was really
nice I liked it
yeah okay that's interesting I I I've
seen that post you're referring to I
think yeah it's its own kettle of fish
isn't it with that tie but um that's
interesting okay so the follow-up part
Felix asked was what are your thoughts
around why we're seeing the Resurgence
of interest in the long flowering
sativas and you know the real trippy
sort of weed
people are finally coming to their
senses
it was just so hard to grow for everyone
before maybe I've seen some Led grows
recently with survivors and I think
they're getting a lot better they're
really starting to you know look a bit
more like like you'd see them in their
in their home setting and um it's pretty
promising I think maybe it's not far
down the track and they'll be able to
get the second thing indoors that you
can if you grow them in a tropical Place
one one could only hope hey
yeah so so and I I agree uh as someone
who's growing some sativas under some
LEDs at the moment they're they're
actually doing a really good job I uh
we're gonna have to talk later about
that I wanna maybe we can we can do our
own little collab I got these these
strains I'm running at the moment
they're called Azazel and uh there's a
lot of different genetics in there it's
made by a a cool breeder could always be
flowering but it basically one half of
it is a seeds genetics Purple Haze so
it's Thai across to the Purple Haze I
think that's the mother and then the
father is like uh
granddaddy purps chem dog so it's like
new school meets old school but they're
very sativa leaning and um I'll get you
some photos but I'll also maybe we can
talk about some seed stuff later but um
we'll put that on the back burner for
the moment the next question we got was
someone who was wondering it's a great
question do you still hold any of what
you would consider your original c99
because they were sort of saying you
know like there's so many different c99s
on the market now be it Brothers Grim
c99 the new brothers Grim c99 there's
like a a fast buds you know like you
know there's like a million c99s do you
still have the one that you think is the
original and what to you is the best one
no that's that's long gone that was so
many years ago that um I did get offered
some recently by a guy and I think it
was original Brothers Grim stuff maybe
you know down the track a few
Generations but um I would I I told him
I'd take it because
even though I thought that that stuffed
uh that stuff the you built tolerance to
it really quickly you know
um we're still delicious
part it was pretty nice
especially that point like we spoke
about earlier and um but no I don't I
don't have any c99 z99
I'll I'm gonna have to send you some of
the new c99 f2s because I've got a bunch
of them just my friend made them for me
I was interested to know what day would
you harvest c99 because what I found to
be the most interesting thing about the
whole c99 story was when I went to I
actually spent some time in Colorado and
went to the brothers Grim facility and
they were kind enough to let me come
there for a bit and
the most interesting part about it all
was Rick Mr Soul said oh you know like
we used to say you know day 49 day 49
um and you could Harvest it on day 49
but you know now that we understand how
to grow weed a bit better it's probably
like 58 to 62. when did you harvest c99
no I was just thinking that as you were
asking the question yeah I I think 60
days but we used to harvest some at 49
days because it was ready enough do you
know so yeah
all that the high was better if you
waited a little bit longer yeah yeah and
you know what it's funny you say that
because that's exactly what Mr Soul said
he said you know like the smell and the
flavor and the effect was there at 49
but at 60 it was like stronger it lasted
longer
um so yeah more enjoyable it wasn't that
you got a flavor at day 60 that wasn't
there at 49 and I think that's why
people thought it was 49 but yeah just
the effect the legs on it it's just way
better yeah no I agree I think a lot of
people pull stuff early there's
down in Adelaide they're growing a lot
of stuff and they pull it at eight weeks
and one guy said they uh they made a
mistake once and I went 10 weeks it was
so much better
you know but they can't afford to wait
10 weeks so they are still always
pulling it out I think it was Jack Herer
it might have been Jack era yeah but
nice
yeah but they they still didn't learn
and then do 10 because two weeks are so
valuable they think I I I'd make room
for that extra two weeks be a bit more
concerned about your consumers I reckon
yeah right right I I and I I think I
said this to someone the other night on
Instagram I said I can't really think of
one plant I absolutely love that
finishes quicker than nine weeks
no some guy one of the guys on the net
said he wouldn't even smoke anything
that plowed under 10 weeks
[Laughter]
I love it Puritan
that's awesome that's awesome okay
um so the next question we got was
um I would love to know about some of
Wally's favorite pure sativas or just
narrow Leaf drug types in general
particularly within the Southeast Asian
you know any specific ties or
um I'll just sort of let you answer that
so far so yeah like pure sativa is what
what's up there for you in terms of what
you rate as high quality
oh I like most of them to be honest I
don't know if I've grown well I have
grown some pure Colombian and it was
pretty nice sort of a bit different to
the tie
even in its growth it's got wider than
it did tall you know tires get
quite tall but uh
I think what you grow up with tends to
be what you favor is and that's that's
what I found so the tie was typically
that it might go to but um I'd happily
try all the rest of them
no problem at all I did like some of
that Indian like I said that was pretty
good
I don't know what what sort of Indian it
was but I I think they were going to the
southern part of India so it could have
been similar to that Corella it was a
Corolla
sure yeah it could have been similar to
that
I I don't know though there's probably a
fair bit of weed in India
yeah wow that's really interesting to
hear that that sort of makes sense
definitely and you've stimulated this
thought in my mind everyone says that
the weed you grew up with is what's most
memorable to you but there's sadly a
whole generation maybe even two
generations of young Australians who all
the weed they know literally is uh like
pgr riddled beasters equivalent what's
your thoughts on that you know a lot of
people say oh you know it's Vietnamese
gangs and you know he lines like that do
you know what strains they're growing do
you do you feel like there's any way we
can change this at all within the
Australian landscape where it's just
like gonna be there
I think legalization's the only way
they're going to change that it's those
Asian gangs you see all the time a
bigger bigger and bigger bust of
greenhouses you'll have seen on the news
and I would like to put a stop to this
bustingham hasn't stopped them has it
it's every every other week there's
another one you know and and wouldn't
they rather see the money go into Aussie
pockets
uh but yeah with the pgr stuff yeah we
did get some we bought some weed from
Adelaide for a while and um so it was
that Jack Herer which we really quite
liked but then they grew this other
stuff they called uh Himalayan Himalayan
indica and that was that you've probably
heard of it it's large buds really big
orange hairs on it it was disgusting I
hated it it didn't get you high it got
you low you know other stuff
yeah yeah just that strain they're using
all the cash cropping facilities a lot
of uh young people they they actually
like that stuff that's their
interpretation of what weed is yeah that
that's all they've ever had oh sad
yeah and you know what it's like that
that was what conv so the day I decided
to start growing weed was the day I had
a weed sample that wasn't that bad
because I some one of my buddies was
like real technologically advanced and
in 2010 he um he gave me this bud and he
said oh that's Granddaddy Purple it's
imported from California
and I was like oh yeah yeah yeah yeah
I've smoked weed before you know like
I've smoked Aussie weed and I tried it
and it was just it just changed my life
you know like it opened my eyes I was
like wow you can grow weed like this
yeah right nice yeah the boys around
here my son I've got a son who's about
30. and um
their memories of the week is the weed
we used to grow so I I uh oh that diesel
remember that diesel what a lucky boy
well he was a teenager stealing my weed
I couldn't believe the Ash and the weed
he used to steal and thinking about
other people who had nothing in this
boys
they're out there getting uh acid off uh
bear you know bear from the Grateful
Dead the manager they're getting hit by
acid I've heard the name yeah and
they're getting uh Wheaton hash off me I
think what an upbringing these guys are
having eh
God the stuff for Legends you know it's
funny I was actually just talking to a
mate the other day and I said I think
one of the purest acts of love you can
do as a cannabis grower is to be able to
leave your children astrained
yeah why not well I always think about
it like whenever I have a guest on the
show and they're like oh you know some
seeds I got off my dad I'm like I wish I
had some seeds I got off my dad yeah
yeah my son would say well give us a bag
now and I'll I'll start with that
that's good stuff that's good stuff so
the next part of this person's question
was you know they're asking about the
like the favorite sativas and narrow
Leaf drug types and they said I'm
probably going to butcher the
pronunciation here so just bear with me
but they basically say do you have any
details on the Hmong Hill tribe tie is
it actually from Hmong or is it Hmong I
don't know how you pronounce it I've
heard it's just actually a fancy name
and it actually came from a guy called
Prof 77 who lives in Thailand do you
know is it actually a land race or is it
just from someone
yeah it's absolutely from Prof 77. I
went and visited him uh twice in uh
Central Thailand there and I
I asked his wife recently he died and I
asked his wife but she didn't go into
much detail she said that um
uh she got it off her father that tie
and
um
the family grew away and that was
basically what I got out of them so I I
don't even know where the Hmong part of
it came from I they never said that to
me they may have said it to one of the
guys they gave it to which was kanga's
friend and
um
but I never I never heard mom a mansion
but that that seed is so I've shared
that with someone I sent that to someone
and they've done a remake of it and then
shared with other people so that that's
where that seed come from I probably
still got some of it somewhere
but um and yeah it's originally from
prop 77. I I I'm glad to hear they're
mentioning the prop 77 that's the
important part that the guy that shared
it gets a little bit of recognition do
you know what I mean
yeah definitely definitely that that's
good to hear yeah kudos to our listeners
you know they're my listeners are only
Scholars and high quality intellectuals
um no but that's good to hear you know
shout out to our fellow historians out
you you've just made me wonder though
you know as when you mentioned you might
have some seeds left I've got to ask
because I love asking breeders this out
of all the seeds in your library what
are the ones like you're most excited
about or feel are like the most rare
seeds you have so to speak
I've still got some of those flower
seeds and um a hole I don't know I must
have like about 10 different label Thai
stuff
and they're all just getting older I've
got this this you know several tins of
seed and I'm worried that one of them
you know I mean how many of them can be
struck and am I just keeping them just
for a Memento you know we should be
growing those things
uh it's sad to see that happening
yeah it doesn't take very long does it I
remember like some of the first seeds I
ever made five six years ago are now
starting to be like fully dead because I
sadly wasn't keeping them in the fridge
and stuff like that and so uh yeah you
get to a point where you're like I like
I sat on them to the point where it was
deleterious yeah I see people with their
Collections and they're really proud of
what they've got but I don't know if
they know whether they're going to ever
grow the seeds that they've
so like from you know 1908 I've got this
stuff you know but is it is it ever
gonna grow
that's it right it's like everyone's
waiting for the uh fake embryonic seeds
to develop or whatever but you know
we'll have to see whether that actually
happens so the next question we got was
uh another land race I'm gonna butcher
it but I'm I'm hoping you are going to
understand the question better than I do
I get the vibe you will so they say uh
can you ask is Wally familiar with
campuccian land race honey
oh
Cambodian campuccia
yeah I think it's that psychoactive
honey right
oh okay yeah I have heard of that yeah I
don't know maybe maybe I'm wrong maybe
if you feel like you know what they're
talking about girlfriend hey Connie I
wish it was that stuff
definitely try some I wonder what those
bees are eating
yeah it's it's one of the flowers I
think there's
um there's like a an atropine type drug
in there so you essentially get what we
would call an anti-cholinergic reaction
which uh is I gotta admit you know um I
remember I spoke to a very senior Ed
doctor one day and he said the most
insane hallucinations like I've ever
seen a person having was
um from that anti-cholinergic sort of
effect not from like LSD he's like you
know LSD makes you like trip a bit but
like an anticholinergic delirium like
people will like jump out windows
chasing dragons like like full-on like
wow so I think that's what the honey is
is that flour get you high or is it the
bees yeah yeah I believe in the same
sense that like you know Scopolamine
from um datura and stuff like that I
think it's that same sort of vibe yeah
okay interesting have you tried daijira
I haven't I got some seeds and I'm too
scared to touch them yeah I've got a
I've got a growing out the back here we
tried it when we were kids and uh it can
be a little bit scary
yeah well I just remembered the guy who
gave me the seeds Mr Bob Hemphill shout
out uh lovely guy he was just like oh
just make sure you're wearing gloves
when you touch them because like even
just touching the seeds like you can get
high off apparently like it just goes
through your skin I was like oh yeah I'm
in PNG when we're younger they reckon
they're where the daichura grew around
the houses there that um you should
probably Rob those places because they
sleep really deeply
yeah okay that makes sense because I
guess over there in PNG they're using it
like I don't want to say medicinally but
like they're purposefully ingesting it
right yeah I would say so
I don't know I I was just a kid so yeah
sure well hey tell us tell us about your
PNG Adventures we forgot to touch on
that yeah we went there my father got a
job over there I I can't remember what
it was he was a seaman so I was like
search and rescue Harbor Master
he sold lighthouses at one point which I
don't know if you ever come across a
lighthouse salesman
it's a bit of a niche one
um so yeah I spent a couple of years
there and um
in the darkest parts of my life you know
when you're feeling really down that's
that's things I look back on because it
was awesome it was just so good we used
every day uh
after school the school was across the
road from the beach we'd wander off to
the beach it was low tide and we'd just
spend hours walking amongst the coral
looking for uh we're actually looking
for sharks me and my friend
I don't think we ever found any but uh
plenty of octopuses and crabs and you
know all the different shapes and colors
of coral and it was beautiful uh but
it's really sad to know that that where
we were it was at Port Moresby and it's
just not like that anymore I've been
told it's horrible you wouldn't want to
even swim in there they say you know so
that was like 1974 to now which is a
fair while but uh
it's totally ruined they reckon which is
a bit sad
yeah wow okay and I mean are you
familiar with the geopolitical landscape
there like I heard just I mean it sounds
like you were sort of talking about like
the waters and the the general
environment but I've heard it maybe it
isn't even necessarily particularly safe
at the moment do you do you keep tracks
on that at all
yeah I'm not sure how safe it ever was I
think it was always okay they used to
walk around with those big bush knives
you know those big bush knives so oh
yeah like like a machete sort of thing
yeah and they would use them they're
pretty brutal you know I they're a lot
of children you know what I mean I I
think uh so happy and happy go lucky but
you don't upset them because if they got
angry you know that could be pretty
dangerous people yeah yeah it's
different the different like it's
amazing the different cultural
differences like I remember
um when I was uh doing some volunteering
at a at a school helping tutor some
Refugee students just to try to help
catch them up to sort of the same level
as you know like what someone in year
four in Australia you would sort of be
expected to be at that level or whatever
and I remember they were telling me
because there was a few of them that had
like um were from PNG and they had um
like a lot of scars on their arms and I
was like oh what's that from and they
were like oh you know like in my culture
like we often settle like family
disputes with just like small knife
fights
you reckon it's true as well
oh they're pretty brutal sometimes and
and so
strong and I the injuries that I've seen
them and get inflicted by or with uh
and they'd barely even notice it you
know it's
I'd be crying my eyes out or whatever
you know at that point but these guys a
big chunk of meat comes out of their leg
and they know it's okay I'm all right
Jesus wow yeah tough people
yeah yeah strong culturally yeah that's
interesting yeah the different cultural
perceptions of pain like in some
cultures like pain is like a good thing
it's like religious experience almost
but there you go okay cool well thanks
for the experience on the PNG and it
ties in well because one of our
listeners wanted to know that uh they
had read online a while ago many years
ago that you were selling PNG and I
think PNG has had a bit of a Revival in
terms of its popularity how would you
describe that strain would you say like
you know it's largely like the other
sort of Southeast Asian varieties or
what what makes it unique for you
oh I don't think I ever sold any I got I
got a mate that was over there to try
and collect some seeds but they were uh
I've still got them I don't think I ever
got any of the strike but uh a friend of
mine has grown some sense that he got
directly from PNG and they were they
were all right but um
no I don't but I I did grow some when I
was younger
um I was one of my first indoor
experiences and
um it was pretty awesome actually it was
really fruity sticky
top top last week BNG gold it was and
um delicious I think that you know
things that stick in your memory are the
ones that things that are good so I can
still almost remember the smell of that
stuff it was delicious
and um I'd absolutely cry that stuff
again but I don't know they don't have
uh
seed banks or do you know I don't know
they don't have ways of keeping stuff to
to be able to get that stuff again from
when I was 25 it would be pretty
hard-pressed to get it I should think
yeah right
sometimes I you you've made me realize
that yeah I don't you don't think about
the logistics of like yeah they don't
have little baggies over there or
anything like that it all sort of plays
into the picture doesn't it yeah they're
just growing what they can and you know
remaking seeds and I did I did talk to a
guy that um
study PNG cannabis uh Ben Thomas I think
his name was I spoke with him for a
while and he thought I was like a
qualified scientist or something he
wanted me to do a journey over there
funded by the government to go and study
cannabis which I said absolutely I'd
love to do that but I'm not the guy you
think I'm just a bit of a Stoner guy you
know
uh but yeah absolutely I would love to
he he put out a paper at some point I I
put it online somewhere I'm pretty sure
so he thinks it was uh they um
did some tests and it was one of the
strongest survivors that came in at like
16 THC which is for a land racer tiger
that is pretty high yeah
wow that's special okay
so I'm gonna have to go look for that
paper after this chat I'll have a read
of it but that's cool okay so the next
question we got was throughout your sort
of growing Journey did you ever struggle
with anxiety related to the law like
were you ever particularly concerned
about the law coming and busting you or
was it just something you were never
particularly mindful of
all the time
I was always worried about I suffer
anxiety so um
and like we talked about earlier
sometimes cannabis can help relieve that
but sometimes it is activated too
so um yeah I was I used to have dreams
that uh I was getting chased uh all the
time by police and sometimes it was
crocodiles but I still think it was
police
you know just that idea in your head oh
wow hey I've had plenty of that I don't
seem to have it so much anymore I still
dream a little bit about cannabis
um but not about getting caught or
chased or
big fields of it anymore so
right there you go okay cool cool and
the the final fan submitted question we
got from our patreon fans was do you
like ABC in terms of the effect do you
think that ABC could ever be a viable
commercial variety or do you think that
it's potentialized purely in the like
discretionary slash camouflage sort of
aspects
I don't see why they couldn't do what
they've done with Frag Show I'm not even
100 sure freak Show isn't related to ABC
uh because we grow a few and some of
them look very similar the sort of leaf
that pattern that I had there's no
reason why you can't cross that to a
really potent variety and make some f2s
and then select some you know freaky
looking left ones
um absolutely no reason why and then
have your camouflage you know UK can eat
it too basically
uh my friend wanted to make I think he's
halfway through making some um freaky
bastard ducks
oh wow the the trifecta
that'll be cool that'll be cool okay
some first of all keep our eyes out for
so we're now moving on to what we call
the final five questions so uh first
question what is the best or single most
memorable experience relating to
cannabis you've ever had
oh
um that's that isn't an easy one is it
there's been so many so I've done it for
so long that I couldn't really pinpoint
one uh I just used to love getting
really high and
um you know forgetting my worries
uh load off load off your mind you know
what I mean
uh I did have a bit of a when I went to
Thailand the first time I I actually
might have been the second time I smoked
weed there but um
had like a uh I got freaked out a bit I
think it was uh the combination of jet
lag and low tolerance that I I smoked
this stuff and I'm seriously I was
spiraling down this dark tunnel see this
isn't a good experience it's actually a
bad one but um I had to be
you know really mindful that it was
actually just cannabis and and it's all
right Wally you're going to come out of
this okay it's only That's How Strong
some cannabis can be it's really
mind-altering some of it I think that's
one of the things that's missing in
modern campus actually that aspect you
know it's more about I don't know more
body and that had that trippy sort of
you know hallucinationy sort of out of
spiraling down dark tunnel stuff uh it's
supposed to be missing these days it can
be a pretty wild ride
yeah yeah it's I thought in a minute I
really did I I thought I was losing the
plot and I kept having to say to myself
look it's it's only pot you're going to
be okay
I love it I love it when you've got to
like back yourself off the ledge
okay
so um on the other end of the spectrum
what's the least memorable or most
disappointing strain you ever tried that
maybe was hyped up you know like I mean
we hopefully it's not the answer but I
mean earlier on we spoke about the
Northern Lights you know everyone Raves
but you were like oh it wasn't really
our thing what's something that for you
was like didn't really live up to the
hype or was just flat out really
disappointing
I did a Tesco once I think it was sensky
seeds I can't it was really in the early
days when I first come online and got to
know Gypsy and and he somehow I end up
with this Tesco I'm pretty sure it was
Scentsy seeds it was called gorillas
Gusto I think that's what it was it was
terrible
I couldn't
and I even had like about five of them
to choose from and I just thought it was
just rubbish you know but I don't think
it made a I don't think they released it
I'm sure other people must have found
what I found it's pretty disappointing
yeah I don't know how I think someone
had sent it to him and said oh this is
the best stuff ever you should try that
but
their version of best stuff ever versus
mine just wasn't the same at all
yeah God that that's interesting there
you go seeing the downfall of Scentsy in
front of you
um
let's do a desert island situation so
theoretically uh back when you were
ingesting I'm gonna drop you off on a
desert island with just three strains of
cannabis for the rest of your life what
three are you gonna take with you
all right pretty sure I'd take that
allow stuff that I was talking about
earlier
and um I guess I gotta have a a hybrid
of that and I I made some with mango
Hayes Lao cross with manga hose mango
hoses
one of my favorites actually and so
probably take that with me too
um
and then I guess there's days where you
want to dribble on your shirt and lay on
the couch a bit so maybe take a bit of
indigo I don't know
I haven't grown a lot of indicators I've
recently grown a bit of sour bubble of
bogs though you know bog sour bubble
yeah
very indicatory looking I I didn't smoke
it because I'm not smoking anymore but
uh it's gonna have like some of the
largest Leaf I've ever seen it was like
a big palm leaf and um not very vigorous
just grew small
uh when you floured it it didn't really
stretch out or anything like that I
don't know how ratio of vinegar it is
but it looked pretty bloody Indica to me
versus yeah fibers I was growing you
know and hybrids I think it's 100 Indica
okay there you go maybe something like
that to dribble on your shirt oh wow and
relax
you can't hold on a big euphoric all the
time I guess so
that's cool that's cool okay so second
last one who is the one person from all
of history you'd love to sit down and
pick their brains about cannabis alive
or dead
oh I'd probably I I had met Sam already
in an embarrassing situation to be
honest for me but um I think he'd be the
guy I'd want to talk to more
I think I'd tend to agree with you on
that one I think our buddy Jingles has a
lot of interesting info for us
absolutely
so final question for our chat today if
you could go back in time to anywhere
any place to collect either some seeds
or some clones where would you go you
got a time machine take you wherever you
want oh I definitely gotta get some of
that Thai
oh yeah like some of that first import
stick yeah and then I'd like to go into
my own timeline and go and get some of
that webbed hybrid stuff and the old
duckswood that I had to I really love
that stuff
yeah I can imagine I can't imagine it's
one of the stuff I had when I was
younger too you know uh memories
[Laughter]
that's awesome to hear that's so awesome
to hear okay well I think that pretty
well brings us to the end of things were
there any uh General comments or shout
outs you'd like to make
uh just a general shout out to the
community who I've been a part of for a
long time I've loved it it's been great
there's some great people you know I
some of the people I've met through
forums in that
uh they just give you a refreshed uh you
know vision of how good people can be
generous and kind and there's some
bloody good people out there
yeah I can definitely back that as well
you know a lot of really good people
looking to help each other out exist in
the scene so don't get bogged down
thinking it's all profiteering no I've
got messages from people to just say are
you okay how you feeling are you good
you know what I mean fancy Someone
putting out a bit out of their day just
to make sure you feel okay that's pretty
decent
there's some good people in the Cannabis
Community got it
yeah yeah definitely definitely well you
know thank you so much for for coming on
the show Wally you know one half of The
Wizard of Oz uh just countless memorable
strains brought to the scene and just
you know likewise a huge amount of work
you've put into whether you knowingly or
not helped progress the Australian team
we're all very grateful and appreciative
for your time
[Music]
oh thank you thanks very much for
talking man
[Music]
and there you have it my friends what'd
you think
huge shout out again to Wally for taking
the time to stop by and share some of
his knowledge
likewise a huge shout out to you for
making it to the end of the episode
as always huge love for our amazing
sponsors who helped make the show happen
CT now best seed bank in the industry
all the latest breeders did you check
out the latest crickets in cicada drop
go hit him up guarantee not just on
germination but satisfaction won't go
anywhere else BT now thank you so much
likewise your garden has to be pumped
and happy healthy packaging free in
order to find the keeper Fino you're
after and in order to do that we
recommend you check out our buddies at
Copper biological systems these guys
help set the industry standard for what
predator might should be check out the
appipharam pure aphid problems check out
the spidex vital for any spider mite
problems I promise you Copper got you
back check them out thank you so much
cute shout out to Top Shelf State Bank
number one seed bank in all stopping all
the hottest breeders internationally and
domestically if you're after my work all
my buddy feral genetics Works check out
top shelf seed bank
and last but not least a huge shout out
to the patreon gang you know we love you
the lifeblood of the show people who
support the patreon truly help continue
to make episodes happen all while
gaining access to unheard content
exclusive episodes and giveaways
if you want to help support the show
please go check out
www.patreon.com the podcast and consider
signing up today
I think that's just about it from me
this time gang
I'll have to catch you for the next one
thanks for stopping by
e we'll see you
[Music]