[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
welcome back my friends for the next
episode of the podcast a cannabis
podcast for budding enthusiasts as
always you're joined by your boy heavy
dairies here from the upside down
Library
and as always we couldn't make these
episodes happen without the patreon gang
we love and appreciate you guys so much
on this episode today we're joined by my
buddy
the true turp connoisseur
and our first Auto breeder on the show
Sean of flying line research here to
talk all things Auto breeding
Californian cannabis history future
predictions all the lowdown on turfs
concentrations extraction
because I found one guys I hope you
enjoy it
alrighty gang we're here for another one
thank you so much for joining me and on
this episode we are joined today by a
friend who's been making some waves in
both the concentrate and auto scene for
a good minute now very thrilled to be
able to talk to him today thank you so
much Sean of flying lion research for
joining me today
happy to be here
lovely to have you on my friend first
question we've been asking people lately
what have you been smoking on today
uh today
we've been dabbing on the lemon fat man
um it's the flavor I dreamed up long ago
from the lemon tree days we always
dreamed of something being so lemony but
that actually would hit you like an OG
and so that's where the original project
came from uh Bodhi uh plant more seeds
finally fixed up the whole lemon tree
debacle by getting the original lemon G
and hitting it with his you know hash
plant you know pollen like he does and
so that was the lemon hash plant version
two seeds I got to test out and it had
that smell I hit it with the fatso cut
um that I got from finest
first ever tissue cultured cut but
anyone I've ever talked to was able to
hit nice pollen too
essentially
you know not wrapping any diseases into
the DNA from making seeds
for the first time available it's a
great tool for breeders really and so
all the progeny have been high yielding
and do what we want to do which is yield
for fresh frozen live rosin and you know
those 90 you heads and have that lemon
terp flavor that's really hard to
capture yeah
and the main reason is you know it's
like you're doing
work all day and it's a it's a work High
yeah keeps you going
that sounds delightful and I love how
many different Avenues you gave me to go
on let's quickly start off I want some
body love when I was cruising through
your Instagram I saw you got a lot of
different experience with various body
strains what are some of the memorable
ones to you
um well it all started out with his
um Afghani crosses with his uh g1388
hash plant pollen
and
basically anything that we've always run
from him for the fresh frozen process
the flavor lingers in your mouth longer
than We've ran 20 30 breeders
on my farm over many many years and
so many of his things were just everyone
asked for it again let's see The Wookie
orgasmatron was a real winner oh yeah
um yeah he's got lots of far out names
uh his jalalabad star uh his strawberry
Mill
uh yeah just so many winners
love it yeah there's there's endless
ones we could go into you just
referenced you know flavors that linga
and I guess to sort of tie it back to
the the lemon tree I would have to say
lemon tree is probably up there with
some of like you know in terms of
flavors that linger there's got to be in
the top five for me do you think there
are others that are better than it or is
it likewise for you one of those really
stand out ones
uh I mean I always thought Elementary
was amazing until I grew the lemon G uh
myself and saw that it had no real
structures a nice fuzzball perfect for
extraction perfect for what I was
working you know looking for really
and then to hear Bodhi worked with it to
increase its potency it was exactly the
kind of seeds I was looking for
um I think the sour diesel cut that the
lemon tree is made out of really watered
down the like lemon tree high that is
like supposedly kind of in the marketing
I feel like
so it's just good to actually bring that
terpene so people are like oh wow it's
unmistakable
yeah and I'm I'm not super up to date
with the origins of the lemon G but from
what I read people say like it might
just be like a Colombian or something
and and that sort of matches some of the
descriptions you hear what's your
thoughts on the origin of the lemon G
um I mean it's pretty common knowledge
that people say it came from Ohio so
it's the Ohio lemon G cut which was
passed around in their 80s
and from there yeah we would need to do
the whole you know genome mapping
interpene analysis and then look at you
know
stuff like that and actually deduce
where the actual land race came from
yeah certainly certainly so it just to
rewind for a moment you were talking
about how hop late and viroid is sort of
everywhere and you were able to get that
uh tissue cultured fat so I'd love to
hear your perspective because obviously
you know being in California you're
surrounded by it how bad is the
situation in your mind in regards to the
hop latent virus
I mean people are finding it in plants
that they think are healthy so that's a
big like you know scary thought like oh
there's nothing wrong and experienced
Growers are getting lab tests and
finding it's not in the unhealthy plant
it just needed more minerals it's in
this one
so it's just kind of sitting there
hidden sounds real scary honestly can't
look at it with a microscope you've got
to take tissue samples to figure out if
you have this virus
um I mean most everyone in the last five
years I would say 95 percent of people
I've talked to have had to eliminate
their mom rooms and reset everything
absolutely
do you think it'll come to a point where
we have to everyone tries to start
afresh at the same time or do you think
it's just going to be one of those
things that's just going to persist
forever now
uh I think just like anything you know
the genetics are here to adapt and
they're here for us so
like what I did this year putting seeds
out and letting things succumb to
diseases and you know that's the real
breeding work we can eventually breed
away from it
yeah interesting I've been wondering
that one myself but that's that's an
angle I haven't thought of I like that
so just to come back to the very start
of all of this we you were saying you
know this this uh the lemon hybrid
you're been enjoying today so it's a
good work strain I love the idea of work
strains they're the exact sort of things
I want to smoke myself what sort of
things lend themselves to that category
in your mind besides obviously just
saying you know sativas are there any
specific sorts of strains you think
really fit that category
well it's really the combination of
limonene and Alpha pinene being high in
the extract that's gonna tighten up all
your blood vessels
vasoconstrictor versus vasodilator
associated with Indica FX
so that constrictive action causes your
heart to pump harder you feel like
you're ready to do push-ups or run a
mile
that's a great thing when you're uh
worked all day the day before or worked
all night pushed yourself and your
body's soar in the morning but yet the
plants are ready they want to get in the
freezer
I love the plates I'm ready to get in
the freezer tell me more about your
fresh Frozen activities because I'll be
honest I I still have a lot to learn
about fresh frozen what how would what's
how would you sell it to me
well we've been
fresh freezing here on our farm for
seven years now
so I've been doing it longer than most
anyone I've talked to we've done the dry
ice we've done the scientific freezers
we've done generators in the back of the
truck
if I was gonna sell it to you I would
say hey if you're a farmer you only get
paid for the total weight of
cannabinoids that you produce
and those finer cannabinoids are
evaporating in your curing room and
that's why it smells good in there
so if you're okay with burning some of
the finest effort that you ever had
every year go ahead and cure your crop
stay in the past
I'll be here fresh freezing
like a Zen monk I love it I love it okay
because I noticed on your Instagram you
had something that I had never heard of
before it was what you called Fresh
froze fresh frozen
pressurized rosin tell me about the
pressurized component that seems like
quite Innovative to me
yeah so a lot of people do cold cure or
what's known as fresh pressed rosin
where they just take it out of the rosin
press and put it in a jar
um this is a way to actually conceal
some of the qualities of your rosin
because if you know what you're doing
you can squeeze out your rosin and then
freeze it and keep it fresh pressed and
it kind of hides if it'll Char the
dab nail later or if it'll be harsh it
just all looks clear
and so if you whip your 90 you
which is like what West Coast Alchemy
does that's kind of the brand that sets
the standards right now
um
you got this wet look on your 90u and
that's the terpenes coating the thca in
this nice kind of achievable quality
where you're like oh okay so the indoor
or really organic outdoor from
experienced Growers that'll have this
really wet look because it has a high
amount of terpenes and that's what
people want is a lot of flavor with
their rosin and it's hard to find
a lot of flavor
in rosin because you know only a few
cultivars work for that process
genetically
brilliant a lot of a lot of details
there I'm gonna have to go over again
tell me how do you think we can get more
of the general public onto these higher
types of concentrates such as hash 90 IU
things like that because I think there's
a conundrum in that like you need to
show people of course but like there's
not a lot of it around so what's your
thoughts
well the price of rosin is dropping and
people are learning the fresh freeze and
the collapse of the flower market with
the overproduction on the White Market
and the cartels
has pushed small craft Growers into
understanding fresh frozen whether they
wanted to or not so if you've got a
family and you've got a big grow set up
and you've got everything rolling if you
dried everything last year you're still
sitting on it and you're looking at
selling it at a loss if you want any
cash whatsoever before the next flood
comes in
20 days two weeks that's it
interesting and and with all that excess
stock from the White Market do you think
eventually a bunch of it will get turned
into just like simple concentrates and
that'll have like a big flood on the
market
yes and that's why all your white Market
investors are pushing for interstate
commerce because we're at the breaking
point in the next year 95 of cannabis
companies didn't turn a profit last year
so you've either got billionaires who
want to keep losing money to prepare for
federal legalization
so their brand is ready
or
you got to make some sort of lobbying
effort between a state that's just
coming online and doesn't have a good
environment to grow
do you foresee that Federal legalization
in those opening of borders happening in
the near future
well it's hard to say there's so many
things at play and so many things
distracting from World Wide weed as I
call it
um you know this it's amazing resource
that can unite the world uh the first
multi-trillion dollar industry that
could
um unite third world countries and First
World countries and put everyone on a
different playing field as far as Global
terpene Production and a global
blockchain to
you know honestly take care of all the
logistics right it's like people want to
buy weed we have the World Wide Web why
isn't it just you can just go on there
and see like hey I'm a farmer I do these
are the soil tests this is my terroir
these are the terpenes that Grass Valley
produces better than anyone I'm sure
there's other areas that are going to
produce unique terpenes but here in
Grass Valley we can produce a wide
variety of nice ones so that terroir
will be understood on the World Market
if everyone can just get over themselves
and see that we can employ
millions of people yeah
wow that's so cool to hear I've been
thinking about this because I've been
getting more into wine recently and I
was wondering do you think that will be
the end State we get to where like for
example if you're in France in the Loire
you're probably growing Shannon Blanc do
you think that's what will happen to
like what you're describing where like
if you're in Grass Valley you're
probably growing extreme because it's
just the terroir matches or something
like that or do you think it'll be more
variable than say wine where it's quite
homogeneous
it'll be more variable than Wine but it
will become more homogeneous but that
will lead to like the Ultimate
Experience for the consumer because as
the real small Market Farmers survive
then they'll have to use the lab and the
soil test to differentiate themselves
and have genetics being made on site to
make true land races for our
place just like
everyone else has done it's this whole
Colony colonization of weed that's been
happening right like
Skunk Man Sam
and that whole crew from Santa Cruz you
know I grew up in Santa Cruz I'm
familiar with where blue dream was
created
over in last chance
this is some smart hippies you know who
were like oh wait like these tribes have
already done thousands of years of work
to hybridize their unique cannabis
strains they don't have airplanes or
breeding sites like let's go to Thailand
and collect their seeds let's go to
Pakistan let's go to Oaxaca Let's cross
all those together and that's where they
made Blue Dream the number one we'd ever
sold
yet those tribes still don't have
running water or solar panels
so that's that's the real next step
right the ethics of genetics worldwide
yeah hugely you can't deny that um the
the funds are not getting back to a lot
of these indigenous areas I'd be
interested to know in this like sort of
future situation we describe do you
think people would be growing
um like more likely modern stuff that's
refined to suit the area or do you think
certain places will just literally go
back to land race
I think with the global understanding of
worldwide weed and the market potential
and the pharmaceutical understanding and
then that joining hopefully in a good
way it will lead to Labs being built
everywhere where weed has been
indigenously bred for thousands of years
if you've got Israel a big Corporation
willing to buy 40 million dollars worth
of weed from Canada
just to research not to smoke just to
put in their gas chromatography machines
and genetic analysis machines then we've
got this onus on us as humans to build
those labs and get that information to
those local tribes and we'll find some
unique terpene in there that's going to
heal all these diseases that are caused
from our modern society and then those
people will have something valuable to
hold on to yeah
yeah that's interesting we've never
really brought that topic up on the show
but I'd be interested to know do you
think anyone is even remotely close to
Israel in terms of their research or
interest in cannabis like medically
no no one has the investment potential
they've put more in they I mean they've
only released that they had the
bioreactor last week to produce
cannabinoids without plants yeah that
was wild yeah I was reading that I was
like that has massive like scalability
production and they could just be
pumping that out
big time uh it's you know the whole
thing about like the ethics of CBD
um a lot of people who maybe weren't
involved in cannabis grew and
overproduced CBD and then went bankrupt
just kind of
magical cannabis Spirit protects herself
from being too taken advantage of
um but yeah but the real goal right is
to have CBD super cheap so that these 40
dollar CBD bombs don't have 30
milligrams of CBD they have 3 000
milligrams because it just costs three
dollars for that much now so that's what
we want is for everyone to have these
things available so everyone can benefit
and then the price point won't alienate
most people who aren't into cannabis
already as far as
getting more people to understand
yeah nice and I mean while we're on the
topic quickly are there any minor
cannabinoids that you're particularly
passionate or a fan of
oh absolutely we're having great results
with uh CBG uh from the Matterhorn
strain from the hemp industry
uh the pure CBG distillate has about 80
percent naturally occurring CBG and 10
CBD
absolutely amazing I've been giving it
to
all sorts of my friends and people tell
me from all walks of life from all
different diseases
my one friend has a gastrointestinal
disease where he throws up unexpectedly
and then he has lots of nausea and he
would spend a lot of time trying to find
certain weeds that would help that and
sometimes he would and then sometimes
the same strain wouldn't do anything
and make it worse and he finally found
CBG he told me every time he adds it to
cannabis his nausea is gone the same
with the 50 year old basketball
Aficionado I will call him he loves
basketball but he's getting old and the
joints the pain he tells me all about
how he just can only play for 10 20
minutes before his legs and knees hurt
and after I gave him CBG came up to me
ecstatic you know Sean like the CBG like
it it went inside I I played a two-hour
game I I haven't done this in 10 years
so those kind of experiences you know
they keep me dedicated to the whole
cannabis Realm
yeah that's beautiful to hear it can
give that sort of relief to someone and
improve their quality of life in your
personal experience do you feel like the
individual pharmacology is like person
to person or do you think it is like oh
if you have
um this particular issue CBG will work
well for everyone
I would say CBG has a higher efficacy
for most people it does have specific
uses just like anything in their CBN and
other minor cannabinoids that do have
other you know pros and cons but for CBG
it's I would say the Panacea because
it's known as the mother cannabinoid
from what I've been told from chemists
all the other acetates are created from
CBG within the plant so it creates CBD
and terpenes
wow yeah that's really cool to hear uh
just to rewind for a moment I I forgot
to ask you so I want to quickly do it
before we move on in that future
scenario we were talking about where you
know there's like more Federal and maybe
even International legalization of
things where do you think fresh frozen
would sit in that realm do you think it
would be like one of the top dogs or
still something which is you know upper
echelon you know like your high tier
whiskey equivalent of alcohol something
like that
I would say the concentrate Market is
growing steadily if you look at you know
any of the sales on the White Market and
any of the trends uh obviously to take a
nice dab requires a laser thermometer
and a quartz bucket and a torch and so
there's going to be a slow adaptation
when there's a complicated tool set to
anything like that and so that's why you
see a big push to rosin disposable pens
or cartridges and that technology is
going to keep getting better so someone
can just literally
suck on a tube and taste the best rosin
ever
more people are always going to do that
I mean we had a big reggae show here in
Grass Valley and all the guys who breed
and grow cannabis here were excited to
be backstage to give their rosin pen to
Marlin Asher or you know Stephen Marley
or all the guys you know oh fun my
cannabis thing oh we have the best rosin
pen because if you think about it right
the worldwide weed Market happens like
people want a bunch of pens for like
birthday or a party
big wedding celebration oh like we fell
in love over this cannabis flavor and so
we're having it made up in pens so
everyone in our wedding gets one it's
it's just like natural like it's the
flavor it's it's gonna be
easier for a
inexperienced consumer to articulate the
differences of the Cannabis high with
rosin or live resin diamonds as opposed
to normal cannabis fresh frozen allows
for those terpenes to really tip the
scales of is this super exciting is this
super grounding am I super tired is this
cannabis super narcotic if you gave just
a beginner you know Sour Diesel and some
lemon G it'd be hard for them to just
totally
articulate oh okay is this one's super
racy but with that amount of terpenes
hitting your brain at the right time
without any carbon in there it's nice
and clean
no cough if it's done right right that's
a smooth thing for a lot of new
consumers they don't want it to be harsh
or to burn and so all those things are
remedied by doing the fresh frozen
Harvest and going through that work to
extract it
wow what a beautiful answer I I
wholeheartedly agree with all of that
and I've I've got to like tell you this
quick story now because I don't think
I've ever told you this but at one of
the emerald cups one year I think it was
like 2017 2018 you came up to me and you
gave me a dab of this thing I don't
remember what it was but to this day
it's still the turfiest thing I've ever
smoked and honestly it really uh it
really helped me understand how like
some guys can get full into like that
whole I'm the Terps slurper dude like it
was like the light bulb moment for me
and so my question is
do you remember what that dab was by any
chance and like what was your light bulb
moment
let's see here
I remember you had like a little
elephant uh rig that yeah that was what
I took a hit out of it was like a little
elephant I think
oh yeah okay okay so that was definitely
the grape crinkle diamonds yes so
because I you know wanted to be known as
doing something unique in my Lane I was
breeding and I still am breeding
autoflowers also known as Rooter Alice
for concentrates and I wanted to explore
all the new terpenes that were within
that whole realm since at the time there
was just blue dream OG sourdy cherry pie
diamonds that everyone had already tried
you know along with your million
varieties of gelato diamonds that all
tasted the same
so
the rooteralis seemed to make sense uh
it was totally organic unlike light
depth which requires you to build
massive infrastructure and have
greenhouses PVC tarps nine yards you
really put a seed into the Earth if
you're gonna Farm
resin which is what I do and breed resin
for the consumer right to have unique
experiences so
yeah that great crinkle really put me on
the map because it was you know I could
just bring the frozen weed pre uh prop
64. to companies and then they would
make live resin because they knew I
didn't use pesticides and I had a permit
to grow
so everything was great and my diamonds
really got out there and I heard a lot
of cool feedback because no consumers
had ever tried a ruderalis diamond you
know they didn't even know what that is
so this is a great you know kind of
mystery to explore now that I'm seven
years deep in that mystery oh it's a
whole world and there's a lot more to go
yeah
tell me tell me a bit more about your
first experiences growing autos and how
it was you came to be like you know what
this is what I'm going to launch into
so the first time I saw Autos was
2007 and it was right around the time
where we had gotten good at you know
selling weed in San Francisco
and we had our art gallery and
everything was going good and you know
right around a certain time and some are
all the depths would uh sell out so
there'd be no more depths and it'd be
like oh you have to wait till October
for outdoor season you know no one's got
indoor in the summer
and this girl showed up and she had the
most lemony
big buds I I had seen in a long time and
they just looked so fresh I was like
when were these cured she's like oh two
weeks ago I grew them in my backyard in
Oakland it's an Autoflower and I just
was so amazed of the quality and The
Taste and the high and the timing at the
market right right when everyone was
willing to pay whatever and she had it
perfectly and I asked her about it and I
bought a bunch of seeds from different
Autoflower companies
and I had mixed results and finally
found a good breeder a Fisto from Spain
great great guys I work with them and
sent them pictures and
you know made seeds and you know made
extracts sent them lab results and they
were like wow this guy really takes our
seeds seriously so they sent me their
experimental seats so I could get ahead
of the whole ruderalis wave so I could
have my own flavors and
yeah I've you know just been surfing
ever since
man that's so neat to hear
um obviously you know mephisto's
regarded in the industry as a really
top-notch Auto breeder
um what what if the uh the sort of
unreleased lines that they sent you
caught your attention what did you
decide to run with
so about yeah six or nine months before
they released their pink Panama and
their
um
glue strains they're orange glue and
their orange Sunshine strains
um
basically
I had these testers and I was able to
breed with them for you know the live
resin process and because the THC was so
fresh and there was no diseases or spray
or anything because the autoflowers are
so fast
the bugs just couldn't figure it out and
climb onto them and so hearing from the
lab they would say oh the diamonds
crashed out of your thing in like four
days it usually takes three weeks this
is amazing
so I would breed those varieties that
worked for the process of live resin
into the experimental experimental ones
they gave me and people love the pink
Panama it's absolutely amazing yeah
that's so awesome to hear and you got me
thinking is there like any differences
in like selection in terms of how you do
orders versus females because you sort
of allude like you use the lab to help
guide you do you just also use the
general principles of breeding like you
know this is sort of my criteria I like
to see how does it differ
well it's you can't hold on to a trait
it's like riding a wave so when you're
reversing your winner which you're
guessing is a winner from the seed stock
that you've already
ran you're making educated guess and
then you're doing that guess with a few
things and so then now you have a few
different seed stocks from a few
reversed females
and then you test those out and then you
can compare okay so that has the trade I
want this one doesn't so then you move
one into production and you hold on to
the seeds that you can produce more of
what you want just like a hundred and if
you have that hundred then you can make
more of those ones and find more of
something you like or cross it into
something new
so you can't actually hold mom stock at
all you just have to hold
seeds of the winners and basically you
know out of every plant that each one
has to be uniquely marked and you have
to like get the biggest seeds out of
there and test those out uniquely yeah
wow you you answered the next question I
was gonna ask which was like technically
how do you breed Autos but I guess you
just sort of did that do you know of any
other ways because I I can't remember
who but someone said there's like a
chemical you can use that'll like stop
the plant from flowering and I was like
that's interesting I hadn't heard of
that do you know anything about that
um well as far as breeding Autos like
obviously you can have uh regular
autoflowers
um but Mephisto doesn't really let out
regular autos because then it's easy for
you to produce a lot of seeds so I won
one pack of white stomper from Mephisto
in an auction one time
so when you're feminizing seeds you're
using silver thiosulfate and that's a
mixture of chemicals that are going to
block the femininity from being
expressed and your feminine plant is
going to grow balls and those balls
don't have a man
Sheen in there they don't have the
chromosome to make a male so all the
seeds are going to be feminized
so this is a great process if you want
to lock in a trait however if you read
genetic you know warnings after four to
seven generations of feminizing you can
end up in a genetic dead end and have
lots of hermaphrodism and problems so
you kind of want to zip up your Gene
with feminization and then unzip it with
a regular Autoflower seed which is the
work I've recently been doing after
doing five generations of feminization
now I hit it with male autoflowers
wow that's so cool and then is the plan
then to work like sort of fresh
feminized stock Ford that's not in that
bottleneck or do you want to work the
male female stuff just out from there
yeah exactly once you unzip it then you
can zip it back up in a direction that
you want and the direction that I'm
going is to make full melt
trichomes that fall off to make live
rosin
a hundred percent in the Genome of the
autoflowers so once right now it's like
60 you know have the nice tacky wash
look 40 percent are going to be greasy
still and are going to work better for
live resin and B BHO or butane
extraction
yeah wow and I guess while we're here
what are your thoughts on some of the
other forms of concentrate like I'm sure
you don't hate them do you have like a
hierarchy of like concentrates in terms
of like maybe fresh Frozen's at the top
and then other stuff or what's your
thoughts
well you've got your BHO diamonds and
you've got your live rosin so those two
things are premium extracts when done uh
with the genetics that they're supposed
to
you can express flavors that you can
never capture in rosin in live resin
diamonds because butane can capture more
terpenes in a way
in another way a really good rosin has a
unique flavor and a unique High compared
to the diamonds so as long as they're
done right and from the right genetics
it's an amazing experience you've got
your you know tiny trichomes on all your
gelato flavors if someone's going to
grow that to an A plus like an apples
and bananas that makes amazing diamonds
and the flavor comes through but you're
not going to get that deep flavor if you
try and wash that strain but banana OG
and you know strains like that they're
going to make the amazing banana flavor
for bras and new consumers love because
that banana terpene is so smooth and
candy like
that's really interesting to hear and uh
what's your thoughts on straight water
hash because some of the heads you know
they still regard really nice you know
dry sieve or water hash to be in that
Premiere tier what are your thoughts on
it
so I've been making full melts
um for a long time I mean since I've had
my farm and moved into genetics I've
moved away from making my own full melt
and all that but before refresh Frozen
was invented we were all about the full
melt
that was the way to go that was the best
hash you could get from let's see 2005
to 2000
14 maybe so
you know focusing on strains that worked
with that process and made really big
heads made for a great experience I've
had glass blowers design me you know
glass rods and things like this before
dabbing invented so we've had our own
ways to like
smoke it in a way and yeah it was
amazing
um but since the rosin was invented and
since squishing it I mean I've squished
my own flower and rosin it's amazing
just like how uh you have to decarb some
THC to make it work for Edibles and this
whole decarbing process
I guess it goes back to your original
question maybe that I didn't get to
um you asked about pressurized rosin
so like there's the cold cure and you
can whip it but when you have a lot of
cold cure and you're like okay we will
try this people realize that you could
put that cold cure into a vacuum purge
oven which actually you know sucks out
all the air and it's what we used years
ago and we would make butane shatter
so it creates like about 90 degrees
temperature
and 180 moles of pressure similar to you
know out there in outer space or
something like that
and it causes a nucleation and the
terpene separation of the rosin and this
causes a texture change and then you can
load your rosin into pens at the same
time you've caused the terpenes to
change and so they're easy to get into
your brain and it's a clearer quicker
High when you turn your rosin into rosin
Jam there's like that's the tech rosin
Jam Tech or there's rosin Diamond Tech
but only certain strains are going to
work for this process there's certain
finer terpenes that are completely
antagonized if you try to make jam
wow so so variable before I forget I
want to quickly ask you just described
what sounds like making a really nice
rosin that you said you know you might
be able to get into a pen I'm interested
to know like obviously the vape pens are
here to stay so to speak there's always
going to be a big sort of casual Market
that really likes them do you think they
will get better over time or do you
think they will be limited at a certain
point just by sort of the design or the
inputs
I said this at the beginning when Vape
carts were you know first invented that
that we needed a PhD thermodynamic guy
in there to really figure this out and
we need some Physics guys and they all
need to talk together and you know
there's a bunch of corporations that are
jumping on this and they're busting out
pen so far all their failure rates are
too high to you know put your valuable
medicine in there so it kind of hurts
when you know you got the failed
hardware and your consumers like well
[__] you're like all right well here's
another one you know so it's so wasteful
it's like God damn it but there's some
companies using hemp plastic and the
pressure's on right now for that sort of
thing so like they have enough money
they've made enough money from selling
us the [__] B grade carts and
they're gonna have a new line in the
next 10 years that are going to be the
smoothest ever experience that it's
gonna make it so that more people will
dab absolutely
incredible and I mean do you think in
the long term the overall Market will
move away from flowers and more towards
concentrates because as you've alluded
to you know like easy use higher terpene
sort of Expressions if like the inputs
are really good where do you think we're
heading in general
absolutely it matches up with global
scalability uh global Shipping medical
analysis medical efficacy it's just the
raw materials is weed right right it's
like the real raw materials really good
wheat make sure your wheat is the best
so you have the best raw materials
I love that I love that I think people
will kill me if I don't ask so we better
jump into it would you be able to give
us a bit of an overview of what your
process is specifically for making fresh
Frozen
uh sure for like harvesting
in terms of like from Harvest to say
when you've got it in a jar if you could
just touch on some of the major dot
points here you don't have to drill into
Super intense details but just generally
yeah so it all starts with being in line
with the biodynamic calendar we don't
work on off days we work on flower days
this has been scientifically Illustrated
you get higher yields from flower crops
and the seed oils that come from flower
seed crops if you harvest them on flower
days so we're in line with the
biodynamic calendar
and we got a crew of lovely ladies that
comes and harvest the plants every night
the plants have to be cold to the touch
obviously if it's overcast then it's
okay too but you can't Harvest lettuce
in the Sun and then go sell at the
market it'll melt into a pile of mush
right same principles you gotta
disconnect the plant from the earth when
it's cold to the touch ideally at six in
the morning right if you can motivate
your crew you cut down that's when they
have maximum terpene production from
defending themselves from insects all
night so right at six a.m you're going
to have that high terpene production as
soon as the light hits then your
terpenes drop considerably on the plant
every day that cycle happens so
you kind of you know get in there when
you can and then get those plants into
the freezer as fast as you can and you
can't put it all into one freezer all at
a time because then it'll compost in the
middle of itself because it's hot plant
matter
so you gotta bag up 500 to a thousand
grams at a time put it on dry ice or in
a lonely freezer not next to other fresh
frozen weed trying to get Frozen
and make a frozen block and then put it
in the other freezer with the Frozen
weed
it I mean essentially like
if there was someone listening who like
grew up in a Butchery they would
understand all the principles and that's
what I tell people who are trying to
learn I'm like look at how you would
treat a wagyu cow in Japan look at how
Native Americans break down a deer
there's a timing there's a way to
eviscerate an animal and get those vital
nutrients and stakes and organs
backed packed sealed and in a freezer to
celebrate life later and that's the same
kind of principles you got to be on it
and you got a big leaf beforehand so
there's not too much backlog while
you're trying to get it into the bags
you don't want a big leaf too much to
shock the plant while it's alive there's
a balance there
uh obviously you want to look with your
microscope and see your trichomes and
see where everything's at and make your
decisions and when you're freezing you
write greasy or tacky to determine if
it's going to work for what process so
many guys jump into it and think they
can make oh I'm gonna make full melt
live bras and I froze all my weed I'm
like okay and so what did you grow like
oh I grew like low pops it's a gelato
cross
like okay bro so you're gonna see like
one percent of your crop yield into hash
I don't know if that's really going to
pay for anything but you're welcome to
do it
oh so much to go into there I want to
quickly ask what is the track color you
like to harvest at
50 milky 30 milky
um depending on the weather right if
it's 20 milky and it's like seven days
of storm let's go you know
okay cool and is that because like it
continues to mature for a little bit
after that or
uh because sometimes you it's easy to
underestimate how much labor is involved
in the fresh frozen Harvest just like
it's easy to underestimate if you've
never killed an animal and then broken
down all its parts into meat how much
work that is yeah certainly so take me
back to the process so we got the plants
in the freezers they're happy where do
we go from there yes so now they're
either labeled by strain labeled by
their date labeled with a paint pen if
you use a marker in the freezer it all
rubs off and you don't know what's what
you got a bunch of Frozen bricks of weed
that you can guess
uh then you gotta get it to your
extractor right so you've either got to
buy dry ice and put it in totes or a
freezer that you know is frozen and then
if you're driving 30 minutes you can
just unplug a freezer put it into your
truck obviously but
it's yeah it's dangerous so if you're
taking like a three hour mission you
gotta have an open bed flat bed truck
with a generator powering your freezers
while you drive or you're buying a bunch
of dry ice to load into something to
keep it cold just like you know you want
your meat to rot
and once you get to your spot you're
either going to bring stuff that they're
going to crush up and load in for
gassing for butane extraction or you're
gonna throw it into your cold room for
your water extraction and obviously you
want to work with an extractor who has
you know good ice cubes good
understanding of trichomes
the cement mixer you know there's some
people who do it by hand
there's a lot of options as far as that
goes but
there's a lot of details and so you
really want to be on it with your
extractor about like what your
percentage is and how much you're
getting back
there's so many guys and there's only so
much you can do what I do is I grow a
bunch of the same thing and I give fresh
frozen to say resin Ranch full flavor
and Gold Country so now they all know
they have the same Frozen weed from me
so I've created like a little mini
competition who's gonna yield the most
who's gonna make the terpiest out of all
the same material and you see a huge
variance a huge variance
interesting uh before we jump into those
collabs because I noticed them and they
look cool I I've noticed that like it
seems like you're one of the guys who
I I might be going out on a limb here
but it seems like you recognize the
limits of where you want to spread
yourself too thin and you're like I'm
not the guy who does the extraction
because you need to be really
knowledgeable in that area I'm sure
you've got a lot of overlapping
knowledge but is that largely how you
see it where you're like I can't do
everything it would just be spreading
myself too thin I need to have like a
sort of demarcation of where my skill
set is going to finish and I'm going to
focus on this is that how you view it or
have I just confused it a bit
absolutely that you're absolutely
correct yeah I mean I got into hash
before anyone was in hash so in 2001
right I got kilos of hash that I you
know helped people out in college with
in a medical setting under prop 215 and
this hash was from soldiers who were
coming back from Afghanistan and this
[__] was pressed with a gold seal
probably five ten percent opium in there
you know the these kind of full melts
from the international market uh were
the first hashes and everyone was like
wow this is amazing but most people
didn't know what it was didn't know what
it was about so I've always been
interested in resin production and why
cultures got into it and how long the
history of all that and
finally when rosin was came around and I
had already been making full melts and
I knew
the amount of Labor it takes to produce
weed I've worked on many farms and seen
many failures go down
so I'm in an educated position to make a
decision for myself about how I can
change the Cannabis industry space
for the better and it's by focusing in
my lane on what I uniquely know and if I
spread myself too thin like he said oh
I'm gonna wash it and I'm gonna extract
it I'm gonna do all the stuff you know
then you can't focus on the genetics
right and I'd love to get to a point
where I can just have more cuts and more
genetics so that I can just work with
that and move actually out of resin
production itself and into just looking
at resin production and choosing the
best genetics for that process a hundred
percent of the time
beautiful very admirable a man honing
his craft I like that and just to jump
back to what you referenced before you
know you work with these various
extractors and I noticed you had this
what I thought was a really impressive
little collab box you put together with
a Gold Country resin and what I really
found interesting about it was each of
those uh six different offerings in that
box was like a different sort of terpene
dominate concentrate so you're really
giving people all the base colors to see
what see what like the primary colors
are basically I wanted to know what
inspired you to do this because it's
such a neat idea and um yeah what was
the thinking behind that
so I had the first test at SC Labs
um with a rare terpene long ago uh my
friend Alec he is one of the guys who
started that I went to college with him
at UC Santa Cruz
so when I first got into the rooteralis
plants and I had my own rooteralis nugs
I obviously brought it to
SC labs and I was like wow you can do a
terpene test wow and they called me back
and they were like we've never seen this
terpene before at a three percent level
this is amazing what kind of flower is
this and getting that feedback really
did inspire me and send me on the
journey I am today like just going on
like because I was like oh [__] this is
a discovery and there's a lot of rare
kind of things out there right and then
like you said at the beginning how do we
get more people excited about cannabis
well
we're at this point where
because the market and the government
don't get along it's harder for the
consumer to understand what's going on
and so because the White Market people
are losing money and the dispensaries
are losing money and the government is
making it harder for those people the
effect is the consumers are confused
about one of the largest growing markets
with so many products being invented
daily right and so it's very confusing
for someone to go into a store and see
something called live resin and it's
super harsh and it's made from trim
there's no regulations in California and
so they use like CRC Clays and filters
and then blast a bunch of trim and then
call that live resin at the store and so
then people have like these bad
experiences right and then the tech you
know the test on the side it's like 90
THC with a bunch of other numbers and
it's super like
confusing like okay well I I guess I'll
have the 90 instead of the 88 uh yeah
but consumers are just getting you know
literally confused by that information
because the
government doesn't require terpene tests
so what I did is I terpene tested a
bunch of black market rosins that I felt
like people wouldn't really understand
like if they just put their nose over it
I don't know but if I got the terpene
test and showed how all these things
were different and how rosin can you
know bring you up help with workouts
help with sex help with cooking help
with appetite help with all these random
things according to the terpenes then
people could start seeing Oh
oh the mercying that works for me when I
get home from work okay
oh yeah that's what's in papaya okay so
I like papaya because it has Alpha
pinene oh okay and so then people can
start making these decisions for
themselves as opposed to constantly
become being confused about
THC percentages which have little to do
with the high or how the high affects
you
what a great answer and just out of
curiosity do you think that these really
single dominant terpene profiles are
sort of more interesting from your point
of view or do you think like a really
mixed variable one can be equally as
interesting
so yeah that's kind of the world that I
want people to explore right and that's
kind of the world that we want to create
to create the understanding of the
terroir we have to create this language
where people understand that like the
first three terpenes are gonna very much
dictate the effects and so I got those
first four on there and yeah most people
were very surprised even Gold Country
himself he was like wow I can't believe
so many rosins are just high in limonene
I thought that GMO and papaya were so
different but they're both
have limonene as the dominant terpene
but the secondary terpene is different
in both of them
so it kind of teaches people about like
their nose and what our sense of smell
is and I feel like that's really
important in this world is our sense of
smell is our sense of instinct it's
connected to our memory there's a lot of
things trying to disconnect us from our
sense of smell and having this terpene
Kit allowed people to do their own self
research right a bio essay like the
medical term for how you felt when you
took your dab you know
like and then people can actually have a
language like oh okay well they can go
into the club and say hey so I Got This
research kit and this one with mercine
and beta-cariothalene in equal amounts
really actually work the best out of all
of them do you have anything like that
and that's the kind of nuanced question
that will put pressure on the bud
tenders to put pressure on the Growers
to get the terpene test and some Growers
and rosin manufacturers are already
doing this uh one company out of Oregon
would put a little terpene chart in
there so I was really impressed with
that with each gram yeah but not much
explanation about that effect so that's
where we need to flesh everything out
yeah brilliant hopefully it becomes a
more Mainstay of the labeling and uh you
can get a better idea of what's going on
under the hood but you you mentioned it
twice and it's sort of been on my mind
why do you think papaya is getting such
a big Resurgence at the moment
so first of all uh they're dropping the
market value of dried flour is going to
change everything
um uh that's gonna push people to look
for cuts that work for hash
and papaya has an amazing flavor and it
always hits above four or five percent
if you get the good papaya cut
and so you're gonna get you know your
economic value out of that and you're
going to get your rosin yields so that
your washer gets his percentage
and
globally speaking most people haven't
had a papaya you know like it's still
exotic as [__] so when you tell people
oh hey like I remember saying oh I've
got papaya and you know after saying it
to however many people who come up to my
booth one person's like what's a papaya
and I was like oh [__] yeah because
papaya is so exotic some people just had
like the fruits that they know of and so
it's just it's just gonna keep spreading
papaya and oh and personally I feel that
the high is like you know like similar
it's got a little bit more relaxation on
the muscles but it's got a lot of Mind
engagement and we'll keep you going in
the day and help with sore muscles yeah
perfect so we've been talking a bit
about the papaya strain and I wanted to
ask you about your durian strain my
buddy osgrown Exotics shout out he he
wants a durian strain he's got his heart
set on it so tell me about yours what's
it like
all right so the durian project is
hitting onion Fritter into the papaya
so uh we have like the Charlotte Sashimi
from tea bezel and that's a good rosin
strain that gives it a Savory uh terp
profile
so if you hit that with Papaya we think
that within that seed stock that we'll
find like the true durian expression
yeah beautiful so you reckon you're just
a little more hunting and you'll be
there yeah that's the goal right now is
we're trying to find uh the durian and
passion fruit the passion fruit project
is forbidden fruit legendary OG hit with
bodhi's lemon hash plant version two
and the durian project is the
uh shallot shashimi
and and papaya cross together yeah my
friend you just made my day that you're
doing a passion fruit project half the
time when I talk to people about passion
fruit they they don't they like what you
said earlier it's an exotic fruit some
people aren't like they're not familiar
with it and whatnot but
I've got a passion fruit line I'm
working on we need to trade seeds my
friend my one is uh triangle pupil so
like TK by Pakistani star pupil by
raspberry Mama which is like a pink
Champagne sort of thing if you remember
that from back in the day oh I love pink
Champagne yeah right so perfect I'm
gonna remember that I'm gonna send you
some seeds because yeah I too have long
been looking for a passion fruit strain
and sometimes you get close but you're
not quite there and it would be really
neat to find one
yeah I was just talking today with uh
the village guys uh who found like the
Amarillo that's what they're saying is
there some females within the Amarillo
or expressing passion fruit some of them
more pineapple so I haven't been able to
find the Amarillo cut I'm doing my
breeding project here starting hopefully
before the ego Clash
um we've got lots of winners lined up
from this year that I've made into
clones and yeah we're gonna do the honey
bananas since it's my favorite rosin and
it won the ego Clash
we're reversing the honey bananas into
as many winning Cuts as I can find
ideally if I can do the honey bananas
into Amarillo I think we'll find
something there I have the sun Satsuma
sherbet
and the Purple Rain which is a masonic's
chop Wilson Fino Hunted
and
the tropical drank which is a Hindu
pineapple Hindu Skittle crossed into
orange Skittle
I love it so many Avenues to dive down
before we jump off the topic we've been
talking about some Australian stuff I
was interested to know what's your
experience with the Australian genetics
yeah I had one worker uh did come back
from Australia she met an Aboriginal guy
and he gave her seeds and I crossed that
onto like gelato and ancient OG and a
few others
to make Aussie lotto and yeah right I
was gonna ask you so I wanted to ask you
specifically about that because we you
gave me a pack of the Aussie Lotto I
brought it back to Australia
um and I think my buddy grew it out on
his farm in the far Northern Rivers like
near that real hot spot of Australia
like that nimbin sort of area and um
yeah I wanted to ask you do you remember
much about that Australian line you used
yeah it was amazing absolutely
yeah it had super cool structure super
vigorous growth and uh
you know drought resistance
what did it look like because I imagine
it might be similar what I was talking
about because they're phenomenal plants
Outdoors but it's just the effects not
really my thing
it had the structure of yeah kind of old
school White Widow
um
you know not anything like we have here
that's for sure
it wasn't round at all you know like no
no round big buds ever
small little bracks yeah yeah wow
interesting that's um that's very
interesting to hear I'm trying to get my
hands on uh a line in Australia called
Zoid fuel which was made by these guys
back in the day they're on the Forum
they were called um the Wizards of Oz
but I guess the interesting thing about
this line is it's the only really
notable line where there's any info on
it where it was bred from a hundred
percent
non-european or American stock
and it's just made from three land races
it's made from a Chinese Yuan uh a PNG
gold and like an Australian sort of you
know heirloom sativa sort of thing and
um it looks like a real modern strain
like it's one of those sort of like I
think Neville spoke about it once where
he was like I could never do something
like that like spin together a couple of
land races to make something that looks
like modern sort of stuff but yeah
there's this lion Zoid feel it's meant
to be super racy from the PNG gold high
like just real
anxiety-inducing and so I'm like give me
more of that and um yeah I'm trying to
get my hands on it if I ever do I'll be
sure to get you some because I reckon
it'd be right up your alley as well
oh absolutely
um yeah speaking of land races we've got
a 16-footer that just made it through
three rainstorms completely unharmed
zero molds
I
uh had my mother she was going to
Tanzania and I was like oh I want the
seeds you know if you meet anyone give
me the seeds and she met these tribal
people who gave her real wild Tanzanian
seeds and I found a male that you know
dropped pollen on like
November 10th you know I was like oh it
opened up then and so
I had my farm manager at the time had
gone over to yoga School in Southern
India to Karnataka
and she got wild weed that was amazingly
purple she picked the purplest you know
and brought it back the seeds just real
land race from India and so I made a
Tanzanian India cross and that's that's
what's growing right now yeah
it'll be done by Thanksgiving
man that's incredible were you getting
any interesting sniffs off it yet
yes honestly I forgot like well I grew
those and they were just getting so big
and had zero smell and now
wow they are amazing they smell nothing
like anything in my garden nothing even
close and I've done this before you know
everyone knows you're not going to get a
lot of biomass or Bud off of it it's
going to be low yielding
but from experience you put 20 30
percent of that biomass in with
something regular and then make your
live resin diamonds
a hundred percent of the consumers
notice they're like this land race terp
it's amazing I've never felt anything
like this so it's worth it
wow that's so interesting you remind me
of a like a talking point Bodhi
mentioned to me years ago which is like
just like not not restricted to one
specific area but in general the whole
art of blending is not really being
explored that much in cannabis whether
we're talking about like blending
strains or blending like cannabis with
other plants what's your thoughts on
blending do you think it's got a spot do
you think it's the future so I've been
dealing with blending from the beginning
since I've been fresh freezing and so
there's a minimum batch size for your
diamonds six thousand grams and then
there's your minimum batch size for
water hash sometimes 20 000 grams so
you've got to think about what's going
to work because I have Blended stuff and
then I tried it and I was like oh
dang it I totally Blended that one and
one of the terpenes is now completely
overpowered and you remember those
mistakes because you kind of know
intuitively like how much people would
have been impressed if that had been
pulled off and then you're like people
will never know
oh man that's a shame
yeah so there's gonna be winners and
there's gonna be losers and you
basically want to do like your cakey
strains with like a little bit of lemon
right and you don't want to mix super
fruity unique strains like you wouldn't
want to mix apples and a papaya so you
wouldn't if if I had apple fritter and
papaya I would mix them both rather with
like a cush mince or something
instead of together because then they
would antagonize each other's flavors a
lot of times they do Dosey dough is a
good background for any of the fruity
ones wow yeah just even listening to
this makes me realize like I don't have
anything meaningful to say because I've
got no idea about this right it's such a
novel field
uh yeah I mean last year at the ego
Clash a blend one so now that's kind of
like standard where people are like
putting it on the label like okay uh
this is my new flavor you know it's 30
this 30 that and thirty percent this you
know
so it's telling you that they're putting
three flavors together that they think
will work good together people have been
blending rainbow belts and Dosey dough a
lot and the moonbow blending that into
pure rainbow belts so it's like more
Moon bow-ish yeah wow interesting stuff
and I guess
the idea of blending in general I you
know it's been proven as a an effective
Concept in other Industries like you
know wine and spirits but but also it
lends itself as you were saying earlier
to the scale up of massive Ag and being
able to acquire a bunch of concentrates
and blend them together to make your
Jack Daniels number seven so to speak
foreign yes now that is the ultimate
goal right the one rosin Corporation
right all small farmers were in the one
rosin Corporation where all have our
name is one legally so none of us can be
taxed and we can produce the best rosin
because we all have so much of
everything that we can do huge terpene
analysis and then always make the most
potent of each of the thing the same
time but the problem is is there's a
huge variance in terpene expression grow
to grow because of the seasonal change
of temperatures even within indoor the
outside affects that and the soil and
the grow technique and the water PH and
so you're seeing a still a wide variety
of that sort of thing and I think the
nutrient companies working with the
Breeders is going to change that
so just to bring it back to the last
question you mentioned working with
Masonic and I saw that you'd done some
collabs with big mace tell me a little
bit about that and um what sort of
things we can expect from those seeds
yeah so this year
um we ended up with lots of seed stock
from last year's biodynamic project
where we tried to you know torture the
hell out of all the males and you know
put them next to russet-made infected
plants and the whole nine yards
and break them in half rip off their
balls time uh the days it takes for the
balls to regenerate
we start with the hundred males
and so last year the Wilson's cake
Crasher
uh just had an amazing Vigor no matter
what you did ripped it down broke it in
half it still was growing just like
normal
so I had already had experience with
females making good rosin
and I had
my nice fruity you know lemon fat man's
that I'm wanting to increase their rosin
yield and hold on to that lemon terp so
I figured the Wilson cake Crashers a
good project
and with the whole Wedding Crasher
Wilson name you know and then the lemon
fat man we figured of calling it like
Owen Wilson or just Owen after that
movie right
so basically we'll have the different
costumes that Owen has played throughout
his like Hollywood career as the
different final hunts as we go through
the different frozen plants of this seed
variety
so people will get to try uh sour Owen
offensive Owen
uh lemon Owen you know
yeah and um you know I obviously
I'm pretty
um undogmatic as far as like seed guys
go like I go to places where I trade
seeds I go to the seed swaggle I trade
I'm I'm down you know I've been going to
Emerald cup for a long time
and
yeah Masonic was just always down to
trade and when it came time to like put
seeds in the earth like I must have
grown 30 breeders my first year here on
the farm in 2015 and
you know you just freeze them and then
you look at the numbers right like you
look at who survived who just fell over
and all the bugs ate you up
and yeah masonics always hit above four
percent for our live rosin process
always
and even ones that you know didn't look
that healthy still made good rosin so
like other plants you know they would
look uh pretty good and then give us two
percent
so eliminated those and
yeah so we need someone who's passionate
and excited about keeping the flavors
going so
pass the test and he's a nice guy so
there you go
that's all the information I need I mean
I've seen so many people say that their
seeds are so fancy and charged so much
for them
and they look good too and then they
just don't perform so
proof's in the pudding you know I think
everyone needs more science in their
life and less Dogma
I love that yeah it definitely proof's
in the pudding I've been trying to
factor that more into my explanation of
things but I'd love to know I feel like
that trop flavor is on like oranges in
general I think are coming back into
Focus I think they died off for a bit
now they're coming back I'd love to know
because I think you would have your
finger on the pulse more than most
anyone what flavor do you think is going
to be the next big thing to hit the
scene and what do you think in general
of the scene at the moment
well let's see I mean you know how Bloom
Seed Co you know you're familiar with
them
yep so I got their drop you know of the
uh strawberry guava Tropicana cookies
uh and their pink marshmallow cross the
strawberry guava
but as far as
um
yeah chop cookies man
I had this indoor chop cookies from
heads that roll who won the ego Clash
the last few years
I I've never seen pink rosin until now
it was bright pink I I'm telling you
I've never seen anything like this they
pressed it was such a low temp to
preserve some of the purple anthocyanins
and so it made this pink rosin
and my God the high was the strongest
most effective
for like athletic performance like I hit
this before the skate park and I had the
best skate of my life and then I put
away that gram and would only hit it
right before I was going to the skate
park Forever After
so I'm gonna be growing the chop cookie
crosses this 2023 here
that's beautiful to hear and you just
reminded me I remember that last video
you posted of you shredding it up at the
skate park like it made my day to just
see someone crushing it on the blades
how long you been doing it for
let's see it started at 14 yeah so
well that's a long time yeah more than
25 years yeah I can still go higher
in the air than all the skateboarders or
scooters hey
I'm strapped in I can do flips I'll be
40 in January I don't know how many 40
year olds who don't have any gray hair
and still do flips at the skate park so
I think there's something to me giving
up smoking weed and shifting my whole
life to the future of dabs and fresh
frozen and if I can be that example I I
am right like I am the living example if
you're falling apart because you switch
to 100 dabs No One's Gonna follow you
down that road
wow before I forget I gotta encourage
everyone to go to your page look at that
video it's it's incredible but to follow
up on what you just said that's
interesting so so yeah so your no flower
your just dabs are you like low temp
only is there any other components to
sort of this lifestyle you adhere to
yeah seven years uh low temp dabs
um some you know vape pens no desolate
you know nothing weird only stuff from
my farm or from my friend's Farms
um
yeah I would say everyone man uh woman
especially if you're in your 30s please
get a testosterone test get a hormone
test figure out where you're at
and if you need to change your diet
because you're too dogmatic maybe it's
time and listen to science because
that's what helped me I had insomnia I
had all sorts of issues now I run my own
business with five employees we have
seeds going to all over the world Peru
Austria recently you know like it takes
Health to make a healthy successful
business it takes a lot within yourself
I see a lot of people get successful and
then the next year just falls apart
because they can't maintain
so you have to invest always with
yourself I've eaten a lot of my
investments you know I've made money and
then I'll just eat really good food hey
and get really healthy and then you can
do a lot more
that is some incredibly Sage advice
which I would urge everyone to take on
board for sure it definitely is an
investment in yourself that's worth
doing
I wanted to ask quickly
if you had theoretically unlimited
resources or maybe like you're even a
bit in the future where you you know
there's like a little more technology
than what currently exists what do you
think will be the absolute ultimate way
to extract cannabis resin in a sense
because you got me thinking you know
with the the pink rosin you spoke about
it's like okay that's like the next
level up they've done like a bit of a
game changer there so what do you think
theoretically will be like the ultimate
you can foresee
so if you talk to some scientists and
some extraction artists they say the
ultimate thing would be like
like a cold tube like a cold trap like
without water without anything just to
conveyor belts and a tube and by the
time the weed the product gets to the
end
it's gone through pure sublimination
so if you could sublimely separate those
tbhc parts it would be you know we're
talking
hundreds of millions of dollars and
Engineers but yes you could extraciate
you through sublimination through the
process of the temperature changing
itself rapidly wow and so what it would
it would essentially go from being in
the trichome to just turning into gas
and then collecting it somewhere I mean
if you could get it to absolute zero
super quick then everything might just
fall apart if it was just on a conveyor
belt with a 90 U Micron screen
underneath yeah with nanotechnology you
know to separate all the little bits to
capture the bits before that part right
wow yeah that's interesting it is it is
cool to think yeah what's what's
possible but there you go food for
thought I'm really interested to hear
that to take us back to just a question
before when you were talking about
growing the various breeders outdoor I
would love to ask who are some breeders
who you've generally been impressed by
their work well obviously third gen
Brandon uh all his amazing Skittles
stuff is you know super time tested from
his farm so it has that genetic work
um one of the guys who's moved into the
Consulting space dragon with matches
always had outstanding genetics
um
bodies or staple guy now he's going to
be mainstream because of his burner deal
which I think is good yeah
he needs to get paid he's done so much
work
I mean for so long you know uh
well there's a bloom Seed Co is just
killing it because they were breeding
for a full melt before rosin that's the
thing they were just making thankful
melt seeds and then so they have a head
start on a lot of people right now
um Bloom seed code just took you know
the smoking jacket with cannabis Chris's
extraction and growing skills
um they found like a pineapple Empanada
Fino
very specific
um but yeah I mean I've been put in
seeds in the earth and seeing you know
who does well like for so long I mean I
was able to give that Aussie Lotto to
[__] because he came to the ego Clash
one year
so
hopefully cookies realizes that you know
they should start a tribal fund for
Aborigines and grow that strain out and
they can make a bunch of PR and money
right definitely definitely well I
wanted to quickly ask because you
referenced Brandon there and in past
questions you reference the ego Clash
what's your thoughts on the current
state of the cups because I've noticed
like more and more people seem to be
more excited for these smaller more
organic based events like the ego clash
and the general trend is that things
like the emerald cup sort of feel like
they're dying off what's your analysis
of the state of the industry in that
respect
you're absolutely correct it was
heartbreaking to see because I've had
fun with you there I've given you a
mind-blowing dab that changed your mind
right like that's why I went to Emerald
cup that's why it existed but that [__]
is gone that [__] has changed and that
[__] is no more last year was The
Ultimate slap in the face of like let's
allow a huge beer garden from the
biggest corporate beer thing we can
think of and let's push all the small
farmers into one area so no one can
actually see how cool they are spread
out and let's harass them with their
displays because they're showing people
weed that they would smell in a jar and
then they could buy in a bag that's it
let's let's harass them so like the
[__] Bureau of cannabis control came
out there all karen like like super
Karen's like let's stop this are these
guys trading hash or are you selling it
we're gonna have to confiscate this and
it was like so different in all the
years before and you could tell like
they didn't even know what they were
doing and it was like this whole you
know social media blitz with the
Humboldt local and got a shot of them
being all [__] shady and harassing
everyone like we're just people dude
we're just you're the state you're
supposed to help us what are you talking
about like get the [__] out of here dude
like we are good people and we make
seeds we're not the cartel you're
looking for how are they producing all
this pounds and you're here at the
emerald Cup right like come on yeah so
the whole thing fell apart and it just
went corporate and there was so much
douchery and so much trickery and like
you could go up to like a booth and be
like oh like hey could I see the weed
and they're like no like you can't just
smell the hash you can't smell the weed
like uh like and like some booths would
be like okay [__] it we're gonna break
the rule here you can like smell the
weed but you can't hold it or you can't
like see it up close like Jesus Christ
dude do you know how to do business or
do you just like and then like all the
free giveaways couldn't give away
something free so I had like this
ridiculous penny jar so it's like one
penny jars filled with pennies and
another one's filled with like nothing
and so you take one penny and put it in
the other jar and so they're like no
here's a free joint saves a pay like all
these wastes of time bureaucracy like
absolutely horrible these people from
Sacramento who made up these laws have
never taken the time to farm anything in
their [__] lives I wish they would I
wish that the governor had made it so
that agronomists and
um like people with degrees in
universities within our system would
hire people who knew about plants to
work for the Bureau of cannabis control
instead instead they hired people who
knew nothing about anything
and so now we're left with this space of
unelected officials you know essentially
stopping the largest global cannabis
Market in the world
what a uh apt analysis I guess it's fair
to say you won't be going to the emerald
Cup this year
no we're gonna do the eagle Clash we're
gonna serve waffles at the Eagle clash
and then we're gonna go to T bezel's
birthday for the next day and surf
waffles again
beautiful man I was thinking of going to
the emerald cup but I was like I can't
bring myself to buy a ticket
like even the scene has changed like
last year I even wanted to see the
headliner and this year the headliner is
like E-40 and all these gangster rappers
who aren't that good so the whole thing
is yeah
gone down the tubes I mean I'd love to
hear in general your analysis and sort
of thoughts on the current state of the
legislation I mean a lot of people feel
like small farmers are perpetually being
pushed out of the industry it's it's
hard to have a small scale operation
where do you see the need for change in
the laws what would you like to see
changed
yeah as I've said before you know
[__] worldwide weed blockchain
analysis of the terpenes to market the
information the genetic analysis to show
the terroir to show the pharmaceutical
Industries and then boom I can sell my
specific thing to Israel if they want to
research it I can sell it to some sick
person in Germany
um yeah absolutely because there's a lab
here I should be able to just bring them
the pound they can process it give me
the magic stamp give it to an
exportation business that deals with the
state to Interstate to inter-country
Commerce and boom there you go everyone
gets paid and small farming continues
there needs to be stricter regulations
because like what I said before the
there's no agronomists there's no people
who are bought in this who are working
within the law so they're actually
allowing for all this poison to like
come out where people are feeding and
spraying too late and a lot of the
pesticides that are allowed on the White
Market will make for a shitty experience
for the consumer in the end run and if
they're prohibited it would make it
harder to grow cannabis at scale and
thus less people would enter the market
or fail miserably
so it's this whole thing where it's like
the ethics of Organics can protect the
small craft farmer because doing
Organics at scale will never compete
because it always goes crazy and falls
down on its face because that's not what
it's meant to be it's not meant to be
scalable
out of curiosity what do you think is
the upper limit that an organic facility
could operate at if someone was like you
know I'm happy to accept your advice you
can't scale infinitely but where what do
you think is the upper limit because
I've been having discussions with
friends about everyone wants to call
themselves craft but it's like if you've
got a certain you know if you've got a
10 Acre Farm is that craft if you've got
a Hundred Acre you know what I mean like
where does Craft end I guess and what's
the upper limit for organic indoor in
your opinion yeah I mean the whole craft
thing and small batch and Nano batch and
all these discussions are you know
they're great because that's what we
need we need to Define this kind of
undefinable thing that's gonna help
perpetuate small craft Farmers to thrive
and help those who don't want to stay
that transition into something that will
Thrive that won't compete with them
right
so I would love it if I saw like uh you
know a five acre cap right and like yeah
if you've ever seen five acres of
production like it doesn't look anything
small or craft I mean I've seen 3.5
Acres that looks insane like a wall to
what 3.5 Acres takes a hundred people
so like how many employees do you have
to manage like when is it small craft I
feel like once you go above like
like
if you get to like 20 people
to like run the farm
that's not a small craft Farm you're
having team meetings you've got multiple
employees you've got multiple shift
managers
you know what I mean
like it's big that's bigger it's hard to
yeah it's hard to like if like 10 people
can like manage all that and then have a
crew come in and harvest then [__] more
power to them right
but yeah the small craft farmer will
always be defined because that's what it
is like you can just literally test all
the stuff and see that anything big does
not make the good terpenes anything fit
all the salts doesn't have all the fancy
terpenes
so I think it's more about the market
understanding what it needs and thus
demanding that and then the mar all the
people who produce will have to flex to
that or realize that they can't Flex to
that and try something else
instead of competing with us
we haven't spoke about it much yet but
obviously you know you're an organic
biodynamic guy tell me what's the
difference between like synthetic or
salt-based concentrates what's the thing
you notice is the difference
so my friend uh started growth science
nutrients they have an organic line and
a
conventional line or synthetic line and
yeah I ran my auto flowers I had the
opportunity to run the same strain
completely organic and completely
synthetic freeze the material label it
extract it and the synthetic material
made larger diamonds less terpenes and
considerably less yield 1.5 percent out
of the total biomass weight however the
biomass growth was at least
40 to 30 percent more
so the Organics grew smaller had smaller
flowering sites extremely like
3.5 and 4 percent yield versus a 1.5
percent yield on your fresh Frozen
and smaller diamonds more terpenes
interesting interesting I mean a lot of
people would sort of say that that's
that's very much in line with sort of
the conventional things we hear in terms
of Organics you know maybe yields a
little less but higher quality you know
definitely
and I wanted to ask you because you're
so involved in the the sort of
concentrates realm does that spill over
for you into the Edibles Realm
absolutely yeah we've been making you
know chocolates and gummies and taffies
I've been making chocolates for what 20
years now so I've always made Edibles
and loved the infusion and the
difference between the edible High and
the dabbing or smoking High
that's Incredibles I want to know what's
your go-to edible I've just recently
gained a better appreciation for them so
I'd love to hear what's your favorite
uh so when you make like you know rosin
you get like the 45 you is like the food
grade you know and then like there's the
90 you which is like the like dabbing
grade and like 120 is like still dabbing
grade so there's a few grades right but
when you make rosin you have some like
food grade where it could you know
collect some particulates or some plant
matter and stuff like that but mostly
the process is down where it doesn't
have anything like that and it's still a
smooth smoke it's just not you know as
potent right so that's what we would use
for our Edibles and uh the Gold Country
collab we did came out really good so we
like send you know all this 40 you rosin
down to these Master Bakers in La uh
honey and uh honey chocolates company
and the um
Starfire Edibles people and then they
you know use half of the rosin for their
Edibles and then they make a bunch of
Edibles with the other half with us and
then send it packaged back
so then essentially we have all these
like Gourmet donuts and vegan donuts and
handmade marshmallows handmade wipes
pumpkin pumpkin spice chocolates all
with rosin
and they'll send back 15 flavors of
chocolates 17 flavors of donuts
wow what a what a plethora do you find
that um you get different effects based
on the strain input or by the point
where you're at like a donut it's it's
more of a homogeneous sort of feeling
so this is a big discussion right now
with all the edible makers and all the
rosin guys big time I'm really glad you
asked this because I have a particular
perspective so the rumor is it's not
confirmed Is that West Coast Alchemy to
achieve their wet look on a hundred
percent of their 90 you not all
cultivars will you know release a 90 you
that looks wet is that they do a terpene
separation on the 40u and some cultivars
produce amazing terpenes that are caught
in the 40u bag when you're making live
rosin and making bubble hash
and so basically you can put
the 40u and squish it for like six hours
at super low temp and put it at an angle
and you'll you'll separate all the Terps
will drip out into a jar
and the thca will be left
and you can take those terpenes and then
add it to your 90u and now your 90u
looks super wet and glistens
and so
basically most cooking processes are
going to destroy your volatile terpenes
so all these strain specific terpene we
put the rosin in there I'm like nah like
I've made gummies okay I've made them
with all this and I know about terpenes
and volatilization so when you're
boiling that sugar mixture to make your
gummies all the terpenes are gone
they're gone
so it doesn't make any sense for the
rosin makers to do it other than that
it's extra work so it's lazy so it's
like you have a bunch of four to you
just give it to the edible maker and
then give me some edibles back and I can
call it the strain that it is
but really they should be separating the
terpenes so that people can dab that
and then giving the edible makers pure
decarbed thca
interesting interesting and I guess
maybe the underlying question behind the
last question was do you think that the
terpenes for the most part are what
dictates the effect like do you think if
you stripped it all away and you've just
got the THC percent there and maybe a
few minor cannabinoids that it's all
going to seem quite generic
absolutely
brilliant I love it I love it okay so I
wanted to ask you I'm surprised I
haven't asked already what's the most
unique Terps you've ever come across
so the unique terpene that I found
um was when my mom was over in Amsterdam
getting me some rooteralis seeds and she
actually got me unfeminized ruderalis on
accident some CBD one to one ruderalis
seeds and we bred that into mephistos
and I brought that to the lab and they
found uh this terpene called borneol
as the dominant terpene and they had
never found this before and they had
just had a meta data scientist plot all
000 successful terpene tests that they
have done on cannabis into a chart to
show them and they showed me how almost
80 percent is Mercy and dominant and
then there's some Piney ones and some
jack ones and a few others and how mine
was like they've never seen borneol at
3.3 percent as the dominant terpene had
always been a super super small amount
0.0001 or 01 or in other cannabis so
that really sent me on my whole thing uh
recently I've seen lab results for the
cranberry Skittles cross and it's got
some high amounts of eucalyptol which
I'm absolutely in love with this flavor
of like I feel like that's a good
Australia kind of thing right if we can
get the cranberry Z there grow it under
eucalyptus will it express more
eucalyptol I think so so
so
I love it that's the Mad scientists
experiments we gotta we gotta make them
happen yeah so
I guess I'd love to hear like what uh
what's your advice for someone who wants
to get into breeding some Autos is there
anything you wish you could tell
yourself looking back with what you know
now
always save 10 C's of everything that
you grow
so that if you grow everything out and
you find a winner and your pollination
is not successful you haven't lost that
line forever
um yeah and then always unzip and zip so
feminize one year and then unfeminize
the next year
and know what to look for in males and
time your mails stress your males look
up close at the trichomes of your males
and
keep track of everything that's the
hardest part yeah because if you have
seeds that don't get labeled they're
like ah
it's a lot to keep track of that's great
advice I'd love to follow up what's your
characteristics for picking an auto mall
because you just mentioned some of them
have resin like do you do you put a lot
of weight or emphasis on that in terms
of that smell being a trait passes on or
is it more complex
so I'm looking at branching I'm looking
at how many ball sacks and how close
together the ball sacks are growing and
the internodal and the Vigor and when
you're feminizing you know oftentimes if
you know the seed is a winner and you
like know it's from an established
breeder who's won awards and you spent a
bunch of money on like five [__]
seeds and you want to make more
basically you just want to look for the
first one that expresses sexuality
the first one that expresses that hair
you [__] take that separately and you
spray that down and start reversing her
that's the secret
wow yeah that makes sense I like that a
lot okay so just so I understand it
basically all auto strains more or less
like are exactly what you've described
where like you have to just test out the
progeny and you don't really get to know
because the parents get burnt off in the
process
yes and breeding long season into
autoflowers is five generation four
generation process because it's a
recessive trait so like I hit something
you know male with an Autoflower and
only ten percent maybe five percent will
be Autoflower out of that seed stock the
first F1 generation
and then would you just F2 them for a
bunch more Generations until you go
close to a hundred percent or how would
you go from that F1 cross to the point
of being like hey I've now got gelato
Auto
so basically you would have to start out
with some Autoflower that you had right
and then hit it with something you
wanted and
that first generation of those seeds you
basically would kill off 90 of the seed
stock because you can tell that it's not
going to Autoflower within the timing
right so you're just like casting hello
seeds being like oh this is going long
kill it you know
so one out of ten is gonna like go quick
right and so then you either have your
feminized pollen ready to paint on or
you're feminizing something actively so
that it ties up with that release so the
ovum and everything's ready so you can
make some seeds but it's not easy that's
why feminist autoflowers are expensive I
mean I've done successful runs three
times in a row and then I failed three
times in a row afterwards and each time
a unique thing happened that stopped me
and it was so unique that it I couldn't
you know perceive that it was going to
happen
wow okay and and do you think by four or
five generations you could have pretty
reasonable certainty that when you do
the Femme reversal to sort of make the
seeds you plan to sell that they're all
going to be auto four or five
generations
yeah
absolutely yes I do you know 1000c 2000
C tests before I release them so that
there's no Herms and no Autos absolutely
that's brilliant and what do you think
in general is going to be the future of
autos because there's obviously this
ongoing discussion about like is it ever
going to be as good as a photo like
what's your thoughts do you think we're
almost there and what do you foresee
them doing primarily in the future as
like a tool
so I had this uh responded to this post
dungeon Vault genetics who I really like
all this work and stuff he posted like
why does everyone grow out of like he's
actually grown my Autos he likes him but
he was just like posing this question
why are people grow Autos if like
everything else is so much better and
they're so much better weed and I was
like well if you feel that way sounds
like a business opportunity to me sounds
like a consumer opportunity to me if
consumers are constantly disappointed by
autoflowers sounds like someone hasn't
done the [__] work and I'm willing to
do that work so hey let's do it and
let's use the lab right like that's how
Mephisto got famous is they got a cut of
the first lab tested proven above 22 THC
to reverse into Auto that's literally
how they did it they didn't do it with
[__] magic they got the first lab
tested cut that was above 20 back in the
day when you couldn't find that
you mean they're Auto tested at that or
they use that as a mother stock
yes exactly to make their first Auto to
get away from all these low percentage
Autos that were all made from Low Rider
and everyone had a bad taste in their
mouth and Autos they
got what I can't remember what it's like
one of the oldest guys you've had them
on your show too
um he passed away recently
um bog yeah bog bog yeah so yeah so they
that's how they made their first Autos
was a bog and a ruderalis that was not a
um you know the shitty ones from before
and then they reversed his four
generations to make their first thing
yeah wow what cool backstory I didn't
know that and um I'd be curious to hear
your thoughts on low rider in general
you know because you don't really hear
much from that dude who made it I forget
his name um but yeah what's your
thoughts on it
well it's just like the best he could do
at the time before gastromatography and
testing so then it just didn't have ever
above 12 Tac so no one really wanted to
grow it once people started to see what
potency was and figure out light depth
it's like no [__] reason but it had
its place for a couple years but as soon
as they figured out up above 20 THC in
autosin it's on and everyone was blown
away when I would bring it to the lab
and they were like this isn't light up
like what they were so impressed to make
diamonds out of this stuff and you know
all the guys who work at the lab they
run through thousands of pounds of
material so whenever they see mine
they're like oh look at this a unique
smell I love this Ritter Alice it's got
the fresh rain turp it's got the fresh
you know this terp oh wow
well and do you think that stock the low
rider was unfortunately like backed into
a corner in that it would be hard to
salvage it so to speak
exactly like I've abandoned many of my
genetics already you know because I
marked them dead ends because I can tell
yeah you have to abandon the seed stock
of the Autos or just extract it all and
not market for breeding once you
understand the traits that it's
expressing or not gonna help the future
like what I said the future of
autoflowers is full melt Auto flowers
from all the best breeders so that no
one can copy it so everyone can get a
little bit of a little bit of hash every
year
we can make that culture from Amsterdam
like for New York City have that [__]
you know grow outside of my little
apartment on the windowsill
yeah nice nice and and do you plan to
ever do
um some more photo period breeding or do
you think you're just gonna stick to
orders for the moment
um yeah we're always doing Auto flowers
and regulars um just because of the way
the market uh is right now you know like
there were not to the point where we
want the full metal Autoflower so we
have to keep working with all the nice
full Mount regular genetics and keep
figuring out what the trending terpene
profiles are uh this year I work with
the Chile Verde male and the 24 karat
gold mail
resin ranches picked them out and they
passed a lot of my tests so we're gonna
see a lot of cool Chili Pepper crosses
like shishito I hit the cake bomb
Skittles with the chili verde
um I'm most excited about are lemon cane
number 66 from mashuk he hunted the
lemon cane to work for the rosin process
really well kind of like how I wanted my
lemon fat man
and I hit the Chile Verde onto that and
so right now there is a flavor Trend
within Latin culture and within
California of this flavor called tahin
I don't know if you know about tahin oh
yeah but yeah we'll be released we'll be
releasing lemon tahin at ego Clash on
the 9th oh yeah oh bro so we'll have
Tajin flavored rosin oh dude you're
gonna have to cross that to um something
watermelon flavor you know the old
staple tahin and watermelon okay so we
have the chamoy do you know about chamoy
so that's the other spice that you
actually put on watermelon so I got the
watermelon ice from Cano research which
is garlic cocktail and pineapple Fizz
crossed together and it's got the
freaking watermelon Terps and I hit that
with chili verde so we're doing tahin
and chamoy
uh beautiful man you got me excited that
sounds delicious cool cool cool well
take me back the question we normally
ask people at the start of the episodes
what was your first experience with
cannabis
so my first experience getting high was
that the Shoreline Amphitheater at like
a big concert where my friend who
um grew his own cannabis and everything
you know at 16 was like here you go uh
here's this clay pipe I fired in my oven
and made myself and here's just weed I
grew myself I was like holy [__] all
right
I I prepared myself and stuck little
incense sticks in a circle around me and
I got high and I realized that everyone
else at the concert was [__] high and
I was like oh [__] everyone's doing this
I was like oh damn like no matter how
old people are everyone's high like I
was a great 16 year old moment of like
realizing that like cannabis unites the
world and all people and all cultures
and all ethnicities and all age groups
it's honestly why I keep doing the sesh
in Oakland I love the sesh the pop-up
seshes because every race every sexual
orientation and every age group can come
and ask me about all my cannabis
products and the farm and everything and
everyone can learn and come together it
gets me the highest of anything is the
biodiversity of humanity and the
biodiversity in the guard a hundred
percent man I've only been to one of the
sessions in Oakland before but like the
vibe was popping man it was like so fun
just to be there and it was exactly how
you described hey it was really diverse
it was great absolutely that's what
cannabis is about and that's the model
that will be sustainable in the future
yes just a small little market pop up
yeah killer killer Okay so
talk to me about how you went from that
Shoreline experience to thinking
I gotta plant my own seeds I have to do
this
I was lucky enough
to go to college and grow up in Santa
Cruz and I understood the lifestyle
somewhat
um really started to unpeel the meaning
of Santa Cruz when I went to UC Santa
Cruz and sold cannabis out of my little
you know apartment dorm room there
and I learned a lot and really brought
people together and
I was so inspired by all the Growers we
don't have a frat scene at UC Santa Cruz
you just go to burning man right so it's
like all these people who had come
before me had grown and you know
successfully and sold their weed and
made successful companies and they were
throwing big parties at Burning Man and
they told me how much this plant had
given to them how much it provided and
how much they had taught you know just
they had learned in general about
themselves in the world and been able to
be a man with a plan and help the world
and it was very inspiring to see a lot
of these psychedelic Warriors out in the
world and representing their Santa Cruz
Vibe and teaching people about cannabis
and learning the science simultaneously
and yeah I mean if just in the scene of
just smoking weed and living out you
know renting houses while finishing your
degree you learn how to grow weed if you
want to or not
like you got roommates they're growing
weeds you're going to learn about it
like right so all of a sudden it's like
wait like this thing really grows and it
just brings people together and it's so
diverse and there's so many flavors and
there's so many highs and it's kind of
like at the birth moment like from 2001
to 2006 where everyone started to really
get into cannabis I watched our 420
little party
uh you see Santa Cruz Santa Cruz go from
like
you know 420 people in like 2002
to 14
000 people by the time I graduated
I mean we're talking exponential growth
here
this stuff was growing so fast everyone
was learning so fast everyone was making
so much money and throwing such cool
parties and
it was just an amazing scene to grow up
in and I was so inspired and
I you know made food for the parties as
like a business there's like a side
hustle you know and would sell my
chocolates and these little things and
I I basically you know I went homeless
during college and lived on people's
decks and
live in the forest sometimes had my
stuff in lockers on campus bike around
sell weed at the skate park you know I
really really believed in cannabis and
it believed in me and I knew I had to
sacrifice everything all my Comforts all
the things that I knew were important
like I had to sacrifice them so I could
learn about this new thing that no one
knew about so I could be ahead when the
time came
and that turned out to be really tough
and I needed a lot of help and
luckily one day I had a big Rave where I
had made all the fanciest chocolate
treats and Sushi and all this [__] this
guy came up to me he's like bro I got
this we grow you seem so awesome and
smart like I have all these people like
can you like feed us like we're just up
on the hill like can you feed us
and I was like okay sure and so I like
built a yurt on this guy's land after we
got along
he ended up being the direct descendant
of
uh Steiner like his name's Matthew
Steiner like as of you know Rudolf
Steiner who made biodynamics invented it
and the guy who founded Waldorf School
and everything
so I got to learn biodynamics from a
direct descendant of it so who was
applying it to cannabis for the first
time because he was the black sheep of
the family
no it was like oh [__] this is like the
opportunity of a lifetime this guy's
like breeding seeds and has a degree in
biology and like teaches me to collect
the mycelial leaf litter to make
mushroom tea for the plants like wow I'm
gonna do this and I [__] did that
[__] I worked hard I watched him do
really good and fail in different ways I
helped at other farms and I got super
inspired and I saw so much waste and I
knew that moment when I could plant my
seed I would be ready and I wouldn't
waste anything
and I was and I did and now I'm here now
I got the farm now we got the flavors
and we got employees and we got people
who believe in us and finally got my
t-shirt and you know new seeds coming
out all the time yeah finally
that's awesome man it's a dream come
true dude really honestly yeah like hard
work pays off and sacrifice yeah dude
that's beautiful to hear man that's
that's awesome to hear you live such a
an interesting and varied life
something we referenced earlier that I
want to ask you about you know what's
your plans to to get your work more
widely available do you think you want
to get yourself out there at say more
Distributors get more of your product
out there or do you still want to keep
it a small scale operation in a certain
sense
so we'll still be a small scale
operation but we want to expand our
reach as far as you know feminized seeds
will be doing feminized seeds as well as
feminized autoflowers in the future all
for resin production for the white and
black market so that people can produce
resin on their own independently or for
big companies that want to like run with
our flavors so that more people can be
aware of the cool flavors that I'm you
know trying to make for people trying to
make new experiences for people on the
Cannabis Market to blow their minds and
you just got to keep up and do that work
and so
you know we're willing to make those
thousands of seeds we're never going to
make like you know multi-millions right
we're never going to make multi-millions
of seeds so we're always going to have
that quality seed and get that out there
and yeah that's the goal for the future
is to win some awards with my genetics
that's my that's my next goal oh amazing
and which which uh award would be the
one you'd be most Keen to achieve in
your career
oh just you know something for the rosin
just something that blows everyone's
mind you know so that people you know
like if I could ideally this is what I
really want I want to make an Autoflower
rosin flavor that wins and people don't
know it's Autoflower so then people are
like oh [__] I've always talked [__]
about autoflowers because I thought they
were the same as cannabis and I screwed
it up when I grew it but maybe I should
look into that again
ha that's brilliant and I mean as a sort
of just a rough guess how far off in
time do you think we are from when that
sort of thing might be possible oh only
12 months oh yeah I've been working on
this last five years oh yeah uh just
another year push I think by by this
time next year we'll have the full melt
genetics that'll be making rosin
in 80 Days From The Sea germination day
wow that'll be special
I would love to ask is there anywhere
people can go to get your seeds now
uh so right now uh the website still
hasn't gotten built but we're gonna do
that that's basically the plan for the
next three months but so far we just um
you know just go on Instagram and let me
know where you're at and figure out if
our local laws can make it work yeah
fantastic fantastic get in touch with
him and a question I love to ask all our
guests
from your perspective doesn't have to be
from the general Public's perspective it
can be because of some special reason to
you
for you what's the rarest seeds in your
vault
well I have you know just a few seeds of
land race like pure land race that I
haven't popped yet so I have those pure
Tanzanian I have some pure Argentinian I
have some pure uh Crimean from the
Crimean peninsula
um I actually grew those out this year
and I'm very excited about that because
I found trading cannabis that I've never
really found before I did one post about
it basically it flowered it got seeded
and then it flowered again so once it
got the signal that it was seated it it
grew four more branches from its root
Zone and started flowering again and
then that got seeded and then it
flowered again so it flowered five times
and so I hit that I crossed that with
the Satsuma sure so I'm thinking about
like the future of cannabis where it's
like a Autoflower timing so in 80 Days
you get like a QP and then 100 days
later you get a half pound and then
October you get even more and you cut it
back three times
uh it was amazing yeah so that's what
I'm most excited about for genetic
traits is something I've never seen
before
that's really exciting I've never heard
anything about that at all cool cool
cool so
so this next one is a general question
but I'm wondering what is your hope
overall for the trajectory of the scene
I hope that the Legacy operators and
like those who care and have won awards
pre-2016 who have families will continue
to thrive
and I sincerely hope that the
billionaires and Canadian investors
continue to go bankrupt
because it's not helping anything I
couldn't believe the facility they built
in Death Valley over here in California
it's like over a hundred million dollar
Glass House the hot water that comes out
of the earth naturally there is like 110
degrees so they have all these chillers
just to get the water cool
and I just couldn't help but think like
they could have just put cow poop on the
earth and put a barbed wire of fence
and then just gotten those Afghani
genetics that can just withstand hot
weather all year or Moroccan and then
just done a land race in the Death
Valley instead of building a hundred
million dollar facility so I feel like
anyone who's like kind of like trying to
like build their way to their empire
needs to just stop and like do something
else and like realize that like you know
there's people who care and there's
people who have done the business for a
long time and yeah you can buy their IP
some guys will sell you their
intellectual property or whatever but
anyone who would do that doesn't really
know or doesn't really care about being
in it long term
so it's like a it's a tricky point right
now there's a lot of guys who are doing
that right now my age who are like oh
I've been in the business I'm just gonna
sell all my information to a rich guy
and then I don't have to worry I can
raise my family
I'm not saying I judge you I'm just
saying like man sucks you know it's like
the paradigm shift
so
yeah definitely a tough situation it's
hard to blame people
I'd love to follow up you mentioned it a
few times the greasy versus tacky
feeling of trichomes I know that you
often hear people talking about greasy
being good for concentrates but I
believe you broke it down into like a
further sort of subdivision how would
you describe to people like the way
trichomes should feel for each style of
production
so the ones that leave a slippery grease
on your fingers are the ones that are
going to make good diamonds and those
are going to be
antagonistic to the water process and
it's like the alpha pinene terp so we
thought this one would wash last year
you know we had six thousand grams of it
it looked awesome perfect rainbow smell
but it was a little Piney and I was
worried we got like a .05 you know 0.5
wash you know
I think half a percent right but not
only that like the texture of it gummed
up all the filters in the water rosin
process so then they had to do an
alcohol wash just to clean just to do
another run
so not only does it like screw
everything up it makes it a lot harder
to like make water hash again if you use
the wrong uh you know starting material
so basically uh the greasy material is
not going to work and your super tacky
material that like stretches like a
spider web or Sandy to the touch that
can work a lot better
and then obviously the whole jar Tech
everyone talking about where you put 20
grams of fresh frozen in a mason jar and
then shake it with ice cold water and
then see what knocks off and the idea is
that if you got 20 grams and you've got
a five percenter then you'll see one
gram of trichomes fall off into the
corner and you should be able to see
what a pile of one gram looks like
and if you don't have that then you're
looking at not a rosin winner yeah
that's a great breakdown
that's why the resin dial was invented
too ah okay interesting interesting
interesting
so on to the final five questions we ask
all our guests great what was the single
most memorable cannabis experience
you've ever had it doesn't have to be
like the strongest hit but just most
memorable for whatever reason
oh oh by far being the judge uh Taylor t
bezel chose me as a secondary judge for
uh the emerald cup before Skittles was
known as a strain and so before rosin
was in the emerald cup I got to dab full
melt and put it in order I came to the
Airbnb in at midnight and I stayed for
five hours or until 4 20 in the morning
I was so high never been that high in my
life and you know Cuban grower and all
the guys in the Russian industry were
like oh we've got these hashes we've got
to put them in order we've got to figure
out a winner they just have numbers on
them you've got to write notes you've
got to be a judge you've gotta and I
[__] took dabs of everything and took
notes and you know five star six star
what kind of flavors multiple flavors is
there flavor on the inhale in the mouth
and is there an aftertaste is it
genetically similar to something I've
had or not so I did all those things on
20 rosins and then put them in an order
and then gonna dab them again and make
sure that the top five were the top five
and I voted for this number one that I
remember the notes still multiple fruit
flavors
and every time I hit it even the second
time I found other fruit flavors and
that ended up being the Skittles which
is what made Brandon famous and
everything so
that was definitely the best high
experience was like trying to figure out
the [__] with no names and just numbers
on them
that sounds beautiful and just for
clarification's sake what do you think
of the genetics in Skittles oh yeah
everyone's [__] like oh it's a pink
grapefruit and oh it's a green Sherbert
and oh it's like I mean I just like yo
let's see the terp test if you know how
to grow it and it's high in osamine then
it's going to have the dominant terpene
that almost all rosin doesn't have most
rosin has limonene mercene or
beta-cariothalene so if you try that
osamine flavor if you grow it correctly
and it has high osamine and it's the
dominant one that's the Skittles [__]
amazing awesome flavor yeah
beautiful stuff on the other end of the
spectrum what is something where
everyone was hyping it up you were super
Keen to try it and then when you did you
were left a bit disappointed
uh let's see uh purple punch
um Gorilla Glue uh
but I've never really liked Bubba
everyone swears by their old school 98
Bubba
I'd rather have Malibu pure Crush any
day over that Bubba smells like it's
just like you know astringent limes
versus like a floral Rush
uh I mean so many people try to Market
all these
crosses like the gelato 33 it's all
right you know I've the original
Sherbert is good
um cherry pie is pretty over hyped
a lot of sour diesels you know because
the original cut so lost
so it's like everyone's like oh this
prefix on Sour Diesel I'm like there
ain't no sour gas and rancidity in here
you know
a lot of things I mean that's why we're
it's like why there's opportunity right
for geneticists because there's like
kind of a lot of like mishmash flavors
that have been re hybridized too many
times I know it tastes like anything in
particular
yeah definitely definitely okay so next
question if I'm going to drop you off on
a desert island and you can take three
strains with you for the rest of time
what three things are you gonna take you
can take clones or seeds
all right uh let's see
Durbin poison for sure
uh honey bananas
to offset that it's like completely
different it's like the opposite like
Durban poisons [__] not sweet it
ain't fruity and it ain't sit us you
know sedating at all and that honey
bananas does all those things it's sweet
sedating
fruity as [__]
uh let's see what's the one that I
freaking love recently I grew a Wilson
cross that was like a mind flare
I didn't know the background
um but it tasted like pink marshmallows
but man I guess the chop cookies because
the the chop cookies hit me harder than
anything yeah yeah cause that I didn't
really realize how good chop cookies was
until you know someone with like living
soil indoor LED who like wins Awards
like touches that cut and like actually
cares you know luckily heads that roll
like relocated to our zone so I get to
trade with them and try their stuff
wow you can just taste the care in that
orange flavor and so then that's not in
Honey bananas or Durban yeah so that's
my three definitely
good lace good list uh in an alternative
situation we're gonna drop someone else
off at the island someone you're not a
big fan of you get to pick which three
strains we leave them with what are you
gonna leave them with
oh so they okay so they like need a
lesson yeah it's up to you what you want
to do but I'm interested what three
things are you gonna leave them with
uh I would leave them with like the land
race from Tanzania that probably has
like you know five percent THC Maybe
you know so they can like earn some
respect for all like the work of the
continent of Africa and the thousands of
years that people have done without
credit you know
um and then like green crack just
because it's like a horrible weed with a
horrible High and a horrible name
and uh
let's see let's like really Bland like
that's like
like the like blue dream cross it's like
like not the real Santa Cruz Blue Dream
but like the blue dream hay that's like
the like oh yeah like oh there's God
damn that one it's horrible bro it's so
like hay and it produces the best
looking Blue Dream buds better than the
original but it has no Terps and so it's
like this horrible cut that got around
because someone was Insidious like and
decided to do that they should stay
there with that too that's the person
who should go there
there you go okay so final question if I
could give you a time machine you can go
back to any period in history you can go
anywhere to collect some seeds or clones
where are you gonna go what are you
gonna collect
I wouldn't have to go back far
yeah I would just go back to like
92.
and just like have you could get all
that seed stock from the 80s and then
some of those new ogs and these things
like the real pure kush and all that
exclusive stuff
yeah and then just start breeding with
it the way I knew how yeah and then buy
Bitcoin I'll be set where is this time
machine Let's Go
I love it getting on the crypto
beautiful stuff so I think that just
about brings us to the end of it are
there any general comments or shout outs
you'd like to make
uh yeah just uh appreciate your always
you know consider it dedication to your
questions and you know your show putting
it out there and being detailed about
you know who you put on your show and
all the things you have to go through
it's taught me a lot I was inspired to
be on it inspired to listen to it
absolutely
it's really good work you're doing we
need more people like you
uh you're too kind my friend well again
thank you so so much for coming on the
show for sharing all of your knowledge
be it on concentrates extraction
breeding growing Autos the whole gamut I
really enjoyed it so again a huge thank
you to Sean of flying lion research for
coming on the show thanks for having me
buddy I can't wait to trade seeds with
you
[Applause]
[Music]
a huge thank you to Sean for joining us
and a huge thank you to you for
supporting the show and for making it to
the end
as always we're super grateful that you
support the patreon
I hope you enjoyed this one and we'll
see you for the next one
[Music]