[Music]
welcome back to another episode of the
podcast a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts as always you're joined by
your boy heavy days from the upside down
Library
we want to give a massive shout out to
all of our incredible sponsors who help
ensure the show continues to happen
seeds here now number one seed bank in
the industry all the hottest breeders
the latest drops everything you can look
for and more whether you're after indoor
outdoor feminized regular autoflow
they've got everything under the sun to
keep you loaded on all the hottest
genetics producing the most fire Bud
you've ever had I hear they've got some
incredible lines from heavy days is
still in stock if you want to go check
that out make sure to do it before it's
too
late big shout out to ctnl we appreciate
you so
much as usual a massive massive thank
you and shout out to our good friends at
copit biological if you want to harvest
the best crop to date you have to ensure
your garden is pest and pathogen free
pumping on all cylinders if you're
battling spidermite check out the
incredible spyx red likewise I know a
lot of you guys are battling apids at
the moment check out their AIP parm this
is another product I absolutely stand
behind from copit if you want to get rid
of apids get rid of spidermites check
out the apy parm check out the spidex
red big shout out to copit biological
thank you so much we appreciate your
ongoing
support the final piece of the puzzle to
ensure that your room is killing it is
our good friends at Pulse their sensors
are second to none industry-leading and
just recently they announced the pulse
Hub what more could you want an
integrated unit for all of your sensors
to ensure that your garden is automated
and tracking all of the variables you
may not be consciously aware of from VPD
to ppf dupoint temperature humidity so
much more you've got to get yourself a
pulse sensor guys it has revolutionized
the way I grow flour and increased the
tping content the cannaboid content the
yield Soo so much more shout out as
always to our friends at Pulse sensors
likewise if any of you you guys have
been listening to the show you know that
I am passionate about helping people
transition to vaporized options if
they're considerate about their
respiratory health and for me dap are
the world leaders in this dap helped me
to transition from bongs to vaping and I
tell you what I've never looked back
their unit is the most potent the most
highly replicating of a bong hit I've
ever come across and through their
incredible munit I was able to
successfully get off bongs a few years
ago now truly one of of the most
Innovative and interesting Vapes on the
market using a totally different design
to others you have found check these
guys out you will not be disappointed
massive shout out to dnat thank you so
much and last but not least we want to
give a massive shout out to the
incredible patreon gang without you guys
we could not continue to make episodes
if you want to get early access to
upcoming episodes exclusive content just
on the patreon including the likes of
mean Jean Bob hmill Bodie Tricom jungle
so much more be sure to go check out our
patreon we give away genetics every
month to our supporters along with
artwork Vapes sensors so much more
please check out the patreon guys I
promise you you won't regret it you'll
get your money back in swag for helping
support us show you love thank you so
much to everyone from the
patreon yo yo yo welcome back for
another episode
[Music]
you know why you're
here the B man himself is here to drop
some knowledge
bombs let's not delay it any further
we're so grateful you guys waited so
patiently without further
[Music]
delay let's get into
it what are like some of your favorite
strains that you enjoy the effect or the
high of the most
I think for my own strains like you know
Goji has always been like had a special
place in my heart that you know it kind
of
was yeah it just all came together in
such a a special way and created I don't
know it always just made me happy and it
always kind of had a kind of like a
heart feeling and it was up just enough
so that it kept you like you could go
out to you know see music or you could
go on a hike or uh it just it just has
it's just kind of that Pinnacle of like
good vibe herb that I loved um I really
love dread bread a lot because it's it
has a really great up
High um it's kind of like a sa kind of
like a TAA but it has enough bottom end
that you feel like you know when your
body feels really good and your mind
feels good at the same time it makes you
kind of want to stretch it's like a good
kind of yoga herb um I I really like
some of the dlas are fun because they
have different effects I know people
really like those kind of like
everything from four and up um let's see
what else I like you know I used to like
tranquil elephantizer was a good one I
like that um for just relaxing like if I
just had to go for just super like gluey
to the
couch what are some other good ones um
you know all the black triangle I really
like the effect like it was really nice
and potent but
really kind of like life affirming you
know you know i'
there's there's some strange you smoke
and they're either too strong or
they're um they just tend to or they're
kind of like SK not scary I would say
like have you ever had a strain that's
kind of like
clinical like it's very like rough
around the edges and just kind of
like like kind of like more if it had a
element it would like be the metal
element like if you could rate
can and like uh motive and then a wood
would be like I don't know wood would be
like I guess grounded and rooted and
then air would be
like like Airy kind of sativas and ether
would be like the electric sativas and
then metal would be kind of like this
these very clinical like in the mind
like make you kind of think but they
don't have a lot necessarily so much joy
like the Mexican Desa like I that a cool
one but it was very clinical it made you
kind of think about things but it it
wasn't super joyful it was like okay
let's just it was like a therapist like
okay let's do some
work um yeah and I like that so yeah if
I could rate them um let's but yeah I
like Bashan uh Sunshine Daydream I just
love the feeling like it just like you
get the right feno and it's just like
welcome to like to pleasure town just
enjoy a movie
uh kind of like all the OG a3s always
created really cool cool plants with
cool highs like they that male was
really amazing that it could it just
harmonized with certain varieties you
know and some of the ones like uplift is
a really cool version of it
um some of them were a little bit heavy
but some of them got got kind of I just
love those like joyful heady highs um
let think else um I like some Wookie
stuff the Congo cashmir I really love
that's a good one that's like a
supernatural selections um and I like
some of the Congo cashmir
hybrids and
um yeah The Wookie stuff is cool it
always had unique things I really like
um killer orgasm is a good one it makes
you kind of feel like a kid but I think
that's more that's an unreleased one
um God there's so many cool I'm trying
to think of all the
different it's just been so it's been a
you know it's been I think I've released
like hundreds of strains and it's been
like a 20
year um catalog so it's like but the
ones that have kind of lasted even ones
that don't haven't existed for 10 years
and last the kind of test of time like
Goji Sunshine Daydream and then there
ones
like um black triangle
and um Congo cashmere dread
bread I like T like some the new
medicine Mountain I like I like
TV um what else cool on I made one
called Dharma bom that's really cool
it's the TV cross to the Big Sir
Nigerian but you know
those to kids off in is a p because I
out and I'll stay up all night if I
smoke anything it seems unless it's a
super Downer like
narud wow that's that's so interesting I
that's I mean yeah it sounds like a
double-edged blade in a sense um well
you just mentioned TV a good buddy of
mine Eli cash he's a a breeder in
Australia here he's got a seed company
called local bird seed definitely
recommend people check it out he's done
some breeding work utilizing a male he
found out of the TV seeds and I'm I'm
yeah I'm I'm really Keen to crack into
some of those myself uh but I'd love to
ask you
what sort of some stuff you feel that
strain brings to the table and um you
know it's got some heavy heavy weights
in the lineage tell me a bit about it
well you know for the first kind of
medicine Mountain was all about kind of
making uh approachable like narrow
leafes or sativas or like or like more
he super energetic heady highs like
making it so people could
actually grow them so TV was like kind
of like the flagship that I was going to
make hybrids with a lot of things and
also kind of as an Ode to it release it
too so that everybody could have the
parents for the for TV like I mean for
the first release and kind of like you
can make your own stuff and basically TV
like the vietnames 7 I want to make it a
little bit easier to grow you know and
then so I took um an F I worked the
Charlie's Destroyer for a couple
generations and I used an A A really
quicker kind of like Stout um resilient
like he was really good at creating
stuff that uh that was workable like
that it would do what it says like if
you know he could his magic was kind of
making things that were grower friendly
and so I found a really nice kind of
faster
finishing uh it was a pearl tie dominant
uh Destroyer and destroyers like I think
what is it Northern Lights it's mostly
tie tie with some what did he BR that
nor light napali or nor light something
but it's a very manageable kind of tie
very strong tie dominant tie line so the
TV is like I always call it like totally
Visionary or um Thai Vietnamese and it
it's just like if someone's always
wanted to grow a tie but can't really
grow it in their tent or grow it outside
it it's it's you can finish it and you
can grow it and it makes good hybrids so
that was kind of the the the reason why
I created that as the first one and then
you know there was a
special one like a gift one that went
out just to friends it was called Dharma
bom and that was the
TV um biger Nigerian I think there was
zap and a few others but there's going
to be more to come as I find you know
it's when you're looking for like n leaf
and Loom sativas and stuff like that it
you gota go through a lot to kind of
find truly exceptional ones and then you
have to make sure they outcross well but
usually you know if they're usually just
distinct enough you get that hybrid
Vigor and you get you know nature loves
new things coming together it applauds
that and I think that's the magic on of
life on Earth is is bringing diverse
elements together to create new things
and so I think anytime that you take
like soall land Ras plants in1 you're
bound to find something that's most
likely better than the
parents and I think that's kind of what
medic Mountain's about yeah that's
incredible to hear you know a lot of
people wanted to know are there any
plans for future releases from Medicine
Mountain uh definitely yeah it's just uh
they probably we won't won't be ready
until next the end of next season
because it is it's like you know you
flowering males out for nine weeks just
to get pollen is not the most exciting
thing to do you know that's why I love
uh uh Supernatural selections is so cool
is because uh you know they're usually
F1 hybrids between narrow and broadleaf
and so collect the pollen from the
broadleaf earlier and just flower out
your your sativas and it's easier to
make hybrids that way but the medicine
Mountain it's your labor of love when
you have to grow things out you know to
breeding is
not necessarily the easiest and it does
take quite a lot of time but it's worth
it in the end for that what you can
achieve and what you can
make yeah totally totally and that's a
cool little point you raised about you
know getting the pollen from the broad
leaves earlier in the season out of
curiosity you know I mean based on what
you've already told us the answer is
probably no but I guess have you had a
chance or are you maybe more thinking
about exploring any of the popular stuff
we've seen Via de par and the other uh
land race crew you know they've
certainly been posting some pretty
tantalizing purple buds recently yeah
they have incredible stuff like yeah he
he we usually trade a lot and you know
he sent me some like
pretty much everything that they release
so there's so much to go through and I'm
loving a lot of these Afghan um
collections like the Maru and there's so
many different cool and I I just haven't
had a space like I would go berserk if I
was still at the Old Farm like I would
have been I would have blown through
those already like I love growing broad
leaves because they're just so they're
you unless you live in a a high uh mold
pressure environment they're just so
cool they're like little cousin NS like
they they're so easy to grow they just
they're so smelly and they're
so I don't know they're like gnomes or
like got garden gnomes you know and and
they're just so fun and they usually
they are they you can trace them back
pretty close to the
source I don't know I I think and they
have such unique and special highs it's
just uh having a breeding program or
having a
long-term uh line breeding program where
you can kind of bring them out of their
you know they have horrible uh
morphology for trimming because in
basically they're hash plants people
don't always like kind of register that
but most of these broad leaves they're
not designed to make beautiful buds in
the bag they're made for their resin
heads um so but I would love you know
what would be really cool is if someone
in the states came up with a uh like a
heirloom broadleaf uh hash repository
like where they just grew broadleafs
point of origin broadleafs and then
hashed them and then could offer uh
traditionally processed uh you know
you're not going to see too much Afric
Afghan stamp bricks here in the United
States for a while until we go uh
globally legal but until then imagine
taking those things and finding maybe
like a high Des environment just growing
like a thousand uh heirloom broad leaves
and then just hashing them out like how
cool I would love to go pick some of
that up sign me up like I'm sure there's
got to be a market people would love
that all even old- I used to get the the
red stamped you know what Afghan King of
Afghanistan ones or the I got red
Lebanese from an old lady that lived
down the block who got it from a boat
captain hairdresser that picked it up in
the kyber pass when she was hunting for
you know
Sasquatch so I wish there was a for I
wish there was a way that people could
follow their Bliss and follow their
their Niche and
really enjoy what they're doing G so
many people in cannabis these days are
just worn out and sad and disenchanted
and you know it's hard to keep a when
you can't feed your family it's hard to
to to have that Joy you know it's hard
to go that and it's so sad that that's
been sucked out of it because that's
what it's all about you know you can see
it even in the seed Community I mean I
mean there's a a immense amount of new
seed companies and so many people doing
fantastic things and boring things and
great things and special things and and
it but there's also a lot of the
old-timers that are having to kind of
find new go back to their old jobs or
find or just you know it's not a
full-time job anymore it's just their
kind of passion side project you know
because things are hard I mean that' be
the beautiful thing about descheduling
imagine if you can make seeds and sell
to the entire country of the whole world
you open it up so much more that you
could actually kind of cover your bills
because you have a lot more people that
can grow your seeds and that demographic
would be there like imag you know I'm
I'm hoping that someday we go federally
legal and I think that would really open
it up so many people that are
stigmatized because they feel it's a
illegal plant they don't grow it but if
it if that was released imagine all
those people that just love to grow
flowers or anything you know I yeah
that's that's how I stay positive is
just hoping that one
day when things do go federally illegal
there won't be a way to stop it and
people's
curiosity uh and the stories they tell
and you know kind of like how
legalization was brought in kind of like
through the charlott's web like kids
needing epilepsy care like that was kind
of the way in it's like once it's opened
it can't be put back
in and I think that's going to be the
thing and it's like once people realize
the person that's not a drug it's
basically the one it's a wonder cannabis
is a Wonder generator for life on Earth
like if anybody that's having that's
never smoked it you know you see those
YouTube videos sometimes of like first
time Grandpa smokes pot and like their
world just opens up like where was the
stuff my whole life like you know it's
such a it's been with us forever you
know the dogon feel that you know you
they come from the Sirus a be the star
system and that the the beings that came
from that place and came and visit him
they brought cannabis as a gift to have
better lives and to have happy times
here on Earth like it's a gift it's a
gift from Source it's a gift from the
heart of the world it's it's our most
it's basically our our Prime Botanical
Ally on this Earth it provides
everything we could possibly need and
it's an absolute crime and shame that
we're in this place and now we're in
this place of Pudo leg legalization it's
not legalized it's just regulated so
people can make money off of it it's
totally not legalized it's even worse I
think I think things were much better in
when it was illegal you know or even or
the best times we ever had was 215 where
it was like this pseudo pseudo legality
where people could still follow their
heart and so what they made and like it
it that was time of great I don't think
if we would have had 215 we would have
ushered right into the time we have now
we'd be even more up the creek because
there would be such it would be such oh
No Just Be A Wasteland
so no I I agree I think that'd probably
be almost a unanimous thing in our
entire community that you know 215 was
clearly Superior to uh to what we have
now and the prospect of what we have
going forward which is really sort of a
bummer but look I've thought about this
a lot and there's a lot of things that
are happening and and as an individual
it's hard to give advice and I've
thought long about like you know what
can you tell someone who's struggling to
pay their bills and stuff and the one
thing I've always thought is kind of
like taking Tibbits of what we've spoken
about already is that most of the new
stuff comes from passionate Hobby People
not big
facilities and maybe one silver lining
of this you know and I don't want to
call it a silver lining because anyone
who's forced out of say being a fulltime
grower and having to pick up some other
work you know I don't want to try to you
know minimize that or say oh a silver
lining you know but one thing that might
be a result of that is that you now have
more freedom over what you grow you know
because your income isn't solely maybe
coming from this one thing and with that
freedom you could maybe use that to
explore some stuff and who knows you
know you might end up finding the new
big thing and certainly that's got more
of a chance of success than you know
just growing the same OG clone like you
know not the only thing you're going to
be able to do at the end of that is sell
the crop you know there's no Prospect of
making something new out of that but I
don't know what's your thoughts what's
your advice for the small time grower or
how can people try to positively
contribute to push the scene in the
right direction is it is it just grow
interesting unique
stuff yeah I think it's follow your
bliss and find your Niche and like and
also find your community find find
people around you so like you you know
you may not be able to grow a lot of
plants but if you have five people that
are passionate about it that you've met
online or at local meetups or whatever
you have five times the amount to try
you have five new uh buddies to to be
creative with it's like I I think it's
all
about grow growing I mean I I like seeds
I like finding new things but clowns are
awesome too I love growing to see what
like it like that's really fun to see
what like the new thing that everybody's
into because it really allows gives you
a benchmark on where not only where
we're at but where we want to be like if
this is the most ultimate thing right
now and you're like oh wow this is
incredible I I agree this is pretty cool
like how was this made like what is it
made from or you could be like H that's
not that great like this is actually way
cooler than you know check this out I
think it's all about growing as as
much unique things as you can but also
finding those if something really speaks
to you and speaks to your heart and to
your your physiology and your biology
endocab system there's someone out there
there's actually probably quite a few
people out there that are going to have
that same Vibe with it so take it a few
Generations really mold it like a piece
of art like a sculpture into what you
want it to say I mean it it's that's the
amazing thing about it it's just
unending Journey we can all work on it
together and it has so many ways to
express itself on every level
from from you know even people like that
are depressed it's like I mean sometimes
people will mask depression with
cannabis but it's like like I said
before cannabis is a Wonder generator
like it really allows you to tune into
the wonder of the world like no wonder
people love to watch movies or play
video games because it enhances all of
our senses and our senses are what allow
us to experience the world you know and
people with all this everybody getting
locked to their phones and all the new
talk AI like go to the original AI the
ancient intelligence you know go back to
the world this this incredible thing
it's like cannabis is Nature's Wi-Fi
like you know you this the signal might
not be there but the reception is way
better it's like you need to go it's
like it allows you to embody yourself on
Earth and to really see what's real as
we get swept away into this artificial
world it's one of the only things that's
backing us back backing us back to like
this Garden reality of like you know I
always laugh when they always say
oh cannabis it's a gateway drug to
gardening you I always think of all
these homeboys like during the OG craze
I'm like okay so now they're just
playing video games and smoking OG and
they're all growing G like how amazing
that it's like a feminite they get to
like experience the feminine you know
growing female plants like it it it does
such amazing things and it's created so
many unique opportunities and I feel sad
when people can't experience that it
would be like going through life not
making love or something you know like
being a virgin all your life well being
a virgin to plant medicine is just as
sad you know if you never that I
encourage everyone you know it to do all
the plant medicines that you can
experience ethically uh especially
hoping that you created them yourself is
the even thing if you can grow mushrooms
it's so easy like and grow them yourself
and put in your love and your like you
know play music do whatever you want put
your Vibe into them they're going to
give you back what you put back into
them it's the same with an and I feel
I just you know it's just a shame that
we people don't have the opportunity to
do this or if they do have the
opportunity they get swacked you know
they get boofed they get they just get
junk I just wish there was a way that
people that have love for it and are
have been doing it and really know how
to do it and create something have the
ability to offer that and be compensated
for that so that they can move forward
you know and also make it a family
business like it should be it should be
multigenerational we can't just Le you
know lose all of these lineages of of
ganja people that go back through time
you know it's not fair to the world or
to
society yeah look it's it is terrible to
think about how much potential knowledge
could be lost so you know hopeful that
there's a a break soon and and some sort
of Reform that allows these people to
continue on and you know when you were
just talking then about encouraging just
plant medicine consumption of of all
kinds I I couldn't help but think back
to in the original episode when you were
talking about we were talking about
blending tobacco with cannabis and you
were describing tobacco as a bit like a
saddle when you're riding a horse and it
allows you to go different places you
might not have otherwise been able to
have gone I've definitely actually been
indulging that a little bit over the
years you know despite the fact I I
don't really consume
cannabis sorry I don't consume tobacco
go uh I I do once in a blue moon maybe
probably not even once every 6 months
but definitely more than once a year I
will consume some tobacco with it and
it's so profoundly different to what I
remember when I used to just
consistently consume tobacco with it and
it really resonated with what you said
you know it was a very different
experience and to me it actually made
anything I was smoking like a sativa and
I appreciated that you know obviously
people get stimulated off tobacco but I
very much was and uh it got me thinking
about you know like the ways in which
you consume it and the ways it changes
your appreciation and as 's gone by I've
sort of been consuming less and less and
we we had one of the um the listeners
ask and it sort of ties in with what I'm
getting at here which is has your way
you consume cannabis changed your
relationship with it because I think for
me at least it's been almost quite
paradoxical in that the less I consume
to a certain extent I still consume a
decent amount it's almost more
meaningful in a way I don't know maybe I
haven't articulated it that well but I'd
love to hear your thoughts you know how
how is your view on and your
relationship with it
changed yeah I definitely slow down but
it's more because I have to be more
responsible and it's not that I can't be
responsible on campus cannabis it's that
cannabis turns me into like a kid like
it I'm so hyp sensitive to plant plant
Spirit medicines or whatever you want to
call it and I'm
extraordinary um sensitive to cannabis
and I love that I cultivate that because
then I can really feel the nuances and I
can really kind of I can connect with it
in a deeper way I kind of try and bring
it in on a daily just as a something
that walks with me but it's true it's
like I don't know the older you get
either you do it a lot more or you start
to find a balance and I I I respect all
the people that can uh turn it on and
leave it on that can smoke all day and I
I and it and it it's like coffee or it's
like anything that kind of allows them
to move through their
experience but I think there's something
special and also uh reaching kind of a
sensitive place with it where it's
you're using it more as a
therapeutic uh experience or you know
you're creating an enjoyable experience
and starting to instead of masking
things you don't like about the world
using it or in your own body or your own
mind you're using it to experience
greater levels of complexity and joy in
everyday
experiences so I've definitely I would
love I used to you know smoke every day
and I would smoke usually at night after
things calm down and I would take my
notes cuz I had just you know 100
different plants hanging in the garage
and and really kind of get into it but
yeah it's when I do do it now it's so
special and so and it's like an old
friend you know you're like oh wow why
am I not doing this like every moment
but yeah I I it's hard like we were
talking before it's like for me when my
M mind opens my mouth closes like I'm
not a I I find I'm in such a Wonder
place that it's hard for me to interact
with people that aren't in that same
space you know do you ever get like have
you gone out to like like the Super
Market stoned and it's just like going
to another planet and you just realized
I am I'm I'm like way too high to be in
this and it's like you're at a Crux
there either you freak out and get
paranoid or you just have the kind of
the time of your life but you kind of
need a sitter like I remember I used to
love to get blazed and go to the movies
but I always need someone to like like I
was a kid like someone to hold my hand
so I didn't do anything too weird um but
yeah I think it's just finding your own
balance with it everybody's different
you know people smoke incredible amounts
and do incredible things and some people
just smoke it once in a while so it's
like I think it's it's we're going back
to that same thing of just finding
finding your how you walk with it
finding your balance finding the the
just the right uh interaction that it it
enriches your life and doesn't take away
from it you
know yeah yeah of course and the thing I
often reflect on is that at every stage
of my life I have reflected on my
consumption and always felt like it was
sort of optimal and so you know it's
interesting to acknowledge that that
when I was younger and smoking more like
that probably was better you know it
probably was better I wasn't smoking as
little as I am now because maybe I was a
bit more anxious back then and as you
said it just ties back into finding
where your own sort of sweet spot is and
I'm definitely a big fan of that I
wanted to jump to uh an interesting
little side point which was that over
the years I've certainly got many many
messages from people who point out that
you were the first guest to essentially
talk about hopl and virus on the show
you know in the first episode you were
talking about dutting and that was
episode 10 very fitting episode 100
you're here uh but you you were actually
the first person to mention I think we
were talking about CIO at the time
um yeah and obviously hplv has just
evolved into its own huge issue since
the S years ago I feel like we've almost
gotten to a point now where it's very
much out of sight out of mind it's still
there but I think people are just sort
of letting their guard down a bit what's
your thoughts on it and how has it
affected
you um well the beautiful thing about
being involved
with um Hayes Valley is they you know
they do all the testing and it's really
interesting like and they're really
allowing me to see like oh this is these
are signs this is this this you see this
that and you know I've learned so much
about it like you know sometimes you
can't you don't even notice it there's
some strains that just grow they'll grow
past it it's still in it's still in the
system it's still endemic it's really
seems to kind of arise when the the
plant get stressed or it's in conditions
that it doesn't really do well and so
you get these big facilities that are
really good at pumping out flour they
have just the right light just the right
you know nutrient systems just like that
and it's not showing up but it's still
in there or you know I've even heard
recently that you know they're saying
now that it can be it could go into
seeds and I'm like yeah I get that I may
be the mom because the seeds are coming
if you're coming out of infected mom but
if the dad how is the pollen carrying
hpl and pollinating a new mother and
that's getting seeds it just baffles me
but you know science is I'm not a
scientist I'm an artist I you know I
think that you could go either way in
cannabis and some people can do both at
the same time which it's not I mean
that's not the easiest but yeah it's
that's a rough one it's like I've seen
it just Destro destroy people's Gardens
and Destroy just take out clones and and
take out clones that you know disappear
like we used to trade a lot back in the
day you know it be like sometimes you
get a call like six months later hey do
you still have the puck or do you have
this or that and I'm like oh no I don't
know what happened that thing just kind
of like it just croaked or it got you
know got something you know something
The Roots like no one really knew back
then it was that you know what duding
was and it was usually oh the plant's
dis old or it's been cloned too many
times and you got to wonder
where where it came from but yeah now
it's in everybody's Gardens you have
everybody trading and you have these
clone Depots that sure not
everybody's testing and I don't know I
mean this is this one where Plant
Pathology is just not my strong suit but
it's fascinating to me I mean there's
got it's a vroid there's got to be it's
got to happened in other species they
have antivirals that they give plants I
me like how how do we how do we get out
of this I know you can breed out of it
there are plants that are immune to it
it's very
rare it's just a it's just plant AIDS
reached I think we reached that as a as
a cultural phenomenon now as we've been
so promiscuous in our um in our ways
that we propagate and share that now
we're experiencing the ramifications of
like a free love kind of situation
or our P integrated Pest Management uh
is not up to par or you know are we just
in a place where we're not educated
enough and we have too many people doing
it just is this just what happens in in
any species any culture when we get too
freeing and to something arises I I
don't know I mean what are your thoughts
on it it's such a weird and strange
thing and I just saw something today on
the internet was like 99% of hom grows
are infected you know it's like this and
I'm like really is this is it that is it
that prevalent is it that in everybody's
situation is it coming through seeds
like what are we doing you know that's
why I let go a lot when I moved it was
like I didn't feel bad about letting go
a lot of my stuff because you know I've
had it I've been able to keep it alive
for so long I thought you know it's time
to start new and it's time to allow
those plants to just move on I have
seeds for like a lot of the different
ones that I was using with Mals I can
always research it but you know there's
you never know and I don't have the
finances to test all my plants and I
don't think anyone does so it's like
where do we draw how do we fix this
situation it seems like it's the like
the elephant in the room that no one
wants to talk
about yeah yeah totally totally and uh I
think that that's definitely the Perfect
Analogy it's the elephant in the room
and and people are not talking about it
I've I've often wondered because
essentially like I don't see a way to
get rid of it per se I think the best
you could do is sort of quarantine it to
like some area that's non-compliant but
essentially like the idea is that
if if we accept there's still some
conjecture around whether it goes into
the seeds I I haven't done that much
reading but I I kind of am of the belief
that it probably does and the figures
that I've heard reliably quoted from
people I trust is like somewhere from 5
to 30% transmission rate into seeds and
so I guess if you believe that then
theoretically if you get a pack of seeds
from a infected plant then there's one
seed at least statistically probably um
in 20 if it's % and we go low ball
figures one in 20 seeds would have it um
and that's interesting because that
would mean that it's basically
everywhere because there are people
buying seeds everywhere and this was
certainly around for a while before we
knew about it and as you said although
there might have been some plants that
were really showing signs of fatigue
from it there was likely many others
that were just looking relatively
asymptomatic it likely swept through a
lot earlier than we thought but in terms
of practically what I thought might
happen is all the Breeders for example
go get certified Cuts Like what you've
talked about doing and then you kind of
just have to start fresh and then have a
policy of like I don't bring in clones
really maybe if you want to go get them
tested and then quarantine them and then
you know slowly like a real sort of
staged integration to your area it seems
like if you were really serious about
keeping it out that might be the best
way to do it but now I'm sure there's
some people who just won't so you know
what I mean like they would just sort of
keep certain plants around and it'll
just sort of continue to exist in a
small part but I think the big
facilities and the Breeders if they did
that that might be one way you could get
it out but see I don't even know like
Can it can it get transmitted like on a
shirt like of a worker like coming from
like is it like a bug like that or is it
like you know what I mean it's sort of
we still just don't really know all that
much but I don't know that would be my
thought cuz for ages I was worried about
people importing clones to Australia and
bringing in all this stuff but it's like
if it's in seeds then it's already
here so like I I don't I don't know what
do you think yeah I don't know I don't
it's kind of like I know it's in the flu
it's it's like kind of like it's it's
it's kind of like plant herpes it's like
we won't I don't think we can get rid of
it it's something that people will have
to just live with unless we get some of
the science folks that are good at uh
creating some kind of antiviral
preparation it just might be a part of
our thing I mean how do they mitigate it
in hops I mean what are they doing and
then we have places that are
actively spreading it like you know
darkart was one of the that pretty much
spread it to all of
California um through their clones I
remember seeing Tre coming into
different places and going and looking
those dark heart Clones look so hideous
they're so I mean what is going on with
they look like you
know and then for them to recognize it
and come up with a now they're selling
the the uh the remedy for it somehow I
don't know what that is but it's just
like we need people need to be more
responsible that are in these places of
distribution if you know these points
they like they're like vectors they're
like disease vectors if you're Nur is a
disease Vector for the
entire uh State you need to change your
protocols like that's not okay so I
think it lies a lot I mean it's I think
maybe we can just ask for greater
scrutiny from Vector points nurseries
um um and and such and I don't know yeah
it's such a tough one I mean I do love
that these new clone nurseries like you
know like Jason's one and stuff where
they're everything is being verified and
tested and Mar stemmed and but even then
it's like one person gets that into
their room that has it and they're like
oh no I just got this clone it was you
know I paid a lot it was marem it's
totally clean and they got it from
somethingone else and it goes out and it
gets it from another plant in their
Garden it's like it's not like people
that you know at least with the person
you can get your HIV test or your herpes
test and you have the ability to things
but plants
uh can't talk in that way they can't
tell you that they infected by a viroid
I mean they can definitely talk to you
in other ways but yeah it's just it's
it's another one of those things I would
be I'm very curious to see how they
mitigate it and if it's a hop lat and
vroid like what do they do in hops like
how do they how do how have they
outsmarted in hops because there's so
much hops being
produced yeah that's a very good point
gosh I I wish I knew I should have asked
mve he he does a lot of writing about
similarities between Hops and cannabis I
think um there you go yeah that that
would be really interesting to know
what's going to happen I think we'll
have to wait and see uh I wanted to ask
you since we last spoke Todd mccomic has
come out with many of his offerings and
specifically the purest Indica you know
I wanted to know had you had a chance to
see it try it what's your thoughts on it
actually you know what I bought a 50
pack of it because we drew it at the um
at the uh uh the hay Valley the late
trials it was a cool plant it they were
really neat I mean they weren't the most
stable but they there were some really
cool plants I could see how it was the
progator for maybe a lot of these trains
that had the frost LEL level kind of
like the white but it but really scruffy
little plants like a Bubba and like
really unique I could see it as a really
cool Foundation for hybrids you know not
all of them had that they didn't have so
much smell and some of them had a little
bit of a neat smell but it was mostly
just very frosty and very uh very uh
just powerful structure like I could see
really unique and power it's something
that it surprised me that it was so
unique you know it's kind of like the
first time you grow like deep chunk or
something but I don't think we got to
try any of them because they all molded
out that's the only issue is they do
tend to be very susceptible to most
things that broad Leafs will
get oh that's a shame but there you go
and you know what I too have always
thought it looked similar to deep chunk
and uh I'd love to give it a run it
looks neat and what that's that's
interesting you know a lot of that
checks out uh another line I wanted to
follow up with you you know I'm going to
be honest there's there's so many
strains and so many questions that just
relate to following up on various
strains um but I've seen a lot of people
have been playing with the uh the fan
favorite the American skunk spray aka
the ass line do you have any thoughts on
using that one again and as a followup
any additional thoughts about the
roadkill skunk do you still think that
Sterling skunk is just that's it or do
you think there's something else that
the crowd is sort of endlessly looking
for do you think it it will be found or
where are we at with it I think we have
a better chance of finding probably in
those like Afghan like a selections that
they're doing um deep and and those guys
in the other groups that are working out
there like you know supposedly some of
the Maru lines like what do they call it
the runchy red or whatever they're
they're finding in in that in the point
of origin these kind of R kill things
and I mean I I don't Sterling skunk is
the closest thing we have in seed form
that I've come across and I think what
that Caleb has come across for smell and
it's a great outcrosser it can really
put that smell into other things but I
think roadkill skunk was a just like a
class kind of like we have gassy strains
like back then they had stunky strains
it's like there was a lot of different
stuff coming into the country back in
the day uh hash and Buds and stuff
brought back from the hippie trail and
stuff and that's just what was being
grown then and I think like most people
agree it was
probably a problem to grow it for law
enforcement and it just got it just got
kind of pushed to the side you know and
you you know some people remember it as
being this insanely potent and other
people believe that you know remember it
being not so potent give you a headache
it's like there's so many it's it has
that through time you know and I think
it I've smelt uh narrow Leafs that have
you know either have a pissy skunky
smell I think it's just it comes up in
all different plants but mostly from
those kind of from that area the stands
kind of like Central Asian trains seem
to seem to have it and seem to have had
it and it's just it just kind of dried
up in the states and then yeah and the
ass ass was just a particularly skunky
one it's not the strongest plant like
hippie Slayer is way powerful than that
you know and that one is equally as
hideous but it's more on the pissy side
you know I just gave uh hay Valley a new
one I'm the name duten
or um Doritos with 3z um or uh garlic
death um Cheetos or something it's it's
a it's a rework of the um um used to be
called the dragon not dragon souls
dragon's ass whatever the stinky one was
that I made a long time ago it's
basically a new version of that and it's
very it's beautiful it's so crystally
and the bud structure so nice and is so
hideous and so gross so people really
like to smoke the really hideous stuff
there'll be a new kind of it's an ass
variant ass barant when you need more
ass in your life but I'm so happy that
people are enjoying that like I share
that thing I even gave um I think I gave
Kore stray Fox and Jaws all F1 seeds of
ass to find their own ass and work into
and make their own ass stuff so I we
find cool stuff I love to give it to
other breeders like that's what the
whole the bandaid thing Hast that was
all we gave that mail that made uh the H
like we gave that out to like four
different breeders and they all made am
amazing things Bob hemple got it K got
it doc d got it I think ET got it who
else someone else and you know if you
find something cool share it I think
males mail sharing should be like a
whole new thing I don't know how I know
people try and sell Poland that seems
hard Poland so it's such a hard thing to
keep viable I don't maybe if you packed
in dry ice or something but share your
males share your females
and you know if you made something cool
see someone else can make something cool
it's like if everybody gives you a box
of
crowns draw a picture make it a gift
totally totally I mean hey there was
that G13 Haze that went around Amsterdam
you know oh yeah yeah and that went to
everybody's Gard everybody had it G13
Haze hybrids from s yeah and and like
and what I always say to people is and
this is something I've leared over time
you know um and maybe others learned it
straight away but like I'm I'm just
trying to say you know I I don't poo poo
anyone for not being aware of this but
like I'm of the same view I'm like give
it out and share it because even if
someone does something really cool with
it you're you will still be in the story
of like that's where it came from and
there's heaps of people in our scene who
are really well known through exactly
that and it's like it's not any nothing
gets detracted from you if someone else
does something with your work you
know yeah I was going to say it's like
you get to be part of this amazing like
history it's like why not be part of you
know in 50 years when the bars go out
and sing their hymns of all the great
cannabis Creations like be part of it
yeah open up share like I mean it we're
all in this together we're all working
on the same thing it's like this is the
coolest thing you can get involved and
it's like I always tell people there's
so many rad things in life you can do
you can get into food you can get into
art you can do all these things but
cannabis is the only thing that you can
do and it actually manifests in your
mind like it has a biochemical situation
like food is amazing chefs like G I love
like I'm more on the plant-based side I
love food and I love to see what people
can be created with food and all the
things but and you elicits emotional
responses but it doesn't get you
illuminated like it doesn't open up new
experiences in your mind like what an
incredible thing that you can grow it
you can trim it you can breed it you can
do all these things and when you're done
you finally get to bring it into
yourself and experience it you know what
other thing do you get to inhale into
your biology and become a part of
it yeah totally totally I like that idea
of becoming part of it that resonates
and and you know what just in line with
what we just said I I I got to give my
buddy uh Bin chicken a shout out this is
a bloke who's creating like these crazy
ABC hybrids that are like on par with
modern strains but they look like ABC
plants and um and he's actually used
some of my work in there and I was
saying to my wife the other day I was
like this is so cool cuz I think this
guy is going to go down as like the dude
who game changed ABC stuff and and my
work's just kind of embedded in there
like that's so neat like that feels
awesome like you know I'm stoked for him
oh yeah yeah yeah you're part of the
mandal something super cool and neat
that's yeah ABC is so all those lines
like the ABC and the freak Show and like
these mutants like mutants are red and I
know me and Caleb both we're both big
mutant guys you that's why he does so
much mutant work it is fun and cool and
it's not easy to do what you want it's
like a labor of love and that's like
somebody finding their Niche and really
taking it further and like it you know
it's cool and like it's cool that W you
know Wally duck being a part of that I
remember I still have a pack of Old
Wally duck um ABC or Ducks foot seeds or
whatever you know it has so many names
what is it quaz what are the what's the
other name that they used to call it um
that Fett used to call it has a name um
but yeah it doesn't it all go back to
Pro like an Australian progator like
it's like ducks foot like so Wally Ducks
stuff it um it goes back to just some
random guy in his town I think and then
all of the ABC stuff goes back to for
the most part it all goes back to this
this one guy we've managed to track down
and he gave it to a few different people
over the years but he was offline so he
never had any idea that like it was
popular online he just thought it was
this weird
thing wow that's so wild and then you
have like what Hawaiian Ducks foot like
you like that's something that people
aren't yeah it kind of fell off what I
don't understand why and you know it's
the same work with like people doing all
these incredible new Autos like how
awesome is that like that's something
that I It fascinates me like just the
how they make the Autos but it's not
something I'd want to do it's it's such
a it's like driving a race car because
you can't go backward like backwards
you're going so fast breeding these
really cool things and then you you
can't since you're always in autof you
can't Capt it's like you can only go
forward is that how it is unless you do
these photo period ones that are basis
at 18 or
something you've almost touched on to
the next question I was going to ask you
so so thank you thank you for getting me
there which was I was I wanted to ask
you know in terms of like the way you
view breeding or philosophies on
breeding has anything changed since we
last spoke like some of the things you
spoke about last time is you know really
flowering out the males to see what
they're fully offering and and resonance
males hey that's a cool little added
Advantage um has anything changed since
then have you do you feel like your
views on anything have shifted at
all yeah I mean there's so many it's
such a cool topic and everybody kind of
likes it's like always a question like
oh how do you do what do you do for
breeding I for me now I I feel like I've
developed like almost a six sense for it
like I can just I know it sounds dumb if
people are be but you can almost feel it
and like I'll double check myself by BL
wearing stuff you know males out really
far or doing all the smell tests and um
checking them out I like to you know
I'll have a mail room and I just
check the males throughout their period
you know because before they sex they
smell differently then after they sex on
the stem rub and you can get unique
experiences like before they even sex
there's so many different ways but when
people ask me breeding there's
goal-based
breeding and there's exploratory
breeding it's the breeding of of you
know looking at new plants looking at
things you've never seen before find
finding the outliers finding special
things finding new smells or uh finding
new morphology uh really digging in the
gene pool and exploring it and really
finding unique things and if you see
something that's really special putting
that you into your collection and
knowing that maybe at some point you're
going to find the perfect partner for
that for this amazing you know F1 hybrid
like I always say that my motto is like
extreme possibilities is putting two
completely different things together to
create some of total majesty and Beauty
that's that that you know that that is
so incredible and then by that point in
that F1 you re you get that hybrid Vigor
you get that you're basically it's the
gift of Mother Nature saying thank you
for putting these two Creations they are
completely different environments and
created shape through time and space
together to to create something
new um and that's like the true Essence
I think of is F1 breeding and that's
where you're really going to find a lot
of magic and also allow the person if
you give a seat to someone they not only
get to experience that magic but if they
like it they can do f2s and find and
really explore the parents and
understand what created those like it
can be a whole teaching like I almost
think of the seeds I create is like a
and like an interactive teaching course
like take something that's very solid
and something that's very well known and
and allow people to explore that and
make new things and if they like it go
further like it go even further and then
when you find plants and you get that
experience and you get those extreme
possibilities and you feel familiar and
you really want to go for then you can
go into gold breeding you're like I love
what this how this plant smokes I love
the high I don't like the smell there's
other plant that's like has an
incredible smell but it just has shoddy
structure it's like gold breeding is um
it's a process and you can really you
can add goals on As you move through it
and I think you know most breeding today
is co breeding but I really really
suggest and and encourage people to do
exploratory breeding really see the
unique things that can come out of it
and by default a lot of today's breeding
is exploratory breeding because we're
putting together these insane Mish
mashes you know and in those Mish mashes
there is great treasure but in those
Mish mashes you're going to have to hunt
through a lot of plants because
they are going to segregate out in a lot
of different ways and I think the magic
of f1s if even f1s that don't that
aren't dis similar enough to get hybrid
rigor you're still getting the unique
traits of just two plants but um and
like for tips for breeding yeah grow
grow as many plants as you can have a
big mom room have a big dad room keep
things around that you like back things
up in seed form um you know stem rubbing
is a great way to see how turpy
something is it may not smell like that
once it it's flowered out but there are
plants that are true to their stem rub
and stem rub before um sexing because
you're going to get a different smell
before and after um for seed making like
I always tell people you don't have
you're you can make seed you can
pollinate a plant and put it right back
into your mom room don't need to keep it
in the flower room it's like you can do
that outside you can make seeds outside
and bring it inside once your pistols
are pollinated as long as the plant is
healthy and happy you're making seeds
you don't have to have so much space you
don't have to create these Ms you can
have a revolving you can do so much it's
such a it's such an easy plant to work
with you know and I think it's the key
is yeah and is sharing and caring and
finding your Niche and and just
understanding finding that plant that
you Ry identify and getting and
understanding it and talking to it
people don't believe in this in plant
communication but I believe plant
communication is through the heart the
heart has like a I think it's what 5,000
times the magnetic field of the brain
and they're finding out now that it's
basically like the six cense this is
basically the heart is a is a field
generat it's a signal generator and it
moves out beyond the body and it
interacts with everything around it
other humans plants things and I think
if you can listen and tune into that
that's a really effective strategy to to
breede is to let the plants talk to you
and you talk back you
know you know it's through the heart and
yeah I mean you you I'm sure you have a
similar thing especially being a
musician I think being a musician really
allows you to have an like motive like
uh it's very emotional music and I think
that's a pathway to uh plant life
too yeah 100 100% you know and as time
goes by I feel like a just from an
empirical point of view the of all the
males I've to around with in the past
the two that I consider to have been
sort of the most success in terms of The
Offspring were ones that I definitely
had more of a connection like I felt
that connection whereas there's other
times of use Ma where you're like looks
good I guess um yeah and that's that's
huge you know in fact I've got one male
I've been lugging around with me
for almost 4 years now and I've only
just used it for the first time and so I
thought tell you what no one can say I
don't feel like you I kept it for three
years just going no it's time will come
but it's not yet yeah that's right no
it's true it's like that it's like yeah
you'll have meales in your in your mom
room that literally like I know yeah
someday this is going to be perfect for
something and you never know and there's
other males that's like that just want
to dust everything all the time with and
it's and but it's true it's they have
their own time and they will talk to you
the plants kind of tell you what who
they want to be with you can almost feel
it and when you work with plants enough
and you really open up to him it's like
you don't you can you almost
know what needs to happen it's like
you're I know we you know people like oh
we select the plants but do we are the
plants selecting through us who is the
selector of us that's selecting the
plants is it the plants is it us is it
something higher than us you know as
when I used to DJ and we were on vinyl
and we we tried to just open up to
source and open up to the crowd because
we're usually like in nature and having
these big free sound system parties it's
the key was to open up to the experience
of what we're doing this incredible
celebration and by being clear you'll
know what what music needs to come next
because it's a feedback loop through the
dancers the DJ and source and it's an
emotional it's an emotional connection
and I think we can develop that just
like you know I think the greatest
musicians are ones
that they had that special gift of I
thing or any artist you know and I think
that's the whole thing with Art and
Science with breing and all these you
know with now with scientific breing and
everybody saying oh you guys don't know
what you're doing you need to do this
and that and this it's like no not at
all it's like there's no way show me one
strain notable strain by any scientific
reader that's in the that's in the
cultural domain do I mean there's no
none that have held test the time
there's like I can't think of anything
oh well this guy made this and he's a
scientific breeder and we still grow
that it's like no sorry there's not
really anything out there um it's all
people that are doing this for the love
you know and do you do you want to
listen to machines or do you want to
listen to plants on this one you know
it's like it's kind of a non secter like
I get it and science always wants to
make it better but it's already better
and it's better through us making it
better so I think breeding is just doing
it for the love and really having an
open heart and an open mind and really
taking notes and taking notice like you
know I have tons of breeding books that
I can go back years and years and
they're just scribbles but I don't have
the best memory and I I sometimes I'll
look back and I'll be like oh my God I
forgot that's why I chose this one or
this one was this one or I did that one
I like oh that wasn't the original mail
I actually used the different one it's
like you're kind in this this beautiful
creation autopilot if you don't write it
down sometimes you don't even remember
all the magic what was happening because
you're kind of in the moment with it and
I think that's where where the fun
really
resides totally totally I think you've
you've got to be in the moment you got
to feel that connection more than just
some sort of uh textbook criteria cuz I
used to ask this question about like you
know if a robot just had a
checklist would it just not pick the
best male and I think that sort of again
is the Crux of what we're talking about
here but in and amongst that you
mentioned the word book one of The
memorable things in our first episode
was we we did a little book club had
some book recommendations I'd love to
hear have you been reading anything
recently that you'd love to give a big
UPS to or or a recommendation for people
to have a read on yeah you know what
it's weird I I notic that people aren't
reading as much it's it's more of like a
it's a lot of
social media and a lot of YouTube and a
lot of movies I notice with the younger
generation um but for books yeah I don't
get as much reading time as i' like but
I sure would but you know I like
anything by if you want to go more into
like plant spirit communication like
Stephen Boer um ell C let me think
there's so many cool things I love
reading if you want to go back and
really get back into that Pinnacle of
like the the natural scientist Movement
Like Steiner and
um uh you know who else is like Luther
Burbank is another you know you want to
talk about hype breeder for the day
Luther Burbank was like friends with
everybody from Ford to presidents people
would come to see him like he was the
man and he created so many different um
so many different varieties of of plants
and fruits and vegetables like like like
some insane amount and he did crazy
stuff he would if you ask him how he did
it like he was the guy that tried to
create um a spineless cactus and I was
reading about like how he did it he did
it you know he had a really insane Mac
for selection like he had like one of
the he was considered like one of the
greatest plant readers of all time just
because his ability to connect to the
plant on a different on that kind of
Heart level um but he would just do all
kinds of crazy combinations and po all
these different things and then his
Knack of selection was just incredible
but he one of the stories I heard about
him was uh he would talk to the cactus
and say hey you're safe here you don't
need to make spines we got you covered
we love you there's you don't need you
know you're totally protected and each
generation they would select they would
say that and eventually he made a
spineless
cactus and isn't that wild and that's
kind of the same story as there's I
heard about there was a plant um
Harvester and herbalist who also would
get their stuff tested in they did a
test where they went out to the field to
harvest like calf Frey or something and
they went out and so first they
harvested it and then they went out and
harvest it second time and the second
time the night before they went out and
told the plants why they were harvesting
and what they needed from them and what
they'd be using for them and the plants
they they talked to had naturally had
higher levels of the beneficial
compounds that they needed for healing
so it's like there's so much cool stuff
that just kind of got
the kabush put on it like just around
you know right as Automobiles and stuff
were kind of kicking in gear I think
after World War II we kind of lost the
heart and soul of of really working with
plants as as you know as we lost a lot
of
our our traditional ways of of working
with plants and a lot of our traditional
cultivars um too as well through you
know just get you know feeding people
and get trying to get what we could to
the markets and
really not falling back into the farmers
markets into all you know I mean people
don't realize too that migration to
America where everybody came everybody
came but everybody brought their seeds
there were seeds from all over Europe
from every part of the world that people
came from and not only did we have an
amazing Melting Pot of humans we had an
amazing germ plasma we had an amazing
like gene pool of stuff from all over
the world and we've slowly lost that and
I think that's a potent like a symbol
and
metaphor for what we're having now with
our own cannabis Jean Pool bottlenecking
you know you know if people want to see
a really cool movie there's a movie
called um seed the untold story that's a
really cool thing all about seeds and
how we've uh uh lost a lot of our seed
stock over time through different things
what else is cool you know I would just
say if you want to go if you're old
enough to be reading books I would say
Steiner um it's a great Natural Science
scientist Boer all the
ethnobotanists um Terence McKenna never
go wrong like I can listen to Terence
McKenna interviews the rest of my life
like I think he's probably the alltime
him and Bob Marley should be the uh
rulers of uh music and science um just
because you know Bob Marley everywhere
you go on the planet he's a saint
everybody knows Bob Marley song you
grown to the Nepal everywhere it's like
there's these people that have shaped
people's lives so I don't know there's
try books that I like I love shulties I
love um yeah I love you know what is
going on I love actually some of these
new websites too I like I just like what
everybody's doing and you know I'm
really thinking podcasts because now you
know when you work you usually can't
read you can listen and I've been
digging a lot of the the podcast and you
know even stuff like in different things
like micro entrepreneur like on all the
mushroom stuff and I love some of the
science stuff and I love lot of the
magical um stuff and a lot of alchemy
like Alchemy is physical Alchemy is
never been my thing but I really love
inner Alchemy and I love to hear a lot
of the you know some of
the Eastern philosophy as people get
just get into it find stuff that's cool
and like go for it like there's so much
out there and you know people always ask
me my like kind of what my meditation
practice is and you know if I it's my
primary one that I have a an initiation
into would be Kashmir shiism and I think
that's a really powerful um form of
meditation and a unique way of seeing
the world and it's also very similar to
even certain Buddhist path like Zan
and those are great starts um super
ancient dosm like Barefoot doctor style
like going back and really just walking
with nature and is really cool there's
still practitioners that just F same
thing in anything find your Niche find
the things that really allow you to to
flower to flourish to bloom you know
because the world is a big old dump of
compost like this world right now is
nuts what we're making right now is BS
like pom poost like so now's the time to
plant your seeds like that's where
they're going to grow best you know the
micro life is there from all the junk
that and it's it's our time to shine
it's our time to really bring this this
place back through planting ourselves
into it fully like blo where you're
planted like be the best you can be use
cannabis to be a better person that's a
you know when we finally get our merch
store again I want to make cool shirts
like not just stuff like you know A5 or
C5 bro what are you like those ones but
like like you know cannabis made me a
better person t-shirt or you know do you
even wash bro
you your plants wash
there's so many it's like we have such a
funny culture and so much it there's so
much joy that can be generated in this
thing I think we need to focus on that
and people soone what's up with
everybody having a beef with everyone
else can everyone just Just Do Your Own
Thing just you know what I mean why is
everybody uptight so much smoke another
joint and go take a walk in the forest
and tell me about it afterwards right is
it that big of a deal
no totally totally I I agree I agree I
feel like the ongoing Paradox you know
how come how come we all be so angry
when there's so many joints to to calm
you down but yeah you know I agree bod
the historical Channeler of uh non what
is it peaceful
resistance I love that and you know you
actually just quickly mentioned a
comment about the shirts we got so many
people asking about the shirts but also
as a bit of a followup just in general
is there going to be somewhere people
might be able to go in the future to get
info about upcoming drops about merch
stuff like that where would where should
they keep an eye on is it like your
Instagram for the moment watch this
space sort of thing or is there a site
yeah I mean what I mean first I want to
preference like as an apology to
everybody in the community I've been
such a Hermit and like I really like
it's been a challenging couple years it
it's it's just been a massive Exodus to
get to where we are now and when things
get really hard I I just kind of go
Inward and stick to family and and
plants and so yeah it's it's been a
difficult time but I feel like that
we're putting our Roots down and we're
really going to make a commitment um to
be an inspiration and to to be here and
to I'm going to try and be more and the
forums are hard because I'm such a slow
writer I'm try and be there I'm going to
try and I mean I think we're finally
getting a website we're going to come
out of the Shadows we're going to um do
that we're going to bring the merch back
the merch stopped because you know when
we moved we couldn't really sustain it
anymore we couldn't buy the stock um it
just we didn't have the time or energy
to do it or the finances and now we're
looking into doing it I love the silk
screen shirts from broprints those are
my favorite but we're also looking into
other other ways and also kind of moving
out maybe even like a Lifestyle brand or
something like just trying to make you
know more stickers like just change
people's minds you know I like things
like even funny things like you know the
Matrix was a documentary bumper sticker
you know like you know
bring things like that but yeah
definitely merch will be coming you know
it'll definitely be the same stuff but
also Med there's going to be n and
Medicine Mountain and um and stuff it
just takes time it's it's every day I
feel like I do so much and and I'm just
exhausted at the time I just every night
I have like a million people on
Instagram I want to write back and every
day that I don't I kind of eats away a
little about my soul but I'm gonna yeah
I'm gonna really do my best to to at all
of us you know we have my wife sage and
S son that we're all working together
right now and the three of us to kind of
bring it
back um you know Especial in this
especially in this time and age
when you know it's like
it's you got to you can either just fall
back into the Shadows or you can really
stand up and be a light and I think it's
time to shine you know in the darkest
times it's the time when it really
really needs to shine so I'm I feel like
we're rebirthing and I feel like I hope
that
everybody is rebirthing and kind of feel
that that that this is the time where we
all need to do it I think that's kind of
a weird roundabout thing about do we
have merch coming but yeah I think yeah
the merch is coming it just might take a
little bit and it might first start
maybe on some service like printful or
something for the colorful uh shirts but
eventually get the so screen ones back
and the hoodies and the hats we you know
try to make them
economical that sounds awesome I know
people will be very excited to hear
there's H something available and you
know in good time things come so uh I'm
sure people will be happy to grab what's
available in the near future as well as
later on I wanted to ask you one last
question before we jump into a few of
the patreon submit ons and that is have
you got any thoughts about the irari
lines you worked with I I remember the
Iraqi R was some really memorable smoke
um any is that just sort of you know in
the in the mix at the moment or any
plans yeah I think that was that was
Street Fox's brother I thought brought
that back um and yeah that's such a cool
line I mean um it was kind of like since
it was St we were just kind of
collaborating and doing stuff with it um
I we did grow one um the seed I have a
bunch of seeds that I made to keep the
line alive but the The Germ ratio's kind
of fallen off so we did get one or two
at the last um hay Valley grow off and
it's such a cool strain like it it's
very Gourmand which you know is very it
has the kind of like the coffee house
smells and flavors of cinnamons and
cloves and cream and and it has such a
great high it's a SL it can be slightly
unstable and it's I haven't quite
figured
out how or what you know how sometimes
after a couple crosses you can be like
oh it doesn't do well with this kind of
plant or it doesn't like this you know
it doesn't like other broad leaves or it
so I'm still trying to figure that out
but that one's definitely that one's
definitely still on point and I would
like yeah I'm I'll talk to stay and see
if he wants to do anything cool with
that as well um and then I have another
persion line from a
uh a friend of a friend who she goes to
visit her family I'd like to check that
one out too that cool and yeah I some of
those those are so like people don't
realize like those Broad Leaf those like
point of origin broad leaves are so cool
and fascinating and they really
Encompass like every imaginable smell
and flavor and even effect and like
there's some of the if you want to find
stuff that hasn't been hybridized yet I
mean it's sad because the reason why it
hasn't been hybridized is because it's
from war torn countries that have been
occupied by um you know people that
don't take kindly to anything coming in
I mean that's kind of our last our last
hunting grounds for truly unique old
school and even then they I mean they
clearcut it a lot of their um their
narrow leaf plants when they started
growing for massive hash production you
know like 30 years ago there was still a
lot of narrow Leaf hash plants and
sativas and some of the finest hash was
made with uh more Highland narrow stuff
and then as the Warlords and the uh mass
production came in they switched over to
the more hashy broadleaf stuff so yeah I
mean there's so much cool stuff out
there you can still find so rad you know
and people too I there's a lot of cool
people doing unique stuff that people
look at like Jaden ector and Jeff and
his garden in Boulder Creek he grows a
lot of incredible plants we go and look
at it every year and it's just
fascinating you know some of them I
think aren't totally 100% what they are
but everyone is fascinating there's some
ones that just are so cool like the
there's a Philippino purple one that's
so rad and there's some great Mexicans
and ties and like he grows stuff from
all over the world and it's super
fascinating to see in a in a big garden
and it's like I almost think like
someday I wish there was like theme
parks or Botanical Parks like it's like
oh it's hard you know I know Rob and
Mojave um did move they get they got to
go to some of the new uh uh Department
of Agriculture grows where they were
growing out these Mass sessions in like
where was it some ways back east and
then also at Davis and getting to see
these government collect
of seeds and Seed lines that were like
they were growing out like thousands of
plants so I would love to see like the
public get to really check these things
out I would probably die if I went to
one of these because all the males all
the Paul and I'd go in a hazmat suit
because I'm so hyper allergic to pollen
now that I've developed over the years
like you know it starts out everything's
good but after 20 years I can't even I
Gotta Wear like a like a like a going to
war or something
to
pollinate wow and out of curiosity you
just attribute that to just like
repeated
exposure it has to be like in the
beginning I I wasn't as it wasn't as
intense but you know I see a lot of
people that just can Wade through pollen
it's no problem but yeah I'm not really
an allergic person but I think just over
time like I can get it on my skin and it
itches and I can't if I I'll just gush
even a little bit I'll gush I try to go
in and sometimes do stuff like some of
my males pre flow and I'll come out
gushing um it's notnot
everywhere yeah wow I I I can't remember
exactly what happens but I think uh
Fletcher of archive also historically
has like some sort of reaction I can't
if it's pollen or tricomes but yeah he
he too has some sort of reaction and is
like got to be careful similarly that's
interesting maybe there's something to
that certain trimmers some trimmers
develop issues it's usually for yeah
like scanning like tricomes and then
some people can't handle thees for some
reason um you know they're just it just
sets something off and that's a whole
thing I mean tury it's like let's talk I
is that a topic I
mean what if if there's really 400,000
which I'm not sure that there really is
but that's amazing if there is like what
a pallet and what what I mean I don't
even know how to to think about that
like that's these are
biochemical it's a biochemical language
spoken to all of creation that's being
generated by plants like what are they
talking about like what are the all
these like what are we're not privy to
like what's really going on you know
when I was in
Amazon I you know I realized that
there's a whole communication Network
that we had no clue about and it was the
insects like you know when I was doing
my thesis work in Amazon with IAS like
and I realized that the bugs that's the
that's the true internet the Wi-Fi you
could tell everything going on in the
entire Forest just listening to the
insects and the birds like it was their
own language so I can only imagine what
nature is saying through these these
this language biochemical language of
Aroma yeah I'm really curious to see
where it goes because as you've
explained it's more and more information
about tpes and their characterizations
is coming out and it seems more and more
easy to present to present the argument
that cannabis is capable of producing
any tpine profile because of the
diversity of composition and
combinations it can do with the tpin but
at the same time what you see is that
we're not really finding new flavor
profiles which is kind of
interesting yeah I mean and then we're
not even finding we're finding these
like hyper aromatic tpine where like
they're not even reading in some of
these labs and it's like but they're
more perceptible than the ones that are
there by by weight and it's like so
there's tures that we're not
even even knowing but our but our nasal
Center is so equipped to pull out scense
like we're reacting even though people
like oh well this is has the exact same
you know just got mering and pining and
lemoning and that's it it's like and
this strain does too but they do
different things is that some
cannabinoid that we have we haven't even
discovered yet that's active in super
you know super minuscule things is it
tpin is it is it the plant it's it
itself is it's like what is it like what
is creating these effects it doesn't
seem like anyone has a clue except the
plants you know it's like no one seems
to know like that you know or even the
Entourage effect I mean there's a basic
basic Entourage effect that certain
things like LOL is calming and and
finding is rejuvenating and and you know
and then we have all the Citrus um you
know style ones that are very energizing
but are they really leading the
high you know it's like what is going
what is happening what is going on where
where are the effects coming
from yeah certainly certainly I mean
look you've kind of um almost stumbled
into one of the questions the patron
fans submitted so why don't we jump into
it and we'll start with this one which
sort of leads on which is over the years
have you found any strains that you feel
work particularly good for painkilling
or have you heard of anything that's
good for like say mild opioid withdrawal
and the reason I ask is because I've
found some strains like sour d is is
really good for that and I'm wondering
do we think maybe some strains activate
opioid receptors I've also heard old
hash plans can help
what's your
thoughts yeah I mean it's fascinating I
mean I mean that's even cool that sour d
is doing that because you know
traditionally a lot of people like
sativas will intensify their or you know
whatever you want to call sativas narly
intensify a pain response so it so comes
back to being so personal I mean there's
classic ones that are for pain like you
know Baba Kush has always been a great
thing master master kushes um you know
like the Sunshine Daydream is good for
nerve pain um certain broad leavs that
are naturally very relaxing and Euphoria
creating can do that but yeah it's weird
when you get into stuff like depression
you want real day brighteners it's like
it's it seems to be we're back to that
same thing of of really getting to try
plants to find what really gives us that
relief and with our gene pool dropping
and becoming very homogenized and very
inbred and bottlenecked and on a
consumer level our choices are getting
reduced it's should be harder and harder
to find those strains those individual
strains that can help us with our daily
our maladies and our you know our
disease like what so it's I don't know I
think it comes back again it's the same
thing it's like is grow Inspire trade
gift
support do whatever you can to make sure
that the diversity of
cannabis is within our reach and really
share that knowledge you know I think
there was someone a while back on one of
the forums that was making a list and
everybody could uh put in their two
cents of what plants were doing what for
them and which amazing because people be
like oh my gosh but at the same time
some people were like oh well that one
actually that does the opposite for me
but there are you know it seems like
maybe NE there's kind of there's maybe
you fall into groups maybe there's like
three groups or four groups or five
groups of people and different strains
kind of work for their biology whether
they're in you then you know some people
are endocannabinoid deficient you know
where and some people like we have one
of our kids you could give him like a
whole entire edible cake and he won't
even get high or he has like that enzyme
thing where it doesn't break
down canono in the system like there's
so many fascinating things I mean I
guess it's just getting the information
and information on the Grassroots level
because the machine ain't going to tell
you and if it is it's not going to be
for a long time and right now is when
we're we're having the pain you know if
you have pain right now you're not I
mean you're not going to be talking to a
machine about it you're going to ask
your friends you're going to ask to be
the dispensary you're going to be
looking for that kind of information so
I guess spread the
word yeah totally totally I I 100%
resonate with what you're saying about
like you know without the ability to try
that wide exposure of things how are you
going to find the thing that hits the
spot for this very specific issue that
works for you but maybe not for the next
person and it's uh it's sort of
interesting I sort of thought to myself
when I first started buying seeds let's
say around
2010 I felt
like there was just a whisper of cookies
hybrids in the market
and mostly a whole range of relatively
diverse other stuff and nowadays it's
like the polar opposite 15 years or so
later you know it's like there's barely
there's a whisper of things on offer
that don't have cookies in it and um you
know very little very little otherwise
um do do you think we'll ever be able to
get out of that or do you think it's
just it's gone too far and and to get
stuff that sort of doesn't have any
cookies or its progenitors onwards um is
is just going to be like you know the DI
hard Forum head type
stuff I wonder I mean through through
marketing and pro you know the power of
propaganda and and and just their
ability they have an incredible I mean
cookies is forces an incredible uh
ability to shape the the consumer
landscape of what people want to smoke
and I think it's kind of anchored itself
into history I don't think we I think
it's cookies is now in the same league
as like OG Kush and Hayes it's kind of
created its own category I think we're
kind of be kind of stuck it's just up
to you know the small breeders to find
those new things and maybe look outside
of of those things and you know lots of
people love those cookies hybrids and
they do uh they work really well for him
so there's always going to be a place
but yeah I think I think if we don't
start looking outside
of what we consume every day we're never
going to find those
outliers you know and maybe it maybe the
newest thing will come out I mean like
if you have a a polyhybrid polyhybrid
polyhybrid poly hybrid and you go
through a thousand seeds you may find
something that's like that has that's
some kind of ancient like you know
recessive plant from that's just the
that's popped out that is the new thing
because it's a little bit of everything
made made so incredibly Sublime and
perfect that uh that it carves a place
in the history of cannabis you know I
even and the whole thing with triploids
like sometimes they're found I thought I
think didn't they say like mac might be
a triploid there's a people still find a
lot of the mutants are still out there
there's still amazing treasure to be
found there are nature still creates all
these things and it's mostly about just
opening our
eyes there's incredible stuff to find
still but I think it's in and there's
such a a magic to the hunt to the
treasure to the treasure
hunters and that's
why deeds will never go away and I think
that's regul too always have a place
because sure you can S2 stuff but I
noticed with s1s you don't you have to
look through a lot of s1s to get
something cool you find some amazing
combinations but it's it's just as much
a hunt and then you don't have guys to
help back you it
up yeah certainly you need to be able to
do the hunt and you don't want to have
to hunt through stock where the odds
aren't stacked in your favor that's for
sure look while we're on the topic
people have been waiting we may as well
jump into it here saying as we mentioned
cookies a lot of people have been
wondering a lot of speculation tell me
about the cookies Endeavor how did you
get into it what happened and looking
back what are some of your thoughts
I think the experience is like I think
it's amazing learning experience like I
I'm I'm glad I embarked on it I know I
lost a lot of them my reputation I
realized that that was going to happen
and I had to make a decision like I was
I had this opportunity to do something
that I thought could really change the
landscape of cannabis
and and it kind of it didn't
necessarily come to fruti but at least I
tried and so the the story that came out
like when I was really originally making
the lavender lemonade and really wanting
to get into strain design and getting
into Nursery stuff and I knew that I
would have to be moving from my farm and
I wouldn't I didn't have a I didn't
really have anything I was able to do
and so I kind of prayed on it and sent
the word out and kind of put out energy
that you know I'd like to do some strain
design and the funny thing is like of
course I had a dream that the first
people that off that wanted to do my
streams was cookies which I thought was
so weird I was like there's no way and
over time uh friend to a friend said hey
burner wants to talk to you about some
stuff and so I was like uh I I wasn't
you know I'd like to make everybody kind
of work for it so they kept on trying
and trying and like well let's go on a
walk in the forest or something but I
don't know nothing panned out but
eventually you know I I he offered uh to
come visit him at his house and and we
got you know over about a year's time
maybe I came over a couple times and we
had some really good talks like I really
found him to be a a a kind and fun and
unique kind of gentleman like definitely
a Goff level like Hustler and manifestor
which I thought was really cool in a way
like you know you got to give him credit
he's created this uh movement that and
this this force that has pretty much
terraformed formed the Cannabis culture
in a way and you know I thought that was
I found everybody at cookies to be
pretty passionate and actually cool and
down to earth and uh I enjoyed talking
with them and I enjoyed I explained what
I kind of was into and I brought we
brought samples and he was really into
it and we talked about stuff and we kind
of had a I think you know we had a
common ideal that we need the gene pool
we were moving into a place that they
were kind of moving into a place where
they couldn't get out of they were
bottlenecking themselves into their own
creation even though this creation is
you know like steering a huge sector of
the Cannabis space for what people want
to try and enjoy and what's cool it was
naturally about to Snuff itself out like
a flame well when it get doesn't get
oxygen you know and we talked about
different plants and land uh land Racers
are
heirlooms and um and the old days and
kind of just went through a lot of
different things and they uh asked if I
wanted to do genetics with them and you
know I had to think long and hard and he
was like this is a really great
opportunity to really expose a lot of
people to really unique and new things
and the flagship straight we're start
with was the supernatural selections
Congo Kashmir which actually made it
onto the the menu
[Music]
um and after that we were going to do a
lot more kind of these like creating
some uh lines like the D 5.3 was going
to be the chocolate milk white chocolate
um really creat some new flavors and new
um effects and new uh things and really
open people's minds to like a whole new
world and by having these new flavors it
benefit them because they are going to
be able to offer these things that no
one's really ever experienced in that
part of the community and really open
some minds and for us for my I mean I
think we both had our own ideas I wanted
to kind of get the Jean Pole out of a
bottleneck and also really show some
other sides of cannabis and you know uh
things are going along we were supposed
to have these big uh containers to be
able to do lots of pheno runs but it
never really panned out the the
containers uh they kept on having a hard
time getting them
licensed um and they'd always you know
we couldn't start and it just went
longer and longer
and
um things just kind of fell apart I
don't have any ill will at all to them I
found them you know delightful I knew
they do a lot of behind the-scenes stuff
that isn't poetic at all and I think
their their karma is showing them that I
know and I you know by being there I I
realized
that maybe the core group is passionate
and and involved and really it is it is
their their love of the life and their
passion but there's you know there's a
bigger situation behind it that's
controlling it and I don't think they
were necessarily happy when I didn't
want to make seeds for them when I just
wanted to just do strain design and you
know over time just fell apart and they
had their karma to work through and I
realized it just wasn't going in the in
the in the direction I wanted and we we
parted ways you know and I'm still
working the one line out I made for uh
burner the lavender lemonade Skittles
and I think it's almost ready I wanted
to at least you know I like to always
finish up my projects like if I say I'm
gonna make something cool I'm gonna I'm
gonna come through so I I polished up a
really unique feno that I'm calling
jenz and it's like kind of like the next
evolution of a a skittles likee plant
and and you know so far it's it's
exceeded All my expectations of smell
flavor and also keeping through the Cure
and and the ability
to create abundant amazing resin so
that'll probably be the final thing that
you'll
see that kind of like the closing
chapter but yeah I it was you know my my
whole thing about extreme possibilities
I really thought it was super F1 hybrid
between between this amazing force and
also my collection of of unique genetics
that we could do something special but
maybe it was a lofty goal and you know I
know people really got upset about it
but you know when I was thinking it's
like I also saw the writing on the wall
of like you know cookies doesn't have
always the the best rep but they're
still part of our original Community
they you know all those guys they
hustled the grew they we're all came up
in the bay we all were part of the same
force that was moving through time and
space as cannabis and now there's some
forces that are coming in that
completely level everybody so you know
it's like kind of like
um like the Han Solo working with the
Ewoks or something you know it's like
the Bounty Hunter and the and the forest
Spirits working against the uh the the
Death Star so I don't know I learned a
lot and you know I I I liked where it
was going it's too bad it it didn't ever
really work
out yeah certainly look I can I can
appreciate your point of view you know
someone's got to get in there and do the
work I guess just just to uh avoid
anyone saying I I I didn't push hard
enough my interpretation of what you're
saying is that like burner and the inner
crew they seemed cool they seemed on
board but obvious VI L cookies as a
company is much much bigger than just
burner and the inner crew and it just
felt like there were sort of forces at
play that just weren't really working in
your favor is that sort of what you're
saying yeah and I think just the
national in inera of the progress of the
plan never panned out so there was no
there was no like what do they call it
proof of concept there was never the
ability there was just you know i' moved
I had a few clones I offered up the
Congo Kashmir clone as as a as the and
you know it it's an amazing Train
everybody loves it I don't know if if
the public liked it as much and after
that not being able to pop more seeds
and to really do these hunts because
there was no you know there was no uh
there was no place for me to to work I
couldn't produce any new and as there
was nothing really to see and maybe it
was just not meant to be maybe it was a
lofty goal and a great thing and I know
uh yeah it just fell apart and never we
never were the plan never was realized
and so when it got to a point we
just we parted
ways sure no look I understand I
understand and uh and I I I'm still
grateful that you tried to do it I I was
always and always have and always will
be in support of this I think trying to
make a difference from the inside is a
valid tactic for anything you're trying
to do really and uh on on the topic you
know you sort of mentioned the the Congo
cashmir in the mix one of our listeners
they uh sent in a message saying you
know I actually went to a cookie store I
got to try some they said look it smoked
really good and I was really surprised
by how well it sort of fit in as like a
flower on the cookie shelf you know like
it didn't seem super out of line and so
much so that like I was really surprised
sort of as what they were saying is that
your experience does it sort of look
like cookies weed in a sense was that
one of the reasons you hand it over and
um what's it like to smoke that
plant so yeah I'll start on Congo
Kashmir um yeah the reason why we picked
Congo Kashmir is because it has one of
the most unique and uh like really
flavorful it's t like you would never
expect it to be an F1 hybrid I mean the
way it looks and the way it grows maybe
uh because it's very it has it's very
vigorous it's very beautiful it's it's
very robust um
and it's you know it doesn't take longer
than nine weeks it was almost a it's
it's really
special so I had a few samples and that
was the one that agreed upon that would
be kind of an entry way because we also
had to you can't just like Drop in like
some crazy heirloom plant into a cookies
facility because they don't always look
good we had to create some I had to
create the find the perfect plant to as
a rainbow bridge to bring that consumer
over to a new level of appreciation so
they'd be open for future um creation so
yeah the Congo Kashmir has this really
Lush like it seems like it has almost
every turpine you can imagine in it it's
almost kind of like um you know some of
those like really hoppy alses that where
they put like every known hop in there
to try and get the ultimate like a
expression of citrus and like Pine and
um and then what else like Earth and um
gas and it just has like kind of
everything going for it it's
visually pretty like it doesn't look
like a you know doesn't look kind of
jungly like some heirloom stuff it has
really nice buds it's very crystally it
holds on the plant through the Cure very
well and it has a really like functional
yet up high where someone that maybe is
used to smoking like the cookie Style
hybrids or indicia Style Plants it's
functional enough for them that it's not
scary or uh frightening or edgy like
it's just kind of like having a cup of
coffee after you had your like whatever
nightly six-pack of hinin or whatever
you know for someone that likes to slow
down after work or to play video games
or something it just gave a little boost
a relax it was kind of like relaxer size
you know like when you're relaxed but
can but you want to exercise I don't
know if that makes sense but I also like
to call it like rert like relaxed yet
alert it would there was a category Kong
Kashmir it would be very turpy rert um
bu that that there that you know that
they that's outside of the Wheelhouse of
that and so that was the entry way like
we had a lot of grandiose like I thought
something was really going to happen you
know and that's okay but it's like you
said all you can do is try and I know
lot of people felt like I sold out and
this and that I you know I didn't become
a millionaire I didn't I just got a I
don't know I just got a a basic monthly
salary and I got to do basically pretty
much not too much
uh you know to create something that
never really happened and you know I
think you know maybe I I'm praying that
in the future that that new that the
bigger companies will pick up really
unique and special things as long but
that's the whole thing of the breeder
the breeder whether it be scientific
natural whoever you are in your closet
in your things out in the fields like
yeah I I think it's important like that
that's what kind of I really some of the
I really learned a lot and you know I
have respect for them even though I
don't agree with the thing all the
things they do the core group and what
they you know they just happen to be put
in yeah I don't even know what to think
about it anymore I just I'm happy for
the experience I realized like it really
taught me a lot and it really taught me
that that the only way we're going to
really be able to kind of change this
environment of bottlenecking is by
finding things that appeal to the
consumer and that also that these big
facilities can can bump out and at this
point we're all you know the people that
are into it are into it they know a good
gunch they know what's up but most of
the most of the states most of the
planet I me not Planet I'm going to just
say most United States doesn't really
know what good ganja is they just know
what's in the dispensary and they've
been forced by that it's like going to
someone that's eat at McDonald's their
whole life they just they want
McDonald's so it's like we have to make
these new plants that are going to fit
in that mold but have the ability to
liberate them from uh not only from the
the the effects of the old stuff but
also the pers pervasiveness of that's
that's you know inhabiting their
Consciousness this kind of
purple glistening candy gas that's great
and it's great for um for doing stuff
but there's a world out there that needs
to be explored you know I think it's a
Birthright to be able to experience
everything that the world has to give us
and cannabis is a great part of that
100% 100% look we we've been talking a
lot about unique and special stuff and
we actually got a really interesting f
submited question which is that you've
got so many magical plants in your
garden and you've given us some unique
descriptions of past experiences but I'm
wondering what do you enjoy on a daily
basis do you ever actually go back to
something repeatedly or is every time
you smoke just something totally new um
I try and mix it up I can tell you like
my wife is really into
manoni she really likes that out of the
last ones that we've Brewing that's like
a it's a new I think that gets released
in a week or two it's the it's a
supernatural selections um and it's the
J mortega old Hawaiian clone um crossed
with the angel wing Afghan and it makes
her like it's just happy for her like um
there's a certain feno one feno is a
little racy for her but the other feno
just makes it's just kind of like a day
brightener like just a lifter and it's
it's it's user friendly like you can go
to sleep on it you can do whatever you
want it's just kind of this kind of like
all around good vibe kind of
Gan and let me think what else uh stuff
that I like to go back to I don't know I
you
know I'm I'm always just things get old
in the jars and I'm always trying new
things I'm always just
searching you know when I used to have
things hanging in at the Old Farm we had
a garage you know we lived in the
coastal fog layer so I had the perfect
humidor so I could have things hanging
for years and they just only get better
so you I would go back to certain things
for certain things I would go out to
music I would like do some GOI or there
was that rogery Shar that I would use uh
that I really love that just kind of
glistened my day like barely noticeable
and you know I the sativa is one I
wanted to get really out
there um and really get psychedelic you
know go down to the Dome and just trip
out or listen to music like I would
really I really kind of move through
stuff but I think for right now the
stuff that I've gone back to more than
once was that coni Mana you know I also
liked um I had some of Jimmy's
um what's uh uh Lily what is it called
oh yeah um lily of the valley that stuff
was really cool and my friend reg makes
has this really incredible black cherya
one that I really I really liked I tried
some that Filipino I tried was really
dreamy love that on I'm trying to think
of some of the ones that recent notables
um what's in my
jars yeah those are the main
ones um that I can think of that I've
gone back to oh there's this one called
Blue camper that I like a lot too and
it's a ogkb orgasmatron hybrid that's
kind of but that's going to be I'm
hoping that one will make it into
nurseries it has like a total blueberry
can for taste and
smell and then you know I did like I'm
making this uh I had a string called
Lush it was a la pure cush that was
really beautiful and so I've been using
that one and back Crossing it back into
the pure cush and I'm trying to make a
pure cush exactly looking
tasting um growing but growing with the
Vigor and the strength of the LA so like
a super cush like you know you're kind
of like pure cush is such an incredible
strain like that
Malibu Malibu PK like all that whole
kind of family whatever that um but it's
stringy and it's kind of a pain so I'm
trying to create I'm almost there I'm
creating like like the Arnold Schwarz
Nega version like the more like pump you
up like strong with a little bit more
head high and that one's been turning
out nice been smoking different fenos of
that before um
before left the planet
um yeah there and I you know and I was I
oh I went through a serious dork out
phase on the lavender lemonade Skittles
when I was trying to do the selection to
go make the Gen z h uh gen Z selection
had to go through a bunch of those which
was okay it was kind of cool um they
were really flavorful what else there
something is there anything else
see those are the main
ones look sounds like you uh enjoy a
really nice variety you know from
between the uh the selection of the Gen
Z through to the the dreamy Filipino
land race you're you're still really
trying a wide diversity it sounds really
really
interesting while we're on the topic
this will be our last patreon one and
it's the one I actually had the most
people asking about it's now clear to me
that I think something has overtaken GOI
as uh the most popular bod strain well I
mean we're sort of skirting the rules
here a bit but without a doubt the Deep
line Alchemy Series has just become just
huge in its cult status and the amount
of following it's garnered over the
years so many people just wanted to hear
you talk a little bit about you know
what's sort of your Direction with it
you know I guess sort of your your
thoughts on Why You released it the
various versions and you you know what's
your favorite what's the Dark Horse any
any plans to do anything further with it
yeah I mean the D it's such it kind of
take on took on a life of its own you
know like I I don't have the that the 88
G13 hashplant anymore like I don't have
that mail it was retired I do have like
all my seed work on it and all the
different ways I took it in line so I'm
sure I could find another mail but uh
I've been kind of hunting for a new mail
and I was think about like an H Al like
an ala or an HLA like it would be a
heirloom um line Alchemy or an ancient
line Alchemy because I can't do da
because that's the original
um yeah I mean the I would I really love
the that thing of allowing people to
kind of because they know that male so
well that when you pair it with
something else it's almost like this
ongoing like uh like a teaching
presentation where you can like it's
interactive because it allows you to
really experience that clone only like
special uh Broad
Leaf um I think the the big run up now
is that uh kind of Triad it's the big J
um angel wing artifact one male I think
may be the one but it really needs some
testing but you know it started just as
a way to to get people turned on to some
of these really cool old um broad leaves
you know and I uh and the funny thing is
I think the second one was it the first
or second one was
actually it wasn't it I didn't use the
adh3 mail I used something else and so
it was it kind of threw it off in the
beginning and there's also some
unofficial dlas like there's wish
Mountain which is the Afghanistan 88 G13
hash so there's some that kind of there
actually are dlas but they snuck through
to other ways and I wish I could kind of
recom find them and uh I'm just excited
there's so many cool plants a lot of
those plants I don't have anymore and
there's a lot of there's a few daas that
were never even released like there was
a the last one that kind I only made
about five packs I just gave a few packs
out was the like the da 17 or 18 or
something and it was the U the SNL the
Captain Jack Afghan the smell of SNL the
the one the bud that they all smoked
during that beginning of Saturday Night
Live Like I guess Dan Aro and all these
guys this is what they smoked before
they would go out on a and and uh film
The Ear Le
snls and so I made that to anything but
the the mom was so worn out that the
seeds the seed Coats were flaking off so
I couldn't really release
it um so I can only find like you know I
only found a out of a huge bag that I
made I think I only found like 50 seeds
or something so that one won't get uh
released but maybe I'll do an F2 of that
you know and then there's ones like um I
think that I don't think the ma8 the
Hairspray the LA hairspray cush one
never made it out and I think there's
one or two more that didn't make it so
yeah DL um so yeah the D what so what a
cool phenomenon what a the great thing
and I'm so stoked that people are like
F2 them and getting them into and
finding like there's a way to like
finding their favorite dlas because
they're all so different like some of my
favorite ones and I know like one that
everyone loves is I love the D four and
five like I love the A1 because the very
first A1 because it still had the really
rank skunky stuff and I love the da 4
the cashmere one because it was such a
frosty cool Plant um I love let's see
what are some of my other favorite ones
you know the D with the the Lebanese is
so cool the
um um what else there's so many there's
the Jala there's the you know what the
da with the kahar black is really cool
too like they're also neat and it's like
it's almost like that just kind of it it
almost became its own thing like it you
know it's every time it's like it almost
seemed like there was a force behind it
that was just working with me or through
me like somehow a new D would always
kind of pop out you know and like oh
cool here's the new D like and you know
I'm so stok that people got into those
and really kind of sad that they're done
but I'm also excited because people can
F2 them and maybe I can F2 some of the
ones that were never released and maybe
we can move into a new era I'm thinking
with this new Triad mail of my three
favorite Afghans they all have such
unique and beautiful traits in them but
by breaking it into threes I think
they'll be a lot less dominant than the
ADH G3 turn 13 hash PL that's the only
problem I felt like with the DNA dlas
that was a problem itic is that male
tended to be even though it was awesome
and it always brought a lot to the table
it was a little dominant you know and
originally the de the ADH G13 hash plant
was a lot it was a different maale it
was the deadly G mail that I worked a
lot further into the future but it
became so dominant that I couldn't use
it anymore so I had to go back and find
a less dominant 8h G13 flash but that's
the one that's used that's been used in
almost
everything so yeah daa is such a such a
cool it's such a cool ride and I'm so
glad to kind of been along with that and
there's so many cool plants it's almost
kind of like a history lesson too like I
get to because you know when you have a
chronological order you get to see like
I remember the first one and then you
know through the years there's all these
different ones and some of the plants I
got and then the plants I lost and it's
just a really cool it's just a cool
thing I yeah I don't know anything quite
like
it totally totally and that's why I
think it's developed such a cult status
and people will continue you to uh dig
into it f to it share it and it's uh
it's a testament to the work I think
we're on to the quickfire questions to
wrap things up and uh we've got some new
ones since last time so the first one I
want to ask you is I'm going to drop you
off on a desert island you can take
either three clones or three packs of
seeds what are you going to take with
you to grow out forever how big is the
island it's huge oh nice so I can
segregate I won't get any like what the
I have no p clouds I can make sure
everything stays you're good infinite
infinite resources to grow as well okay
three I that's super basic I think it's
pretty easy I would do like a CBD Rich
line you know maybe like like Harlequin
or something for health and Harmony
healing and then just give me like a
just a really nice Afghan and and just
uh a well worked Haze line and I think I
can make just about anything sure so
which ones are going to be the seeds oh
all the seeds oh they're all seeds I
love it perfect I'm not risking clones
on this island
for there you go good good idea good
idea I love it you just recreate
everything with that yeah why not that's
perfect that's perfect all righty next
one is uh if you had to restart the
entire company all of the companies with
just one pack of seeds which pack would
you take oh I would you know I would
probably that's a tough one I would
probably start it with like it's either
Goji or Sunshine Daydream like I think
GOI I think I would like that's a great
starting point I just it's just such a
great feel good
strain perfect and then you know sort of
similar but slightly different without
being able to know any details about the
person what's one strain of your work
that you would recommend that you just
think you know people are going to like
it people will like it I don't know I
think Congo cashmir is pretty digestible
to just about anything I really like
that one um something that everybody
would like
though yeah it's got to hit every kind
of
pallet okay I'm gonna say cono
cashmir yeah that's a good pick I I
stand by it Al righty our final question
for the
interview what is your hope for the
trajectory of our community and indust
My Hope for the trajectory of community
thing is just to plant seeds share those
seeds plant them everywhere Inspire
everybody meet friends meet uh talk to
plants don't talk to
machines just love each other create
Pathways for learning communities get
involved get involved like uh go to the
forums make your own things make your
own Facebook pages just
just Network and just the key is just to
nourish this community to and to really
know that it's special and it's so
healing not only for everybody involved
but for the entire planet like this is
the time to come together and just let
all bygones be bygones and know that hey
we're doing something really magical and
and and it's so it's so beneficial for
the future and should just yeah just be
hopeful and you know I know things are
hard right now but just find that Niche
that thing that really turned you on and
go for it because whatever you do with
your heart you know is worth is valuable
and is worth you know that's I don't I
just be kind and plant
seeds beautiful I love it what a what a
fitting ending so with that I think it
just about brings us to the end of it
for this one any comments or shout outs
you wanted to make yeah just everybody
that's that's following their heart you
know and and making the world a better
place and yeah big big love and
blessings to to everybody in the
garden 100% so again a big thank you an
absolute pillar in the world of breeding
a real breeders breeder a man prolific
his output of work one of my favorite
people B of B seeds thank you for coming
on
thanks and there you have it gang what
do you
reckon huge huge huge shout out to my
brother
bod taking the time to come on the
show share some
love Inspire us all
[Music]
if you love this episode please consider
supporting both the patreon as well as
the websites of our incredible sponsors
if you're looking to transition from
combustion to vaping check out our good
friends at dap you will not be
disappointed cheap affordable and
Incredibly efficient units likewise
check out our friends at Pulse sensors
if you want to make sure that your
garden is dialed in and you are tracking
all of the variables that are going to
ensure your next Harvest is the best to
date you got to get yourself a pulse
guys it's a
no-brainer in order to ensure that your
garden is pest and pathogen free please
check out our friends at copit they are
the number one in bior predatory
technology copit thank you so so so much
for your
support likewise a big shout out to our
friends at Organics alive for all the
most incredible powdered organic
products usable in all systems both
organic and hybrid a huge thank you to
Organics alive we recommend them highly
please check them out if you want to
take your organic game to the next
level finally massive shout out to our
good friends at seeds here now they got
heavy days beans go check them out guys
I promise you will not be disappointed
they got all the latest drops the
hottest breeders fem Auto photo period
CBD whatever you need they're here to
help you out a massive thank you to our
friends at seeds here
now and big love to the patreon gang we
love you so much thank you for
supporting the show they got Early
Access to this episode over month ago if
you want to get extra content please
consider supporting the show you'll
score yourself genetics a whole bunch of
swag from our sponsors and so much
more so that just about brings us to the
end of it for this
one big thank you to you for getting to
the end yet again and for the
support Big Love is always from your boy
heavy
days signing
off see you
[Music]
oh