[Applause]
[Music]
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
alrighty everyone we are back for
another breeder Awards we're quite late
and I can't really blame it on Covert to
be honest I think we've just been doing
our respective things but nevertheless
as usual I'm joined by the man with his
feet on the ground in the scene I'm
stealing that one from Adam Dunn thank
you very much James Bean for joining us
thank you appreciate having me again I
uh I feel humble always you asked me to
be on these and do these this time I was
like May then we do this one already but
you know I get stoned so I appreciate
you not I love the show of course
uh that's very sweet if you we love
having you on so as usual we're gonna do
our uh usual awards for the year
including strain of the Year breeder of
the Year hottest new breeder on the
Block we've got some hall of fames some
shout outs and uh maybe some final
thoughts at the end hopefully that
sounds pretty good to everyone
uh so the first award we'll do this year
we might do uh the strain of the year or
clone of the year we've sort of combined
them together you know it's uh it's if
you want to call it a strain of the year
and it comes from seeds no problem but
we'll also count clones in this category
so
gosh I'm trying to remind myself now
what won it last year
the year before that it was Mac we
definitely did like runs we're ahead of
the curve on runs and then runs one and
then oh yeah yeah last year ice cream
cake and what a [ __ ] good pick that
was man yeah now that if you've seen
that show at that TV show
all right cool so I mean let's think I
gotta be honest I saw a lot of Oreos
this past year this past uh what we say
15 months or so
and I was considering that for a bit but
I also saw a large sort of group of
disparaging comments saying that um you
know all look no substance I haven't had
it myself so I can't comment on that but
that was definitely one I had in the mix
was there anything you sort of had in
the mix before we revealed the winner
oh I don't know what your winner is yeah
you don't you know I I wasn't leaked the
list uh but uh
well I just I I know what I know what I
think is gonna flood the the West Coast
Market
what's that
jealousy
I'm not sure if that's your take that's
a pretty good pick
I said I I saw I must have seen if I saw
if I saw one I saw a thousand and one
Cuts flying out of the animal cut for
sure like no question uh that will be
grown and that's the situation with the
Clone is that you have the same thing
that everybody else has unfortunately
um with a c you're guaranteed something
unique of course I'm pushing seeds but
you know
that's going to be in every Greenhouse
by the thousand and I guarantee in six
months we're gonna look back and we're
gonna say man I can get jealousy for ten
bucks a grand you know cheap as hell out
there so I would say that one or I don't
know if you're extended there's this one
but the Gary Payton
that's a pretty good guess as well I
definitely had those two in my top
selections didn't actually get the
winner though so that's cool because we
sort of sort of collectively covered
them all I guess for this last one this
last year I should say that
the thing that I considered was both
what I saw in flower but also what I saw
a lot of breeders incorporating into
their repertoire so
really popular among some of the more
heady breeders in my book so the
2021-2022 strain of the Year clone of
the year goes to none other than Lumpy's
apple fritter
[Music]
on that one uh definitely uh with
jealousy it's gonna be everywhere apple
fritter is a more tightly held cotton
that you know a certain group of
breeders definitely got their hands on a
great strain has been used definitely
everybody's kind of used it I've seen a
lot of different crosses with it
um no it's a yeah like that's it like
Skittles ugly plant but breeds true you
know have a fairly decision great plant
so I definitely interested to use a
bunch and yeah
for sure
yeah it's one of those ones that's sort
of been gaining momentum for a few years
now but I've definitely seen a lot of
really killer crosses coming out with it
in it and I also think it's good you
know like shout out to lump status a guy
who's contributed a lot of really cool
clones to the scene
um a part of that original crew with
like you know ABF Frost boss nor Cali
c-mag those guys from the Bay Area just
putting in work over the past 15 years
or so so yeah congrats apple fritter
it's everywhere
um notably I've seen some sick hybrids
skunk VA posts some they look cool I've
also been iron off Bloom's done an Apple
Fritter hybrid that's cool as well
um yeah a lot of cool ones in the
Woodworks
and so the next category we're going to
take a look see at will actually be
let's do the Hall of Fame let's get that
one out of the way
it's uh the Hall of Fame for us is
actually always a strain not a person so
we're thinking about what strains have
contributed significantly over the years
recent or Years Gone by that have really
sort of guided the way paved the
landscape for future strains to roll on
through uh so we're always sort of
looking back in this category and I
think there's a lot of really good
contenders so after considering all the
things I just mentioned I'm thinking
that this year we're going to actually
go with blueberry from DJ Short
it's uh really a body of work that's
hard to ignore both in terms of its own
Merit standing individually as a strain
the uh the F1 hybrids that come off it
in DJ's Arsenal or that have lineage and
commonality with it uh such as you know
things like the f-13 and the trueberry
all of these strains tried and tested
but I think one of the other Testaments
to the blueberry family is that there is
a huge arguably bigger body of work that
exists from what others have done with
it outside of What DJ has done so you
know the the list of clones is literally
endless I could name a few you know even
obvious one you know Blue Dream haha but
like even if we get even more into it
like I've had strains like um Blue
Diamond I've had a whole range of really
cool blueberry crosses from AK Bean
brains because he's done some cool work
with it likewise my favorite stream
remain in seed form the blue Magoo comes
from the blueberry it's it's really you
can't overstate how much of an impact
this work has had and I think there's a
famous quote that's been said that
something like 40 of all the plans
tested at philos or something had
commonalities with blueberry and I think
there has been some healthy and robust
discussion around that but if nothing
else it really does point to the fact
that this strain has had such an immense
influence on the the genetics that have
come there after and it's it's so tried
and tested it's really one of the only
strains you can say that is on that
level that a we still have active seed
stock for and B is not a clone only we
we you know DJ's still around he's doing
his thing
yeah no I think I I you know his son
uses the F4 male uh quite a bit and and
the strain has had such a huge impact in
history there's there's you know the
humans from blue dream blue dot I mean
we could lose ourselves in the face here
for sure
um and and yeah it was you know uh just
a short flower indica
just a great a great plant
yeah a really special plant and the more
you dig into it the more it sort of
actually becomes really interesting
because it's like it doesn't have
uh The Afghani in it that's in a lot of
other Afghani genetics it's almost like
you know it doesn't have Afghani one in
it it doesn't have the same Afghani many
other people have worked with it's got
the uh the the Oregon purple tie in it
which is just such a mythical strain in
its own right it's all of the individual
pieces are so interesting and again it's
so so tried and true it's really a
strain that has continued to involve
over time as DJ and his son have both
continue to work it
but again I think one of the biggest
values of it is that we still have
access to males and females
um you know notably DJs selections of
females are out there in circulation
maybe not necessarily easy to get but
they are out there and uh likewise his
breeding parents are still around which
is really a unique consideration for a
strain that has this uh body of Legacy
associated with it
yeah and and as he puts it the finished
product has a very fruity Aroma and
taste of blueberries producing a notable
and pleasantly euphoric High the highest
quality it's very long lasting
resistable tolerance buildup always
enjoyable everybody has a long shelf
life store as well over extended periods
a long cure enhancing the flavors in
effect winter of course in the 2000 High
time standard step
uh we sell this [ __ ] at it and it's one
of the most ripped off strains as well
like um you know there's other people
that will sell other banks that sell
blueberry and they don't claim it to be
shorts blueberry or they explain it as a
tiny earthy strain which is exactly the
opposite of it
um and then like you mentioned so not
only is the most ripped off strand of
all times but uh it's also probably most
used you know other people have used it
in their process over everything you
know you go through my catalog and just
you know looking at like you said if you
know whatever the catalog and throw it
in an induction real quick yeah a lot of
that stuff is going to come back because
it's been around since the 70s so it's
it's been there and it's you know when
canvas was a lot different than it is
today
Yeah a hundred percent and there's so
many little various facets of it that
we're just going to fail to even do
justice in discussion wise like I've got
to meet in the UK who always reminds me
that because I I frequently say on the
show you know they love cheese in the UK
he goes bro we don't grow cheese here
anymore we grow blue cheese it's like
cheese in seed form but better and and
so you'll see as you reference blue
cheese one of the most knocked off
recreated cheese um all the Femme seeds
out there in general you know every sort
of Spain feminized country uh company is
going to offer a blue cheese because
it's just synonymous so uh with skunk so
yeah it's it's like the more you look
into it the more you start to get to
Surprise by where you see it popping up
and and you've nailed them all you're
right right you're like okay that was a
big one so you know you name another one
like oh [ __ ] I forgot about that one too
I mean it's just it's it really has been
used I guess once again it's been it's
it's been a home run since since the 70s
I mean Kim 91 91 TK we're putting that
around the 90s as well so this has been
one of those older strains that
um you know and and also you gotta
approach to to the breeder and whatnot
but people back then weren't they didn't
have these giant facilities like exotic
or like
you know uh they'd be easy they don't
have they can't grow a thousand or five
thousand plants out and then pick that
one you know some of these guys were
using tents you know if they if they
grew more than 20 they were drawing some
heat for sure and for them to grow it
for seed production they could be
growing it for weed production and
getting paid that was you know even
something even crazier what do you mean
you're going to plant for seeds that's
nuts but if you wanted The Preserve it
if you wanted to use next year well then
you made them this year
that's what you know like I said that
from what it took them so yeah great
strain great addition and definitely uh
you know definitely has a place in in
that you know
fantastic well
congrats DJ Short killer strain love it
blueberry tubes definitely up there for
me it's one of the best
oh it's and yeah it's just it's just
it's just a really great strain and
it's it's in literally everything
alrighty so moving on to our next
category we have the most anticipated
seed drop of the year so in terms of the
most anticipated sea drop number of
candidates this year and I think one
that definitely sort of caught my eye
was it's sort of like a joint one it's
the the nl5 reproductions so there's
notably inspector and Matt riots nl5
reproduction that's been done by csir
inspector and then there was also the
Todd McCormick NL reproduction uh both
using seed stock that came from Greg so
I know there's been a bit of
anticipation around those ones so that
was definitely a contender in my mind
and for people who don't know who radios
bread is
[Music]
McAllister the guy I know of to be
created with the NL and the nl5 and the
the entire line of an else and when he
was when he first came to me uh we spoke
and he told me he was responsible for
the NLS and the nl5 and
that's women here I said so you should
tell me that you you did this that I
mean I said most people are telling me
that they're using a cut of this and I
have to vet them that they're using the
cut you're telling me that you're
responsible for these uh oh sure you are
sure yeah let's smoke some more uh
because then I'm like how do I vet this
guy who who's going to ask us man I'm
done because everybody knows Adam that
he has no clue who Adam that is but if
we think about it he was doing [ __ ] in
the 70s he wouldn't know who Adam Dunn
is I'm done didn't come around until the
90s this guy was doing [ __ ] like in 72
when he came back from the war
and so who do you vet him through who
you got this pretty he'll do tell him he
made the ship but the guy who made this
[ __ ] is probably going to be this crazy
old dude so I'm thinking I'm thinking
thinking operation green Merchant we'll
see though [ __ ] farmer in this guy
guy who used to write Cincinnati tips
and so uh call Wolf you guys involved
this guy tells me he can spend anything
else he's like oh Greg I said that's his
name he's like yep yeah that's who did
it uh I I was right with him and he did
that in 72 when I was around the island
there and I was like really I said well
he's contacted me he's like oh yeah I
told him to I was like oh [ __ ] well he
has and so yeah so that's so that's
great so sorry so I guess Greg from the
phone I wasn't aware of it until after
it happened but I guess that Greg gave
Riot and those guys some seeds is that
what you're telling me yeah I believe so
yeah I was I wasn't familiar I wasn't
aware that he had given them uh since
I'd heard that he had possibly had but
um so David so how does it become an
inspector in Riot thing
I think I mean I I think that he so he
definitely gave some to Todd because you
know their mates and they chat and I
believe that likewise he's friends with
Matt and he gave Matt some of the seeds
and I think Matt passed them on to uh
Caleb CSI because uh you know inspectors
so well known for his ability to
reproduce old strains that uh yeah it
just ended up becoming the two of them
doing it
[Music]
when his stock comes in and flies out
he's a great dude
um so so yeah so no definitely
anticipate because who doesn't love the
NLS I mean those were you know and I
guess the story behind him you know
because that's the first thing Donald
asked him was why why the numbers he
said only he named him one through
eleven based on size you know the one
was the shortest one the eleven was the
tallest one the five would be in the
middle would you think about if you're
breeding and you're using that stuff the
one in the middle is probably going to
be the one that gets used the most
yeah interesting stuff well you know a
hot Contender for the the winner but I
think that to be honest the winner for
me and for a lot of people who I've been
talking to is it's a bit of a uh a
washout a blowout to be honest because I
haven't seen the amount of momentum this
drop got for a very long time and so I'm
very happy to say that the winner of the
most anticipated sea drop award for the
2021-22 period Goes To None other than
crickets and cicada with their puck back
cross one line up absolutely destroying
it including the bx2 as well as a
variety of other crosses to things like
Scentsy star hash plant 13 which was
actually I'm gonna do a mad plug here uh
Mr Bob and Hannah ball just so
incredibly generous donated 30 packs of
their seeds to our patreon just just to
give to our patreon supporters because
they're like we love the show we want to
support the listeners so we gave out 30
packs to our listeners of their
unreleased hash plant 13 across to the
back cross one male they did hash Planet
13 being an incredibly rare clone Top
Dog and uh both Mr Bob talked very
highly of it but you know this drop in
general had some bangers in it including
the uh the rare red red Lebanese hash
plant crossed to the park the Scentsy
Star Killer and uh if you've been
following Mr Bob's Instagram he's been
posting up some absolute bangers with uh
this Northern Lights female he's been
using so I believe there might be a part
two to this drop coming featuring some
additional strains or at least I'm
secretly wishing they'll be
but uh they've just crushed it all
around
so I completely slept on this one uh
when when my guy Rob was doing the
ordering
um it it was you know uh
the [ __ ] back prices
uh Skelly has plant crossed with nl1
and those strands are out there right
like it's not it's not that trendy it's
not nothing hype [ __ ] it's not you know
it's
[Music]
but man I smoke some I I'm not with him
he gave me some that [ __ ] is good it is
heavy it looks amazing it is it's it's
it's
nugular it's the kind that makes that
that don't sound like you're cutting in
Turkey trays don't you know
it's uh it's just uh and and I think he
had four or five different uh different
the crosses there when we've been smoked
with him and uh there were there wasn't
one that outshined the other they were
all just massively great it wasn't like
just some nugs were big they were called
awesome stuff oh good stuff and
everybody that smoking I smoke a fair
amount of weed uh it definitely knocked
my dick in the beard it's it's old I
mean it's two old strings right but it's
two old strands done damn well and from
the guy who would have the quality of
those old strains from the librarian so
um and then like I said I was blessed
enough to attempt to smoke some and
we'll definitely say uh it got me high
you got me
yes it is undoubtedly some killer killer
stuff so shout out to crickets and
cicada Mr Bob Hemphill and Hannah bolt
crushing it as always
onto our next award being hottest
breeder on the Block
this is a prize that historically just
to clear up any misconceptions
historically it doesn't go to someone
who's like in their first year of
breeding it's it's often people who have
been around for a while but have really
sort of started to get a bit of momentum
maybe even caused a bit of a splash with
a seed drop or two so this is for people
who are really you know starting to get
to the levels of where maybe we think
they should be because they're they're
often really good breeders maybe a
little under recognized but often some
exciting names in the mix I know that
last year I believe the winner was Soul
fire and heck we killed it with that
pick he's gone on to do that Bahama Mama
cross which just looks insane
then if you want [ __ ] that washes uh his
his stuff is insaneous Frost as hell uh
great stuff it's flies out we the mama
mama crosses were awesome
um it's just it's a nice plant uh it
puts in a lot of work a lot of hard work
and definitely well deserved and um it
definitely is is one of my top 12 for
sure a great great guy
yeah definitely and years prior to that
we've even had in years prior to that
we've even had none other than our
friend on the final frontier AK Bean
brain sweep this award so definitely
some big hitters in the prior winners of
this award and there was a few names
that sort of came to mind when I was
thinking about the newcomers of the year
I definitely want to give a shout out
Max yields the guy who created Oreos and
collab with Thug pug to make Pure
Michigan you can't deny we've all seen
those strains popping up here and there
they're doing pretty well so kudos to
you Max heels you've been doing some
good stuff however for me there's
there's another name I've got in mind
but I'd love to hear did you have any
honorable mentions Mr Bean
you know of course all my guys everybody
they picked up in the last year I think
is enough of a newcomer I'll try to
check them out and I can't if I mention
one I'm gonna have to mention 10 of them
so I can't I can do one in particular uh
there's like your favorite child right
um I will say the one the year picked
before that has done very well uh we've
always been well in our picks uh I think
you've got a good one that you're about
to about to name but uh yeah I would
just uh kind of I think I think the one
that we both have in common is the one
I've done yeah other than that I can't
pick more than one favorite child
that's the way it is yeah you'll end up
stealing the Thunder from me that's okay
that's all right
um well let's get on to it I think that
the the hottest new breeder on the Block
award goes to none other than Bloom
seeds Mr Harry Palms who has just done a
momentous job crushing it over the past
few years in fact but it's good to see
that he's starting to get some
recognition from the masses his work as
well has really surprised me in how
Frosty it is the consistently high
quality I've seen some mates grow it out
and they're all blown away they're I
even know one guy he's like disciple of
the Church of Bloom he won't touch
anything except Bloom so you've got to
be doing some right if you can get
people to have that level of passion for
your brand and you know he's got some um
some notable history behind himself
um having formally been a part of Oni
having been a part of the Trump picana
cookies creation this is a guy who's
been around for a while and has really
put in his due diligence and it's great
to see that bloom seeds is really
starting to take off with the masses and
seeing some cool strains come out of
their stable such as the grape cream
cake I've also seen that his garlic sour
cookies are sick I've also seen him do
some other cool stuff with uh what is it
purple full stack that looks dope as
well
purple ice water shines that thing's
gray sticky grapes
um you know the Batman bar the big back
big bad cushman's Cross of course we
live with the cream cake
like you said it's kind of really a lot
of prostitutes and unstable a lot of
frosted takes
yeah I think Bloom has got a reputation
for being like super terpy super resony
that's what I think when I think of
Bloom so yeah concentrate guys this is
the one for you for sure but again you
know great to see someone like Harry
who's been around for a while really
starting to get momentum two years in a
row now we're going towards you
concentrate guys
yeah look that that might be the trend
and that plays into the general sort of
uh macro politics and movement of the
scene you know we're seeing bigger
facilities and uh bigger facilities can
do have the capacity to do big volumes
of concentrates and as a result strains
that are concentrate orientated more
likely to get run there's also just a
growing uh
group of enthusiasts who are really into
the concentrates you know like I think I
think people are still growing you know
we definitely haven't reached our Peak
concentrate Enthusiast uh curve yet
before we start swinging back to flower
I think we're still on the up and up
well I think I think there because
there's a science behind it right
there's different ways to do it now and
we can all go in our backyards and blow
some blow some you know some some butane
and try to explode our house and get a
little a little yeah a concentrate but
to take that process and refine it and
make it such an intricate specialty deal
that it is today and and then by using
different because you know what to put
inwards and what you're going to get out
you know I've always said these
concentrate guys that make that make
this constraints were great because the
you know a Frenchie started with
aficionados gear right Cuban was using
the Exotics gear Cuban's great but he
had an exotic steer and so if you know
what you start with is what you can
pronounce so you know a lot I see bloom
in a lot of a lot of concentrates so
um that and the now that we have like
you were saying the ability to run five
thousands because if we rewind the clock
which I work with a lot of older
breeders these guys were growing in
their tents and they had 10 12 15 to
work with and and for them to have chose
what they chosen for us to give away is
excellent for that but now we're talking
facilities of five thousand and you can
really sort out that one that's
different I mean all these are plants
and they're all marijuana plants down
and they're all this planet like that
but there's that one that's just
different than all the others and that's
how I've heard it told when you go into
a room is that you'll just
it's just different and you're like well
what does that means
you just see it let me see it and so and
to have that ability to run those
numbers and then just get rid of the
others either if you're putting in the
flower on your shelf or whatever it may
be
um you know that's why these guys that
we've nominated to be best growers in
the year uh of the year in the past
um because they're working with the
giant phenol hunts because that's what
it comes down to if you want something
in their bill test then then you grab a
club if you want something that's yours
you can grab a pack of six
that's it that's it plant more seeds but
uh shout out to bloom you know doing
some good work as always for sure for
sure so on to our next category
we're gonna give a quick little detour
being that it's been you know I think
probably 16 months now since our last
episode unfortunately we have had a few
Veterans of the scene bid us farewell
and and so we bid farewell to a true
Pioneer of concentrate and notably the
hashish scene Frenchie cannoli who
unfortunately passed away early last
year
and Frenchie was a pivotal man in the
scene in really reigniting the fire
under the artisanal hash and concentrate
scene him and his wife held numerous
workshops were affiliated with various
Crews such as Aficionado as well as many
others who really tried to push the
limits and to raise greater awareness in
the consumer's mind around not just the
quality of artisanally produced products
but also to pay homage and respect the
traditional practices that have produced
them over the years and the way in which
the application of these sort of
indigenous knowledges can be tailored to
each product to really bring its merits
and qualities to the Forefront
so it is with a heavy heart that we say
valet Frenchy canoli
yeah Frenchie um I was lucky enough to
uh work with them to have dinner with
him do known him through mening to and
come to parties with them
um he he was he was the one gentleman
when he started talking everybody shut
up
because for one he talked really
quietly and Purdue of course his name
implies zebra's friendship and so
you looked up you know and you do this
and you do this and you do this and
everybody would just shut up I mean he
was like entire restaurant should be
quiet whenever he talked because you you
want to hear what he said you want to
get that information out of him and and
so it was I mean I've seen him quiet
many of the crowds just practice by
talking and so that's uh not only is
that is that just kind of a gentleman
that commanded the space around him and
humbly so like was was not of that I'm
the coolest person was just you know
happy to be where I was and uh so I
remember he he lost a one gram triple
ball and a party I had before a High
Times event we had a free party and uh
the rumor is he left the one one gram
Temple ball somewhere in the house left
we never found it so that's a fun story
but um you know he he I I knew him
through his work with Aficionado with uh
Evan Bruce with Leo and
uh the awards they won and perhaps they
won
um dinners we'd have after August and
stuff so you know I was very uh lost a
good one and they all go to her early
you know we all wish we had more time
the French is definitely one of the ones
that she shouldn't you know his last
artification workshops
a lot of people attended them
um I think that maybe that's where your
legacy lives is in teaching people
knowledge
and people remember like bog like people
that we've had in the past you know sub
from different videos several always go
down because how many people I can't
tell you I can tell you how many people
tell me that they watched Subs read nerd
videos like and whether it's submute or
Not by him doing those videos he created
a cult that people were able to watch
when when YouTube was cool and so
passive knowledge John Wayne I think the
three guys we've had in the Hall of Fame
are the four guys that have all been our
uh oh sorry I guess the you know the
three guys that we've lost recently
um bog sub and Frenchie were one thing
they all had in common is they were all
great teachers they took their knowledge
and shared it with people
so you know I'm sure we've lost others
but maybe maybe that's what we take from
this is that it's cool to know
everything but to take that knowledge
and share with other people that's what
makes you remembered
yeah definitely a very altruistic and
selfless sort of act to be a teacher and
as you said one that will certainly
leave you in high regards and in warm
favor with people
so moving on to our final Award of the
year the breeder of the year the big one
the Big Bopper
this year there's there's a number of
people who are in contention and I think
that it's important to note that this
award goes to people for a variety of
fact as it goes for you know like how
popular they are uh how good the work is
not just like you know otherwise uh
bloody Candy Rain would have won that
year right it's not just about like how
interested people are it's also about
how good the work is and does it
germinate
um it's also about a variety of like
logistical and technical things you know
is this unique stock uh so it's it's a
very multi-faceted sort of award and so
I think that some of the people who will
get the sort of honorable shout outs or
the top mentions in my books we'll go to
Chris of compound genetics I wanted to
give an honorable mention to him he's
done some cool work with the apples and
bananas as well as some of his other
crosses he's done I think that we've
seen a lot of derivative work from other
people people and that's not to say I'm
not interested in it but it certainly
has amassed a wide following and has
even had other people sort of doing
similar crosses utilizing those cuts
when they've got access to them likewise
I think that given that Chris of
compound has worked with cookies you
know you can't can't argue that's going
to help with the old reputation
yeah uh definitely compounds uh the
apples and banana is has been it's
definitely been released so that it was
in a lot of gear surprisingly I
certainly used a lot a lot of reading
projects yet it would release it you
know Chris of course had a great Booth
you know an emerald cap on as part of
his nft he was one of the first beers I
knew that was actually pushing nfts I
got an ft to his pre-party
[Music]
good good stuff and he's been doing you
know good stuff in the past as well and
um
you know definitely uh uh a bit almost
first a bit almost first
yeah he he's very much up there he's
been doing some huge waves and I think
this year is the year that he really did
come to the Forefront in terms of being
a really close front runner
um just to give some other sort of
honorable shout outs
um Soul fire you know we dropped it
before he crushed it with the Bahama
Mama line this year honorable shout out
to Exotic Mike the Scotty 2 hottie has
caused a lot of momentum I know that
James Bean will be happy that I've
mentioned that because he is a big
exotic mic fan also shout out strong on
his page right now
yeah just Crush you he just pressures it
just good stuff likewise a shout out to
Mr skunk VA who's I think probably added
maybe even six to eight lines to his
repertoire using some interesting
females crossed to the old favorite Kim
and I think I read it I think I read a
comment on his page earlier someone
asked you know like what are you sort of
looking to do with your chem lines and
he left a great answer which said you
know I want to impart all the best
qualities of the cam without dominating
the mother still letting the mother
shine through a bit so uh yeah some
really nice crosses coming out from the
lucky dog camp but I wanted to give a
second really close second like tied
tied second sort of shout out to mean
Jin who's had an absolutely killer year
he's brought out some cool new lines in
collaboration with other people he's
bought out some outdoor specific lines
which is really cool to see breeders
really honing in on their craft it's got
some cool stickers that sort of indicate
like hey you know do what you want with
this is but I think they're best suited
outdoors and he's also released some
interesting genetics that are not
related to some of the other work he's
done so really injecting some fresh
blood into his stable and notably I'm
excited for some of the Pink Champagne
S1 hybrids he's done he found a nice
seed in some Pink Champagne a strain
that's near and dear to my heart I love
it also goes by the name the Phantom and
uh yeah beautiful stuff check out me and
Jean he's done some cool work shout out
I know I mean Gene from his uh from his
dad is working with Aficionado and
um just you know I I used to explain
them as as I think that guy pops a five
gallon bucket of seeds every year like I
really really do because once again
we've gone back to funeral hunting we're
going back to finding that that
different thing and Gene's a great guy
I've worked in a lot of fundraising
things
um his he has he has a home run with
root beer I mean the marketing behind it
uh the it's just it's a great strain but
it's so great and he's done such good
things with it that he can that he can't
sell it now right because he's done such
good things that he's done he's donated
so much and so you know that's a guy
who's unselfishly taken a home run and
and donating it back to the community if
you will
um he's always on different panels and
that's a he's definitely a Breeder's
breeder like if uh
the guy that works gear and is going to
find something different and uh uh you
know that's it's different than Gene I'm
definitely a big fan of his for sure
hell yeah
so
without further delay
the breeder of the year for the
2021-2022 period Goes To None other than
crickets and cicada Mr Bob hemp here and
Hannah Balch absolutely hitting it out
of the park you know they they started
off the year strong releasing some
unique hybrids like the light of Venus
which was a cool purple Urkel uh cross
with a bit of Kabul Kush in the mix some
really cool elements going on there
sticking to their tried and tested
recipe of using some cool old school old
worldly genetics mixed with some old
Staples and more recently they've done
the puck back cross one drop which sold
like hot fires across absolutely every
seed bank it was sold out within you
know 15 minutes across the board often
even less time than that and some
beautiful looking flower coming up on
their Instagram that are the results of
them growing it out I cannot tell you
how many people messaged me and said I
caught up with Mr Bob at one of the
organic seminars he tried he gave me
some of their bud and it was the most
memorable weed I've tried in a very long
time
yeah uh
I I really enjoy their work um he's he
was and people who don't know can go
back and listen to a couple of your uh
other podcast interviews that you've had
with him you know where he goes into his
history with Coastal seeds
um I was lucky enough to met with him uh
earlier this year uh in March uh he gave
me uh selections of of the uh of the
current Prospect because of that
Crossing
um you know he he's a librarian for sure
and and you mentioned anabot which is
his wife
um and she does a lot of the work you
know I asked to ask Duke I was like what
what should I get him he was like
Sharpies
sounds like Sharpies what do you mean
well a guy that does Cuts in those
clones and has a library might need
Sharpies because he writes and writes on
Solo cups right it's only like Sharpies
and of course and you know he's known as
Librarians he's got you know almost 100
different females or whatnot plan to use
just keeping and uh because he doesn't
want to lose them to the to the to the
period of time you know and then we
everybody has him and he's he has he has
things he doesn't even like he's keeping
just because he doesn't want them lost
and to keep a library like that
and he's not a job facility and sort of
keep a library like that you know I'm
not wasted in a room but not earning it
to keep in a room is is a benefit for
anybody that needs to use it and one of
the coolest things that
uh that that I really noticed when I met
with him this last time is that he
stressed to me he wanted people to use
his product
like he wanted people to breathe his
gear and I was like wait a minute
a lot of people don't want that they
don't want to he's like no no I'm I'm
preservationist like like the pressure
Pakistan you spoke of that was an open
pollination that he did because he wants
to reserve that line he wants to make it
that available so you're not losing it
doesn't get tainted and so and he wants
you and his his starting stock for new
breeders or new guys coming in the scene
that want starting stock to breed with I
think you you couldn't go wrong with
with anything from his lines I mean it's
just it's older stock and older crosses
but they're done right from the guy who
should have them I mean no question
um
so much so that I know that earlier we
discussed uh
save this before here uh earlier we
discussed the NL Series right uh I
didn't know that Greg had sent Pax 2.
McCormick and uh Ryan
I also you know Greg obviously I also
got a pack of seeds about that same time
which gray got married because I didn't
think because Greg I told you I didn't
know they were kind of acting like an
old schooler so I didn't know that they
were I wasn't there I didn't get them
but thank you now I know what they are I
found a
since I found them of course I want to
grow them because
if they went there say they are then
well I would want them but the person
that needs to have them would be to me
this guy
would be [ __ ] Mr Bob heffield so I
gave him the packs that were given to me
by Greg McAllister so he has now the
same packs that uh Riot and McCormick
got so we'll see what he does with that
little empty ones but I figured you know
you know the crucial to who should have
these than a librarian I won't I will
you know he he knows so much about
playing she's a talk to him he can tell
you the difference what what this shows
and what that shows and what the
Lebanese shows and what that shows and
he's just he's really he's not the most
excited uh Amplified guy but it doesn't
really get excited over much things but
but man his weed just [ __ ] gets me
high I tell you what good stuff uh yeah
and there's teamwork on that one for two
like I said you're keeping around 100
mothers right we're not talking about
how to plant your mother's that's you're
not painting anything to keep those
around
so sorry shout out to him and uh
excellent choice excellent choice
yeah definitely a huge shout out and
that's really exciting to hear that
you've been able to get the seeds into
the librarian's hands hopefully we'll
see some really special work come out of
that and uh yeah just Echo the sentiment
you know so awesome to have uh Mr Bob
Hemphill and Hannah bolt take it they've
really been Staples in the scenes for
years dating back to their work with
Coastal and before that even and uh now
really getting that recognition for all
the hard work they've been putting in
over the years preserving and creating
some fantastic strains
[Applause]
alrighty friends we're back at it here
with the winner of the 2021 2022 breeder
of the Year Awards Mr Bob Hemphill and
Hannah bolt of crickets and cicada
congratulations and thank you so much
for joining us
thank you it's an honor it's uh
very much appreciated
look I feel like I would not be the
first to say that this has like been a
long time coming I think there's a lot
of heads in the scene who know that you
guys have been putting in a lot of work
over the years and like myself are
really really grateful to see the The
Wider Community really embracing it it's
it's killer to see did you ever expect
that you would get this sort of
reception to the puck crosses
I had no idea that um there would be
this many people interested in the
project and honestly I had uh
you know no expectations of it turning
out as well as it did it's just a you
know amazing thing
yeah look it it really caught me by
surprise because of the fact that you
know the scaly hash plant it's been
around for a while and I think there
have been a small number of crosses done
with it but I'm not sure if the demand
for those crosses really reflected what
you got here I guess you're the best
person to ask do you think I mean I know
that puck yeah was quite popular but do
you think that other Puck crosses really
sort of gave you any idea of how this
was going to go
you know I I think people really got
excited about the fact that it's really
inbred uh good breeding stock and you
know to get something that uh
is you know inbred and and bread to be
potent um
just appealed to people
yeah hugely hugely I also have been
thinking that I think it's sort of a bit
unfortunate but I think since Neville's
past people have sort of re-examined a
lot of the older work with like a
microscope and a like hey this is
actually like really good stuff and
there's like a more General sort of
awareness would you say that you've seen
any of that at all I guess I'll also
just quickly add in like in relation to
Park Shore but I've also seen people you
know quite keen on the NLS and the nl5s
and stuff do you think people are more
keen on the older work at the moment
you know it that always happens with an
artist when they pass people appreciate
their work
um but to be honest you know he's been
an inspiration to me since the 90s and
um
always looked at him as the greatest
cannabis breeder of all time and um
you know since the 90s I've been trying
to collect as many clones from him as
possible and you know there's not many
of them left but any of them that stayed
around this long or truly as good as any
new hype strain there is
so
um you know the the puck project is just
continuing his work um I didn't add
anything else in there that he didn't
add and
um you know I just kept getting better
with the end breeding so
um you know taking out their his style
of breeding
um really paid off
oh yeah I can only imagine we're gonna
see some people sort of uh recreate the
breeding steps you've taken to do this
but maybe with some other clones I'd be
interested to hear are there any other
old school lines that you're sort of
keen to work with now that you've seen
with you know the Skelly that this is
like a viable sort of commercial path
where people are keen on this sort of
work anything new on the horizon
well you know um the goal is to get a
bunch of old clones in the seed form I'm
working on the Master Kush project right
now
um pollen is flying right now to make
that back cross one
off the Clone I've been holding for 20
years and um
then uh purple into Kush working that
one and uh
there's a whole bunch more but those are
uh some of the ones that that and
sensory store the Scentsy Stars Luna I
have I also have that at vx1
right now
oh wow what Mao did you use for the
initial cross on the senses
The Brood X oh God what a good pairing
yeah
um I also made some f2s off a few select
brood X females and um really excited
about you know digging into the f2s and
you know the back cross
I'm gonna take that and um
make a bx2 and that's where I'll
hopefully make it available if it passes
testing and I'll take the bx1 and
cross it to the census star cut
um Wick gave me and a bunch of other
good clones too a bunch of old school
stock
yeah that sounds killer and I mean you
just mentioned Wick I I have to be
honest he's been posting some cool stuff
any chance we might ever see you guys
collaborating together or do you sort of
feel like it's already happening because
you guys share a lot of cuts
you know it definitely is already
happening and um he has
you know and Mother collection he's been
holding as long as I've been holding
mine and he's been putting in work and
um
he really you know loves the plan he's
one of the people that does it for the
right reasons so um
you know if you're really into crazy
sativas that's a really good place to
look right there he's
um making some really cool things right
now
hell yeah but you know what this
interview is about you and I think
you've been making some really cool
things right now so let's talk about it
I seen you posted the uh the Tom Hill
Hayes cross and pollination you did tell
me a little bit more about that
well the Tom Health Chase I made um an
open pollination years ago with the
um original Three original packs from
him and then um when I did that open
pollination I stuck in some old timers
days female so I made Tom Hill's f2s and
then f1s of the Old Timers and the Tom
Hill's Haze I just got into refreshing
my seed stock and I made f3s of the Tom
Hills Haze that's positronics F4
really excited I'm gonna let a few of
those out just so the line stays alive
there's not many people that have kept
that line alive and um
also right now I'm working on making f2s
of the Old Timers by the Tom Hills Hayes
and I also um
have some Tom hails Hayes crossed to
original Haze in there too also some
pure original Haze to you know hopefully
add what um genetic diversity is left
into the pure Haze population and um you
know honestly I'm just gonna treat this
Haze like open pollination land race
work and I'm gonna put it out there and
I'm gonna help hope that some breeders
are gonna take it and work it Forward
um
because it really needs to be looked
through at large populations at that
point and selecting the best for making
f2s and outcrosses I think it'll be some
amazing breeding stock
yeah certainly I know that there's been
um some other Haze releases and some
people have enjoyed them some people
have sort of said oh not quite what they
wanted so maybe this will be more of a
successful route for them just as a
quick follow-up did you notice much uh
discrepancies between the like you know
the positronics haze and uh the
old-timers Haze or were they fairly
similar
no um you know I've done as much
research as I can about the old timers
and it's really you know who knows what
it is
um it's very similar to Hayes it might
be a haze outcross or some of the same
Colombians that made Hayes
um it was slightly different than the
Tom Hill's positronics phase when I grew
them out together
there's you know more sativa I would say
that that that old-timer one Hayes is
more sativa um
Tom Hill's Hayes is very sativa in
itself
um I think condos is the best out of
what I've seen from
um samples of original Haze and what I
saw of old timer one Hayes and um I
think Tom health is the best
wow that's really exciting and I guess
one of the first thoughts that jumped to
mind to people who follow you on
Instagram where are we ever gonna see
you recreate like an nl5 Haze
you know I put um the nl2 cut from Jim
Ortega in with the Tom Hills Crews open
pollination and I also put in uh nl1 cut
from AK Bean Brands and
so I do have seeds of those and so yeah
we're going to get some of those tested
and um we'll see how nice they turn out
fingers are crust
yeah out of curiosity I mean I like I
don't have a ton of experience with the
nl2 for example but would you just if
you had to use your imagination expect
that those seeds would come out similar
to the nl5 haze but maybe like a bit
less sort of stretchy or what do you
imagine they'll come out like
man if they come out anything as good as
uh what Neville did with that nl5 case
you know I'll be extremely happy I think
that's one of the best readings in
history the nl5 phase you look at how
many clones of nl5 haze are still around
in their pure form and they're just
extremely potent and then uh you look
what JJ did from Top Dog he took that NL
Haze and made the Nigerian has so you
know it's amazing breeding stock and you
know the cuts up stood the time as good
as anything ever created in history
yeah definitely some Mammoth stock for
sure so a lot of people had messaged me
and asked it looks like there might be a
part two of the puck drop happening
because you've been posting some sort of
newer crosses that weren't in the first
part is that what the fans can expect or
is that more just some personal r d
no 100 I'm gonna um bring more of the
puck the puck bx3
um I'm gonna bring that to the public
after testing fingers crossed and then
I'm hitting a bunch of clones and um the
same ones that really clicked well and
then a bunch of other ones that I think
will click well you know like 398 Bubba
the Scentsy star from WIC Shoreline
you know some really I think stuff that
I have a high hopes for old skunk one
clone that also came from Wick
yeah wow I remember I grew out of
Shoreline S1 like 10 years ago when I
first started growing I think it came
from uh Devil's hardest Devil's Harvest
crew and I think they're legit even
though maybe a checkered past but I
remember that was a very unique plan
even in my very newbiness at growing I
could tell it smelled totally unlike
anything else is that what the
shoreline's like as the original clone
or did I just get lucky with that S1
man it
it reminds me of that old school 90s
smell you know like that really good
stuff and most everything in the 90s was
uh from Neville you know
I just assume it's some NL skunk type
I've heard rumors of it being skunk and
then NL skunk so um it's looking like
it's got some NL in there
so you know and I'll skunk by the puck
should I got my fingers crossed that
should be really good
hell yeah hell yeah I'm Keen for that
one
uh another question I'd had a lot of
people interested in was I think we
might have touched on it briefly in the
past but just to cover it again because
people seem to be very interested do you
have much of a backstory on The Nepalese
hash plant you use in the puck crosses I
think people see the photos of that and
they're really blown away and they're
like wow what is this Nepalese hash
plant
man that thing is really really unique
um Kevin Jordan's sourced it out of uh
Grass Valley and he's you know brought
it over to Humboldt you know with
Wonderland nursery and shared it out to
a bunch of people and um
it's just amazing old school stock you
know and when you cross it to something
like the puck you get you know
Throwbacks that are old school [ __ ] that
you're not really going to see anywhere
that breeding just clicked most of the
puck crosses uh produced really huge
buds but
the way those uh Napoli's were just
covered in calyxes and uh just like next
level
so that one's definitely gonna meet the
BX too
yeah wow and just to clarify I think I
already know the answer but again a lot
of fans are interested it's not the uh
The Nepalese variety that uh Bodhi used
in Goji OG is it no there was a rumor
recently going around that uh you know
people not Bodhi but people other people
just assuming it was and um I showed
Bodhi samples of it like five years ago
now when I first got the cut and he was
like wow that's an amazing bug but
that's not the Nepalese that he used
yeah I think like when I spoke to him at
his house one day I think he said that
he suspected what he used was like
misnamed that it was actually like an OG
or something but it just got called that
but there you go now we know well it's
not the same cut you know who knows what
you use so
interesting stuff nonetheless so uh just
to our final question or two before I
let you get back to it a lot of fans
very keen to hear probably Mr James been
also very keen to hear any chance we'll
ever see any feminized work coming out
of crickets and cicada
only if one of my really close old
school friends wants to do the work you
know there has been Talk Amongst a few
of them that they would do the work
you know obviously people would love to
see the red Lebanese and Cuts Like That
feminized and released in their pure
form and um
if I had somebody really you know old
school trustworthy friend that you know
needed a something to do that might
happen but it's never going to be what
I'm going to be doing I'm going to be
focused on getting them in the
pure seed form
um regulars you know I think
you know if the people want it or not
that's just where my heart is and you
know that's where uh I feel good about
what I'm doing and especially since I'm
trying to get these old clones in the
seed form is you know close as possible
um choosing the males to the original
clone try to preserve the qualities as
much as possible I feel like that's
where I should be going and you know
with the people's interest in the puck
that only reinforces that so that's you
know where I'm going to be going
yeah 100 that's that's awesome to hear I
I wish I lived closer so that I could do
that Femme project for you but even if
it doesn't happen we're uh we're
incredibly blessed to have access to
your work in general I think that's just
about everything I wanted to ask for a
little segment here were there any
comments or shout outs you wanted to
make
you know Hannibal is I could never be
doing this without her she's uh you know
a rock and um I just want to thank her
she doesn't like getting on and doing
these interviews but uh it's much much
appreciated from her too made her really
happy so thank you guys yeah 100 as as
someone who's seen the uh the inner
workings of crickets and cicada I can
definitely vouch that Hannah boat does a
lot of work has the eye helps out so I
always try to make sure we give props to
her as well she's fundamental in it all
and I also just wanted to give you guys
another shout out props for the award
you know a killer year so far not just
the puck back cross even The Brood X
which it's crazy because I guess it's
sort of maybe for some people feels like
it got a little overshadowed by the puck
releases but that in its own right was
like Contender for really up there with
strains of the Year sort of thing so I
think that's why collectively it was
obvious that you guys were the choice
for breeder of the year and I also just
had a lot of patreon members who are
like you know the hardcore listeners
message me and just say you know like
they feel really good that you guys want
it you got the right Vibe and a lot of
people really relate to how you've got
this organic approach and just people in
general just uh expressing that they're
just really stoked to hear that you guys
got it and that they felt you've
deserved it a long time coming well you
know I couldn't be more shocked and more
happy and it's greatly appreciated and
thank you very much
foreign
y I think that just about brings us to
the end of it for the past 15 16 months
any comments any notable shout outs you
want to give for people who maybe didn't
make the list but uh near and dear to
your heart and let me save you the
effort I know everyone you stock is
phenomenal they're all your children
you're a loving Papa you've got you've
got a shout out for all of them
and go through the list and they're like
I represent all these guys because
because if I don't I'll feel bad so
um it really is because it also comes
down to if
they're all individual they're all
unique that's the fun thing about Siege
if they were all doing the same thing I
wouldn't need 60 of them I wouldn't want
60 of them I just steal a couple of them
right because it's like sometimes we
need to deal with them I have to tell
them people are dealing with you know we
deal with Stoners on the phone right I
deal with super Stoners when I talk with
breeders those are guys who are trying
to get higher and so uh so sometimes you
know you get the uh the bumps in the
road that come with the deal with
superstars but um but they're all but
they all do different things and so you
know when I pick up a breeder I pick
them up for a reason and for what he's
doing what he's working with and so free
to pick one over the others it depends
on what you're looking for right each
breeders can do something different for
you
um if if you if you're growing uh you
know High Frosty THC stuff I might tell
you get it back to snow height go with
some land race go some crazy Off the
Wall stuff that you haven't grown before
um that you might see different things
you'll see some original characteristics
of what they used to be before they were
so heavily worked you know if you're if
you're big into you you know exotic
genetics I might tell you it go go try a
pack of 420 faster you know fast buds
Tracy monoflowers why why not you got
two pots in the plant try them and say I
always talk [ __ ] about them well other
plants have revolved check out how
autoflowers are involved give them a
shot it doesn't cost you anything one
plant gives you keeps you excited to go
out to the girl I know when I was
growing my my whole room was the same
thing I can't get bored because I saw
the same thing that I'd grown for the
fifth time and so if I kept like one or
two plants at the front there might see
different things it would give you
motivated to go out to the garage and
you definitely want to keep your your 90
of your canopy paying the bills but do
the five to ten percent you can play you
know scouting and looking and going
something that's exciting so what do you
guys say uh I got I got lots of stuff
over 60 breeders on the website check
them all out they're all great shout out
to all of them uh definitely a big shout
out to uh you know second place
[Music]
definitely a big shout out to crickets
and students
[Music]
once again you know I'm not a new guy
not a flashing the pan not someone who's
been here you know the last five years
this guy's been put in the work has the
genetics to show it and uh you know I
finally picked out one of the strains I
wouldn't want you to put me on one
because they're all they're all just
phenomenal like there's there's not
depends what you're looking for so
really good stuff
thanks for having me on again I
appreciate it everybody uh of course I
am James bean c2now.com and seeds here
now sh and auctions which if you don't
have an auction site give myself a
little plug uh we auction off stuff for
my Vault and over the past 12 years I've
been working with breeders and I always
keep two of every pack
we keep uh say I get 10 packs in and I
keep two of them as my own as is my own
stock I buy those two put those involved
you know that way if there's any
situation down the road you're gonna
have to replace the pack I've got that
pack and I can fix it for you to make it
right
um well over the years those packs that
never had any situations with them ended
up staying in the vault so they're kind
of trying through packs and those packs
I'm not growing I because I run a cement
I can't I shouldn't go in my garage like
I used to so uh those we auction those
packs off and uh there's all kinds of
good stuff in there it's everything I've
had over the past 12 years that's coming
up so it's kind of it's kind of cool
just to look at it as a library of the
packs that used to be right and they're
my packs and so they've been in a bank
storage Vault like in an actual bank
that has an actual security guard uh all
kinds of fun stuff and then our portion
of all those uh options go to uh the
breeder Relief Fund which we've you know
had in the past we raised to have helped
through community help raise money in
the past now it'd be really fun so if
something happens we've got some money
to help somebody sometimes so a little
Shameless plug of course the website's
future now.com breeders satisfaction
guarantee they have a situation with my
product let me know I'll make it right
with you I'll tell you to send your
seeds to tell me to stop
that's all I got thanks once again I
appreciate it appreciate the uh the
podcast you know a lot a lot of history
every time every time we lose a Facebook
page or an Instagram page you know we
lose that page but we also lose that
history we also lose those photographs
that that proof that those things
happened and as we lose and we get
censored by YouTubes and they take down
our our videos for violating censorship
here and there we lose those stories
that happened and so we need shows like
this that keep that [ __ ] straight so
we're gonna go back and look at what
happened and who did what we have those
available through us and say hey this
you know yes now you can vote on the
corner store and buy that pack of joints
but it wasn't always like that and this
is
I try I appreciate you doing the podcast
and keeping it up for everybody and the
church labor love it's got to be a thing
to do every you know I gotta go do
another one but we do appreciate it and
keeping history spread
likewise we appreciate having you as a
sponsor and you know it's a labor of
love but there you go friends so to do a
quick rundown again of the winners for
this year congratulations to everyone we
have the breeder of the Year crickets
and cicada Mr Bob Hemphill and Hannah
bolt we have the strain of the shout out
to lump status with his apple fritter
newcomer of the year the one and only
Harry Palms of Bloom seeds the most
anticipated sea drop goes to again
crickets and cicada with their puck back
cross one we've got our Hall of Fame
being blueberry The One and Only from DJ
Short likewise we've got farewells to
our friends uh Frenchie cannoli Pioneer
of the hash and concentrate scene thank
you so much for everything you've done
I think that's just about it for the
breeder awards for this past 15 16
months hopefully we do the next one a
little more quicker
the Sabrina awards for the year we'll
catch you for the next one cue the birds
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign
questions
[Music]
foreign