foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
podcast for budding enthusiasts
as always you're joined by your boy
heavy days here from the upside down
Library we couldn't make episodes happen
without the amazing support of our
sponsors a huge shout out to seeds here
now number one seed bank in the industry
guarantee on satisfaction not just
germination with all the hottest
breeders the latest drops and some of
the best prices in the industry go check
out CT now guys you will not be
disappointed likewise you need your room
to be dialed in if you want to get some
killer crops check out our buddies at
Pulse sensors who help you keep all of
your parameters in check even the ones
you may not be aware are creeping out
including VPD temperature humidity ha so
much more they've got everything you
need to keep your room dialed in if
you're ready to get serious get a pulse
sensor guys
and finally to make sure your crop is
perfect you need to check out our
buddies at cope at biological systems
these guys have everything in terms of
the latest predator and predation
technology from the apipar M which will
keep efforts out of your garden your
plants happy and healthy to the spider
which literally changes colors in front
of your eyes proof of predation
technology get on top of it guys cope at
biological systems we love you thank you
so much for helping keep our Gardens
clean and for supporting the show
as always a big shout out to the patreon
gang you guys are the lifeblood of the
show helping ensure future episodes
happen if you'd like to get early access
to upcoming episodes unreleased
exclusive interviews genetic giveaways
every month from some of the latest and
greatest breeders as well as Discord
chats so much more check out the patreon
www.patreon.com the podcast we
appreciate you guys
[Music]
so my friends on this episode we're
joined by Jake and Marco from no till
Kings here to chat all things no-till
cultivation
how the company has grown and a little
bit about some of their cultivars
this is a quick one today I'm very
grateful for the boys dropping by
[Music]
Unfortunately they had a bit of
emergency mid episode
you have to cut it short but I'm sure
they'll be back for another one
so without further ado
let's get into it
alrighty gang here we are again for
another one and today on this episode we
have the Legends behind the no-till
Kings the organic Fanatics and the humus
beings themselves Jake and Marco from
no-till Kings thanks so much for joining
us
thank you thanks so much for having us
on
oh man it's uh it's great to have you on
as a as a die-hard organic fanatic
myself it's uh gonna be a very
knowledgeable episode I think so to
start things off what are you guys
smoking on today yeah the new way Widow
that we're dropping that one's fire I've
been rolling up a lot of gelato 41.
I like the gelato 41 that's uh super gas
and uh we had a batch like a month and a
half two months ago of some sfv times
animal mints I've been smoking on that
Jake likes the gas I like more like the
fruits and the Citrus our Mimosa our
Jack our White Widow those are all just
those are my favorite
I love that the two different ends of
the spectrum I'm gonna have to say I'm
with you Marco I'm I'm more of a fruity
sort of guy myself and I caught up a lot
of flack from the gas heads for that
for sure yeah Jake's all about the gas
the cookies and stuff I love gas too but
yeah I mean just the the Terps on on
some of those fruitier strains are just
I love it yeah yeah let's let's delve
into that a little more but first
quickly I just want to ask you Jake
given you like the sfv animal means
what's your favorite OG cut
oh
tough and like
it's tough I mean I would say like what
Josh D is growing like the ojika story
like the Josh D cut
uh uh that's one of the top OG's out
there for sure
um
I mean quite a few years ago like what
kushco was growing the cushco cut a lot
of the OG Cuts floating around La are
similar
um are like similar OG Cuts but yeah
definitely uh I would say like like the
Josh D cut probably one of the best I
haven't I haven't had some in a while
but that's definitely one of the best
OG's uh out there for sure
nice nice and do you guys run any pure
OG out of curiosity
we don't have a uh we don't have like a
pure OG we have the sfv animal mint
cross which is definitely a sfv dominant
um but yeah we're looking we're looking
for like that original cut and uh maybe
it'll make its way over to us one day
lovely lovely and in amongst those
initial strains we mentioned um you guys
mentioned the White Widow we got a lot
of fans messaging us uh uh requesting
that we ask you about it because as you
guys would be aware you know it's a
blast from the past people are super
interested in it tell me a bit of the
back story you know where the seeds come
from where the inspiration to Fino hunt
this classic come from
yeah it's um we don't actually even
really remember what of where we got the
seeds it's been so long
um but we've I we've been trying to find
about white widows since we started
growing that and Northern Lights and um
you know you just you pop seeds you can
pop hundreds of seeds and none of them
are winners we've done a lot of northern
lights in the past and we haven't been
able to put any out
um just because they haven't you know
been you know the blood structure hasn't
been good or they haven't smoked as good
or that the smell just isn't quite there
so we're really stoked to have a white
widow come to Market that you know it
kind of hits everything the blood
structure the Terps the look
um it's it's just very pungent we're
super excited about it a lot of um I
think people want to
put their stamp on new brains and cross
things and and eventually we want to do
that too but there's just some sort of
nostalgia that you know these old school
strains have I think for a lot of people
um you know growing up smoking these
strains uh they were so potent back then
um and and there's definitely a need and
want for these old school strains to
kind of surface to the recreational
Market again
um so that's just kind of what we're
focusing on and yeah we're super excited
to have the white widow White Widow come
back so we we know hunted a bunch of
seeds and the number 11 was the was the
seed that we chose that made the cut
also something too with uh with these
old strains that are that are somewhat
making a comeback and we're bringing
some back as well
with that a lot of people may remember a
white widow they've smoked 10 15 years
ago and ours may not be the same as that
it's definitely not the same because we
hunted it from seed
um whereas a lot of these old strain
names were clone only strains of a
specific cut
and so white widow originally was bred
between two land race strains so it's a
Brazilian sativa crossed with an Indian
indica and our Fino that we found is
definitely more on the sativa hybrid
leaning side it's super fruity it's got
like a like a candy chem nose on on it
and uh it's delicious it like the
flavors are outrageous yeah so we're
really excited for it to drop
yeah that's a good disclaimer there Jake
I think I think
um yeah with all these old school
strains a lot of people will have uh you
know a certain
phenotype in mind you know like a
certain clone that they had one time and
it's just like there's so many other
phenos from the same lineage of seeds
um so that was really good Jake that you
yeah hugely there's this huge sort of
reminiscent Rose shade glasses thing
when people look back and I also find
sometimes people maybe even try the
exact clone they are nostalgic over and
they're like oh this actually isn't as
good as I sort of remembered it but
that's a different story I'd love to ask
um out of the other phenotypes the ones
that didn't quite make the cut
um were they just sort of more bland or
did you find things that were maybe
unique but as you referenced like it
didn't have the bag appeal or the
structure or was it like yeah how did it
go
sometimes just you know the bug gets
really larfy or um it's just not as
dense
um as we'd like it uh and then it just
also the nose just isn't quite there
that the what we want it to be
um we pride ourselves in having some of
the terpios flower around and if if
you're not opening the jar and it's not
slapping you in the face
then then we don't want it in our jars
what a great answer this sort of segues
nicely into the next point because I
noticed on your Instagram you guys do
Fino hunt
um various stuff and I love that and I
saw the post about the Pineapple Express
where you sort of said oh you know we're
not sure if it's gonna sort of make it
let's see how it smokes it got me
wondering how often is it that you Fino
hunt something and at the end of it you
may not have anything really to show
most of the time most of the time yeah
like pretty much out of a hundred seeds
you may find one or two uh and if you
find five or more than five that's like
really good
um and so if we if we pop a batch of
seeds and there's like 10 or 15 from one
strain like it's I mean it's a roll of
the dice you really never know until you
grow it and sometimes we have to grow at
a second or third time
and sometimes that second or third run
actually gives it a better chance
um so oftentimes it's not even after the
first round of testing that we even know
we if something is closer on the on the
fence we will run it a second time
um and yeah like most of the time it
doesn't work out
yeah that's uh that's cool to hear that
you guys have like such a high standards
for things to meet and before we sort of
move on I'll just quickly curious are
there any other sort of strains from
yesteryear that you guys are thinking
about maybe delving into in the near
future
yeah well we are hunting some stuff
right now we have some green crack on
the hunt
um as well as a couple train wreck
finners uh some ghost train Haze ghost
train Haze and there's a one or two
Afghani
um so we'll see what's up with those oh
wow and Northern Lights northern lights
were always one against the northern
lights
um
but yeah I think I think if we could
find a solid green crack too that's
another just super pungent strain that
is a blast from the past as well I
remember the first time I was smoking
green crack and it was just
it was something like I never tried
before
that's beautiful it sounds to me like
you guys run a reasonably balanced
selection of sort of really new hype
stuff like maybe you say like you know
the gelato or the cushman's and then
also some of this older stuff is that
how you view it and and was that
intentional yeah definitely I
um yeah especially on the on the rec
Market you have to have flavors of all
kinds
um you know it's so challenging nowadays
uh in the recreational markets so many
Brands so many marketing tools so you
definitely have to have an array of
flavors
um at any given point so we like to try
to keep it
um you know 50 gas 50 fruity
um you know any flavors uh you know
sativa dominant leaning Indica dominant
leaning we definitely try to keep a nice
well balanced so uh customers can go
back and and get something different or
they can have something you know for the
daytime something for the night time
um yeah it's really important to have
well-balanced flavors
yeah and when when I talk to guests
often we move into this idea of like
sort of like a hierarchy of traits and I
guess I'd be interested in knowing for
you guys what's your hierarchy if like
obviously you know in an ideal world
everything looks great smells great it's
great you know but let's just say we had
a plant that maybe didn't look quite
where you wanted it to but the effect
was just unparalleled just Second To
None would you entertain that or do you
feel like it does sort of need to be
well-rounded in a sense it's um
it's a balanced combination of a lot of
different factors and so
what we really are looking for is one
how does like how is it growing because
that's that's the first thing is is it
is it can it make it through the growth
process can it clung can we flower it is
are the buds is it not herming out
so that's the first thing that we'll be
looking at and then I mean really the
first thing is like the Terps and
smelling it but then it then it goes to
the growth process and so as we're
looking at how the plant is growing we
then if we have 10 seeds of of one
strain let's say with the white widow
for example when we're hunting through
that we're looking at the growth of each
plant in addition to the terp profile
and then and the the nug structure as
well while it's growing because we can
tell a lot of a plant while it's still
in the flowering room
um and that's how we like we originally
selected Our Winning Our Winning White
Widow Fino in the flower room because
the Terps were just out of the like
person out of the room and uh none of
the other femos really really hit that
so the biggest thing is like looking at
the Terps but then it's also a large
combination of the growth of the plant
and does it grow does it yield is it the
right structure for how we farm
and then once we chop it we have to dry
it we have to smoke it we have to
actually see how it smokes and like with
the white widow for example we knew like
that was destined to Winter from the
flower room but sometimes something will
smell great in the flower room and then
you dry it and it's just really enough
yeah wow you read my mind always let's
let's delve into that because I was
about to ask you and you just started
answering it so I was going to say it's
obviously genetic dependent right it
depends on the strain but in my
experience I find exactly what you said
right often you see a plant and it looks
like the winner and most of the time it
does translate and I've always felt that
was interesting right because as you
said looks doesn't necessarily determine
the effect but I find a lot of the
genetics I run it sort of does correlate
right the one that looks like the winner
often smokes the best as well do you
find that to be the case like do you
think it's an exception to the rule less
of the time or do you think it's it's so
variable you can't really make make
these broad statements well I think it's
safe to say I mean obviously there's
some phenomenons like the old school
cherry pie that everyone talks about
that would like perm out you know
um but other than that if it if it's
looking good and smelling good in the
flower room it's most likely if you do a
proper drying cure gonna also be good
but that's another thing too if you're
not properly drying and and curing the
flour I've seen harvests get absolutely
ruined
um because that process isn't handled
with care
yeah um exactly and uh and like Marco
was saying most of the time if it seems
good in the flower room it's gonna smoke
well but there is you know time to time
again where you do where you have a
strain that's just fire but it it
occasionally harms and that's kind of
like you have to make the choice is it
good is it that good that you want to
keep running it
um or is that like a you know is that a
deal breaker and so when we're hunting
stuff it it's really a combination of
everything we we have to look at like I
even smell the stem when it's vegging
like you rub the stem and see how it
smells in in the vegetative growth and
sometimes feeling the stems in the
vegetative growth can help you like can
really show you how resinous the plant's
gonna be
um if it's just like like stems can
straighten up just be sticky
um and sometimes Jake actually
oh no no no go ahead
I was gonna Jake actually picked our
winning Mimosa Fino
from a veggie Mimosa clone that we had
in the bedroom it was crazy wow is it
just like super stinky yeah it was like
like me I was looking at the leaf
structure the the actual internodal
spacing as it veggies because that's
something that's very important too how
lanky is the plant is it just super
stacked where it's not going to grow
tall at all so like that's a factor and
then also yeah like the like how the
stem smells
once you've been doing it for a while
you really can kind of start like
telling which plants are gonna are gonna
do well
yeah that's great and I mean on the
topic of you you mentioned mimosa and a
little earlier ghost train Haze got
mentioned I feel like you guys are one
of the smaller group of people who are
putting out some very sort of sativa
leaning offerings in some strain and and
not just offering sort of these like
middle of the road hybrids I'm curious
to know do you find the public reception
for those sativas is is good or do you
feel like people are a bit hesitant
compared to like gassy indicas how does
it all play out I think originally you
know Southern California was all about
the gas I grew up smoking OG and
especially LA with you know the San
Fernando Valley OG and and Josh G and
all like it it California has just been
heavy with OG and and I've always leaned
like once I started once I started
smoking sativas after being heavily
smoking the ogs I just really Started
Loving sativas a lot more
um just you know the fruitier strains
um and I'm absolutely seen a shift in
the market and people being really uh
receptive to our fruity strains
um they I think because a lot of Growers
don't really grow them
uh I it's it's been really good for us
we've had a lot of positive feedback
but yeah I would say the uh because the
market has been growing a lot of just
like cake strains and we've stayed away
from all the cake strains and uh
there's just a lot of that kind of bland
hybrids out there so when we bring
something that's just super fruity and
pungent and it also hits the the market
definitely receives it well yeah
brilliant that's that's sort of the
answer I was hoping to hear and as sort
of an extension of that idea do you guys
in general prefer to run your own
phenotype of a certain strain because
it's like it's a bit different to what
other people have to offer or do you
feel like you know when you've got an
established clone like a lot of the
marketing's done for you like where do
you sit on that one we're so we're like
a mix of both we love running our own
phinos because nobody else has them and
they're like are marked that's what
we're cultivating but at the same time
for example the gelato 41 is probably
one of the best gelato cuts out there
um and we are cultivating it to a really
high degree so there are strains like
that that we like that you know you
couldn't grow without having the Clone
because it's a clone only strain but in
general we are trying to cultivate our
own phenos and phenohunt everything
in-house and eventually one day breed
but that's a long time down the road
um but the more that we can cultivate
in-house and come out with our own
phenols that nobody else has it really
helps kind of create like a a market for
us that of of strains that other people
are not farming
so much of the market
um you know a lot of these a lot of
people don't realize a lot of these
Brands they don't even cultivate their
own flower they're just buying bulk
flour from these other farmers and
slapping their label on it right and so
it's it's that's why the market is just
flooded with so much of the same boring
cake streams and all that stuff is
because it's coming from the same
batches even
um and just all these brands are calling
it their own when it was grown by the
same grower and so yeah being able to
differentiate ourselves not only just
growing and living soil but then also
having our own phinos is is absolutely
what we're going for yeah that's that's
brilliant and um and Jake touched on
maybe down the road breeding I was going
I was gonna ask you that question and
sort of my thoughts have been for the
longest time that I view the way the
jungle boys did their sort of seat
operation as the way to do it right like
you spend years finding these unique
phenotypes and you've got this whole
whole pool of mothers to breed with
would you say that sort of a plan for
you guys
yeah
um definitely uh in major respect to the
Jungle boys they've you know created a
phenomenal uh just infrastructure of
cultivation and distribution and Retail
um and yeah they their breeding program
and tissue culture program is definitely
something to model after and in my
opinion every hydroponic Farm across the
world is modeling their hydroponic farm
system after jungle boys
um and yeah that's I mean that's the way
to do it you have to have your you have
to have your genetic library and then if
you can which jungle boys did if you can
hunt males only in a room they have
flowered out entire rooms of males to
test the pollen and then select the
pollen to breed with and so I mean
that's like pretty Legend status on
breeding and if we ever get to a point
like that that would be amazing yeah wow
I have to admit I hadn't heard of pollen
testing when you say testing like what
were they actually testing like like
visually or like doing like lab testing
no like they'll lab test for the terpene
profile in the pollen wow that's cool
yeah love that so yeah looping back to
sort of one of the questions we were
talking about earlier when you're
talking about pheno hunting and stuff
like that and you're saying you know
we're sort of always looking for an NL
and stuff like that like how much
emphasis do you place on the provenance
of seeds like if some guy messaged you
and says hey I got some old NL like my
gut instinct would be that that might
not be NL at all you know like where do
you do you feel like you got to really
make sure you Source the stock or are
you open to hunting most things if
they're given to you well we're
definitely we we can't be because of the
laws and the regulations so the seeds
that we have are the seeds that we have
to work with
so you know the the people that are
familiar with the metric system in
California it's just been very
challenging to really grow things that I
mean it
yeah it's uh it's pretty difficult
but yeah we don't we're not uh we're not
looking to basically take random seeds
we have a good seed stock that we've
been hunting for a while or that we've
been like saving for a long time and
what Marco was talking about it's the
it's this m metric m-e-t-r-c it's the
software system that the state requires
licensed uh all licensed cannabis
businesses to use and it's the track and
Trace uh software and so
basically stuff has to be in integrated
in the system already for you to use it
um and that's why we eventually want to
get into seed production so that we're
able to produce our own genetics
um but yeah and it just like it it takes
so much time effort money resources to
actually Fino hunt a strain and so we
want to know that if we're going to hunt
something that it's legit
um absolutely and yeah so we definitely
don't don't take random seeds from
random people yeah that's uh totally
understandable so let's delve into some
of the more the more technical aspects
of it but but quickly I'd love to ask
what inspired you guys to to go down the
organic cultivation side of things even
before say you open the facility what
was your entry into the organic world uh
Mountain Organics actually
um you know he's kind of a what we
believe the legend in the space was one
of you know
the earlier guys that was uh showcasing
no-till on in you know with cannabis
indoors
um
and uh we just saw him on Instagram and
we just became absolutely fascinated
that you don't have to throw away soil
that you know all these worms
microorganisms are living in these pots
um and that it truly is you know a
healthier better terpier alternative and
the first uh side-by-side grow that I
had
um
growing just in regular soil versus uh
no-till was so much of a difference and
just kind of never looked back after
that um a clear High
um you know a terpier taste every you
just felt better smoking it ever since I
grew my first no-till pot it was just a
clear way not only that knowing how
small of a cultivation we are just being
Jake and I and then you know we have
eight employees we knew going into the
legal Market that we had to do something
different anyways
um and so it just made even more sense
for us to grow indoor living soil yeah
wow and
um what what stimulated you to
transition from say like growing
wherever you were before your current
facility is to being like let's do this
big operation was there any was it just
a slow sort of gradual thing or was
there like a defining moment where
you're like you know what no one's doing
this I reckon we can pull it off it was
uh it really was so in California
Cannabis became recreationally legal on
the in the ballot in 2016. in November
it was voted in to be recreational and
so
uh uh Marco and I grew up working in the
prop 215 era and uh you know working
with the shop and
um
we had small you know a small grow
before and we just
are the goal was to join the legal
Market
and to transition out of what was the
medical Market before
um because the whole licensing structure
is still a learning process for
everybody but each city is different and
so basically we had to make the decision
to stop trying to cultivate on the
medical Market that wasn't the licensed
Medical Market because now there's the
licensed medical license recreational
but it's it's all together now and so we
had to really make the decision to stop
doing everything we were doing and look
at how we can get a license and get a
license in the city that will allow us
to operate and so it just spent like it
spent a year we I spent a year looking
for a building we had to get this
building we built it out we took a year
to get another year to get our building
permit so we're two years in and then a
year to build the place so basically
three years we had to kind of put
everything on hold so we could go legal
and not have to look over our shoulder
and not have to worry about getting
everything chopped down and all the
money lost for no reason
um so we so we put everything on hold
and then we uh you know we dove into the
licensing I got the license and I built
the facility
and uh yeah it's been a it's been a
gnarly gnarly process that's for sure
hey uh I'm I'm so sorry I I gotta jump
out
um because of this emergency but uh I
just wanted to say shout out to
Australia for uh keep doing your thing
hopefully it uh you know pushes forward
there into into recreational sooner than
later and uh mad love to to everyone
that's uh growing cannabis and um you
know following our journey and and we
just we appreciate all of you so so
thank you so much for having us on and
and uh Jake will take over for me no
worries huge thanks take care Marco I
got this yeah no thank you so much Marco
for stopping by we appreciate your time
and uh hopefully hopefully everything's
all good and we can chat more in the
future thank you thank you likewise all
right bye
cool cool cool so I mean on that on that
topic Jake do you find that the the
legal framework is still really
challenging to navigate or do you feel
like you're at a point where where it's
sort of a little bit of smooth sailing
but you know it's still hard
um like for us because we have the
license it's not as bad now but to get
the license was just a nightmare and the
regulations are still evolving and
changing on the city level and the state
level and so it's just like the taxes
are changing
um and like certain licensing procedures
and so it is still it's still evolving
we're in a better place than I would say
if you were like just trying to get your
license now because it's just the market
has become inundated over the last you
know four years with so many people
getting uh licensed
so it's uh
it's been it's been a wild roller
coaster that's for sure yeah certainly
and and just as like a little follow-up
I hear from lots of people who go
through the trials and tribulations you
just mentioned and sadly many of them
aren't able to get the license and or
various things happen and a lot of
farmers that have ended up ultimately
leaving California because it's just
they feel like they've been pushed out
of the market do you feel like that sort
of um sentiment has ever affected you
have you ever considered leaving
California or was the goal always to do
your thing there of
yeah I mean we've just been like
extremely persistent and so I'm from you
know I'm from San Diego and uh in
California and uh we're up in Long Beach
now so we cultivate in Long Beach but
I've never considered leaving California
um in my opinion it would be an I mean
it's really tough here don't get me
wrong but it's gonna be tough anywhere
and I don't know any other area like
another state to go operate in
um and to have the connections and you
know the to build things and have
contractors and all that and so we've
kind of established a network here but
thankfully we haven't had to consider
leaving but a lot I mean It's just tough
a lot of farmers were left behind and
most of that is like it's a combination
of reasons there's some Financial a lot
of it is that the city that they are
that they live in or they're operating
in just won't license them because the
city bans it still or the county bans it
still because there's a lot of farms in
what we are considered unincorporated
land where it's not in us like it's if
you're in the city of Los Angeles for
example there's also the County of Los
Angeles and the county has been illegal
for up until now I think there was a
ballot I don't know if it got passed yet
but the county did not have any
licensing only the city and so
the unincorporated land which most land
like in San Diego County San Diego has a
bunch of different cities in every
single city has a different licensing
structure
and so in order to get licensed in any
particular city the city that you are
operating in has to sign off on what
you're gonna do so if you wanna if you
want to build a cultivation facility in
whatever City it is that city has to
have ordinance and a licensing structure
to Grant you a City license
if the city that you are in will do that
then the state will grant you a license
if you do all the stuff you have to do
to get the state license but it all
hinges on the local on the local area
that you're operating in and that's the
biggest problem is that so many cities
in California just outright banned
cannabis because they're
just not with it and they don't see the
benefit
and that will change but it's going to
take it's going to take years and takes
ballot initiatives and people to vote
and ordinances to get written
um and so it's a slow slow process but
that's why the Black Market has been
fueled for the past you know forever in
California because it's a lot easier for
these guys to just keep selling on the
black market
because the city they're in won't even
give them a license anyway yeah that's
that's an interesting point and I have
for a long time wondered what the uh the
landscape of the scene will be in say 10
to 15 years time and I'd love I'd love
to hear your thoughts do you think we're
going to move more towards like a jet
like an alcohol style model where you
know there's maybe less Brands and
there's like your Bud Light sort of
equivalent or where do you think we'll
be in 10 15 years
I think so like
it's a it depends like it depends on if
cannabis becomes federally legalized in
the United States
and if that does happen and Brands like
us or anybody that's legal in California
or any other state if we are allowed to
sell to other states legally
that will change the market a little bit
however with that being said
this is a brand new category
of a commodity so like cannabis is one
of the largest agricultural crops
by volume and dollars sold in the world
now and especially in the United States
and in California it's like it's a it's
in the top ten and so
because of that
we like the whole cannabis industry has
created an an entirely New Concept of
how things like a whole new category of
things legally sold is now available
and that's why there's and like I'll get
to the point that I'm making but that's
why that there's all these
we had to create stores just to sell
cannabis
whereas there are individual liquor
stores there's individual beer stores
but there's all but they also sell all
of those products at gas stations at
supermarkets anywhere in the United
States is selling alcohol and uh liquor
you have to have a liquor license but
with cannabis we had to create an entire
new structure of
licensing and retail stores and all
these new ordinances to sell this
product
so I don't know if the regulations will
ever allow like a normal grocery store
to sell cannabis or not because this is
a brand new agricultural commodity that
required all of these retail stores to
be opened purely to sell the product
so that like that's the challenge and
the other challenge in the United States
is that even once it becomes federally
legal
it's going to be dependent on each state
to create the licensing structure so
let's say a state just outright bans it
then you know it's uh they might ban
sale like it's it there's a huge gray
area in the United States with that if
if a state is Banning it but it's
federally legal can you go buy it in
another state and bring it over it's one
of those tough things and so once it
goes federally legal it's going to be
somewhat similar to what it is now it's
just going to be more available and
you'll be able to see brands that you
might not have seen in a state because
they couldn't sell there but with that
there's currently large groups that are
multi-state operators where they're in
California they're in Michigan in
Florida now in New Jersey too and New
York and so there's a lot of like not a
lot there's like a handful of large
large companies that have partnered with
some of the top brands that are from
California
so that they position themselves to have
the cultivation infrastructure in
multiple States because currently to
sell in a particular State you have to
grow it in that state so to sell weed in
Florida you have to grow it in Florida
to sell weed in California legally you
have to grow it in California in a
licensed facility
and that's also one of the craziest
things too because no other agricultural
commodity is required to be sold like
everything from that region that is
grown required to be sold in that same
region because nothing nothing could
sell that much and that's part of the
problem with the market there's
oversupply because everything has to be
sold in the state that it's grown in
and it's just crazy it's I mean it's
it's a crazy concept because like if you
think of like wine that comes from most
of the wine produced in Australia is
produced for export they're exporting it
to other countries
because like no no country could consume
the amount of agricultural Commodities
that the country produces
and that's what we're seeing with
cannabis and that's that's hurting the
market also to touch on that point about
like the brands and a Big Brand like the
thing with cannabis that is different
than alcohol is
like even if there's a brand that
becomes like the Bud Light of of you
know cannabis it's such a challenging
thing like there's going to be like the
low quality weed that is basically the
same across all the states once it's
federally legal but if you want like top
quality flour stuff like that we're
cultivating you can't
reproduce that on a massive scale basic
like and that's the channel is that
these large groups have been trying to
do what like what we can cultivate with
a hundred lights you can't replicate
that and do 10 000 lights and have it be
the same quality and so that's the
challenge with cannabis because it's a
we're growing like a dense flower that
has a ton of moisture content and so
it's so hard to standardize that on a
massive production scale
and actually scale the quality whereas
with beer it's a lit I mean it's still
hard like they can't do the craft batch
on a massive scale either and so it's
kind of like that but cannabis has
always started from that craft batch
quality type type of grow and so that's
kind of the difference there of what
will be of like the massive outdoor
Farms just putting out flour that's
super cheap that is the same basically
and like your top quality you know
indoor grown hundred light facility so
there's a huge difference yeah you
nailed it that was going to be one of
the questions so as a quick follow-up do
you think the answer then is if you
can't scale up if if the quality starts
to drop off at a certain point is the
answer to set up a second facility
somewhere else that equally does a
second small craft batch
yeah
um I mean it's tough right so like the
reason that you know or part of the
reason we're able to have the quality
that we have right now is because you
know I'm here operating the facility all
the time and so
everything that's coming through our
Harvest Room my eyes are on and it's
like until we can really put the
training in place and you know the
standard operating procedures to teach
all this stuff and replicate it It's
just tough because the one thing with
cannabis is a lot of it is nuanced uh
like how we dry stuff when it's 14 days
dry versus 16 days dry and like the the
moisture content in the stems and the
leaves and actually seeing the bud cure
and all of those things it's it it all
comes with experience and so it's not it
what these large groups are finding is
that even if they're setting up 10
facilities that are all 200 lights not
every facility is going to produce the
same quality because it's just really
hard and so even for us like personally
if we were to do another facility we
would want to do a large Greenhouse
because a lot of it would go for
extracts we would also do some for flour
but we know that we just can't produce
the quality of flour that we produce now
on a massive scale
and that's just the challenge like
either you want to stay quality and and
do it small like there's maybe one or
two companies right now that are that
have been able to scale and keep their
quality and It's just tough it's just
really tough It's really cash intensive
it takes a ton of money
um to actually build another facility
and then actually run it and all that
it's uh it's definitely tough yeah so
for us I don't I don't know that we
would even want to do another another
facility yet until we're until their
demand is so high that like we can't
even keep a jar on the Shelf then it
makes sense but the demand's got to be
there sure and as a final quick question
on this sort of discussion of scale if
you did scale up with your organic
cultivation practice what is it in your
mind that's the primary thing that
affects the quality is it the pest
pressure or is it just each plant is
getting less attention because there's
more plans
yeah it's um
it's a con like it it could be a
combination of those so as groups scale
look it's hard to care as much because
you've got so much more volume that
you're putting out and and so much more
plant material to work with so if
there's a bad run it's like oh well
there's another one coming down next
week
um and so it's It's just tough but what
happens is that just keeps continuing
down the line oh this is bad oh that
runs bad oh well now everything is just
mediocre
and uh and and it's just tough I think
uh I think scaling is in cannabis is
like in the cultivation side of cannabis
is one of the toughest things to do yeah
no doubt well let's jump into some of
the brass tacks of some organic growing
so I wanted to know what's the basic
composition of your soil is it the
standard 111 ratio of compost aeration
peat moss is it anything different so uh
so we run the like our base soil is the
Builder soil 3.0 blend
um and then after we have that that's a
well-blended mixed like living soil base
um once we get that so if we like for
for one room it'll take about 20 yards
of soil
um 20 cubic yards and 20 to 24 or so and
then with that we will then we're
running 24 foot long growing beds so
they're four feet wide by 24 feet long
basically one meter a little more than a
meter wide
um
but yeah four feet wide by 24 feet long
and we put 10 000 worms per bed to start
and then we will also soil we will test
the soil when we get it to see if we
need to amend it with something else to
kind of help it get up to the elemental
levels that we want to the mineral
content
um and then we will let the worms kind
of work in there we put mulch over it so
the worms have something to eat
um
and then and then it's pretty much ready
to rock and as we continue growing in it
we keep testing the soil so we can add
the top dressings of the minerals that
we need as well as we water in
biodynamic compost so the compost that
we use is extremely rich and beneficial
uh beneficial fungal networks and
nematodes and beneficial bacteria
and so we uh water in what's what we
call a compost extract because we do not
brew compost teas anymore we got away
from that a few years ago
um and the reason is because when you
are brewing a tea for an extended period
of time 12 or 24 hours it has quite a
high chance of becoming anaerobic where
it is without oxygen and when you put
that into your soil you end up killing
all of the beneficial bacteria and you
end up in like uh you end up putting in
anaerobic bacteria which wants to like
destroy the soil
yeah definitely some wise words there I
myself have been guilty of using a uh a
pump that was not sufficient and I come
back to my tea and I've got cider so um
I can I can relate to that one for sure
I wanted to ask
um do you use any microbial supplements
So like um mycorrhizae trichoderma
anything like that you specifically want
to get in there
when we transplant so whenever we
transplant clones into like a small pot
we we use a micro we use a powdered
micro his eye and then we it's mixed
with water and so we'll we'll coat the
roots with some microhizae and then also
anytime we transplant into our flowering
beds uh we will put micro his eye on the
like we'll just spray with the water
solution so micro his eye on the root
ball
um to really help that Network grow
that's amazing and I love that you uh
mentioned you inoculate the soil with
worms to begin with I think a lot of
organic Growers can sort of understand
that my question becomes I know that um
Mountain Organics uses uh some wedding
agents and I know that some wedding
agents like saponins can be harmful to
worms but I haven't tested it in reality
I've only read the literature do you use
any sort of wedding agents or saponins
and do you feel like it has any effect
on the worms or you think it's probably
a bit overblown I mean not like we're
not using stuff like directly in the
soil we use the Mountain Organics
Botanical tinctures that we foliar spray
um but for the most part the worms when
they're down in the soil protected by
the mulch layer if you're not putting
you know actually harmful stuff in there
uh most everything stays pretty solid
uh yeah yeah I would say for the most
part the worms are pretty chill as long
as you're not you know as long as the
environment that they're in doesn't
become hostile
um they're they're pretty tough yeah
brilliant brilliant and do you do
anything to your water do you have to do
anything to your water or you find it's
pretty good where you're at and you can
just use it straight so uh we do reverse
osmosis and that the main reason is one
it gives us uh chlorine free water so
that we're not harming the worms but
also the problem with City water in in
California Long Beach La is there's so
much stuff in the water
um mainly we've got like a ton of
nitrates and chlorides and then
chloramines as well but the problem with
chloride is that the chloride will lock
out nutrients and so by doing reverse
osmosis we keep it the water stays at a
neutral pH right around seven
um and that allows us to really like
when we water in our compost it's just
plain RO water mixed with compost and we
just water that into the soil and then
the nutrients that we use which are from
Organics alive and they create basically
a dehydrated uh powder that is produced
from a bacteria and so there's a
specific bacteria in an enzyme and when
they're together the byproduct
uh is then dehydrated and the specific
byproduct that they make is
like depending on the bacteria and
enzyme that they're using it creates an
A and like an NPK ratio so they've got
four different bacterias and enzymes
that they use so and so they have four
different products that all have a
slightly different NPK ratio
and like one is higher in nitrogen and
then one of them is higher in potassium
and then they've got one that's also
higher in phosphorus and so
those uh the Organics alive nutrients
that we use along with some of the other
stuff from like soil symbiotics uh all
like all made for living soil having
that neutral pH and by using RO water
really helps uh stabilize everything and
so we do not pH the water it it will
change slightly down to like a like a
6.36 between a 6.2 and 6.5
uh based on like the the nutrients that
we're putting in and so we lab test the
nutrient water as well to actually check
everything that's in it and all that
yeah brilliant brilliant so throughout
the cycle do you guys ever top dress
with amendments or is it more done at
the end of the cycle
yeah so normally when when we transplant
a room and also keep in mind when we
when we do transplant a room it's not
immediately flipped to flower we
actually veg in the flower room for
about two weeks so that the plants can
really soak their Roots into the into
the soil
and we will Top dress generally right
when we transplant and then we will try
to top dress again before week three of
flower and so generally we'll have to do
a soil test about two weeks after we top
dress so that we can then have a new
amendment made for love you know the
first two weeks three weeks of flour
yeah okay so just to clarify it sounds
like whenever you're adding nutrients
you're basically going off tests and
you're not really like winging it
yeah so so we do a lot of soil analysis
and we work with this group called
cressive soil and they help us dial in
our our actual amendments that we use
and it's all based on uh like the soil
core sample so we take core samples from
each bed uh and like we blend it
together for one room and so we send
that out to a lab to Logan Labs here in
uh they're in Ohio
um in the United States and we uh and
they analyze all the elemental content
they check the pH of the soil and they
look at
all the available new like all the
available minerals
um
and then from that test then we uh then
that then it changes what we amend with
or the quantities of what we amend with
yeah okay interesting and out of a
personal curiosity
to what degree do you allow beneficial
microbes and biology to exist because I
know sometimes I look at my pots and I'm
like man there's a lot of Rove beetles
and hypoapsis just running around having
a ball do you have to keep your eye on
that or your you can just be comfortable
letting it do its thing
most of it stays in check so it's it's a
combination of the soil biology as well
as the elemental and mineral content so
the compost extract really helps the
soil biology
um we also one of the people from
cressive is a microbiologist and so we
haven't done it in a while but we need
to do start doing it more is we send
soil samples to them and then she will
look at it under a microscope and
actually chart the bacteria like the all
the colonies of fungal networks that are
in the soil and from that they can tell
us are these beneficial bacteria is this
is this anaerobic bacteria
um so we we need to start doing it more
but that's how we check the health of
that type of stuff is by doing uh by
looking at the biological activity of
the soil
so so and as a general question do you
you know like crop steering is like the
trendiest word in the industry at the
moment in my opinion and I'm wondering
do any of those specific Protocols of
how those soilless guys do crop searing
does any of that translate to you like
are you doing anything that would fall
into that realm or do you think now
we're still sort of doing the the more
organic thing yeah and like are you
talking about guys that are all farming
in Rockwall yeah yeah I guess what I'm
referring to is like you know the way
they do the temperatures and they're
pumping certain nutrients at certain
times like is any of that applicable
like outside of the obvious difference
in
not so um when they're watering multiple
times per day they're generally farming
hydroponically in Rockwall and also for
people that aren't aware when we say
farming hydroponically we mean that
someone is farming in a soilless media
so they're farming without soil so cocoa
is a hydroponic media and so it and so
is Rockwall one of the most famous ones
and uh because it's so light and easy to
work with
um but yeah we we do not water like that
we also hand water but Rockwell cubes
have to be watered four to five times a
day because they dry out quickly as the
plants get so big in them so
um that's not something that we have to
do with soil
um and then there's also a blend of
people farming in soil pots using
hydroponic nutrients
and what happens there is that they end
up throwing away all their soil each
round uh whereas we're able to reuse it
and like in one of our rooms we're on
our 13th cycle so we have harvested it
12 times before
that's amazing that's that's the dream
right I um I did want to ask you because
I saw that post
do you think that theoretically soil can
be used infinitely or do you think that
like you know at a certain point it
might be beneficial to get a new batch
no I think that as long as we're
amending it properly it will get better
with time and the worms will keep
working it but it's it's it's kind of a
it's a strange thing because when you
farm indoors there is there's not a long
off cycle so a normal indoor Farm can
realistically get four to five harvests
a year if they time it all 60 days apart
they can get five harvests a year
because they're just replacing the
growing media every time whereas in
living soil we really can only max out
at four harvests a year because we have
to let the soil rest in between harvests
and so
it's it's one of the things that we just
have to do in order to farm in living
soil and to produce a higher quality
product
um and with that if we keep amending it
and working it it will get better but
the the difference between farming
indoors in living soil and like rotating
your crops on like four acres of land
where let's say you grow on this acre
and then you rotate and you grow
something else
it's just different because we're
growing the same you know we're growing
different strains but we're farming
cannabis in this same body of soil over
and over again and so it will get better
but we have to actively work every month
to amend it and make sure otherwise it
does get depleted and you'll see that in
the runs
yeah nice nice and in terms of when
you're amending at the end of a cycle
what sort of nutrients are coming up
like is it like it's it's mostly a lot
of nitrogen and calcium we're trying to
replace like what sort of things are you
commonly yeah I mean it's everything so
like we're replacing nitrogen calcium
phosphorus uh uh like amino acids from
all the trace minerals as well
um so you've got like you know Iron
copper other trace minerals
um
and so it's a combination of everything
that that has to get replenished and
that's we can tell that by testing the
soil
and the question I wanted to ask you
most prominently in this whole interview
was how do you deal with IPM I have to
imagine this is one of the big issues on
scale for you guys is your pest pressure
what sort of your protocols for that
yeah so I mean it's a combination of
things uh first and foremost is keeping
the facility clean
um when you farm in living soil there
are bugs and that's just part of the
soil life in the soil food web is
there's a balance of beneficial bugs in
there and beneficial insects that are
going to be in the soil and so
when we've had fungus gnats in the past
we've uh put in nematodes into the soil
and we water in uh nematodes and those
really help kind of clear stuff that we
don't want we also use sticky fly traps
everywhere and we spray them out in
Organics Botanical tinctures in veg
which is all like all organic
ingredients in there and so the like the
peppermint and stuff that's in the
Botanical tincture that stuff really
helps with the you know the Leafs and
things like that
um and like thrips and stuff that could
like be living on the leaves but in
terms of in the soil like if you look at
our soil you'll see all sorts of stuff
crawling around in there and there's
beneficial we've got like beneficial
mites in the soil that have kind of just
appeared over time and uh all that stuff
is fine and it just stays it stays in
the soil and it's helping work the soil
food web so like the biggest thing is
yeah we use Mountain Organics Botanical
tinctures
um that would be like our main spray if
you want to put that on the IPM list it
would be like Organics Botanical
tinctures
um as well as just really trying to keep
a clean environment the nematodes are a
huge IPM protocol as well
um because those get watered in and they
really help the soil out
um
and yeah just really trying to keep
everything healthy and just inspecting
inspecting the plants regularly
and if you were to get some sort let's
just let's just hypothetically let's say
you've got a my infestation is that
something which with your facility you'd
be able to handle reasonably easier or
is it a bit of an uphill one I feel like
I feel like with like spider mites you
have to really be neg ENT
to like for it to become a massive
problem
because like if you aren't inspecting
the plants regularly and you don't see
that the mites are starting to appear
um it's like it's just not good in
general like you might have pm on your
buds at that point and uh and so I feel
like
anything that is bad like if you notice
it you just gotta get it out right away
um but if you're doing a spray regularly
and like ours is all organic 100 but
other other Farms that are spraying a
pesticide every every week uh I mean
that normally does it for them but like
we're spraying only organic stuff and
that seems to do it just as fine as well
without harming the beneficial insects
that are in the soil yeah a brilliant
answer a brilliant answer so one of the
uh patreon submitted questions we got
from one of our listeners was they're
big fans and they wanted to know you
know do you still have the terpene
content displayed on the packaging and
do you think that that sort of education
is translating to the consumer
yes yeah so we do put our terpene graph
uh on the back of our box uh we've been
using that now for a bit and people
definitely like it I think uh
I think it's still new like people
looking at the Terps that are on it but
it really helps you know it helps kind
of catch the eye to our box
um and it helps us display the strain
name as well
um but it definitely it's taken time a
lot of people still care about THC but
thankfully for our brand not as many
people care about the THC numbers it's
really about the quality of the flower
um but yeah it's hard to say like the
knowledge of terpenes and the different
terpenes and how they and how people
like the different flavors it's still
kind of evolving and uh people are being
educated at the dispensaries you know
what are terpenes like what are all
these things listed on here and so it it
just takes time it's still it's getting
there for sure a lot of people a lot of
people are being educated about it
um and I think us having it on the box
it really helps show the consumer you
know what what are the eight like
prominent terpenes that are in this
specific batch
um and for like people that buy our
flower regularly they'll see batch to
batch the the terpenes change a little
bit and uh you know we want it to be as
consistent as possible but when you're
farming something like this there's
going to be a little bit of changes and
so I think as people see that over time
like you know they'll really start to
get a good idea of hey I like this
strain because it has this terpene in it
um you know stuff like that but it's
just it's kind of still a little early
and not not a lot of people are you know
yeah it's still early and it's just
being educated still sure sure so
another question we got from one of our
patreon supporters was are you under any
additional or more stringent testing in
regards to like you know how we talk
about like cfu units on the plant and
because we use beneficial microbes that
might play into it does that affect you
any differently to anyone else or it's
all pretty straightforward easy sailing
no
um yeah no everything gets tested the
same in California and so there's like
we're tested for a whole list of
pesticides uh and everything heavy
metals the the like the the microbial
test test for five different types of
mold
um and so
like we've definitely gotten that
question before because people will
think we'll hear hey you're watering in
all this biology is it not just on the
buds but it's definitely not at all like
what we put into the soil stays in the
soil and it really the biggest thing in
farming when you're farming cannabis
indoors is the grow environment and the
temperature and humidity that you keep
in the room as well as the airflow
that's what causes microbial
contamination is when you don't have the
right VPD where your your vapor pressure
deficit is off and your temperatures and
humidities are not correlated and you
can get mold that's what causes all the
issues yeah sure
another listener is Keen to know what's
the biggest challenge you've faced in
running the facility in today's market
and do you feel like people are becoming
more interested in organic cannabis
yeah I would say people definitely are
becoming more interested
um in you know living soil organically
farmed things and I think with cannabis
it just takes more time
um but as people you know are demanding
more living soil products we hope to be
positioned where we are one of the
original living soil Brands
um but it's just it's just tough I would
say I mean I don't know what the
toughest thing would be that we faced in
today's market uh like
everything is super tough just
cultivating legally like I mean just
building the facility the licensing like
it it's all super tough and uh
I think it's just like the toughest
thing is just like having faith and
staying persistent to actually execute
on our plan because it takes months to
cultivate this product and then we have
to dry it and trim it and package it and
then sell it and sell it in a reasonably
quick manner so that it's fresh and that
it doesn't sit and you know become old
and so it's just like
I kind of describe our facility it's
like having 10 like you know car engines
running 24 7 that you always have to be
keeping up with and it's like things can
go wrong but it it's just like it's just
there's a so many moving Parts with all
the dehumidifiers and the ACs and the
water and everything there's so many
moving Parts it's uh
it's definitely tough to run a legal
cannabis business just overall yeah for
sure for sure oh get heckled if I don't
I want to ask you what's your favorite
organic Amendment and your least
favorite and I'll I'll give you mine
quickly so you don't feel like you're
getting thrown under the bus my favorite
input is oyster shell flower I love it
and uh my least favorite would be
Dolomite because it screws your soil up
long term
oh interesting
yeah I mean
I don't know like
I don't know what my favorite Amendment
would be I feel like because we amend
with a lot of different things I I'm
like uh I like I like the blend of
everything that we use and it kind of
it's kind of nice
um well oyster shell is very nice it's a
nice you know like soft powder
um definitely nice he was great you know
this this the soil likes it um I like
gypsum also gypsum's good to use
um
I don't know what I I mean I don't
really like neem I'm not we're not we're
not big on neem and uh like neem cake
and stuff like that we don't use it neem
can sometimes harm the biology but like
like some products have Neiman a little
bit in it and that's totally fine but we
don't we try not to put a ton of neem
into the soil or anything like we don't
really put any
um and like like neem seed meal I didn't
really I haven't liked using neem seed
meal before
uh yeah it's not my favorite yeah no
that's a good answer I think a lot of
people including myself use a lot of
names so that that's cool to hear that
there's another side to the coin and
I've certainly heard and read about some
of those negative things about neem so
everyone go read into it a bit more for
sure so final question before we do the
quick five at the end
do you care about the whole so-called
Clean Smoke white ash debate or like do
you think that because you're coming
from this organic background it's like
it's sort of a bit irrelevant
yeah that's a good it's a good question
um
so there's two sides to it so when you
farm high oh okay let me press if it
preface it with a living soil and how we
approach it so when you are farming in
living soil it's not as big of a deal
and it's not a clear indicator that this
is good or this is not but with that
said uh when you do farm in living soil
and the plant ripens at the right rate
and is cut when it's mature and ready to
be harvested
the ash should be fairly white even if
it's mixed a little bit kind of salt and
pepper looking it should have a nice
looking Ash and it should hold together
well and part of that comes with the
plant dying appropriately and being at
the end of its life and when the soil is
healthy the plant will ripen on its own
now we all we will water with plain
water for the last you know week usually
um so when we're in living soil it's not
as big of a deal because there's still
nutrients in our soil 100 we're not
flushing out all the nutrients by any
means there's still a lot of nutrient
content in the soil but the plant is
ripening on its own and ready to be
harvested and when that is the case it
should have a good Ash and if it's dried
properly if everything else is done
properly it should have a nice looking
Ash now on the flip side when you farm
hydroponically the reason that white ash
like the reason in cannabis why white
ash is uh preferred is because
hydroponic farming is what kind of
jump-started cannabis into the culture
that it is and so when you farm
hydroponically you have to flush out the
nutrients because you don't want to
smoke the synthetic nutrients that
you're feeding
and so
in hydroponic farming a white ash can
sometimes indicate that this has been
flushed better than let's say if it's
darker
so that's the difference on the White
Ash debate when you farm hydroponically
versus when you farm in living soil
I love it I love it everyone should uh
should just growing living soil and then
it's not a big issue right
exactly exactly so that brings us on to
our tail end and what we call our final
five so first question I want to ask you
what is the single most memorable
experience you've had with cannabis so
it doesn't necessarily need to be like
the most potent hit but just like you
know maybe you're at the creek and you
went for a swim and just like everything
was just hitting right like what's the
most memorable thing for you
oh
um
I don't know probably like I'm just like
tracing through my head like racing
through my brain right now thinking
about that and I popped to when I
harvested my first flower successfully
um because before and it was like three
clones that I had grown outside in San
Diego that I got from clone because
before that I grew probably 15 or 17
plants and they all died like nothing
came out of it there was no flower there
was nothing and then I finally after a
summer successfully harvested these
clones and uh that's probably one of the
most memorable things of like actually
being able to harvest it I dried it it
smoked it was awesome it was a sfv cut
and uh it smoked really nice
um and that kind of was like wow like
you can grow this plant and then if you
do everything right you can then smoke
it and it was like I always knew like I
love smoking weed I want to grow this
because I don't I want to be able to
produce it for myself and uh that was a
huge point for me to actually
successfully Harvest a plant after
failing like literally 17 times
yeah yeah I love that that's cool
there's so many aspects like the
realization of self-reliance is there
and I just as a quick super quick
follow-up do you think the fact you
harvested an sfv might have been the
stepping stone for why you love gas
not just that like I also worked at I
ran the
we only sold OG and so I was just I've
been brought up on OG and like some of
the best ogs in LA and uh
yeah I don't know it's definitely what I
like to smoke I think it's uh I think a
lot like
for like heavy heavy smokers a lot of
heavy smokers like like those kind of
like deeper strains but I also love
smoking fruity stuff too
um it's just you know it it's all a
different time oh yeah don't don't you
worry I'm gonna when I hang up this call
I'm gonna smoke some biscotti pancakes
it's very gassy so on the other end of
the spectrum quickly what's a strain
where like everyone was hyping it up
when it came out and you were super Keen
to try it and then when you finally
tried it you were like oh is that it
oh that's a good question let me think
um
I don't know I mean I try to just smoke
like the like
fire ass stuff and so like it's
it's uh it's tough like I've been
smoking what we grow for a while but let
me think
they're a hyped up strain that I've like
tried that I didn't like
um I don't know I don't want to put any
brands on blast but there's some of the
top brands that have been grow like some
of their stuff's been falling off and
it's just like
but that's what we were talking about
back to the scale is like you just
you can't scale with the quality and so
it's like there's been like some of the
top top brands that that you can think
of uh their batches just aren't quite
there anymore and so it's like stuff
that I might have wanted to try of the
strains that they were growing three
years ago I don't even want to try
anymore because it's just like you know
that the quality is not there
yeah so I'd say it's it's more stuff
like that I think
I'm trying to think there's like I mean
jungle boys grow a ton of strain so
they'll even admit they've got some
batches that aren't the best
um but I feel like when I uh all the
stuff I used to pick up before we were
cultivating here like I was you know I'm
very particular like super particular
and so like I feel like even if I picked
a bad one it's still kind of it's like
all right you know
um oh you know what I I there's one
strain I remember that I was before like
dispensary time it was called snow cap
and I thought it was gonna be uh I
thought it was gonna be great but it was
just like a terrible representation of
it like
it was just like it smelled like hey I
mean it was terrible like and the guy
was hyping it up and it was just like
man this what am I gonna do with this
like
yeah that's one I could remember that
was like oh this is not I thought this
was gonna be great
yeah I remember having some snow cap a
long time ago that it wasn't
particularly memorable so there you go I
love that okay so uh next question oh
yeah by the way I want to say it because
you won't when I was in the states
recently I had a lot of good connected
Cali stuff but high rise from connected
California was [__] yeah other but but
they also had some great stuff their
geline was sick yeah exactly and it's
it's that's exactly my point like they
they've got great genetics but they just
are that the scale is losing the quality
definitely definitely so next quick fire
one is I'm gonna drop you off on a
desert island and you can take three
strains with you they can be clones or
they could be seeds if you want to maybe
do some breeding what are you gonna take
with you
oh that's tough
um
definitely like the best OG cut that you
got
uh
uh probably yeah like Josh D like one of
one of his cuts of OG whatever the best
Kush that they have right there
uh and then
I really do like gelato 41 a lot like
it's fire
um that strain is dank
so I I would say the best OG and then
gelato 41
and then
I need a I need like a sativa strain too
for the desert island so there's a
strain that I haven't been able to get
in a long time uh called Alaskan Thunder
[__] and that strain is like the
craziest sativa that you've ever smoked
and I would love to have that strain
yeah those three
that's some good picks there I like that
and I agree you can throw the hate you
want at me but gelato 41 slaps oh yeah
so next one this one's a little Varian a
second last one it's a variant from what
we normally do I'm gonna give you a time
machine you can go anywhere you know in
history and around the world and when
you're there you're going to collect a
big bag of humus
where do you want to get humus from
throughout history
uh I don't know I feel like
I'd have to go like
hundreds of years back like maybe like a
few thousand years to get some like real
nice like untouched like volcanic soil
that hasn't been tainted with pesticides
and stuff
yeah like I like at least you know 2 000
years probably yeah man let's get let's
get that Nazareth Jesus OG going for
real
exactly yeah so I mean yeah something
like that I don't know so there's still
like I don't even know that's a good
answer that's a good answer now I'll
give you the the final question we
always ask people so same thing I'm
going to give you a time machine you can
go back in time you can do whatever you
want but this time you're going to
collect some seeds or a cutting where
are you gonna go what are you gonna get
oh where would I go hmm I don't know I
mean uh I would go
back to the 90s and get a cut of OG with
like the original Kush crew and uh
because that's like that's that's like
one of the like Kush at that time was
like the top of the market
um yeah so I would get like a real cut
of OG Kush
yeah so I think that just about brings
us to the end of it for today were there
any general comments or shout outs you
wanted to make
yeah I mean we're uh you know shout out
to to you guys that want to listen to
this and you know hear us talk about
living soil and kind of what we're doing
here at no-till Kings
um we're definitely trying to cultivate
you know the highest quality flour that
is available on the rec Market
um and be consistent with it as well and
I think that's the toughest thing is
just being consistent batch after batch
at like a really Elite level
um it's definitely just tough so you
know we're working hard we're a super
small team uh and we're working really
hard to cultivate the highest quality
cannabis that you can
incredible I love the message so again a
huge shout out to both Jake and Marco of
the no-till Kings for joining us today
it's been very enlightening we're
incredibly grateful thanks again
absolutely thank you guys
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign
there you have it gang what do you think
huge shout out to Jake and Marco for
stopping by dropping all the organic
fanatic knowledge and a bit of tidbits
of information about some of their
cultivars I hope you enjoyed it
if you're enjoying the show please make
sure to support our sponsors or our
patreon our patreon is at
www.patron.com forward slash the podcast
we'd love to have you a part of the
patreon gang getting access to early
episodes unheard content and genetic
giveaways
and likewise a huge shout out to our
buddies at CT now for all the best seeds
in the industry your number one seed
bank guarantee on satisfaction not just
germination pulse sensors the best
sensors in the game I use them I think
your grow will improve if you integrate
one into yours whether you're a single
tent a single room or a multi-state
operation pulse has everything you need
to keep your room dialed in and finally
a huge shout out to our friends at cope
at biological systems these guys will
help keep your garden Pest and pathogen
free all while pumping on four cylinders
to ensure your next crop is the best to
date check them out now guys after you
param for aphids spiderx vital for
spider mites you know them you love them
Copa biological systems thank you so
much
and That Just About Does it for this
episode my friends thank you so much for
sticking around to the end
we'll see you for the next one
Happy Days signing off
[Music]