foreign
[Music]
welcome back to the podcast
the number one podcast for cannabis
infuses as usual you're joined by your
boy heavy days here from the upside down
library and as always this couldn't make
the show happen without our fantastic
sponsors huge shout out to CT now number
one seed bank in the game you know them
you love them they got all the hottest
drops and they're gonna sort you out
satisfaction guaranteed check them out
see here now
likewise a huge shout out to proper
biological systems number one choice for
any beneficial predators that you need
to keep the garden happy and healthy
check out the acuparem or the spydex
vital two phenomenal products that are
gonna keep bugs at Bay and your Harvest
popping and pest free carpet biological
systems check them out guys
[Music]
spur the more big shout out to The One
and Only Pro mix you know promise I've
been around forever making high quality
mediums you might even be using her
right now but did you know they make a
killer mycorrhizal product pro-mix
connect your number one mycorrhizal
product with a guarantee on the viable
spores inside meaning you're getting
amazing value for money because you know
the product works go grab produce
connect it's your number one choice
last but not least our buddies at
Charlie's cannabis you're after some
high high quality flour hit them up
they've got amazing strains that they
finno hunt themselves using the work of
some fantastic breeders you're after a
high grade product in Oklahoma check out
Charlie's cannabis you will not be
disappointed Charlie's Canada thank you
so much for sponsoring the show
and last but not least the patreon gang
we could not do this without you if you
want to get access to content early if
you want to hear unheard interviews
extra segments and so much more please
consider joining the patreon
www.patreon.com
gives you access to everything you're
after and more you are the lifeblood of
this show We Appreciate You patreon
supporters thank you foreign
Exotics gooey breeder himself
hit her spanned upon our first episode
talking new genetics old genetics
upcoming projects where you might be
able to find his Cuts predictions for
the future and so much more so without
further ado
thank you
let's get into it
alrighty friends we are back for another
exciting episode and in this one we're
joined Again by the head honcho of
counter Exotics the land race lover a
big welcome back part two with the resin
Master gooey breeder thanks for coming
on the show
hey thank you very much and God bless
everybody who's giving their time to
come in and say hello to me and listen
to this old fool Gabon
no we love it we love it and first
question of the day what have you been
smoking on recently
um well you know what just before I got
onto this uh I uh was smoking some mum
mum gooey
I always spoke to mom always start off
with Mom doing
um no I'll tell you here's a reason why
and and I will get right into this
Dewey's one of those things that's a
little bit configured different than
most cannabis is
and this is just one of the plants that
that came out of that run that was just
so unusual and different and unique and
what I found is is that it has a couple
of different qualities it only runs
about 18 percent
so you know it's not a you know a
Thumper as far as that goes but what it
but people always comment how strong it
is and how much stronger it feels like
that and that's because of the
arrangement
of all of the different chemicals that
are in the GUI that are line up just so
and it gives it that perfect mix between
body and mind and you can feel it uh in
different different ways and at
different times plus it has that uh
um effect of being kind of it
exciting in the morning and mellowing in
the evening it's got it all as far as
that goes and then you can exacerbate
all of those by going ahead and
adjusting the picking times because it
has a wide window and even let it go as
late as 10 weeks which is really long
for that plant because they normally
start harvesting about six and a half so
I mean oh yeah it's a very fast plant uh
which is something I like and which is
what I build into all of my stuff I
really try and make them quick because
turn around it's time to get it going
next so anyway yeah gooey is a is always
a standard
um but then you know you can we can take
you know some of these things like this
and we'll turn it into you know these
purple beautiful black things you know
and we'll just you know let all that go
just keep on going and getting to work
and doing other things but you know that
black stuff I just showed you is the
latest thing that people have been
seeing on Instagram it's the black
wrapper and it is amazing smoke it's got
it all it's got the taste that you would
just die for you can uh feel the nice
warmth of a nice balanced high that
comes from it I'm really excited about
it and I'm happy to bring it and add it
to the black lines that I'm developing
now so the next thing is to take that
big ass bud that I just showed you and
convert the size instruction from the
other into that and get rid of
everything else about that big butt
because basically it's it's a it's a
cute little smoke that means nothing so
but the structure is wonderful and so
we're going to use that and turn other
varieties that have everything
and give it that structure and that way
it'll be good for
um one of the I'm just developing for uh
this is kind of like an offshoot I was
developing for a company in Colorado
that's coming up with automated
harvesting equipment and they wanted me
to design plants that were you know
applicable to that machinery and this is
one of the designs that we're we're
going to give to them but we're going to
replace all the genetics in it except
for that structure so because it's easy
to trim and it's you know it does it was
a quick Harvest a lot of good things
about it just wasn't good smoke you know
so but that's not a big deal we'll deal
with that
so anyway that's where we're at and
that's where that you know that's where
we're going and that's what I've been
smoking lately is those things and hey I
love it and I want you too
that's beautiful I've I've been enjoying
myself browsing your Instagram quite uh
heavily over the past few days and is
that the uh the Syrian you were posting
about yeah that was that is a Syrian
that's almost gotten 20 000 likes in
that picture incredible looking plan the
structure is phenomenal it's beautiful
and it was like it was a gift given to
me uh to try those genetics from over
there and you know uh I kind of tend to
think this is more of a service crop for
a multiple things not really so much it
may have been I don't think it was
developed for drug I think it was more
for other other they use it for various
other things you know I think this was a
c hired CBD lower THC has a nice smell
has a a pleasant kind of a
oldie you know folksy kind of a taste to
it that you remember from way back when
when dope wasn't very strong which I
really kind of want to get into a little
bit you know people look back and they
say oh back in the day all the old ties
and stuff that you used to have that
like this one here which is a very old
tie
um
they they were so much better and so
much stronger no they were
they you know they weren't they they
were just
um for the the time they were the
strongest there was and you hadn't
experienced when you were used to three
and four and six percent THC and
brickweed then all of a sudden you come
up with something from Hawaii that's 10
and 12. it's gonna knock your socks off
well that was kind of how it was with
those you know those plants but
intervention over time breeding with
people doing selective breeding they've
gotten those THC numbers up artificially
that didn't happen it does not happen in
nature nature kind of goes the opposite
direction
um
um man has selected that so we just got
to keep that boat cruising right along
yeah I wholeheartedly agree and I mean
brought up the tie there because I I
wanted to ask you I had seen in some of
your New Creations you were using a
parent that I think you were just
labeled as Old Tie is that a new one or
uh something you've been using for a
while
no it's actually a blend it was a Thai
crossed with a pineapple tie and uh the
oh the top the Old Tie was a was
basically a pretty old variety that
um I had had around in storage for a
while and had made some seeds to kind of
just keep it going but it hadn't really
worked it and now I started growing this
out again this is the black tie that
came from uh that set and it's a guy
it's a traditional look this is the way
that you know they used to grow and uh
this is how I remember most ties going
this is not the best example but within
the genetics there are better ones so
I'm gonna just slowly draw those out and
so yeah the pineapple I thought was
really nice the only problem with the
pineapple pie was is that the pineapple
smell and flavor came in really strong
at week three and then by week five it's
kind of gone on and drifted on something
else and I hate that so I have a fix for
that and I'm working on that there you
go I mean recently we had some guests on
who have been uh maybe working with Thai
themselves and one of the thing was
which sort of came out regularly was
people talk about this love for the
Colombian influence in the top sorry in
the haze my apologies people have been
talking about Hayes
the tie and the haze yeah yeah and I
guess what I'm interested in hearing
from you is do you see a lot of Thai
expression in your Haze lines or oh yeah
oh oh yes oh yes
as a matter of fact the old Mendo Hayes
mother which is like I don't know a
dozen years old now
um I use her all the time as a as a in a
whole host of ways and it's because of
the heavy tie expression she's got it's
lanky it doesn't you know it spreads
it's got a lot of you know it's got a
lot of lowland tie kind of Expressions
to it that from what I've seen uh from
what I remember back in the day too uh
same kind of thing only this one plant
out of this set from the old Hayes
Brothers stuff that was up from a guy up
in Mendocino it is just phenomenal in
its expression and every time I every
time you know people hear me say that
they kind of yeah okay fine and every
time they actually smell it in person
and see it in person it blows their mind
because it's so pungently lime vodka
um yeah you know and it gets all it gets
the resin structure and the
High bright uh Terps from the Thai side
that's definitely from that so I see a
lot of it in there and I and that's one
of the reasons why I like using it the
other thing I like using it is because
this this guy when he did it he trained
it so that it was a Mendocino Harvest
Time and so he went for a quick Harvest
time because they get rain up there
faster so he selected for that before he
passed on God bless him and um we uh we
now celebrate his his work with that one
plant uh in the Arsenal as something
that it was the only one I found that
was like that but it was an exceptional
thing that's why I tell people you've
got to search through all those seeds to
find out really special one and then
hold on to it and use it because what
I'd use the old Mendo Haze for a lot is
amplification it has the ability to go
in and take another strange turf and
bring it forward and louder in that own
expression in its own expression so it
doesn't overwhelm it it may add a little
Ting at the end you know what I mean but
it's not going to be uh something that
overwhelms the in all cases not in some
cases it will overwhelm it you know and
that's just what you get in breeding
especially when I breed I want that
spread because my people are breeders
themselves and they want different
phenotypes to select from they don't
like to get locked into something it's
something that's already been worked
that's their job you know so um so I
want to give them that spread and this
is is just really so great for that and
I use it as an amplifier to bring all
kinds of different Terps you know if you
want a nice gassy smell or something
like that and we well we can make it so
that it looks you know when you walk in
a room it kind of spilled gas all over
yourself and what have you been doing
cycling
so yeah no it's uh it's it's definitely
a useful product and I believe that the
tie is a it is responsible for that so
yes
brilliant I'm glad to hear someone who's
very fond of time myself I I'm very
reassured to hear that and you brought
up an interesting discussion point there
about the gas and I feel like in the
past few years gas has really come back
into fashion it's the popular thing and
so I'm wondering do you ever get people
who are like hey I want some gooey
breeder that smells like pure gas
oh yeah oh I get it all the time and I
tell them no because that's not what I'm
into I really don't like it I I and I'll
tell you why because mostly and this is
a good good thing to get into because I
was going to bring up gases and stuff
gases have only been popular since about
the late 80s when they first started
showing up and breeded material when
breeding first started to kind of
everybody started to realize that wow
you know a plant that's three feet tall
can be worth fifty thousand dollars you
know all of a sudden they started to get
that you know and and that's why now you
see this proliferation of and breeders
who frankly probably could you know
stand to do a little more education and
and stop and get to know their stock
better a little bit first because I
always preach know the backgrounds of
your material make sure that you uh have
that fully in your mindset before you
start Crossing with other things and you
need to know both sides so you need to
know intimately both sides so that's why
I always tell people microbreeding helps
you to learn those things a lot faster a
lot gets through it a lot uh safer and
with a more predictable outcome than you
know these these things that have come
about because and one of the reasons the
gas is so prevalent is because the gene
pool has been narrowed down so much with
people using other people's stuff that's
already successful now I understand that
and when you're talking grow setups and
millions of dollars in investment and
and and and what you're talking about in
this modern age uh going with a trident
true that's you know sold and produces
well before is a smart thing to do on
the surface
but everybody's doing that and all of a
sudden now people are starting to see a
glut in pot in the dispensaries they're
starting to see a a backlog I know
several professional Growers who still
got last year's crop that they've got in
storage that they haven't been able to
turn
and it's just because they're shit's
like everybody else's that's out there
you want to fix that come up with new
[ __ ] you want to come up with new [ __ ]
the way to do that is to use new
genetics now that's where the sticking
point is really difficult for a lot of
people a lot of people aren't me I was I
was a nerd weed nerd from way back and I
saved a lot of stuff and I had people go
out and get a lot of stuff that came
from point of origin and did and that
really contributed a lot to the ability
plus I never integrated the mainstream
stuff
into any of my word so when they anybody
gets any of my work
they're getting something that isn't in
the gene pool as a whole unless
somebody's used my work before because
these are Composites a lot of different
stuff I've created so it that's a really
important thing when uh people are
trying to make a name for themselves in
this business and become I'm at the tail
end of it right now I'm tired I'm old
I'm not going to last that much longer
this [ __ ] will kill me here you know one
of these days soon because you know
that's just how it is
um but
but the the new people coming up they
need to
start seeking out those
pocket grows and those pocket areas in
the world that are still enclaves of um
of good genetics that are perhaps they
don't meet up to today's standards but
they hold the recessives that when bound
with the stuff that they're growing now
and stuff can awaken new stuff that's
buried deep and can't come out any other
way
that's the thing you gotta drive this
stuff forward the way that and that's
why background knowledge is so important
for the strains because a smart breeder
can therefore know exactly which
directions can know exactly which which
well I should say exactly but
approximately uh to a good degree what's
going to become dominant out of these
things and what you know if he's tried
to dig out something that's been there
from the past that hasn't been seen in a
long time find something else that has
that genetic in it you know that's not
expressed
made them and bring it forward and all
of a sudden they'll be right there for
you to use then make it dominant you
know and it's not hard it's just people
just need to take the time to do it but
it's going to help the new breeder in
this day and age separate themselves and
it's a tall task because
you can't live my history for you know I
I there's nobody that can start right
now and have what I have and that's
scary and it's unfortunate but it's just
cold hard fact it's just another
scientific fact
and so that's why I like to get my stuff
out there to breeders to get it out into
the into there to start improving that
gene pool or to change it at least to
something that's different that's that
they can market now
having said that I want to get into the
um dispensary thing and what
dispensaries are taking and what and
they're what they're being driven by
because that's one of the things that is
causing this bottleneck of genetics that
people are using because dispensaries
don't want to take everything that
everybody grows if it's Airy if it's
they don't want it
but I gotta I gotta tell you I have a
soft spot for Airy pot and I'll tell you
why and I think it's more important that
the customer have the availability to be
able to get it than not and it the
reason is
when you smoke a bowl and you're smoking
um
let's say oh and you just you insert the
dispensary weed in there and put it in
there it's a nice hard nug and you put
it into a bowl you fire it off and you
have a few hits great hits those are
wonderful hits put the bowl down walk
away doing something else come back a
little while later think you'll finish
the bowl and you start smoking that
again and where is that same Buzz it's
not there it's not there why is it there
because you vaporized all the stuff that
was in there and those first few hits
and so you've got a really good strong
hit and now it's just converted and and
and and and past tense and you are not
getting what you had in those first few
bowls plus tastes like [ __ ] okay so who
wants that I have always advocated and
it's
true proven fact that your THC levels
are more steady in looser pot plus you
get the chance to be able to load up
maybe two bowls instead of one but the
flavors there all the time and you enjoy
it better what's wrong with that and it
looks nice when you're getting instead
of getting a little nug like this it
costs you 50 bucks or whatever it is you
get an actual baggie that has you know
some substance to it and you feel like
you've gotten something and it's more
enjoyable when have you ever gone into
the dispensary and seen these nugs and
seen the full crystals that you see on
let's say my plants that you that are on
Instagram those crystals I guarantee of
those crystals are still there on this
bud when it hits you know wherever it
hits and it's not there when those super
dense hard buds that they take and
they've processed and they've rolled
first to take off the you know so that
you you're missing all that that's
[ __ ] and it should be the the
customer's choice to be able to have
that
dense weed or not and the only way to
change that is to make looser weed more
marketable and more palatable to the
public and make them understand that
this is to your benefit you're going to
remember things that you haven't had you
know since your first time smoking if
you're old and if you're not you're
going to experience things for the first
time that are you're going wow that's
really something you know that's really
good and you've you've tried some of my
stuff you know what I'm talking about as
far as flavor goes well you know they
aren't real super dense but they're
they're they're driven towards that end
it's your enjoyment I'm working on and
so that's where we want to be and that's
where I want every breeder to
concentrate and that's why this is so
important to do all of it is so
important to do so we need to change the
public perception we need to be able to
open up those avenues for more rows and
be able to make sure that they can still
afford to make you know their payments
so you know just got to make good plans
to produce well and it's it's important
it's important we drive the industry the
industry needs to understand that that
everything that's done in a conscious
Breeder's effort is for the customer's
own good and then once they get that
we're on a compatible Road together and
moving this plant forward to the next
phase and I don't even know that next
phase is going to be
you know I I've taken it as far as I'm
going to go I'll tell you right now
I'm tired
look I wholeheartedly agree with
everything you've said and uh I wish we
could snap our fingers and make it
happen with that in mind I've been
thinking you know how can we get this
message out to the masses and the common
sort of feedback I hear from people who
work or own dispensaries is that
everything's so driven by numbers and
names and I'm sure you're you know very
aware of this oh yeah so my question
becomes do we try to market the benefits
of what you've been discussing to the
individual consumer who's maybe not so
plugged in or are the store owners and
employees The Gatekeepers
well
again you're talking apples and oranges
because the um The Gatekeepers so to
speak you know have it they have a job
to do they have taxes to pay they have
overhead to deal with they've got
everything that they've got to deal with
as normal business and then some in the
Cannabis business the Cannabis business
is very the onus on the the owners of
those places is just incredible and it's
really an overburdened institution to
begin with but you know having said that
um to deny the customer the choice
is to me the greater sin and so I think
that maybe this little talk will have
somebody just one person
and just experiment and try what I'm
saying maybe find a benefit and then
that gets tell two friends and they tell
two friends and then you've gotta you
know you've lit a fuse and and that's
what you want to try and do again it's
for their benefit I have nothing to gain
from advocating
something that isn't going to be a
commercially viable product other than
knowing that somebody was ended up
enjoying it more than they would have a
commercial product
you know so that's how I look at this
kind of stuff I I don't look at it from
and and that's my flaw I understand that
my flaw is is that you know I'm looking
out for the customer over my
self-interest it comes back to you I
believe it comes back to you but
having said that you got to put food on
the table so it's a it's a really hard
thing to balance but I think
again a gram of pot is a gram of pot uh
in a dispensary in fact Graham you know
is this big or is it this big
who cares I mean I know these people
have storage I know they could store you
know this kind of stuff and packaging
comes into play too I mean getting
creative with the packaging I want to
see Earth friendly packaging as much as
possible you know but again it all comes
into keeping that bud secure until that
person tears it apart for themselves and
I just I I just really think that the
customer has a benefit from being able
to have that choice I think they should
have that choice there are a lot of
young kids these days who won't smoke
loose Bud they just they look at it and
they laugh you know
uh and roll it up for him and pass it to
him and it's like oh damn what is this
you know
oh it's that thing you just went over oh
oh well let's talk about this you know
and then you get them into conversation
before you know it they're advocating
you know along your lines and they're
passing over and you know all of a
sudden they're telling you that they're
going to that bag that you gave them
over store-bought stuff until that bag's
gone before the store-bought stuff that
they spent money on is
that then you know you've done your job
that's it the empty the empty jar tells
no lies
so one of the one of the questions which
I often hear discussed in this sort of
General conversation is that like it
would be great to get these you know
really uh unique weed varieties to
people but because of the numbers it
makes it challenging and so I guess what
I'm wondering is do you think it's
possible to retain the unique elements
of some of these more old world plants
but maybe bump the numbers a little bit
not necessarily to like 30 or anything
but just enough to get people more
interested while retaining those special
characteristics
well again uh you know it's really all
about the uniqueness of if somebody
hasn't ever felt this arrangement of THC
molecules and the way that they are the
the cannonoids are just all arranged to
where they you know are different than
they've ever felt before though it gets
their attention mom always gets people's
attention she's 38 years old this year
she always gets people's attention
because it feels different it doesn't
have to be stronger it has to be
arranged different and the only way to
arrange things different is to have
different things to arrange in this kind
of a market setting at this point
yeah a great answer a great answer there
you you mentioned earlier that you know
you were smoking on some gooey this
morning I wanted to quickly ask you do
you prefer the flower or the
concentrates you get from her
you know what I I am not a and I get
[ __ ] for this all the time I don't smoke
a lot of concentrates for a couple of
different reasons one I'm 63 or years
old my lungs are like little raisins you
know right now so I I I I I I I can't
smoke a lot of stuff like that that's
going to kill it and make it even a like
a little
I don't know what they're crazing you
know it's gonna be awful
um but having said that
my I I I can't get used to smoking
concentrates because then I can't
evaluate what I'm doing and everything I
do I smoke everything I do every plant
you see I smoke and it's because I need
to know what it's doing I've saved it in
case I will whoa you know that's good
you know I I need to you know explore
this more and and if it does that to me
then I know it's something that is going
to be something you enjoy if it does it
to me with the amount I smoke you know
the amount and what I do
if it does it to me I know it's
something that you folks want and so
that's why I don't go to concentrates
and that's why I I'll smoke them
occasionally when they're given to me
you know as a gratuity or something I
just did the a couple of days ago to the
the Cannabis Cup winner from
um 2017 he uh invited me over and then
and he just wants to get me into smoking
you know all the extracts and I'm like
okay yeah and then I'm done you know
okay fine I don't know but I I it's
because it has a purpose I have a real
reason and if I didn't if I did the
other way because he tells me he doesn't
he doesn't smoke flowers anymore he's a
grower he's a professional and he
doesn't smoke flowers anymore and to me
that's a flaw because you know the
concentrates are going to be good if the
flower is good so why do you need to in
it you know if you need to smoke that
then stop smoking for a while and get
back to square one and then start you
know getting into more different stuff
but you know you're not doing as much
damage to your lungs as far as the the
tars and waxes that are in those
concentrates you know they're they they
you know believe me I've been doing this
a long time and I've smoked a lot of
different stuff and it doesn't do your
your body a lot of good so you've got I
mean it does it's good for your body in
certain ways not this way but it's for a
purpose it's for you
yeah now look I wholeheartedly agree and
I made the switch to vaporizing only uh
over a year ago now and I've never
looked back I appreciate flowers in in
such a more unique way and one of the
reasons why I brought up that question
about the concentrates with the mom is
because I uh I I enjoyed that post on
your Instagram about that the machine
you were looking for the hash oil
machine have you managed to find it oh
yes God bless people I tell you God
bless people I I I I I don't want to you
know name names and stuff on here
because they don't need that but there
are people that just jump through hoops
and to get me machines and uh I'm uh I'm
just so grateful because it's such a
unique little uh goofy thing in today's
world they're really impractical and not
really a a thing I'm still gonna use it
because it's what I grew up with and
like I was telling a gentleman yesterday
about when he asked me about it and I
said you know I had one of those back
when they first came out in high times
and I think there were like 179 it was
expensive you know it was really
expensive and so I ordered one and it
came uh all brown wrapped paper wrapped
and just you know just just discreet as
all get out and
um I made some really fun raw hash oils
out out of it you know I didn't refine
it and make honey oils or anything just
raw hash oils but I was using old you
know little flowers and and a lot of
stuff that that people were using it at
that time with just leaves and and
whatnot and I now you know I'm gonna
throw in a bunch of the other stuff and
I'd throw hash in there that I'd make
and everything and get it all in there
and then I take Thai sticks just like
these you know and I'd make sticks and
then I'd roll it in there and let it dry
and then I'd give them away his
Christmas presents every fall that was
my little thing and so it was it was a
um every time I see one of those or I
think about it in the fall I think oh I
wish I had one of those and Bam people
have come through and I am just
overjoyed and they are it's going to be
paid back very handsomely for it look
I'm glad to hear and uh part of the
reason I asked that is because the
connoisseur hash scene has really seen a
Resurgence in the past few years it's
been great to see and I guess I'm
wondering for any of our Avid hashmaking
listeners out there are there any lines
of yours particularly that you think
would do well making some high quality
hash
yeah yeah pick one I mean literally pick
one I I you don't have to I mean there
are if they're looking for uh things
that are
oh gosh you know that's really that's
such a hard question because I can sit
here and I can think about
several of them that just stand out as
far as the resin quality but everything
is so close I I mean there the the
differences are nuancical they're not
dramatic uh and that's intentional I
build in this heavy resin stuff to
everything I do because that's how I
like it I need that in order to be able
to have the the Terps overwhelm me and
to have the high be as pronounced in me
as I need it so uh any of the gooey bass
stuff is wonderful it uh comes you know
like the pure guise and uh anything with
mom in the front tends to be dominant in
that that way and those resin heads on
her I designed so that they were larger
because I kept choosing and every every
breeder really does need to just always
have their loop with them so that they
can check
everything and do measurements do size
they test things look you use
microscopes use loops and get in there
and just be picky as hell and I'm
picking out what it is that you think is
just a little bit bigger or if you can
measure it Micron wise do it you know
and and that's that's how I got things
to be about two and a half times as
large as they started out in the in the
other Lander stuff that I used to make
gooey I just kept selecting for the
larger heads because it kept they kept
growing and I kept seeing that this was
a little a little more pronounced Plus
at the same time I got lucky and same
time those heads were getting larger the
stocks were getting longer well
everybody knows that the THC is located
on the skin of all of that and that
inside there is no THC it's all other
oils and and things but the skin so in
my mind increased the size of that
bubble and you've increased the potency
range yeah which is how it works out so
um those are the kind of things that I
think about uh when I'm I'm doing this
kind of thing and so uh we you when you
have
um the uh psychonas those are very good
for um
Ash production because they're really
coarse uh the one that I liked this last
year was the Kings banner cross because
it kind of upped the game a little bit
with uh the king's Banner it was it is a
Bruce Banner uh thing and I it was a
request
um done some people wanted that
particular strain cut with a few things
and and so I did and I did that for them
and then whatever I had left I went
ahead and I just was giving out mostly
to people for free but yeah I did sell
some of them I think or or Matt may have
a
that may have sold the majority of it
but you know these little packages I
mean they can they hold a lot of good
stuff for people and I really want I
think that you'll uh be able to uh see
when you start growing uh that just
about anything I I do is made for
extraction and for
um people who want you know that Bold
Flavor forward kind of an experience
so yeah I I I recommend anything with
Mom GUI I recommend anything with uh
midnight snow
um all those are going to just just be
really well pronounced the psychonas are
going to be real pronounced
the Hawaiians you name it you know it's
I I just like resin I'm just a resin guy
so you're not going to see it if it
doesn't produce like that
that's reassuring to hear and uh
interesting to hear about the king's
banno we'll come back to that in a few
questions but I wanted to ask you
because you just gave me the perfect
introduction there where you said you
know like things with the GUI at the
front tend to be good with the resin uh
some friends of mine and I were really
lucky enough to be able to try a a
midnight snow
c99 gooey hybrid you gave us a beautiful
beautiful plant hits all the all the
things you could want out of a good
plant and it got me thinking how did
that mail you selected out of the c99
GUI how did that like what traits does
it pass on because as you said the GUI
is very dominant but then again a c99
probably pretty dominant as well how did
how did you find that one worked out
here's here's the thing I didn't produce
the mom times c99 portion of that that
was done by Duke diamond and Duke
Diamond did those and sent me God knows
how many seed if oh five six thousand
seed he sent me to just to you know to
have to play around because he had used
mom to make this cross and uh I I went
through
some of those things and uh I generally
only give those away as freebies because
um it's not something that I made and
you know what I mean and and and and so
I can't make money off of somebody
else's hard work but I can certainly
pass on that work to other people for
them to experience his work and build
enjoy it uh but I found adding I did a
couple of crosses with that and one of
them was a mom times mom
times c99 and that quite frankly opened
up the recessives in the c99 and I got
quite a bit of interesting uh stuff in
there but before that Mom didn't
dominate but the c99 I
I I got to be honest with you you
probably wouldn't have been my selection
of breeding for for something to use I
have never really found that special c99
that I've heard so much about over the
years and quite frankly I haven't really
looked that hard for any other breeders
work it's just not I've got too much
else of my own to do uh and I we all we
all stand on the shoulders of those that
came before us I don't care who you are
we came from all those hard-working
people that that work before us to
create what you're using no matter what
it is
to this day so it is only incumbent upon
us to do the best we can going forward
with that knowing that and being
conscious always of that that you're not
you're not the do-all end-all in this
and that's why I everybody says well how
can you stay so humble you know what I'm
a tool of God and ask anybody who knows
me they'll tell you I'm a tool and
that's the way it is so
is but you know what I'm blessed I'm
happy to have this experience I'm happy
to be able to help people and I'm happy
to be his guiding you know work in this
so that others can go forward this is
what it's for and c99 is I I think
there's some stuff that people really
like in it and and God bless them for it
I I think he that he's an incredible guy
and I thank him very much for the
opportunity to be able to give other
people his work
yeah that's interesting to hear you know
because I we got a lot of questions
about the king's banner and why you
chose to use that line can you give us a
little bit of a more fleshed out
timeline of was it simply just that you
had some friends requested or was there
a little more that went into picking it
no there were some actually some
professional um people that wanted yeah
and uh that was something I was
commissioned to do
um with the understanding that I was
going to you know give some of them away
uh it makes a difference because uh it's
part of the BPS uh black Platinum
Society Set uh most people aren't aware
of all that and it because it's an
invite only for breeders around the
world
um that paid for genetics to use in
their own as their own and usually
they're very trait specific things uh
the king's Banner was chosen because it
has a a few of the
um recessives of some very old indicos
in there that this this this company
wanted to go ahead and have
um and so they commissioned me to go
ahead and tie mom into that because
you know mom's got some excellent you
know you're getting five different
landris things in basically Landers not
Hawaiian but uh everything else is all
raw genetics and so there's a lot of
recessives that when you pair them with
other stuff that's old and way back that
was created you're gonna find some
recesses that match up and bring out
completely new stuff like I've mentioned
before and so this was their thinking in
this that they wanted to have that
spread
um and that set of stuff because you
know they could deconstruct it very
easily I mean there's methods to tear
anything apart and get back to the
individuals it's just if you want to
take the time to do it well I I I'm past
that myself so I let others deal with
that and they're one of them so they can
go ahead and they can deconstruct that
into the two separates and then they can
even take it further and separate GUI
all the way back into each and
individual component
you know small numbers all numbers
yeah Okay and like in terms of future
projects do you have any current plans
to maybe bring another sort of external
genetic into the library and incorporate
that or oh yeah oh yeah oh yeah uh
um well the cerium was was uh one
example there's also some old Lebanese
that I have recently been gifted that
I'm looking forward to that come from
the red regions you know so I'm really
hoping for that uh I will know them
because I've dealt with that kind of
stuff when I lived in England I I saw a
lot of material from
the the Middle East in there and so that
I have some experience in that so I know
what to look for and uh I am also really
excited about the Colombian thing
because while
the Canada Exotics genetics are very
popular now becoming now in Colombia
I've also discussed with some folks down
there who are actively going into the
hills and going into it to find small
Growers breeders that have been using
these stocks in their families for
generations and that's what I want and
he's the gentleman that's over there
doing this for me uh has assured me that
he's uh looking at some very unique
things that are have been growing for
there for a long time the old punarotas
uh these kinds of things so I'm very
excited to look into those because
pairing those with gooeys and stuff are
going to bring out those old Colombians
and and and the Mexican the Acapulco
Gold that's in there it's going to bring
those forward a lot and I those are
really fun genetics those are really fun
genetics yeah wow that sounds that
sounds very special it you've got me
thinking on our most recent episode we
had Todd McCormick come on the show and
I'm not sure if you're familiar with his
work he's been in the scene for quite a
while doing things here and there but
recently he's paired up with Mel Frank
and a few other people to bring some
really old school gems back to the
market and the one I wanted to ask you
about specifically was he's got what he
considers to be an original haze from
Sam the skunk man as well as most
specially original skunk one from Mel
Frank and I thought to myself would you
be interested in doing a pure GUI
project using that skunk one if you
could get access to it and were
confident it was real
yeah I probably would because I used the
skunk one before I and the the skunk one
that I used was from the old sssc
um back when it first was uh uh it was
the first seed bank uh and that's that's
uh that was the genetics that I used to
cube gooey originally because it has
some of the same genetics in it that
gooey does and so it was a good it was a
good matchup and it was really easy to
work as far as that goes so yeah the
original was very very malleable
compared to later versions I don't I
don't even recognize a skunk one now
that that exists now I don't even
recognize it I've seen it and it doesn't
have any of the characteristics that I
remember Sean Guam was a very very well
crafted seat I really enjoyed it really
enjoyed it
yeah look we might have to get you two
in contact and as a follow-up he's also
been able to get um original seeds of
Northern Lights from um Seattle Greg
who's the guy who gave it to Neville
back in the day and it got me wondering
would something like Northern Lights
ever interest you or it's just too
Indica too nope nope I'll tell you why
because I don't want to offer that to to
people it's different it because other
people are doing it other people have it
that's something that other people can
do I want to stay as original as
possible because that helps the public
be more diverse and the more that I sit
there and do exactly what I'm railing
against by using other people's stuff is
the hypocrisy would grow and grow and
grow and and that's just not what I'm
into I'm into diversity and making sure
that we've got a selection of things
that just you can't get any other way
than other than keeping them separate
you really can't now I do a lot of inner
breeding and stuff but I always have a
purpose for what I'm and this is my flaw
I see nothing but holes I don't see the
good stuff I see nothing but holes and
where and to me a hole needs to be
filled and it needs to be fixed and I
got to take care of that and you know
I'll use the black Raptor plant people
were just freaking out over the black
record fat how pretty it was all I saw
was is that it had buds that were you
know this long on top and then there was
a bunch of stock and nothing else and
that's that's a dirty plant that's not
you know that may work in indoor grows
and and where they trim off the bottoms
to you know promote the stuff like the
production grows it may be good for that
but it in my mind it's it's it's a hole
that needs to be filled and so my
problem has always been it always will
be that all I do is see holes in other
people's work and it's an awful thing to
say it's an awful thing to have it's an
awful thing to experience but I just
can't smoke something and go wow that's
great I got to go hmm you know it's kind
of acidic and a little harsh on the
throat and doesn't the buzz comes on and
really slow and I analyze it to death
and this is one of the bad things about
being at the uh the type of breeder that
I am is this this is this you just see
nothing but holes conversely you guys
all benefit from that I hope because I
filled the holes and then you get the
stuff
you know but and you know for me it's
just a series of uh misses and Strikes
and
towel
we're lucky to have you and your unique
perspective it's uh I I see it's awful
oh little L that's okay though that's
okay like I said somebody's got to do it
and I I I if I didn't enjoy it this is
this is what I've done all my life I
have people have to understand I was 13
when I started growing my own plants
because I moved around all the time I
was an Air Force brat I always had to
have a stash where am I going to have a
stash and the only way you can do is to
grow your own
so that's what started all this you know
and then that High Times ad that had the
first Colombian gold in it because they
couldn't sell the damn stuff in New York
and I got hold of some of that pot that
Lit the fuse
Outlet diffuse and then I started
reading it and the very first time that
I ever had
um two only two plants it was in Texas
Arizona it's one of those I think it
might have been Arizona had two plants
little plants and one of them died and
the only thing you got left was a female
and it grew seedless and I thought I'd
invented something I started going what
the hell is going this is fat oh my gosh
it was the best spot I ever had and then
I started reading about them and oh oh
the Chinese for 5 000 years I've been
doing it like this I'm not anything
special at all and then the next year
after that it was like super popular in
in California they were making whole
Houses full of it and you know oh yeah
all this amazing seedless
yeah yeah I lived through all that [ __ ]
so it's it's a weird uh it's a weird
life and I unfortunately that's the kind
of perspective that I have to look at
everything through
yeah no a brilliant perspective
um and I wanted to to jump into some of
the more technical breeding questions
but I just got one last Quick one for
you that was submitted by quite a number
of listeners and they wanted to know
have you ever been impressed by one of
the more modern hype strains and if not
what was the last thing to impress you
wow that's a good question
um
the only thing that comes to mind is
something that came out of Humboldt in
about
87.88 uh that really took me back it was
I I remember I was I was in a parking
lot and a friend of mine and I smoked a
bowl and I started to drive away and
realized I forgot how to drive
um and that that was some Afghani based
material and that was the last time that
I was taken aback by by something uh in
many a year it's been many a year so no
again I only see holes and and when I
smoke the commercial stuff it's like
yeah you know a lot of it is high THC no
soul
if somebody mentioned that online and I
thought that's very well put
um because that's exactly how it is
um
uh I call it bottle rocket pot where
you're projected up and you're high as
hell and then all of a sudden poof and
it's gone and drifts away with the smoke
and and it's just gone and I hate that
that's that's
and unfortunately the genetics are to me
like that but you see again I'm colored
by so much use and so many different
strains smoking all the time but it it
it has to be
you know it just has to be something
very unique that's going to take my body
by surprise otherwise it's just another
thing that you know I've had a thousand
times so unfortunately I gotta say I
probably know I haven't smoked very much
that I'm really impressed with I'm I'm
sad to say that because I I know that
sounds really horrible and I'm not that
kind of person to want to come off like
that it's just the truth
note to fee I uh I had a sneaking
suspicion you weren't gonna tell me you
were impressed by runs but that's okay
um and it brings us to sort of how you
go about creating strains yourself and
so the first question I wanted to ask
you is you were talking a little earlier
about you know these flavors that emerge
from your new lines and I I certainly
can agree with that having tried a few
different ones and so my first question
is do you create lines with the
intention of sort of filling a flavor
profile you don't have
yeah no no no I always have a Target
there's always a goal yeah I'm not I'm
not hitting anything any plan with
anything without a goal firmly in mind
for that plant and I know exactly what I
want and I know what I want to bring
forward and I know how I'm going to
bring it forward and I know what I need
to do in order to get that done the most
efficient way as possible and so and
this all goes back to knowing your
strains inside and out people will look
at at my stuff and they'll say well uh
you've got this combination over here
and this combination over here and
they're kind of the same thing and I I
can get one or the other and be all
right and be in the same no you're not
you're going to get a completely
different thing from this than you were
over here even though they're using the
same genetics in different combinations
why the target was different for this
batch than it was for that now there's a
lot of unique flavors from the old
African strain that I use for the
purples that that really come through
and levels of Spike devices and
different kinds of of
uh it's hard I want to stay away from
the earthy flavors because those are
predominant everybody complains about
your comments on earthiness I don't want
that I like the Moroccan spice bizarre
kind of uh of a thing and so I only
select for that kind of an effect from
those genetics and that's what you're
going to get out of this and I hear this
all the time wow I've never tasted
something like that before
Bingo that's what I'm after is that
effect right there because
more and more pots becoming less about
being stoned and being super high than
it is about the whole consumption
experience in itself and that's going to
translate whether it be oils whether it
be resin whether it be flour whether it
be hash it it's all going to translate
over in that way in that form for you to
experience and that's the set that I
want to be different from everything
else so when I'm designing something
it's always with a whole kind of a
mentality right there's a hole I'm
trying to get filled let me give you an
example
foreign
microbreeding you know these look like
little tiny plants that don't mean [ __ ]
and this particular batch doesn't but
beyond that they show me in all these
different sections
they show me what this spread had and
how many were good to go and I want you
to look at this real close if people can
look
look at this expression here and look at
this expression here they're off the
same damn seed well WOW one's like a
drug you grow if you grow and you only
get this expression what are you gonna
do with that you're not going to look
any further in that but microbreeding
shows you these different levels of
color different levels of resin and more
importantly the smell each one has their
own unique smell some of them are like
the others you know and some are very
different and you're targeting whichever
trade it is that you're looking for in
that spectrum of what you're trying to
design for and then you choose that and
you neglect everything else
kill everything else
because
and don't look back and people fall for
this all the time oh well this is pretty
I want to you know maybe use that for
something else unless it's super
exceptional and you've got a target for
it everything else goes
so and that's the mentality that I live
by and that's how and I wanted to bring
that up because the microbreeding thing
am I that is microbreeding and what
microbreeding in this company is is
growing a lot of seeds taking them out
after only letting them get so big so
you can have fast turnover you're not
waiting expression doesn't change all it
does is demonstrate what's in that seed
and then you choose that and you take it
to the next step that's why I never
wrote the book because it's just that
simple you're going to take it to the
next step to see whether it's a viable
plant for the other purposes like
production like you know how it does as
far as a big plant goes but you've
eliminated a lot of trouble and a lot of
of uh unusable material a lot of time
money and space you've eliminated all of
that and you've only focused on what is
proper and right and good and you've had
it in record amount of time now you can
move forward and that's how I can do
things so fast people say how do you how
can you do this stuff so fast and how
you could and and they think that I'm
one of these people that doesn't test my
lines this is how I test my lines you
know I see what I'm going to get I know
the numbers of the of the different how
much male and female I'm going to get
which I want to get to in a second
because breeders can drive male and
female percentages and I'm going to use
an example uh from an unlikely source
which is really interesting and I this
is something I experienced back when I
was a kid in Nebraska
they grow a lot of corn corn is
everywhere and there's a lot of wild
hemp everywhere it's all over matter of
fact I used to hollow out the wild hemp
Fields they were close to the corn and I
would plant Colombian seed and then go
in there and that was how I never had to
worry about you know growing anything I
would just and it would it back then I
would just seed with everything and
males and females and all that but at
least you could nobody was stealing your
stuff and they were you know leave it
alone and it looked basically the same
because it was Colombian
um so you know it was a it was that was
a good way but one of the things that
was noticed by farmers in the area and I
had a conversation with one of them once
that kind of eluded me to this to notice
this and is that there the there was an
increase in females adjacent to the corn
crops and the one deciding factor that I
could see that was different
besides you know it being runoff which
is another Factor but uh was nitrogen
and uh what it turned out to be and what
and nature kind of does this as a
survival kind of a thing and I can
understand this because it makes perfect
sense
in a nitrogen
tree flower
nitrogen-rich or nitrogen enhanced shall
we say setting
Nature's gonna
prefer females because the plants get
larger they can grow they can be more of
them and there's less need for males to
be as proliferous and so Nature's over
time and with the conditions being that
way in a Landress setting you will see
this effect happen where they have an
increase in female populations by
introducing a little bit of nitrogen
pre-flower than more than is normally in
the in the mix so just upping that a
little bit
over time now it's different with
polyhybrids
we'll get to that in a second I'm
speaking right now about Landers because
landers's show that variation in an
environment much more readily and
predictably as demonstrated by the plant
than the other polyhybrids poly hybrids
you gotta know what's in it and know
what's being expressed otherwise you get
fooled and most people don't have that
knowledge so or they don't go to that
depth so so when we're speaking with
Landers it's easy to see this effect uh
take place and so I always like to tell
breeders that maybe you can over a
period of time when you're breeding
these stocks again and again and again
you can up that percentage of females
Express for your customers because most
of these people buying seed are looking
for females
um you know that you you want the best
for your customer again that's that's
what we're working for now I tend to go
for a 50 50 shot with mine because
breeders are my main people
but I like to tell breeders go ahead and
let's make these small adjustments like
this uh and it makes a difference and so
learning that just first hand it was
really kind of interesting to see that
effect in a raw Nature State and then
you know to kind of figure it out and
have it confirmed and plants are always
going to do what is best for them they
don't care about you they don't care
about music people say oh they respond
to music no they don't they don't they
don't respond to music they they don't
respond to vibration they don't do it
they respond to whatever is best for the
plant and that's it and they've done
studies that back in the 70s they
thought that plants were responding
better to rock music uh than they did to
anything else and stuff subsequent
Studies have just proven all of that
double-blind tests yes it does not exist
so keeping that in mind when you're
growing this stuff is very important
whatever is the best for the plant is
what the plant is going to do and that
is going to affect its expression
because microclimates make all the
difference and I use gooey as an example
uh I've grown gooey for so long and I've
grown hurt under so many different uh
methods and styles of growing indoor
outdoor deep water culture aeroponics
everything I have used over the courses
of all this this stuff uh enhanced soils
you know unenhanced soil it does you
know all the every single thing that you
do affects a different expression that's
buried in that plant that is going to be
the best for it and this is why people
say dialing in the plants is so
important and I couldn't agree more you
want to go ahead and dial this stuff in
and the only way to do that is to try
different things and see the reaction
and get that stuff going because I'll
tell you right now there are some people
out there that take my stuff
and they can they do amazing things with
it that I could never do I could never
do it they're better at it than me
they're better at growing my pop and
iron
and that's fantastic and that's because
they've learned how to dial it in
yeah a brilliant sentiment there and an
interesting discussion point about the
male to female ratios I'd be interested
to hear your opinions in terms of the
more modern polyhybrid strains do you
think there's much you can do to
influence the sex ratios or it's pretty
sad
um you know again you're gotta know the
backgrounds you have to know what's what
how these things are built and what
ratios that they were used in and and
whether they back crossed it any at all
uh that Crossing it has a a tendency to
reinforce
background recessive it doesn't bring
them necessarily forward
um
that's the thing that people think that
they're they're they're maybe bringing a
recessive and making it dominant by back
Crossing and that's not necessarily the
case especially with polyhybrids you
could just be shoving it back into the
into the mix further uh again
the best way to bring about something
that is unique and different and and
powerful and everything is probably by
introducing an unfamiliar genetic that
allows the recessives that it's made up
from to pair and become dominant in
there I keep going back to that but
that's really the Crux of it Luther
Burbank you know taught us all these
Basics and it's just what I live by I
live in the same county that moved
through Burbank used to live it and did
his work in I mean this is The Sweet
Spot in the global world it is the one
place that he called the best place on
Earth you know for growing as many
different things as possible and so all
that mentality comes back to that kind
of thinking and and this is where I base
everything on
yeah look I one of the things I remember
very vividly from our last discussion is
your fondness for Luther Burbank so
that's good to see it still alive and
well yeah always for the rest of my life
I mean the lessons that he teaches are
simple but they're direct and they're
fully applicable to any single
first time grower on up to the seasoned
professional it's all applicable and you
know why you know the only other way
that you could change things now and we
can get into that if you want is gene
splicing uh they're doing some amazing
things with that now and they're
inserting uh terp profiles that you know
just never existed in the in nature
before and they're doing that kind of
thing and
um
and then even right down to some of my
own silly little work with uh silver you
know to to do female uh material
um which by the way I want to give a
little tip to people who are trying to
make their own plow silver for uh making
females is use just one battery
don't use three batteries and the reason
is is because you want those particles
to be as small as possible and the more
current you've got flowing the larger
those particles are going to be and so
they're taken up a lot better if you
take your time and let it go say
overnight rather than you know a few
hours with a a bunch of batteries
um I find I have found much better
effect uh in material that doesn't like
to do that like mom does not like to to
change sex even with the silver it's
very hard to get her to do it did it
much more readily with a smaller
molecule than a than a larger one but I
use those kind of things in my own work
uh only to
highlight certain
certain traits in a certain particular
um project per se it's not something
that I normally do but I will do it in
this instance but I want everybody to be
aware in States like less to use
California as example I couldn't take
that
let's say I used a mom and old Mendo
Hayes female that that I went ahead and
forced and I've got females see you
can't enter that into the uh the plant
realm in California because it's
considered a GMO
so uh then the state is against
GMOs so yeah and I understand that to a
point is
I'm wondering if everything and this is
something that I don't know
I'm wondering if everything after that
that you go and convert back to normal
you know regular genetics whether that's
all considered GMO and it in my mind it
seemed like it would be so uh be very
careful of that
um if you're producing product to go
into the system uh be aware of that and
you know they can figure it out so I
mean they've got smarter people than me
that are dealing with this stuff that's
for sure
so yeah look I'd love to talk about that
a little bit more because in the past
we've had some guests on who have spoken
notably about one company called
molecular Farms they won the emerald Cup
in I believe 2017 and I guess what's
interesting about their win is that
they've got a few well-known people
working for them and it's never been
confirmed but what people hypothesize is
that these guys have used maybe crispr
or something like that to do what you
said and to create a very specific
turret profile and the reason people
think this is because it was the first
sample ever tested worldwide that had
zero mercy and people just thought Mercy
is one of the base terpenes people just
sort of thought it has to be and
everything to an extent would you agree
with that that if it's not there they
probably did do something on the
molecular level or not necessarily
oh you know Nature's pretty freaky you
know you can come up with some really
interesting phenotypes that you know I I
I I can see something naturally skipping
a component uh whether
they did that
there's no way to tell I mean there's
really no way for me to tell I mean I
can't sit here and say well sure they
did that that's the only way that could
happen because no that's not true uh but
by the same token yeah it does seem a
little suspicious I have to say that but
beyond that what they should just be
quizzed on their methodology and finding
out you know how how it is that they
specifically did that if it's a trade
secret that only muddies the waters more
doesn't it that's exactly the opposite
of what I'm doing here exactly the
opposite and I'll tell you right now if
you take like you know some of the
hybrids that and and you that I made and
you put them up against something that's
been designed turquoise I bet you
they're damn close just from selective
breeding I'll bet you they're damn close
yeah so I you know I I think you can do
the lessons for that is I think you can
do it the natural right way you just
need to invest the time effort and and
be as picky as all hell yeah I think
that's the other like sort of
alternative Theory I guess the follow-up
question to that is let's say that they
had made some sort of genetically
modified line like that on face value
you might sort of think well who cares
um but people have raised their concerns
that what if there was the potential for
this to sort of be like
um like The Strain Hunters thing where
like this plant pollinates other plants
and then all of a sudden plants are
losing their ability to express mercy
and do you think that's a reasonable
fear or it's maybe a bit far-fetched why
not why not has anybody done any tests
on these plants to see if that's a trait
that gets passed on or if that's
genetically only set in seed that's
developed on the F1 you know and if
that's you know again methadone you
don't know their methodology that's the
missing link to that whole thing see
none of these questions could be
answered without knowing first what
their methodology is if they stick to
straight selection then you know and if
that's true then yeah it's possible you
know it's possible anything is possible
I mean you you can have plants that are
completely devoid of chlorophyll you
know in nature you know I mean
that's chlorophyll is a natural
component that's always there
well you know that's not true
and then you then when you look at stuff
like the old colchicine treatments and
stuff I think we talked about that last
time where you know you're stopping the
the division at the point of mitosis and
you have double sets of chromosomes and
you know uh
all of that stuff nature takes care of
and it it will fix that kind of thing so
subsequent breedings and stuff will tell
the tale as to whether those components
have been set as a trait expression or
not and my guess is is that if it's been
manipulated naturally without
intervention further it's going to come
back into normal because the plant will
fix that each and eggs are a lot older
than we are
you know yeah so I just wanted to
quickly loop back to the microbreeding
for two seconds because I got two
questions that I think will help the
listeners a bit the first one is when
you do your little you know your test
selection that you just showed us
shortly ago are you initiating flower
from seed like just going straight into
12 12. no no generally I'm letting them
get a little bit bigger only because
um there is a
a period
that I believe and I don't know if this
is fact or not but it seems to be the
case with what many of the things I've
made over the years is that plants
really need to be about two months old
in order to be able to fully express
everything that they're going to do but
the ones that like the ones I showed you
there they were just put into this into
the grouping and they had about a week's
worth of growth and then they went into
flower
um and that was just natural flowering a
lot of times it's done in a more
controlled environment
these little tests like this are really
more just to see what's there and not to
for real work like that one was just a
very super small example of what it
would normally be normally they'd be
large trays
all under artificial lights that can be
controlled with
soil only uh and and cow [ __ ] no uh I
don't I don't like to use any uh
chemicals and I'll tell you why
um it changes the expression and I can't
tell what the plants genetically is
doing if I'm changing its expression it
goes back to the environment you know
the environment affects everything you
do so when I'm looking for trade
expression I want to be as basic as
possible and generic as possible
everything gets the same light
everything gets the same water
everything gets the same soil and air
okay show me what you have so that's
what I use and how I do it and
I urge breeders when they're if they're
doing breeding and they're doing testing
use pots
you have to use pots you can't put them
in the soil because there's too much
variable you can't put it in Hydroponics
because then all of a sudden you're
manipulating the environment beyond what
it's naturally going to be you're not
witnessing uptake correctly you're not
metabolizing correctly all these things
are changed so in pots with soil and cow
[ __ ] tell you everything you need to
know for a test of the genetics and I
really urge breeders to do that for a
number of reasons one you know pots
you can go ahead and move if there's a
if there's a a let's say a rain event
outside and you're right in the last
throes of it you can move the pods if
they're in the ground you can't move
them you can only cover them covering
them changes things you know it creates
molds and possible powdery mildew and it
invites you know more things to live
underneath it and be protected with the
plants and so that's all of that stuff
is affected by it so if you put them in
pots and you put them everything gets
the same treatment if they have to go
inside because of a weather event they
all go in together and so everything's
experiencing the same thing and you're
going to get the truest expression and
know exactly what you're getting
naturally
that you can do your work from from
there and that's how I do it
and when you find something that excites
you and passes the tests do you try to
re-vege it or you just pop more seeds
and start from there
no I Revenge that plan
no I I don't need to pop more seeds I
already I've already done that and I've
already seen a spread I've already made
it to selection now I want to see what
that plant is going to do in the next
phase which is production you know
full-size plant what it structures like
how it responds to different stimuli so
I won't I'll take I'll revege that I'll
grow a number of the same plants and
then they go under different
sets of growing methods so that I can
see which one is Optimum and what they
do under each set that way I can speak
to you intelligently when you ask me a
question about X doing this with this
what's going to happen here's what's
going to happen under that scenario and
I can speak intelligently about it if
you're not doing that as a breeder
you're disservicing your clientele and
people on the seed buying end need to
demand more of their breeders they need
to demand more accountability because
there's too many genetics out there that
are trash genetics that show Hermes in
the second and third generations and
they just bomb uh or they pass on
horrible traits uh it just goes on and
on I think I can sit here and listen
[ __ ] all day long and I'm not going to
do that we need to get past that and
that's up to you as a breeder
to correct and do deal with and the ones
and everybody says oh well I can't do
that look at how many look at your
competition look at how many people
you're dealing with out there now as
seed breeders that I look think about me
I have been all of my life dealing with
an increasingly growing number of people
getting into this business that I love
so much and muddying the waters so
thoroughly and I'm seeing it happen and
they're making money hand over fish
while I'm sitting there trying to do the
right thing then it comes back to bite
them in the ass and I I don't know how
many times there's been great seed
companies they're gone now see ya
look how long I've been around and
there's a reason is I'm thinking faster
that's why that's why I'm still here
because I'm a picky bastard I'm an old
crotchety [ __ ] and I like to think I
know what I've experienced in life is
the right thing look you got my backing
just as a quick follow-up re-veging is
still a conversation and a subject area
which is surprisingly
um sparse with information I would love
to hear do you have any tips or tricks
for our listeners about how you read it
yeah reventing is simple revenging is
absolutely simple the problem that
people do with reveging is they don't
leave enough material on the plant they
don't leave enough material
give if it's a special plant is that
little bitty bud that's down there on
the bottom worth anything to you as far
as in a bowl where it's going to be gone
or is it going to be worth it to you to
re-vege it and have the plants spring
from that which I will post some I'll
have some pictures of of a few things
that I've reveged throughout the year uh
that I can show what the effect is with
the plant and I will post those up on
Instagram uh to show people how stuff
looks when it's it's done and what I do
is I normally reap
I dig up the plant if it's in the ground
if I have a ground plant and I want to
keep it I dig it up and I give it some
B1 and I put new soil around it and I
water the [ __ ] out of it and I leave
enough green on there for it and then I
move it inside under 20 hours minimum of
life
and I don't like to use uh high
intensity discharge lights for this I
like to use cool white fluorescent bulbs
and there's a reason for that it's 70
percent
uh blue 30 red and it produces you've
already got a root system so it doesn't
need the red so much it needs the blue
to be able to Leaf out and it those will
happen much faster because they don't
produce a lot of heat so you can have
the plants close to it and just go for
it and you put it under 20 hours of
light minimum
and we'll get to that in a second
because like gooey is a real problem
um
gooey was under
24 hours of light for decades and so
anytime now you drop gooey anything
below without working it and really
being very careful and letting it go
down in increments that are very small
uh she'll just flower boom because she's
38 years old she's tired it's time is it
is it time to flower now that's that's
what she's thinking all the time so
there's a there's a I always tell people
that because when you're re-veging and
you're using a 24 or a 20 hour at some
point you want to work it back to a
normal life cycle that you can then move
a plant outside if you want to without
it going off and flowering right away so
there's something stuff to think about
when you're doing re-veging but that's
the fastest way to revege a plant is
just to do exactly what I said little B1
a little nitrogen you want to give a
little nitrogen you know if you want to
I I just use ammonium nitrate and just
go ahead and I just water a little bit
of that in because everything else is in
the fresh soil that it's going to need
for
regenerating you just want to promote
that leaf growth and get it going so I
will post up pictures of that that show
just how easy that is and you can do it
at any stage I have saved gooey once
by I had harvested plants and not
realized that I didn't have any gooey
mom left and I just had Buds and I took
a bud and I cut it and I put it in under
the 24 hour light in a glass of water
and I kept changing the water and doing
it and I regenerated that bud and got
gooey mom back after you know almost
losing her one year early way early on
so you can do anything with this stuff
it just
takes diligence and vigilance and a
little bit of love and caring and just
giving at the plant What It Wants in
order for because the plant wants to
live trust me it doesn't want to die
you know so it's going to try and do
everything you can to live so all you
just got to do is make that happen and
that's the best way to do it that's an
incredible story I've got to ask gooey
might be the oldest clone in terms of
like it's it's actual age that I'm aware
of in all those years have people people
sometimes talk about like plants
deteriorating over time have you ever
seen anything like that
no and I I I've talked about this before
um I don't believe that you can live
long enough to experience degration and
genetics uh from environmental uh I I
just don't believe that that's I've
never seen that what I have always seen
and what I do believe happens is micro
climates affecting expression and people
are noticing those differences the soil
may be different the air may be
different the
um uh more moisture less moist you know
if you just got too moist of a of an
environment resin is suppressed you know
you because the plant doesn't want to
mold so it's going to try and increase
air flow think of everything in terms of
what the plant
is trying to do and the plant is always
trying to reproduce that's its thing and
it wants to make as many of the little
babies as it can and so you know
everything goes back to that it really
does and it so degration of genetics uh
most people are are of the common belief
that uh radiation you know is what
degrades genetics over a period of time
uh that and the the ends of the
chromosomes of course becoming small
well
when you take a cutting of a plant
it's as old as that plant is
in what the plant knows its life and I
always tell people like gooey gooey just
thinks it's been one long day
and so I can take gooey and I can grow
her in any different of these different
scenarios and reproduce exactly what I
got all those years ago with the right
environment now I've always said my
favorite GUI is rock wool slabs General
hydropolics nutrients under a high of a
metal halide like that's the favorite
flavor and favorite expression that I
like of the mom GUI and other
Expressions come out and they would they
may be deemed as genetic
degrations you know because they're not
Optimum for what you know that
Target is you know and so that's what
people are experiencing I think you'd
have to live several hundred years
with the and you know there are tomatoes
let's say back from Roman times that are
still this is hundred and
forty-year-old tomato plants uh that
have been kept alive and have been doing
for a very long time not Roman times but
they come from Roman genetics
um Roman apples as they were called
um that you know they haven't degraded
and they're those those stocks are 140
years old
so uh this this uh
this notion I I think is
I think a lot of times it can be
um something that explains poor breeding
and and mass for breeding uh it masks
poor growing it masks changes all these
different things are what people are I
believe truly experiencing and they're
not experiencing genetic degration
yeah that's that's very interesting to
hear and I mean you spoke about making
some babies in there I just wanted to
loop back for a moment you you actually
mentioned you were making some feminized
seeds and you got me curious what was it
that stimulated you to look into this a
bit more than you had in the past
well it's it's only my own it's strictly
really from my own views I would give
whatever I have left over away and one
of the things that uh I did notice is
that I think I introduced a plant that I
hadn't rinsed fully and let kept
segregated enough before it shed some
other pollen that was actually the
father of the black Raptor uh got into
that mix and so I would never ever sell
those seeds as a result because you may
get a purple male out of there that you
know or or a purple female that that
doesn't belong in that set and uh
otherwise
the reason I made that is basically to
Target certain traits which
worked out wonderfully that I can do
some specific work with Mom
um dark desire and old Mendo Haze for
some refinement
portions of some very targeted aspects
of the traits that I want to see for
those lines and then I'm going to go
back and turn them back into regular
seed and those I will make available to
folks to use but they will have very
much highlighted traits that the people
really kind of
concentrate on when they experience them
the most I want to bring those out even
more and this is just a cheat sheet fast
way of genetically doing that is it's a
cheaters way of of doing it and it
doesn't hurt anything it doesn't color
any genetics it doesn't it's just a fast
cheating way of eliminating half the
gene pool so that I don't have to deal
with it my internet connection is
unstable it says I wonder what's going
on yeah I could still hear you great so
so that's that's good to know I was
interested in asking you you obviously
mentioned how you make your own
colloidal silver solution have you ever
trialled STS so any preferences or it's
just what you chosen it works
no it's just because I could do it
myself and I didn't have to deal with
anything so that it was just the
quickest way that I can again I'm a
control freak as far as that goes I want
to be able to be in control of all that
and that's just the easiest fastest one
to use to come up with this and it
doesn't genetically shift anything
people have said that it genetically
shifts things I think that what they're
seeing is recesses that are being made
dominant by
um introducing the gene sets that are
available to the plant and a recessive
and recessive or are mixing in to become
a dominant and one of those dominants is
pornographism so you know I think that
that's what they're seeing is
expressions of that and they're saying
that it's changing the genetics when no
it's not changing the genetics because
the silvers are just uh
hormonal manipulators is all they are
they're they're
overwhelming the system the female
system and fooling it with a male
component so that it just grows male
so you know that's that's a simple just
a science thing you know it's just
yeah
that's the reason I use it is just
because I can control it no I can
totally understand that one and just out
of curiosity when I was doing some
research for our discussion today I was
reading various Forum posts and seems
like people still just absolutely dying
to try the nor calgui themselves I'm
wondering do you think an S1 would be
too recessively dominant to give them
that or is that something they might be
able to get in the future
you know uh just with the tests and
stuff I still find that it fragments uh
and it goes off into the in the in more
into the individuals than one would
think
um I don't it's not as collective of a
thing the that's kind of the reason why
I went with the the S1 for the cubing
pure GUI and going back to it because I
can control that and and keep the mix
from from breaking apart
um and that's all just back to selection
so uh you know I'm working on another
set of of pure GUI in a different
fashion uh I want some aspects of it
that I used to really love about the
individuals especially the Vietnamese
and the Thai
I want to bring those forward more and
so I've been kind of working with that
mindset and people have known this I've
been kind of leaning towards
um a much more Far East expression than
I've gotten in gui's pure goodies from
the past because they tend to you know
carry on some of that S1
um in their flavor in the Smoke uh it's
not bad by any means it's just not what
I'm tuned into getting so I'm now
working on a different pure GUI that it
might take a little longer to produce
but I think it's going to uh get a
better result and we're in the midst of
um a huge project here in Northern
California with a
large
grow legal grow operation that's coming
into to being and one of the aspects
that that's going to be is to be able to
open up the Exotic cuts the Exotic Cuts
has been something that I've been
telling people about for years but we've
been stalled because of Permitting and
all these other things but people will
actually be able to get Mom and old
Mendo Hayes and dark desire and all of
the stuff that I've been working on and
that were are
the classics of my lines they will be
able to get those plants when that opens
up so we're actively we're we're just
waiting on
the counties to do their thing and get
us open because I have a tendency to
believe that what I want to do is uh
offer those genetics to both home
Growers and to professionals to be able
to uh use in their arsenals of growing
and so that everybody's going to be able
to have a chance to experience by that
time maybe a 40-year 40 year old plant
yeah I did the math and I was like I
think sometime next late next year might
be the 40-year Mark is that right
yeah it's no uh it will be let's see
this this
right around this time right now uh it's
going it was 38 years
and so it's about two more years to go I
would say before it gets to 40 but it's
uh it's been a amazing journey with her
I I just love that plant I really do I
just love it because it's so
versatile uh the only thing that I would
say that I don't like about it is that
it's so thick and it's so heavy
producing and the leaves kind of tend to
be easy to exaggerate if you feed just a
little bit too much nitrogen you'll get
a lot of heavy uh heavier than normal
Leaf growth uh in in some of the flowers
but everything everything I've seen 13
foot talls plants that have coal is this
big on top and they're as big as your
leg and thigh on the bottom just huge
buds just huge
a lot of Growers don't like that they
don't want that
it's too much work it's too much it's
it's uh there's too much trimming to
deal with and all that stuff and these
are the kind of things that you know the
public would love to have it but it's
maybe not perfectly practical for an
industrial setting so you know I kind of
tend to think gooey is going to be
situated as a homegrown
plant that I think people can just enjoy
and we're gonna we're probably gonna
Market it towards that you know to where
the home user and the small plant grower
you know maximizes their benefit by
getting that and then it's always gravy
on the top to have something that old
and spin around and you've heard about
and seen and and you've you know only
wish you could try I want that for
everybody I really do even if I have to
do it for free I want it for everybody
somehow yeah look you're you're a mind
reader when you brought up the Exotic
Cuts program I was going to ask you
about that but you did it for me but the
follow-up I had for that is we see
recently breeders are commonly
partnering up with uh bigger facilities
to run larger numbers or to run their
select Fino at a big volume so the
masses can really experience like what
you're describing and I guess my
question is if you had a big facility
come to you and say hey we want to grow
something that's unique but it's still
going to have some appeal to the general
masses to sort of the hype Market is
there anything that you think would fit
that bill pretty nicely
oh yeah oh I have several that are are
tuned in just for that and that's
exactly what these people that I've
teamed up with are doing this is a full
Nursery uh size unit with with 10 000
square foot
um
Grow rooms uh we're talking a very
industrial size
um outfit and they want to use my
genetics because
they can have an inroad into the
dispensaries and stuff it was something
that isn't available any other way and
this stuff is showy and pretty and plus
we're trying to in this County we're
trying to um get um the tourism aspect
of it going and you've seen my work with
the pinkleberry that's geared towards
that aspect because I want to have
you know fields that are showy and
beautiful and
photographic ready for the masses to be
able to look at and it doesn't hurt that
those plants are also tasty flavorable
and strong
so um
this is the kind of the mindset that
we're going for because again we want to
benefit this community we want this
community to to draw attention like no
other and we kind of feel like we've got
a unique set to be able to do that and
offer and that's just one aspect of it
but boy you know designing those plants
I have the exact thing in mind I want to
look at a field of those and see nothing
but dark purple
plants with beautiful
effervescent fluorescent magenta pistols
and then the
um water leaves all turn a bright orange
yellow bright orange and it'll make it
look like there's a field of Fire
and just gorgeous absolutely gorgeous
and this is what I'm fashioning these
lines to do is specifically that so they
are photo ready and yeah I've already
built in all the other stuff the flavor
and all the other stuff so that it's a
marketable product on top of that but
there's always holes to fill and we can
do better and we're continuing to go in
that direction so that's what all this
is for
I love it a brilliant approach I had
noticed on your Instagram you'd been
posting some photos over the past few
months of Australian you're calling
American sunshine and the thing which
really caught me about that one was do
you say it's got like a vanilla profile
to it which is quite an underrepresented
sort of terpen profile how would you
describe it and do you think it might
get quite popular
oh well I'm I'm actually breeding with
it there's two uh females one purple and
one uh green I'll post them up on
Instagram as to what they look like at
the moment because uh they're just
finishing up for those those runs right
now but the profiles of the of the
vanilla tend to fade away after week
nine but before week nine
you're getting this distinct I I
actually
said here to well I think it was
Northstar who mentioned it
um I said what are you getting off of
this because I already had vanilla in
mind he says oh it smells vanilla you
know oh perfect there you go that's
exactly because I hadn't heard of a
vanilla one before and I haven't really
come across anything like that but it's
the first thing that comes to mind when
I smell especially the green one the the
purple one is a little bit more spicy in
the back because of the the components
that it has from the colors
um but I could steer it back over and I
will do that and that's what I'm working
on now is to get those into some very
dependable vanilla flavors because then
you mix that with a nice coffee variety
you've got a latte
I was funny you mentioned that I was
curious to ask you because you got such
experience with sort of creating these
new flavor profiles I remember that you
know the late sub cool rest in peace uh
often described creating strains and he
would say if you've got one that's
chocolate and one that's vanilla you
combine them together you got a latte
something like that would you say that
you sort of agree with that sort of
mindset or do you think it's unexpected
no it's it's this it's the clock is
wrong a broken clock is right twice a
day kind of a syndrome that and I used
to tell some that this is that you know
you can go ahead and you can have these
different expressions and
unless you lock that down and that's the
purpose of going ahead and re-veging
plants you
you've got to be able to lock that down
well if it's present and pronounced in
the phenotype that you're dealing with
you've already got half of it going you
just need to make that a set a set thing
and that's not hard if you're using
other genetics that you use to create
this to go ahead and reset that dominant
intest and to keep it dominant you want
to be able to do that and I use the same
things where that came from but that
means you got to know your backgrounds
or your stuff it all comes back to the
same thing these Basics that I tell
people all the time and they they look
for these complicated
methods and how they do these things
it's simple selection and being picky
period end the subject I can do anything
I want
with a given set of genetics if it has
something that I want to make it come
forward and anybody else can do the same
damn thing you just got to put the work
in
yeah certainly certainly we had a an
interesting question submitted by one of
our listeners and I think it was sort of
inspired by our first discussion and it
seems like they they really took on
board the point you made about how you
know you can take a certain trait you
like from this plant and improve it or
bring it to another cross and what they
were sort of wondering is let's just say
I've got like four base plants and I
like certain things about each of them
and I want to sort of ultimately lead it
into one end strain where I'm
incorporating the things I like about
each into one thing do you think that
it's practically possible for someone to
do that or logistically it would just
require a lot of work
it's going to require a lot of work it
if you're willing to do the work then
you've got to have multiple plans of the
set of the same plant that you can use
to work with and do your your your r d
with and you've got to just go through
it to me and that's why I always tell
people when you're beginning and when
you're when you're not as sure about
your genetic stock
concentrate on one trade don't
concentrate on anything else this is
again what you're describing is what I
was telling you about oh this little
plant is prettier and I can save this
for another project no that's you're
that's getting that's you getting in
your own way
and so I always tell people it's better
to focus on one thing get it locked down
then move to the next thing if you want
to work on four plants that's great
save copies of the other three work on
the one get it right then move to the
next one because you're going to be a
lot more efficient you're going to get a
lot more done and you're going to do it
in a lot shorter time than if you're
trying to [ __ ] around with four plants
four different expressions and you're
trying to stabilize each one of those
expressions in a line
now I do it because
I'm you know I know my [ __ ] backwards
and forwards as far as my genetics that
I'm working with I know those genetics
most people don't have that Luxury Plus
they're working with a lot of poly
hybrids in this industry that are you
don't know what they're made of people
can say it's made of something when it's
totally different or that's what they
were told it was you know and it and it
isn't at all
so it's better to do the work yourself
and I always feel it's better to
concentrate on smaller chunks and get it
right it's like when you're cleaning
your house if your house is totally
[ __ ] up and totally needs cleaning and
you get overwhelmed looking at this
whole house not clean
stop
go over to this three foot little area
and clean it that's your task for the
day
next day the three foot next to it and
so on and so forth before you know it
your house is clean you hadn't suffered
any and it's done perfectly
same thing
brilliant analogy just keeping it simple
I like that and another one of our
listener submitted questions was how
many seeds do you like to pop of one of
your own lines before you feel satisfied
you have a good idea of what's inside it
well if it's been a refined targeted
line I I you know I can get away with a
dozen
you know it'll show me it'll show me the
spread of basically everything that's in
there you might get these recessive
oddballs here and there but you know
that they aren't going to be something
that expresses
as readily as those other 11. you know
they're they're going to sh it's going
to show so I I just I tend to think that
now if you're doing R and D lines oh six
seven hundred seeds
you know I'm serious really and people
people laugh and they say how do you do
that well you know when you're growing
little tiny plants it's not as much it's
it it's a lot easier than you think and
half of those are going to go away as
males anyway
you know and I don't chase males I never
chase males I and I always Advocate that
people don't chase males you know males
are a tool the females are what you
chase and the females are what you
refine and you everything is done to
refine that female don't chase males
period so what sort of guiding
principles do you use When selecting a
male do you find the female that has the
qualities you want and then try to find
the male that matches up to it
it all goes back to what it is that I'm
trying to do you know if I try to color
it okay does that mail Shield color
dependably is it going to pass it on
does it come from a color line that has
color already built in or is the color
recessive and only showing in that one
phenotype it all goes back to targeted
results as far as what you want to do
and how you want it to be expressed that
that's all you choosing and knowing the
background and using that background
like that
yeah
so I believe you're currently working on
an old Mendo Haze back cross and I had
me wondering what traits about the old
Mendo Haze you really like and which do
you think could maybe be improved a
little
well I already did that and that cross
fix that but the the Mendo Hayes has a
hell of a stretch to it and I didn't
like all that elongation so I kind of
kept the elongation because it was
easier to to fill the empty spaces than
it was to uh stop the elongation
um so I took the easy path in that
direction so you get big plants that are
sativa base and there's a lot less
um
stem you know a lot more
Fuller flowers larger flowers the flower
sizes increased
there is a marker that I use which was
the dark desire as a color marker so
with it when I was cubing that I was
steering away from that color marker and
then gooey is in there also because of
the resin expression but she's in the
back end
um with um uh and that was used with a
pure GUI was used for that not Mom GUI
so it was the uh
um the mail that I did that for only to
increase the resin size on there which
indeed it it I and I can again show
people on Instagram I wish I had
examples right here that I could bring
up because I have examples of all this
stuff where I can show you the
difference between the the old Mendo
Hayes mother and the improved version
and what it does and how much better it
is as far as a overall grower experience
from that point but it still has the
bright
overwhelmingly bright flavors the 24
minimum THC is still there
um all those familiar flavors that I
talk about when I when I take the lime
and the Vodka those are very pronounced
and everything is there it's just a
fuller plant that produces better Bud
and bigger bud and has you know it's
cleaner
so you know it's more refined it's
basically that's all that is but then
there's the color marker in there just
for my own work but yeah you know if
someone were to cross it with a
recessive color all of a sudden they'd
get kids that are all kinds of different
colors and that'd be that's always a fun
surprise you know it's not a it's it's
like a little genetic Time Bomb but it's
a good one not a bad one like her you
know that kind of thing very nice and I
mean I ran one of subcool's breeding
theories by you and so I'd love to run
one of DJ shorts by you which is he
always spoke about he liked to have the
more sativa of the two plants in the
cross being the female he never really
explained why that was have you ever
found anything like that or got any
thoughts
uh you know again I think it's more a
strange specific in that instance but I
mean yeah if you're dealing with hybrids
and stuff I I tend to lean towards the
sativas myself only because one they're
bigger uh they tend to be Fuller you
know with a lot better production uh and
I I just like to high better as far as
that goes it's a brighter more
pronounced
kind of high that fits my personality
and that's the thing uh that's all very
s person specific stuff that you're
talking about there somebody who else
who tries that may go and go for the
Indica side because it that's what they
favor and their brain craves kind of
thing so it it all comes back to me is
to I want everybody to have the choice I
want you to be able to choose what's
best for you and so yeah I I I like to
have a a spread on the things that I do
for breeders I like to have that spread
I myself choose the sativa sides more
but you know me I'm a Thai Vietnamese
Colombian you know I'm old school Mexico
I like those I I just have fond memories
of them and I just feel like they're
more efficient at giving me the type of
vibe that I'm looking for
I'm not into sedative
yeah you know I'm Into You Know euphoric
and and psychoactive those are the kind
of highs I like I like clean I like to
be able to to like go go to Hawaii smoke
a nice sativa bowl and then go out and
enjoy the day not sit there on the beach
and veg and bacon and sand and get a
sunburn
yeah here here I can agree with that one
other thing which just came to mind when
you were talking about that is DJ Short
commented and it's very much a personal
thing he said oh yeah I really like
smoking flour that's been seeded I feel
like there's some sort of slight changes
in cedared Bud versus Cincy yeah do you
fall into that category or not really no
I don't I don't like smoking the flowers
to me it gets harsh and it's just you
know I don't like it I don't like it
because again
what happens when it's making seed is
the plant stops THC production and what
THC is available there goes into
post-tac products and you're getting a
lot of of the degraded THC and that's
probably what he likes about it is that
that CBN kind of a feel that that
settling that that heaviness that
sedativeness that uh it's great for pain
kind of thing uh
um yeah I can see that as being
something that would be present in
seeded pot and I remember
plenty of seeded brick weed from back in
the day that was just thicker than [ __ ]
far as a high goes you know oh and
that's all to me is just degraded resin
is what that is so if you like that kind
of high let your plants sit around
what's what they do in in the hashmaking
uh regions of the world is in the
especially in the poor regions they'll
just pile the plants in the corner and
let them sit for six months and then
they make the hash out of that and the
hash is very sedative very heavy you can
feel it a lot in the body and that's all
from just sitting around and just being
exposed and oxidizing you know that kind
of thing so it really kind of depends on
what your tastes are and where you're
going for but yeah degraded resin yeah
it's never been my I don't really care
for it as much as I like the bright
newer resin I'm always a new plant kind
of a guy but I think that's kind of my
thing from growing so much and having
samples all the time I've just gotten
into that that rail of fresh smoke all
the time because it never ends I mean
there's not a day that goes by that
there is something fresh and new that
I've never tried before that goes into
my lungs so
you know I I speak from that perspective
certainly and I mean if we're on the
other end of the spectrum of shore
flowering things you mentioned at the
start that you you have a number of
lines that are quite quick and you know
the GUI can be harvested reasonably
early I guess my question is do you
think there's such a thing as too short
of a flowering time in the sense that if
I came to you and said hey I got this
line Freddy in 35 days people say oh
yeah but like the high probably won't
last that long or something like that do
you think that's true or do you think
you can get great high at a very short
flower time yeah you bet if you can trim
it down that much you bet and it's a
little that's really short but you know
that's almost just going off of auto
flowering kind of stuff
yeah I have some reservations uh myself
but that's there's nothing that says
that you can't have
full product in a short period of time
nothing there's just no reason for it
doesn't make any sense
there is a the only thing that I can say
in that conflicts with that is my
two-month rule for plants is that if you
want to see a full expression you need
two months I equate that as the same
thing as a prepubescent girl being able
to get pregnant versus one that's gone
into puberty
she's just not ready yet you know and
she's just is not able to concede yet at
that age then she goes and gets old
enough boom she's mature and she can
reproduce it's the same kind of thing I
think that the genetics set up and are
able to establish themselves and express
themselves more completely in a slightly
older plant
so you've got and that's why I when I
microbreed if I'm going really fast and
I'm taking things really quick and
they're not made quite too much that's
the whole purpose of having a secondary
growth set you know as a test nothing is
said in stone where I've picked that
plant the first time it's just gone down
to the next stage is all you know
there's still a lot of evaluation and a
lot of rejects that come off of that
people look at the rejects that I do and
they go well Jesus is really nice why
are you rejecting that sorry didn't hit
the mark for that it's out of here next
because Life's too short to mess around
with crappy genetics
and you just you just raised the topic
that you got some reservations around
Autos would you be able to tell us what
they might be
what do you mean well like would we ever
see a gooey Auto project in the works or
is just not something you're interested
in
ah
I don't know I I I
uh
I don't know
see I'm so busy just doing but what I'm
doing that and I've got so many irons in
the fire with all of the stuff like this
now adding more stuff is just I don't
know it's always a possibility I guess
you know I haven't considered it myself
as far as uh
a separate project goal thing to do uh
I do uh
I do want to be able to
bring the brand around I think that's my
main focus right now is to bring the
brand around to the public to
they're only just now kind of really
fully getting that it's different and
that it's not the same and people are
hearing stuff about it and that's the
really the main focus of my all my
attentions these last few years is kind
of getting that because I think it's
good for the public
I think and and so my heart and my
efforts are really
concentrating on that
yeah totally understandable you
mentioned earlier the the black Platinum
Society is somewhere where you get some
high quality genetics from I was
wondering no no no no
black Platinum Society is mine and
people get their genetics from me to use
in their lines some of the most famous
breeders that I'm not allowed to mention
because that's part of the black
platinum's uh society's uh rules are
that you know we don't discuss but one
of the other rules is that those they
can use those genetics as their own and
they don't have to promote them in with
uh my company or anything like that and
I always tell them might be a good idea
to tell people that they come from these
genetics because it just incites more
interest in that that genre or that that
area you know that that uniqueness and
stuff and that would draw more people in
to that just by virtue of that but it's
not a requisite and so no that's
something that
over the years I've invited you know
professional breeders and whether they
want to go ahead and do it most of them
approach me and then we go ahead and
talk and if it's all right then I'll go
ahead and I invite them in but uh no
those are that's something that comes
from me and goes out not other ways
coming in
sure yeah my mistake on that one I guess
my question I'm hoping is still going to
be just as relevant in that I'm
wondering you know you've obviously got
a very reputable collection of genetics
Joe keep your eye out for new land races
coming out in the sense that there are
guys like Indian Land race exchange and
stuff like that who are doing these
trips and trying to Source it you keep
your finger on that pulse at all no I
don't and the reason I don't is because
of the same thing I've always said
they're doing that and that's their
their
their selling point that I don't want to
mix my genetics in with that what I want
to do is I want to take raw genetics
whatever's left in the world which is
we've I've as we've talked before you
know the gene pool is shrinking ever and
ever more but you know you can still
find these little enclaves of of areas
where you can get Lander stuff that's
been bred by small farmers in very
remote areas and you can bring that
stuff forward and use that and that's
where my focus has been I have a friend
who's a producer in Hollywood and he
um also goes around and does stock
footage filming for
um the you know the various industry you
know that he does stock footage you know
so
um in his travels he goes around and
he's the one that got me the African
he's gotten me some Jamaican material
before that was very old and and this is
the kind of stuff that he does he goes
and he searches out these areas to film
and it happens across these Growers
talks to them gets their confidence and
then sends me the material to use and
I've had great success with it that way
and I think that that just again
brings more diversity into this field
and allows more uh customer uh Advantage
I think customer advantages everything
and I think the only way to do it is to
get new stuff and that that gene pool is
shrinking what's fun is is that I all my
old stuff is that it's all old stuff and
and since I've kept it separate it's
available for folks to enjoy and that's
what's fun to me I really find that I
found that I find that so much fun
because I know how it was when I was a
kid experiencing these new things for
the first time and I just want to bring
that pleasure to people and I don't
think you can do it by mixing even no
matter how Landers C and everything are
that's somebody else let them benefit
from that let them benefit from that
Niche and enjoy that which they worked
very hard for you know now you if
somebody wants to take their material
and then they take some of my material
and they blend them together and they
come up with something unique for
themselves that's what we're here for
that's what we're here for
I remember uh seeing on your Instagram
you had mentioned that the Hawaiian
blush mother really special plant and
something you were hoping to touch on I
was wondering what about it makes it so
special to you
oh the blush yeah the blush is is
actually a combination of a couple
different things and it comes from it
there's an old family in Hawaii that has
some
quote unquote Hawaiian varieties that
they kept to themselves and only use for
themselves and I got some of their work
it's a composite still of old Island
strains I believe because I can see a
couple of different things in it but um
it is it is Harkens back to the older
Hawaiians with those very unique Eastern
flavors uh and and that bright
effervescent kind of a feel that you get
when you smoke uh a good Hawaiian for
the first time where it kind of grows
and feels almost bubbly and effervescent
you know it really is uh that that kind
of a feel very alive awake
um no suppression and mood but very
almost psychoactive you know just very
for a younger person that doesn't have
as much THC in their system as someone
like me it could be very psychoactive
and very pleasurable and so using that
line that they gave me to be able to do
that
um I mixed it with
what did I mix it with
it was a color marker that I used and I
don't think it had a name
but the color marker would go back to
Zen
the Zen would be the and that's a very
grapey kind of thing and I used to like
to use that for a lot of of the flavor
components that it had and I think that
that I think the Zen I haven't had my
notes with me I actually got my notes
but um yeah it it it's a Zen cross and I
do believe it was Zen
times
um Kona sunset
cross with Zen and that's and that's why
it was Hawaiian blush because the the
Hawaiian material that was the male that
I used with it was crossed into that
female uh of the blend and then that's
where the Hawaiian blush came from it's
a pretty plant it's really pretty
I actually Reve that and say that I
seated the [ __ ] out of it and then I I
revenged it just so that I could grow it
again because it you know I see these
dark purples and stuff all the time that
I do and you just kind of get yeah tired
of them and then you see something that
has a nice red here to it like the Reds
that I've used uh I've been trying to
develop it's uh those are just exciting
to me they're new and different showy
and big plants look really whoa you know
wow uh and I'm into that I'm into into
it it being a display I always wanted to
come up with a a landscaping company
that would tailor different pots for
different areas in your yard you could
have edges and you could have tall wispy
things and it would just be a beautiful
yard I always wanted to do that
I'm gonna convert them to perennials
well you know that would be nice
wouldn't it that would be nice yeah well
that's what everybody always says gooey
you know how can you make an annual
about perennial well you you just
control it
there you go and I mean while we're on
the topic of Hawaii one of our patreon
listeners would love to know if you
could tell us a little bit more about
your connection to Hawaii and if there
are any specific Hawaiian genetics you
feel really drawn to
oh I've always liked the big Islands
material Big Island material always had
the most punch to me the Maui's were
cute and bright and
uh nice and the the quiet electrics were
always really
amazing materials
uh but I don't know the Big Island
always had the punch to it that really
set it apart so that kona's the konos I
was gifted were another old strain that
has been kept on that island for all
these years and it's really resistant to
mold and it grew big and has flavorful
colas and the punches there I just
really enjoyed the Kona more than I
really probably enjoyed anything else
from Hawaii
interesting and I mean do you have any
specific history with Hawaii or it's
just somewhere you really like
no actually I have family over there uh
yeah and I I used to go over there quite
a bit plus uh uh the the uh on Oahu the
first dispensary in Hawaii they use some
of my genetics uh so I have a kind of a
little bit of a
of a a soft spot for for just a life or
what it's given for Mom gooey all those
years ago with the first 1972 Maui wow
he's
um
that uh there's always that kind of
always was one of those special things
excuse me my dog needs to go out for a
second oh
yeah I had no idea he was there
yeah he's a 14 year old Dachshund
miniature doctor beautiful so he's a
good boy but um yeah I like Hawaii I
have always liked uh it it to me it was
always a very challenging place
for a number of reasons as far as
growing so it really always attracted my
attention to that because you really I
mean the way that Hawaiians
traditionally grew stuff is they would
put small plants out up in the hills and
they would let it go and they would come
back a few months later and harvest and
put another one in its place
um and that was always a very
interesting dance because of the the
police that were so Vigilant about
trying to do the eradications over there
was always something I always thought
was wrong so anyway anytime I go into
the back country I'd really take a few
seeds and I'd spread them around and
into the jungles and stuff just
I've had some people tell me they come
across the purple plants that I've never
seen oh okay yeah
I used to hide stuff I I I go to Hawaii
whenever I go to Hawaii I always have a
kind of a
a hunt for and I hide seeds on the
island that I give people Clues and they
go and they search them out and they
always find them that's a guy a little
treasure hunt yup yup yup it's always a
good time I always enjoy doing that and
I said anybody in the world that goes to
Hawaii can go there and get them they
usually make it worth their Wild
so that's always a fun thing to do in
Hawaii so yeah I like Hawaii that's
great that's great and uh a follow-up
from the same person who asked that
question but sort of different they were
wondering I don't know if this actually
has an answer they said do you have any
cool stories from when you did the photo
shoot of the dark Desire with Worldwide
magazine sorry weed World magazine you
know as a matter of fact no uh that was
done by a Canadian grower and
photographer uh oh cannabis is is his
name and he's the one who initiated that
whole thing I sent him Cuts uh of of
those plants because you know he and I
hit it off and just said oh here let me
help you out and you gave him that and
he grew those and then submitted it into
into uh
uh the magazine for them to print and
they ran it and
so that's
yeah and there's other references uh
there in one of the bet 100 best sativas
in the world or something like gooey's
in there uh there's a there's a whole
bunch of books and things and I don't
know it goes on and on I'm just happy to
be able to give people something to
photograph and enjoy yeah that's cool to
hear that's cool to hear we had another
listener who asked if you had any tips
on taming really sativa dominant plants
indoors
yeah I
it actually it's crazy plant like that
to grow plant lit method do the plantlet
method rather than growing full-size
plants drew a whole bunch of short
um cuttings and flower those out in Mass
create a whole carpet full of nothing
but Bud that ends up only getting about
three feet tall even on the stretchiest
stuff start out with two two inch clones
and flower them directly and even the
stretchiest plants will only get up to
about you know two or two and a half
three feet and they'll just be nothing
but Bud
lovely I love it the next question I
actually got from your Instagram page
beautifully beautifully well thought out
worded question from one of your
followers and they wanted to know how do
breeders effectively work around the
reality that genetic expressions are
constantly moving and given change
especially given changes in
environmental conditions is this
something that washes out with the more
experienced when growing in breeding
lines or are there more nuances at it
you know it depends on what you're
talking about you're breeding with it
all comes back to the selection of
genetics if you have wide based genetics
you're going to have wide-based
Expressions if you have narrow base
Expressions you're going to have narrow
Expressions come out that's just how it
is so my my biggest point I always tell
people is consistency in selection
consistency and environment and
consistency in your
methods of how you select what you're
looking for and you will always overcome
these nuancical things that can come up
yeah you can't control for an
environment that changes that's outside
so you know I always discourage people
from exclusively breeding outside it's
something you need to experience and you
need to do it
but it's not something that I think
people need to cut their teeth on I
think that it's easier to control an
indoor environment
where you are learning all those aspects
and are controlling what you're seeing
in this expressions of the plant that
you can then dependably go forward with
a breeding project that's going to give
you predictable and and Equitable
results that's just that's just it all
goes back to Simple Stuff folks you
don't make this stuff so complicated and
don't make it any more than it really
has to be but it comes back to what
you're selecting to use for your genetic
gene pool to work in Period
it's a lot of these things have the same
answer they really do
and I hate that I I hate that it's been
made to be believed to be so
uh I I it complicated there's there's
either two sets of ways of looking at
breeding from people who don't know
anything about breeding it seems like
it's an incredible
monumentous task and people who are
breeders but are lazy breeders think
that pollen chucking is the answer and
that you're going to hit it right you
know no matter what and both of those
are bad ways of looking at things you
know you that's not how you deal with it
yeah I understand where you're coming
from with that one so on to a slightly
different topic in the past we've had
some guests on who have discussed how
there's the emergence of now cannabis
specific pests like the Cannabis aphid
you may have heard of and this is just
one of possibly many cannabis specific
bugs that we're seeing come out of the
fact that cannabis has just been grown
on such large scales do you have any
thoughts on how we might try to prevent
more of these superbugs from emerging or
what can we do to combat it
boy that's a good question because you
know a breeder should be using bugs as
an indicator a breeder should be a bugs
for a breeder or something different
than they are for anybody else
um
bugs tell you
what plants are
the preferred plants before they have
the plants are ever expressed if you
have a group of plants like this this
set right here that I just showed you
the microbreeding if I go through those
there will be plants that have more bugs
because they're outside and there will
be more plants with bugs on it that
wants to have more bugs are the ones
that are going to be sharper flavors
heavier Highs but more pronounced highs
the bugs know this before they even get
to this stage and so I always tell
people pay attention to bugs if you're a
breeder because they're telling you
they're pointing away early on
uh it's pretty amazing
having said that uh when you get into
commercial stuff
uh you're you're starting to become a
real issue with uh stuff like that
in indoor crops where they can have free
reign I've always found that
if I've had a problem with something
that I needed to control natural methods
seem to be as good as
um chemical methods
as far as oh let's say you know oil on
spider mites you know tends to do the
trick better than
um
spreading poisons around that linger and
stay in and seep into the plant and you
ingest it will ultimately but no I don't
have any magic answers for that but
again I'm not the right person to ask
for that
I'm really not
that's not my job my job is not
production my job is not producing
beautiful thick plants that are going to
be sold in stores and stuff that's not
my that's not my purpose my purpose is
to design this stuff so that you can
take it and do that end of it so I'm not
the best person to ask about stuff like
that
so I mean there's another sort of
similar discussion not really similar
but uh it's somewhat related I guess in
the sense that people are talking about
male sex stability and using these males
as pollen donors and I wanted to ask you
specifically have you ever bred with
males that show some amount of female
expression or do you think that's just
shitty intersex traits shouldn't use it
I I don't I don't use them I and
whenever I see it I I even I've I've
heard all the accolades about they tend
to fail you know favor female you know
expressions and and all of that and uh
to me it's dirty genetics it's just
dirty genetics because I don't care how
good the quality is or how it is if
you've got it in a mass and you're
trying to do something
on an industrial scale we're doing that
and yeah genetic like that in there
you're ruining that whole rock or you're
tainting that whole crop or you're
influencing that whole crop and to me
getting rid of any inner
intersexing at all is so important I
have done it for years dealing with when
Guru is being developed because the tie
had a tendency to show some
hermaphrodism if it was pushed any at
all and and that would be the case I had
to breed that out of subsequent gooey
stuff because you know even in uh even
in the the later stages of growing the
pure gooey and designing the pure GUI it
was very
um much something that I had to watch
for because recesses would merge and
they would come in and then you'd all of
a sudden you'd see expressions and it
would change uh sometimes you'd see them
very early other times you'd see them
really late in Flowery anything that
displayed anything like that at all was
immediately removed from the gene pool
that's how I do it
look on that topic of removing things
from the gene pool I know that you you
end up you know not releasing a good
majority of the things you end up making
because you decide oh you're not up to
scratch if you had to put a number on it
what percentage of crosses do you think
don't make the cut for you
wow very strict I like it
oh no no seriously I'm dead serious
about that almost everything that you
see won't make it past the second the
second uh
set of tests everything out there that I
shown on Instagram and stuff is all
great first F1 material that
that you can see that particular strain
giving that particular expression but it
goes through another set of tests and
those are put through riggers for stress
for uh different
um uh types of of
uh tolerances for nutrient and stuff
like that because everybody knows I
don't like to spend money I'm cheap as
hell and so
I build in that economy into these
plants so that I get complaints all the
time about people saying that they they
my plants burn easy don't use as much
that's it they will produce just as much
with half of the nutrient and they're
designed to do that because I don't want
to spend a lot of money on nutrients and
expensive stuff when I don't need it and
I can get the same thing with half
so they're designed to be to be
sensitive like that because you don't
need that you know I'll save you money
again it's for the customer
gosh it's so easy an act of service it's
interesting you raised that point
because there's currently a discussion
on the Instagram Community about like
what is due diligence with testing and
and sort of to summarize that people are
like yeah it's all well and good if you
test your plants and get good results
but you've got to give it to the
shittest grower there is because they're
going to expose it to stuff you're not
gonna blah blah blah to me I wasn't so
sold on that idea do you think testing
things yourself and if it passes that's
good enough or do you think you really
have to stress it out a bit
great question and here's the answer
that's simple and I've already actually
touched on it again I don't use anything
but soil and cow [ __ ]
that's it so my stuff is all designed
around that basic mix because let's just
say that no one someone who doesn't know
and I've said this many times to many
people online before
that everything is geared towards the
person who doesn't know what they're
doing to still get Optimum results for
as little effort as they're going to put
into it because a lot of us know that
there's people out there that kill
plants they just kill them they kill
them with kindness they kill them with
with uh carrying they kill them with uh
um just an over sense of love and and
this is um designed for people who are
the other end of that spectrum they kill
them because they're lazy they're
killing them because they don't pay
attention to them they're killing them
because they didn't give them enough of
what it was to do what it is that's why
less less nutrients are needed and you
get the same expressions with full
plants big flowers nice resin good
flavor and it was just soil and couch
[ __ ] so I'm already designing for the
base
that you're talking about
and that people that's why I tell people
I tell you that there's people out there
that do amazing things with my stuff
that I can't even do
you know that's the other end of that
spectrum that they took it to that next
level that the plant was able to handle
and you and utilize the maximum and they
got even better than what would happen
if cow with cow [ __ ] and soil but
everything is geared towards couch and
soil so yeah I've already built in those
designs for these seeds that's exactly
what is is I'm meant to do is to make it
easy for the simplest person to get the
best results
so yeah yeah that's a
that's that that's what you do yeah and
look you just gave me a great segue
because you you spoke about people doing
really well with your work and you
reference Joel of Northstar earlier and
I wanted to bring that out quickly and
just sort of ask
I I see he does a lot of uh projects
with your lines in them and they look
great and it got me sort of wondering is
there any distinct differences between
your work like if he did a cross that
used two of your lines is that sort of
just like a gooey breeder strain in a
way yeah it is it's a let me let me let
me address that because Joel and and Jen
are just they're phenomenal people and
they really are they know what they're
doing they're good at what they do and
he's using a diverse enough genetic set
that he's making totally different stuff
than what I'm making he's going in a
different direction he does tend to have
a tendency to use some of the more
commercial stuff in his some of his
lines but not always
um and uh I just I I just really think
that he's got a different expression
up to the point where like let's call
let's just and he will say this too
dirty little secret is his one of his
most famous strains and it's actually
the one that I was speaking with with
Mark Emery talking about how he thought
that was some of the best part he's ever
tasted well that's dark desire and and
purple Mayhem and those are both mine
and Joel acknowledges that whenever he
you know somebody asked him he says well
basically it's a gooey strain you know
it's just he just maestroed it with the
masterful skill that he has into a
wonderful set of selections that he
didn't you know was able to cross and do
it but you know I I support that kind of
thing I want him to you know he I think
he was even going to keep that going
just because he wanted to have that set
of genetics because it gets so much
attention it brings so much people into
the fold they get a little bit of gooey
breeder that they've heard about and
it's he makes it much more readily
available than I do and so they get a
little bit of that but then they get to
experience his stuff and his and his
things that he's designed in conjunction
with that and and then so he benefits
from that and I think that that's just
exactly what I gave him the genetics
because they're good people uh I love
them to death and I want him to be
successful and somebody's got to carry
this [ __ ] on when I croak I mean really
I mean he's I was kind of hoping that
he'd help carry the mantle among other
breeders you know and just keep it going
and keep the brand alive
so you know but he's tired
those guys work their butts off I mean
Jen's in Philadelphia right now uh at a
show
so they're far flung they go to New
Jersey uh to go to shows and uh the last
one they tried to do there was canceled
but I mean uh you know it cost them a
bunch of money but they're out there
getting it trying to get it done you
know and and I admire that they work
well together they're a good team and I
think that they're somebody that people
ought to uh
experience more of their stuff yeah
definitely I've always looked at their
work and thought it looks really
interesting and there's unique
combinations in there and you sort of
just touched on you know yeah as a
community we've we've had some some
struggles you know with shows being
canceled things like that it affects
everyone in different ways and sort of
something I realized they were parallels
with is during covert we've also had a
sort of a cannabis plant covered in the
sense that the hot plate and virus has
really taken a Stranglehold on the
community over the past two years that
we've been dealing with covert I know
you don't bring in a lot of genetics to
your library but have you had any
experiences with it at all
nope not a thing not a thing nope very
lucky very lucky I guess a good reason
why to keep your stuff to you and don't
bring external in
well you know and I also too I I do
Harden everything so that you know it's
within itself it's very strong so that
it can withstand you know attacks and
you know when people sit there and say
oh you know it attracts powdery mildew
and stuff yeah there are some genetics
in there that are prone to that
unfortunately mom GUI in her later
periods of life has become
uh much more prone to possibly getting
it but if you control the bloom then it
it might as well not have it you know as
far as that goes and so I just figure uh
at this stage with her age and
everything and the way the
susceptibility is uh that you just kind
of gotta control it rather than try to
breed it out of it because quite frankly
there are just some things that follow
along the very desirable lines that
you're you're gonna it's gonna take a
while to breed out specifically and keep
the good stuff and yeah I've had a mixed
results with doing that with plants
where there's some stuff that you just
can't you can't get rid of and in in in
gooey stuff powdery mildew can be an
issue
now other people have had it had really
great success in mold prone environments
with their
um you know they say it's very strong
so I I you know I I can't speak to that
because I can't see it you know and
that's anecdotal at best
um so I can only speak from what I see
and that's there that's it in a nutshell
yeah sure makes sense makes sense
so I was curious I've seen you've been
posting recently about a strain called
Island fire and I remember a few years
back I grew out one of your freebies
called Island mix and it was beautiful
Australian very tropical great structure
I was wondering did the island mix
somehow make it into the island fire
nope nope that that Island fire uses the
same genetics uh that went into
uh uh the Kona sunset uh in in the pure
Kona I do believe
uh went into Island fire along with a
subset from the death grip line that was
really purple uh it had a really strong
initial feel to it like it would just
grab you and Shake you right off the bat
and then leave a very very noticeable
long-lasting Buzz to it and uh so I use
that uh and
I I I got the balance right I think
it's just a little bit hairy still Leaf
wise for me
um as a whole so I I was had hopes of
releasing that line and now I'm thinking
I'm going to refine it a little bit more
and get rid of some of the because the
best plants are a little leafy I think
for my taste and you could trim it out
and it would be fine and it's beautiful
stuff very very
distinct coloring uh towering huge colas
uh very nice but
it still needs a little more work
so it's look it's good to hear it's it's
almost there and yeah
another one of our patreon submitted
questions was they were wondering what
are the genetics behind the black rafter
and what sort of traits would crosses
with black Raptor and it bring to the
table I think they're trying to figure
out which cross is going to be best for
them
black Raptors based on uh midnight snow
and black raptor is basically a dark
midnight snow but it has a definite uh
heavier feel to it it's really aromatic
uh the flavors are along the same lines
but the the Raptor's a lot heavier
um and I use the uh people might
remember a lemon purple male that I had
that was just about black
uh and a beautiful
sunning kind of a expression of coal a
black Cola really long I love that plant
as far as that goes and it is that that
plant I crossed with
a
midnight snow dark desire
old Mendo Haze and gooey
and that made the flavor really
pronounced and really heavy as far as a
bright in your face kind of a of a
flavor and then use them the male purple
uh lemon purple in and mix with that and
then that one was the father of the
black Raptor and it was hit to a pure
um
um midnight snow
so it set the color it set the flavor
and it just deepened the smell deepened
the the effect and midnight snow is
already around 24 I think black backer
is a little higher
but it's really a nice a nice I always
like it in the morning because it's it's
such a bright it's like it's not it's
not doesn't taste like orange juice but
it has that same effect as drinking your
glass of orange juice it's really bright
effervescent in the mouth and really
opens your eyes and gets your day going
oh lovely lovely another interesting uh
sort of genetic component I'd seen you
working with was the cinnamon that
caught my eye I'm like such a die-hard
cinnamon fan I was just wondering what
genetics are in that and is it truly
cinnamon
no no no it is not and the cinnamon
actually came not from The Taste but it
was described as cinnamon from the look
and color that it would come from
because it had a lot of Amber to the
resin right off the bat and so it was a
cinnamon color bud when you kind of
dried it and and got it ready but the
smell and taste were very bright uh very
floral
um kind of unique uh I I I really
enjoyed it and I do not remember where
the cinnamon came from I
it's I I had had that thing for years
and years and years and I don't remember
what its genetic makeup was or where it
came from it might have been given to me
um but no it did not it wasn't a
cinnamon profile and the flavor but God
darn it looked like cinnamon colored you
know with that
beautiful especially when you made Ash
out of it you you'd think it was
cinnamon there was that it was that dark
it was just under the wow of course
cinnamon no that's a resin so yeah
that's where the cinnamon came from
that's cool I love it when Australians
have like a sort of cool backstory to
them like that that's that's really neat
I was wondering I love to ask every
guest this question what seeds is gooey
excited to pop next
here's the deal uh
I I have a backlog of eight years right
now I've trimmed off two years I had ten
at the beginning of this year I've I've
cut down to eight years of backlog
and I make seed every year I don't know
how many different kinds I make it
depends on the year and what up what
it's for but you know if I'm doing stuff
for clients or something like that I'll
go ahead and I'll keep a portion of
those for my own use and that's always
agreed upon
um and I always tell them I won't be
releasing this in and of itself I'll
just be using it in genetic research so
uh uh I've got about eight years of
stuff with their stuff that I have never
mentioned and I have never told anybody
I've had yet just because it hasn't come
up
um it just it just hasn't come up and
and what I thought I'd do is I'm going
back to that old
working on this three foot area of space
to clean up I'm I'm dealing with a small
set of genetics and refining those and
getting those out to people and then I'm
going to be moving into this next stage
and doing and so people will see less
from me during that interim period and
I'm trying to avoid that so that's why
I'm working on the sets of genetics I am
the black lines those kinds of things
I'm working on those to be able to to
have something to tide people over while
I get this next set of things ready and
we'll see how far how many times I could
do this before I end up Six Feet Under
look I think you'll be around for a
while longer and we're all grateful for
that
one hopes one hopes well thank you and
you're very kind no certainly I think I
Echo the sentiment for everyone
um it's interesting because we've sort
of briefly touched on it a few times
throughout the episode but a lot of
people do complain it's sometimes hard
to get their hands on your work and I
guess the question becomes how do you
deal with banks do you wait for them to
approach you or you do you approach them
how does a breeder work in the current
landscape
oh well how breeders work is a different
question than how I do it and and and
and and I'll tell you right now I work
with a set of reps and I let them deal
with with distribution and everything
like that once I turn it over to a rep
it's their gig they can do whatever they
want however they want to do it as long
as they you know you highlight the brand
in a positive light as it should be
unless it doesn't deserve it if it
doesn't deserve it I want the rest to be
able to feel that and then say hey look
out for this or he told me this or
because it does this we're going to give
you free this as a replacement to make
sure that you the customer are taken
care of and and so that kind of attitude
pervades everything that and so I don't
know uh you know
uh
I think I'm smoking gooey again
hit that one hit that one I love it I
love it
oh well
my wife is saying that it's about time
that's perfect
oh it was wonderful
yeah look I had I had one final question
for you that I was interested to hear
your take on outside of mom GUI there's
been a variety of different pure guis
and various sort of recombinations of
GUI which one is the most standout in
your mind
now again that's a weird question as far
as are you talking about other things
like there's an old goo
that comes from Santa Cruz that has been
around since the 70s and it's
different than gooey it's not it's not
gooey it's different now whether people
are still using that goo or not
um it has been described to me as being
really similar really similar I have
never
um
had it tested or anything like that
because sometimes you know we'll we'll
genetically test things to see if
they're related like you know somebody
was questioning after gooey and they
have shown that in subsequent tests that
Mom GUI is is the the mother
um so but that hasn't happened with uh
other goo strains since there's a lot of
people that name stuff you know they
don't they don't know you know what I
mean that uh especially the newer
breeders and whatnot
they don't bother to look up and see
what's active online or what's been
around a long time they'll just name
something something and then it gets its
own little traction and stuff going and
you know you have to be aware of that I
I think that's one of the fun things
that people can count on with Canada
Exotics and and this stuff is that this
genetics has been around a long time and
it has a long
history that people can follow and and
and that seems to be lacking in the
other kinds of Expressions that you're
speaking to you know you don't find that
history to be able to to you know Avail
yourself up and that makes a difference
so I I kind of tend to just fall back on
that whatever whenever people ask me
about other variations or other uh
materializations of something like that
I just kind of fall back on only what I
know and go from there yeah okay
brilliant and do you have time for one
last Quick One
sure so I would be interested to hear
what's your thoughts on how legalization
has turned out versus how you thought it
would go
oh well yeah I actually always thought
it would be a lot more uh streamlined
and uh
I knew that there was always going to be
a little bit of contention and a little
bit of of societal
um unrest around it as you transition
from a something that's been
traditionally illegal it always has been
and always was prospected to be that is
going to be illegal because it was
deemed bad you know War on Drugs kind of
thing that kind of stuff and then it uh
uh it started to shift and legalization
now I kind of think has gone and swung
the pendulum the other way too far where
it's over regulated it's over controlled
um over taxed over
um over produced and over bread with
too many holes in each of those systems
with different stuff falling through all
the time I think a more measured
um
type of
method needed to be used I think the
Genie's out of the bottle now and we've
got to kind of adjust to what we have
and correct the wrongs that are you know
present in the system now
because I think it's just a learning
curve I don't think we've ever been here
before and we don't you know we didn't
you knew kind of how Society was going
to go you just didn't know
which direction and how far how fast
and now we're seeing all of that right
now and I kind of just tend to think
that cooler heads will prevail
eventually and and and it'll settle in
we have a a plan with the legal material
that I'm trying to get set up where
we're going to provide
genetic stock for Vineyard people that
are wanting to convert a portion of
their land over and you know we want to
provide those
genetics and a consistent multi-year
contract kind of a thing and uh
we're you know you have to bounce in to
the system that's set up
with the reality that of what the future
may hold and the future may hold a very
low price you know and so all of our
pricing is based on 275 dollars a pound
and you're still able to do you know
make a good living uh on that kind of
number right now right now it's nowhere
near that here but it's nowhere near
where the Apex of how it used to be uh
you know over four thousand a pound it's
over near that either and a lot of the
people that got into the industry when
that was going on that was their target
they thought they were going to see it
was going to stay like that forever and
that's just not real so I think that the
pendulum is going to end up you know
being in the middle and we'll be okay
but uh uh until we vacillate through
this stuff and get and work back and and
all the entities that are against it
have their say and all the ones that are
for it Heather say you're I think we're
in for some tumultuous years
I really do I think the intelli gets all
settled and it gets normalized in the
federal government goes ahead and and
normalizes things and has one consistent
set of laws for it and they're governed
by the whole United States then you'll
see then you'll see you know real
progress until then fractionalization
and stuff like that are really an
impediment really an impediment
some wise words there for sure
I think that just about brings us to the
end of things gooey were there any
comments or shout outs you wanted to
make
I just really want to thank everybody
that just bothers to give this old guy a
listen I really appreciate your time I
appreciate your support I appreciate
your patronage and I really want to tell
each and every one of you that your
garden is as important to me as my own
and I will always promise to give you my
very best and I hope that you'll allow
me to enjoy
the fruits of your labor by maybe giving
me a a a look-see at what you've
produced and show people and uh I'm
always always open to criticism I would
much rather hear people's negative
thoughts and stuff about material
because I learned more from that and at
this stage in my life I like to learn
more I really want to do the best I can
and the only way I can do that is with
your help so I really appreciate you I
thank you and I care very much about
each and every one of you
a beautiful sentiment there again from
the head honcho of counter Exotics so
again huge thank you gooey for coming on
the show sharing your knowledge a bit of
history and we hope to see you again
thank you very much and appreciate you
having me and I I enjoyed my time thank
you so much for letting me blather on
[Music]
there you have it gang
some wise words from one of the best in
the industry gooey breed I thank you so
much for coming on the show again we're
so grateful for when you stop by and
share your knowledge what do you all
think I thought it was great
as usual we want to give a huge shout
out to our sponsors there's seeds here
now best seed bank in the game
go grab it
likewise proper biological systems thank
you so much for everything you do
without your amazing predatory bugs our
Gardens would be so much harder to keep
clean check out the yakip RM or the
spydex vital to Absolute Hitler products
that will help your garden to be
successful
shout out to Pro mix for their pro-mix
connect best mycorrhizal product in the
game increase yields resins cannabinoids
turpins whatever you're after it's
probably going to increase it check it
out guys
Charlie's cannabis number one spot in
Oklahoma if you need fire of any sort
they got you back
remember Charlie's your bird
last but not least thank you to the
patreon gang we love you
without you the show really couldn't
happen
if you want access to episodes early
additional interviews unheard content
giveaways and more check out the patreon
www.patreon.com
[Music]
I'll see you for the next one game
we'll see you
[Music]