hello and welcome my friends for another
episode of the podcast a cannabis
podcast for budding enthusiasts as
always you're joined here by your boy
heavy days coming at you from the upside
down library and on this one we want to
give a massive shout out to our
incredible sponsors who helped make the
show happen C now your number one seed
bank in the industry a guarantee on
satisfaction not just germination with
all the breeders and the latest drops
why would you go anywhere else if you
finish a grow and you're not satisfied
with the end product hit them up they'll
make it right they only stock the
highest quality breeders and I know they
got some fire packs from your boy heavy
days there check them out before they're
gone guys massive shout out to C1 now
your number one stop for all your
genetic needs but in order to get your
garden pumping on all cylinders and
producing the best crop to date you got
to make sure your rooms dialed in to do
that check out our friends at Pulse
sensors Number One sensors and
integrated hubs in the game measuring
all of the variables PPD VPD temperature
humidity du Point all the extra
variables you don't consciously track to
help ensure your next crop is the best
to date whether you're running a single
tent a single room or a multi-state
operation pulse sensors are the number
one in the game and they've just
recently released the pulse Hub a
central unit to integrate all of their
monitors to make sure that your rooms
are the best they can possibly be
massive thank you to pulse sensors we
appreciate you so
much likewise you got to keep your
garden Pest and pathogen free and to do
that you got to check out our friends at
copit these guys are the world leaders
in Sustainable biocontrol Solutions for
pests and disease if you're battling
spidermites check out their new spidex
vital plus sachets these are new pillis
breeding sachets that release predator
mites into your crop consistently over a
period of several weeks providing you
with sustain gained spidermite control
now you don't have to spread carrier
material through your garden just to
introduce predator mites just hang the
sachet on your crop let the person
millist walk out and do the work for you
trust me guys you don't want to have to
go up against a spidermite infestation
without spidex vital plus these are
truly the best predators in the game I
promise once you use it you'll see the
quality you'll never go back massive
shout out to copit likewise you got to
check out our friends at Organics alive
if you're growing
organic and want to use high quality
powdered organic fertilizers you simply
cannot go past Organics alive these guys
truly walk to walk and talk to talk they
have been picking up cups left right and
center with Growers all around the
country sweeping categories using their
products that is the ultimate Testament
in my opinion if homeowers are winning
competitions using their products the
proof is in the pudding guys no matter
what stage of the plant cycle you're at
veg transition flour in need of
micronutrients or a very specific sort
of boost in late flower they've got it
you got to check out Organics alive guys
truly one of the best in the industry
we're super stoked to be working with
them because we know how amazing more
products are us in heaps of breita
gardens that we have on the show again
check them out Organics alive massive
thank you massive shout out for
supporting the
show finally a massive shout out to the
entire crew at dap these guys make some
of the best vaporizers on the game I'm
really passionate about this one because
they help me to get off combustion and
smoking bongs if you have any concerns
about your respiratory health or Heck if
you just want to try a different mode of
ingestion maybe try to get a better
flavor hit you've got to check out the
DAP these guys units are cheap they're
incredibly welld designed and most
importantly they're very customizable
you can take your Vape game to the next
level getting insane turps all while
retaining the potency you'd expect of a
combustion or a bong truly I was smoking
bongs for over 10 years I'm now Vape
only massive shout out to DAP they're
one of the best in the industry and we
owe them a massive thank you shout out
again dyat massive thanks for supporting
the
show finally a quick little mention to
Our patreon Gang truly the lifeblood of
the show if you want to get early access
to episodes unheard and unreleased
interviews as well as going in the
running to get amazing genetics each
month and fortnite come on check out the
patreon at
www.patreon.com
thee
we do live smoke with heavy sessions
every fortnite and give away heaps of
Swag every month come check it out we
love you the patreon gang thank you so
much we are so
appreciative so on today's episode we
got a special one joined all the way
from Europe a real connoisseur grower
Keeper of the A5 C5 hashplant has so
much more a hashish Enthusiast and
Keeper of the flame
massive thank you to Yo Sammy for coming
on the show
today here to talk all things Dutch
history
hashish cannabis culture
breeding and so much
more without further
delay let's get into
it all righty gang a big welcome back to
another episode and on today we've got
an old school European head a
preservationist keeper of the A5 C5 hash
plant Haze and so many more a big thank
you to Y semi Sam for coming on the show
today thank you good night my time
pleasure to be here it is great to have
you on my friend first question we love
to ask people what have you been smoking
on today well hashes so I like Hashi so
mainly I uh I smoke hashes and it's
getting a you know a nuisance to uh um
you know tap into the broader varieties
as before you know that's a little
bit something that that I do not like
about the evolution so there's less
quality import but there's still you
know good things to find so I mainly you
know smoke spliffs actually like the
Europeans do you know tobacco hand roll
um joints uh with a lot of hashes and so
that's what I talk talk mainly but now
in my stash weed wise is Mexican Haze um
the shortcut Variety and the New Horizon
Haze some A5 and some nabl Haze that I
keep around sadly the bandaid Haze 7 is
just finished because that's actually my
favorite
one you read my mind I was going to say
is that because the first J to go empty
is the best yeah yeah yeah it's really
good it's really good nc5 of course also
you know usually the best things are
smoked
first so
I love that I I before we touch on some
of those incredible strains you just
mentioned I want to quickly loop back
you mentioned talking about hash and how
the cultures changed a bit what sort of
varieties of hash would you still feel
represent that narrow Leaf drug type are
there any of the uh you know Imports
that still have that old world
effect well it's hard to access them now
because uh yeah you know like the
smuggling uh in these day and ages it's
not an easy thing okay when you for
instance for me the best hashes I ever
sampled was a
nepales dry sift from high up the
mountains there you know it was like uh
it blew everybody's mind that stuff get
you so high you smoke it it was like you
know it obliterated your tolerance also
but it was really nice to smoke you know
and taste and everything so it was like
a candy it was like a treasure okay and
um we don't get that anymore so but uh
hash types like that they have that lld
high too you know what I mean so
Moroccan is different each has their own
unique s so they're very they have a lot
of character that's why I like Hashi so
much so my first joint I ever smoked was
also Hashi because I like the smell of
that came from it okay they were totally
I never was interested in cigarettes
because uh they didn't you know like
smell so nice but as a teenager I I
smelled has shees and I was like wow
this stuff you know like maybe want to
try and yeah I did and it was yeah
revelation of course then you get high
for the first time and the whole world
Paradigm changed so uh but for me it was
mainly hasis it still was and the the
weed the ganja of course I also
appreciate very dearly but uh it's like
a different league so to speak
okay that that's really beautiful what a
what a cool experience to have been able
to try that nepales hash and I'm sure
many others over the years out of
curiosity do you find yourself like
interest interested in more modern
representations of hash so like maybe
from the Band-Aid Haze the A5 the C5 or
do you feel the magic really lies in
those Tera coming from the
equators why you then you are comparing
apples and oranges so to speak you know
what I mean because import hasis it's
from a yeah it has a very different
connotation than a one strain uh um
extraction so to speak okay which
doesn't mean it cannot be nice but it's
like a infused rocket it's very uh
onedimensional you only get this kind of
type of variety high so it's boost up
and it's really nice so it's really pure
and everything I think concentrates are
also really fantastic especially for the
Met uh people like oils and ures also
but in terms of smoke smoking like well
if you have nldd cultivar D cultivar
like that they're really strong if
you're going to concentrate that [ __ ]
and smoke it wow here seriously good
luck with that okay so it's like good
for once in a while I think things like
that but you know I'm not opposed to it
but I'm not in I'm not a fan of it I
don't smoke it daily you know I do
occasionally do a dab but I'm not really
so I like my type of smoking let's say
because I'm used to it it's more like a
traditional embedded in our culture here
so to speak
okay yeah sure and you know when when
you're trying some of these like you
know land race origin hash
do you ever find that you get an effect
that's quite different to say um the
varieties of flow that on offer so like
for example a lot of sativas people
think of them as either racy or like
clear and stimulating do you feel like
the hashish from various different
places can offer like a different
dimension yeah absolutely oh yeah it's a
different they're different Realms and
the that's the beauty of cannabis as a
whole actually so it's such a diverse
univer universe actually you know like
you have ganja you have Hashi you have
like you know you can do so many things
with these plants there are so many
varieties so there's uh yeah variety is
the spice of life so it's like hard to
compare Moroccan hasis for instance like
the top quality to nepales or Kashmir or
Afghani or like we used to get also
Turkish and lebanes and so it all got
diminished a little bit because of
geopolitical yeah things and um it's a
sad thing I hope in the future with the
change of the legislation with is now
first and foremost aimed that of course
ganja and everything comes with it the
cultivating and such but in time I hope
it will spread further to the countries
where these hashes is traditional still
being made and we can access it again
because you know for me that's the true
richness and the epiphany of cannabis
for me personally because it has this
character that you don't find in modern
extracts not to saying that they're bad
or something it's just like you know
it's a different League of of getting
high let's say okay and also I smoke
with tobacco so it's a Milan more so I'm
like a smoker you know we like to smoke
so it's not that be like dabbing you you
it's different thing you know like you
you also smoke but you know in
obliterates it's more direct let's say
and we enjoy the smoking Also let's say
okay so uh it's a it's a different
approach and different uh
yeah methodology to to to get high from
Cannabis so to speak okay so we like our
hash and mainly that's why the reason
why um we smoke with tobacco because it
was like that back in the day you just
you know when the tolerance system in
Holland started it was only Hashi there
was no indoor grown weed so they did it
to separate the market from soft and
hard drugs because the heroin um plague
uh that was across Europe back then well
it cost a lot of young people's lives
and so the Dutch were then um separating
the market to try to fight
the um heroin traffic better and they
were very successful but with that came
the import hasis that was mainly the
thing here in Holland okay and from
there it then grew further into kanja
cultivation and actually it got
completely upside down a little bit
so it's kind of crazy how things can
evolve over over 40 years of time let's
say okay or 50 wow what an evolution
look let let's come and touch on the
tolerance system in a moment but I just
want to quickly loop back and ask you
for anyone who's interested you know
there's lots of our listeners who still
visit Amsterdam and Holland regularly
what would you say is your general
hierarchy of the hash that's currently
available is there still generally speak
like for example would you say oh you
know most of the African hash you get is
generally not the highest quality like
how would you describe the current state
of the landscape for anyone who wants to
come to Amsterdam and maybe try some
hash well for for my experience at least
so I'm just like I'm not really um
somebody that goes fishing in coffee
shops for Hashi I have my connection so
to speak and you know the the the top
qualities usually reside more in like
smaller quantities know so they cannot
put it for sale because it's just so
they only have like uh limited access to
this kind of material and so um the sad
thing is that I found that all Tibetan
made hasis and also Indian like Kashmir
and everything also turkeys like
libanese it Al it vanished so we are now
only having uh Moroccan varieties there
is also a big change there of course
with the modern cultivar that are being
imported there so it's still TR
traditional made and hasis but they
don't
use the necessarily the old cultiv from
um back in the day so to speak okay so
there's also a little bit of change in
that but you know great Hashi is like
it's like it gets you high in a certain
T it's very nice to sit around with you
know like people smoke and have some tea
and you know like talk and discuss about
life philosophy it a little bit it's
more that vibe that it's important okay
and also the taste and everything so uh
um in coffee shops you know it's hard to
really determine the quality I don't you
know I don't visit them so much so I
can't really assess their quality so
much what I do know is that import
hashes is like in the background now
it's all modern Hashi okay whether it's
isolated or whatever and usually they're
also made not from the traditional
cultivar it's like these modern extracts
and so the market in that uh sense has
changed lot okay but um for me
personally as a hash favorite from the
hash countries well it's not so a great
Evolution but of course we still have
the great ganja so you know one must not
complain and uh you know be happy with
what we still got and try to increase it
in the future as good as we possibly
can a I love that what a beautiful
sentiment and a few questions ago you
mentioned the tolerance system in
Holland and how that sort of played out
over the years how would you give an
overview of the scene currently how
would you describe the Amsterdam scene
to people as it is
now well the Amsterdam scene I so I come
from the south of Holland and so I was
more like secluded from the Amsterdam
scene
because yeah what we had here with this
hazes and these Hashi people well so we
we we went frequently to Amsterdam
because it's a nice city to go to okay
and of course we did some coffee shops
but usually the gear that was in our
pocket we found Superior than the gear
that they were offering because yeah
it's a little bit of a Commerce thing
there but there are still nice so in
Amsterdam was always nice things to be
found and it's like yeah you know it was
the capital of cannabis let's say for
many many years about the whole world
was still uh repressing cannabis very
hard the Dutch were the only one to like
yeah like I said tolerate it because to
protect actually their youngsters from
uh getting killed by other mean drugs
you know what I mean and um it was a
good thing but yeah over time it changed
a lot so now with the legislation Chang
in America of course you had this um
wave of like tsunami of more North
American strange the cushies and the
cakes let's say that kind of
um yeah come flooding there and uh yeah
it's a popular thing here also so for
the youngsters it's like this now so the
market is in continuous flux also so
it's always is something new and so the
these Hypes will eventually blow over
and uh you know cannabis I think it's
more for the people also it's for the
broad people I hope as many it's it must
be accessible to all you know what I
mean and that's a good thing but I mean
uh the true passionat let's say well
they they always steer to the quality of
things and not so much the Hypes and
they stick around of course over the
years and that's how it
is yeah that's awesome to hear and I
mean would you say in general that uh
the majority of the people involved in
the the scene SL the industry in Holland
are more of the old school sort of he
nature and they're they're looking for
those older effects or is it like most
places in the world where there's still
quite a a strong majority of people who
are into the more newer modern hype sort
of stuff well you know the Amsterdam
Market wasn't so purely Dutch actually
you know for instance a lot of uh people
from other countries are there establish
themselves there to work work this plant
and to you know be a part of the
community that later evolved to become
an industry you know I mean like Neville
also did his work in Holland Sam the
skunkman brought the seeds to Holland
you know I mean everybody came to
Holland and so Amsterdam was actually a
metropolitan that attracted various
people from over the whole world okay to
work this plant and so there are only
few really Dutch people that do this
also that still reside from back in the
day before actually the indoor um ganja
St seen and the coffee shop uh uh Market
exploded okay and there are still uh
Dutch people in Amsterdam but I wouldn't
call Amsterdam uh you know like purely
Dutch in that uh P persp perspective in
terms of uh who works plants there and
who provides weed to people okay it's
more like an international Collective
there and there are a few people from
Amsterdam that kind of um um represent
the um more d kind of approach to it
let's say okay and the hazes and
everything incorporates with it because
yeah it's the Cradle actually of the
modern hybrids more or like the hybrids
from before where the modern hybrids are
made from so Amsterdam is more like yeah
like I say a metropolitan for you know
it it magnetized a lot of people
throughout the world for years to come
to this city to you know to be involved
in the Canabis because they also love
getting higher so it's like this and so
it got like a uh a brewery a mix of
great people that coming about and like
you know like really uh try to grow good
wheat and enhance the Jean Pool and
whatnot so you know it's a good thing
but that goes for the whole of Holland
Amsterdam is the heart of it you know
you have also rdam and then the Brant
area and the South limberg and Sealand
where actually also a lot of people and
you have coffee shops there so you know
but Amsterdam has this alluring thing to
it because it's the capital of Holland
and it's a nice cozy City you know I
mean coffee shops it's renowned okay so
it's a good thing but I wouldn't call it
necessarily only Dutch this approach
there in Amsterdam considering the
Cannabis Market if you want more Dutch
you have to you know go into the country
and maybe go to the South or to the
North and then you have a a better
Assumption of what truly Dutch coffee
shops are and what they serve okay I I
must say because um you know I I
encountered these ha so cannabis came
into my life in the late 80s mid to late
80s and then I got in touch with Haze in
like 903 in the early '90s and when I
first smoked my haze joint in 93 I was
yeah so impressed by it I was like I
want to have this okay what is it and I
want to meet these people who are like
who are what so you know it was so from
that day on I was into Haze and so there
was no rival to it so to speak so we
kept it also in a in a tight group of
people in a tight crew because it wasn't
so uh widespread available let's say but
I really felt for the haze and so what
else emerged from um other cannabis I
followed up on it and uh but once you
like I started cultivating ha 93 also
and so when you start cultivating plants
like this these old hair looms and you
try another variety you're like not bled
by it at all so you kind of you ditch it
and we stay to the haze like loyal true
Haze
Freaks and so nothing else could compare
so whatever the story about the white wi
is I don't know you know I don't know
and so but ingamar plays a part in it I
think a very big part and so I think
it's not a bad variety I like all
cannabis let's make no mistake so for me
all cannabis is good but I have my own
personal preference and like this MLD
kind of thing first it was the old
hairloom that I encountered and from
from there my knowledge also grew and I
got uh yeah interested in the nldd and
the the more psychoactive tropical
varieties okay because these plants yeah
they have character they're jungle
plants okay they're not like these yeah
uniform more tweaked plants to I don't
know so it's a different leak so I go
for the jungle plants any and every day
it's like my personal preference
I love that what a beautiful sentiment
um I'd love to ask you you know you just
mentioned it what are some jungle
varieties as you put it uh you might
recommend to people who are looking to
expand their Petes but have only ever
really had sort of more modern
representations of Canabis
M well yeah that's that's you know when
you start growing these other varieties
and you have to go to Hay well usually
they don't well that's a totally
different league so they normally they
Tred once or twice and then they ditch
it because like yeah they're not used to
like having these jungle plants around
so you know if you if you want to
cultivate wheed or you're like a real
passionist and you usually go for the
varieties you want you prefer yourself
and for me it was the haze so the first
seeds I sprouted was actually skunks it
was
1991 and so then I moved to Spain for a
little while and there was not any
marijuana there not anything so I had to
grow my own to have some because it was
all hashes there also and so I was in
favor because back then we had some good
grass here in the coffee shops in
Holland too but um not the haze and when
I encountered the haze I was like so
blown away by it I wanted to you know uh
smoke it and I then smoked so much of it
that these people kind of said man
seriously you take so much maybe you
should grow some and that's how it then
eventually uh I became then a cultivator
of these varieties and it's hard to go
back you know I mean like we have a
personal preference I like these plants
so much the other plants don't impress
me so much not to say that they are not
nice but cultivation is like yeah I that
you I I just love to tame these wild
beasts you know and get them into life
it's it's it's fantastic but it takes
longer and a lot of more care and so a
lot of cultivators they also want to
more guarantee their um result so to
speak so then um the modern varieties
well they're easier to grow so you have
more like um and they don't take so long
so in that kind of aspect I can only you
know I encourage any dja growing no
matter what strains they put under the
light or the Sun for that matter even
better so all marijuana is good to me
but uh personally I would recommend to
try some um of these great ganja plants
these Queens they're really
special I love it what a beautiful
sentiment I guess one of the questions
we do get from our listeners very often
is they're sort of after like
recommendations and the the question I
hear a lot is that there are people who
are Keen to sort of dip their toes in
the waters of the nld varieties and
they're like look you know I'm happy to
run something that goes a bit longer I
just want to experience the feeling that
you know describe on the show do you
have anything that you might be able to
recommend that's like 100 days or
less yeah well it depends on personal
preference also but if you want to have
a haze then you should grow a proper
Haze I think what's available on the
market well there are a lot of people
that doing nice uh small things let's
say okay it's more like in the realm of
the people that really have heart for
cannabis you know when your
industrialize
um this our you know passion let's say
you lose something also a little bit
that's only normal I'm not opposed to
anything U but you know when you work
100,000 plants or you work 100 well it's
a world of difference let's say okay
it's like with making wines or like the
the finest things of Life Cuban cigars
you name it okay single m whiskies
whatever Champagnes U whatever you want
there is finesse in in everything okay
if you want
then you have to grow it and so these
hair looms represent it but there are
many other land races for example you
like the tie which actually I think it's
more coming from LA or something okay
that's also debatable but anyway we all
have our personal preference okay and uh
if you can cultivate that well then you
have what you want and so it's it
depends what you want okay so
um yeah with like super silver is still
around mango ha I personally find mangu
ha is one of the better varieties and
they are also a little bit more uh easy
to grow and um so the wildness the Vigor
is a little bit um less so they're more
practical for like the average grower so
to speak you know and it's a nice
variety I think I like it very much in
High and um things like that I would
recommend and also of course the things
that I'm working on myself you know with
uh what I do now is collaborating with
the original dumping coffee shop in
Holland to make some uh small breeds and
then offer some uh some unique lines to
the to the public you know to access and
to be able to grow them but they will be
also around 100 days give and take it
depends on the phenotype I like them
wild so I like my seeds to be like the
authentic thing that can have also this
um uh VIP in to them like from the hay
side you know what I mean that's what we
all aim about to enhance enance the haze
or like to preserve it as good as we can
this high this feeling okay because it's
a certain unique vibe to it you can't
explain it's more deep let's say Okay
than any other um high it's a sativa
hybrid or like an nldd hybrid variety
and so what it is it's debatable but
it's clearly like fire okay we all agree
on it and once you love it well you want
it and so but there are Tibetan
varieties for instance that are also
really nice also but yeah you have a
land race variety growing indoors well
it will change okay you so to have a
harsh cultivar in a harsh uh environment
in the you know in the mountains of
Tibet while there it thrives let's say
if you take it out or from SE and it s
here and you put it in you know under
indoor conditions well you get a totally
different expression in it and it's
therefore not necessarily better okay so
but on what's on the market you know I
uh you know look at to the passion I
would always say you know like uh and uh
they're nice things on the market I
think the genan pool by people that are
preserving plants and you know bringing
them what they preserved uh making it
available so it enhances the gene pool a
lot and that's uh something very
important I think towards the future you
know like cannabis is going to
revolutionize the world because this
plant is so versatile it's amazing so we
need to the broader Humanity needs to
educate itself a little bit more but it
will come and uh the interest grow and
that's a good thing but like the
immaturity of like the market it's some
sometimes saddening okay and that
implify also like things so everything
is in continuous flux like I say so
things evolve and now we have this
latent hemp thyroid that is uh also a
nuisance actually because uh a lot of
things are being shipped worldwide now
and so this latent hemp thyroid it's not
really detectable for the average grower
let's say but once it's in your plant
and you utilize the same scissors for
instance to for you get an infected
plant and you're not aware of it while
it infect your whole library in a year
time you can throw it away and so there
are a number of people in the industry
that's uh putting their heads into the
sand and don't want to hear about it but
it's a real threat okay and we should
really pay attention and educate
ourselves and um you know to keep it
free because this viid well it's a
Potential Threat to uh to certain
varieties okay and if we uh don't make
the good precautions it could be a
threat okay since everything is sent
abroad and not being checked well I see
a lot of plants that are infected and
yeah so there's a big discussion and
people are not aware of it it's the AIDS
of plants and it's kind of like the
similar vibe to it like it's like a
taboo almost okay no it's not it's a
reality and you know it needs simple
precautions you just need to clean your
tools with bleach and then you know you
can Safeguard it but uh so if you have
uh things sent to you I would say to
everybody in the Cannabis industry pay
attention Okay because it can ruin your
partials and uh endang endanger
preservest and preservation towards the
future
okay wow I feel like you must have uh my
list of questions you just touched on so
many great talking points we'll have to
loop back on several of them but I mean
while we're on the topic the hopl envir
does certainly seem to have sort of died
down out of the mainstream Zeitgeist and
discussion and feels like it's sort of
like a bit out of sight out of mind
what's what is the state of things like
in the EU at the moment from your
perspective and what's your sort of
biggest fear in regards to the viroid CU
I I too share similar concerns yeah the
problem is that well in most European
countries the official legislation to
cultivate Recreation on cannabis is
still not implied so we're still waiting
on it and it's only uh like the medical
Market that can do it that means that we
cannot lab test our equipment you can uh
in Holland is available but it's quite
expensive okay and so a lot of people
don't do it but so there are a lot of
things getting shipped worldwide now and
so it's a Potential Threat and it's
that's why I want to talk about it
because uh people don't want to hear so
much about it and so it's a it's also
like powderly Milo and other things it's
visual so you can assess it immediately
or like spider knes or any other pest
well this viroid not so it's like you
know you think this plant is healthy and
then it deteriorates over like a half
year say when it put it under vetch then
you will see it but then it's too late
especially if you make seeds with it
because you send it worldwide to make
seeds well its progy will contain at
least 30% of it of the seeds will be
also um containing this thyroid
potentially also infecting again other
cannabis uh Gene pools and genomes and
so it's important we keep that a little
bit in check okay especially if we're
going to revolutionize the world with it
well we have to you be prudent about it
okay let's say it's not like uh it's
just a p as any other but rinsing your
tools for instance with some bleach it
takes a little bit more effort than time
maybe but it's well worthwhile okay to
keep everything a little bit healthy so
it's like with any other organism right
if you truly love it you want to be able
to that it's you know in the best
condition as possible and so it's not to
be something underestimated and I see uh
in the industry from top to Z to bottom
let's say people in it that uh you they
preferably not not want to talk or they
say our plants are got clean while I'm
like you know yeah so I'm just giving
out the shout out to everybody like hey
pay attention to this viroid because
seriously okay it's a threat and that's
it uh hopefully um you know we can keep
it out of our Gardens as good as we
possibly
can yeah certainly you know I think
everyone obviously you know the goal is
to try to stop it from getting into
their Gardens I guess I then wonder do
you think think this will be something
where we may be able to eventually
eradicate it or do you think it'll just
become one of those things that like
floats around in the background it's
like the flu like you get it some years
you don't other others well now I see it
as a Potential Threat if people do not
you know take this seriously to lose
some potential lines that are available
for instance because the parential once
they're infected well well we cannot
make seeds with it anymore okay or um
you can make seeds with it but then you
have to really lab test it for it
contain so there is
we have the technology to um to um
prevent it and you know to fight it it's
all here we just have to do the make the
do the necessary you know put the effort
in and not um like um be light-headed
about it or like rather not hear about
it because it's a it's a it's a thing
that seriously you know if a breeder
makes seeds and send it to people and
he's not aware of it itself that it's in
his partials well all these people
accessing these seeds will have um
plants that contain this viroids so in
that sense it's like better to um to um
prevent it than to suffer from it okay
so it just it take some prevent prevent
um uh you say like uh things to do and
then uh you know you can sleep uh sound
at night okay so it's not in your
library you just have to be uh you have
to Ren your tools properly and you have
to like um be aware about it so I would
suggest that everybody just pay
attention and educate himself or herself
a little bit about this fire to keep it
out and uh so that will ensure us that
we do not lose uh seed lines or like you
know like genotypes in the Cannabis uh
varieties that will then then be
infected and downgraded and we just have
to kill it okay it has to be
eliminated 100% 100% and hopefully you
know it is something that we are able to
eliminate in the future I want to um I
want to talk about some of your breeding
but you know what I think it'll help
first to lay a bit of the groundwork so
why don't we go back to the start tell
me a little bit about your first
experience with
cannabis yeah so the first experience
was this hashy it was at the festival I
was like uh just 16 or just not just
before I got 16 anyway we were at the
festival and so this guy was rolling a
joint I could see it I see it before but
you know it was now close and it was
somebody from my own group of friends or
like people I knew let's say the locals
but he was a little bit older and uh he
saw I was interested and so like you
know he R the joint and then he said
yeah you want to try it and so I did and
this whole festival got kind of yeah
yeah everything enhanced you know the
whole sphere and everything so it was
really brilliant and I really liked the
aroma coming from it okay so it was
mesmerizing and uh so the first
experience was a really good one and
then uh so you get interested and then I
live close at the border with Holland so
I not touch myself but I Leed over the
border that say because uh yeah the
tolerance system in Holland I really
liked okay and I wanted to get high and
all these hashes available I'm like yeah
yeah yeah this is great you know so and
uh and then uh it stayed like that and
of course also weed you know we like
both so we smoked wheat and we smoked
mainly Ash and uh the wheed back then it
was used usually skunk or skunk hybrids
uh more or less they were nice but not
really like flabber gasing nice okay but
we smoked it we smoked everything
teenagers you know how it is and then um
like I said I was a little bit older
like just before I got 20 I was sitting
in a bar it was a normal bar in some
bars in Holland you could also smoke you
know like uh sticky we call it it's like
a hand roll cigarette but a small one
not really big joint and you just like
smoke it and it was also tolerated back
then so to speak okay and in certain
bars anyway and so this guy come sitting
next to me and I knew him you know we
knew him from like going out scene let
say okay and so he said you want to try
something what are you smoking I said
yeah skunker I said yeah smoke this okay
I say what it is it said it's Haze A5
Haze so I never heard of it so I roll
one and I was like you know you always
rival each other I'm thinking this guy
okay we test it okay well I had little
drink also and really I went to the
toilet I came back I was like what's
this okay seriously I fell in love
immediately with it it was blow I never
had beat like that before okay it was
like it blew my mind in every possible
way in every positive way also so I was
like hooked from that moment and so
short after I uh you know I saw
interested and Blown Away by it so I
wanted to meet the people that offered
it and so shortly after I did and then
so I got into a whole different um group
of people that held hasis and Canabis in
a very different way than in the coffee
shop or like the more commercial scene
in Holland okay these were more also
they were older than me they were like
um the age of they were the Dutch
hippies let's say okay and more activist
also uh very politically engaged and you
know they wanted to also reform Holland
and they believed in this PL also and
the hashes and everything and tolerated
system we all always dreamed in that you
know in the early 90s that it would be
legal by 2020 at least okay like 2,000
we thought in the best case scenario and
it still it's still hasn't happened here
like what we waiting forever but anyway
this uh completely aside so I was so
blown away by it so I I I I loved it and
my friends also loved it so I was like
getting this Haze for every body okay
they were all like back in the day so
there was no competition for this weed
because this group of people I
encountered well they tapped into them
these cultivar so they were the first to
grow it to really full potential okay
and that's so then it shines and then it
becomes what it should be you know
because if you don't know how to
cultivate it well it can be a stack of
hay also so you know but these people
really were the first to you know
produce this Hast to full potential and
it was it blew our minds back then and
we fell in love and so it grew from
there and I started cultivating short
after and so um yeah it was a fantastic
time throughout the 90s there was really
a lot of Hope and prosperity and and
know looking at the future it would all
change in a in a good way and actually
you know that the legislation got
actually far worse uh with the coffee
shops booming out and so it kind kind of
got out of control a lot of French and
Belgium people and German people they
flooded the Dutch borderlines to get
their beats and hash there and so like
Europe was facing a little problem there
and so the the Dutch government got
tapped on their shoulder like hey what
the [ __ ] is wrong with you you know all
our youngsters are going buy drugs in
your country it must stop okay so they
made like crazy legislation then to
reform the Border areas while Amsterdam
and the rdam area were then in a
different kind of legislation while the
whole country was actually under the
same legislation so it's like you know
it's like the most surreal thing ever
okay you cannot nobody makes up [ __ ]
like this
okay you just got to laugh with it and
think like all right well we have to
wait a little bit longer to just like
cultivate out in the open okay but we
still do we we kept into the hobby
sphere here also for us it's a passion
it's not really s it's a lifestyle more
it's like you know it's not something we
do for to enrich
ourselves to sheare MoneyWise you know
what I mean I mean we all want
comfortable lives but that's not the aim
the aim is to get highest [ __ ]
and to benefit from it and to bring
something to the table for others that
can say hey man this is really something
unique okay and we try to maintain that
finesse and and you know it's a nce
thing it's only for the people that
really like it okay and uh well so a lot
of people also they get anxious or
paranoid from it and they kind of steal
away from it like they prefer a little
push cake it's all
good I don't
mind what an epic story so many details
I feel like we need to touch on I guess
the first one is this crew you're
talking about are they the uh the people
online referred to as the A5 crew and as
a followup did they ever tell you like
the story of getting the cutting
yeah well so these people were pasados
and uh so they lived in same area where
Neville did his first work and one of
them there were actually three people
one of them he was uh so nille and him
became
friends and because these people were in
the you know they they they were uh so
they love psychedelics let's say but
first and foremost hashes they were
really has lovers okay and uh the top
quality varieties
so these top shelf quality hasis they
also uh yeah impressed nville okay so he
smoked some of it and uh so they got
um uh acquinted more better let's say
okay by the hashes and so then they
became social to each other and so
nville actually uh provided these
cuttings also like to share them with
also to get a better uh grips on his own
breedings because these people
cultivated it to um you know to deliver
some Haze on the market and um so that
helped them also to maintain their uh uh
top quality has trade so uh it was all
kind of in that regard that there was
this exchange was being made back in the
day okay when the nille did his first
breedings and these people got handed
out uh five phenotypes of every uh breed
line and so they kept them or like more
I'm not sure of that you know how many
they actually so these people are older
than me I always kind of looked up to
them with the greatest respect they were
really nice lovely you know like regular
people that did it from their house okay
they didn't have a coffee shop while one
of them later did have but you know so
it was a different it was more a family
thing like say really a group of friends
that share things with each other but um
so they were the first to really realize
how important these plants were okay
they were also the initiators of the
preservation and then uh we in our
little Collective here and some people
also in a different part of the site
took upon themselves to safeguard it
when later in uh around the Millennium
change uh the legislation in Holland
changed so hard and these people were
targeted by uh uh justice really hard
okay and so then everything came to an
end the Glory Days and so then uh yeah
we salvaged what we could Salvage from
uh that um brutal error and uh went
underground with it okay to save God it
and preserve it for over all these years
because yeah we we always recognized the
initiators especially but we also the
smokers that you know like could tap
into it and then later cultivate it we
all recognize the sheer unprecedented
extraordinary power that resides in
these plants okay and so the high speaks
for itself the plants morphology when
you grow it and you compare it to like
other breach well it blows most cultiv
away okay but you have to know how to
cultivate them otherwise they just keep
on growing and like you have a lot of
vegetable of vegetable growth but not
really the flowers you're looking into
so it's not for everybody I guess I was
privileged and uh I'm blessed to you
know like this happened and it it was
more like a southern Dutch thing Neville
with his breeding took it later to
Amsterdam and so that was his breeding
but so the preservation of the old
clones it was done in the South by
people that really you know like love
these plants so much like I said for me
these plants are like family okay we've
been keeping them around uh you know it
initiated from the day n bre them so
it's like mid to end 80s and then later
like
1991 and then the exchanges were made
and so like from there on we kept them
around and um when uh uh justice then um
hit these people heart um yeah we took
it uh we we tried to save what was
Salvage ible and to get underground and
you know preserve it for future and we
also wanted to in our stash so we so we
love these plants you know what I mean
so so it's like yeah it's almost like
your children and nobody takes it away
okay you care for it you protect it you
uh you know it's uh it's not uh so it's
also a collective thing we cannot do it
anything like that because people get
raided or you you have pasts or like
something happens you know we all have
our lives so you know we all have our
dramas in life and whatnot so you know
by this Collective effort we are uh wow
it's been a remarkable Journey keeping
these uh hair looms now uh still into
our human reality let's say and it's a
great thing you know every time I talk
on them I'm like
yeah so it was a privilege but also a
Challenge and it's good that they are
there and so now they are made available
for a broad public and you know a lot of
people can access them better and better
in one form or the other okay and that's
a good thing that's what I for me it's
all about that preserving them meaning
also shipping them to places where you
know they have legal grounds to have you
know to be preserved for for longer than
just us these plants will be around when
we are not imagine that that's the best
case
scenario of course what an epic story I
love that I I've got to ask uh you
mentioned a few times that you've you've
made your best efforts to preserve what
was salvageable which cuting do you have
as far as I had heard it was like the A5
the C5 the hash plant Haze were there
any
others yeah there's a G13 cross to the H
A that uh we managed to safeguard thank
God
and then there is of course the
Neville's Haze it's also uh one of the
first Neville hazes ever okay that was
selected for it certain uh yeah uh
morphology and everything from back in
the day okay but like I said back in the
day it really stood out to other plants
you know like these people that love
them so much and could tap into this so
there were people around them with green
thumbs Holland is uh so the Dutch are
really good
in hyro culture let's say okay like
whatever it is okay like so they are
there University also that is really one
of the top leading universities in like
the science behind how to cultivate
crops okay and so they this knowledge
from the Dutch then and combined with
the ability to tap into the genetics
properly well so then it could manifest
it to what it was and uh so like it has
to be grown to uh to to proper to really
make it China and that's why the
commercial scene rather stay away from
it because when you [ __ ] it up well yeah
you're a half year further and you don't
have any proper return well you can only
do it twice if you [ __ ] up twice yeah
you're a year further well if you have a
big investment and you don't uh get a
return in one year you have a problem
okay so they all go for the more easy
return it's a commercial thing I can
understand it okay so Haze is not so
easy to be capitalized on except when
it's growing to with Y with people that
are really can you know that they know
what they're doing so to speak okay and
then it can manifest itself to something
really beautiful but you know like I
said it's not for everybody so it's
always a niche market let's say okay but
for me um it's one of the maybe the key
elements also that helps us enable us to
maybe you know have a little influence
now on human awareness that yeah the
hasi is okay it's all about that but
people just do not get it so much but
believe meashi is the Pinnacle of K is
okay once you really understand it you
it's like you understand it okay so
ganja is great too I mean I love it
don't so but it's a different so it's
more spiritual for me let's say okay has
a deeper level it has a something sacral
to it know something sacred and um ganja
also every cannabis
uh has it okay more or less but these
are these the ones I love they have it
in a certain higher degree that's why I
love also I love psychedelics myself too
okay I think psychedelics in the future
also will be uh very important to pave
the way uh in human uh awareness and
Consciousness because this world
seriously in this day and age people are
still beating the [ __ ] out of each other
I'm like hey maybe all smoke a joint you
know seriously and you know seriously
okay so this plant for me is like really
important to bring it uh and to uh yeah
to make it more accessible to for for
people okay no matter how they take it I
think it's a very good uh um Ally in uh
in our voy on this planed okay we need
to listen to it really and educate
ourselves and uh yeah put it more on the
foreground but yeah it's a struggle so
it's a slow process but I'm thinking
we're gaining some momentum finally
that's good I think yeah you hear
ripples about that uh sort of worldwide
currently which is good to hear that was
an epic array of plants that you know I
think these are probably the only
remaining plants that like Neville
selected himself would you agree and as
a follow-up could you give give the
listeners a an overview or a description
you know how would you describe each of
these plants they sound absolutely
legendary you know I first want to say
this
so and back in that day when these
plants were first uh created let's say
and exchanged so they were a new thing
and they were like the yeah it was like
it blew everybody away let's say okay
then like I said nille went then on so
it was more he was the breeder so for
him it was making seeds well these
people in the South well they had a
different approach okay so they embraced
these plants in a different guard that's
why they kept them secure and safe and
also secluded from um the more
commercial Realms in Holland back in
that day I mean
okay it was also these people were not
looking for any Spotlight okay they they
didn't want any green Merchant thingy
going on on them like you know they were
just wanted to smoke and get high and
like like you know have the best weed
and hush available and so
um they embrac these plants with a
different attitude so they became the
first reservist of it and then later we
took it upon ourselves to like I said
Salvage what Salvage because we also
love these plants by then so much and so
preserving these plants well it has a
different I didn't know what I actually
was preserving uh I knew that they were
uh like um Haze hybrids and uh for them
they always said that nl5 haste hybrids
were the best so like C5 A5 and nv's
haste or had the highest quality and
potential but also with the G13 and the
has plant they were nice cultivar back
then you had also Duran cross to ha
these Haze varieties and they so we lost
that also the cg13 we lost that I've we
lost here in the vicinity than the A5
due to mislabeling and uh later I hooked
up with some people that were
um
um had interactions with the same people
I had interactions with in the Centum of
the South so to speak and they were
thankfully able to preserve the A5 that
we lost and so we then were able to
preserve the AG13 the has blant ha uh
the N Haze and the C5
Haze and um yeah we kept these were the
best so they were the queens of all so
over time some hered some were like less
resilient and you know like uh so over
time a lot of things happened okay
they've been cloned so many times a key
element in like keeping them healthy for
us was also you cannot um keep plants
under artificial light continuously okay
so you have to re Revitalize them
preferably each year and so we take them
like um in the springtime here we have
an ideal veg climate late spring and uh
early summer and then we can put them
like two three months out doors in the
in soil and you know get them sun and
get them you know like in in the
outdoors so they Revitalize and then we
clone them again and take them indoors
to um be able to um keep them um vital
throughout the winter okay because they
won't survive out there and that's how
we do it and kept them in in good shape
but um the preservation of these plants
well so and usually in the Cannabis
quote unquote industry there are like
two streaks they say breeding and uh
cultivation and or okay but I think
preservation is actually the one that um
exceeds or tops these two because
preservation whether it's in seed form
or especially in plant form well it's
very you know important thing if you
have an
extraordinary hair Loom that's really
you know blows your mind let's say or
you have more of them well you want to
preserve them of course plant
phenotypical Expressions preserving like
we did is of course different than seeds
with seeds you never know what comes out
of it but it's equally important but
plant preservation well it's a living
organism you have to keep Al over all
these years and if you have a multitude
on it well it's not such an easy thing
when you're working in in a climate that
fights grows continuously and harasses
like you know and consider us to be
criminal and we're like what it's like
are you kidding me it's a plant okay
yeah and then by the way here is a
coffee shop you can buy it there so why
can I not grow it it's like a little bit
strange okay but anyway I'm not
complaining because the duts still are
tolerant towards it so like the penalty
for it it's like okay but it's changeed
also so now your house can be taken away
and stuff like that so it's not really
getting better and it's time for the
legislation to just change so that and
they have to learn from like the alcohol
uh industry you have micro breweries and
you have big ones so yeah it's each to
their own like you like you have single
Ms and that model of doing business with
fit cannabis really good I think okay
especially here in Europe but yeah they
consider it still as a a drug so it's
like I don't know what it is okay I need
they all they all need to smoke some
Haze man that's what I think and then it
will maybe get a little quicker because
seriously okay so it's a very immature
market and it's a sad thing when you're
a mature smoker in this kind of thing
okay but anyway it is what it is and
let's make something beautiful out of it
okay wow look I can can only imagine all
the effort it's taken to preserve those
cuts over the years in the climate you
describ so kudos to you my friend and I
mean on that point itself you know
you've just given us a great tip about
how to store plants longterm you know
with the revitalization we did have a
lot of listeners chime in and say you
know do you have any other tips you
might have for preservationists to help
keep Cuts around in the long term are
there any other little tips or tricks
for keeping them happy maybe in the
indoor period when you're working on the
legislation that are unfriendly then you
have to do it in a group Collective
because if you're the only one and you
get raided or whatever in the worst case
scenario or you have a pest and it dies
or something well you don't have any
backups so backups are important if you
really want to preserve a certain
cultivar you need to have it at
different locations you know even in
legal climates by the way because you
know somebody can get like the latent
hire out or what and it's not aware and
you know like so backups are important
and you know like keep them healthy you
know like don't overfeed them like and
keep them short and
like make new cuttings regularly so
everything is optimized as good as
possible I usually do like two
generations during the winter time and
then that generation uh the third will
go outside when I make cuttings so to
keep my moms as fresh and in Min
condition as possible because under
artificial light it deteriorates okay
you cannot keep plants forever happy no
matter in what soil I'm so it sinks a
little bit it gets hard I keep my moms
usually on soil not on hydro because um
I think it's a better buffer and it's
also more organic so it's a better way
and
um yeah have multiple cuttings of each
uh cultiv that you want to protect also
so not only one because if something
happens with it you lose it and so keep
good keep him happy okay so keep him
green let's say and don't overfeed I
usually like rain water for the majority
and like um uh organic fertilizer and
sometimes I've give them a little salt
like I do for hydro to give them a
little boost like when I want wanted to
make cutting for instance so then I like
letting them veg a long so I'm I do
small operations so for me cutting
making is not such a a big thing so I
can do it uh like more uh so I can keep
my things um as vital as I possibly can
and over the years yeah you accumulate
also a little bit knowledge so I keep
them also Bonsai styled I don't like big
moms because big moms will only produce
like uh possible pests you know and they
breed a lot and you know so they damp a
lot by keeping them smaller and bonsing
them and keeping them like healthy but
in a small miniature version while you
can put more plants also in uh smaller
locations so it's like a it's a
practicable thing for me as a more
hobbyist let's say okay if you have big
facilities it's like you you have to
work in these layers of frames but um
the important thing is like yeah keep
them healthy okay and don't overfeed I
see a lot of overfeeding in the business
and uh so you have to really you know
like it's better that they pay out a
little bit and you give them some extra
so you know what your dose is at least
if you're learning and um by that you
know you see also what the needs for
instance okay so it's better to
underfeed T see it and then you know um
adapt nutrients than to overfeed it and
burn it it gives stress to plants and it
tends to also uh get into the gene if
you stress out a plant too much it can
make possibly hermite on you or whatever
okay even if it's in the in the mother
plant you're stressing it okay so it's
not so good keeping your mother plants
in healthy and Min condition is the
first thing okay so that's why I say
preserv preservation comes first okay
and then from there you can you know
take cuttings and do some breing work or
whatever or cultivate or whatever okay
but first thing is keeping the parential
in M condition that's first and foremost
keeping the moms the parental stock
clean and vital first
thing yeah brilliant sentiment there I
think that's really really important and
um you know it does take some time to to
to get a Mastery on keeping those moms
long term I have to admit still
something I'm always trying to improve
on while we're on the topic of
preservation I wanted to quickly ask you
you know a topic that regularly pops up
when we're discussing like some of these
older World genetics especially in the
context of stuff that's still on offer
today is this idea that you know maybe
some of the older um Amsterdam or
dutch-based cannabis companies have lost
some of their mothers over the years and
and they get replaced with different
things you know is this something that
you have experienced yourself and do you
think there are like any companies on
the market like that are still offering
sort of that real original old school
authentic
stock well because I have my select
Niche interest Market I do not really
access these kind of seats so I wouldn't
know but I read some on the boards and
stuff like that and so like you know
like I say preservation is a hard thing
when you're working under a climate that
you know doesn't really promote uh ganja
growing whether it's uh parentals or
whether it's cultivation because they
all see it as cultivation the justice
department they see every marijuana
plant as a possible uh money benefit so
to speak okay that's how they target it
and that's how they also um raid you
let's say okay so when you're preserving
plants and keeping a library well it's a
nuisance because they destroy everything
okay and so
um yeah so I I I think that a lot of
people in the in the Amsterdam C or
Dutch SE no matter where they are they
got severely targeted and lost parental
for sure okay what kind I could not say
I can only say that we kept what we kept
and that's that's for sure but what
others do with their parentals well it's
up to their and I see a lot of claims of
this and that so and then I follow up on
the people that access them and then you
can see and establish for yourself which
is what and what is so like uh there's a
wise man once said that uh you know um
people ey plants like people ey plants
nothing they don't lie so the plants
will reveal everything you want to know
about certain pedigrees and plants uh
possible loss of parentals with certain
uh seed brands or whatever but like I
say it's not usually um like they want
this to to happen it's like because yeah
it's like yeah you still get targeted
for keeping plants so when a library
gets like raided yeah you lose it and
then you have to tap in some seed line
maybe that holds the the like a sister
or a brother plant to what you had as
parental but it's done a different
phenotypical expression and that could
tamper possibly the the seed line that
you are making so The Offspring will
then be different let's say and so over
time over all these years that seeds are
being produced and certain seed lines
are being offered yeah of course there
will be lots of potentials and
everything that comes with it but I
cannot point my finger at anybody that's
doing it because well you know the
privilege of having these plants around
is also that when I later than went on
the boards and I could understand what
we were actually were
preserving and you then you start
meeting people from the world like uh
and um so you get together and so then
you start connecting to people in the in
the community that are also doing the
same okay passionate uh and so I
interchange with them mostly to tap into
to seeed lines that I find them
interesting so because of uh um AR
restrictions here and under this climate
that we have to work we are also we have
to keep an eye into our plant counts and
everything and that's sometimes a
nuisance when you want to tap into seeds
so but um from experience I can say that
you know like compared to these old hair
looms yeah it's hard to find the plant
morphology speaking I mean I don't
necessarily say that there are better
plants uh in potency on the market okay
but um but in morphology speaking like
the sheer wild Power that is in these
hairloom well I tried a lot of seeds
there are only few that can stand next
to them and uh or rival them okay so
they have a special Unique Kind of um
figure in them okay and so um it's hard
to find that in modern seed breeds okay
it's it's like this because everything
over the years got over hybridized a
little bit so
then uh that's why it's important to
have these genetic and pure form still
so really interesting things can to be
made and cannot wait to tap into my own
seed Vault that I have when the
legislation will change well there will
be something nice to emerg because like
I say this network of passionat of
people that are you know like uh also
preserving certain genetics that are
mind-blowing well it's going to be it's
going to be a great thing towards the
future on the the legislation will
change I'm sure so I'm looking forward
to that cannot wait but meanwhile we
just keep it secluded and do small
operations let's say you know yeah it's
like
this oh you've you've got my ears perked
up now I want to ask you you know if you
were in that legal climate you describe
what's uh you know some seeds from The
Vault you'd be interested in being able
to crack you know what's some rare seeds
that you're looking forward to getting
into oh well you know like uh we reveal
that when it's time but I could say it's
very nldd leaning and so it's like with
cultivar also that been preserved by
people like you know like uh yeah for me
it's like the anod Vari is okay like we
all know that the haze it's more D from
Colombian Mexican and uh you know like
Southeast Asian and Tha possibly but
there
are yeah abundance of um land races in
the world that people have tapped into
and also done a little work with to you
know mix with other things and then you
know establish something that's also
remarkable and can stand on its own
let's say okay and so I'm hoping that uh
when the legislation here in Europe
starts changing that this transatlantic
and also uh preferably Australia and
actually you know like the global
hopefully then it will go Global but
let's say you know the countries of
Interest let's say well then we can
establish things that are un precedented
because these two worlds will will then
be able to merge in a better way okay
because um for now well I don't have
interest into starting an American or
Canadian business let's say okay I grew
up here this is my world and so I'm
waiting for this legislation to change
and then uh it will be so the hobby work
that we do it holds a certain value but
when you throw when you want to throw a
lot of seats that you have you know and
do selection better also so to establish
your partials to go through especially
the males well you can only do that in a
legal framework okay and so that's why
I'm waiting to do my work here once it's
allowed and for now yeah we also do nice
work because over the years we were able
to refine a certain um so by you you
start reading uh plants let's say okay
and you are better aware of the seed
lines that you want to tap into it I
think the Vietnamese and other Southeast
Asians the LA and like pure Duran from
South Africa you know there's some fire
there really that's really remarkable
also and maybe other the Chinese is a
little bit difficult there are certain
Afghan varieties also that I like but
you know because Afghanistan is a
country that makes a lot of hasis so the
hybridization there is also strong thing
and so I don't so it's like a little bit
yeah I'm more a traditionalist in that
kind of way okay I
don't I do not have anything anything
against
hybridization because these H hybrids
are also hybrids I mean but over
hybridizing you get then it Blends out
too much okay and you don't go really
for that characteristics that are really
embedded in a certain strain in in like
pure form let's say you know so it's
diluted and more and that's a little bit
this yeah what I want to steer away from
and more go to the pure things and cross
pure things that you can actually say
okay this is not life 5 AC for instance
C5 cross to Vietnamese black and then do
a large selection out of that it's also
the parability yeah so you never know
what the progy will be between two kind
of cultivar how they will inter intermix
and how to yeah the overall so you have
to test it and be aware of it and so you
know uh to do these nldd so they are all
long flowering varieties it takes also a
little bit more time to do it
properly also the evaluation and whatnot
so and that's my goal you know to bring
really that finesse to the market once
the market will be ready for it okay in
the meanwhile I do uh work and I
consider that to be the you know like
the forl let's say of uh what's to come
let's hope at
least uh I love it and I mean I'd love
to hear a little bit about some of the
hybrids you offer through the uh current
dram King seeds what what are the
Creations are you responsible for and
how would you describe them well you
know so I made a mail uh so I created a
male that was C5 so I always like the C5
very much um in its
potency I think it's the queen of the
hazes in potency wise okay she also
delivers nice but she's very fin to grow
so when you don't grow it dial it in it
can be a very leafy cultiv especially
indors so uh it's not the most favorable
cultiv to grow but I like it's high when
it's really grown to food potential it's
really so it's the only one I can talk
daily let's say Okay A5 or Neville Haze
for me it's like nice for a little while
but then you know like it has this dark
exhaustiveness about it that I
personally for my personal preference do
not like so much in my daily routine
when you smoke that [ __ ] for too long
well it puts you in a different realm
let's say okay not the best one for me
so C5 is more like the more playful one
and I always liked it so then I was um
thinking about what to cross with it so
I did some Crossings with u Malawi first
to see if that brings some um because
the Mala um is a m so it's not really
the most loud strain let's say okay it
has a certain Zang to it but it's not
really loud like kishes or like cakes
and so I thought this African variety
would allow me to bring some of the C5
into it uh then I made the New Horizon
Haze with these males so that was my
first interactions with these plants to
make them um outcross them to each other
okay and then uh I became a member of Mr
Nice board and he offered five HC so
it's a different form but it's in the
same family so I thought I tap into
these seats to see if there was an
interesting maale to make uh to cross on
the C5 and then have like an IBL mod so
so to speak but to select a mail from
that one that could stand to the next to
the C5 in terms of morphology speaking
also how it flowers and you know and so
when I found that I kept it around and
then uh I start started to use it on the
AG13 and these plants that came from
that I test thr them they were amazing
okay so that became the Isaac Cas that
they now offer it's AG13 cross to C55 HC
and then now uh we did some work with
the nville ha we use the same mail so
it's one mail I preserve for the
original dumpling because I like these
people very much they're a good Cozy
Coffee Shop in the heart of Amsterdam
and uh so they like the old traditional
Dutch bringing still the H like it was
and I like that you know and so
um by this good uh understanding between
each other I um I favor them to wow they
allowed me they offered me a platform to
do some of my own work so it's actually
nice to make these first steps into like
the more quote called breathing spectrum
because well it's not really breathing I
consider you know but I can vouch surely
for that's that there will be some fire
in these seeds okay and that there will
be in the seed lines uh for sure so
that's my work for now but like I say
okay these long flowering cultiv well
say they take long to test and uh verify
and you know like to really get into
them so but it's good that they are made
available for the audience so they will
have then you know the PLS will speak
for itself Okay so so that's uh the way
I and I like the C5 so I want to bring
that more to the foreground like the H C
Spectrum let's say it's a good balance
with the with the H A in it I like it it
gives it more a little bit raciness but
I still select towards the tur so the
turbines coming from the SE line mode
then the a line it's a personal
preference ah beautiful stuff you know
as I mentioned I love that C5 smell so
I'm I'm on board with that can I just
quickly clarify um did you say that it
was uh you got a haze mail from Shanti
or was it an NL Haze NL Haze yes so an
NL haze from Shanti the the 5 HC which
is then actually uh like a half sister
let's say of um the
C5 okay because he's not a light five
version is uh a different one than the
original one back in the day so then he
crossed it to the H and that's why I
thought it was interesting to merge
these two because in effect they are two
times nl5 HC let's say and so from that
it enabled me to you know find a male
that was really uh worthy and tpin and
you know like lead really to the it's
like more or less a
C5 e IB y male you know and so that was
then my uh that was one I was looking
for and when I tested the progy I could
see also that I was satisfied with what
came out of it and then this male became
of interest to see what they should
bring there's also the CC Top Line it's
actually a C5 cross to this mail again
so it's all C
then you what you
get yeah totally that that sounds like a
really cool mixture of genetics and
there's actually a homie of mine shout
out to Eli cash he's got um a really
nice Isaac Hayes cutting so there you go
credit to the work I'm I'm sure a lot of
people are interested in hearing because
unfortunately you know very difficult to
get samples of these strains but how
would you describe the A5 and how would
you describe the C5 for someone who's
never been able to smoke it or smell it
like what's the smell what's the effect
yeah so C5 there's a lot of fress also
Piney there's some some yeah like a
chemical undertone under it when it's
grown it's also depends on how it's
grown okay because in living soil for
instance it comes out as a yeah a very
different thing than on hydr based uh
salts like we grow them okay so it
depends but it's more like to the fruity
Le side of it you know like uh the the
Tero the the lemon let's say okay it's a
little bit lemony like uh uh I could
also refer like the mango Haze has a lot
of this uh in it too like you know the
haze SE is more like the perfumey kind
the floral kind let's say okay well the
A5 is more like the liver scented uh you
know like this more meaner kind of um
dark sometimes a little bit fermented
and uh yeah so it's like a very darker
but it's it's a very nice smoke I think
A5 taste wice it's really delicious okay
but the effect I do not like so much
okay because yeah it's
like it's like it puts
you it's just like you know it's like a
I don't know it's it's a unique thing
okay but I like it smok ability like the
that incense Thick Smoke you get from a
good well grown A5 well it stands out
okay and uh it's progy can also be very
good okay so the aine is very well it's
a very unique special
hazeline that's being preserved and I
like it so it's good that people can
access it and do their own work with it
because that also enhances the gene pool
in that regard you know these power
plants they really you know uh yeah
they're changing the the the Cannabis
industry as we speak don't underestimate
it but like I say it's for the niche
it's a niche market it's not for
everybody but it's good that sparkle up
some other genetics and um so a opposed
to C yes so see is more uplifting also a
little bit soring it's also a little bit
like this uh so they they're all nl5
haes and so what people sometimes say is
that they have this crash in the end
let's say from coming from the
nl5 and uh yeah it's true compared to
100% nldd or some of them so some 100%
ND can be very sorting High very uh wow
you know like uh it's a leak above the
haze hybrids still okay but usually they
are not the best plants to grow uh for
like years let's say okay and they also
take F long so the hybrids are like the
middle ground let's say between the
commercial and the non-commercial okay
and so but they still contain that that
strong Haze influence which we like so
much and so A5 is very introspective
okay it's very um yeah it's better that
you when you're not used to it and
you're going to smoke a really well
grown uh A5 joint for the first time
well do it secluded somewhere like you
know you feel at ease and at home and
comfortable it's more like a psychedelic
a little bit okay well the C5 is more
friendly and she's more playful but also
not to be underestimated in uh in sheer
potency for uh the novel smoker let's
say okay not for the ones that really
are aware of what cannabis is and uh
they can take it more but when you're
used to cush cushies and cakes and you
smoke your first Haze joint well it can
give you a little smack let's
say that's a that's a great way to put
it I realized I don't know if I'd
actually asked you yet have you ever had
much experience with just straight Haze
in the various incarnations it has yeah
well I had the pleasure to uh you know
encounter people that hold yeah also
special pure Haze lines and tap into
those to really see what comes out of it
and props to them because yeah yeah
they're really like you these plants are
like but like I say usually they don't
deliver so much so it's like more um so
it's like more for personal usage these
people are that are really into it like
uh when you grow full hazes
I don't say they they don't exist there
some phenotypical Expressions might
produce really nice okay but um compared
to these hybrids uh from my experience
they are more finicky and they're yeah
they're they're also different leaking
plants but um the high that it produces
well it's like an amazing thing okay
it's also different so it's more for
really the
Pasion um that um that really uh wants
to get high from these that truly
Embraces them and I know of course
because I'm a passionate of myself you
get to know these people in your
community and uh and and then you travel
or you go we have a fair PES in
Barcelona each year so you know like
I've been going there for a lot of years
now and there are other fairs too like K
and and you know there's some things in
Germany Germany is looking to legalize
it too or like regulate anyway so um I
see a lot of good things happening in
that regard and you meet a lot of people
and some people yeah you know like yeah
they have also fire it's great you know
and they're usually not really the the
yeah like the the biggest names in the
industry or like have the biggest
Instagram Pages or what they're usually
more like yeah the people that really
you know have the passion for it and
like you know they so we sit around the
table and exchange things and yeah it's
it's it's always a great thing okay to
meet likeminded and people that yeah and
especially the
because I'm always looking for that if
there's some with a good piece of really
that good old authentic lianes turkeys
or you know like Nepal the best case
scenario yeah geopolitical there it's
very tough okay these people live under
so so tight regimes they cannot do what
the Smugglers also not so it's time to
reform the world so that we can access
this hashes again so shout
out
I love it I love it we are 100% right or
die for hash I love it really seriously
okay these people been doing it for
thousands of years and you know with
modern technology that we can provide
them in the west so that was also what
made the nepales that I referred to
earlier as the best smoke I ever had
that made it so exclusive because there
were people Wester there that were like
helping assisting these families to
produce an extra quality of hashes okay
like to refine it more pure with modern
techniques okay and that led to a
spectacular Synergy that provided the
best MH I you ever was able to access
for me personally in my uh personal
realm of reality I do not say that other
people have maybe also Treasures in
their pockets but for me that was the
Pinnacle of GES okay and so I'm sure
it's possible to make it there but yeah
you know like now Nepal is not such
a stable area sadly so um it's yeah we
hope to change that in time okay let's
hope and pray so we can access this
marvelous thing again okay because it's
really something unique and very know
it's a treasure of humankind also okay
and we need to learn from it and respect
it but yeah like I say Okay small steps
towards the future man
and hopefully a GI Le
soon 100% I think we all can get on
board we would all love to try some of
that nepes hash you describe it sounds
like it's uh it's going to be worth the
wait but I just want to quickly loop
back because the the listeners will be
very upset if I don't ask you know can
we grab a quick description in the same
way you describe the A5 and the C5 of
the hash plant Haze the Neville's Haze
and the
AG13 yeah well the ag3 and the hush
blant Haze they're more like um Afghani
influenced okay but they are really also
two Haze Expressions let's say the hash
plant Haze it has this remarkable hashy
taste to it and it was very
stoned Haze okay it was the stonest of
all so it was really like it's a
different Stone than for you could say
that you get stoned from A52 but it's
like more obliterating like okay but
this one was really it cracked you down
the Afghan was strong let's say in the
harsh plant Haze and it delivered like
this giant galaxis also it's like a
unique cultivar very shining very
abundant and resin also um but um harder
to grow so like a little bit more less
power to it than compared to the ANL
hazes in terms of sensitivity because
when you grow it right it has power but
it's more sensitive let's say uh the
at13 is a it's also a very unique blend
it's more like a Musky kind of type Haze
um to smoke um I I prefer it for me it's
the best hze a hybrid uh in the spectrum
of these old cultivar or at least what I
consider to be the best h a Crossing was
AG13 because the G13 gives more like an
relaxed tone to all this Haze Madness
let's say Okay especially coming from
the side
and so it D it dampers it it's like you
know it's like it's a really good
combination it's more medicinal I think
also okay it's like an ideal smoke to uh
to have when you're like not feeling
good and you want to you know first do
something initially it gives you this
flash but then it goes it's more
relaxing okay it's more kind to to um
compared to A5 so I think it's a better
balanced uh Haze hybrid and all sense I
like that the most from the a side and
yeah the hash plant H like I say okay
it's a very finicky plant to grow also
it's not really popular on the agenda
for most cultivators they all kind of
like it's also what the market demands
so the market usually demands A5 and N
because that's the two most powerful
ones and so the C5 and then the has
plant are not so much demand for it
because it has to be grown to full
potential to really be appreciated for
what it is and so a lot of Growers
excuse me that attempt to grow it and
fail a couple of times well they don't
want to grow it anymore so they rather
go to the aines ad13 now says A5 because
um in that sense well it it needs
different parameters to get to full
potential than the C lines and so
they're uh more a little bit more
practical I think okay they have other
complications let's say but so they are
also more rock solid in butt formation
and well the sea line tends to go a
little bit more open flowerly when you
not
uh cultivated it to full potential and
in the worst case it turns to Hay like I
say so if that happens to a cultivator
paying in like four five months also
putting in the effort and the cost and
nothing comes in return because it's a
Hast stack yeah he's not going to grow
it again let's say or you have to be
really good
motivated so it's like this so the a
hybrids they have more appeal also for
the people so they like the Flash and
bank so to speak that obliterating
feeling it's like popular to but to
really delve into the finess Finesse of
hze I think the the seaside is more um
but over the years it got more
hybridized with like shorter flowering
varieties and so actually they breed
away from the haze instead of enhancing
it more in Dutch terminology then
because it was more practical to grow so
they want the flower time from going 14
weeks to let's say 11 weeks 10 weeks but
still bit haesang into it and then um
yeah you start selecting for that and uh
for commercial purposes more well we are
being we kind of dig it so much and we
also know how to grow it that we keep
these plants to ourselves and cultivate
them and we are like a little bit the L
of the moans I think in that regard
because um but now it shines back again
like I say okay because this is a solid
value in like the Cannabis Community
these dayses and yeah and they will be
forever there because when you grow it
to full potential well you know you can
throw it on the table and no matter what
anybody carries they will say like wait
this is unique like what that's very
nice
that's the way how you connect also with
people in the community and uh that's a
great thing you know I uh yeah it's been
been a a Crazy Life over the years with
my uh beautiful cultiv and the people I
have met by them that's awesome to hear
I think uh you know in the midst of that
epic answer I heard you mention that the
Neville's Haze is one of the more potent
ones can you give us just a quick
overview of the smell and the effect cuz
I know that it's it's one you really
don't see a lot in the modern SE and so
people find it very elusive yeah so well
it depends on also the set and setting
with these smokes so when you are in a
comfortable set and setting it can be
very uh Pleasant initially let's say
okay this sorting High you really
connect and you get into something and
you're like completely in the zone but
if you then have to go to pick some
groceries in the shop and you step
outside you're like what like this
because like then it hits you how how
you how High you actually are you know
and that can produce some anxiety with
people you know like it's like this when
you're used to smoking it but I found it
very so it does something to your mind
frame um you know like it's an awareness
this plant so it it tampers with your
awareness like getting high there's so
many varieties in it but these special
varieties well they're unique but I
think the Neville's Haze and the haze
eight lines they very dark you know
they're like they're nice to indulge in
for a little while but then you kind of
like yeah you lose it a little bit okay
I mean like you because you live too
much in your own world or something
because yeah you know like it's hard to
maintain like a daily job and you talk
this weed on daily basis okay because
you step into this different realm if
you're an artist then you can produce
art it's maybe nice but when you have to
work as an IT agent and you have to put
your mind at think it's just nice you
know what I mean
so I wouldn't say Hy um you know for me
it's of course a passion and it's became
my life but so you have to have a little
bit of this passion also to appreciate
it and to like yeah I don't know like uh
live it like we do okay but uh I would
not Advocate it to smoke um it daily
when you're not ready for it so you have
to really want it in your life and love
it otherwise it can do a doing things
with you and it still does for me once
in a while too that's why I love the
bandid H7 number seven so much because
it has the depth and um um figure it has
all it takes all the boxes but so it has
a more friendly High to it okay so it's
less exhaustive also okay so it's very
dreamy like mushroom wheat but in the
best way possible it's very kind and A5
and nille say the aren't kind so each
plant has this temperament let's say and
so the temperament of the Neville's ha
and the A5 Well w not so much okay
that's not my lady to go to to to go
dancing with every night because she's
rless okay she throws me around like
[ __ ] so i' rather have
like you know like a a different thing
it's nice little a joint you know you
get high and a few hours later it's gone
but still you know so like the A5
lingers too long you know like it it
puts you a little bit in this uneasy
feel and the Neville ha said well it
[ __ ] you up in your mind okay you know
what's also the thing is I think with
these more psychedelic or like so
they're more spiritual and bettered and
so they increase your awareness of
things which is not always easy because
well we live in a brutal Society okay
and so when you're [ __ ] high
all the time and look at what the human
concept is and what we make of it well
it's sometimes mindboggling let's say
like what's smoke a joint and get high
because then it's nice like I say when
you sit around the table with a lot of
people comfortable and you share a joint
like that or at a campfire or a festival
or like you know in these best case
scenarios it really can you know enhance
your experience so much okay I once went
to Mexico and I saw the palen ruins
there the first time I went there I was
sober and the next day I encountered
somebody and I could smoked some Haze
and we went back again and believe me
like Mexican I don't know what it was
but it was five okay well it was like a
totally different experience as the day
before let's say okay and that's the
weed I kind of like like to weed that
that has this it's more a spiritual
thing okay for me it's like really makes
you pay attention that's why I kind of
like it okay but indulging in it in our
society well it's not the most easy
thing long I can certainly appreciate
the sentiment and we'll definitely get
to the the healing Band-Aid Haze very
shortly I just want to ask you one last
quick question in regards to these cuts
and more specifically Neville did you
ever have any interaction with Neville
any thoughts on him and do you regard
him as the the greatest of all time in
terms of
breeding oh well well nille his
influence is indisputed this man created
some things that are extraordinary okay
that's true but you know like so it's
like the story so Neville created the
hybrids and with that actually you pav
the way of modern cannabis let's say
okay so we the whole cannabis industry
and Community owe this man a great deal
of uh yeah you know like it's like yeah
of course he is what he is and uh but
that also counts for instance for S
skman who was bringing the seeds from
America and also then when you go past
that the haze Brothers whoever they were
and maybe even the beatnet generation
that were initially interested in uh in
getting highlights say okay and so um
then it's all a little bit connected I
see also his originated in Santa Cruz
California as far as historics
go if we follow the historical
uh uh uh part and uh
so then it came to Holland and nille got
in touch with it and made something
really remarkable for it because he has
he had a nose for it he had yeah so his
bleeding work is like it speaks for
itself okay we still live in his legacy
for uh and we must be thankful for that
of course and uh you know we we were
lucky to um save guard theart from this
man's Legacy and that he okay by being
preserved by loving them and like I said
I never really understood who Neville
was it was um later by so we held the
Clones let's say from these people got
into trouble and we took the medip to
ourselves that was like 1999 the
Millennium change let's
say then we went underground with it
okay but I lost the A5 and I wanted to
find it back and so internet then came
and it revolutionize the world we can
all agree on that too and so I was uh
going online searching for it and that
brought me then to the M&amp;S board because
there were similar genetics being made
available so I'm like hey man this is
maybe uh a way of retrieving the A5 back
and so uh I was a member on the boards
and then Neville so I was reading about
it and by being on an international
board you could start understanding more
about it so it was like a mirror that
was placed in front of me and I was like
realizing now so we were never really
affiliated with the Amsterdam scene back
when I met these group that were Hing
the hazes okay like I say we went there
for a like to see the city and do some
coffee shops but we never went there to
really as as a cannabis Enthusiast let's
say okay that came later but for us then
it so we didn't have to drive two or
three hours because it was available
like around the corner so um so we held
it
here and um by being on the bars then I
could really beginning to understand
like hey man we have something special
here I knew they were for Neville but I
never really paid attention how this
cannabis Community before the bigger
scheme then was in at play so I was just
my secluded grower at pres preserving uh
preservest of these plants safeguarding
them by loving them so much and and then
you get this feedback of people and then
later through M&amp;S I got ined in inter in
brief interaction with NVA but then the
whole thing exploded there and yeah well
so it came became like
a something I rather steer away from and
like oh my God okay well so I just love
these plants and uh yeah man so na may
his soul rest in peace and we owe this
man a really great thing and um because
he did something remarkable but you know
he did it in Holland and so it's like so
it's more like so the people that are
not in the spotlight also usually for
preserving these plants well we owe them
like really a ton of gratitude
because uh nille was a great breeder but
he was not a prist okay and so that's
usually breeders are not the best
reservist for one or reason or the other
I don't know why it's used to also with
illegal legislations not being able to
keep the plant parential clean or
whatnot it can diver like it can have so
many reasons okay why it goes wrong but
um so I never intended to breed with
these plants until I could assess for
myself how unique they were in the
Cannabis genome okay and uh so then you
start paying attention but I never
wanted to to you like um exploit them
for any benefit sh for my own you know
it's been part of our lives for so long
and so by being then on the Bo and
realizing what you had well you know
some people ask me like I really would
love to smoke this A5 and you know like
so then we interact and so I give it
away okay I'm like here grow it because
I love these people
also and then it's a different thing
okay and then they can grow it and then
yeah of course it get shared and it's
like how it is so it is what it is
they're out there in the world and I
think that's a really great thing
because that's where they belong and
that's also why we kept them around for
so many years okay only to yeah first
and foremost be able to access them
ourselves don't lose them and then in
the best case scenario that's what
smokers do we get high together and of
course if you want it and I really you
know we share that amen of course course
that's how it
happens yeah what what an awesome
sentiment and uh an interesting
observation as well you made about
breeders and not being able to preserve
I uh I've certainly lost a plant here
and there I have to acknowledge it I'd
love to ask you what's the uh what's the
backstory on the Miracle tie that ended
up creating the Band-Aid Haze can you
tell me how that one went down yeah it's
a good question actually because in the
end nobody knows what this medical tie
supposedly is so so it actually it
became Miracle because there was a
coffee shop in that area that was called
miracle and so these people that were
providing A5 flowers they had a crop
there and whether it's like I don't know
what it is so something pollinated a
crop and there were some seeds from it
and so these were kept around for Long
by the people there that were the people
that actually also safeguarded the A5
clone for long well uh in this this area
got lost and so the seats would then
sent to the US where they resulted in
this mail that then eventually uh
produced the bandaid number seven it
speaks for itself so thankfully we we
made some seats with that also so we
have it now in our vaults ready to like
I say when the legislation change all
these seeds and these genetics were made
available and thank God we have enough
of them like the A5 crossed to the A5 TI
which are nice lines so we are
preserving what we can whether it's in
plant form or seed form to once you know
like uh tap into this genome more
um uh deeper let's say and see what
comes out of it because the band 87 it's
just an example of what to find in that
it's such a unique beautiful cultivar
but also not easy to grow so it's also
like this when people are used to grow
going like Haze hybrids that go like um
12 weeks and they used to chop it around
let's say the 90day market or like then
well the Band-Aid start then then
producing Beauty so you have to give it
time because it goes like to 15 weeks up
to 15 weeks and even then you might go
to 16 weeks if you really want to grow
it properly but then she is like wow she
blows she's like amazing okay wow this
really can stand next to it and so that
only shows the potential of these
genetics towards the future and so I'm
thankful to be privileged to be working
these uh exclusive genetics in that way
and then you you also see how the
breeding potential how how high it is
okay but like I say most commercial
Growers don't want it okay because they
have streamline facilities and if you
are like you know doing a a thousand
indoor lights and you put it cultiv like
that and it and it goes wrong well you
are 20 weeks further and well it's a big
problem let's
say that's really interesting I I
haven't uh been fortunate enough to to
try the Band-Aid 7 myself but the the
thing I was wanting to ask you was
obviously it was Miracle tie onto that
A5 and then bod crossed it to the Cuban
black Haze the Cuban black Haze that's
suspected of being like a very A5 like
it is very A5 leaning for heard and then
the A5 itself is in there so it's
interesting that the Band-Aid Haze like
would you say the effect is like the A5
or not
really it's much better the effect you
know like so it has the deepness of like
the h a side to it but it doesn't um
[ __ ] with your mindset so much okay it's
not so negative the effects so it's much
more positive and bright inspiring and
creative instead of more that kind of
[Music]
overthinking things like you know like
like or you get fixated at something or
like it's hard to describe how it works
actually but it's much more friendly and
it has this A5 progy like you say it's
actually you know so A5 cross to
question mark this mail and so it would
be nice to with our modern technology
like to lab test it further to see in
the future which actually is close
related to whatever the male was that
pollinated this A5 because when you look
at the B7 well it's exceptional okay and
so it's on the Cuban black ha as you
said now I haven't grown the Cuban black
Hae itself here and I know there are
many Cuban black haes going around so
it's hard to distinguish actually which
one body used I I I don't know that so I
cannot confirm it but so it's probably
also from what I've heard the best
assumption that I have to make from
my you limited uh abilities to assess it
let's say it's probably uh a nville haze
that was shipped back then in the early
90s or maybe late 80s when it's these
tester seeds were available maybe back
then I'm not sure it's just like
speculation okay but the morphology of
this Cuban black Haze well it's more
comparable to the NV Haze we have here
than it is to A5 or C5 it has a
different structure okay and I see when
I see pictures of this cultivar of the
Cuban black Haze I see more like um this
type of um Str morphology structure as I
can see it in the navel face and that's
different so it has more like
um it's it's very uh but it's Stout so
it's more stouty compared to the hazes
we have but it's branching is more like
this uh so uh it's also not floting so
long I think it's only 12 weeks or
something anyway that's what I heard so
that's the best assumtion I have if
that's the case then it's actually uh A5
cross to AC cross to A5 cross to
question mark okay whatever it is it's
like a really good um combination and um
so it's only sad that only the band Haze
got selected because I think in the seed
light could be more but it's a unique
culer and it's it's really a keep it
plant this one okay and I have tested
many seeds I didn't come across uh any
keepers like I tested many hazes other
hazes the Amnesia Haze was also nice but
yeah it didn't really appeal to me uh in
um High and overall plant compared to A5
or
C5 uh also super silver is not so much
like like I say okay the mango Haze in
terms of morphology also not but I like
the its um smok ability a lot okay so
it's like this yeah but the Bandit H
really sticks out so whatever the male
was that hit the A5 well it has it's
makes a really good Bland let's say they
were all seats also I think they TR them
all but they only had success to find
one mail in it but sadly it got lost
okay that's also that we come again
preserve preserving okay may like that
well it was for nille also back in the
day h a also got lost very early
actually so then there was only HC left
which make the ace a hybrids more like
mesmerizing or like legendary because
they are only few few of them okay well
see then later got that was uh around so
much later so it was then usable to
create other hybrids but like I say
usually they steered away a little bit
from the haze side the commercial side
of the spectrum then because the in
Practical to cultivate it to full
potential okay so they had they they
that two more Streamlight plants because
it's
more easy to cultivate let's say okay so
then the hybridation further came and
you know so the je got a little bit
diluted in the H SE thing but if you
have it in pure form still well it has a
sheer power and it's more friendly like
I say but on the other hand the Band-Aid
Haze being cubid black Haze which I
think is also leaning more to the haze
aite definitely in Scent so I had the
privilege to go to New York so I didn't
grow it I have didn't have a chance to
grow it but then I was able to sample
some of this cubid black face and it's
clearly related to uh the aine okay so
it has the same kind of more seene smell
to it like you know it's not that liver
I didn't find liver in it so much but
yeah it has that darken rotten fermented
thing to to it in a certain way so I can
see the relation between the Cuban black
ha and nville work clearly okay it's
definitely related 100% but when you
then think that the cub in Black Hae
with this A5 cultivar produce such a
nice um cultivar in morphology I can
understand it but in smok ability it was
a surprise because it doesn't have this
um um
negative so possible negative um sphere
that usually comes from h a hybrids you
you know it's more to the SE side of it
that's why I think the Cuban black Cas
might be a n say okay there's some C in
it or this question mark pollinating the
A5 might also have a play in it who to
know we should also look into lab
testing it to find out maybe okay where
it fits into like a but this science is
also emerging we can now test genomes
and whatnot but like this library is
still a little bit
debatable like it's like not really
clear yet so we have to investigate
further to see the correlation between
things okay then we can establish to say
it's possibly this I don't personally
think it's a th that pollinated this A5
but who who to know okay who's to know
it's a miracle that's what it is because
it produced the bandaid and yeah so
fabulous go okay
unique totally totally speaks for itself
and as you said it'll be awesome one day
if we are able to test these things and
get an answer one of the questions we
had submitted by a few different
listeners is uh you know dubie of a
seeds good friend of the show we'd love
to hear a little bit about your
collaboration with him what were some of
your thoughts on the crosses and do you
have maybe a favorite yeah well you know
do we had an interesting Library I think
in potential plans to make these clones
also uh and more available to the wide
stream audience in a way I saw
more fitting the hair looms itself
because like I said usually they been
Brad with to away from the haze and so
his more nldd Rich Library sparkled my
enthusiasm to contact him and to say hey
man you know like you have nice
parentals I have some special hair looms
you know uh what you think you know we
can maybe you know enhance the Jean pool
with that and make this wheed accessible
because over Years A lot of people ask
me to please send me the A5 please send
me the C5 and I can understand it but
you know I I I would be mailing like 100
clones every day just not possible it's
just not doable okay so I have shared it
with some people that I consider being
part of my intimate sphere okay and it's
it's like this usually that that these
plants are exchanged also and they
become friends and then you do it then
of course it spreads out but that's a
different story but um so with is I had
like so his partials were nice and uh so
we done experimented and got together
and we are still working on um like um
so it's an R&amp;D phase so he chose the
Malawi because he's in favor of that and
I did some work previously myself with
Malawi that actually brought me to a
seeds because I had a um a mutual Um
passion let's say he was working with
this a seeds line and he had poen from
an excep Mayhill he found in the Malawi
line so then he we he exchanged pollen
with me and I did my own little work and
I was like hey man the progy is really
good okay the first time I see like
something I'm looking for in like what's
what was the progy then of these
meetings and so that's uh by going to
spab Lou is also based in Spain uh yeah
our wells you know connected there so um
we then uh decided to look into it and
uh do some breedings together I
personally like the super Malawi uh Haze
or like this yeah what's it called
Malawi Haze I think it's the nille haze
cross to the Malawi and uh so like I
said they are long flowering plants so
he has now also released some with
ohakam and uh with Panama and so I
smoked some because we also have a
collective here of people that you know
like pop some seeds to see what's in it
and so I liked with the Panama the A5
Panama liked really nicely and so there
are some people growing it now it takes
long to grow it so we are waiting for
actually the people's preferences and
then there will be a few lines that Ace
can uh use to enhance his own library
but I think he does fabulous work with
his own thing and uh he's good guy and
he knows a lot about bre so in that
regard I found it very interesting also
to make so a lot of people beg me for A5
and no know okay so I'm like okay let's
make it accessible for people you know
but in a way I think it's a good way not
uh do another Super Silver ha story or
like you know Jack har or whatever you
know or also not with cushies because I
think the Kush takes a lot too much away
from h i mean morphology wise they can
produce really ex extraordinary PL PLS
but you get this Custer pins in it you
can so it downgrades this haste too much
it's too overpowering so I rather have
done a natural blend in it like Thai or
like natural varieties land races that
are also being refined by a breeder work
like Ace is doing and then bring these
two Wells together to you know allow
people to have you know like an idea of
what it is to smoke an A5 because you
have phenotypes so I
like so I like it very much and I like
get a lot of gratitude from people also
to make it available in this kind of
more sphere okay and we are all yeah
based in Europe try and we are also
fighting for better better legislations
here and so we are assisting each other
also to you know enhance our
capabilities to uh yeah you know uh make
the broad awareness here uh that it's a
good B it's a normal thing okay it
should be considered as mind making so
you know like this
tolerated more or less um wave that that
has hidden Europe uh while we're not
there yet okay we need better
legislations and then we can do proper
work let's say okay but I think a seeds
is one of the more professional here in
Europe that has some interesting
genetics and therefore I wanted to cross
and I would say that thaten to I I
personally like sea lines a lot
and so usually the people go for the A5
cross to whatever okay because they all
want this A5 Z but I recommend people to
tap into the sea line too because yeah
the sea has something you know like so
people that want to smoke daily this and
the the sea line yeah it's a treasure
okay so I can only recommend people also
to look into that because it's
worthwhile believe me what an awesome
answer I love it and uh i' I've sused
theist this out myself plenty of
mouthwatering options on there I reckon
that all be killer I'd love to ask you
you know cuz Ace offers and works with a
lot of land R stuff have you have you
been tracking or got any thoughts on
some of the newer land race genetics
that have been coming in by way of
places like Indian Land race exchange
and some of these other cool cats in the
community some of these other guys in
the community who are out there
collecting land race genetics and
offering them do you have any thoughts
on that yeah well you know it depends
also what your personal preferences so
land races well
so a land race is usually not the most
suitable cultiv are to place in an
indoor VAR environment okay then they
have to be exceptional I don't say it's
not possible but you give and take the
fact that if a plant is produced for
instance in India for like number of
years and you you tap into a seed line
here well it's a very different cultivar
than let's say uh uh yeah than any other
cultivar and so it's a personal
preference taste okay um for
me ganja is ganja so if I want to smoke
um Indian varieties I smoke their hash
preferably
okay and so I'm not really looking in
that but some land races of course are
different okay so ganja the ganja
countries uh they have different land
races than the har countries when you
look at the Thai varieties or like their
regions that these um or like southeast
Asia more generally speaking okay they
they smoke the ganja there and then so
like um from areas where Hashi is
produced well these cultiv they're harsh
cultiv okay so they're totally different
and to place them in an indoor
environment
well well it's not what I would aim for
or look for you know but ganja VAR ities
land race varieties they are really
interesting to um enhance the Jean Pool
the ganja Jean pool with okay so I don't
necessarily say it's bad to have a the
better variety in your Jean Pool I think
they could be nice surprising in terms
of getting high maybe but they're not
really made for um the realm of people
that produce weat I think it's not for
the big Market I think it's also a very
niche market so people will dive into it
for personal preferences but not
necessarily because they are the most um
yielding and rewarding PLS or out
speaking so to speak okay so it's all
about personal preference which is a
good thing and I only you know like
applaud these people for doing it but
for me personally it's not the my field
of interest interest in merging um
Realms of ganja with each other because
has well like I said they are made but
they are usually has cultiv it says
speak for itself like the has is a very
good example so it can work for instance
but
um so you have to have a so you have to
throw a lot of numbers of seats to be
able to do proper selection in that
field and so for me it's not a
possibility okay but for people that are
working business large scale yes of
course I understand why they do it okay
you might find that one exceptional
parental that can enhance the Jeep pool
in certain way that it's so that's the
beauty about cannabis also and working
these plants you know that's why I don't
like uniforming them so much I like to
so the difference must be there okay
like uh it must be a good blend so to
speak or good hybrid so you're aware of
it's this and that and you keep also the
pedigree clear and so everybody knows
what it is okay because I think the
majority of the market is like the nine
weer cultivation wise okay okay and then
you have like the finest blends to it
and that can go up to like maybe 20
weeks okay but that's really a niche
market I think and it's not really
something that will be grown in big
facilities I think never okay because
you don't have the market for
it yeah very true very true you know
it's hard hard to imagine popping some
land race seeds and getting something
out of it the market would be accepting
you did uh you know pick my curiosity
when you're answering that last question
is sort of slightly unrelated but mostly
related um have you ever tried to make
hash out of any of the you know the
heirlooms you hold or do you feel like
the magic is within the flower oh no no
no we did you know but it really works
best from uh outdoor grown so when you
light dep it here in summertime and uh
we were fortunate to do it uh and then
uh you dry sift uh under the best
possible condition so traditional also
well I must say that ag3 it's that's the
winner we sadly hear over now we don't
we don't can access the has plant Hast
temporarily due to also the legislation
that's unfriendly so we have to regain
it uh so it's a little bit tricky but
that would also be a very good cultiv I
think to do that you know when you light
dep it under Sun you know Outdoors W man
yes the hash from it it's really good
okay even if it's a one
um phenotype hashes so to speak okay
well it was yeah it absolutely was blow
my mind and it's much better than the
other other concentrates I think okay uh
Rosen is also of course a very nice way
to tap into um the thing but you have to
have this machine and it's very sticky I
I kind of like the the dry shift
methodology and then you know like you
uh you press it and you have like yeah
what we like has but yeah yeah 813 wow
the rest wow it's very heavy okay to um
to have this concentrate yeah it really
blows your mind also people are a little
bit afraid of
it especially those from Nal ha and then
A5 you know like seriously it's like oh
you don't want to give it to somebody
that do know what to because that stuff
is it's brutal okay so it's like
Yeah well yeah but also in so the type
of hashes so that comes more more to
really that type of Afghan psychedelic
hashes well the at13 absolutely was the
winner in that regard so yeah yeah we do
make hash we also isolated it we do BHO
we do a little bit of everything okay
but um my favorite is that kind of thing
but yeah you have to grow outside so
it's here with this legislation it's
hard to do it let's say because it's in
the ey and so you have to have the spot
and so it's very complicated to get it
done but once it's done well it's
absolutely uh yeah something unique
also
definitely oh I can only imagine that
sounds like it would be a real treat one
of our listeners wanted to ask are your
flowers like sort of or your cruise
flowers sort of consistently available
at Dr King if they were to go visit
Amsterdam or is it like a hot commodity
and you got to sort of be you know there
at the right moment yeah that's actually
the case because you know I'm not I'm a
secluded man so I cannot do big things
okay so I can only recommend the people
to ask the bartenders like if they have
some semi grown there because it's there
you know it's also like it's not so it's
hard to to to be to be delivering that
consistency in that kind of League
because well I'm not in this commercial
main frame so and it also it takes a lot
of time along with these long flowerings
so you know there are some batches of
course that he uh that they uh uh safe
but you know it's a hard thing okay and
when it's really good like I told you
it's like quickly sold also so you know
it takes a little time to uh to fill the
tank again but U yeah we do the best we
can so I recommend people going there to
like request the tenders there if
there's anything available and I'm sure
they will uh assist you accordingly so
yeah I do the best I can with the means
I have so to speak okay that's how it
for now at least oh look I don't think
anyone blames you it's understandable
with all the parameters you mentioned
and you know sort of ties into another
question we had from another listener
which was how do you feel about the new
legal system in Holland and why is it so
hard to find real ha in Amsterdam
anymore well because nobody wants to
grow it it's like that okay and also the
Hypes of the of the mod strains like the
cushies and the cakes are like the more
C strains well so they are all also a
hype here and everybody jumps on it
because it's yeah of course it makes
more money let's say it's actually crazy
in Amsterdam these squishies like the
Cali strains are often retailed for like
35 Plus EUR a gram well mine is like 16
or something okay I don't mind about
that because I think you know it's all
about an honest smoke also but I'm just
saying they're like nine weekers easy to
grow and then like you but so the market
is completely upside down but it what it
is okay and so
um yeah what can I say about it okay
uh Haze was there was a time in the '90s
when the cultivation was less targeted
and it was still more open that hazes
were also more frequently grown by the
passionates and you had more hom Growers
let's say okay but when they started to
Target really the home cultivators well
it moved a little bit to more like uh
yeah the criminal sphere they pushed it
in that because yeah you know seriously
okay so they incriminate the cultivation
more while they still enhance the U
coffee shop being so it's like a
complete absurdity but anyway that was
the sad Evolution and so that was also
the reason why secluded Growers like
myself went deeply underground and then
like yeah has also have to face the
consequences but in the way yeah we we
do it with passion and with heart and so
it got a little bit pushed away by the
uh transformation of the whole cannabis
culture also the so legalization in
America and Canada or like
regularization or like you know I never
expected in the '90s if somebody would
have told me like it's going to be legal
or like you know regulated in America
prior to Holland I was like so you crazy
okay because we were expecting
legalization within 5 years and then it
became 10 years 15 20 20 53 I'm like
what and it's like this okay so the haze
got a little bit pushed away and so it
then it kind of reside only in the
people that kind of treasured it because
everybody yeah was growing Amnesia
suddenly here because it was a sturdy
plant easy to grow nine weaker variety
also you know you had different so they
have different types of Amnesia but the
one that's uh kind of grow it's the I
think the hypr cut well so you it in 9
weeks usually they chop it a little
early at 10 maybe tops and it yields a
lot and it's potent wheat okay so but
it's not really it doesn't hold any like
the sacred thing is a little bit breed
away from it and so we want to maintain
that but yeah we are like the last of
the moans with this say everybody says
you're totally insane
okay but anyway insane or not we do it
anyway oh I love it and look you know
you're referring to like the sacredness
of the haze high and I guess you know a
common breeding strategy we see being
embraced more often is Old School versus
new school and so I guess what's your
thoughts on the idea of like uh C5 cross
to gelardo 33 like do you think there's
any value in that or do you think it's
just too dominant yeah I think it's too
dominant and the so for my personal
preference I don't say it will not
produce really Stell plants and be maybe
a mergin of Two Worlds okay so bringing
the haze to the cushies but you know so
it's like different two completely
different Two Worlds it was like also
back in the day the people the
initiators of the preservation they
weren't so fond of skunk line because
that was overdominant and every kind of
variety almost you found on the Dutch
Market back then so they wanted to keep
the haze as good as possible around and
not intermix it with skunk I must say I
also grow the old school Haze and it's a
great mix of skunk and Haze so it it has
potential okay but for my personal
preference I wouldn't go for it because
I personally I like all cannabis but I'm
not so in favor of certain cushies so
from my also limited uh accessibility
also to trying them and to proper
evaluate them but um I don't say there
are cushies maybe in the field that I do
uh like
smok ability wise and also morphology
wise you know so that um but it's not
something I'm looking for because
usually cushies are short flowering so
then you will have an offspring that
will diminish also it will take away
from the haze experience so to speak in
high usually that's the case and produce
a less or more yeah sedative kind of
stone in it like you know what I mean
that's my experience with cushies anyway
but um so they're more like um sedative
kind of they can be good also a little
bit more relaxing some of them are a
little bit overpowering like couch Loy
but it's not my type of wheat that uh
that that I would access if I have a
variety on the table also my preferences
was not so we tried it ourselves and I
know I didn't like it so much The
Offspring plantwise wow really amazing
plants came out of it but I thought the
the flowers were too um so it's it's
steering away from the haze uh too much
for my personal taste so I wouldn't
really um go into that myself but if
people like pushes and they also like
hazes yeah man I would say go for
it I love that answer there you go I
guess we're sort of circling around the
idea of this topic of like how do we get
more people interested in these older
varieties and one of the sort of ideas
that pops up is that that some of these
older heirlooms and just um really
special strains in general don't
necessarily test that high in THC and it
seems like a lot of the general
consumers of the market are largely
driven by those values what do you think
is a way in which we might be able to
get more people aware of you know the
special effects and nature of these
older plants well it's a Synergy between
compounds it's not so numbers do play
into account I mean hey also is like
around let's say 20% THC but now you
have varieties of 30% THC that produce a
totally different High than coming from
these hazes and they are not so
psychedelic or so I think um the Synergy
between all compounds not only THC but
also like flavonoid flavonoids and like
terpenoids that is like um give this
wheed its character or its potential so
this whole book let's say if you just
like read one page of this book well you
can uh uh extrapolate it and look at it
and like but there's much more to read
and so that works on each other and so
to only focus on um THC although it has
its relevance in making us high it's
like not something that uh will produce
necessarily better high or like a a
better product okay it's like a little
with with alcohol it's also like that
you have this strum kind of varieties
it's 80% full alcohol I mean you don't
drink that in pure form it must be crazy
for that okay so you dilute it with
something so if you have a strain like
yeah sometimes they make extracts of I
don't know like pure THC and you dab
that well yeah well it's not really so
it's a cannabinoid but it's very mon so
it's very mono so it's very yeah
monistic let say I'm not for that I'm uh
like you know like like a painting yeah
you know what I mean it's like the whole
painting not just a fragment of it and
so to only focus on numbers that would
be uh it's like you read every not from
a symphony but you don't hear the music
of the symphony okay so it's like um the
people that are focused on numbers to
enhance their own profits they're like a
little bit OBS obsessed with numbers too
much I think okay and so they shouldn't
smoke a good joint and
reevaluate there you go there you go I
guess in a similar vein I'd love to ask
you let's say someone's listening to
this episode and they're like you know
what I'm sold I want to try some of
these cool heirlooms what sort of
genetics would you advise someone to get
if they had to use seeds and they want
to get their toes wet in this sort of
effect and plan well the the seed that
we are making available at or little
dumping I would say yeah go for for it
and then of course what I do with a
seeds also I say also go for it and
there are some people in the business
here in homeand that are working also
with these hybrids and producing their
own variety so like you know you just
internet is full of them eh so if you
type in uh certain seed banks are
offering them now and it's only like the
beginning I think because there will be
more offerings and more work to be done
coming future and so for now I would say
like the AC SE lines are very nice with
the
hybrid so we collaborated on and um so
the bars are full of it okay I think
Wally for instance also makes like nice
things available for an yeah there I
think there are some people also that
are working uh to when the legislation
change a step further out of the closet
and make their own kind of uh uh nldd uh
Spectrum or bring their own kind of nld
spectrum to the market which are they
are working already and it's nice to see
people collaborating with passion around
the world you know sharing things and
then you know you bring worlds together
and you can really make uh extraordinary
plants if you combine Elite plants with
each other yeah of course the result
will be something Elite so it's it's
like this okay and also the good Synergy
between two plants because not
necessarily two hybrids that are really
Stellar uh you know can enhance uh
in its progy their parentals so you have
to really test it and know what you're
doing but a lot of Pion in the in the
world are working and I think once the
legislation in multiple countries will
change well well well it will change
also the accessibility of uh of uh the
more ha uh dominated spectrum of
cannabis let's say or nldd for that
matter totally I hope that definitely
happens I wanted to ask you one last
question before we jump into our final
five it's a fan submitted one and they
said can you ask Sammy what's his
thoughts on the early pearls silver
Pearl
well you know it's like every plant has
its Unique Kind of um morphology and
Spectrum okay so I was never really um
fond of it because yeah all it the laps
it lacked Vigor toward to the plants
that we kind of embraced and although
it's nice to have it around and to be
able to have Growers here in the local
communities that are still you know also
busy with uh these other old hair looms
that they are keeping and try to yeah so
for me these kind of I like it I like
every kind of cannabis like I said but
cultivation wise I never really um went
in these kind of spectrums because we
had the haze handloom and we had our
hands full so it kind of you know
enriched me but also limited me in
tapping into certain seed lines myself
and better evaluate them so my take on
it is like I don't know like original
Norther light for instance five well I
never accessed it and so now it appears
to have Reimer or whatever it is I'm not
sure if this is all true I'm just
speculating but I have to grow to know
it and so I never had a chance to grow
this particular cultiv he's mentioning
all tap into the seed line so I cannot
really assess it we all smoked it and I
know some people who grow it but so it's
like a different League everybody has
his own kind of Niche work here a little
bit and we stick to our own let's say
okay and we are the hze people and other
people well they do other things
okay ah there you go I've never had it
myself so I really can't comment too
much but it's certainly one people are
always very very curious
about well brings us to our final five
the first question I want to ask you was
what's the single most memorable or
impactful memory you have with cannabis
doesn't have to necessarily be like the
most potent cannabis but just an event
where it was incredibly
memorable yeah well I had the number of
those things okay whether to the good
positive side of to the yeah w wow you
know it enhances your um experience I
think okay Canabis does and so in the
best kind of moments well yeah it makes
everything more beautiful okay
everything you you you feel like
U yeah it's a it's divine feeling okay
that's why I think it's a very spiritual
thing so I was I had a fortunate to do
some traveling and like I say okay
sometimes cannabis can really enhance
your uh awareness of being there and
feeling the environment tap into it you
know like be in the moment like uh you
know and it can also take away a lot of
things you know when you to totally
obliterate it you know I had so when I
for instance when I met these people so
it was before GPS and things like that
so you know sometimes I drove back from
them and I lost away because I was so
[ __ ] High ending up in the like
in the mid zone of holl while I'm having
to the South like not really realizing
it and suddenly like what where am I
things like this okay but also the best
way possible okay you know so um so I
was high on like I'm always high I think
okay since I was 18 years old I kind of
indulged in in the Cannabis Fe and so
it's like yeah it enhanced my life
completely as a whole okay and uh for
the good or for sometimes the the
challenging one because it's also Al
confrontational like I say okay it's not
also an easy Legacy to carry when you're
working under under stigmas like you're
a criminal or something while you're
really actually loving something and and
you know what it's for okay and when you
make people high from it that's also
something I like very much about being
able to treasure something uh that's
really valuable and being able to share
it okay so people that access my flowers
and sometimes my work they really
appreciative okay and sometimes I had a
fortunate and the pleasure also that
people took their time and effort in
coming to visit me here okay like people
you meet on the board and then they come
here and Sample your what you have and
then yeah you know like there so the
Gratitude you get from it it's really
great okay it's like really fantastic if
you have something that really you know
have an effect on people's uh emotional
and mental awareness for the good you
know it's like a very um thankful and
humbling thing also to be part of that
okay that's why we do it also so the
getting high and gathering with people
the deeper connections you make now also
more abroad and everything people coming
together I think you know this
likeminded vibe that you share it's
really great and mizing I think it's one
big good thing also also medicinal and
everything okay for me this plant is the
healing of the nation and so so um yeah
I guess a lot of people don't want to
hear it or see it I don't know why okay
maybe you should drink a little bit less
and smoke a little bit more but
anyway hi
digress I love it I love it I love it
okay uh so the next one is what's uh one
situation where you've been really
excited to try something it's been hyped
up everyone's telling you it's great a
strain and then you finally get to try
it and you're not really impressed well
like 99% of everything actually okay I'm
sorry I might be privileged to comp
having to compare it with like Elite
cultivos I'm not saying so the Maxa that
was a variety I tried I got also sent to
by that I really like that one in high
but I sadly lost it so but Maxa was one
that stood out for me over the time and
of course the band 87 I said it of
course um
um well I tried many okay I
also there were many good ones but
Keepers really only yeah hard to um it's
also because I work under this
legislation okay so I cannot keep
everything because I would love to but
uh so it's hard so I'm thinking I'm
thinking you know I had some
um really yeah so one of the things also
that blew my [ __ ] mind I went
to span this year years ago and so this
D thing came up right I wasn't really
used to it so then another Canadian
there and had also the T so I took nine
tabs you know in a row well that
obliterated me kind of you know
like since then I'm aware of what D is
let's say okay just uh to to rephrase on
the on the former question actually but
um yeah what can I say okay about these
hazes
so I think youve uh you answered it
earlier on it was a good answer for sure
uh the the next question I've got for
you is I'm going to drop you on a desert
island and you can take three strains
with you for the rest of time it can be
the Clones or a pack of seeds if you
want what three things are you going to
take with you well you know [ __ ] man
things then that's difficult one to an
island cannabis related things let
secluded to that well of course this
nepales highit can out you know if it's
ever accessible again I would like that
to have like a stash full of it so it
lasts a lifetime let's say okay and of
course good ganja yeah man if I would
choose I would go for C5 because he's
the queen but you have to you know like
so C5 was most accessible for us before
we retrieved the other clones we only
had C5 and has BL H for a number of
years here well that's how I learned to
grow it to Finas like because you you
know couldn't has any other things but
this completely aside we had then this
best C5 but you know when you have only
one thing to smoke no matter how good it
is you don't have any uh point of to you
know like to compare it with okay so
it's like you get bored with it
essentially okay so variety is the spice
of life only three things so I will
break the rule I need like more things
okay to go to the you know seriously
otherwise it will be seriously i' have
to stay here then I'm not going to that
Island I'll accept it that's the first
uh answer of that nature I've heard and
we'll allow it so on the other end of
the spectrum you're going to drop
someone else off on the island someone
you're not super fond of they've uh
they've dirtied the Jean Pool what three
things are you going to leave them with
on the
island you know they should really
educate themselves what can I say okay
maybe you know I could drop them with an
educational thing about this whole thing
and you you make them read and then they
can go back from that island and you
know like uh put in the necessary work
okay it's not that difficult and
complicated you know first they need to
acknowledge it and take it for a reality
okay otherwise I wouldn't you know say
it also it's just like a call out that I
make because you know as a homeg grower
and Essence imagine you paying like 80
or 100 bucks or whatever to buy some
seeds and you get them
and they are infected and imagine you
have like a few Keepers there you're not
aware of it and it ruins your whole
Library okay for these people it is a
disaster okay and so maybe pay attention
and see really if the parential are not
infected and if they are yeah then you
know like do put in the necessary to not
spread this because for a lot of Growers
well it's a nuisance let's say okay and
that's a sad thing because yeah put in
the effort and when you plant like theor
it's on you and you have no awareness
from what it is so the people that are
aware in this business should be aware
and take precautions so that it doesn't
happen Okay and then everybody's
happy and that's the notion about it
okay that's
all I love it I love it we're changing
the words not the vibe so the final
question is I've got a time machine for
you you can go back anywhere anytime to
get seeds clones whatever you want where
are you going to go what are you going
to
get oh my god
seriously
[Music]
well in retrospect knowing what we know
now you know the heritage of what nille
did there was very important okay but um
I think these seeds how so it's all like
I wasn't there so I cannot verify any
story yet but um so imagine the seed
that he had back then if you would have
the technology like to sprout them all
and not just get like uh five or six
firew plants out of it but like you know
like maybe a 100 a thousand well you
know that would be a world of change and
difference so it's hard to kind of you
know like I don't know it all originated
also somewhere in in in various places
on the world and brought has brought
together so like um you know I think in
the 60s what happened there was kind of
really revolutionary also in um
spreading awareness around the Western
World about being more tolerated towards
this plant you know with the bnck
generation starting it and then the
hippie momentum and everything that
resided from there you know over time we
this plant came so it was cont became
in the 30s and we all know why it was
for after
the when they ban alcohol and so they
needed another scap goat thing so it's a
RAC it's a racist story it's actually a
very sad story and how this plant became
um demonized let's say but um now that
it's back kind of in our spheres uh we
can normalize it and then um you know it
be becomes another thing okay well what
seeds I would say the 60s were crucial
so really these Haze Brothers whoever
they were well their seed talk yeah I
would kind of like to access them let's
say that whoever they were in the 60s
throughout the 70s these guys seats yeah
I want to access this access them in
pure form but like in large numbers and
do like [ __ ] broad selection out of them
I think it would be like yeah it's a
dream for everybody I think okay
something like that yeah something like
that so the haze brother seats I want to
delve into so that would be like late
60s yeah yeah what a brilliant answer I
love it I'm sure there'd be some gold in
there no doubt so I think that just
about brings us to the end of it for
this one do you have any comments or
shout outs you want to make yeah shout
out to my friends here locally and uh
especially also a tribute to my exwife
because we were a long time together and
she is still my uh partner in that sense
and also so so the good people I
interacted with over time you know I
built some really good connection that
I'm really happy with and so I can only
um hope that we all do our best to um
kind of change the legislations that are
still needed and we can then build our
way to have a an enhanced gene pool so
we can all have our personal preference
of cannabis available in our own seed
stash and grow it ourselves okay that's
what we're aiming for and working for
every and any day in our lives okay to
liberate this plant and to have a
widespread um genetically
availability and we do our thing with
the hazes and with the nldd varieties
and we will hope to continue to do it
and everybody that assists me and the
community around me of these beautiful
people well you know who you are I would
say thank you for everything and uh
let's continue our Voyage
together what a beauti beautiful
sentiment so again a big thank you to
the European old school head
preservationist Keeper of the A5 C5 hash
plant Haz and so many more big thank you
to Yo Samy Sam for coming on the show
today thank you it was a
pleasure there you have a guys what do
you think as usual massive shout out to
Sammy for taking the time to come on the
show share all the
knowledge and a massive thank you to you
guys for making it to the end if you
want to help support the show support
our sponsors CT now number one C Bank in
the industry you know them you love them
all the best breeders the hottest drops
guarantee on satisfaction not just
germination why delay guys I promise you
will be stoked if you get some seeds
from them they only stop the best in the
game likewise a massive shout out to our
friends at Pulse sensors all the best
and latest sensors in the game including
their New Pulse Hub which integrates all
of their units together to ensure that
your operation is on point producing
bigger yields better turs higher potency
whether you're running a single tent a
single room or a Multistate operation
pulse are here to help you guys get
serious get a
pulse further shout out to coper the
number one leaders in Sustainable
biocontrol Solutions for pests and
disease if you're battling spidermites
please check out the spidex vital saches
I can't tell you how annoying it is to
have to spread carrier material in your
garden just to get the Predators out
these new sachet circumvent that just
hang the sachet in your crop let the
personnelist walk out do the work for
you trust me guys you won't look back if
you give it one go you will see the
quality you will be converted a massive
shout out to copit we appreciate your
support so much these guys are industry
leaders check them
out huge shout out to our friends at
Organics alive number one for powdered
organic fertilizers if you think
thinking about giving Organics AO get on
board their products make it so easy
whether you're in veg transition or
Bloom they've got products that make it
easy to dip your toes in the water
likewise if you're a seasoned veteran of
Organics I promise their products will
help take your next crop to a whole new
level massive shout out to Organics
alive they have some of the best
products on the market really fast
release because they're small particle
size you will not go wrong with Organics
alive hit them up massive shout out and
thank
you finally a big shout out to our
friends at dap just a week or two ago
they came out with some new models the
titanium M Series in two different
colors you can get yourself the nebul or
the quantium I've been rocking the nebul
I love it guys please give it a go if
you've ever tried a vape and felt like
it didn't hit the way you were looking
for it these ones will truly a game
changer based out of the US owned in the
US dap truly one of the best Vaped
companies on the market I really really
love their products and we are super
appreciative of their support massive
shout out to
DAP last but not least massive shout out
to the patreon gang thank you so much
for your support if you want to help
ensure the show continues to happen
please consider checking out
patreon.com theep podcast you will get
early access to upcoming episodes
unheard exclusive interviews and you go
in the running to win a whole range of
Swag each month we give away genetics
cannabis artwork a whole range of
awesome products all while ensuring the
show continues to happen again a massive
shout out to the patreon gang we love
you so so so much thank you thank you
thank
you that's about it for this one my
friends I will catch you for the next
one thanks so much for hanging out heavy
days signing off from the upside down
Library we'll see
[Music]
you