foreign
[Music]
welcome to the next episode of the
podcast a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts
as always these episodes could not
happen without the Fantastic support of
our sponsors
[Music]
seeds here now you know I'm in love them
best in the business if you're looking
for a North american-based seat option
featuring the latest and greatest
breeders all the hottest drops and guess
what they got an incredibly Schmick new
website with fantastic new prices
they've been slashing the cost of
everything to give you the best deal
while still offering their guarantee on
both satisfaction and germination don't
delay best in the business thank you so
much
likewise huge shout out to our friends
simply souvenirs our homies holding down
the fort in Europe if you're in the UK
or Europe and you're looking for a
hand-selected range of Boutique genetics
from both local and international
breeders check out Simply souvenirs they
have the best customer service in the
game as well as new drops occurring on
the regular including some amazing
smoking accessories Vapes dab
accessories and rigs so much more check
them out Simply souvenirs we appreciate
you guys
oh
in order to make a name for yourself you
not only need to find and make some good
genetics you need to run them properly
check out our friends cope at biological
systems they have all the best Solutions
in the game for all pests and pathogens
the best way to keep your garden happy
healthy and pumping on all cylinders is
to be proactive don't wait for an
infestation guys get on to it now grab
yourself some massive RM if you're
worried about aphids or some spidex
vital if you've got spider mite issues I
promise you guys knowing that your
garden is pest and pathogen free is next
to heavenliness there's nothing better
than a high quality crop that is 100
free of contaminants and Shout Out
Copart biological systems we appreciate
you guys so much
likewise you've got to make sure you're
getting the most out of your guards and
for that we need to give a big shout out
to our friends at Pulse sensors if
you're after more yield more resin
higher quality concentrates and flowers
you need to get serious about your
growth so get a pulse there are many
hidden variables that can hold your grow
back but you simply may not even be
aware of VPD is a common one you can't
feel it you can't see it you don't know
about it but let me tell you your plans
do if you get a pulse sensor and dial
the parameters in you will see your
plants responding in front of your eyes
from a single tent to a single room to a
multi-facility operation don't hold your
next crop back get serious get a pulse
sensor
[Music]
a huge shout out to the patreon gang if
you guys want to get early access to
upcoming content unheard exclusive
interviews with some of your favorite
guests as well as access to ad-free
content and genetic giveaways going down
monthly check out the patreon
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
[Music]
all right all right all right my friends
we're back for part two of this special
installment with snow High the
incredible genetic genius behind snow
High seeds
I hope you enjoyed part one if you
haven't heard it go back and jump into
it before you hear this one it'll make
more sense
[Music]
so without further Ado let's get into it
so you just referenced the uh the OG and
the Skywalker the I've heard rumors of a
few different Skywalkers going around
I've heard one that it's like just a
straight OG but I've heard that there's
another one that goes around that's
actually like the original one crossed
to Bubba or something like that and and
that's also called Skywalker and it's
very good do you know the one you're
fond of is that like the very
straightforward OG one or does it seem a
little different to you
well when when I was growing these and
breeding these this was like the height
of the doji Kush crazes you know
um as far as the medical clubs having
them so there's like the height of the
medical club scene
um
I have you know I got them before they
were like super popularized the
Skywalker also a lot of people thought
there was one done by like Barney's Farm
or something which is like blueberry and
something mazaro and blueberry that's
not Skywalker OG Skywalker it was just
meant as you know A high-flying og you
know that's why I was called Skywalker
not because it was part of like some
Dutch hybrid
um Skywalker and some of the ogs
um they're different than each other so
there's like the the triangle push out
of Florida there's uh OG Kush out of uh
Southern California there is the Tahoe
um they all look different so what what
is happened is these are all familiar
these are all strains that are very
familiar to each other because the
genetics are very similar but they are
definitely different they grow
differently they look differently and
they smoke differently but they have
similar character you know
characteristics
so a lot of the what people call OG
cushes are different lines that are
similar you know they are
Afghani Pakistani in lines with maybe uh
some tie-in involved in there it's hard
to say exactly but the Skywalker grows
and looks differently than the Tahoe
Tahoe looks similar to uh like pure kush
um
the San Fernando Valley looks similar to
Bubba but they're they're different
um
Master Kush looks similar to San
Fernando Valley and uh G13
um
but you know there's there's different
varieties that are very similar to each
other but they're definitely different
and the problem is a lot of stuff that
was popularized was from bag seed so a
lot of people got bag seed and they grew
those out as the strain and then that
was what most people got their hands on
and even with you know um bag seed the
plants will look different you know than
the mother you'll have different
variations or it came from a impromptu
fertilization of different lines that
were growing you know they it harmed on
another you know clone that they had and
then he has some like multi-poly hybrid
of a you know a cush variety
um so the the problem is there was no
real breeding done with a lot of these
varieties so you know it's hard to say
what it was what it was like that's why
I breed with certain
land race and heirloom lines so I create
lines that I know the you know the
pedigree otherwise a lot of people are
arguing like oh no that's my clone that
was my work it's all hearsay but
um you know and I don't want to fight
with people there's no point to it so if
you want to create something created
from original you know lines
um but you know there's there's it's
just at this point there's been so much
mix that they call
um you know OG Kush but OG Kush is
actually several different varieties
that have the same effects and same
looks and tastes
yeah that's a good point
I guess I'm wondering you know can we
expect to see you then work with any of
the other more sort of modern strands I
know you've done a cross with cookies
before but I haven't seen any runs or
gelato do you think you'll incorporate
more of the popular stuff or just stick
to the more old school
um I I could do the other lines where
I've always had like Girl Scout cookies
we we grew the first uh cutting
available at the time I call it panty
dropper
um
I didn't release the seeds much some
people got some packs but there's the uh
the panty dropper and the panty dropper
special edition
um
so uh yeah there it's Girl Scout cookies
with the uh
the two males that created the the true
gangster cush uh that's that's the panty
dropper and the special edition is uh
the panty dropper with the Hell's Angel
um line which is doji Kush with the true
gangster cush light
um
and those need to be Revisited and kind
of worked out because the instability of
the Girl Scout cookies was it was uh you
know
um driven poison in OG Kush with the
Cherry Pie and there was some backseat
issues you know it was created from
hermaphroa it did A reproduction and so
instead unstable to begin with then
that's not kind of great for you know
creating lines from
um you need a stabilized line and then
release it
um
if I'm going to use a cutting I'm going
to grow it out and then see if it's
worth
you know the trouble like the Pink
Panther was kind of a
unstable line but trying to breed with
it to stabilize it some for the
qualities that it had was worth the time
because it uh produced some medicinal
um get smokable flowers you know the
flowers turn purple and red and had a
beautiful
um grape liqueur uh smell and taste so
it's like a grape oat ji Kush but it
grew better and yielded better but it
also has some CBD to it so it had some
medicinal qualities that were similar to
um
the anti-seizure CBD strain called
Charlotte's Web it had the same ratio of
like three to one CBD so it was
medicinal at the same time
um
yeah so yeah there may be some uh in the
future some of the modern stuff but why
everybody else is doing that you don't
need another person doing it unless
there's going to be
um
you know an increase to the line I'm
going to improve it in some way like
with uh the East Coast Sour Diesel there
were so many sour diesels on the west
coast that there were [ __ ] to grow they
weren't worth growing because they
didn't have the Full Flavor Of The Sour
Diesel you know they didn't have the the
sourness the the smell the taste Aroma
but they were Sour Diesel ish and that
was what was going around as clones for
sour diesel so it wasn't worth growing
it yielded well but you know it didn't
it wasn't Sour Diesel like it should be
the East Coast Sarah diesel clone was
tired
um it didn't yield well or root well
um but had the smell flavors of the
great perfect high so basically I wanted
to work with something Fresh So I self
did
um
and then I created a couple females from
that picked the best one the first
generation with the Neville's Hayes
purple time male
um you know they're 50 50 sometimes
they're they're there's some good
females and some of them are kind of you
know not so good so I had to pick the
best
um plants from that first generation
into the f2s and f2s is what I released
as the West Coast Purple Diesel so you
get those you know qualities the East
Coast are these are what those good
traits of smell the sourness uh that
fantastic high resin production Aroma
but with good rooting big plants big
buds it's everything you'd want from
what was supposed to be Sour Diesel but
without the problems not to say that
recessives won't pop up but you're going
to have a more stable line which will
give you all the characteristics that
you love from Sarah diesel and that
would be the only reason to kind of
revisit some of these lines that are
popping with people
yeah interesting are you in General open
to like s-wining old clones and just
sort of trying to revitalize them like
that I know that CSI no okay yeah good
tell us more no no I I don't I don't
like uh selfie anything because it
if you're gonna sell something it should
be true breeding because if it's not
you're going to be inviting problems if
you're selfing or you know feminizing
plants that aren't stable when you grow
them out you can have all kinds of
issues they're not going to be exact
replicas they're going to be all over
the place and that's the issue
um
you know if you're going to do that
might as well just make you know regular
seeds
um because you're gonna invite
instability and um
intersects traits into a plant which is
unstable to begin with and then you're
going to be having people that aren't
expert Growers
um that are stressing out the plants
creating more plants from the the
intersex traits that are gonna
invariably pop up from these unstable
plants and it's just a mess that I don't
care to get into unless I'm trying to
save a plant
um you know if there's only like one
plant then there's ways of you know
selfing them going to those lines
finding the males and females from the
selfing process and then slowly breeding
towards something that is stable from
that you know uh selfie of that line
that's you know lost or uh extinct you
know if there's only one plant left and
I'll come into that problem where I had
only
um you know a few plants and then those
plants that were with it that were the
same line died I only have one plant
left and then I had to breed uh similar
plants like the Acapulco Gold Line I
bred which was two different Acapulco
gold mines but I could have self them
and then you know hopes for males to
breed with the females to eventually
make them more stable ions so in that in
those cases I am uh I think selfing it
has this place and then for tired lines
uh like there was uh a string called
Afghanistan it was grown for like 30
years from Kansas
um you know when you breed with that
line you make seed
um the seeds don't last as long because
they're from a tired old clone
um and the viability of those seeds is
even shorter so
um you know creating an S1 of that and
then breeding would might be the the way
to do it but creating you know growing
from that old clone uh these clones are
just replicas you know copies of copies
of copies you take a copier and take a
picture it gets blurrier blurrier uh
same thing happens with these clothes
they're just not the same as it once was
um and they need to be refreshed once in
a while they need to grow from a new
seed and be refreshed otherwise they're
just very tired old seeds or old seed
lines and there's issues to them
yeah that's a great point and we've had
guests in the past say that one way just
speculated that um you might be able to
sort of revitalize these plants is to
let them veg Under the Sun if they're
indoor plants at all I guess given your
library with so many old school clones
what do you do to maintain those old
mothers and is there any special tips
like the sunlight one you have
um well it depends on where you live so
if you're
um you know far enough South you can
actually grow plants all year round
Outdoors
um depending on your environment or with
the help of a greenhouse to extend your
growing season you just need to use a
little nitrogen to kind of put them back
into veg chemically and then
um leaving enough growth on them to
you know maintain growth until the um
the sun is into a place where it starts
vegging again
um
so you I've had plants growing Outdoors
uh one of them is chocolate time I've
ran for three years Outdoors but I've
had
uh what was it I had another one that
went for seven years
um and just kept growing It Outdoors
um you know to see how long I can grow
it
um
and that happens like in Nepal you get
these plants that have been growing for
decades and they get to be you know
three four stories above the house you
know in Nepal and these huge plants and
that doesn't just happen over like one
year it happens over you know years and
years of it growing
um
but
as far as maintaining the plants uh it's
hard to keep a library of all these
different plants so um I think that you
should make a line that is
um strong with males and females so you
can preserve the line of seeds and then
that way you don't have to keep clones
of it you can keep the special plants
but it's really difficult to keep a
library of you know all these different
plants it's just too much stress and if
you have health conditions like myself
it's almost impossible to do because you
might have days or weeks where you're
not able to tend to the plants so you
know things happen you know as far as
dust plants and you don't have anybody
attend to them so
um the other thing is is micro micro
propagation doing like in vitro tissue
culture more people should try to get
into that where they can maintain things
with uh you know a little plantlet a
little stem and maintain plants that way
and I think that that'd be a good way
moving forward for people to have large
collections in a smaller place
um you know to be able to maintain those
things you know
um seed oil seeds will be able to be
um germinated a lot easier with those
type of methods as well so you know
trying to get lost seeds seed lines that
aren't able to germ any other way is to
you know propagate them that way
wow that sounds like some cool stuff I
know a lot of people have been chasing
the um
what is it the artificial embryo sort of
for well and truly sort of dead seeds
but in your personal Library what are
the oldest seeds you have and what are
some that you're sort of keen to look
into that get you excited
oh man I have seeds that are back from
the 60s
um
60s 70s 80s 90s
I have a bunch from different periods of
time
um
yeah I have old Acapulco Golds I have
old Panama Reds
um you know those and I've got a bunch
of other old Mexicans that are just
you know who knows how old they are uh
but
um they need special
um you know propagation methods
um yeah there's a lot more and it's not
telling you everything but there's a lot
of cool stuff that would be great to
revive and um you know I'm working on
methods to try to
um revive those old lines so that we
could all enjoy them again but basically
they're extinct to this point until the
method is
made better to attempt to bring those
back so the processor it's it's a work
in progress at the moment but I've been
able to work on Old seeds I've been able
to germinate you know 30 30 plus old
seeds
um so that's
you know that's not an easy thing 10
year old 20 year old see it's not a
problem that's kind of
you know typical
wow that's really impressive I think a
lot of people are finding it's
definitely becoming more challenging to
to pop seeds that are getting older do
you have any tips for people who are
trying to pop some old seeds there's
another method too the seeds that were
created from organic methods meaning
they were like sun grown seem to last a
lot longer than seeds that were
chemically made like with chemicals
indoors a lot of people find viability
of like seeds that were created indoors
usually like chemicals but only lasts a
couple of years
um you know with sun-grown seeds you can
grow them six to ten years no issues and
if they've been stored well they can
even grow them you know keep them for
longer periods of time
um for germinating seeds for old seeds
um
it's sterile methods
um same thing as like the scarification
um you can use there's lots of different
methods some of them might work some of
them might not but the only thing that
kind of pushes things past now dormancy
is um gerbilic acids but the problem
with gerbilic acids is uh that if you
use too little it does nothing if you
use too much you end up killing the
seeds
um and if you find the right amount
you're still dealing with like
elongation like long you know
Sprouts in issues that way which you
know if you got an old CD that's no big
issue but it's hard to find the right
ratio to germinate seeds that way but if
you only got a couple seeds you could
end up killing the seeds so it's almost
not worth it but I'd say
um
softening the seeds with like a
disinfectant like hydrogen peroxide 50
50.
um and then pulling off the seed coat
after uh two to three days uh taking the
embryo and then doing in vitro would
probably be the best method after you've
um you know disinfected it
um and then you need a certain augers
and hormones to be able to uh
you know germinate those seeds in auger
solution like you would for tissue
culture
yeah wow brilliant very high tech answer
I love it I love it so in general this
is a bit of a curveball one but I
thought you'd have a probably a good
take on it what's like the most wildly
unexpected results you got from popping
like a land race or like an heirloom
sort of line just really left the field
hmm
I found I've popped seeds that had like
double embryos like it was uh two plants
in one seed
that was kind of cool
um
you know like getting two different uh
germination Sprouts out of one embryo
seed
um you know
um oh yeah usually one is weaker than
the other you know but uh
it'd be interesting to see how those
would turn out you know from beginning
to end if you know one was more potent
if one had certain traits or if one was
more female and the other one's male
I've had like a loud strain which
um it topped itself and then on one side
of the plant which is what had one one
root but it basically went up and
snapped in half and then one side
was all female with female flowers and
then the other side was male so it was
like a monacus plant
on one plant
so it was you know one sex on the other
it wasn't an intersex but it was male
and female on the same plant you know
self-pollinating itself so I found that
to be cool yeah wow that's that's really
neat but as far as germination processes
um you know I don't know there's nothing
real special about germination it's
you know
uh I like to pull them off and you know
I use like a pinching motion to kind of
pinch off the the films
um off the uh the embryos so once you
pull off the seed shell there's a
there's a film which you can kind of
pinch off
um and then you know it basically comes
out you know you have the little Sprout
like a little embryo Sprout I'd say
don't be scared of that a lot of more
people should be popping their seeds and
removing the seed shells because you can
get a higher percentage to um germinate
once you've
um you know removed the shell the
problem is it's kind of a you know it
sometimes you end up squishing them or
destroying them but if you don't if you
wait too long more than like three days
the embryo will become too soft anyway
and it'll just you know mold or squish
very easily so you got to do it within
the two to three day period there's a
small window which you can actually move
them and you know they'll hold together
um but sewing those in a sterilized uh
soil will improve germination
um so you you'll get maybe you know a
few more plants and sometimes you get
all your plants germinating if you
didn't you'd only get a few sometimes
um so I'd say people should practice on
seeds
um that aren't as valuable to them and
you know practice removing the seed
shell and then removing the film and
then sewing those seeds I think that's
something that people should do
um for all their seeds after a few days
otherwise they're going to rot in the
soil or dry up
um yeah and I think digging up the seeds
if so if you sow the seeds directly in
soil you should also dig them up after
uh two to three days and do the same
clean them off remove the seed shell
remove the film and then sew them back
into the same spot they were or in fresh
soils because sometimes if they're the
soil is too moist uh that you'll need to
um
um you know provide another sterilized
soil the other thing is providing little
fans over uh the uh germinating places
so if you have uh seeds in like a
starter tray or in beer cups you should
have a little fan providing circulation
over them so it kind of dries them out
otherwise the heat from the the lights
or the sun and the the moisture in the
soil will cause molding which will cause
a damp off which will kill the plants or
the seeds and seedlings so having a
little a good air circulation is very
important for germinating seeds a lot of
people don't do that and then their
seeds die and then they you know blame
the breeder
yeah definitely look I agree that people
need to learn to become their own little
seed surgeons I lock yourself save the
number of seeds that probably wouldn't
have made it otherwise but I mean while
we're on the topic of saving plants I
wanted to know what's the oldest plant
you've managed to save and hang on to do
you have like a super like 30 year old
cutting what do you got
no I don't
um
I've had old cuttings given to me by
other people but I typically like to
preserve a line in seed form because
it's easier to store and travel with
um
because it's just too much energy to
maintain clones for years and years and
years uh there should be a reason you
know unless it's something special that
you want to keep around
um majority of stuff I like to to
preserve in seed form just because uh
you know if something happens you've got
to back up that way uh otherwise you've
got to spread those clones out to
friends if you don't give out your your
clones to friends then you lose that
line
uh just like I lost the chocolate pie um
during my my aunt's passing of cancer
um if I had been able to pass it out to
people I would have been able to
possibly get that back so sharing is
actually a good way of keeping the
genetics and even be able to get it back
at some point
yeah certainly I've learned that myself
in the past unless you shared out there
you risk losing it so some Sage advice
there and while we're on the topic one
of the fan submitted questions we got
said please ask snow hi to talk about
doubles chocolate Thai and the Golden
Dragon
Golden Dragon
I don't know any about any Golden Dragon
uh oh uh gold dragon my strain I guess
yeah
the the dro Dro is is my friend's
um name backwards
so it's his name backwards
yeah yeah Howard yep yeah Howard so uh
Howard is you want my uh my wedding uh
he's a good friend of mine so Howard the
these came from chocolate tie these came
from chocolate tie sticks
um
so what people don't realize is it
chocolate type was named by the sellers
so here it looks like you know what
people have is chocolate Thai he's got
the uh I still have some of that uh
chocolate's High stick left too I need
to pull it out and smoke it
um but it's got a Musky Aroma tastes
like tobacco and chocolate
um it's got a euphoric effect a body
effect but it also has the Thai soaring
effects so it's
um kind of like a punto Colombian Punta
Rojo but it's like the Thai equivalent
you know it's got the the body effects
so
I had theorized that the chocolate tie
has was a lowland variety
um because it's got like um Indica
characteristics but it's not an Indica
um so it's got a chunky larger flowering
uh bigger buds
um
it's got the characteristics of you know
muskiness uh like a purple tie there's
also purple typhenos in it but it's not
as common
um
so uh that chocolate tie was from
chocolate Thai sticks and um it should
be grown out in
um larger selections done on it but it's
been a conservation of a chocolate Thai
stick wine
um and it is a great and super potent
line it may not look like much growing
that's the problem a lot of people have
is like they expect this narrow Leaf
Highland tie looking plant and it
doesn't grow like that and especially
when it's in veg
um because with a lot of sativas and
tropicals and equatorial plants
um the leaves are solar panels they in
veg they are trying to produce stem and
growing the plant structure so when it
flowers and starts to flower the solar
panels the leaves will go from like
seven to five to three to two to one
well three to one typically not two to
one but
um basically the the C the the leaves
will narrow so they'll get narrow and
they'll be less leaves and production
will go to producing cannabinoids resins
um turpins that type of thing and less
growth of the flowers and stem is done
in that period of of growth so people
don't realize that when they see these
plants in veg they'll have broader
leaves because the plant is creating you
know its roots and structure you know
it's not it's not yet producing the
flowers so as it flowers then they thin
out
um some of them are naturally thinner
than others some varieties like the
Highland varieties will have thinner
leaves but there's so many different
varieties of leaves
um you know some of them are super long
like um
like a eucalyptus or a weeping willow
um you know or long banana leaves
they'll be thick and long or they'll be
really thin and long
um but people have this thing in their
mind that these Thai varieties are very
narrowly thin
um and not there is some like that but
they're not all like that and they come
in different sizes and shapes
um
so that that is a chocolate tie line
derived from seeds from imported
chocolate High sticks that's the dro
chocolate tie and it's very potent it's
got a euphoric high it's colorful it's a
day brightener
um your shittiest day will be happy
um you'll you'll feel a lot better it's
colorful it can be really intense at
first but they kind of it lightens up a
little bit but it is a wonderful high
it's very resinous it's got a sickly
sweet smell and taste to it it's divine
but it doesn't look like much
um when you're growing it it looks like
it's not impressive not at first but as
it further goes into flower uh it
becomes more impressive as it goes but
when you're first growing it um and even
a veg and mid-width your flower it's
just not
it's just not an impressive plant like a
lot of lions you know a lot of lines you
go like oh I know that's going to be
great but
um not all plants are like that you know
you can't judge a book by its cover
um and that is a very impressive line
unfortunately a lot of people you know
uh think oh it it's not a Pure Line but
um in Thailand there's hybridization
done there's
growth there's there's Low Land
varieties there's Highland varieties
um you know there is a bottlenecking of
varieties there's so many things that go
on with plants that some of this has
been done in the past and people look at
it and go oh there's some Modern
characteristics to it
um especially if grown indoors so if you
see
um a plant grown indoors it may look
you know kind of like a modern plant but
if you took that same plant Put It
Outdoors the environment the Sun the
wind everything will make it look more
like it should you'll see these you know
very tall upright High looking plants
that are kind of you know bamboo like
um
or you know uh Japanese maple looking
you know the the different structures
Outdoors really brings out what a plant
should look like indoors it's a
controlled environment you're only
getting one aspect of what that plant
really could be unfortunately and then
people are flowering out these plants
with different light sources if you're
using LEDs plants end up being more
chunky shorter and they they Branch out
differently if you're using fluorescence
they kind of um you know will Branch out
look you know pretty good they just
won't be as dense using a metal halide
and they get very resinous and good
plants so using HPS they get very uh you
know squat and branchy um you just it
just depends on the light source you're
using for the looks of these plants not
only that
[Music]
um
indoor versus outdoor
um you know it all matters uh and that
the length of time a lot of people are
using too much light to grow their
plants they think oh more light the
better that's not necessarily true these
plants are like humans there's circadian
rhythms they need you know the darkness
and the light they need sleep they need
to have the restorative sleep where they
produce any of these
um precursors to create cannabinoids or
you know these things that protect
themselves from you know pests or
whatever it might be
um they're they're created when they
sleep so they need a a dark period so
you can't use like 24 hours of light and
think they're gonna be okay
um
you know resting the plants will
actually be improving on the plants so
you have to have the right ratio you
can't have too much Darkness you can't
have too much light
um you have to have something right in
the middle so that's why
um
I've developed ratios of light and
darkness so 10 and a half hours of light
and 13 half hours the darkness is kind
of like the sweet spot for most all
varieties around the world so if you
want something to work for everything
that ratio will work for flowering for
everything
and especially if you're doing it from
seed if you're starting off that way
even better
um they're veg to seed uh anyway if I I
can give people breakdowns uh I've
written uh documentation for anybody
that's wanting this uh if they want to
um contact me by email
that's incredible I'm gonna have to look
more into it myself I would like to ask
so sort of based on what you were saying
there what's your thoughts on orders
given they don't get uh much Darkness do
you think they'll ever be able to get to
a point where they're comparable because
people espouse that as the aspiration do
you think it is possible for
autoflowering cannabis to be like say as
good
yeah
um
autoflowering uh
yeah and you know there it's just a
hybrid they're using something that
flowers or it's an early flowering
hybrid Autoflower is kind of a Mis
misnomer you don't want to use a lot of
stuff that's hemp variety autoflowers
they're basically using stuff that's uh
flowering early so photosensitive
varieties
um so you can take anything that's
photosensitive and make it grow well as
long as they're you know using good
breeding practices it just depends
sure uh so what one of the common
questions we got from a lot of different
listeners in fact was they were
wondering if they could get some advice
because a lot of people want to try to
grow some of these like really wild
stuff but I but they're indoors and
they're like how do I do it you know
like I want to do it I just don't know
if it's possible do you have any tips
absolutely so one of the problems is
that a lot of these like books and stuff
that people buy is oh uh you take a
plant and you basically veg it for a few
days and then you flour it right away
that way they're shorter the problem is
that's not good because you don't have
enough roots that can deal with stress
and if you want to grow something you
need to veg the plant long enough to
grow roots so grow when you're growing a
plant grow The Roots train the plants so
by doing that making you know more main
stems like topping it forcing the
oxygens to create more Roots if you can
kind of put some focus on the roots
first by doing that and then repotting
them you know pull off the bottom of the
pot look at the roots use beer cups at
first that are clear so you can see the
root development
um you know examine the roots kind of
make sure that the soil isn't overly
moist and wet use a moisture meter you
know check the plant you know check the
the container several different places
make sure that it's you know dry enough
to actually water because a lot of
people over water and then there's no
root development it stunts the plants
and it pisses the plants off where the
Herm on you
um and mold and then die so the problem
is root development grow those roots
first and then flower them out and then
if you have the right ratio you can save
several weeks on these long flowering
varieties so if you're doing what a lot
of these magazines magazines and books
will tell you the flour 12 off you may
never ever finish your plant or it will
take forever to finish because that
light regimen doesn't
isn't uh in nature it's not something
that happens on Earth
you know there's no 12 hours of light
and 12 hours of Darkness anywhere on the
planet
so why would you do that in an indoor
grow it doesn't make any sense
um
so basically you have to have the right
ratio so if you use
um you know the right amount of Darkness
you can flower plants faster and and sex
them faster so if you're vegan plants
and then growing The Roots You can sex
them
and then revert it back to your veg
period so you can sex your plants know
which males females you have then you
can either clone the ones that you like
um
or grow those plants into the plants
that you want to a certain size or you
kill the plants that you don't want in
the pot more seeds if you need more of a
certain type or more numbers or males of
a certain type
that's a killer killer overview I'm
really Keen I was gonna say I noticed um
the Australian epic Haze it sounds
incredible do you do anything different
when you have those Ultra long flowering
types or again same thing just expect it
to end up a little bigger
majority of the plants will finish in 14
to 16 weeks even some of the longer
flowering varieties will finish in 16
weeks which is not so bad there will be
longer flowering varieties that will
take longer you can always take things
earlier but patience
um you know why grow something for eight
or nine weeks that will finish better in
in 14 weeks
um why take something earlier
if if the quality is not there
you'll find that something like a
Colombian that grows you know for 20 to
26 weeks in a greenhouse you know
finishes in March or April Outdoors
being like it takes a whole year of
growth and then flowering to finish it
will finish indoors faster because
you're able to manipulate the lights
um but if you're using a greenhouse
those last few months the colors will
come out the the Reds the oranges the
purples all this that beauty in the line
will actually present themselves the
resins that take long weeks to grow will
will be um
more present so you get these uh Turpin
and cannabinoid profiles that are just
amazing psychedelic and very Great
Expressions of cannabis you know very
delectable connoisseur
but if you harvest it too early you
won't get those expressions the other
issue is you need to know the variety
some varieties will finish faster than
others and if you wait too long then
it's
um oxidized and you'll have more of an
inferior product like some Mexicans will
finish Fast
um you know once they have the peak THC
content you know the trichomes are fully
developed you should harvest the
Mexicans because a lot of times if you
wait too long then it starts to oxidize
and then they kind of get dried out and
you know loses its quality so you just
need to know the variety and if you have
the right variety then you need a
harvest earlier at Peaks concentration
or you you wait the time it needs to
finish to to get the best qualities out
of it you just it just depends on what
time you're you're willing to put into
it and then grow the variety that you're
willing to put in that time you know if
you're not willing to put in 20 24 weeks
don't get a pure Colombian
um you know some Colombians will finish
faster
um but majority won't you know these
equatorial lines are at the equator
they're not as photosensitive as
something that is uh grown in the Hindu
Kush
um but Mexico is kind of something
that's more northernly higher latitude
and will finish faster but it's also
longer flowering but you know may finish
in
October versus December January February
March
yeah that certainly makes sense you know
picking according to what you're willing
to do as well as all these little
amazing tidbits of info there
I guess I would love to quickly ask you
though do you feel like you have to put
any consideration into what we might
broadly call the commercial viability of
your strains because as you said you
know people need to go into this sort of
knowing what they're getting into does
that ever hold you back or do you feel
like you just make what you want and you
know Let it go
well I don't pick strands that are uh
fast flowering I'm not picking strains
to finish Fast though there will be
strains that will finish faster
um I'm picking for quality and potency
above all else so those those are my my
criteria so if a person's coming with to
mean that they want a seven or eight or
nine week strain
I'm going to have
some things I could show them but
they're going to be limited if their
constraints are time frame because the
best qualities take a little bit longer
and if you're constrained to like
needing to harvest something in eight to
nine weeks then you need to probably
look somewhere else because
you know I'm not choosing things to
finish Fast I'm choosing for quality of
potency and those take a little time
typically you're not to say that you
can't find those faster phenotypes and
there are varieties that will finish
faster just the majority of the quality
phenotypes take longer that's just the
nature of things
certainly certainly
so if someone were to take a look at
sort of your overall back catalog of
work to me it seems obvious that there's
a more of a predominance of sativas than
indicas is this a reflection of just
your personal sort of preferences in
regards to flavor effect things like
that or is it more a case of like just
the stock you're working with and you
know other factors
well the majority of them is tables
because there's more sativos tropical
equatorials than there is indicas it's
just that's the world there's just more
of that than there are these other kind
uh
and the reason why I'm working for
certain varieties is I'm trying to
preserve varieties that may be lost so
I'm putting more emphasis on Mexicans
Hawaiians Colombians that the seed stock
is in short supply it takes a long time
to grow these lines and they're almost
lost so I'm trying to save these lines
so my my focus may not be on exactly
what I want to grow
but I'm trying to preserve it for the
future
um so that's where my focus is at
otherwise I'd I'd be growing a lot of
these faster flowering varieties and
pumping them out and trying to make a
lot of money
um which would be nice but I'm trying to
preserve these lines that take longer
because
if I don't they're gonna be lost
um and unfortunately because they take
longer um
instead of popping out something that I
can grow within a short period of time
and you know make a thousand couple
thousand seeds hundreds of thousand
seeds you know in a quick period of time
I'm taking you know years to grow
something that may not produce very much
um
and that's where people don't understand
is is that you're unfamiliar with how
long and how much work it takes to
create these lines
um that there's a lot of time involved
not just the flowering you know the
selection process the growing the
vegging
um
and uh you're just not making as much
seed and takes a lot longer to grow so
you know things take longer they they
cost more because it takes a lot more to
produce them
certainly that makes sense and we're all
very lucky to have someone like you
ensuring the preservation of these lines
I
um I have to admit I sort of engineered
that question well because I wanted to
get to this next one which was that one
of uh one of our guests uh they said
look you hear a lot about Afghan indicas
and maybe you know a bit of Pakistani he
said but you really don't hear too much
about indica's in the rest of the world
and occasionally you know Chinese little
blip on the map the Yuan
um what's your experience with indica's
outside of the conventional Afghan
Pakistan what's your thoughts unsung
heroes anything we should keep our eye
out for
oh Lebanese should be iodized some of
the best
um Lebanon has one of the oldest
cannabis cultures there was a um a
temple there to
um the the Mysteries you know for like
wine production in the ancient past
um but wine in the past was used as a
vehicle for preserving
um not only the alcohol but other
medicinal plants like cannabis so they
were able to take their canvas plants
and preserve them in wine and um
in that area they were able to grow
um cannabis and preserve them in the
wine and then in the winter they would
able to have their cannabis along with
their wines because they weren't
drinking water they were drinking wine
because it wasn't safe to drink water ah
that yeah that makes sense that's a good
point
so and in Lebanon they have an ancient
cannabis history or um you know that
goes back once so there are varieties
were selected for Generations in the
Levant which was like The Phoenician
um stronghold of that area so basically
that area is um you know they had the
ziggurats the Sumerians there's ancient
cannabis culture the area which is uh
the bulk region of Afghanistan was the
zohustrian area which isn't too far so
those Pro film pilgrimages from other
areas like Lebanon Syria which had hash
plants
um Egypt it also it had hash plants
indicas
um
you know parts of uh cashmere
um different parts of Pakistan they all
had these Indica varieties Iran has the
ancient Persian history they had
something similar to Soma India had the
Soma which was uh cannabis but the
Persians the ancient Persians and the
austrians had
um the heoma which is basically you know
the same thing and they had their Vedic
um type books as well uh indicating you
know this ancient cannabis
um you know Sacrament beautiful stuff
yeah so unsung indicas around the world
there are indicas in different places
like Mexico has hash plants Colombia has
hash plants
um different places around the world so
um it just depends China has some the
Yunnan Province
um there's a there's a lot of
variability not only do to
um its placement but it's it's
um altitude it's the lowland variety
some of them were able to um look a
certain way and some of them as they
went up higher in elevation they would
look you know
um differently so lowland varieties
tended to be more broad-leafed because
they're trying to capture more light
um and then the Highland ones were
actually more elongated and stretchy uh
because they were getting a lot more
like they had to deal with like high
winds so they had to be able to be a bit
more bendable on different things
um
it all depends you know your environment
plays a role on how the plants
acclimatize change
um you know some of these indicas may be
um
tolerant and resistant to humidity that
is from a cold dry environment or a cold
humid environment or hot humid
environment
so when people say oh this line is
um you know resistant to humid
environment you know is it a hot humid
or cold humid because if you grow the
wrong thing it'll mold real easy and you
won't be able to grow certain varieties
you know on the coast for instance that
grew in Hawaii in California
it just depends so these different
things of climatization matter and they
affect the qualities of these turpins
and the way they evolved
I uh I don't know how we're gonna get
there so I'm just gonna have to really
bluntly put it out there what's uh the
Old School Big Bud like was it ever good
like objectively or was it just big
yielding oh yeah
uh it was big quality wise it was old
school Mexican uh Afghani is what I
figure it is
um the the Mexicans were large the early
well the stuff even up into the 80s were
large plants
um you know some of them would have the
clothes desero which were
um tales of the the fox so Fox Tales so
everybody's colas get it's the name from
the Mexican word for colas de Zorro uh
the foxtails but they're only saying the
Tails portion the Mexican word for it
Spanish word for it
um but they used to a majority of the
Mexicans produced you know big bread
loaf looking Spears so you have these
big spear looking plants that were like
candelabra style or upright or these big
Christmas trees you know like giant
Pines uh that were 20 30 feet tall
um so uh the big bud was uh Crossing of
some of these larger yielding Mexicans
with uh some of the um early Afghani
stuff that was coming along
ah okay okay and how come you think it
died out
I'm sure some people are still growing
it I had it for a little while I lost it
but as anything
um if somebody's usually has it
yeah just hiding out I mean look on the
topic of someone usually has it there's
a huge push within the community to find
the roadkill skunk you think someone has
it
oh yeah I have some seeds that are old
school skunk but uh they're old so I'm
trying to germinate those bring them
back
um I had roadkill skunk back in the day
last time I had it
um offered to me was back in the 90s 97
um you know it was on the border of
Canada and Washington State uh that
stuff stunk so bad it was super hashy
the joints just kept putting themselves
out and it stunk like you know you ran
over a couple skunks I mean the juices
like that really nasty [ __ ] skunk and
yeah you really stoned it was credible
weed uh the stuff that people know is
like skunk number one is it's different
it's different something different
um
is similar
um but it's not the same thing what I
think the the old skunks were were
Mexican Afghani hybrids or
um you know Mexican Durban or something
like that but there was skunks before
uh the the label skunk number one was
available
oh and I'm working on uh I've got some
other skunk lines uh I did the Fester
skunk with but I'm trying to grow out
more of that but uh I've got some
afghanis that have the skunk properties
so uh if anything I'm gonna recreate my
own skunk so that's in the works as well
oh exciting now you got me wondering
what are some of your favorite afghanis
oh my God uh one of my favorite is the
petroleum head stash
um there was
um one that was it was an Afghani line
and from the guy that created um
harijuana he was a Steve talk no the guy
that actually did it that Steve tuck
made the seed line uh reproduced it
um but the guy who made it was in Ukiah
uh in California
um but oh wow this guy was growing
Mexican
um Mexican varieties in Colorado before
he came to um uh California
and um at the time uh the afghanis came
in they basically killed all the
Mexicans that they were growing and
started growing these afghanis which
were medium-sized Bush
um catalabra style bushy afghanis that
turned red and purple
um and he showed me pictures of these
things
um and the the petroleum head stash that
I grew was like fruit punch like
Hawaiian fruit punch
um super tasty
um euphoric body
uh body effects and Stone Anaheim at the
same time so it was like a clear uh
Afghani and that was that's what people
should want it's like a you know it's
not a narcotic effect it's it's
basically you know what people would say
like OG Kush is like a sativa It's like
got that up high but it's got the stone
and body effects at the same time so
it's like a concert clear
um
you know effect which is very pleasant
euphoric and that's kind of like what
most afghanis should be is like that
um
but the petroleum head stash there's one
that was done by reefer man and that one
isn't the same as the the inbred line
that I've had of the petroleum head
stash I think they're either two
different lines or that's something
different or it's a hybrid of something
else
um but the petroleum headset that I had
was like Hawaiian Punch
um or fruit punch and um just delectable
yeah I wish I had that again
um
anyway that that's that's what you want
is uh one of those
um
afghanis that has that
um Quality high in that you know kind of
sticks out you know it isn't like a
cloudy Stoney a narcotic drug type
effect
yeah beautiful stuff sounds great I wish
I got to try it I have tried heroin or
maybe not an original clone or who knows
wasn't verified but also some really
nice stuff yeah heroin here heroin is uh
there's a lot of variations to it and I
think that's because so many people got
their hands on it so it's hard to say
what's what
I think that one's killer New Haven and
the petroleum head stash
um I don't know how much of the
petroleum head stash is really in there
or which one
um
but uh if I can talk to the the breeder
again maybe I'll see if he's got any
original seats I'm supposed to bring him
some special afghanis
um that he's been looking for so you
know he's a an old
head that's been in the know for a long
time so
oh that's very exciting to hear
hopefully something comes with that
oh it it will he's easy to find and um
you know he's he's in the middle of
uh Mendocino there so
he's not a sea producer he doesn't he
doesn't breed you know most people don't
even know who he is he just he's just a
guy that
um tailors to the the community and they
wouldn't even know that he is uh you
know old school breeder
that's that's the same that goes with a
lot of these guys that don't seek
recognition but
um you know they've been doing their
work for years and helping out the
community because people don't realize
that they're you know their doctors
their business people their you know
their gardeners they're different people
and they're all out there
um and I wish they would share their
stories and either share them with me or
you know get that you know
get that story out there because a lot
of the sad stories that go along with it
you've really got to document it
otherwise it just gets lost to time
doesn't it right yeah absolutely and the
people that should deserve quite you
know uh you know
deserve credit should get the credit
yeah 100 100 so
take me back what was your first
experience with cannabis
oh man God what was it
um God
I I you know I I think this first was
like hash uh my sister had hash and I
probably smoked some of her hash that's
probably my first experience with
mushrooms and hash but the the true
first variety that I had was a Colombian
green that
um
my friend got it from his father
and this Colombian green was
um grown indoors and it was super
resinous but it caused uh that Colombian
choke
um and if you had this old Colombian you
you know because basically it takes the
wind out you smoke it and you're just
coughing up along this
um makes immense clouds of smoke
um you're barely touching um you know
with the flame the bud because you're
you're getting through the resin profile
but it's a you know it's a pure
Colombian
um
and uh man it was it was incredible
stuff that was just so potent after a
couple hits you're just uh
you're just kind of uh you don't want
anymore but you're just so high that
it's it's it's incredible
um that was some Columbian green and
that was like the first variety that I
had other than Mexican varieties which
were plentiful and many
um and all that was brown bread and when
I saw the green Bud for the first time I
didn't even know what that was
um I was like wow that's some green butt
that's some cool looking stuff and then
um the brown butt is what you know I I
was majority familiar with brown or red
or had different hair colors
um you know Green bud and brown bud was
the majority of what I grew up on and
when the killer green buds came in with
the afghanis
um
that was something different and those
there was a lot of uh variations some of
them were good some of them were so
hashy that uh they were asterid and
off-putting because there was no
selection and they were getting all
these land race afghanis and um you know
they were just trying to find
you know the good ones to grow but we
were getting like you know everything
and some of them were not always good
you know if you're doing selection some
of them are you got perfumey and Scentsy
asteroids gunky uh those Astrid ones uh
were just super hashy not tasty uh very
hard to consume
um but you know that's that's what
happens when you're you know doing
selections some of them are great some
of them are good and some of them are
kind of off
there you go and so what was the
progression from sort of that experience
to thinking I want to start growing
I started growing the Mexican seeds that
I used to get so
um I used to dig holes in the backyard
in the the back seat I would get for the
Mexican varieties because my cousins are
Mexican and we used to get different
Lots from their cousins so all their
different cousins and family were
bringing different types of in Mexican
weed up from Mexico
um you know visiting family members so
I'd grow it out in the backyard
um we're in Northern California you know
14 miles away from Mendocino County
um it was a perfect climate and then I
dig holes in the hill and then I take um
Greenhouse
Roofing which was semi-clear and laid
across the ground and I dig big holes so
I was doing these greenhouses that were
in the ground so as a helicopter a camp
helicopter would come by and look down
all this thing is like you know trash or
you know Greenhouse you know stuff
that's just on the ground or in piles
and they wouldn't realize there's you
know being plants being grown
underground in like holes so I was
um I'll grill a whole Grill grower and
that was my first Growing Experience of
these varieties some of them would be
above ground but I did a lot of stuff
indoors are in the ground for a while
and then I did uh I grew on a roof
um growing plants on a roof was kind of
sketchy
um because of planes but I try to put
them near trees or something like that
to kind of avoid them but they were
Mexicans so they were pretty tall and
other ones would grow next to pine trees
and they would get uh the size of pine
trees
um you know within a small amount of
time you know with the hot California
Sun things would get really quick I'd
get really tall really quick and so you
know one week you'd walk my plan and
it's a couple feet tall the next week
and it's freaking you know 15 20 feet
tall
with uh you know branches that as long
as a human you know 14 feet long
distance so these things get just as
wide as they get tall and they're
they're massively crazy big and uh I I
miss those things I need to find those
old Mexicans like that
that's really interesting to hear how
you did it back in the day do you
remember when the first sort of uh brand
name strain started rolling out like
strains with names or uh was it sort of
a progression yeah well I in High Times
I remember uh you know there was in
Thais and Mexicans durbins there was
those type of branding brand names were
like Durban Poison
um
I think skunk was known
uh I don't think Northern Lights and
that stuff hadn't been around yet not
until later
um
there was there was Hawaiian there was
Maui Wowie
um there was Panama Red
aquafical gold
um Colombian was colors a lot of stuff
with colored weed so there was you know
those Mexican red there was red hair
there was um
uh you know Colombian green there was
Colombian Brown those Colombian gold uh
there was Thai chocolate Thai
things had names or places where it came
from that was the majority of what stuff
was coming on when there was like you
know seed lines the cephan the seed
banks started coming around
um
you know I think
Northern Lights skunk I think those ones
were the first ones that came out
um Northern Lights with
skunk Haze skunk you know Northern
Lights I think there was all
combinations of the same stuff I think
the first
um
uh
like Cannabis Cup brought some of those
seeds being sold over here I you know I
I don't remember too much it was all uh
Tutti Frutti names people made up you
know that was it was but the seeds the
seed plant seed bank stuff I don't
remember until later on
in those early days were there any
breeders who you sort of looked up to or
were you so into it like you just hadn't
even heard of them no back then it was
so uh everybody's so paranoid that
um you know no you had to like have
family members and know people within
the family to like get anything it was
really paranoid
um very stringent
um you know anti-cannabis laws and you
know you didn't want to be busted with
anything at that time
um
you know uh so everybody kept to
themselves there was really a you know a
lot of paranoia everybody's a snitch um
you know people got busted for
you know seeds and stems and
not a whole lot so um no a lot of people
just try to keep to themselves or they
get busted you know if you if you didn't
know anything you couldn't tell anybody
yeah yeah very much understandable given
the harsh penalties so I guess I'm
wondering I how did you get the name
snow hi and B when did you decide you
wanted to start sort of formally
breeding and giving your seeds out
oh man
um this name his name snow High came out
my friend uh Dustin
um and I he was growing the snow cap he
got um one of the first clones out of
Fort Bragg and when the Growers
Mendocino were done growing it and no
one else was growing at Lake County
um
so when I was uh it came online in the
early 2000s
um it was just the strain that he had
been growing that
um I was selling down here and uh I just
used the name to see how many people
were familiar with the screen to see how
prolific it was around and not many
people had known about it not at that
time
uh so it just happened to be the name I
used as at the time of the set the
strain I was selling
which was a really tasty good strain at
least the first
um version of it that came out because
it soon became hybridized in The Taste
and everything went downhill but the the
real true Snow cap was mentholated minty
Menthol uh candied
um you know Wintergreen type smell and
taste and flavor you know tropical candy
it was very tasty and resinous had a
great fantastic high and grew nice big
Spears and this you know it was a it was
a good good plant but uh it was really
good at being able to deal with humidity
and mold so people were growing in Fort
Bragg
um
my father's uncle or cousin was growing
it in the town of Mendocino and that the
fog Bank was so thick
and Mendocino the town of Mendocino that
the plants were dripping with
um with condensation just dripping
because the sun was blocked out you
could barely see the sun because it was
like a little ring of you know a little
bit of light but it was so thick with
Haze and moisture on the coast of
Mendocino because it's right on the
coast of Northern California with all
the Redwoods but these plants these snow
cap hybrids were growing under like pure
condensation I mean he was taking a
bleach water solution spraying the
plants and that's how I was able to grow
with like almost no bite it was amazing
but those hybrids became more uh
prevalent and the majority of people
that got what they thought was like snow
cap was this hybridized version kind of
the real stuff kind of wasn't available
to people ah
anyway that's the video Hive was
basically uh snow cap and then um me
saying snow High I guess I I just
adapted the snow highs no caps no high
thing and then that Bodhi convinced me
to um
to sell seeds I was basically you know
selling to the clubs and doing my own
preservation work and you know doing
stuff for fun
um and my family's homes were uh being
you know the the banks were trying to
collect from them
um family went through some uh times
where they were in the hospital and
weren't able to work so I tried to save
my families
um Properties by selling herb and I did
that for a few years so that kind of got
me into selling the herb to save their
homes which I was able to do and then uh
seed stuff just kind of evolved with
that as well but mainly places but fun
and uh trying to do preservation
beautiful beautiful and is there a
difference between legendary genetics
and snow High seeds
well uh legendary genetics was supposed
to be for uh California it's no high for
the rest of the world when the uh
you know clubs weren't legal the
problems with covid covid kind of
destroyed all the the business that was
going to be done and established at the
time so a lot of
um
the work that Bodhi uh kagyu and Coastal
seeds and and myself we were going to be
uh
in the clubs in California
um unfortunately covet happened right
when we were getting into all these
clubs but the clubs went out of business
all the seed stock that went into these
places was lost
uh saw that time money and effort was
lost
um
but there was supposed to be a
a separation of the two so we could do
something here in California
um and then something for the world that
was already done previous to that
unfortunately kova destroyed a lot of
stuff and
um trying to uh get back to uh work is a
work in progress you know a lot of
people have had to do that you know
start over you know deal with their
losses unfortunately I've had health
problems
um along the way as well so it's a
double whammy when you're not well and
trying to do things that
um you know take effort
so one of the questions we got submitted
quite a fair bit from the viewers across
both Instagram and patreon was that they
were wondering these days how do you
Source new genetics do you find it's
becoming increasingly more difficult to
find good sources for stock
no
um
no I've always been the type that
I help out my friends and my friends
help me
um so I try to be good to people and
then people are also good to me so
um it's kind of a Karma thing
um you know if you're just trying to do
uh your intentions are good
um you know you should get something
back with the good intentions
um so I don't find it hard to find new
genetics but it's also there's a lot of
genetics that just need to be preserved
already that still need work so there's
no there's there's no time to lose
there's a lot of work to be done and not
enough time to do it
sure so in general would you Advocate
that people should be open to the idea
of like maybe traveling to some of these
native zones where land races come from
and sort of doing their own little
Expeditions or do you feel like overall
it's it's probably too diluted and like
maybe hard to find real stuff
it depends on what kind of person you
are
um
some places that are you know
historically cannabis producing places
have been dangerous for some people and
depending on your level of
um Danger uh your ability to deal with
diseases
um lack of food lack of services
may affect your ability to go and get
some of these things
um other times you can you can go on a
trip and find certain things but it just
depends on
um how you're trying to Source things
are you trying to get it from a reseller
or are you trying to go directly to the
grower up in the hills
um sometimes going directly to the hills
won't work because they've already sold
what they had to the resellers that sell
them at the beach say in Mexico so if
you go to the highlands of Oaxaca you
may not find anything there because
they've already sold everything that has
been sold at you know the local beaches
um and then the the cartels are
something to deal with because you know
you could end up with your body's head
cut off or something like that because
you're in the wrong place
um so this depends on the country the
place you're trying to go
um
yeah but I mean a lot of these there's a
lot of countries in a lot of places that
a lot of the the varieties are
disappearing so if you are historically
trying to help these people uh
documentation
um and and helping them is a way that
people could could do it you know
um
we're trying to figure out ways of doing
some people are trying to help the
people by providing you know vegetable
seeds and
um a way to sell those those foods and
try to make something for those
communities so they can be preserved
um unfortunately a lot of cannabis
producing areas have gone to like
poppies or other things because
um they're just trying to survive
because of drought because of the um the
laws
um or the the racism that's gone on that
kills like indigenous peoples
um
so we we need to say what's here before
it's lost because every year things lost
even a few years ago uh certain places
are producing cannabis are producing
cannabis anymore you know
um so there's there's a lot of loss and
these people need help and their history
needs to be preserved so
I say you could go to certain places
absolutely
um but um sometimes
you may going be going to a place that
uh you're not gonna be able to find
anything anyway so you need to do your
homework and um
there's got to be ways that we could
actually help each other and help these
indigenous peoples
um so
I think eventually we're working with
like-minded people around the world uh
we can help out these communities a
little bit better and maybe like a
global seed bank which the the funds
will actually trickle down to the people
actually should get it not just the
people at the top
do you think that something like that
will happen or it might be like
difficult to sort of get people on board
no I I I think it should happen and it
could happen
um it just has to have the right people
involved
yeah I'd be interested to hear your
thoughts on the recent legalization by
the Thai government I've often sort of
in recent weeks sat and wondered to
myself if there would be like a
Resurgence in sort of Thai terroir
produced land race and and like if the
quality of it would be any good or do
you suspect like you know people over
there are just going to grow like modern
you know stuff
it depends I mean the terroir type stuff
would be beneficial and it'd be good for
the people uh along the borders but then
you have the indigenous people that were
you know growing these varieties to
begin with
um they've been forced from place to
place anyway
um for hundreds of years so
um there should be protection for these
people and there should be uh ability
ability for these people to grow some
things but if they're growing
hemp on an island
uh you know and destroying the the the
lines that were indigenous that area
were acclimatized the area
um it's going to be like counter
defeating the issue but you know like
anything the people that are going to be
able to grow these varieties usually the
ones that have money
um so it's a tough thing it should be
kind of like
um a protection as well as
um like a historical type thing where
we'll preserve the knowledge of the
people along with the strains because
it's like um
you know it's like global history these
varieties so there should be protection
and uh the legalization will impart good
things and bad things it always does
yeah I'm certainly interested to see how
it plays out it'll be um it'll be really
cool to see if they started pumping out
like some like really intentionally
farmed Thai land race like what a
treasure that would be well I'm actually
trying to work with some of the people
there
um that are there now on you know things
like that as we speak so some of the
stuff I'm growing right now is from some
of the Resurgence of the tie lines there
preservation ties uh analyzing them so
that is being worked on
um I hope that we can do more of it and
then make it so that
they are preserved and not just you know
it's just a a grab for genetics because
it's more important than just the
genetics it's the people it's the
history there's there's more to it and I
hope to to be able to help some of that
if possible yeah look I'm sure you're
gonna have a monumentally positive
impact in it all out of curiosity would
you look to go in there and want to sort
of try to use the tie that's there that
might be available or would you want to
bring in like some of your own stuff
that you think are this may not even
exist there anymore
well there's there's always that so I
think there's enough time varieties
there that
they have enough but there might be a
few that maybe need to be reintroduced
but the majority of stuff they already
have it
um some places around the world I've
tried to introduce stuff that's been
lost like in in Mexico a lot of the
varieties that they once had needed to
be reintroduced so I've tried to
um send seeds to places that
um these varieties originally came from
and tried to get them re-established in
the property the same thing with wine
varieties I've been trying to send uh
Hawaiian Lions to people in Hawaii to
get them to grow these lines again
um
I don't know if it's
um naive or not but um you know
hopefully
there'll be some kind of resurgence for
these varieties being grown in a place
of origin Hawaii is kind of like not the
same thing but
um the idea is to bring back old
varieties like gold and the Guerreros
and the mutual cons and have them grown
by the people that have lost them some
of them have tried to get them out of
the country to save them because the
cartels have basically forced them to
stop growing these varieties
um
but they're trying to get them out to
preserve them or protect them
um the cartels are usually like young
kids like you know 12 13 16 year olds
all messed out and you know they create
like their own gangs like Zetas and
stuff a lot of these are just young kids
um unfortunately and they they get all
messed out and they go attack other you
know groups and kill each other and they
get Savage because they've been on meth
for so many weeks and months
um but they also destroy you know the
Cannabis production and then they go to
poppies or something else that's you
know quick to make money unfortunately
but these these lost lines need to be
reintroduced and saved
um and I think the only way to do it is
to kind of reproduce them somewhere else
and then bring it in and then hopefully
when things have stabilized some wet you
know have it spread to more of these
farmers
and that should be done in Thailand and
other places but some of it should be
maintained and you know you shouldn't
have been bringing in things you know
um like if you're on a strain hunting uh
Safari you shouldn't be bringing your
hybridized Dutch varieties and giving it
to the locals because it just pollutes
the gene pool
I'm so glad you touched on that because
that was going to be the next question
about our Dutch friends but um I would
love to quickly touch on because we've
had this discussion with a few people in
the past but someone mentioned you know
what what are you meant to take them if
you're not gonna take them seeds and you
know that's a great question we should
delve into it vegetable seeds well it
depends on the place that's like in
Nepal Bodhi was trading them vegetable
seeds you know something that they can
grow you're not bringing in
invasive strains you can get this the
the seeds there locally but you're just
providing more of what's already there
to Farmers that have you know no money
or a little money and you're providing
something that can grow for food
um food's always something that's you
know we take for granted because we have
supermarkets and most places around the
world they don't have supermarkets you
know even in Italy you have like markets
but they don't have like what we do in
in the United States or in other
countries where you can have these big
huge places with all these different
foods and meats and availability we just
live so much higher uh lives than a lot
of people do around the world we take
for granted that you know
seed stock of vegetables is is you know
desirable and much needed and food in
general
so that would be one thing it just you
find something that could be
um used by them that you know does take
up a lot of room see it's as long as
they're not
um brought in from another country and
have diseases or pests which can be
negative that's why you don't want to
bring stuff from your country because
you can bring invasive insects like
stuff from China if people are getting
seeds from China a lot of those have
like weevils and and mites and different
things that could destroy your seeds and
destroy your socks sucks so uh freezing
your seeds before you bring them in
would be important but you should do
that for all kinds of seeds that you're
bringing in from another country that's
why they have these sanitation
certificates that you're supposed to use
when importing seeds from other
countries it's important because you
know you're bringing in pests and you
could be the one that was responsible
for a plague uh you know insects that
are bringing a certain fungus that's
killing all the different citrus fruits
or trees because you bought in cannabis
seeds from somewhere you know that has
this this type of insect that has this
type of mold with it you know or this
virus
um it's all connected but if you get
something from that country usually safe
and you can buy it in bulk you know it's
not too expensive and then you bring it
to the people or you find something that
you could trade with them that they want
but those would be better things than
providing genetics that can pollute
there but they already have but
if they have sources to you know
International genetics already uh they
can also import them themselves you know
they can import that and dilute their
their uh gene pool by themselves you
don't need extra help from us
definitely they definitely are people
out there in uh these land race areas
who came to grow some Californian stuff
so I guess there needs to be some
acceptance of that just as a follow-up
to the last one if you were you know
totally relieved of all responsibilities
and we're totally able to go anywhere do
a land race Expedition where would you
want to head off to
well before the uh the government went
haywire I wanted to go to Miramar what
was previously Burma and explore uh all
that because
um there's so many uh temples and
there's quite a large country in you
know between India and um you know
southeast Asia so it you know a lot of
export varieties could have been there
and there's a lot of different
indigenous peoples groups that are kind
of you know been cut off from the rest
of the world so it's kind of like a
um what do you call it like a a time
capsule you know these people are living
in decades you know or
hundreds of decades behind some of us in
a ways so uh finding some interesting
stuff there would have been pretty cool
um uh Africa going to the Congolese
Basin countries uh a lot of that stuff
has been uh pretty um
pretty hard to get into and as far as
the diseases and uh just the unruliness
of the gorilla type
um you know armies in there uh it's it's
really a hard place to get into a lot of
that's been kind of um
this range because the Belgian
people had gone there and tried to take
over the Congo years ago and they had
hemp varieties so there's a lot of hemp
varieties that were Escape cultivars
into the congoley Congo and the
Congolese Basin countries that surround
it uh so a lot of people that think
these there's indigenous sativas there
some of it might be uh Escape cultivars
that um you know acclimatized in the
environment
another place would be some of the um
South African South American countries
um I definitely like to go back into
Mexico I've been there a couple times
and trying to find things but Mexico uh
would love to find some more stuff down
now down to Columbia uh Bolivia Peru uh
that'll be uh fun places to go look at
yeah certainly and and you touched on um
you know a magical talking point which
is that I wanted to ask you about what's
your opinions on the Congolese you know
we don't see them represented too much
but they are some really special strains
what's your thoughts on them
well the there is
um there's there's pygmy peoples there
there's several different groups of
pygmies that are in the Congolese Basin
countries
um and I'll I'll make this reference in
Egypt they had their gods and one of
their gods was named Bess best was a
pygmy
um dark-skinned pygmy and he was a
fertility God and in their fertility
um bases they would find
um
cannabis residue and seeds
now the pygmies were from the Congolese
Basin country they weren't from like
where Egypt was now
um so they must have seen that these
indigenous pygmies were consuming uh
cannabis
um and they were using it for
childbirthing you know for the pain and
everything so they were using it in the
ancient past for that purpose
um the other people that were a close
relative to the pygmy people were the
Kalahari bush people and these are some
of the oldest known the oldest like
people living on Earth that are closest
to modern humans
um but you know still a distant
um human and these people are closest
related to the pygmy people
um it seems like these the Kalahari
Bushmen
um have a cannabis history
um but their their genetics go back to a
very old age where it seems like they
left
um Africa
um maybe
76 000 years ago up to 130 000 years ago
and then went into like southeast Asia
and then back to South Africa
um during like floods of the world
um so we're talking about a time frame
of like 130 000 years
um and then you see in their genetics if
you see a picture of a Kalahari Bushman
you see that they have Asian
um
features like from China or Laos
um and then I and in the early 90s or
early 2000s I was looking at DNA because
the they did the whole Genome Project
and I found that these people have
um Asian descent back you know from like
70 to 130 000 years ago so basically the
genetic testing confirmed what I saw in
the pictures
um I also looked up the phonetic words
for cannabis that were similar to these
Kalahari Bushmen for the same use and I
I looked it up phonetically and then I
looked up the pictures these people and
then I backed it up with genetic
sequencing
um that they left
um Africa and then came back
um you know
at one point which was kind of crazy so
if you guys have time look up the sun
people or the Kalahari Bushmen
and you can see that they have like
Asian descent but these are black
indigenous
Africans and there's supposed to be like
the oldest living people on Earth
um that are like you know been in the
same place
um you know from time immoral basically
so my thoughts are that Candace left
Africa with them or with other
indigenous people and that's how it's
spread around the world is from Africa
and then you know went to the Americas
uh went through uh Africa through the
Middle East after the kyber pass through
Afghanistan up and through China up
through India and Southeast Asia and
then down through Australia and then
land bridges to Americas there's a lot
of
um
knowledge and genetics that show uh
travel during the low
um the times when the waters were lower
and there was more islands that there
was more
um trans-pacific
um migration of peoples like some of the
people that are in Mexico kind of like
um
they look like some of the Africans from
Western Africa around Senegal
um
and these are some of like the oldest
um Mexican peoples in the uh the
Americas
basically they tracked all these old
people ancient civilizations and found a
lot of cannabis history among almost all
the ancient civilizations and it's in
the book I wrote which I'm still trying
to finish up so there's a book on all
this craziness as well but it needs to
be finished
oh wow any idea of when you know might
sort of be looking to be done
well hopefully next
year or so but maybe sooner it's been
done but the the publisher said it was
too big so I separated two books so the
first book is called uh the tree of
knowledge and it's basically um talks
about the two um the trees that were in
the Garden of Eden one was the tree of
knowledge and one was the tree of life
so I based the tree of knowledge being
the varieties that give you
um knowledge and then the trio life
being the varieties that give you
um you know life like uh you know
healing properties so I kind of separate
the two in the the two books ah okay so
sort of like psychedelics encounter this
sort of thing well they're both cannabis
but more of like uh the the varieties
that give you knowledge and the ones
that kind of have more healing
properties so I've kind of separated
them like the Indica hash plants and to
one book and like the team is
equatorials Mexicans and all that to
another book so it's kind of splitting
up the Cannabis genome into kind of two
different sections yeah well beautiful
stuff that's something to look forward
to in the future
hopefully as long as my health uh keeps
up but yes yeah that should be uh
something to kind of put my knowledge
down on paper and kind of give people
some interesting history to uh to look
at because everybody loves history as
long as as well as cannabis history
there's so much there that people are
just not aware of that it you know kind
of highlighting some of it's kind of a
cool thing to do to kind of
definitely and and during your answer
you referenced uh you know the the
migration of things down to Australia
what I'd be interested to know is
earlier on in the interview you also
reference Mala Madness what's your
thoughts on Modern Madness and do you
know if it has any relation to Old
Mother sativa or if they're quite
different
you know I don't I haven't grown old
mother sativa so I don't know
um but a lot of those lines were there's
a lot of Thai varieties
um Colombians
uh that were grown in Australia so
there's a lot of Southeast Asian
varieties grown there
um so from the Mulan buddy Madness it
has a certain growth structure that was
um similar to uh the the Neville's Haze
that I saw
um so that's why I was coming up with
you know thinking that mall and Buddy
Madness might be the source of
um like the Neville's Haze instead of it
being like um you know like a haze
variety and anyway the Mullen bunny
Madness uh has this upright structure
I'd have to see some pictures of it and
you can see it's got a certain growth
similar to zamal where it's kind of like
an upright plant lots of shoots
um lots of smaller flowers coming up
from it but it's got a certain growth
look to it when it's flowering out like
an upright plant
um just unique
um so maybe it's coming from some of the
Thai varieties that it it you know that
were there
um but Australia's got some very good uh
varieties you know from the the Thai
lines the the the closeness to Papua New
Guinea there's a lot of varieties from
Papua New Guinea
um the surrounding Islands Malaysia
there's a lot of small stuff that's you
know been through Indonesia that you
know because of the drug laws they're so
stringent that not much of it gets out
of there but like Sumatra and Indonesia
Malaysia there were some good varieties
but they don't get any um knowledge of
because of the drug laws you know you
don't want to be king to death um not
not a cool thing for smoking cannabis or
having a couple seeds
um
but there's a lot of cool stuff that you
know Australia do the proximity has been
able to get
um and create some really cool stuff
um and you you look at the the size of
the plants that grow in Australia the
trees the trees have some growth with
the eucalyptus and some of the other
trees that grow so large so fast that
cannabis that grows there also has some
of those effects so acclimatizing stuff
to Australia and then growing them
elsewhere would be a great thing for
some of the canvas breeders because of
just the the environment of Australia
yeah beautiful you heard it guys buy
some of my seeds
sorry just kidding around we've got a
nice uh pool of fan submitted questions
here but before we get into them I
wanted to ask you this one might be hard
maybe should have given it to you
earlier to think about but
how would you rank the overall hierarchy
of hazes and when I say that I mean heck
you could just say like Colombian at the
top or something but you know what I
mean for all the people who say they
like Hayes what's the hierarchy for you
what's the number one and then how would
you sort of rank them
oh
that's a really tough question
um
I don't know if I can answer it uh
honestly because uh I just I love I love
them all
yeah that's a good answer as well you
know and and depending on the phenotype
or the plant you know they could be a
little bit different or something
special I uh especially like the Purple
Haze phenotypes I like the
um the profile the turpins because they
have this like uh
this port wine you know this grapey port
liquor
profile which kind of um like a
Blackberry port wine liqueur
um Aroma and taste but uh the high is
luxurious transcending uh mind expanding
psychedelic
um
and this the flavors and taste just uh
you know
make it luxurious and the effects it's
just amazing
um
yeah it's hard to say I think um
the old timer's hazes which is not like
real Haze but it's you know like a haze
those Colombians are very special
um
but some of the hazes that were uh like
original Haze are very good too but it's
a different type of effect
but they're also very special it just
depends
sorry for the shitty answer guys
no that's fine totally understandable I
did notice in your catalog you had uh
the black raspberry Haze it sounded
pretty interesting can you tell me a
little more about it okay well the black
raspberry Haze it was uh it was just
called Black Raspberry at one time but I
didn't realize Bodhi had
um
a black raspberry uh had named his right
before mine so I put the haze because it
has the purple tine Devil's Haze in it
it's basically the Maduro
which is organ purple tie line braid uh
done by
um
RC colas in in Canada and he basically
uh bred
the Oregon purple tie traits out and
made it more uh you know forward in the
line and he he grew the line out of um a
blue moonshine and then another organ
purple Thai variety
um and then pulled out the traits so
Maduro is an organ purple tie dominant
um variety and I used
um
a couple phenotypes for that and they
turned purple and blue and red
um
when I was growing them and those were
the mothers I used for the black
raspberry Haze and then the male I chose
um was the one that has the purple
um trichomes on the the sepals so the
male flowers that have the little Pond
sacks had uh standing trichomes which is
not too usual for male and they were
purple coloration of the resin glands
um and I use that mail on the Maduro
line so it's organ purple tie
with the Neville's Haze purple tie male
line
um so it's an F3 Neville's Haze with the
purple tie and the organ purple tie so
it's a real special Pine levels Haze
line and um the
black raspberry Haze
um
grows into these pink and purple red
colored buds so you get these nice
purple buds but the resins that
extracted from it have that color too
they retain that color so extracts will
have this like raspberry
um you know raspberry color like um
Chambord you know that raspberry liqueur
it has that color to the extract so you
can make extracts that have this
raspberry color to it and it makes a
wonderful uh awesome high and they're
tasty delectable sweet candied like
raspberry taste
um but it's got that nice Haze high it's
wonderful one person said it was the
best high he ever smoked I said thank
you you know it's nice but the the color
and the special trichome resins that it
produces is very special so it's it's a
very good line to have in order to smoke
great for breeding great for smoking and
it's one of those you want to keep to
yourself and share with special friends
I love it stands right up my alley uh
just while we're talking about the
backstory of hazes quickly
I know that this one's not made by you
but I have a feeling you might be able
to give me a bit of the backstory but
can you tell me about the metal Haze you
know there's not a ton of information
about the backstory and you have used it
for a few different things what's your
thoughts on it well metal Haze was done
by Dutch Flowers
um it's a very potent line uh there was
you know a couple phenotypes
um the phenotype that I got was one
selected by the Rev he got the seeds
from my friend four dragons
um and he got them from the the auctions
and there wasn't many packs sold so
there wasn't much metal Haze that was
actually available unfortunately uh rev
only
um selected the one female and then you
know called the rest uh so there wasn't
any to breed with I tried to take some
F2 metal Haze that I had to breed with
F1 but all I had was um
females I never got a male so I wasn't
able to breed the f2s to F1
um
so the metal Haze when I've looked at it
and growing it out and seeing the
Expressions through recessives it looks
like it's supposedly supposed to be a
mix of a bunch of their sativas or Haze
plants that they were growing under
metal halide lights
um but what I saw from growing it out it
it looks like it's got Mexican
um punto Rojo in there
from the leaf structures
so I think some of the the metal Haze
um with the special parts that is
Mexican punto Rojo
but that's just my uh interpretation of
the leaves and uh you know some of the
aspects I get from the stems and the
coloration and that's just from you know
years of growing different writings that
could be off but that's what it looks
like to me so
um yeah so I have one called Dr Doom
which is the metal dragon which is the
metal Haze with the Burmese
um in purple Vietnamese which is black
purple phenotype which is Vietnamese
with Vietnam Black and the Mexican Punta
Rojo traits seem to be pretty dominant
in that
um and it's going to be fantastic I got
some growing this year so it's gonna be
can't wait till those are done
I love it sounds good uh we'll move on
to the uh the fan submitted questions
before we finally wrap up with the final
five we give people the first one we got
is a good one someone must be paying a
lot of attention because I didn't even
know about this but they said can you
ask snow hi if you can tell us a little
bit about some of the rare hemp seeds he
has specifically I think he has some
fujian
uh fujian it's a there's a province in
China uh there it's not Fiji it's from
uh it's a province in China
um
yeah I've got a lot of different hemp
strains honestly I've got uh maybe 120
different strains yeah a lot of them
from China A lot of them from you know
um
Uh Hungry Romania
um some from the Congo
um some from
uh you know uh
all the different Rush uh I have stuff
from Siberia
um
Mongolia
you name it I've got a lot of different
apps I've been all the way to like Italy
so there's Southern Italian varieties
there's
um
um Slovenian Slovakian there's Czech
there is
um French
um Spanish
um there's lot fian there is
um
yeah basically I've got a a lot of
difference Turkish all these different
hemp varieties and uh even I have some
from North Korea
wow you managed to get him
yeah these were collected um in the
1950s
um or before the CR right before the
Korean War
they have two varieties and they need to
be preserved because uh they may be
getting unviable at this point but
um yeah I was trying to do um a
preservation of hemp varieties as well
because I think I like all cannabis and
can there's so many different uh things
we could do for the world with them uh
you know as far as medicine or
um you know
supplements or building materials
um Plastics I mean there's so much and
these have varieties will be just as
valuable as you know these drug
producing varieties
um not only that you could have um you
know disease resistance in some of these
hemp varieties that may be lost in some
of these I know drug varieties and that
you can incorporate some of those
resistances
um and pest resistances into these you
know drug types that might be favorable
to certain places of the world or we can
produce a hemp variety that will grow in
a tropical Place unfortunately
um heat tends to make even drug
cultivars I mean hemp cultivars into
um like ganja because of the Heat it
changes the the environment that it
acclimatizes to the environment and then
it produces THC wow like what happened
in the Congo with the Belgian varieties
wow that's that's really cool to hear I
hadn't really heard that Express before
there you go so
one of the next questions we got is
someone says right now from sort of the
the menu the current offerings that snow
Ohio has what's his favorite and why
oh my goodness
um
too many favorites but one of my
favorites right now is for a long time
is called the devil's tit
um
basically when I first smoked the
parents uh the devil came to me with
fruit in my ear and told me what to call
it
um
Devil's tit is Durban Poison it was from
a a clone from Mendocino that I got from
um
guy that was an old breeder that bred
harijuana
um he he didn't have that but he
his friends had the Durban that I got it
from so
associate of that person anyway this
Durham poison was some of the most
potent herb I've smoked to date
um
it turns purple has orange hairs red
stems and the the devil's tattoos and
part of those properties
um extracts from it are so powerful like
I've been in fetal positions because
it's been just too strong
um and I've heard that from a lot of
people that the this is too potent for a
lot of people
um you know and that that's not
necessarily a bad thing you'd smoke less
and sometimes you know you just need to
dose yourself a little bit less and
you're fine uh the forest affects the
The Taste is like strawberry lemonade or
cherry chapstick or there's a skunk
phenotype as well
um all very uh rich in turpins and um
THC doesn't seem to be too high in that
in the test results so there's something
else in that that makes it extremely
potent I know it's thcv or what it is
but something in the devil's tit
um makes it very very potent
um and not all lab tests are conclusive
because uh you know when I was testing
things at the emerald cup they weren't
testing for thcv and some other things
so this is the problem with a lot of
labs they don't always test for
everything unfortunately
but um that was one of my favorites
because it's um there's some faster
phenotypes
um it yields well it's got you know the
the looks and smells the taste
everything wants and it's it's got the
potency Beyond and it's got equality to
it that's very unique
um it can be a roller coaster but it's a
fun roller coaster
I love that description that's beautiful
the next question we have is someone
wants to know what strain do you have
that's got the most unique terpenes and
as a follow-up what sort of turf end
profiles are you most interested in at
the moment
oh wow
um unique turpins there is a Mexican
variety
um
called El Primo which is a Mexican punto
Rojo it is uh it's got
what I believe it's got this
um
the simple Turpin profile that is a
fuel-like Aroma profile
um but it's it's basically what I think
when people smell the chem lines they
smell this simple Turpin profile and
that's what they love out of it it's
like the unadulterated mixed up what
they love out of the chem lines it's got
that fueling smell but it's not it's not
a sour diesel or you smell like that
it's just got that simple fuel Turpin
profile which
is very unique
um but it's um psychedelic it's it's
potent it's very luxurious
um and it's
it symbolized form it's it's the
building block for what we love
um in some of these lines so that's
coming out of that Mexican Punta Rojo
and it's surprising because it's coming
out of a Mexican cultivar and it's
Unique and I think that's you know what
a lot of people you know been digging
around for and can't find and I think
it's in one of those so El Primo is um
the line that um I found it in so anyway
if people are looking for to recreate
some of the chem lines I think that's
where it's from
I also think I have um
what created the uh the chem lines the
Dogwood uh I think my friend made it and
he um he just didn't realize that's what
he made yeah he called it something else
the mongrel and it was also renamed the
the dog bud but he called it
the mom girl because it was a mix of
different stuff
um
and that may just be one version of it
um but I have the seeds I'm gonna try to
grow them out and see what it comes out
of them they're older so we'll see what
did he describe it as the plants sort of
how were they like Indica sativa
indicas and sativas okay so they're a
mix yeah it was a mix yeah I think he
said like five different things he
called it the mongrel so I have the
mongrel seeds and it has the dog Bud
seeds
um so I you know and these dog blood
crosses and stuff so I'll see if any of
those will uh
we'll make it we'll be able to germinate
so we'll see what comes out of them if
they're similar or what they are wow we
wait with bated breath that's cool I
mean you know if you had to guess the
exact sort of genetics that were in chem
dog what would you say it is
well I'd have to say that there has to
be some Mexican in it from my
you know finding this Mexican Punta Rojo
so some Mexican
um Afghani
um
probably Pakistani uh probably some kind
of Southeast Asian in there too
yeah I mean something that I've been
discussing more with people like skunk
VA and some of the people who are very
associated with the chem dogs is that a
lot of people will talk about them as if
they're like this most hardcore Indica
but many of them do have a decent amount
of sort of sativa like traits to them
and aspects to the high they're just so
potent you're sort of sometimes feel
like it's Indica right and that's right
the Mexican comes along and it's super
potent it's got the chem qualities but
the Afghani kind of I would think would
go along like if you wanted to reproduce
the chem wine with that Mexican Puerto
Rojo and add some certain some specific
afghanis you'd have something pretty
close but the Monger I think was like
five different things but
um you know who's the I'm sure meant
more than one person be dog but the
whole thing is
no one is claiming this and nobody knows
where it came from so
why not my friend that did some work
around the same time and a lot of people
got seeds from him
um
a lot of people got seats from him and
then he because he got busted he kind of
went out of the the
um you know from growing for a while and
he had heart he's got heart conditions
and issues like that so
um yeah it's a bit interesting if that's
what it is but you know who knows there
might be some other person that created
dog but and there was a lot of other dog
lines out there there's dog [ __ ] and
there's you know lots of people come up
with the same name so it wouldn't be
unlikely that more than one person
created the same thing or something that
was named the same thing so I'm not
saying it is but uh I'm gonna dig down
the hole and see what comes out of it
yeah look I'm Keen to follow your
progress and see how that goes
the next question we got was a good one
what's the most paranoia in juicing weed
you've ever bred so one of your strains
someone wants to get Paranoid by the
sounds of it
um
let's see here paranoiducing
uh there was
um
one I grew that was Senegalese
with
Hayes and um
oh God it was Angola red with the tie
so I did one with Senegalese Haze it was
um Angola Thai with Angola red and it
was Angola red tie
um Senegalese and uh like Neville's
Hayes and I think that was one of the
strongest paranoid inducing ones
mostly was um from African sativas
equatorial blinds
ah interesting interesting okay because
you don't really see too many people
playing with them outside of like
yourself and maybe gooey burrito
yeah gooey's not too far from you know
from where I grew it's in the same area
Northern California
cool have you ever grown Mama gooey at
all
I have uh gooey is very nice
um yeah and I did some work with it I
need to grow some of the seeds but yeah
it's definitely a producer it's got some
wonderful buds on there and yeah it's
it's good stuff good good stuff to grow
and breed with
yeah beautiful love to hear that so the
next question we had was what's your
thoughts on the makaido and how was the
strain collected
Mikado
oh God you know I heard that was it was
like a
uh skunk Northern Lights Haze
combination kind of like Jack Herer but
other than that I don't know it's
definitely strong and it's got some
unique traits to it so I don't know
yeah now look I I feel you on that one
the next question
um someone says can you give us some
insight into your process of harvesting
the trichomes from seeded bud with dry
ice
oh very easy so basically
um a lot of people are like I don't I
can't try my my strains because I seed
them well if you're if you seed your
lines you basically take exceeded Buds
and if you use dry ice with um say
um
the the the the bubble bags so you use
uh I think 130 trichomes uh sorry
millimeters High centimeters uh micro
mesh so 130 micro mesh bag and you put
it in put your seeded buds in there with
the dry ice crushed up and you take like
a paint bucket and you flip it upside
down you shake that out over
um you know something that you can
collect the resin glance out you can
basically separate even fresh Bud fresh
Bud works great
um because then you have like you know
that fresh
um dry uh sieve and it's it hasn't been
decarboxylated yet
um so you use fresh buds which are great
or you can use the dry buds the good
thing is you can separate the seeds and
they're clean and then you got this nice
nice fresh resin that you shake off from
the plants and I use the 130 because it
kind of you know it gives you the
smaller microns and the larger mesh you
know it kind of takes out the dust but
allows you to get the resin glass
and you collect that with um you know
um a credit card or some kind of other
card
um and I I usually shake them over you
know a plastic drum that used for like
collecting oil or something some big
plastic thing you can kind of lay down
and collect
cool that sounds great I'm gonna have to
try that next time
and you could you could shake out your
resin glands within a few minutes you
know and collect them it's really a fast
way of collecting resin glands
and then you separate your seeds
afterwards and uh if you wanted to
separate the seeds from uh the trash and
stuff you can use
um a two liter Coke bottle cut up with
strips and a vacuum um
uh connected to the back end of the the
two liter bottle and the bottom cut off
any kind of
um can feed off the the Trashy sticks
and everything that are associated with
the seeds and then what will be left
behind are the seeds because they they
have a density and weight to them so
it's a good way of cleaning your seeds
that way
Ah that's good I'm cleaning seeds right
now so I'm going to implement this
I'll show you a picture of it so it's um
you know I'll show you what it looks
like and kind of explain to you how they
break down it's pretty easy you kind of
build a little adapter to put on the
back into the vacuum so you can use your
vacuum with it
fastest way to decede
amazing amazing on to the last few fan
submitted questions the next one is
what's the most unique land race
experience you've had
oh God unique huh
hmm
you know you got me stumped on that I
don't know
um unique I love them all
um I love the oh the Thai buds you know
it's the Sweet Taste of the tie uh like
the dry you know it looks like you know
what we used to get is Thai sticks or
Thai buds the sweet taste the high was
just euphoric and soaring and it's just
that wonderful
um this high and it tastes so good I
think Thai buds are just amazing
um you know compared to other stuff but
um you know I love Mexicans as well you
know there's the Psychedelic potency the
quality the giggles the happiness from
it so I'd say it's a draw between Thai
Thai Thai sticks and Thai
um and Mexican
um stuff and I've had some stuff from
Veracruz that was just so psyched out
the potent
um that it it can be noise-inducing as
well very apparently inducing I remember
being in Cancun and um smoking a big old
uh joint outside the window and then one
of the uh Federal is the guys the cops
there shined his lights and at me
because I was smoking outside the window
and I think he was trying to scare me
and [ __ ] with me and it got me all
paranoid because I was smoking this you
know strong ass weed
um that ended up flushing the rest of it
down the toilet after smoking half the
joint
but it was legal at the time so I think
it was just a
you know got overtaken by the paranoid
inducing effects
it's interesting you touched on the tie
there because one of the questions we go
is have you ever found an interesting
terpenes in the tire lines besides the
standard sort of spicy Haze or the lemon
that you commonly see
uh yeah I mean there's Juicy Fruit Thai
which has got like a different fruity
Aroma and taste it grows different too
um you know it's more of an upright
um bilateral like it grows like uh what
I would consider like a golden tie
um somebody's got into the stuff for
them the gold golden tie gold King tie
uh it grows in like a an upright
straight plant
um some of these ties I don't it's hard
to say they're kind of like a bean pole
they go straight up and they have
um branching that's
um
basically they grow perpendicular to
each other alternating perpendicular so
it's like perfect alternating form so
it's straight up and back and forth
um and the The Taste is more of a
fruitiness
um
you know ripe fruit kind of like a mango
or you know Juicy Fruit gum
um and then there's uh the mango ties
which I think are very in the same
family and I think there's another
Highland variety and those were a lot of
the Thai sticks uh there's lemon ties
which are this highland ties and those
could be purple or green
um and those have like a lemon Aroma or
high limonene Aroma
um
and those are there's lots of different
lemon ties
um
so you know it's it's hard to say uh
there's the
um grassy varieties which are like some
of the Highland varieties are grassy and
they're more jungly uh like The Chiang
Mai
um
there's the chocolate ties which I think
are mainly Low Land lowland varieties or
purple purple Thai varieties
um but I'm trying to narrow down the
specific varieties that that make up the
the chocolate ties I think some of the
60s were some of the the purple Highland
ties or some of the Lao varieties
um those were like some of the first 60s
chocolate ties and then I think the
lighter chocolate ties were some of the
uh lowland Lao or some of the other uh
lowland ties that also had purple traits
to them uh I think those ones are musky
euphoric coffee tobacco tasting
um
and there's also the red ties there's
ones that red red pigments
um or like um Brown and those ones have
uh at signings the the red trites the
the carotenoid traits that seem to turn
on red uh red stemmed red flowers
um which also turn into like a purple as
well when dried
um kind of similar to like a Panama Red
and those who kind of have um
what is very similar to all the like the
purple traits and those type of lines
and they are kind of like the Blackberry
Port wineish grapes-ish but not like a
candy grape more of like a a liqueur
um Turpin profile
um
but many of them have sweet tasting
stuff too so it's hard to say but
there's so many different ties
um and I'm trying to get my hands around
a lot of them uh we're gonna be able to
see all the different differences but
there's there's many different fruit
flavor types as well as the sickly sweet
types Highland lowland
um and then you have stuff that are more
ganja varieties and more of the uh
what they use for Thai stick and then
some of the um
Indica types they're like Thai indica's
Ah that's something you don't hear every
day well they're they're not in the true
form like an Indica but they have the
you know the hash your plant there
they're thicker larger you know they
look like
hash plants but they're they're ties but
they're pure ties they're just you know
tie derivatives indicas
if that makes any sense so they it would
be nice to see what the the chemotype
compositions are if they have CBD in
them or
um you know if they're similar to you
know Mexicans or other things the other
thing is some of these lines were
imported from Mexico uh during the um
Thai stick lines the guy named Brian
Daniels was the Importer of a lot of
Thai sticks his wife was married to well
he was married to a time woman and her
family her father was part of like the
the head of police in Chiang Mai and I
think they they got indigenous tribal
people to wrap the sticks and grow them
on different
um pieces of land and then they were
able to transport the sticks down to the
the water and avoid
um you know police by you know paying
them off and basically this was done for
like 20 years
um and they would import sticks into
Sausalito into like a San Francisco area
into Australia into different places
um
so a lot of the stuff was brought in
from other countries like Mexico to
speed up the the the growth rates of
some of the ties so some of the the
hybridized highs that were grown in
Thailand and and Cambodian Laos were
probably like Mexican seeds or Colombian
some of the Colombian seeds were brought
to Colombia
um and produced a line called sky blue
blonde because some of the tie lines
were the Thai varieties were shorter
flowering than the long uh you know
Plumbing gold varieties you know ties
are extremely long but Colombians are
even longer
um but you can't grow a lot of Mexicans
in Colombia because they couldn't deal
with the the extended um you know
um daylight hours so they had to find
varieties that would grow there
huh what a detailed tie backstory I
wasn't expecting to get I love it well
good
yeah it was about to say it does make me
wonder how many other toys there are out
there that just sort of don't get any
mention
well I mean what people grew there they
were you know they they'd call it one
thing and then they they'd rename it as
something else so there's Highland highs
lowland ties
um
stuff that was purple Thai maybe renamed
here in the state's chocolate tie
lowland Laos could be renamed as
chocolate Thai some of the mango ties
could be sold here as golden ties some
of the Juicy Fruit ties could have been
renamed as like golden ties
um some of the buddhistics could have
been renamed as you know from
some of the lowland Laos or cambodians
uh you know it was three sellers trying
to make money off some of this stuff
I know in 1988 I we bought a chocolate
pie out of San Jose for it was 80 bucks
for an eighth which was a lot because
most eights were you know 10 15 bucks
so 80 80 bucks it was quite a bit or 75
bucks for an eighth for chocolate Thai
it was quite a bit yeah nice so the
Final Fantasy mid question we have which
is actually a really good one
um they have asked what is it that keeps
you up at night in relation to cannabis
what's the most concerning aspect of the
modern cannabis scene or culture in your
opinion
uh the loss of
um genetic germplasm we're losing so
much
of these old lines because people are
growing up gelato and these other fast
flowering lines that are kind of generic
um
and what they what should be growing are
these varieties that will give them
these awesome highs and these effects
but the problem is no one's experienced
them because they didn't grow up in
those ages
so it's genetic loss that I'm fearing
the most because there's so many
varieties that we lose due to non-viable
seeds due to not getting the
support to remake them or to make them
available
um
it's just genetic loss because there's
so much that is awesome about the campus
I mean these things have evolved with
people so cannabis is is is is is
unique and um and varied as all the
people in the world so you have all the
different spices and tastes and colors
and experiences of all these different
people and fruits and vegetables that
cannabis kind of
um holds in its you know it's makeup
um so it's like an experience but a
human experience in a plant that you
grow that you can smoke so you can ex
you can excuse smoking experience
so all that's going to be lost all that
history
um
unless we're able to preserve some of it
and
you know I can't do it all and and my
friends can't do it all so we need help
from the general public to
help you know make this something that
people want to try because once you get
to try this stuff you're going to want
more of it because it's it's uh
beautiful and happy and you don't get
stoned you get high and you get um you
unlock knowledge that's not necessarily
available to people unless they partake
in something like this cannabis allows
you to
use your mind in a way like a person
that's studying meditation for you know
many many years like a yogi somebody
that's able to get their mind to a place
where they're able to perceive
um things that most people can't because
they're able to get to that level well
cannabis is a tool that allows you to
get to that stage in a much much faster
rate just by smoking it
it allows you to free your mind from the
constraints of what we think is moral or
immoral and allows you to see things for
what they are
and normal cannabis that people are
smoking doesn't do that but some of the
varieties that are Thai or Mexican or
Vietnamese or Colombian those can allow
you to get to those places and allow you
to access that knowledge that you
normally wouldn't be able to get
so
I just hope more people will take the
time to either support the people that
grow these varieties or help the people
that can make these available to more
people
sentiment so that brings us to our final
quick five questions for the interview
so first one being what is the single
best or most memorable experience in
relation to cannabis you have
oh man uh I think the first time I
smoked ham I read
I was uh at my high school and I had
smoked some Panama Red and I thought it
was laced with LSD I didn't realize at
the time that you can't smoke LSD but I
had had L Steeps before that and I knew
the experience so I was so uh so high
that my friends had to carry me
um up to the school because uh it was
just too high uh from the experience
that I thought I was uh it had been
laced with the LST and I thought I was
going to be flying high for a very long
time because some of these experiences
from Cannabis can be
um like a very strong psychedelic
experience for a short period of time
you know a few hours or hour or whatever
it might be it feels like hours but that
was a very memorable experience that
first Panama Red
amazing I love it I love it so on the
other end of the spectrum what's uh
strain that all your friends were you
know hyping up telling you was going to
be great and then when you finally had
it you were like oh is that it
G13
G13 was something that was always kind
of like hyped up for many many years it
was this government strain
when I smoked it it's it's it's potent
it's narcotic it's
it's generic it's not some it's it's
great cross to other things it's a it's
a shitty grower it's a small little hash
plant it's it's nothing special but it's
hyped to be something special so you
know hype works I guess
I love it I love it okay so if I was
gonna drop you off on a desert island
and you can take three strains with you
to grow for the rest of time what would
you take with you
oh that's hard
um
Purple Haze
Acapulco Gold
this is hard
chocolate Thai
this for lack of you know I think I'd be
happy with those three strains though I
I still want others but uh yeah those
are being very happy for a long time but
I still want others but I think that
kind of covers a lot of things
love it love it love it love it so let's
say uh you're dropping someone else off
on the island someone you're not a big
fan of what are you gonna leave them
with
um
foreign
but you know I'm a nice guy so I
probably let him have some like Northern
Lights or something
yeah something to numb the pain yeah
totally cruel
love it okay and so final question then
if I gave you a time machine and you can
go back anywhere in history anytime
where you're gonna go and what are you
gonna collect and presumably seeds or
clones
wow
um
I think the the zwustrian age uh you
know when everybody was migrating to the
bulk region uh worshiping cannabis is
heoma they're bringing in cannabis from
all over the world
uh you know there's Sumerians there's
um
acadians there was all kinds of
different peoples there
um
Indus Valley
yeah so yeah this is Western age so
basically
um like 13
1300 you know 1300 BC e and uh I think
I'd be collecting a lot of different
stuff at that point yeah definitely I
think it would be wild the other place
would be maybe the 1960s in Colombia and
Mexico
some brilliant answers there I love both
of them get funky with it so I think
that just about brings us to the end of
it were there any comments or shout outs
you wanted to make
um I just like to say that
um I couldn't get here without my
friends
um you know some new or some older
um you can't do anything without your
friends so you should always
um you know
thank the people that help you get where
you're at so thank you to my friends uh
family
um that's it
thank you guys incredible incredible so
again huge thank you and shout out to
John the snow High seeds the land race
lover breeder extraordinaire so much
more we're so incredibly appreciative
for you taking the time to join us today
thanks for having me
and there you have it friends a huge
thank you to snow high for coming by
sharing all of his knowledge land races
breeding preserving history future
predictions so much more we're
incredibly appreciative thank you so
much John
[Music]
and as always huge thank you to our
incredible sponsors seeds here now all
the latest breeders the hottest drops an
incredible new website they've been
slashing prices to give you the best
deals while still offering their patent
guarantee on satisfaction and
germination check them out likewise
simply souvenirs if you're after a
hand-selected range of Boutique genetics
both local and international check them
out guys they've got everything you need
from seeds to smoking accessories to
Vapes everything under the sun simply
souvenirs they'll look after you best
customer service in the game huge shout
out Simply souvenirs
big shout out to our friends at
corporate biological systems providing
all the Predators you need to keep your
garden Pest and pathogen free check out
the spidex vital if you're worried about
spider mites you should release these
things periodically guys I promise you
you will view it as an investment in
your garden ensuring that you never have
any spider mites in your garden should
be one of your key priorities as a
cultivator
huge shout out proper biological systems
we appreciate you and your support
likewise pulse sensors you want more
yield more resin better flour better
concentrates who doesn't
check out pulse guys if you're ready to
get serious get a pulse sensor from a
single tent to a single room to a
multi-facility operation don't let
hidden variables hold your prop back get
your growth parameters in check and
start yielding the highest quality
possible huge shout out pulse sensors
thank you so much
likewise big shout out to the patreon
gang we love and appreciate you please
consider checking out the patreon if you
want early access to upcoming episodes
additional interviews you won't get
access to unless you're on there as well
as genetic giveaways and ad-free content
check it out friends that's the patreon
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast or one word we love and
appreciate you
[Music]
and there you have it my friends part
one of this two-part hitter from the man
himself snowhigh
[Music]
come on back to the next one I'll see
you there
[Music]
I'll see you