[Applause]
[Music]
alrighty a big hello and welcome to
episode 38 of the podcast a cannabis
podcast for budding enthusiasts
as always we want to give a big thank
you to our sponsors
radio ridge nursery these guys have all
the premo cuts from the best breeders
including the newest from fig farms
all these cuts clean as a whistle and
saves you the time pinot hunting
[Music]
however they don't have every cut on
earth and so if what you're looking for
they don't have maybe you should head on
over to seeds here now grab yourself a
pack or two find that cupofino for
yourself
guarantee on satisfaction not just
germination hit them both up radio ridge
seats here now they've got what you're
looking for
[Music]
as well as always a big shout out to 420
australia and organic gardening
solutions abroaskies from down under
holding down the fort
[Music]
big shout out to the patreon gang who
helped make the show happen
and last but not least big shout out to
our guests for this episode the dynamic
duo that is dragonfly earth medicine
we're joined today by josh and kelly for
another wicked installment of organic
growing and health knowledge
so let's get into it
[Music]
alrighty a big thank you and welcome to
two of my favorite humus beings for
taking the time to join us again today
for the second time josh and kelly of
dragonfly earth medicine thanks so much
for sitting down and chatting with us
today
thank you so much for having us thanks
so much for having us we're really
excited to be here with you this evening
right back at ya so the first question i
wanted to ask is the normal first
question but it wasn't the first
question i asked you last time so it's
time to do it what was your first
experience with cannabis
my first experience with cannabis was in
utero because my mother
liked to smoke
hash while she was pregnant and it just
felt good to her and she was an old
hippie and of the area and maybe she had
some morning sickness or some different
things she was working out but really
she was just a
naturalist that was living in southern
oregon and just wanted to you know
be in nature and and that was just part
of her medicine so and and so as i grew
up i was always surrounded by it and
luckily it was i was in southern oregon
so
you know that we we saw the first
you know sticky kind buds you know
coming in and the oregon big buds and
the purple cushes and
and i was just lucky enough to always be
around it i really never had to smoke
you know the mexican brick we eat and
different stuff that people had to smoke
and as i grew up i just always had good
good cannabis around and so you know
that that started my love and i and i
never did any other hard drugs or any
other things in life because that was
just a good print for me so that that
was my introduction and then me and
kelly met when i was you know
just 19 and that's a long time ago now
26 years but uh
um we're we're we're
we've had a journey in life since then
as well so yeah you know that's
something we've already talked about
and my first um
experience ever was i wasn't like josh
doll i grew up in virginia
um and was super conservative
you know
very
yeah east coast conservative family so i
never really saw it around you know i i
never had grown up with it i never saw
it around
and then i went out skiing um in wyoming
when i was probably about
14 years old
and a bunch of skier hot shots were up
on top of the mountain and everybody was
lighting up joints and i thought hey i
think i'll take a hit of that
and we were at the very top of the
mountain and a huge snowstorm came
through and it was a total white out and
i was stoned for the very first time in
my life
and it was awesome it was so great i
felt like wow i could see through the
white out and i'm the best skier in the
world and this is amazing and so like
josh i never really um
went into every happy drugs or got in
really to anything maybe alcohol for a
very very short time in my life but
cannabis has been a part of my life ever
ever since that day
how important do you feel it is to try
to have like a really positive first
experience and how much do you think it
affects people going forward in terms of
whether they're willing to try it again
whether they enjoy it overall
i think that it's
it's definitely you know that first time
is a really important time it's sort of
like
it's important i think to have a really
good experience and
now more and more people are able to
have good experiences i think because
people have an understanding of the
different values of oil or hash or
whether it's a joint and
even the youth have sort of an
understanding and and it's at its at the
fingertip you know you can go on to the
internet and you can learn so much about
different cannabinoids and what they
might do to you and stuff
but i think you know for us
at the very beginning
i know
for a lot of people that are my age um
mexican brickweed was was pretty much
like the first experience that they had
because that was what was available
you know in the late 70s and into the
early 80s that's all that i saw
and i think a lot of people
didn't necessarily have a very good
experience with it um maybe because the
way that it was cultivated or maybe
because
you know it was actually really
incredibly strong whether the
the cannabinoids show that it was super
high thc or not it just seemed like
those flowers that were coming from
mexico at that time are really strong so
people were having not necessarily a
great experience you know just with that
but there's a lot of
ways that cannabis has given out
nowadays too so i mean one could have a
first experience in so many different
ways it could be phoenix tears it could
be medicals and so you know there's
one and i would take it maybe even one
step further and just say
you know from a
biological standpoint we we have you
know more receptors in our body cb1
receptors in our body than any other
receptors so
we
may or may not be
you know having a complete
endocannabinoid system you know some
people may have
taken pharmaceutical drugs maybe some
people have antibiotics whatever it was
maybe they haven't been close to nature
and so maybe their first experience was
like wow you know a neurological you
know completion to was almost shocked to
their system and and
that could be you know something that
that would really affect your first
experience and and it could be
overwhelming you know at times but i
think that
once you start you know finding the
right dosage or finding the right
medicine that works for you you know you
do start completing your endocannabinoid
system which then allows you to
heal in ways that you know is
adaptogenic and your your immune system
can decide what it is so uh you know
first responses
is um could mean a lot of things based
off you know and i think when you're
when your endocannabinoid system is
really flooded
um you're definitely going to have a
much better you know experience mentally
and emotionally as well
so i think that it's really i always
tell people if you didn't have a very
good experience the first time it's
probably because you know your
endocannabinoid system is a lot like a
dry sponge it takes a while
for the cannabinoids to sort of be
uptaken by by the body and and once that
happens
i think the chances of having a good
experience are way better and some
people don't even get high on their
first smoke you know it's like you hear
a lot of people oh i didn't feel
anything and then two
three times later and then by the third
time you're like oh
yeah i got it you know and so that's
that's really interesting too and i
think that just speaks to the molecular
biology and and the natural medicine
that it is so yeah
yeah some really really interesting
points you raised there one i just want
to touch back on quickly is how i think
kelly you mentioned how you know some of
these mexican strains had such potency
to them
a lot of people speak about this idea of
how
some of the strains people think back on
when they first started smoking and
they'll talk about them as if they're
just so much stronger than the stuff
today and then the counterpoint is
raised that well because good weed was
kind of so sparse and it was just near
and far in between where you'd get it it
it emphasized that and it maybe makes
people feel like things were more potent
than they were do you feel that's the
case or do you feel that there truly was
this very unique profile back then which
really did make things just kind of blow
your socks off
well i mean you always hear oh people
bred out the cbd and they just only bred
for the high and they only bred for thc
which means that at one point there was
none of that happening so that's the
early 70s in the late 60s so at that
time you would think there would be
potentially a more complete or wide
range of cannabinoids at the time i
would i would think you know people talk
about how i smoke a whole lid you know
with the the term back in the day
and um you know and it wouldn't get you
totally ripped but it would just be like
a beautiful high and it was like the
flower power and the and like the
beautiful things of the of the 60s and
70s back to the land all that
was really done like on that kind of
herb and in that kind of medicated state
so
i i also know that you know i think it's
kind of known that the columbia
colombian gold was uh was really strong
you know
and or the acapulco gold was uh you know
really strong too and and and the
oaxacan some of the oaxacan streams were
known to be really strong so i don't
think that i've seen cannabinoid reports
from back in those days but um that's my
gut feeling
yeah and i think my take on that would
be that the terpene ratios are you know
really important when we talk about that
i think that
you know in the inner breeding that
we've done you know all the way to this
point now from you know back in the late
60s
we're really breeding for different
types of terpene ratios and we keep
seeing the mercene you know going up and
up you know so a lot of terpene profiles
are starting to be bred out of it and i
think when you have a really full
rich terpene profile
then you have more of a chance of like
getting sort of that psychedelic feeling
you know when you have full cannabinoid
full terpene
i mean and i and i've even seen that now
in tests i'd be like you know that one
really sort of felt a little bit trippy
i felt a little hallucinogenic with that
and maybe that's what people are talking
about because i can think about you know
my first joints it was all the mexican
brickweed and i was actually going into
it was at school in arizona for a short
time and
i mean that's the way i made my way
through college was
sort of swinging that around and
i definitely feel like
that flower did create a hallucinogenic
effect every time that you smoked it and
i could say the same thing about the
original purple tie stick that people
used to get a hold of or just the tie
stick
that was another one that really sort of
created like that hallucinogenic feeling
and maybe that's what people are talking
about when they talk about you know
getting really high maybe they weren't
getting necessarily really high but they
were feeling sort of that hallucinogenic
psycho
you know and the terpenes you know they
do play on that and if you travel to
mexico in back you know throughout your
life you may have seen
better mexican weed you know then when
it got bricked you know it is true you
know it affect the terpenes and so you
know you lose a lot of that
and it is sad there was um paraquat was
a was a really big part of you know
growing in the mexican weed and when my
dad was was dying of cancer he had a
medical intuitive that was saying that
the paraquat that was in
the mexican brickweed that the
governmental
agents just sprayed from the air from
from helicopters was you know uh was
really in that herb right right there so
that's that who knows what other and
that could have maybe made you feel more
high or psychedelic too you know what
was being added to it
but anyway that's those are some
thoughts
really really interesting ideas and it
raises my next point which is where do
you think we're going to go with
terpenes next and the reason why i ask
this is because
i feel like you know to kind of lend
from the school of thought of bodhi that
terpenes are almost like
a gateway or cannabis these days is
almost like a gateway drug to like
wanting to discover terpenes more you
know like i feel like it's only kind of
natural or intuitive to want to get more
into like kind of
perfumes and alchemy and just
generally exploring it more because
something i've noticed is like when i've
got some incense burning or i've maybe
smelled some ood recently if ever i
smoke i seem to get way more high even
though the terpenes aren't necessarily
from the cannabis itself so where do you
think we go next with terpenes
well i i like that that we have the
ability to explore different strains and
there's a market for it there's consumer
interest in it and there's more
education on terpenes and
when you really just start analyzing
strains simply from the standpoint of is
it high in mercene at or in high in thc
or not it's amazing how many strains are
high in mercy and that's been said you
know many times so when you get into
high you know
beta asamine or or terpenoline or you
know different strains like that it's
it's a f it's part of getting high it's
i mean it's urine it's just like food
you know you're letting down
saliva or different compounds in your
mouth as you smell things and that's
like a pre-digester to your food it's
just like kind of a pre high to smell
the weed i mean that's why you want
terpene you know ratios in your in your
lab test to be you know three percent to
six and you know maybe seven percent
would be amazing because that's part of
the high
so um
so terpenes you know food there's food
terpenes there's if you're gonna extract
terpenes and add terpenes to food and
use essences you know that's a that's a
really big open market there's countries
that won't allow cannabis derived
terpenes and there's ones that will um
but there's also people in the cannabis
industry that use food grade terpenes
and did you want to talk about that or
yeah no but um yeah so the the
food-grade terpenes are you know not
necessarily made to the same standards
or the same purity that can have uh you
know
uh ganja terpene may be made so
having cannabis derived terpenes is you
know a really really good thing for
medicine and for being able to use it in
food and different different drinks
and what i see um
in the industry right now which is what
josh just touched on is that
the more that we abuse this plant and
the more that we continue to grow her in
a synthetic environment and the more
that we disregard
ecology and disregard the environment
and microbiology the more that the plant
is going to react she's an adaptogen she
adapts so she's going to adapt to
whatever environment that you put her in
and what we notice is that you can take
a full spectrum cannabinoid plant with
full spectrum terpenes in it you can put
it in a
in an environment where she's not being
you know taken care of and not being
regarded in a very high manner and
what's going to happen is that all of
the terpene ratios go away thc rises and
the mercene rises so to me that tells me
that those are both stressors
there are stressors within the plant
that that's what she does when she
starts to adapt now you can maybe even
take that plant that's super high mercy
and really high thc you can put it into
a deep soil beautiful living bed
outdoors under the sun and then you'll
really start to understand what the full
genetic is of that plant i don't think
that the way that we are growing now in
the way that we're trading these
genetics that we think are just the bomb
and the fire
you know is very respectful to the plant
so i feel like she's reacting by you
know lowering her terpene and hiring her
thc counts and i think that the future
of the medicine is nootropic i mean and
also you know full spectrum and and it's
really important to have nutraceuticals
over the pharmaceuticals to where the
plant is being used and i think that
when people are being given a choice on
what they want to smoke or what they
want to ingest
if they have a choice between a plant
that hasn't been very respected and is
put into these heavy synthetic
environments with high mercine and high
thc
as opposed to something that has been
totally respected and is able to show
its full value in its genetics they're
going to choose that full spectrum plant
so i'm really hoping that in the future
more and more people have an ability to
be able to
experience the two different varietals
and be able to experience um you know
full spectrum and i would like to think
that that's going to be the future of
the industry with terpenes and i think
the reason why the terpenes you know are
better or last longer with living soils
is because they have
the fungal filaments in the roots eating
the microbiology and really
adding you know the right waxes and the
right terpenes and the right gases
within the within the trichomes for the
cure to last right you know if it's
grown
synthetically or you know hydroponically
it doesn't necessarily have the same
body of flavor you know in the long run
and it may not last you know longer than
two weeks and still be fresh but when
when a plant is grown when we say
respectfully we say you know in a in a
living soil that's really active and and
adding metabolites to the soils and to
the plants so the reason why it's better
is because it has a
complete system that it's working with
with which allows it to complete its
system so and i think that a good way to
for people to understand it is i just
believe like that high thc high mercing
is really the cortisol of the plant it's
the plant showing its stresses and then
when you have a plant that has full
terpene and full cannabinoid ratios that
that plant is just really full of
serotonin it like has all of the happy
things and i believe that you really
feel that as well you know when you're
ingesting a plant that's happy you're
gonna have a way higher chance of of
having a better experience
of course so many points we need to
touch on but i mean the first one which
comes to mind is when you reference kind
of you know growing the plant
respectfully and how that means in a
really nice well catered organic matter
to me it raises the idea of is it
possible
because i'm not sure myself is it
possible to grow quote organically in a
coco medium
well
you know then you just start getting
into terms you know so i mean
yeah it's possible to have probably like
for the you know the usda which is to
you'd have to check your country you
know but i'm sure that you could just
use organic products that are certified
and say yeah it's organic but
from our standpoint you know the organic
has been hijacked in that from that
perspective and and that's why
regenerative makes a lot of sense to us
because
to say the word regenerative really
means you're regenerating life which
means you have living soils and so
uh those soils are
aiding in the medicine and that makes
the medicine better so um you know to
have
a more diverse soil
is going to be more regenerative and
from our perspective more natural
and and better than organic
and then you you're really addressing
the endophytic reaction which is within
the plant which is something that we're
just absolutely
you know
fascinated with because i'm incredibly
fascinated with the human microbiome as
well so if you take a plan and you're
growing it in cocoa and you're giving it
organic
amendments like what josh says sure you
can say that it's grown organically but
was it grown naturally was it grown in a
biological way the answer would be no
because you're not really creating any
biology in your coco coir there's no
living food web there's no you know
microbiology and it really doesn't allow
the plant to
reach its full potential because a full
potential of a plant is when you have
maximum
endophytes within it and it's all
working within the soil and all the way
up to the leaves it's it's a complete
cycle and microbiology you know it's
like well you can you can say that you
could be on an organic diet too
like if you
you know are you are getting fed through
an iv tube or something like that you
can say well you could put organic you
know nutrients into the iv and the
person can stay alive and you can say
well they have an organic diet but
they're completely passing the
microbiome which is the digestive system
which is the same as when you're you're
taking away that living soil attribute
so is that person who's you know living
on this organic iv diet gonna have the
same
you know full immune stimulus response
as the person who's using their
digestive tract in a full living
microbiome you know the answer is no
it's really no different for a plant
of course of course reminds me of like a
use it or lose it attitude but it raises
a very interesting point around
classifications and certifications
i've long been very skeptical of the
omri certification i'm sure a lot of
people are as well you can it takes you
know no less than five seconds to find a
product that's clearly not organic that
has an organic certification on it so it
raises the question do we just look to
avoid it and just go based off things
you know for sure are organic because
you often hear people say oh i don't use
anything from a bottle but at the same
time there are some products i use that
come from a bottle that i know are full
well organic so how do you kind of
navigate this minefield as it may be
well you touched on something really
important which is omri omri is a
registration
it is not an organic certification and
if you go on to omri's website that's
the first thing that they say it's a
registry and the language is really
powerful and important because omri will
state that this is you know um able to
be used in an organic for use in organic
yeah for use in organic agriculture but
it's still up to the third-party
certifier
on whether that's organic or not so it's
it's only a registry created within that
system that says you know you if you
didn't have
a product available
when in need you know that you had the
ability to use a chemical here and there
and so
and so we you know and this is not just
a philosophy so we we have over the
years been very we have products as you
know you know so we've had all of our
products tested so we're testing
raw materials for 12 years now and
and we you know we're really aware of of
what's
where there's glyphosate you know and
glyphosate's just one compound you know
there could be decamba or just there's a
thousand other compounds but that are
defoliants and whatnot but
so but we're careful about that so you
know
do you look for a certification well you
know i think at this point it's just a
matter of education you know if someone
says they're biodynamic
you know that may or may not be to the
usda standards or it may
but you would probably feel pretty good
about it because you know the biodynamic
standards are strong and people are
really of the earth
that are doing that and they're making
the world a better place um
you know other other organic standards
that are based solely on products so you
can have an organic product in a bottle
but
it if it's it still has to have a
stabilizer in it and usually that
stabilizer is a small percentage of
non-organic compounds so i mean from our
certification we really
recommend against anything in bottles
and go with raw materials because that's
just the closest thing that you can get
to something that's natural which is
going to feed your
microbiology if you're getting something
in a bottle if it's not like expanding
and blowing up in the bottle then it's
not alive really if it's in a little you
know it's it's being stabilized and i'm
not saying it's not useful because
obviously people are using things in
bottles and growing plants so it's it's
not that it's just
if you want to
regenerate life on earth you have to go
you know beyond beyond the bottle and so
that's you know we have our
certification and we've gone beyond just
certifying products like our our
certification is not okay give me a list
of products you know and let's go
through this this process of deciding
whether there's heavy metals in them or
or um uh maybe you know something like
pyrinthrians or something that's going
to
fail a test so what we do is we say okay
well let's try and grow it naturally
let's try and enhance our natural biome
and our natural plants so certifications
can mean a lot of things and and and it
really is a it takes education to learn
what each certification is about
yeah of course
so would your rule of thumb in general
be
you know if if you want to something
from a bottle so to speak just make it
yourself
i mean that's what we suggest and i i
think also
you know we
we created the certification and we've
actually even had people say well it's
so romantic you know it's like something
that people could only strive for and
maybe not or only dream of and not
really do
and the reason why we created the
standards that we created which is
really utilizing as many closed loops as
you can whether you're an indoor
gardener whether you have a tiny little
small plot in your backyard there's
still so many easy things that you can
do
to become closed loop and it wasn't
because
it just is sort of this romantic idea
what we're realizing is that the more
closed loop that you are and the more
vigilant that you are about what is to
your plants then you don't even have to
sweat it when somebody buys your whole
stock and they turn it into a
concentrate because what we're seeing
over and over again is people that are
organic certified and they're following
all the organic you know certificate or
all of the organic registering uh
products out there that they're still
failing
yeah and department of agriculture is
like yeah thumbs up it's so awesome you
could totally do this this is organic
it's usda or it's canadian certified or
whatever it is
then
the the flowers are concentrated and
they fail heavy metals tests they fail
all different kinds of crazy tests
because
they're they're concentrating it because
it's becoming concentrated so whatever
was in that flower what was ever in the
soil or whatever was in your your
soilless medium is going up into your
flower this idea of like oh you can
flush it out
you know
we always thought it was a joke and now
science is proving it to us that it's a
joke you know it doesn't just flush out
it goes up into the plant and it stays
there for its duration and it stays
there all the way until you know it's
done and and then you turn it into a
concentrate and it becomes really
apparent
and there's too many farmers out there
that have lost their entire crop because
it's turned into a concentrate and they
fail a test
so it's really beautiful it's like
cannabis is giving us this beautiful
opportunity right now
to
look at our food sources to look at big
agriculture to look at the what we're
feeding our plants to to to all of a
sudden have a look at the apples that
are you know in the store and wonder
geez you know
what's in this because now i know with
cannabis testing
it's just really leading the way and and
it's not surprising because it's a
master plant and it's what she she does
she gives us different ideologies and
she gives us you know different keys and
and solutions you know when we ingest
her and also when we cultivate her and
it's not just um you know because
we don't believe in the system it's just
when we you know we've learned that 75
million tons of top soil have been lost
since the industrial revolution and we
know that
um you know there's a million species on
earth that are you know potentially
going extinct maybe the great barrier
reef is dying you know so what we're
trying to say is you know our our
certification is certifying farms when
we say the word regenerative we know
we're regenerating life on earth and
it's really meaningful to us and we're
we're growing medicine that's beyond
just the term organic because
or the term organic at this point is
just a
sort of a word that's just been
you know hollowed out by the system you
know and so what we're doing is we're
you know these these close-up systems
are are creating ingenuity on the farm
so
you know we can put carbon back into the
soil because agriculture you know
releases up to 12 gigatons of co2 a year
i mean there's there's so many reasons
why we have to do better and we we know
the small farms have to save the earth
so we're creating small farm webs that
are saving their earth
that brings us to a perfect next point
which is that i've had a lot of people
message me from both around australia
new zealand and even some other distant
parts of the world and all of them ask
questions along the same line which is
you know how can i become
a a pure farm myself maybe not in a farm
sense but you know how can i try to get
my little tent or my little
uh you know backyard plot as closely
aligned with the dragonfly ethos as
possible and i guess it raises an
interesting point you know will you guys
be looking to expand internationally
with the certification
we already have we we already are
international and that's the beauty of
this is because it's community run and
community involved and it and it really
is creating
sort of a network um you know as the web
gets wider the weave gets tighter and we
all have an understanding
you know josh and i go out we and and we
do consultations or or we or we talk to
people and i always say you know people
like whoa that was so amazing it was so
great what you said and i always say
well i didn't really teach you anything
i'm just reminding you
so i think that we have all of this
great knowledge deep within our dna of
what we know is right on the earth and
when people you know hear about what
we're doing in the certification there's
so many that want to jump on because
they're reminded
of something that they know is a better
solution than than what's happening now
and no matter what size you know plot
you have you can be pure certified you
know we we we talk about having six
closed loops and the importance of that
and um you know so we're certifying all
different size farms from huge massive
hemp farms you know
to to small backyard plots and and and
there is a limitation on massive you
know hem farms and stuff but you know
when i talk you need to talk about 10
acres you know regeneratively or 20
that's that's pretty big and stuff so
that's that's the way we're
what we're thinking there and and so we
have you know um eatle green uh farm out
in switzerland who are certified and
uh
there's three farms in canada that are
certified and there's farms around the
us we went to thailand and we're in
communication with farms
with some some local farmers in thailand
and um
we really
do want to expand it into the world and
we do travel quite a bit in the world so
we would love to to visit an area to
really define what it is bioregionally
you know what pure certified would mean
or what you know regenerative would mean
in a bioregion and right now we're not
certifying a lot of indoor farms what we
have is mostly sun grown outdoor farms
and people with food gardens and so the
part of the requirements of what we have
is to have a food garden and to have
pollinator and flower gardens aside from
your cannabis or or even better mixed in
with your cannabis so and it can be done
indoors and we are working on creating a
pure certified indoor
um certification which would and entail
um
you know
some type of alternative energy or some
um ways that you've lowered your energy
use and your grid using led lights or or
some kind of a mixed spectrum um so um
yes i you know we would just like to
tell people out in the world please get
in touch with us i mean you know what
we're interested in is really earth
stewards uniting and telling our story
together um it doesn't have to be just
cannabis we you know food farms are out
there getting in touch with us too um
wineries anyone really it's it's kind of
a way of life
you know and we we support each other
the best we can as family
um you know to to just be natural and
make a difference and and also we we
find ways we can work together with
business
and it's not it's not an exclusivity
thing it's it's absolutely earth
stewards unite it's it's so important if
you have these wonderful ideas and
there's a way that you can make a change
within your own you know community or
your own neighborhood you know do it if
something inspires you then we're just
really encouraging people to do it see
what happens you know part of the pure
certification that we do also is that
you have to be part of community
education in some way so you know
go out there share share your successes
share your failures you know talk about
what worked and what didn't work we have
we're at this wonderful like bell curve
of knowledge in the human race right now
we're able to find knowledge at a single
touch of the button and we're sharing
knowledge in such an excited way and i
think that you know the more that we're
able to align with nature she has more
and more solutions with us and and
that's really
you know the main connection not only
are we connected by this master plan but
we're also connected for with our love
of nature and also i'll just just add
really quickly that our our ultimate our
best way of of taking on new areas is to
find a model farm say in australia or
new zealand you know a model farm that
would have us you know show up at the
farm we could have a gathering where we
met you know local farmers
and then what we do is we because our
certification is free it's more about
you know
being able to complete all of the
requirements and and then once we visit
you know say that model farm then we
could create a
peer-reviewed um
inspection so once one farm is uh
uh certified then they go out and
certify other farms and then they can
tell from that farm whether it reflects
you know the level of standards and
ethics that they have and that's the way
that it builds within each region so we
may come for the original one and maybe
we try and come back again later you
know on other years but um it becomes
peer-reviewed and it and it's we take it
really seriously so all farms are having
everything
you know every input on the farm is is
tested and inspected to human uh grade
quality and art and all of our products
are also you know tested in laboratories
so you know we we have to walk our talk
and and create medicine that's
um you know really valuable to the
market
most certainly so at the start of that
one you mentioned that you had been
looking at some stuff in thailand i
noticed that you've been posting a
reasonable amount of content from bali
what's your involvement with that
um we've been going to bali for a really
long time uh let's see i think maybe
about 17 17 years
we've been going to bali and and it
started with me at the beginning is that
i was um josh and i were both
instrumental in opening up a free clinic
for women and
in a birthing center so also for
pregnant women as well as postnatal
women to be able to come in and receive
help um to receive care so that was
something that we started and we just
kept going back and then when the
tsunami happened um
we were the first boots on the ground in
the aceh province
we worked with permaculture
ngos edep was one and
while he which was friends of the earth
and we we worked with other
world ngos to to come together to create
you know safe place for women and
children during chaos
so we we did a lot of work in in that
area and also supported a clinic in bali
as well
so we have a lot of family it's it's
it's sort of another home for us that's
another heart space for us in the world
so
when we go there we you know we see a
lot of family and friends and i get to
be surrounded with a lot of older
children that i got to see you know into
the world so it's it's just a it's a
root for us and we we do custom sarongs
and make custom surrounds but we also
you know that's a side thing but um
we um work with permaculture you know we
we
really really like seeing the expansion
of permaculture that's happening on bali
and there's a lot of international
people there and just a lot of really
amazing food to table
uh farm to table
um
raw food places and and farms that are
really beautiful there so it's been
really fun to watch the conscious
expansion
yeah being one of the
countless australians who's been to bali
myself i can attest that the uh the food
there's great and the fact that it's
grown locally and organically only helps
i guess the question i'm wondering is
what's the local production of cannabis
like there because from my extremely
extremely limited experience it was it
was hard to find decent quality stuff
but that's very much from the
perspective of like you know someone
who's not in the loop with any of the
locals or anything what's it like when
you're part of that inner circle
well in bali particularly we wouldn't
recommend it at all you know it's a very
indonesia's incredibly strict
even though a lot of the the older
balinese and especially when you go over
to sumatra you know you definitely see a
lot of the locals using cannabis and
it's sort of a normalcy for them
um some some of the most isolated
cannabis in the world you know that i
believe to still be you know true land
race is in sumatra or is in some of the
islands in indonesia because it's been
so blocked off but
you know if you if you go to bali it's a
really good time to take a break it's
it's not a time to ask people on the
streets you know where to find it or
where to get it um you know people are
found with with five grams and they're
spending 17 years in jail as australians
it's not something that you want to be
doing and really the quality that you
get is going to be from another island
so
um
you know
i would just really recommend to people
that that's just not a place where where
cannabis mixes with their vacation
right but of course you see a lot of
these old land races that i was just
talking about and that's something that
i'm really interested in you know when i
went and worked over in sumatra for many
months i learned a lot about
the relationship that the locals had
there with cannabis it's a very tight
close relationship it's something that
they used to calm down it was something
that they used in their daily life
when they would come into the clinic i
would say you know how much do you smoke
and they would say well i smoke you know
six of these and they would point to
their breast pocket that had the tobacco
and they'd say i'd smoke eight of these
a day and that's you know the cannabis
pocket so
even though there's this really
incredible sort of
strict regiment um and laws
yeah sharia law it's really interesting
is a c e h which is an acronym for
arabic chinese european and hindustani
and um it's it's it's it's just because
c is as that sound in indonesia but that
the aceh region is in northern sumatra
and it's one of the most strict islamic
areas
in
indonesia but it's where all the herb is
grown so it's super kind of like and
they have gorilla kind of they had that
you know different autonomous
regions there and and they they say that
the their weed came from india back in
the the dutch trading days and stuff so
i you know exactly how long it's been on
sumatra
maybe hundreds of years we don't really
know exactly because
it has really closed off but it is
interesting how it's in
common you know the common person's
possession in northern sumatra you know
in that area and it's a real
tall
thin leafed variety
that has you know uplifting terpenes uh
you know more like a limonene
beta-caryophyllene terpinilline um they
take an incredibly long time to flower
um
so they're really reminiscent of
of just interesting cannabis
that you know is not something that and
it definitely gives you a very different
feeling you know we were talking earlier
about oh you know those old land races
and what does it make you feel like well
you know that really isolated very far
removed and not interbred with a lot of
the modern cannabis
um
of today
really gives you a totally different eye
than than what the modern uh cannabis we
brought we brought some seeds back so
you know we're trying to give it a try
to germinate them it can be a little
difficult but you know what we we are
always a little bit of uh
you know
crafty let's say
yeah things manage to just appear back
at home somehow
and malaysia's laws are changing so
we're really hopeful that indonesia's
laws change with that with thailand's
change the world
you know is changing and and i would
love nothing more than to be able to to
work with
hemp or hemp oils in indonesia because
there's crazy sicknesses happening there
and and i'm in love with rice and what's
happened with rice is their staple diet
is creating a lot of weird illnesses
there so i mean they they could really
use the medicine and it would be nice to
see some law changes there and it was
great this time that we went to bali
there was
more and more people asking us about it
and really absolutely you know how i was
talking about earlier of just being
reminded that this is a good medicine
and they would say oh well my
grandmother used that in tea absolutely
you know
there's no like bad reflection you know
on cannabis or they haven't been through
like any kind of a political move they
just know that it's illegal but they
don't really get why it's illegal
yeah it's in the village but it's not
given out to the tourists there's a
clear distinction and stuff so yeah
that's that's what's happening there
yeah kind of backs my uh limited
experience admittedly i was what 14 when
i went there so many moons ago but uh to
jump onto something a little more recent
it's been well over a year since we last
talked probably should have asked this a
little earlier on but what's new in the
world of dragonfly
oh
so much
i feel like you know one week in the
cannabis industry feels like a year
so
there's
so much that's happening right now you
know we just wanted to be humble
cannabis farmers and producing beautiful
medicine for sick people and now all of
a sudden we're learning about genetic
coding and patenting and markering and
corporate takeovers and creating a
business and how you have to you know
learn the rules so you know how to break
them and
it's just and federal licensure and how
to do it without a consultant and
you know still having our products and
still growing a whole new garden and
every year but mostly exciting the most
exciting thing we think is just
this the the collective of farmers and
businesses that we're working with and
the science of regenerative cannabis
tour that we've been doing is really
amazing and just the expansion of
knowledge of organic and regenerative
practices and
we've recently formed an online
communication hub where we can all
communicate with each other live
and it's really really excellent because
there's you know you know 75 people on
there that are very you know active and
we all can communicate with each other
and and it's just really really helpful
and i think like as much of the heavy
feeling of licensure and the man coming
down on you and heavy duty fines and all
that sort of stuff or you know people
having to close up their farms because
they can't make you know they're in
economic struggles you know as much as
all of that is really difficult and that
is happening
is as equal
of what is fabulous and fantastic that's
happening right now i mean
we are so totally sparked on by people
you know this is a perfect example we we
got back from indonesia we had been on a
flight for i don't even know it felt
like 36 hours josh and i hadn't slept we
spent two hours in in vancouver and like
it's great in vancouver so we're able to
like smoke some bulls right there in the
airport
just right outside of the airport and
then we flew onto michigan and it was
dark and it was snowing and we had just
come from indonesia we're like what in
the heck are we doing here this is
totally crazy
and then not even five hours later
we walked into a room of people at the
conference at the science of
regenerative cannabis conference
and it only took one second to realize
why we do this
like
as much as it seemed like whoa that was
a really crazy journey like the energy
in that room of people that just want to
connect over this plant and
want to connect over nature and want to
connect over like learning about
microbiology and how to better their
life and how to get off their
pharmaceuticals because it's all in
relation you know we really have this
understanding that if you have healthy
soil then you have healthy life
and it's like all of that is happening
too so it's this really beautiful yin
and yang right now and i feel like
they're equally as potent and it's and
and and that's why i say you know one
week in the cannabis industry is a year
because
so much is happening within that one
week that you know you really want to
like hold on to it and soak it up
because it's just all so potent and the
farm bill passed and the hemp is you
know a really big frontier and
feminization of seeds and you know
there's there's a lot that we've been
we've been talking about so
that can spark uh you know more
conversation
so you guys brought up the science and
regenerative cannabis conferences how
has that been and what types of things
can we expect to see kind of springing
forth as a result of those conferences
well um what's really beautiful about
the conferences is that it is
really rooted in science and it does go
through and give you really nuts and
bolts
information from really good presenters
but it's almost been become like a
spiritual thing too because
i mean
farmers
have to band together right now and and
not only is it exciting to create a
natural system and get you know good
product it's also kind of a beautiful
networking
opportunity for people to come together
so you know we did it internationally
this year for the first time in
vancouver and
um farms are just becoming you know
they're just branding themselves here in
in canada and british columbia this year
so they they haven't been able to
you know
say you know i'm a farm until you know
now so there's it's now almost new here
i'm humbled i know was it was really
really amazing and
farmers are really really coming
together
and showing up in numbers and just
really seed swapping and sharing seeds
with each other it's really just an open
public domain of knowledge sharing and
it's not just a presentation you know
we're we're staying in the parking lot
in between we're eating together we're
staying around at night and so we're
really really connecting with the crowd
and going to areas where they really
haven't had conferences like maine and
michigan and a lot of people you know
were saying that you know i came here to
learn about science of soil and cannabis
and i left with 120 brand new amazing
friends that i know that i can call
within a minute so
it's like
what these are giving us is inspiration
like there's so many crazy things going
on in the world and you turn on your tv
and if you get sucked into those
doldrums of whatever that is
it's like we need to get out of that we
need to just look at each other in the
faces and talk about things that inspire
us and it's so amazing to be in a room
with all of that those people that are
that inspired by nature that really want
to make a change in their own lives and
we really you know recommend that you
know you asked earlier what can people
do they really want to do something
what we recommend is start with yourself
it starts with self-love and it starts
with wanting to make changes within your
own body and then that ripples out and
when you have all of those wonderful
feelings about yourself and the health
and well-being within your own body then
it's really easy to educate it's really
easy to get the word out because you're
really walking you know your talk
and you know there's there's like we
said there's science presentations and
then we will have our pure
certified farmer's panels in the evening
where you can do question and answer and
it gives each farm an opportunity to
say what they do on their farm that you
know maybe has taken some of the
practices that are being taught and
shown people how they've put it into
action so it's really useful
for people that are attending the
conference to hear you know from five
different farms that are you know
publicly you know creating medicine and
and putting themselves out there to say
hey this is how i've taken these systems
and put them into action and that's been
really useful the question and answer
and um and the genetics talks and you
know there's a lot with genetics right
now so
there's been a lot of a lot of talk
about that
a bit of a left of field question but do
you find that the people who attend
these conventions or in general just
people are part of say the pure family
tend to gravitate towards certain types
of genetics or do you think it's rather
a diverse spectrum
diverse yeah i think it's diverse but
there's more and more topics of full
spectrum cannabinoid profiles and full
spectrum terpene profiles and the
importance of that
in really bringing forth the medicine so
that
you know we can hold a good voice for
the plant so it seems to me like you
know more and more people are
gravitating to that but of course the
old strains are out there and people are
i mean you know there's a there's a
there's a good amount of us that are
keeping land race alive there's a good
amount of us that are really keeping
hash strains and and
searching for the best hash strains you
know this is a big part of it hemp is a
big part of it and a breeding project
for hemp is a really big part of it um
you know i wouldn't say that everyone
loves you know gas or fruit or flora it
really is it's something for everyone i
think that's that's what's awesome about
it it's it's never uh it's always
different
of course so
part of strain selection for any farmer
is considering the types of pests you
have to deal with in your area or within
your grow environment i remember at the
emerald cup last year i asked a question
that was essentially around the lines of
what happens to the predator bug
excretions like is that a problem in
itself and our colleague on the panel
ron gave a fantastic answer but i also
remember having a look over and seeing
this huge grin on kelly's face when i
asked that
i would love to know what's your opinion
on this what happens to the bug poop
um you know
there's an incredible
web of microbiology and you know if
you're even somebody that wants to order
predators out there in the world you
already probably are not spraying crap
on your plants and your and you have if
you look under a
microscope you would see a tremendous
amount of microbiology and there's
cyanobacteria that's on the leaf
structure of the plant and when you have
a really healthy plant you've got a huge
diversity of different cyanobacteria
different types of fungi on there so a
lot of the times if there is predator
poop it is actually being digested
by what's already on the plant you know
the microbiology it feeds the plant you
know the more you know natural
expressions that happen on the plant and
the more that we mimic nature which when
you're mimicking nature you're going to
have an incredible diversity of both
microbiology and macrobiology
on your plants and if you allow you know
that nature and that full you know
potential you know
of
of what is possible within nature then
the plant is really absorbing that and
it becomes an incredible nutrient for
the plant so
that's probably why i was smiling i was
thinking you know that's probably just
good food for the plant
and depending on what state you're in
and and what your your
requirements are for passing tests i
mean
you know you have to be extremely
careful nowadays with what happens with
your flowers and whatnot and stuff and
and and there's there's pathogen tests
and and aspergillus is you know things
that have been brought up that have may
maybe have been associated with
predators and stuff so
you know you
it's it's it's the system that's been
created to grow cannabis in is
almost impossible
so i think it's amazing that people are
doing as well as as they're doing and
honestly like in life
you kind of need to be able to to eat
like microscopic insect poop or smoke it
even that's what i think but just to
survive you know of course because
an immune response within the plant and
within your own body as well which is
just incredibly important we're
suppressing our immune response with all
of these outside sources of just like
sterilized sterilized antibiotics kill
the microbiology and the more that we
learn we're realizing that microbiology
is what's clean
so you know worried about a little bit
of poop that's from a predator you know
might
it's definitely something to look at if
you're doing really strict regimen of
testing but as far as a home grower or
somebody that you know is
is just making medicine for other people
and for themselves and sharing it i mean
that's awesome and and also you know you
probably don't want to get your
predators really late in your flower
cycle it would be a really good idea to
allow them to
you know eat eat all of uh the pathogens
on their
you know several weeks before harvest
yeah fantastic and i think you know i i
don't ask that as though i feel like
it's a major problem i ask it because
it's it's the commonly used line which
people who are
whether overtly or kind of more
subconsciously are critical of predator
bugs and maybe organics in general
that's what they use to try to kind of
discredit it and i think it's an
interesting point but maybe not as valid
as maybe a other one they could come up
with but i digress
something we also spoke about last year
though was how big of an issue aphids
were
how do you guys advocate to combat it
you know it's it's an ever-changing
problem what's your solution to aphids
or just in general bugs outdoors
polyculture
absolutely
there's a wonderful example
you can go into williams into southern
oregon
and we have a whole lot of pure farms
there and a lot of friends that have
farms in that area it's definitely like
a cannabis mecca in the world so when
you go into williams area you've seen
you know cannabis farms pretty much
almost every single property there's the
rare property that's not growing
cannabis
and
they got hit really hard with aphids
this year aphids is absolutely the new
pathogen that everybody needs to prepare
for
and we know of one farm and that's casey
over rising phoenix
phoenix rising farms
and he did an over abundance of
pollinator like garden like you wouldn't
believe flowers just everywhere he's a
gorgeous farm and he did flowers
everywhere and he didn't have one
single aphid at all because wasps eat
like triple their weight in aphids in a
day so and same with you know all these
different types of bugs out there as
well as bees and i mean and as well as
birds um
so
that's just a perfect example and maybe
you have a
nursery and a greenhouse and you can do
a heat treatment at 120 degrees for
50 degrees centigrade
you know two hours or whatnot and and
maybe three and you just monitor it make
sure the plants are doing good but you
can heat treat a nursery pretty easily
and that's a really clean easy way to
deal with it also you know a good spray
with water
um early on
can can can get them but you know that's
another thing and and some people have
had success after heat treatments um
uh
with with like a
a good uh
swing oh yeah
we've had the the best experience when
when when it first came out i noticed it
right away i've said whoa this is not a
normal aphid i don't care what anybody
says this is we're not dealing with a
normal aphid so
i put it into jars i fed it all these
different things i was watching how many
it was reproducing or cloning itself i
was feeding it all different types of
foods you know even brassicas and it was
running from the brassicas like what
aphid runs from a brassica like david
survive off of brassicas you know it's
their number one food source and this
one was so different and
it has like these little hooks on its
chest that other aphids don't have so i
knew that we were like up against
something really interesting
and the way that it was
you know propagating um itself was like
quadruple the rate
at that time and so we're really
watching this and i think josh and i you
know we put this out on instagram right
away
and
many several years ago
and people were like what is that those
look like normal aphids you know and
what we noticed is i sprayed
probably 25 different oils on it and all
different homemade things and things
that i could and finally we just came to
what would happen
if we mess with the bacterium which is
inside of the aphid which has to be
some kind of have have some kind of a
heat issue going on
and that bacterium is what helps it
propagate and what clones itself so if
you mess with that bacteria which is
inside of the aphid bringing the
temperature up high then it sterilizes
it and we realized that really soon on
so we started doing tests and how many
hours and how high did the temperatures
need to get and were they harming any of
our pollinators or or was it harming
some of the other important you know
insects that we had within the
greenhouse
and we really came to that 120 degrees
for two to three hours
and your
pollinators just thrive in that heat the
plants thrive in that heat as long as
they're damp and they're not in small
pots you cannot be heating up the roots
to that but the plants really thrive in
that and the aphids are completely
sterilized and then within a very short
period of time
all of your insects that like to eat the
aphids will come in within a couple of
days and just pick them off because
they're not
propagating and recolonizing themselves
so heat treatment i think above and
beyond anything else it's absolutely the
way to go
um and also pollinators if they're
outside because they are in our natural
environment i don't know where they came
from they came like an incredible
vengeance um i would you know venture to
say that
somebody made them up as an evil plan
but you know i can't you know put my
finger on that by any means but it just
the way that it came into our community
and they weren't just being passed by
clones because we don't use clones we we
only started with seeds and all of a
sudden they were here
so
i think i think that pollinators if
you're outdoors and heat treatment for
greenhouses and indoors
some really solid suggestions there i
remember that another major point that i
took away from that discussion was that
the use of essential oils was
potentially a lot more problematic than
people are aware would you be able to go
into a little more depth for our
audience who maybe haven't been able to
hear that discussion
um
well i mean for me i don't i don't
really like to be covered in oil
you know i don't know about you but sort
of that thick oily feeling all over your
body is really no different than what
the plant feels and when you're spraying
heavy oils or any kind of volatile
essential oils or even like a coconut
oil then that's going to immediately
change the microbiome on your leaf
surface and when you change the
microbiome of your leaf surface then
you're allowing in other problems and i
always look at
what you do to your garden should be you
don't look at the first ripple you know
like if you drop a stone into water and
i know i've said this before but if you
drop a stone into water it's not the
first ripple you need to look at the
very last ripple so if you spray your
plants with essential oils for pests are
you going to be bringing in more
pathogenic leaf mildew you know or what
other factors or stressors or the plan
yeah light sensitivity or what other
stressors are the plant gonna have so
it's really not a solution
and it's definitely and it's and it's
more of an allopathic look at it rather
than a real holistic look which we
really encourage people to look at their
gardens more holistically so then we can
have a better understanding of looking
at our own health more holistically
because
cannabis has an incredible lesson to
teach us all which is
you know what she thrives best in is is
what we also thrive best in
yeah of course of course
so
what do you think of the emerald cup in
general we've had a little discussion
about our talks thus far but the overall
consensus i've had from a variety of
guests on the show is that the kind of
overall vibe and more specifically the
energy that's normally in the air just
wasn't quite there last year
how do you feel about that one
well first of all we really really love
the emerald cup and
um
you know we didn't know that was going
on because we were in our teepee
it's awesome in our teepees
i mean in all fairness i guess it's the
laws that have changed you know so the
laws in california have dictated the way
the event can run so i mean it's not
like
you know tim and taylor came out and
said oh you know we're gonna
or hazel whatever we're gonna we're
gonna run this you know like this you
know you know they're they're trying to
do the
most heartfelt amazing you know show
that they can do
you know with the laws that they've been
given
and and if you want to get get upset at
something get you know get upset at the
state of california and and the way that
they've created you know distribution
you know for farmers and
so because now you know you're not going
to get as many farmers as you did before
because they're probably through some
kind of distribution
company and maybe the distribution
company is awesome or maybe they're not
but
um yeah you know that the tents were
different than they were before and and
you could you know to get directly to a
farmer was different but
there was as many panels as there always
was and
you know for us the emerald cup is a
really great experience because we have
two teepees and we have our cocoa going
and we have all of the farmers that
we're working with
um around the whole time and we're we're
giving you know where we have seed
exchange happening and um you know we're
able to
you know consume and just really enjoy
each other and really talk a lot of
stories so i mean we have like you know
epic
times at the emerald cup and and i would
say you know
times have changed and that that's
what's hard but at the emerald cup it's
still a gathering of you know some of
the most amazing farmers in california
and there's really not another event
that's you know better than it at all
and
so you know we're really stoked about
what they've done and we're proud to be
part of it
and i can feel you know where those
people are coming from too and i think
you know josh really hit the nail on the
head is that
what people are feeling
is the new regulations what people are
feeling is you know
not that same direct voice from the
farmer
not the same type of diversity they're
feeling that you know
three years ago
a tremendous amount of farms that were
there no longer in business because they
couldn't stay in business because the
exorbitant licensing fees or
timing or you know people who have
applied for licenses and it's just
sitting in an office you know for years
i mean
it goes it goes on and on and on the
incredible regulations that farmers and
breeders and extractors and product
makers are under is is is so significant
that it absolutely doesn't surprise me
that people felt that energy at the
emerald cup
yeah so i think the general consensus we
have within the community in the moment
is that there is a lot of elements of
disunity and i guess distrust more
specifically for the way legal changes
and the way bigger companies are acting
on them how do you see us going forward
and what's the best way to kind of get
everyone on the same page in terms of
morals and ethics
drop the competition
we are not
in competition with each other these
outside big entities are coming in and
they're instilling a fear within people
that they need to be competitive
we are not competitive we are not in
competition we are the opposition we are
not in opposition we are just an
alternative we need to join together and
be really happy for other farmers
successes that are doing wonderful we
need to be happy for
you know passing out your your genetics
and somebody else did a better job than
what you did like that's freaking rad
we need to be happy for each other
because this sort of like fear-based
competitive thing
is coming into play and i really think
that if we can drop that
that's just the answer and realize that
you know that we are really a commodity
and that you know the large corporations
are
wanting to capitalize on
our intentions and on our ethics and
then
if farmers are not mindful they could
potentially join forces with you know
corporations and then in the end the
corporation just acts like a corporation
doesn't they just sell
potentially sell you off or sell off
your whole
your your face or what you've created
your marketing what all that and then so
you know this is a time when we're just
trying to say hey you know what let's
just
not be exclusive with any one person
let's just keep your autonomy let's
create independence and autonomy and
autonomy let's create products maybe
they're together maybe they're within
each farm and create a network so right
now it's just
don't get eaten by a corporation that's
that's that basically the money you wake
up in the morning and okay okay how am i
not going to get even by a corporation
and don't think that you know you've got
one contract that's in front of you that
that's going to be the last one that
you're ever going to see and we really
want to see more pro tracks rather than
contracts
no contracts
contrary to your well well-being you
know and and independence and realizing
that you can work together with other
farms and say hey you know what's hot
what do you guys got going on and the
more that you share and we talk to each
other then we're creating
a much larger commodity like josh said i
mean we
are the commodity for the first time you
know this year we started realizing how
many thousands and thousands of pounds
that the pure collective already
produces per year whereas these huge
corporations are just talking about you
know what they're going to do in 2021
we are already doing it the only way
that these corporations are going to get
the keys to our castle is if we give
them to them so keep the keys to your
castle share them with your friends who
are going to be respectful
and ethical in the same way that you are
a co-op
for sure so you guys put out your
perspective on the whole phylus debacle
a few weeks back
and to me it was you know beautiful kind
of statement of authenticity and kind of
reintegrating what we need to do to move
forward but there wasn't a lot of
views expressed on specifically how you
see the file or situation and what
they're doing do you feel like we're at
a point now where it's almost very
problematic to incorporate any sort of
genomic testing within our kind of
garden or our cultivars
well i mean you know
for sure we
were
totally against what happened with
phylos and what happened there you know
that just seemed like
something that you know it really
brought up the conversation as as
farmers where do where do we stand you
know what how do we work together and
and we look to like our food systems and
we look and we're looking to what's
happened with like food i mean you know
this this has happened before so we're
you know we're looking into open public
domain and
and breathing and you know i do
genomic sequencing comes from you know
large corporate machines and so you know
you'd have to be really skeptical to use
that information to think that someone
else isn't going to use it and maybe
they have better technology to use it
than you do i mean personally i just
want to give a big shout out and a thank
you to philos
what an incredible opportunity
that we were all given to look at the
dark side and to realize we better get
our [__] together and we need to start
creating this powerful entity you know
within ourselves and how is it that we
can pull together and since that time
has happened i mean the education that
josh and i have have searched out you
know we've gone to mentors we've been
talking to people that are way smarter
than we are and who have had way more
experience than we have on this and how
do they feel about you know public
domain and open source and and markering
and patenting and what i keep coming to
as far as the cannabis plant she's an
adaptogen
cool patent away
because great you're going to patent a
seed and then i'm going to take that
seed and i'm going to put it into my
deep red
rich beautiful garden beds and it's not
going to look like your seed that you
just patented
so
you know we need to give credit to the
cannabis plant as well she
is not just soybean she isn't tobacco
she isn't corn
she's not going to be that easily
controlled you know in that way and i
think that
we need to focus more on being the best
what is the best genetic that we're
going to put out this year so you can go
ahead and you can you can patent your
your 2017 strain but let's talk about
what we do in 2020 we need to be pushing
ourselves to be better and to create
better strains um not be looking at the
past of what was because she's
constantly changing and you know when
you say open source and
and um
you know genetics like that's exactly
what it is so if you put every all of
your information out in the public you
know that anyone can use it so you you'd
have to be you know
really skeptical about or or decide
whether you care or not i mean because
maybe at one point you're just like well
you know
i'm in evolution right now like kelly
said you know what i'm in the middle of
right now is making something new and
making something new i mean none of us
really necessarily keep the exact same
strain forever
and if and if ganja could have been
could have been patented and controlled
i think they would have done it back in
the 30s when they got rid of it so that
they could chemically fertilize cotton
and other
wheat and stuff like bring in hygiene i
think i think that the cannabis plant
would have been genetically modified
then and controlled then but i don't
think it actually can so i think maybe
on one level we may not actually have to
worry
you know about about that but we are
also
not joining that and don't condone that
at all either
yeah and i and i don't feel really bad
that people are spending millions and
millions of dollars to try to figure out
how to patent and marker this plant like
go ahead do it i i'm really having all
of my bets that the cannabis plant will
have the last laugh and we'll just take
all of their money so you know that's
that's sort of what we go on but also
the silos thing has given us now
you know like i was saying we we went to
corvallis we sat down with alan capuler
for many hours and any of you who don't
know who alan capuler is aka mushroom
please go online learn about him he's an
incredibly intelligent geneticist he
understands what markering and and
genetically modifying is because he did
that in his earlier years of life and
and what we came to is
you know since all of that has happened
we are now which we were already
planning on doing but it's with much
more intention is we're doing a pure
certified breeding project right now
so that we can get seeds from a
particular farmer and we can pass it out
to 50 different farms we can take a
little bit of data between ourselves
that is public domain that seed that
varietal becomes actualized and that's
really important because there's 40
other farms that have done it so we
really say bring it into the public
domain if you want to
you know have a seed or or a varietal
that is yours that you would like to
keep as yours you're going to have to
give it out
to a whole lot of people so that that
becomes actualized so that nobody else
can take that from you and we feel like
that's much more powerful than paying a
whole bunch of money to patent something
that can be changed anyway
so how do you feel about
genomic testing in general do you feel
like it's almost inevitable that
ultimately the data set will be sold off
or do you feel like there is a way to
get this information while feeling safe
about the results and not falling into
the hands of say big ag
well garrett guaranteed it's going to be
sold off
so to think that you're joining
something and it's not going to be sold
off is just this is not true i mean it's
it's already been sold off everywhere
it's but with food and everything so i
think that human beings sell out yeah
corporations are meant to sell out it's
like being
angry with a cougar that kills a bunny
rabbit you know like it's the nature of
big corporations big corporations are
gonna come in and they're gonna crush
and the only way that we can prevent
that is by joining forces with each
other like i was saying before so maybe
you use it and you and you you know take
what you want out of it and maybe you've
you've created a
pro tract that works for you with your
with your
uh with genomic sequencing company there
are companies out there that might
anonymize your information and you know
you you might find a company that you
you can trust you know for us you know
and there's universities you know that
you might trust too um to to work with
but
you know to think that big ag is not you
know out there that's what it's what big
ag does you know it's what they do with
genetics and stuff i think our our value
i think we should just not worry about
it and just make our value
the way that we grow
and the the diversity of genetics rather
than worrying about one strain and i
think that it's really interesting it
brings that sort of this this term
ownership into the world like
the ownership of a certain strain that
you've been working with 10 years but
the human beings were working with it 10
000 years before that so
it's like
what's ownership what what is it that we
own and it's like we feel like oh geez
well we have to own it before they own
it and i think that you know is is sort
of this this fear and that's where sort
of that that the competition thing that
i was talking about like why is it that
humans feel like we need to own
something especially a seed like i can't
even believe that that's legal but
of course i can because legal is based
in corporations and corporations are
here to crush so
i i love what the dalai lama says learn
the rules so you know how to break them
and we can look
at the incredible failures that genomic
sequencing and gmos and and even
hybridization has given us like oh yay
so now we have 17 different varieties of
2 000 different potatoes that we could
be eating on the planet but there's only
17 like i'm just making up those numbers
but
it's like
is there something about humans that
likes to set up a system that we can't
even work within
and i think that if we just sort of take
a step back and realize what wasn't
working within genomic sequencing is
we'll realize like why do we want to do
that what
it
it just doesn't make any sense because
then it starts to have ownership and
like i said before i i love my varietals
and josh and i work really hard on our
strengths but we got those from somebody
else 20 years ago and it's kind of like
you know they give it away you know
adage or maybe it's a grateful dead vibe
you know you could the tapes were not
you could never sell them you had to
give them away and it only made
everything better i mean when we gave
our
we give our seeds away to say nick and
liz at greensource gardens and they come
out with something that they like like
they loved the zelly's gift and they're
like
oh my god i'm gonna you know put that
into some of my genetics i mean to me
i'm like oh that's that's awesome uh you
saw something in our genetics that we're
working with the oh yeah go for it you
know make whatever you want out of it
you know have it have an awesome time i
can't wait to see the plans um you know
so we why would we have seed exchanges
and seed swaps all the time everywhere
we go every single event that we do if
we were worried about patenting or
owning anything i think we just
it's so diverse just fall in love with
the diversity and just not worry about
it that's that's kind of what we feel
right now we've always given our
genetics away we're not going to patent
them
and it is and and i get it too it is
really weird that this you know guy is
coming in with a three-piece suit on
he's never even smoked cannabis but he
wants to rule the cannabis world i get
it it it is very strange you know we had
this tight-knit beautiful cannabis
community for you know is my entire
adult life so this is like a whole new
trend
transition that i'm i'm sitting at the
table with these people that are talking
about cannabis and i'm like i know
you've never even smoked it before so
it's it's a really interesting dichotomy
and i think that it comes back to what i
was saying before you know if if we
don't want the castle to be given away
then don't give away the keys you know
keep your genetics tight within the
people that you love and see what they
can do with it and be happy that they're
creating something awesome and be really
grateful that your own genetics came
from somebody else that worked on them
for a really long time be grateful to
them rather than feeling like you've got
some sort of an ownership over it so
josh worried about some of the license
producers stealing our genetics and
doing better than we can with it
it's not going to happen
like
go for it but you're just gonna steal
the genetic and put it into like a
stupid system and it's not gonna she's
not gonna perform
so it's just kind of like ah
you know and uh you know anyway so we we
loved the idea of open source we love
the idea of being able to see the
genetics and being able to see the
connections that was the coolest thing
about the idea of the galaxy or
something like that during the time was
to be able to say hey this is
connected to all this lineage and i mean
that that would be really interesting
for us in genetics but i think we're
moving into a time that we're almost
moving away from strains on some levels
and we're just looking at plants more
like
chemovars and and and what their
chemical compounds or their terpene
terpenes are and stuff and so i don't
know there's a lot of ways
to to work with the cannabis once it's
grown now
okay good answer good answer so
something i wanted to ask which is kind
of related but not really about genomic
mapping type of thing
i've seen a few people post more and
more frequently about how sap analysis
from leafs can be used as like a
nutrient profiling technique how do you
feel about that as kind of the basis for
the evaluation of a nutrient program or
kind of some new things you're
implementing within your own cultivars
well anytime that you can learn more
about the plant that's all really
exciting and
adding a sense yeah and sap analysis has
been happening with with all different
types of plants you know within
agriculture
for a long time and now people are just
starting to talk about it with cannabis
and it's just another way to look at you
know how well your plant is uptaking
different minerals and different
nutrients and that's really gonna still
come down to the microbiology and and
what's present and everything in your
soil as well as
leaves but there's also an incredible
you know intuitive value of being able
to look at a plant and be able to get a
feeling for it and say yeah
you're healthy and you just know that
it's healthy and i think that
you know
what i would suggest to people that are
listening to this is create a better
relationship with with your plants in
your house with your cannabis plants
with your garden plants with the plants
that are around your property because
that's going to give you a better
you know communication and a better
relationship with plants and i and i
think that
we have this deep
connection with plants as human beings
on the earth because we eat them we
cultivate them we can't really live
without them they create our oxygen
the symbiosis is so deep
that
i feel like that's a really beautiful
thing to be able to see the health and
well-being of your plants is just being
in tune with that dna connection that we
have with plants on the earth and i
think a sap analysis you know is going
to tell you you know whether you have
enough you know
trace minerals or whether it's you know
a strong reading or a high number or not
but it's not going to tell you oh you
need more magnesium you know it's not
going to be like oh you're you're
you're high on boron or something like
that so i mean there's this going to
take a level of intuition i think that
that it's extremely crucial maybe to use
the sap analysis as you know part of
your analysis
you know and then and then you also have
a soil analysis that you have and a
bridge
and and
and
with soil tests and soil analysis you
are able to test you know your organic
matter counts and your microbiology and
that's and i think at the end of the day
you're just gonna you're gonna recognize
oh well this soil is really
rich enough you know when you have a
really live living rich soil like on our
own land right now
our greenhouses and all of our land is
like i'm feeling
super good right now about the plants
getting into the soil right now and just
taking off
so
and even even when you test a soil and
you could test the soil and then you
could say oh well it's got these certain
amount of minerals but you still don't
know what the plant is uptaking or what
the plant is not uptaking so
you know diversity in your soil is so
important for the ultimate health of the
plant because then it gives the plant
the ability to uptake what it needs as
it needs
and
i mean soil analysis after every flower
cycle is really helpful if you're doing
indoors you know and outdoors maybe once
at the end of the year or something
unless you're light dapping and then you
know you could test it but i think what
we've just come to is just add more
raw materials create more biology and
just make it just
a crazy worm farm
a crazy worm farm i like that analogy
that's pretty much what it is
that's good that's good so
we see the claim that there's a lot of
the hydroponically or synthetically
produced what people would refer to as
cali bud
uh most notably strains like cookies and
gelatos it'll often be kind of commented
that oh those are full of pgrs just look
at the way they look you know you can
tell and likewise we don't see people
like the cookie fam or people who
produce these cultivars really talking
much about the nutrients they use
do you feel like if someone doesn't want
to disclose something as seemingly
simple as their nutrient regime
it's not too far-fetched to assume that
maybe something more than what meets the
eye is going on behind the scenes
yeah i mean that you know my guess is
that they're surviving every single
round that they're getting through
and you know they're just stoked they
have wheat at the end of the run you
know and plus
you know it's with cookies and and
different varieties like that
you know it's they're hard to grow so
you know it's it can be it's a finicky
plant it doesn't have like the big you
know harvest and the big you know buds
or whatever like that so
um you know i mean i think if you have
to question it don't smoke it don't buy
it it's it's that simple yeah you know
if you have to question it and you don't
know what people's growing practices are
because they're not out there in the
open and they're being secretive and
private about their growing practices i
mean that's not ip people try to say oh
my growing regimen is ip that's sort of
silly okay intellectual property and
what you're feeding your soil all right
to me that's a big red flag just
people that are more you know upstanding
um
about what it is that they're doing and
what they're adding is the people that
you want to support
yeah of course of course
so
how do you i mean you kind of touched on
the point right there but how do you
feel about organic companies that like
maybe produce a nutrients or a soil
and again they won't release specific
information about maybe the ingredients
they use and yeah they say it's ip or
it's proprietary do you feel like that's
you know even if it's quite an organic
product it's just it still needs to be
viewed with suspicion
well i mean i can only say what we've
done and
if you look at any of our products it
has every single ingredient in it and it
has the exact ratio so
what we say to people is everything that
we put out is something that is good for
the world and if if you want to learn
from it and
you know you want to copy it i know
that's not what we're necessarily
talking about but go ahead like for us
to be able to be forthright is just
really important because
i just i just think that it's important
to share information and if people are
not sharing then of course you got to
wonder like what kind of skeletons do
they have in their closet and
and people will say well
you know people can grow and make your
product and and go and do it themselves
and we're like you know more power to
them that's that's awesome
has it hurt our business absolutely not
um
people want to buy our products because
it says exactly what's on there it's no
different than if you go to a grocery
store
i want to know i want to know what
ingredients every single ingredient in
the food i'm eating it's no different
than in what i'm smoking so what i'm
putting in my soil is what i'm smoking
so of course i want to know every single
ingredient yeah it's it's pretty obvious
so do you favor a fungal or a bacterial
dominant
soil during a specific stage of the life
cycle because we hear things like
having say a fungal dominant soil
is good for boosting the plant's immune
system maybe for things like terpene
production which are often thought of as
a secondary metabolite or a secondary
function of the immune system whereas
say a bacterial dominant soil might be
more advantageous to promoting growth
during vegetative or the early flower
stages do you agree with these ideas or
do you just kind of let the plant do
what it wants
well we let the plant do what it wants
and but we also so
but having said that i would say that we
would we would go you can't just
spoil from material to fungal dominant
you know based off your cycle your
plants so you kind of have to choose
like you know what's a soil that you
feel is is really live and rich and a
fungal dominant soil
is really really important for
um nutrient um
breakdown and
metabolization so we would want a
nutrient
a fungal dominant soil and maybe for the
vegetative we would use
some of our fermented plant juice or
some kind of high bacterial plant juice
teas to be able to get some of that
nitrogen or growth hormones in them in
the vegetative cycle so we would that's
how we would do it and fungi and
bacteria they work together you know
it's so important to have
both of them in the soil at a lot of
different diversity and a large
amount you know you want to have lots of
colonization of both
and
just like within our body if we were to
check our own microbiome it changes from
day to day it changes with whether it's
a cool day and then you've got like lots
of bacteria that wants to come right up
onto the surface of the soil or whether
it's super hot and they go really deep
well the plants uptake is going to
change from day to day as well and when
you've got like an indoor situation um
what we've been learning more and more
is that you have to
what we were going into gardens you know
many years ago and doing consultations
and and taking a lot of um
microbiology
a look at the microbiology that was
happening within the soil as well as
nutrient and and what was going on with
the mineral ratios and all of that and
we were realizing that in cannabis
indoor gardens there's a tremendous
amount of bacteria and people were
really trying to grow these plants that
were super bacteria rich well when you
have soils that are super bacterial rich
then you have such a greater chance of
any type of a pathogen coming in and
taking that over because fungi
is so incredibly um voracious and it's
it's very strong so if there it becomes
like a garter and if there's
a pathogen that's going on the soil or
you've got suffusarium or pythium or any
type of a root rot like that you know
your fungi is the one that's going to be
you know right there at the beginning so
fungi is so incredibly important to have
within your soil at all times as well as
bacteria feeding your plant foods so
you know there was that thought that
fungi is the only thing that can break
down phosphorus and yes that's totally
true so then people started saying well
now you want to have a really fungi rich
you know environment more in flowering
because it's going to be breaking down
the phosphorus
and
that is true and also
plants are still going to decide from
day to day and and colonization is is
going to ebb and flow within that soil
so adding a lot of different types of
food in your soil
that's going to feed your beneficial
fungi and your beneficial bacteria is is
really ideal higher amounts of organic
matter
yeah
yeah of course
so
this is a kind of a zoomed out question
but i've been thinking about this one a
lot
how do we go about raising the value be
it perceived or just simply in the
marketplace how do we go about raising
the value of sun-grown cannabis in the
mind of consumers is that the end goal
to get it on par with indoor or is it
simply a case about producer
well i think it's partly it's create
good sun-grown flower you know i mean
show
where it can shine so to speak with with
its um sun
and um
you know and just um helping people
realize the ecological impact i think a
lot of people when they go to
stores or dispensaries or they look
online and they're buying i think they
if they've come across
um a co-op of farms or
a farm itself and they have the
opportunity to buy from a farm that's
doing something that's agile
ecologically sound and positive
that i believe that that does add the
value
at adds value and we've seen that with
farms and we've seen that with
dispensaries that like soulful in
california is a really good um
you know uh example of of a place that's
really shown
you know
the say californians what good sun grown
looks like and and the farms that grow
it you know and there's there's farms
that they work with and they and the
farmers go into to the place and they
talk about their product and they meet
the farmers so
um and when regenerative farmers all
join together then we can actually set
the value
of what super high quality
flower looks like and you know i think
it's important too here that you know we
really appreciate all of the indoor you
know growers out there that don't have
an option to be outdoors you know
thank goodness for you for supporting
you know sick people and supporting
patients and supporting your friends to
not be drinking or taking hard drugs you
know showing them the way with cannabis
we think that you know indoor has really
helped
bring the plant forward you know she's
been the one that's been incredibly
persecuted and if we can hold these
strains and still have these indoor
gardens well we're activists and still
having a voice for that plant so
you know we're not i think that there's
an incredible value in indoor especially
when you're just still respecting the
plants so
i don't know if the conversation is so
much about indoor outdoor i think it's
about like respectful
way that the plant is growing conscious
cultivation you know i mean
what's what what's valuable about sun
grown is that it's positively um
impacting the earth as we've talked
about numerous times already tonight and
that's and that's a real why that's
important
and then if you're looking at an you
know cannabis as an industry
you know you you it's it is a plant that
that is
naturally grown under the sun and so to
to be able to support farms that do that
you know is really valuable and we've
really seen you know farms
have more value with their plants so you
know it's you kind of have to be you
have to be a jack of all trades you have
to be a farmer and you have to be able
to really share your story in a way
that's enticing and and really helpful
to um consumers and it's really
important to us that these people who
are cultivating this plant and have a
tight relationship with this plant have
a future with this plant it's so
important that the cannabis community
and the cannabis culture continues
forward that corporate you know takeover
doesn't completely happen and we believe
that that's going to happen by people
producing the
the least amount of you know cost per
gram
for them to be able to stay in this
industry and for them to be able to
continue their cultivation so that's
another reason why we really encourage
people to do sun grown to do outdoor
light depth to use the sun because it's
so much less expensive and it re is
really
being able to offer that alternative to
the corporate cannabis we need to stay
in business and a good way to stay in
business is to save a lot of money
yeah of course on that same topic of sun
grown cannabis
what types of companion plants do you
recommend to use in conjunction with
cannabis farming because recently i've
seen some posts that criticize clover
which is often held to be a a really
good companion plant and some people are
saying oh you know it just robs the soil
of nitrogen it's not really that good
what things do you recommend to go
alongside your canner cuttings
well clover is an indicate you know it
can be an indication it can be a
communicator that tells you whether you
have bugs or not so i wouldn't say that
it's
you know
creating the problem at all and and part
of using clover as a cover crop is to
understand
how to use it you know you wouldn't want
to let it grow too long to get super
infected you would want to you know kind
of work it into the top layer of your
soil and if you keep it you know young
then and vibrant you know it's it's way
less likely to have any pathogens on it
so learning how to use your cover crop
is
is really important and some you know
buckwheat is is a really good companion
plant um
sorghum uh suit in these sorghum grasses
is a is a
cover crop and a companion plant that
you can use that
colonizes mycorrhizal fungi so it can
help build the colonies of of
grass and of mycorrhizal fungi and also
cover crop what's around you know
see what's thriving in your zoning area
if you're in an outdoor farm you know
for us
everybody we just showed a bunch of
pictures on our instagram of our plants
that are coming up and people said oh
you know what kind of cover crops did
you
plant and
there's a ton of them in there but we
didn't actually plant any yet um it's
just what's coming up in the native soil
so
that's another really huge benefit on
utilizing
closed loop methods
that you can just see what wants to come
up and what wants to thrive
but for indoor scenarios or people that
just have like
you know maybe a small garden that isn't
that connected to nature
we really love to rotate our cover crops
and start out with sort of a nitrogen
rich one that breaks down really easily
like chickweed at the beginning
and then it can move more into um
quinoa is a wonderful one buckwheat is
another great one and then you can start
moving into more like phosphorus rich
and potassium-rich ones you could do a
corn if you wanted to if you grow your
own corn but whatever your comfrey is
one that people use a lot but it's one
that gets powdery mildew if it gets if
it stays alive a long time so you almost
kind of have to keep that
um cut down and really fresh too and
that's another thing is that you were
talking about clover it's sort of
getting a bad rap well it gets a bad rap
because people are leaving it too long
maybe and then you know more things will
colonize on it so we really love to pull
up our cover crop and lay down a new one
continuously
we know that i mean pretty soon it's
going to be exciting we're going to be
able to have hemp as a cover crop
because you know we're producing so much
hemp seed that we're going to be able to
you know have that also and see what
that's like so we're just continuously
trying new things to know you can use
lemon balms and holy basils and
and different things you know around in
your gardens and not as a cover crop
because then it would go crazy but um
yeah i mean you know nettles grow all
around but that's not necessarily the
best cover crop either but we kind of
have it as a cover crop in our area
poppy is a really amazing cover crop you
can grow poppy flowers and it create and
it contains the highest amount of
phosphorus
in a plant varietal that we know of so
if you take a whole bunch of poppy seed
and it only takes a few poppy heads to
do a massive cover crop in
in your indoor garden or even in a
massive outdoor garden
and that's like immediately readily
available phosphorus so we always like
to end our our flowering with with poppy
and in between you can just look at
different valley
values mineral values of different seed
varietals and say oh yeah that would be
cool to try during this time and
use your intuition use your creativity
come up with new things
of course it's all about finding what
works for you
absolutely
i see a few different uk grow and hydro
stores now stocking some of your
products which is absolutely fantastic
to see
i note this because the uk has
historically been a very kind of you
know hydro or soilless dominated market
do you feel like the tides are finally
turning in this regard and how can we
help to crack hydro store strongholds so
to speak
just through education i think that even
the hydro stores um you know have been
taught the wrong thing they were taught
by big ag you know npk ratios and they
thought that that was what was the right
thing to do and if we have the
opportunity to
bring a totally regeneratively grown
indoor
deep cultivated soil with dragonfly
earth medicine buds into a hydro store
and say look at what is possible that's
an incredible education you know to them
as well so do i think that the tides are
turning
hell yeah
the tides are definitely turning and the
tides are turning because microbiology
is making a comeback
in the cannabis world and the more that
we create healthy microbiology the more
healthy microbiology enters our own
microbio biome which makes us more
intelligent which makes us make better
decisions which helps us educate the the
growth stores and and i think that you
know like i said before we're on an
incredible bell curve and we all just
need to run with that and not feel like
oh well if i'm just getting into the
game and i'm just learning about this
that i have nothing to offer you have
tons to offer everybody has something to
offer
that is some kind of a teaching around
nature or a way to do it better that's
better for the earth
so i see on some of these stores that
you guys have got your own molasses
product which is great because i always
had people ask me a lot of questions
about molasses and some of the variants
like treacle and the blackstrap molasses
and all that what type of molasses do
you guys like to use and how do you like
to use it
well um
definitely organic blackstrap molasses
would be you know something that people
usually cut corners on
but um we're not we don't actually even
use
molasses anymore you know or any kind
and we don't actually have a molasses
product well that's that was the
dragonfly europe and that yeah so that
was interesting there was some you know
enough in europe to have it but the
point is do you use
molasses or not and
initially it was like you know
tablespoon per gallon molasses and
that's going to add to your microbiology
but i feel
over the years of testing that
um the the sweetener and adding molasses
and sugars has really been overdone and
could potentially spike
uh pathogen uh pathogens in your t's as
well so um if you're going to use
molasses
make sure it's organic because a lot of
people will cut that corner
and um it can be a really good iron you
know iron or mineral supplement to to
your teas but i would not overuse it but
use it in very trace amounts such a
tremendous amount of sugar is already in
plants
and
you know we can really see that with
if you're feeding your soil a whole lot
of sugars it's really no different than
if you're feeding your own body a whole
lot of sugars you're going to have more
yeast problems
which is you know pathogenic yeast and
soils sort of have that more mildews you
could have all different types of yeah
it's going to throw off your ph it's
going to make it way more acidic and
repetitive use of the scene yeah so just
be really careful in nature you know
plants survive off other plant juices
there isn't really like molasses that
comes into nature so
really think about your microbiology and
and like i was talking about before you
know that first drop and how many
ripples it can create you know look at
that last ripple and you and you wanted
to be
a healthy balance all the way through
and when you use lactic acid bacteria to
break down plant you know juices and
weeds there's there's a lot of
living material in there and a lot of
sugars that are just naturally present
so it's it's kind of uh it balances
itself out we don't use any extra sugars
on our property
okay and if someone did want to use
sugars like in say like a molasses form
or something along those lines is there
one that you would use preferentially
because i've had someone ask me you know
should i use honey should i use molasses
should i use agave nectar and when it
came down to it i thought well molasses
has got a few little extra minerals in
it but i mean i'm not sure if there's
too much of a difference what do you
guys think
it's a big difference yeah there's a big
difference honey can have all different
its own different microbiome um honey is
alive especially if it's non-pasteurized
um it's alive it has so many different
types of things in it so that can throw
off it can be anti-bacterial in some
forms too and different things yeah so
you know
as raw of a
good sugar as you can get that's not
highly processed and that's totally
organic
is the one that we suggest and also to
use it in very very low ratios a half a
teaspoon per gallon really is all you
need to spark those initial that initial
microbiology sparks those initial
bacteria but it's really no different in
a brew than in the body you know when
you're feeling a low blood sugar and you
eat a candy bar you know that that candy
bar is only going to last so long but if
you eat like something really high
protein and really rich and full
balanced then that's going to keep your
blood sugar going for a really long time
and the teas are no different in you
know you don't want to burn out your
microbiology you want to give it
something that it can feed off of long
term as well and the best i think the
best syrup or the best sweetener that
you can use is yacon syrup and i'll
spell that y-a-c-o-n
and yacon is a south american tuber
that's really watery and really sweet
and it's a prebiotic that's really high
in inulin
and it can be really good for human
consumption as well
but it's often
boiled down and and juiced and it
creates a molasses and
we um are growing a lot of yacon on our
property and encouraging a lot of
farmers to grow yacon um on their
property and that's a real and you can
also sometimes find it in a natural food
store yacon syrup
everyone you hear that store that away
in a neuron somewhere
what would you say to someone who says
that they really want to get into
organics and you know they really feel
passionately about the general message
being put forward by dragonfly however
they just feel like they can't quite get
their crops high enough to merit
switching over
um
i think that you just have to try it out
you know it's no different whenever you
try something new there's always a
learning curve there has to be a
learning curve i mean if there's no
learning curve then we we wouldn't be
learning how to get better and better at
things and
we hear that a lot and then we also hear
the same person say that come back a
year later and be like oh my god are you
kidding me i can't even believe that i
ever thought that i couldn't have higher
yields or that i couldn't grow better
medicine
so
we know that organics and living natural
biological soils
is the way to go because that's what
plants grow in
um it was humans that took them and put
them in some other type of a medium and
tried to
you know create that
growing
cultivation practice and
i just think
give it give it a little bit of time
learn as much as you can
be curious
be creative
get new ideas and share them and maybe
just about you know the ending yield
maybe it's the journey along the way and
all of the good information that you're
going to get and all of the good
microbiology that you're going to get
along the way as well that's going to
help you become a better gardener in the
end anyway
so
if this was someone's primary concern
for switching to organics for example if
you're forced to grow in a non-organic
way just specifically to get enough
yield to say support yourself do you
feel like there's been a certain
something missed there in respects to
their relationship with the plant
well what's missing is
that it's actually the opposite that in
a lot of
legalized and recreational jurisdictions
it's actually
you have to grow it regeneratively or
organically in order to pass all these
tests so it's it's kind of
turned into
a good thing for an organic farmer
because in the end it's it's kind of
yeah i think a lot of people have said
oh well in these new systems you almost
have to grow organically because there's
too many residues and different things
that show up
in the flowers so
um i i think you have to ask yourself
what do you have in your relationship
with
are you having your relationship with
the fear of losing your job and being
forced into something that you may not
believe in and may not even be part of
your ethics
or are you having a relationship with
the cannabis plant and i think that's
just something that you want to ask
yourself some people
just want to have a relationship with
the money and do a nine to five
and um you know not think about anything
else and and
you know there's a whole lot of people
on the planet like that
i personally
want to have a relationship with
everything that i do in my life
and i know josh feels the same way we
just
want
to be involved and
want to be able to have integrity with
what we're doing so that we can be proud
of it and so that we can be interested
in it and so we can remain creative with
it and we're not just working a nine to
five and we're looking at the bottom
line
and and in a way that i could really
tell people who only are looking at that
bottom line
polyculture is equally as important as
poly economy we cannot just be growing
cannabis maybe anymore why not have an
early spring crop of strawberries
on your land or try to diversify with
other things you know we can't just be
selling a pound of wheat anymore and
think that that's going to suffice for
us we have to become product makers we
have to have an ending product that
brings more value to our flowers so that
we can bring value to our organics and
have a higher quality product we have to
become more creative and and that is
what's going to give us
more value for what we're doing and more
value for the product in the end
definitely definitely so how do you
think we can go about raising the
general perception in the mind of the
consumers about the quality of outdoor
because at the moment as maybe
ideologically inaccurate as it may be
there is the general consensus that
people want you know to quote that
indoor um how do we go about changing
that so that people are demanding that
high quality organic outdoor
right well i think it matters where you
live you know what i mean i think that
uh
people are not
being able to see good quality outdoor
and you know the indoor that's around
people think that it's just about the
looks when it's really about so much
more than that so i think it's just a
matter of education and and i mean we've
brought our
cannabis to different cups and different
things and i mean it's incredibly
crystally and
it looks really beautiful it smells
really good and i think that in certain
ways we've redefined what's even
possible to grow outdoors up in british
columbia and
um
you know the light deprivation has added
a lot of quality to sun grown you know
plants so light depth is a really easy
sell to people
and um
i think that just
having a good cure and a good quality um
way of harvesting
your sun grown and just being able to do
it right i think
when people say you know
can i make the leap of faith organics i
mean it's not much of an actual leap
because you know just building a really
good soil and having a really quality
stable base within your soil is going to
give you the ability to take advantage
of the sun and green and create you know
good flower from it so we see
really amazing outdoor sun-grown
cannabis so i think you know it's
possible to do it in other areas and
you know
it's what it's what makes people feel
better most of the time too
yeah and i think that people who say
that you know indoors better than sun
grown they just haven't had good sun
grown i mean that's really what it comes
down to which is what josh pretty much
just said
and i think that that's important so the
more sun grown
that's out there with really good
varietals that do well you know in the
sun
because what people are doing is that
they're taking
these indoor varietals or a clone or a
seed that has been grown indoors for a
really long time in a synthetic
environment or in in a soilless medium
and then they try to grow it outside and
they don't understand why it doesn't do
very well well that plant doesn't have
the intelligence
of a natural system it's lost its
intelligence it's lost the ability
you know to be able to uptake and grow
to its full potential because it's only
been used to sort of that iv feeding
more allopathic npk
that doesn't understand microbiology or
an endophytic
you know reaction within the plant
so
you know outdoor is really wonderful
when you're working with outdoor strains
and just like josh said
i mean i wish i could give every single
person out there listening you know one
of our flowers and
you know they would they would say
something really different and there's
often a really good feeling that comes
with it i mean if we hear that a lot you
know people smoke our weed and they're
like oh you know i
i usually have a certain feeling
associated with it but i think when you
get a really good
sun-grown herb and and even within in
our experience people have a better
feeling from it so i mean if you're go
why are you smoking the wheat are you
smoking the weed because of what it
looks like
or are you smoking the weed because of
how it feels so maybe you know
challenge yourself on on why you're
doing it
definitely
so the pure seal itself is very much
communally orientated and accredited
certification do you see this model
expanding into other facets of the
community over say multiple avenues and
specifically do you think we'll ever see
something like say a pure dispensary
where it's just full of flowers and
products produced under the pure
certification
yeah it's happening already so it's
exciting this is already happening and
product makers want to have the peer
certification so that they're only
sourcing flowers from pure certified uh
farms and it creates this beautiful
sacred commerce that's regenerative and
yeah there's been lots of talk about
that there's dispensaries that totally
want to come on board and see what
that's like so what we're looking at as
a whole collective right now is
different certifications uh that's still
pure certified
um
that represents that same
really high quality and
community monitoring and community run
one of the questions that got submitted
by one of our fans was if they say just
bought a stock standard because i know
that there's so many variables here
let's just say they bought a pretty
standard farm
how long would you guess it would take
for them to get it up into shape to the
point where it would probably pass the
pure certification
i mean it's really hard to say i mean it
would take having you know
when we say closed loop systems that
means some type of system that you've
you know some
that works on top of itself some compost
or some you know good things that you
have that you're
catching water saving water making your
own seeds i mean i would say you know
you can't just get it and within two
weeks maybe you've bought someone else's
farm that's already done something
really amazing i mean you could actually
you know come in and and pretty quickly
then we've we've had people take you
know five years that are just coming to
it that said we're finally ready we've
been five years in the making and we
really want to do this and then we've
had other farms that have done it in one
year that they put all of their energy
and effort in and every bit that they
had you know to creating more closed
loop systems um
so it's really not a time thing it's an
energy thing and and also depending on
where you are because if you're in the
tropics being closed loop is is a whole
lot easier than if you're in the desert
so
you know there's different variables for
people but what is really cool
is that the tremendous amount of closed
loops that have come to our attention
you know like
people have created closed loops out of
just pure brilliance and that's just
really awesome so yet again it brings
that intuitive sense of creativity and
and that your land is
specific to you and that you know
everybody is a little bit different in
the way that you do things on your own
land or in your own indoor garden or
your own tiny backyard garden
you know is it's a holistic
certification so you know you have to be
ready to not be using non you know toxic
substances like
butane or propane or
some type of height we don't allow
hydrocarbon extracts like we've talked
about before and and people can
you know tell us
how clean it is and they can give us
tests and they'll say all kinds of
things but in the end we just
for us it's a toxic compound and to
clean it a toxic compound out seems
counterintuitive and it's just
it's it's supporting an industry that
creates a you know toxic compound and
and that's not okay so as a you know
pure certified farmer you just have to
be able to have a food garden and you
have to be able to have
flowers growing and you have to be able
to have some you know ways of making
soil and you have to be able to have a
functional um farm and you know that can
come within one year it might take a few
years
of course
so
to change the topic ever so slightly
what are some cultivars or strains
you've been vibing with a lot lately
well um you know there's
uh
a lot of hemp strains that are being you
know
explored and those are really
interesting to us right now because some
of them are
you know really high in terpenes and
and other ones are high in cbg and other
ones are high
thc and different things so
right now we're just really interested
in exploring
uh
you know cultivars that are unique you
know i mean and and so some of those
cultivars are
i mean it the cherry wine has been
around for a while as a hem cultivar but
we've been playing around with the
cherry wine and the auto and the
spectrum
and those have been really interesting
and um
yeah we're looking into doing some more
varieties on that front
and we've been still you know moving
forward our own varietals
you know we have our 840 mail that we
still work with um as well as other
males that have been made off of that
you know our zelly's gift we rejuvenated
this year and we did some in-line
breeding with it
way back so something that's been really
interesting to us is we brought out a
lot of our early 2000s seeds just
recently for all of our varietals on for
this year and now we're growing them
again so we can re-breed those back in
and we can really create stability and
what we're seeing in stability which you
know stability is a shaky term in the
cannabis industry and i realize that but
what we're seeing is as we
bring even our lineage further of what's
interesting to us um
we're
choosing plants and then they're being
tested
we're really moving into and most of our
varieties are full spectrum full terpene
and that just seems to be coming
naturally
with with treating them well and so
we've been even seeing some of our old
like temple spice varietal now that's
starting to have cbd creep into it so
i think that it you know we're moving
along our own stuff and and like josh
said we're like now 80
hemp on our property and we're really
interested in
working with the hemp varietal that
finishes here so our really big goal
this year in breeding is to try to bring
forth an early finishing high cbd hemp
varietal and also we're working with
some autoflower seeds that we got from
heart rock mountain
and the cali gold and that's been a a
project they've been working on for a
long time and so we're excited to
you know to work with some auto flowers
um
and we are you know working with some
hash varieties that we've gotten from
uh you know kush kirk and and some 24k
varieties and um
some snapple cookie varieties and and
different things like that just to see
you know what kind of uh
syrup we can get just kidding
but we have reindeer reindeer syrup is
is another variety that's a rude or
alice strain that we've been you know
that we're that we're going to try out
and um so that's really interesting this
year i don't know we've gotten a lot of
strains from a lot of different people
this year and we're just doing our best
to do a little bit of everything just to
see
to further explore you know what we're
what we can grow you know we've got some
land raised varieties happening some
milana creams
i'm going and yeah
yeah a really nice diverse mix of
genetics there
when can we expect to see the launch
itself of dragonfly genetics because a
few people have told me they're hunting
for your seeds like nothing else and you
know the struggle is real to get them
certainly seems like there's demand when
is it gonna be time
um you know
maybe we'll do some this fall this fall
it might be a good idea to to do that
and you know we have given out a lot of
seeds when we see people and uh
you know i guess it's just a matter of
you know making it happen and we make a
whole lot of seeds every year and we
give them all away
so our genetics are out there
and uh i guess it's just people that see
us in passing we're happy to gift them
with varietals but we do always ask
people you know how are you gonna grow
these and it's a really nice idea for us
to know that our seeds are going out
into
a respectful garden or you know somebody
that's gonna turn them into something
really cool
um but i you know i don't know
we just keep giving them away and people
keep out i think that we give away too
many to actually sell any
[Laughter]
so yeah we'll see
what we really want is a field test kit
so that we can really do you know a lot
of the breeding that we really you know
analyze you know the analyzing on our
own property so i mean eventually we get
a good field testing kit and that would
really help our breeding and that would
really help us you know feel good about
putting seeds out into the world
of course and i know that you have some
interesting kind of collaborations or at
least working closely with snodgrass
family farm genetics can you tell us a
little more about this
well you know they they have really
amazing breeding products that they're a
part of and since they're you know
family to us you know we've we've traded
genetics back and forth over the years
and um
really um
bobby and meredith just have a really
beautiful piece of land and and they're
just exploring you know genetics that
have come to them throughout their
things so we don't have any
collaboration you know official
collaborations happening
um
at the moment other than we've been
sharing scenes for years and reading off
of each other's stuff
so in that way it's really collaborative
yeah no it would be really fun to come
out with something with something
together when we come with something
when we get to something that's really
beautiful but
um yeah i would know they every year
they they explore a huge variety of
genetics and do a lot of breeding so
it's always really interesting to find
out what they come up with
and would you ever consider doing like a
rather formal collab with someone who
you really closely align with like maybe
you know duke diamond or someone along
those lines who you respect and vibe
with their work already
always oh yeah for sure we love that
yeah we're all about collaborating
you know in any way that we can with
information
with uh you know good flowers with seeds
we even have some heavy days genetics
going on right now yeah we do what i'm
saying we're pretty stoked so you know
there could be a collab coming right
there just saying
big grin on my face thanks very much
guys
um so the next thing i wanted to ask you
is they're coming up really beautiful by
the way really gorgeous so super excited
about it oh you guys are too kind i'm
sure you're giving him a very loving
home
oh we for sure are
so with that being said how important is
it in your opinion to continually be
pheno hunting
it's everything
i mean that's what makes it exciting
if we're not pheno hunting then i always
feel like what am i doing you know
everything that we've gotten up to this
point we did without you know only maybe
in the last five years if we've been
doing it even any testing
everything was pheno hunting and what it
smelled like and what it looked like and
how it did in the garden and what it
made you feel like when you smelled it
or touched it or you're next to it or
when you smoked it or you ingested it or
put it into your food you know
pheno hunting is
is being a cannabis cultivator
they go hand in hand
so
this is a bit of a peculiar one but i
really wanted to kind of dig in here but
i tried some mach 1 that was grown in
the states outdoors with you know the
kind of the pure type of i think it was
grown on a pure farm but you know if not
we'll just say you know very closely
aligned with that type of thing
and to be honest it just didn't come
across to me as it was on the same level
as some of the indoor stuff
in terms of the caps in terms of the mac
specifically and so my question is do
you feel like there may be some cuttings
that are just more suited for outdoor
than indoor or for indoor than outdoor
or do you think that anything has the
potential to shine just as good in
either or
um well i think that i touched on that a
little bit before is that you know a lot
of these varietals uh have been grown
indoor for so long they've been cuttings
off of indoor they've been put in
synthetic or soilless mediums and they
don't really have the intelligence to to
go into an outdoor
uh cultivation you know methodology or
or practices so you know it's
particularly with the mac that's a
really indoor varietal and you know it's
been cloned off a whole bunch of times
so i think it would take you know
several runs if we ever get an indoor
clone uh from somebody or something that
we're really interested in wanting to
grow out we take a couple of years to
grow it out to see what its full
potential is because guaranteed for
getting a synthetic clone from somebody
it takes a long time for that clone to
come to its full potential because it
doesn't have the intelligence of
biological uptake
so you know it's going to take some time
and i think that the plant's
intelligence needs to match the
intelligence of the soil
of course so something i wanted to ask
you guys your perspective on was the use
of quote natural growth regulators so
i know that i've heard and seen a lot of
people using gibberellic acid in the
vegetative stages and some people will
consider this to be on par if not the
same thing as using pgrs you know the
more kind of
synthetic uh natural ones but other
people will say oh but it's just a
natural hormone that's in the plant
anyway
where do you sit on that do you view it
as a natural thing or is a synthetic
thing
well
gibberellic acid is a natural compound
that's found in nature so i wouldn't say
it's not a synthetic compound but i
think that you know anything that's been
it could be that it's synthesized and it
could be that
some of those i think it's kind of like
do you like isolate you know cbd or do
you like full spectrum
you know medicine i think that you know
when you start just using gibberellic
acid on its own
you know you're you're
you just don't know what the source is
and i think that you can get plenty of
gibberellic acid just in
like nettles or you know in some kind of
plant and i would just much rather get
it from that so
you know to me that's just uh it's kind
of like using an isolate
that's what i think
yeah okay and so
would you view it i guess just as a
clarifying point as
somewhat akin to
uh tricontinol where it's like yeah just
get it from the alfalfa it's all good
exactly that'll be that's a perfect
analogy i mean it's kind of like yeah
exactly it's just
you know humans desire to
think that it's one compound over the
all it's not to say you know cbd on its
own can cure but you know the whole
entourage is way better gibberillic acid
you know on its own can grow plants
exponentially
and i've even heard with feminization
that gibberilic acid used in conjunction
with colloidal silver
um in the early flowering stages can be
a way to feminize your plants silver
theosulfate which is what's commonly
used for feminization so
you know um
gibberilic acid is is is a really
heavy um
growth hormone
and
yeah so i i anything that's isolated
like that we're just automatically
skeptical of and we don't use it
yeah good point good point so i'm gonna
take a bit of a step off the edge here
and talk about something random that i
saw the other day on instagram but i'd
love to gauge your opinion on it what do
you think about the introduction of
mushroom spores from psychedelic
mushrooms
into your grow media because i mean i'm
sure we've all seen the odd mushroom
poppets head up throughout a flowering
cycle when you flip the lights on what
if it turns out you know you had some
cubenses or something like that pop up
well i mean i think then you would have
the most awesome thing in the world
happening you know because who who
wouldn't want psychedelic mushrooms
popping up underneath their their ganja
i mean any any sane person would want
that you know
so
i i'm
i'm going to say that you know to say
psychedelic mushrooms
is
you know
a little bit broad so you'd have to go a
little bit deeper you'd say okay which
ones do i want wood loving psychedelic
natural mushrooms like azure essence or
cyanescence
or um
[Music]
uh potent psilocybe which is already the
cyan essence but anyway those are wood
loving so you you could inoculate
um you could get wild
and um spores and wild patches and
mycelium and and inoculate those in your
grow medium you would just have to be
pretty
you know intentional about giving it
enough other
other
um food to eat like so wood chips
you know a lot of people are doing huge
culture and wood chips well that works
really really good for
[Music]
wood loving psychedelic mushrooms
so i think that's really really smart
when it comes to
um cubensis
that's gonna be more of
a manure loving mushroom so um a way
that a person could utilize a kubenzus
run would be to um you know make compost
and sterilize your comp your compost
with you know through turning
um the compost and then you know you'd
have to know
mushroom cultivation but you could
inoculate
a manure compost and put it on as a top
dress to your plants
and grow a flush of cubensis with your
weed
but cubens is really like super high
humidity and and flowering cannabis
doesn't necessarily like super high
humidity so that's
that you true
find there it would be like you would
want to have your
mushrooms flowering during vegetative
time and then be done the best way to do
that before flowering two greenhouses
one on one side which is a flower
flushing um
mushrooms and that one on the other and
that would be pushing co2 air into the
other greenhouse which was growing
weed and that would be beautiful
and so
what are some mushrooms be it
psychedelic or not that you would
recommend people to try to incorporate
into their life and ingest kind of
regularly if possible
all the medicinal mushrooms rishi chaga
cordyceps aguerocon
um turkey tail
lion's mane it's a nootropic there's so
much damage that's going on within our
brains within wi-fi that we need to
start introducing nootropic medicine
which is the lion's mane um you know
incorporating a lot of the different
tree polypores because then it takes all
of the intelligence from the tree and
puts it into the polypore and then it
makes it where you're actually getting
direct tree medicine
through
the the polypore so allying with
mushrooms right now at this time of
earth's toxicity is really important and
then how do you utilize that in you know
in what mushrooms do you use in your
cannabis grow
because a lot of ones she she mentioned
like chaga is not one that you can grow
you know that's that's a wild mushroom
that only grows on birch trees but
um
you know you can inoculate logs and use
that as a as as a way of building your
beds and you could have reishi or lion's
mane or maitake logs making a raised bed
and you can bury um lion's mane logs in
the soils so there are ways of
of building your soils with uh medicinal
mushrooms um through log spawn so people
can look up log spawn and find out more
about that but that's and then also
garden giants like ellie said is king's
tropharia or rugoso annulata
and
that's actually amazing compost eating
mushroom and it's really useful in
living soils and if you and if you can't
grow it then find somebody who is
growing it you know in an organic um
cultivation
because
yeah ally medicinal mushrooms are are
really important and a lot of them you
can't grow you know like lion's mane
it's something that would be difficult
to to grow inside of your indoor
cultivation of cannabis but you
certainly can find it out in the woods
or you can find somebody else that's
cultivating in it
in a respectful way um turkey tail is
another one you can grow on the logs
yeah and like agaricon is is almost
impossible to get unless you're buying
like the mycelium of somebody who is
cultivating the mycelium
or reishi you know it's it's sometimes
finicky depending on where you're
growing it so
i think we we think that it's okay to be
sourcing it from other people that are
growing
organic medicinal mushrooms as well
it's hard to spread yourself that thin
right
i mean it's i think it's a crucial part
of a really sweet like farm to have
mushrooms growing on it so i you know
we're all about you know people taking
it on oyster mushrooms i mean that can
be
a huge easy thing to grow on your
property
yeah definitely i think i'm probably
going to go eat some after this there
you go
so
this is something i've been dying to ask
you guys about for a while
how do you feel about the rise of what i
call
cbd everything so like you know cbd
burgers from in and out and cbd candy
from the gas station is this a positive
thing
yeah we have cbd gas we just got for our
car it was incredible
the car really loved it um
yeah well it's great because then more
hemp is being farmed and there's more
people cultivating it
then the plant gets to come more out of
her prohibition she gets to like make
make more of a scene you know into the
world and
and more and more people are cultivating
her and
as more hemp is is being grown more land
is being remediated and that's a huge
positive um
on the earth so
cbd everything hurrah then that also
means that people's cannabinoid
receptors are going to start getting
flooded and that's wonderful too and
that's only going to help people become
more healthy i mean it feels like you
know
a phase and it feels like something
that's
fad and it's kind of like
you know maybe it makes you roll your
eyes in a little bit but it's just kind
of a testimony of just like
create rules and everyone's just gonna
exploit it on on all fronts so i mean
really the main teaching is
you know to to think that cbd is like
the be all endo compound is really
not true i mean so
it's just
it doesn't have thc in it so it's a non
it's not intoxicant so people can put it
in everything and i mean if people was
putting a full spectrum
extract in there instead of just cbd i
mean that would be
awesome and i would love to go i would
love to have it in everything i eat
because really
we that's why our we have an
endocannabinoid system is for it to be
fully
saturated you know and having it in your
foods and smoking in our ways of doing
that so i think it could be really
healthy and maybe
back in evolution hemp was fed to
animals and animals ate it in cbd and
all the compounds were in the animal and
then the people ate the animals and so i
think that hemp and cannabinoids were
have been an essential part of our food
chain through evolution so really it's
only
respectful to our evolution that we have
now cbd products and everything i just
think that maybe we should demand more
than just cbd
of course and so how do you feel about
vape pens are they a necessary evil and
given they do have generally speaking
such a bland cannabinoid profile how do
you think we can go about getting this
what seems to be like a vital stepping
stone between
the casual enthusiasts and the more
hardcore fans to incorporate a more
holistic profile in it and really give
people these medicinal benefits they're
maybe not seeing otherwise
yeah i mean you know the vape pen is
kind of like
the remote control like for the tv you
know like back when it then you it was
just convenient you know it was just it
didn't really matter you could still
you know do whatever you needed without
it but the vape pen is just kind of like
people want to drive around or travel to
other countries and have a vape pen it's
just it's like it's more of like
a lifestyle thing
you know nowadays i think the the thing
that sucks about vape pens is that
there's just such a such a
these are fake
but they're very convenient for people
and i think that's what people
also have you know depending a high
so a high quality vape would be one that
doesn't have weird residues on it
because of where it was manufactured in
china
so
vape pens can be toxic
to the consumer and also toxic to the
environment because they're just
disposable
so an ecologically minded person really
doesn't love vape pens
that i guess that would be my answer
or make sure that they're refillable and
you know ones that
because like josh said
i think steep hill just did a massive
study a blind case study
of shopping and all the different
dispensaries and they found that
i don't know the percentage but an
overwhelming percentage of the vape pens
you know were just toxic in and of
themselves because of the coil that was
heating up so
i think that we can do better i just i
think that you know with these beautiful
extracts that can be made from flour
i think that we can do better
and um you know refillable reusable ones
that have glass
um also people are maybe a hemp plastic
vape pen you know i mean
let's just hope that innovation can
catch up if we can get
a good
you know vaping unit that makes it
there's there's maybe reasons why vaping
makes sense you know it's less smoke and
it's less carbon and if you have a
challenged lung i mean i'm not going to
demonize anything i think we can be a
non-discriminatory
ganja ingestors i think you know it's a
right place at the right time you know
what did rome do as the romans you know
i mean like you might have to smoke out
of a vape pen you know what i mean every
once in a while
but i'm not you know
you know it's not going to be the
natural choice
of course
so one thing i wanted to bring up with
you guys before we jump on to some of
our fans suggested questions was this
idea of the green renaissance i know
that
julie and the good folk over at skunk
magazine have been pushing this idea
hard and you guys are well on board with
it too
what kind of stimulated you to push and
put your backing behind this idea of the
green renaissance
well i just think that it's kind of what
makes sense it's what's natural you know
we like like julia stated it's you know
it's it's
not a rush you know it's more of an
awakening it's more of a re awakening
and a um
you know something
that's more long-lasting and it kind of
has an essence to it so you know it just
it feels good to to think of it as
you know something that's emerging and
and you know a lot of people talk about
you you know kids don't want to be
farmers anymore and and indigenous
cultures and different places in the
world but
actually a lot of kids do want to be
farmers thanks to weed you know and i
mean as long as the governments don't
[__] it up too much you know we might be
able to you know have a lot of young
amazing farmers that want to grow you
know because we get people that are
young all the time that be like you know
the greatest dream on earth would be to
have their own farm so
um i think that you know there's just a
lot of ways to look at things
of course so we might slide into some of
the fan suggested questions
these are in no
particular order or rank but the first
one i've written down what are some
inputs that people can easily grow for
themselves on a small scale that would
be beneficial to both their gardens and
possibly even their body
nettle comfrey um alfalfa is awesome
super easy to grow you can cut alfalfa
so many times in a year and it just
keeps coming up same with comfrey those
are all really easy things to grow
edible flowers are really great to grow
you know they contain
you know terpenes and and they're nice
for our own bodies
and i think you know lots of different
diversity um
is is great
but those are the four that are really
easy to grow and anyone can do it i mean
you can grow yarrow you know there's
there's a lot of different
um
foliar sprays that you can i mean if you
can grow ginger and garlic i mean really
i think this is what you should grow as
much as you can
like what the how about this what can
you grow grow that
because really
it's it's not just like choosing one
thing you know there's it's there's a
world out out there we're on the
internet right there anyone lives
wherever they live they could be in sao
paulo brazil right now and 20 million
people around them and what can they
grow they can just grow simple cover
crops
and pots and then just take the cover
crop and cut it and make a fermented
plant juice out of it and they can water
all their plants you know in their house
from that um
you know there's there's so many things
you can grow and i think it's just
explore botany you know understand
kinship gardening and the evolution of
plants and just try and grow as much as
if you can grow a moringa tree that
would be awesome because you could just
sit there and
cut the moringa tree back all day and
another thing people can grow as
spirulina
i mean you can grow
algae and you're in an aquarium in your
house and that's something that's really
healthy for you
and it's also good for your garden so
and you can grow deciduous trees because
leaves are really amazing uh leaf mold
is is so beautiful for soils and that's
something that can be collected every
fall and it offers great oxygen around
your property so growing fruit trees
also you can use fruit
there's
yeah
really the sky is the limit just what
what grows well in your zone and area
that you feel like you can take on that
makes it really easy that then will make
you more curious to want to grow more
things
and there's lots of plants with known
high biomass so those that look for
plants high in biomass
definitely spirulina is definitely one
that's been on my radar for a minute now
and it ties into this next question of
what is a good place to start in regards
to bringing what would be considered a
very nutrient deficient soil back to
life what are some of the ingredients
you would first and foremost be looking
to incorporate
um
well
life
so you know you could plant cover crops
on it
and turn that in and that would be the a
really fast simple way
go to the forest and find some
area that is living and
really healthy you can bring that back
i would look maybe to worm castings or
some kind of compost or
um composted manure or some kind of
animal healthy
animal place that's near you
maybe someone has alpacas or
llamas or something or rabbits
and you can get some good pigeons i mean
you can get some pigeon poop and
chickens
something like that you don't want to
overdo it with that kind of stuff
because it can be hot but if you're
trying to get quick life back in there
you know animal manures when when it's
coming from a healthy source is a really
good way of doing it or worm castings
and and one of the most immediate ways
that people in suburban areas is just
always keeping nice compost going and
having worms in it so that you always
have good accessible inoculant biology
soil to put on top of any of your plants
at any time so just using your kitchen
scraps and then that makes people more
knowledgeable about hey maybe i want to
grow organic food because then that's
going into my compost pile which my
worms are eating which is then going to
go into my cannabis and and put bokashi
and you know bokashi and when your food
scrap so your food scraps are already
pre-digested when they when they go on
the worm farm you know
at one point you're just playing you
know what i mean
yeah okay
so
the next question i have i'm honestly
not too sure about the context of so i'm
just hoping you guys kind of understand
it better than what i do but someone
said
how do you feel about the flowcanna
slash
other sellouts
um and how all of the regenerative
cannabis farming award recipients get
lumped into this same group
well i mean
to say that the regenerative farm award
winners got lumped into a group is just
it's not it's not like it wasn't
premeditated by any means it would what
it was was
flocano was wanting to work with really
intentional conscious farmers in
northern california and when you win the
farm award you just get to be known and
people are like hey i want to get your
product so i mean i think it was just
uh you know it's just kind of a natural
thing you know
what the pro i think here's the i think
what the problem is
is that
when companies get really really huge
they start taking investment from other
companies and with flocana they just got
really huge and they took investment
from companies
that are not in line with regenerative
practices so it put
it's starting it started to put
an ethical question in with the farmers
so you know what they're you know what
you want them to to be doing a good
thing but when they're taking investment
from companies
you know that are connected to marlboro
or altria or companies that are you know
harmful to the earth
you just have to
it's it's really hard to navigate you
know that territory so people are torn i
would just say in the community right
now you know on on that subject right
now because of those
because of those principles
and
and it's really important to say that
you know there are there are you know
new
horizons that uh cannabis farmers
haven't thought about before you know
when cannabis farmers are signing
contracts that's why we were saying it's
so important to only sign protracts
right now because and and we can use
this as an example you know when when
farmers are signing contracts they
weren't necessarily thinking about well
geez this company could sell out to
something else and then where is my ip
and and where is is is my sops you know
within that or what is the name where is
my branding of my own farm so it just is
really giving us the ability to
become more intelligent and more savvy
with the corporate cannabis world and i
think the more that we see you know
what corporate cannabis um you know is
capable of is the more that we need to
come up with smarter alternatives but
you know with the floccana thing they
have really beautiful farms that are
working with them and they have not
changed and how they're cultivating and
they haven't you know they're still
growing regenerative and they're still
you know creating wonderful education
within community and there and everybody
is really wonderful it's just
we're being caught in a corporate
riffraff that as cannabis farmers we are
new to and we need to become more savvy
it's similar to what happened with filos
too i mean they started joining forces
with syngenta and monsanto and
and dow chemicals and all these things
that's just when you start getting you
know
that that much investment you start
having to like what you'd say sell your
soul you know to to the monster and
that's why we were just saying we want
to
be independent of that and we don't want
to be swallowed by corporations
that's just you know it's
new it's new territory we we have to be
um dolphin pods in an ocean of sharks
yeah great analogy
so
where do you hope to see the craft
cannabis market in 10 years from now and
how do you think big ag will factor into
this picture
well i think big ag can just folly
around with the idea that they can
cultivate cannabis in a way that's you
know better for people i think it's just
gonna be
funny to watch them you know
fall on themselves over and over and i
had to be like whatever on that front i
think
um craft whether it's you know when
someone says the word craft cannabis i
mean you would ha
to me i'm like does that mean organic or
regenerative so it's not descriptive
enough and so just because they're small
doesn't necessarily make them good so
if if it's crafting it better i would
hope that it's already regenerative or
you know i i use the word regenerative
instead of organic because
we want you know you know more than
organic so
and in the future what i would like to
see is
a really huge
value for consciously cultivated
cannabis
what i would like what i i'm assuming
that it's going to be like
safeway or some kind of large
supermarket chains selling food all over
the place but the farmers market in any
town is always gonna have better food i
think that there's gonna be
like micro brews or more valuable or
something like that i think that you
know consciously cultivated small farms
that have better strains and a better
story i'd like to see that that be a
really well defined
um
you know market to where people are
really well educated on what corporate
cannabis looks like and what potentially
regenerative craft cannabis looks like
and i think that you know it's really
easy to green wash and it's super easy
to green wash the term craft
so just because they're small are they
using the same synthetic nutrients that
big corporate cannabis is using
it definitely needs to be more
definitive and you know what we want to
see in 10 years from now in the cannabis
industry is
much more conscious cultivation
because the earth needs it
we need it as it's you know as its
consumer and the plant really deserves
it for um you know healing us for you
know so many years since the beginning
of humanity
and i'd like to see
processors and really conscious food
companies and which we are seeing so you
know what we're seeing is the beginning
of
conscious commerce i mean
a company that wants to make
a cannabis product
has to source their products
if they go to source their products and
they come across the peer certification
and pure farms i mean it's kind of a
no-brainer i mean of course they want
that so i would i would i i'm seeing a
high value
for
consciously cultivated products and i i
guess we can just leave it there
i think that's going to grow it does
grow that's why natural food stores are
growing that's why
the whole movement is growing because
people want they're tired of being sick
and the system incorporation is just
constantly making us sick everywhere and
it's just it's not cool and that's why
cbd is so popular because it all of a
sudden is offering an alternative it's
giving us a little bit of a gauge on
what's happening with humanity and
what's happening with society right now
is that people are you know
feeling disenfranchised and
disillusioned from
big pharma and big ag we're learning how
to do it better and
heck if if it's going to be cannabis
that leads the way that's going to give
people you know more knowledge of ways
to do it better then that's freaking
awesome
so you know a lot of people are saying
oh cbd this cbd that well
that's definitely a gauge on what
society is wanting and that's outside of
the pharmaceutical world right now and
to me that's
awesome
so
given the success of the dragonfire of
the dragonfly brand in regards to
cultivating sustainable cannabis do you
have any plans or interests to become
involved in say large-scale production
of hemp
uh well what we're definitely
interested in
hemp production and um you know how
large can it be is basically what we're
looking at this year you know i mean
this is a year when we're deciding
whether feminized seed hemp growing is
something that we certify
uh we're deciding on you know can there
be a a hundred or a four hundred acre
hemp farm you know can a 400 acre hemp
farm be
pure certified or regenerative we don't
have that right now and they would have
to really stand out and have some kind
of
really thought out you know crop
rotations or something happening but um
we're having those discussions now
really big time within our group as to
you know people are saying oh you know
is it scalable well it's really
interesting because we utilize the term
scalable and big ag
and is is scalable the way that we've
been doing it successful and the answer
is no
so we need to
understand what is scalable for
regenerative agriculture period not
necessarily what's scalable for
regenerative hemp even but just what's
scalable so you know what we see in
saving the earth is you know a ton of
small farms
small farmers are what is going to save
the earth right now and that absolutely
goes and to have farming
if there's big corporate hemp that's
going to come in and they're going to be
you know producing 50 million acres of
hemp which is what's going on over in
china right now
can they do that regeneratively
you know
we don't really believe that that's
possible we need to bring back the small
farmers
but at the same time there's a lot of
hemp that's overtaking
other crops in the field which is a good
thing so
large-scale
hemp farmers might be um
taking out
a farmer might be growing that instead
of something else which they would spray
so you know hemp could be you know
is going to be something that's going to
save you know agriculture i think in a
lot of ways
very much so
so
this is related specifically to your
i'm going gonna have to clarify this and
re-ask the question do you pronounce it
pagodas
well we have so many different
structures on our property we actually
have a couple of structures that look
like a pagoda and josh is an amazing
builder and he uh always takes on a
project with like amazing
creativity so every one of our
greenhouses you know that's been hand
built by us is just really beautiful it
has a style of its own
because we want to remain creative and
keep the juices flowing for us too if
we're building you know
10 of the same greenhouses it's sort of
boring so we're always trying to keep
style and beauty
involved on our farm
of course of course i love that home
kind of feel they must all have and so
just in regards to the various types of
structures you guys have how does it
compare having one on say a hillside
versus on a flat surface like does the
gradient change the dynamics of it and
specifically this person wanted to know
is airflow problematic when you're on
the side of the hill
well um for us we have a really
beautiful
airflow that comes through off our leg
and
and our
so
a hill is really nice to have because
it creates natural airflow in the
morning
the heat is rising
in our valley and the air is always
going up
and in the evening it's going down
because the air is cooling off so we get
a lot of really good
you know airflow and i i prefer to have
a slope to grow on really because if you
have a water source above you then you
can gravity feed everything down and
it's kind of
you know it's a natural way of
collecting
you know you can create different zones
and environments really easy by
terracing so by going to asia you know
all these years and even guatemala and
central america terracing you know is
something that really just caught our
eye and we're just like oh my god
terracing's so beautiful and so we've
made really big terraces on our land and
what it does is just naturally makes an
environment
and then each environment can grow kind
of a different thing so
um a flat a flat surface is hard to work
with you know it's a lot more exposed
um you have to you know really use trees
i think a lot more for flat surfaces to
create environments and and food for us
and stuff like that so
our slope you know makes makes helps us
out a lot
of course
and we build our greenhouses
to have a flow-through design for air so
we don't have any um fans in any of our
greenhouses and the way that we utilize
them is more of like a roof or an area
to where
it's um there's a flow-through design so
there's no stagnant energy anywhere
yep
so we've kind of touched on this before
but it's a bit of a specific question so
i'll throw it out there maybe we'll get
a specific answer to this specific
question but
if you were to get a plant from whatever
source it may be a friend just maybe
it's just had a bit of a unlucky run
with things let's just say it's really
quite sick and it's not doing too well
what would be your protocol for getting
this out of that heavy shocked state and
back up and alive and boosted
first of all separate it from the rest
of your
your plants that's the first thing that
you want to do so many people feel like
oh well just bring it in with my other
plants and into my environment
where my other plants are healthy
because pathogens um you know are so
prevalent right now
and a lot of them you can't see with a
naked eye like say a broad mite
and arrested is even hard to see even
though you can but you know isolating it
and then just putting it in a really
beautiful soil immediately and just
giving it teas
i always feel like earthworm casting tea
is the same as chicken soup
if you want to bring a plant back to
life just feed it earthworm casting tea
because it's easy it's absorbable it has
all of the nutrients and it's really
basic and easy for a plant to uptake
because just like when we get sick
it's difficult for us to uptake things
because our immune response is low our
microbiology is low
you know things are not uh responding so
easily so
that's a lot of biology and if you can
have it outside and have it get rained
on or
you know if you can you know use the
natural elements to your advantage
depending on the time of year and
everything like that you know you have
to be
you know you have to be smart about it
but
you know if you can bring it outside and
and
you know have the natural elements on it
that's really smart too
so this is an odd one but hopefully
you're going to have some perspective on
it do you have any thoughts on how
vermont was the first state to legalize
cannabis via state legislation as
opposed to a referendum and do you think
it should have happened by a referendum
i think any way that it can become
legalized is great and it just so
happened that in vermont it became
legalized through um more political
power rather than people power which i
think
that's awesome that shows how it's
matured too i mean oregon
also just um through state legislature
just
um
[Music]
is the export of cannabis to other
states so it's not legal to export to
other states but within the state of
oregon it's legal so
what they're saying is you know this is
we're ready for this law when it changes
so i i think that it's it's always gonna
be better
you know for a long term you know to not
have systems change and stuff like
you're not if it's a vote by the people
then you're basically still against
the the legislature and if the
legislature makes the decision then you
may not like their decision but it's
going to be more
stable i think for the states so that's
that's what we think
yeah good answer good answer so
another specific one but probably going
to be more easier to answer this fan
wants to know do you view comfrey as
better to use during a vegetative phase
during a flowering phase or it's equally
good for both
i think it's equally good for both
it can it contains a vast
amount of different minerals and if you
have a comfrey patch you know feed your
comfrey patch with good teas and stuff
as well so it can uptake
good nutrients but it's so well balanced
that you can use it during you know from
the very beginning stages of a seedling
all the way up until your last day is a
flower almost
and the roots are good on winds
so what would be your go-to source for
organic boron because it's a trace
element that's commonly mentioned as
lacking in soils but it's also quite
difficult for many people to come across
um
i don't have an exact source of natural
boron other than just creating really
good compost you know from diverse
sources and you know getting your boron
from naturally you know and if you're
really concerned about any type of
mineral deficiency within your plant or
in your soil then it's always better to
have it come from a plant source
rather than
a whole mineral source it takes a
tremendous amount of time for a mineral
to break down but if you do have a go
between plant
like say that you know borage actually
is a good boron plant
you can add like a tremendous amount of
that to it and then use that plant in a
ferment or chop it up to put it into a
soil because then that's going to become
in you know equal or very easily
absorbable
it's just plants understand plants
and whenever you're utilizing a plant
source as your main mineral source it's
just easier for the plant to digest it
it's easier for the microbiology to
break it down
instantly and it becomes readily
available
yeah good answer
so what kind of resources and approaches
would you recommend we look into using
to help educate our politicians and
should we be pushing for exclusively
legislation that's designed to help care
for the earth at the same time as
allowing production or is simply a foot
in the door approach good enough
initially
well i mean i think ultimately we're you
know looking for a full package and
there really are a lot of really good
examples of
of companies that have been able to to
provide that you know so um there
there's
i don't know of
of a piece of
literature that you could point you know
politicians too that would say you know
this is a you know reason why you should
legalize i just think that there is a
lot of
activists out there and people that have
really
you know made differences in their local
jurisdictions and they're you know
they're moving around the country and
there's a lot of lawyers that have
become more and more savvy to what works
so
i think it's just um
part of of the conferences are also you
know connecting people with lawmakers i
think lawmakers are actually looking for
people to communicate with in the
community so i think if you make
yourself a little bit more available
then you will be able to to help change
and i think that anytime that we're
talking about agriculture we need to be
talking about health and well-being of
the earth that's where we went wrong
that's the reason why we have tremendous
illness on this planet is because those
two conversations didn't go together we
decided that plants and agriculture
should be more involved in science
rather than in nature
and
we really missed the mark there so hence
we have tremendously sick waterways and
soil systems and if we're not having
conversations as we move into the future
when we're discussing agriculture about
ecology and about healthy
water and earth
then we we're not doing our job and i
mean the whole entire cannabis industry
as we know it started out as a medical
you know gift to to ailments you know
that whether it was aids in san
francisco or you know that was the
epicenter of legalization was
stemmed from that and and so it usually
a place becomes medical first and then
it becomes recreational afterwards which
is
because then the whole medical
aspect it gets kind of thrown away
because recreational is kind of just a
big
tax
bracket thing where everyone can get
paid and then you kind of forgot that it
was a medicinal thing well it's the same
thing with cultivation i mean you'd
almost be missing out
to just say oh well let's just legalize
weed and just forget about how it grows
it doesn't really matter
you know i think that we should
consider hey well this is a medicine and
it should be cultivated like a medicine
which is medicinally good for the earth
so for us
you know we're just going to go for the
full
home run or the
you know whatever it is and we're just
going to say i think we should have it
all i think the time is now where this
is no time to skimp i think we should
ask for
everything
i think we should have all of it a
healthy environment and legalization all
of it but it's medical access
you know in canada it's legal but we've
lost
access
really i mean there's less products
available to the consumer now through
legalization than there was before and
that's lame yeah definitely
so this one's a bit of an odd one when i
first read it but i mean you know
there's a place for everything right how
would you feel about sprinkling the
ashes of a loved one into the soil and
growing a plant from it
well i mean i think that's a kind of a
no-brainer
or maybe that's not a good term to use
but um
i think that's uh
my mother is in our greenhouse yeah i
mean i think that's just you know
sanctifying the the ashes i mean for one
ashes are good for soil
so you're good there
and you're able to transform the energy
and put it into a plant i mean
maybe you have a placenta too and you
put it underneath the tree you know what
i mean it could you could go on and on
and on it's the cycle of life and we
think it's beautiful and all of our dogs
are underneath our cannabis plants too
we felt like that was just super
respectful why not grow
a beautiful medicine you know over some
something that you loved you know that
soul and spirit's not still there but
that body is and it's a wonderful way to
respect the body that walked this planet
most certainly
so
someone wanted to know do you guys offer
tours of your farm at all to the public
specifically those who are quite
interested in joining the pure family
you know we do not because we're really
far away and we just don't have the
setup to be touring people around and
then and and if we we the time to i mean
as much as i would love to i think it
would be healing to you know people to
be able to come to our farm and i think
one day we would love to to do that but
we're just not set up for it
but
i think that you know
in a way that's kind of cannabis tourism
or it's like ecotourism and i think that
is a thing that could be really
beautiful for farms and i know a lot of
farms
in california and different places are
embracing that bringing people to their
farm
and they could be
super smart
i think that we just don't do it right
now and we have lots of farmer friends
and people that are in the industry that
will come here to
get a little bit of education and then
we know that they're going to pass that
on or something so
we've been open to it but really the
truth is we're we are so far away it's
nothing but like us out here and um it's
like our own spiritual temple retreat
too so i think we just kind of get
rejuvenated by being on the on our land
and
sometimes that's what we need because we
have you know a lot going on so cannabis
packaging and branding has become a
focal highlight of discussion in recent
weeks most notably anyone who's ever
shopped at a dispensary probably has a
myriad of containers that are just
starting to accumulate after only ever
having a few grams in them what type of
packaging do you want to see going
forward
well
that's a sad reality to you know there's
so much there's millions of pounds of
garbage you know
based just on dube tubes you know which
is kind of like amazing you know so
sauna packaging is one new company
that is making really conscious
packaging that is
hemp plastic
and also they use recycled ocean plastic
and that's pretty cool and and that's
interesting it is still plastic in the
in a way but
if it's hemp plastic then that's just
awesome
um
when it comes to biodegradable
material the only thing about
biodegradable is it might be gmo
biodegradable and you'd have to be
careful of that so
i think that algae there's algae
plastics that are coming out and that's
also something that's of interest and
well and also we package all of our
products in glass because we feel like
it's important to also have a reusable
packaging so not just something that's
recyclable
something that people can also reuse so
i think it's a thing
too because i don't i don't in canada i
think for example i had
i think you can only use if you're a
licensed producer i'm pretty sure it's
like
you can only use their packaging and
it's really weird black plasticking
plastic that they just like did some
studies on a couple of months ago and
they left it out into the sunshine and
realized that it off gas like a
tremendous amount of toxins so
you know
whoa that's not very creative nor
ecological and it's unfortunate because
canadians are really upset about it as
well as a lot of producers are feeling
like wow i've grown this beautiful you
know flower and i got to put it into a
weird plastic container that's going to
fill up all of the and and and the
plastic that they're putting in it's not
even recyclable in canada so people
could grow their own weed and then they
wouldn't have to worry about packaging
that's one thing that would help there
you go grow your own
that's definitely it so do you think
that there has likewise become too much
of a focus on the aesthetics of
packaging like is having a fancy
packaging like a legitimate reason or
claim to charge more for the exact same
product
well
i mean i think it's kind of a bummer too
to make you
bring your packaging into your pricing
it's kind of like
how it's unavoidable i mean you can't
really
do anything about it but i think that um
you know cannabis packaging oh god it's
just
it's it's it's a thing that you can't
really i don't know i don't really know
what to say about it it's it's an
unneces it's a necessary
evil
yeah no i agree it's like there's
there's always going to be people who
want to package their product more fancy
and more shiny and flashy and that's one
thing but then
you know yeah to have these rampant
markups is just a bit of a different
realm as far as i can see
i think it's partly standing out you
know i mean if you have
your own
equipment or your own packaging that
you've designed yourself
it can help you stand out and at the end
of the day standing out matters and i
mean if someone
loves their packaging and it's awesome
and it's just sitting out on the counter
all day and they're like oh check out
this product i mean it helps you know
what i mean so
you know if you have to make sales
you know you might as well be crafty
about it and make something good but
you know
[Music]
don't go
nutso you know what i mean and create
something that's you know
a cost too too expensive everything is
already too expensive
alrighty so i think we are down to our
last of the fan submitted questions so
it's a good one i left it to last for a
reason how do you guys feel about
cookies
in general
um well i mean it has like the keebler
kind
no
but
um you know i it's it's
it's all about the hype you know
i think it's it's a flavor
you know i mean it's do you like the
flavors so i mean you know i i think
that a lot of people like the flavor and
that's that's why it
that that's why it sells but i think
that people like
wedding cake now too and you know now
it's just
cakes and cobblers and cookies and
you know i mean
gelatos and oh my god you know and the
mac
and that it's just like whatever is the
new flavor surprise there's not a mac
and cheese yeah you know i'm just
waiting for that one to come out because
that that's probably gonna be
pretty sweet you know
um
but you know i
it's a flavor you know i i'm not gonna i
i like weed so you know i'll smoke
cookies i i'll be happily do it you know
i'm i'm personally not into that terpene
profile of the cookies um
as a midwife for a long time i can smell
like cookies from you know 100 other
different bags because it reminds me of
breastfed baby poop is what it smells
like
which is awesome it's really you know an
interesting smell but it's not really a
terpene profile that um you know draws
me i mean there's so many flavors
but of course tons of people love it and
and that's great
yeah okay a lot a lot of good points in
there just to quickly mention i think
that uh old calculator has made a mac
and cheese strain cross mac cheese well
there you go see
if i so if someone's thought about it
someone's already done it
that's it right it's one of the rules of
the internet i think so um
on to our final kind of little quickfire
questions
first one i wanted to quickly ask you
what type of genetics would you like to
see make a comeback
i would like to see
um
god
ones that are
i mean i really love the acapulco gold i
say bring it back big time love that
just just you know as much as the
original acapulco gold and there is like
different strains that people are
calling acapulco gold and it's not
really same but
that was really awesome stuff when that
was going around
yeah i think that just um you know
non-feminized stable bread you know
smart strains you know that's what i
like to see
great answer so
if you could offer one or maybe even two
tips on selecting a mail to our
listeners what would they be
um well uh
it would be really nice to have a male
that is strong and comes up you know and
grows faster
i think is a good is a good trait
because it shows you know that it's
vigorous and
and
of course you know smell rubbing the
stem does help you get smells
from the male and i think that you
should
know
what you're looking for in a mail
because sometimes there's
colors in the leaf or in the stock that
show up
really early on in life and it can kind
of tell you a little bit about what's
happening
later in life
um
you'd you'd want to look at the the leaf
structure
the um
if if you like the node height that that
that it's growing maybe it's short maybe
it's
reaching um mostly we choose our males
like to be really manly
so we like our males to be really strong
and
and maybe it it flat you know maybe it
came to its flowers early so it's an
earth you know it's more it's not late
flowering
you would want to look for something
that um
progressed faster
um and sometimes with disease resistant
you'll sometimes get trichomes on the
males and that can you know
signal that it's going to be you know
more
oil rich and oil productive
and uh you know
red stalks or red stems can be something
that you look for you know it's like
it's really it's depending on what you
it says hard to say
yeah of course it's a it's a varied one
right
kind of i mean it's really strange
specific i mean if you were
you know breeding land race you would
look for the thinnest leaf that you
could see you know something like that
or
you know with maybe a fat leafed hash
strain you know i mean there's a lot of
it's i love that it's endless it's
fractal medicine yeah just keep doing
so and next one
what is one strain that you just never
particularly vibed with
um
[Music]
for me definitely kush
i don't i don't you know sort of that
like traditional like what people call
like a kush flavor which is like really
high in like a human
i don't know that's not something that i
necessarily vibe with and
yeah i really never met a hundred plant
that i didn't love but that's just a
terpene profile for me and i would agree
with josh i like them all
yeah that's good i remember i asked you
that last interview and you gave a
similar answer you were saying you know
i pretty much like them all so there you
go consistency
yeah for sure that's what we like
so what is one strain that maybe you
tried maybe you had the cutting but it's
now gone it's now either out of
existence or simply just out of your
hands that you would like to be able to
get back if possible
i do really like the jack herrera clone
that we had for a long time oh we had
such a beautiful cutting it was from
oregon and
oh just one of the original from the
jack herrera family oh and um there was
this uh the white witch which was uh
from the early 90s and the early trinity
the trinity
[Music]
like in 1989 and 90 that was really
awesome it was just super dank like
crazy crystals and just had amazing
flavor and you could ah it was so good
mm-hmm that one was good uh yeah i mean
you know and the list goes on and on
because we grow a thousand plants on our
property and
you know we don't really clone them
so
they could have all been amazing
we have a black a black or almost blue
grateful breath cherry puff that was a
really amazing and i really hope that we
get a a good we have some seeds of it
and we're growing it again this year but
that had been an another good one
yeah i think i remember even being able
to sample that one um
[Music]
how did you like that that one was nice
huh it was phenomenal and i think one of
the things which standed out in my
memory was that you would never have
been able to guess that that was outdoor
grown it looked just as good as anything
you'd ever seen indoor
give thanks exactly blessed be
that's it so
on to our final question for this chat
what is your ultimate goal slash hope
for the overall trajectory of our little
community
my overall hope is that
all of the intentional
amazing farmers
can continue to stay in business and
make amazing products
thrive in business i would like that to
thrive i
really
want to not get
it feels like you're getting penalized
for making medicine and you know when
you're getting all these crazy
prohibitive
licensing and all this stuff it just
feels like you're almost getting
punished for like creating medicine and
i i would like to live in a world where
it's not like can you get a licenses
it's once you have a license it's how
good can your medicine be so i would
love to see small farms
being able to make really really
intentional products and being able to
sell it anywhere in the world i would
love to be able to sell
our products to any country in the world
and i think that anyone should be able
to have access to it and i think it
should be really fun
rather than
funky you know which is kind of what it
is right now so i'd like to see a world
where
we have these really beautiful diverse
gardens we're growing amazing plants and
it's just simply a matter of our
ingenuity to make really good products
to be able to sell them that would be
nice and for me i mean just
one last you know statement on that is
that i'd really like to see
all of the people that are incarcerated
for cannabis to be let out because it is
uh really not cool in so many ways and
that's really light language that i'm
using
that people who are in corporations are
doing it legally uh and people who are
incarcerated were doing the same thing
so i would like to see all cannabis
incarcerated people let out and it would
be nice if they raised the hemp
thc counts to make it delta nine instead
of total
thc counts and so we could have better
medicine availability the world that
would be nice too
and i hope that cannabis can change the
world uh through teaching us
so many things from seed to seed and i
think it's great that denver
decriminalized
uh psychology yeah and i think that's
really cool too
and and we really like nice people too
so hopefully our community can continue
to expand and we can create together and
we can be
um communicating and we can be
collaborative in our efforts in moving
forward we can protect our own seeds by
putting them into public domain to where
we all can use them
to where we can all actualize them
and we could go on and on
yeah
yeah definitely they're all fantastic
suggestions and ideas so
i guess to wrap it up do you guys have
any comments or shout outs you'd like to
make
uh the shout out we would like to make
is to the earth big shout out to the
earth yeah for you know providing us a
place to live and the opportunity to
speak together
um thank you
and this is uh amazing opportunity to be
able to share some of the things that
we're interested in
um we'd like to
shout out the pure collective and the
pure certification and just all
regenerative farmers and all seed
readers and people that are making a
difference in the world and
shout out to people that are
able to resist the corporate takeover
that's happening and shout out to seed
breeders and
shout out to all of the people that are
still cultivating um cannabis in an
illegal situation we feel you we're with
your brothers and sisters thank you for
continuing to grow the medicine it's
really important
smoke weed every day
smoke weed every day what a brilliant
way to end it so thank you so much josh
and kelly for taking the time to sit
down and chat with us again for the
second time
thank you so much you're awesome we
can't wait to see you hopefully are you
coming out again this year oh we're
gonna see you on our land maybe we're
gonna see you soon hopefully
yeah i'd love to i'd love to lock that
one in so let's hope we can link again
very soon
yeah we love that thank you so much for
the opportunity um today we just
appreciate you more than words can say
all right back at you guys again
final thank you and we'll talk to you
again soon
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
as always a big big big big thank you
again to josh and kelly for taking the
time to talk to us today be sure to go
to the dragonfly with medicine website
for all product related queries or even
just info about the pure certification
[Music]
as usual a big thank you to radio ridge
nursery for their support your one-stop
shop for clones seats here now for all
the best offers on seeds they are the
best in the business
420 australia organic gardening
solutions
[Music]
and last but not least the patreon game
whose ongoing support continues to make
sure the show happens
[Music]
i will see all you fine friends in the
near future for the next episode
[Music]
thanks for listening
see you
[Music]
you