foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
as you're joined by your host heavy days
and this episode as always was brought
to you by our incredible sponsors
see you here now number one seed bank in
the industry guarantee on satisfaction
not just germination go check them out
all the hottest drugs all the best
breeders they've just put up some new
stock to go see if it's what you need to
make your next run fire as hell
likewise in order to get the best run
out of your genetics you need to keep
your garden happy and healthy and for
that we'd like to give a shout out to
our friends at Copper biological systems
these guys have all the best predators
in the game to keep bug infestations
away and to fight off any unwanted
issues you may be experiencing check out
their spidex vital or the acipa M both
fantastic products for fighting off
spider mites or acids respectively to
pass a lot of Growers struggle with but
they're here to help you get on top of
it
furthermore huge shout out to Pro mix
these guys have been in the industry for
years you know them they make great
media based products using Pete and
mycorizer but guess what now you can get
their fantastic mycorrhizal products on
its own Pro mix connect number one
mycorizer product in the game helping
you to achieve greater yields better
resin enhanced flavor and perfumes
helping you to make your next harvest
the best today check out Pro mix connect
for all your mycorrhizal needs
[Music]
you would like to welcome our newest
sponsor onto the show Sally's cannabis
these guys are family-owned small batch
craft cannabis out of Oklahoma City
providing you with fantastic flavors
incredibly high quality flour for anyone
who's in need of some high quality
medicine growing strains like Star
Pebbles chemical sunsets and so many
more go check out Charlie's cannabis for
all the best craft more back Oklahoma
grown cannabis they've got all the
flavors and herbs you need to make sure
that you're puffing good last but not
least huge shout out to the patreon gang
you guys know you're the lifeblood of
the show helping to ensure episodes
happen if you would like to help support
the show and ensure future content
continues to be created please go to
patreon.com forward slash the podcast
and sign up you'll get access to unheard
content additional interviews giveaways
and so much more patreon gang love you
guys so much appreciate you
on this episode we're joined by the one
and only East Coast chem Kings JJ NYC of
Top Dog genetics here to talk all things
ham and star dogs east coast history Top
Dog genetics going forward and so so so
much more
so without further ado
let's get into it
alrighty a big thank you and welcome for
joining us today one and only the East
Coast chem King JJ NYC of Top Dog
genetics thank you so much for joining
us today
thank you for having me
it's great to have you on finally we've
had so many requests for you but my
first question for you today is what
have you been smoking on recently
uh well recently you know I just
actually we did a um
a release
um with a dispensary
um Verde so you know I started working
with them in the beginning of the year
um you know I gave them some genetics
and finally we got you know the final
product out you know we started this uh
discussions in December I got those guys
some pollen some genetics and uh finally
we got a final product so we right now
um I'm we're in the process of Fino
hunting so I mean we I mean uh we did
like
I don't know like maybe like a thousand
seeds or I don't know exactly the exact
count but
um I think we did about 200 200 of the
mango uh Black Mac black Pips I'm sorry
the black Pips
and so
um that was the first release and so I
think out of the 200 I think we had
a little over a hundred females
so uh just you know going through all
the different uh phenotypes you know uh
judging them by smell
um you know the way that they grow uh we
did some uh test washing and
um you know just doing overall
evaluation of the flower and everything
so we had to do that with the black pith
and now this week we just released the
sour 2018
the New York City chem f2s some store
cookie
uh there was like the chem Z and the UW
back cross uh so I've been uh sifting
through all this flower and you know
um judging it and you know I have to go
back to the team with my recommendations
of my of my top three of what's up what
I like and everything so luckily for me
this all fell on the holiday weekend so
I'm kind of enjoying myself
Ah that's awesome it sounds like you're
in for a good weekend you you just
mentioned so many strains that I was
interested to talk to you about so thank
you for that the mango piff that's an
interesting one do you feel like there's
a growing demand for those sorts of
sativas nowadays
uh yeah well I mean the pith has always
been a staple in New York city so I mean
it's always been you know the people
that grew up in the New York metro area
most of them know about that he's and so
I mean it's always had a reputation
um kind of like the sour diesel I mean
it's really you know comes from the
scene the seam uh area that the sour
diesel blossomed out of
and uh so I just think that a lot of
people just you know they might have
heard about it read about it but never
got to experience experience it so you
know I was breeding I had done you know
a lot of breeding with some of the mango
stuff and then
um you know I had the Black Keys
um years ago and I did a breeding with
it and so um I had uh acquired the pith
S1 uh clone so I thought it would be you
know the perfect choice for the the
mango the mango Nigerian
um black Haze and that was the male
times the the pith S one so that was
that that's what made the the black pith
that were uh currently uh that we
currently released
wow that's that's great to hear I'm I'm
one of those people you describe who's
heard so much about the pith that
obviously never tried it I guess the the
first question that I sort of think
about is you hear a lot of names thrown
around like um we're like Uptown Haze
Cuban black Haze the pif are they all
the same thing or are they different
yeah no they're all the same thing uh
they're just different kind of slang uh
terms for for that for that strain but
also
um it's the same as the E5 the E5 from
Amsterdam or the same genetics they're
they're a little bit different you know
the E5 is
um was a little bit meatier I think but
it was still kind of that same Colombian
pissy type of genetics uh which was very
rare I don't think that you know Neville
ever really commercially released uh
that strain I think that was something
that you know he had a small release of
at the time and you know and these are
and this is what had survived out of
that you know obviously they have the E5
I think the cat shoe in Amsterdam has
that's one of their house streams
and it's been a staple you know for
Amsterdam for a long time and then the
same could be said for the the black
Haze you know which was you know um came
out of Florida originally that's where
they you know originally started growing
it and then commercial shipments would
come up to New York City and so
um there was always a New York Miami uh
there was always a uh that was always uh
like a a cocaine route uh with guns and
drugs Etc so
um a lot you know back then you know all
that was just you know balled into one
so they were trafficking stuff back and
forth bringing up you know
um a lot of that up into New York and
then once they got established uh I
think they started producing you know
some of this stuff up up into New York
in New York City area area so I remember
hearing a couple busts back in the day
and it was up Uptown and it you know it
was the Dominicans and and and those
guys up there that were were running
that stuff so I mean even to this day
they still have a Stranglehold on that
on that strain
yeah that's I think that's one of the
most interesting aspects about it is how
it's still so tightly held and so
elusive I guess another thing which came
out about your previous answer was that
you work with the S1 and it made me
wonder do you think that the real one
still exists or maybe the S1 is the best
we have
no no I think that the
um you know the real one still exists
um I think you know I just reacquired
the black Haze
um cutting I haven't finished it out so
I can't verify it but
um it seems to be a lot more people in
the community that are using it now it's
getting passed around a lot more now but
you know that's you know uh that was
around you know 10 years ago so you know
I had done some work with it you know
maybe nine ten years ago and um
it you know people just you know weren't
really interested in Hayes really uh you
know there were a few people but really
since the death of of Neville it seems
that there's been a a re you know uh
reviolation of uh of interest of the
haze so uh you know and then you know
with you know with uh with people now
um you know talking about The Black Keys
and the pith a lot more and it being a
little bit more available
um people I think are you know and once
they try it you know then they're you
know they're interested in growing it
and and my funerals are going about 70
to 77 days you know so um you know with
the you know with the breeding that I've
done you know it originally started with
nl5 Haze times the Nigerian and then
back Frost into the Nigerian and then
crossed into the the mango Haze and
that's what made the mango Nigerian and
that was basically you know um uh an
earlier uh sativa strain because there
was a little bit of indigo with the nl5
in it and then and then and also the uh
the Nigerian was an early finishing
sativa and then crossed into the mango
um and that was kind of early finishing
because that was um I you know that was
the A5 time skunk one I believe
and so that was a little more indicate
in there so uh you know the lines
um basically have been kind of bred with
a little bit of indigo and um but you
know they were way more sativa leaning
and just really just cut down the
flowering time on on a lot of those long
flowering sativas
you know so then I you know you know
then I crossed that into the black into
the black Haze and then obviously I
crossed that into the the um
the S1 which was an early finisher but
the S1 I felt
um kind of fell short for me on I mean
it was really crystally and it finished
it early and when you smelled it and it
was grown it smelled really piffy and
everything
but when you smoked it it didn't have
that that psychedelic sativa uh effect
to it and when I say that when you smoke
this
um it's pretty much like a head high and
you can take a big hit and blow it out
and close your eyes and you'll just feel
the effect of of the third eye and a lot
of moving parts inside of your head
almost you know it's kind of hard to
describe when you
um you know when you smoke some of these
psychedelic sativas you know they're
more of an up high a more clear
um you know you'll get a little race see
a little a little heart race you know
you feel your heart you know beating a
little bit and you know for the cheese
and smoke or you know you're able to
handle that but if you give that to
someone that's not a seasoned smoker you
know they'll get uh you know they'll
start to get anxiety the racy effect and
what I call
um cannabis overdose you know when you
it's almost like when you eat too much
Edibles you know you get the feeling
that you're almost gonna die your heart
is raced in you're breathing heavy you
feel uncomfortable and you know you just
got you know with you know experienced
smokers know that you know that you know
uh that you just gotta kind of just
chill out and relax action you know it's
it's gonna go away but for people that
you know don't really know they start
getting more uh they just contribute to
the paranoia of the whole thing and they
don't you know instead of trying to
relax they go in and start getting more
um you know upset about it and and it
just contributes to their you know some
people go to go to the hospital and
um
so
yeah a great answer you know I hope all
of our listeners have been there at
least once
well if you eat too much Edibles we've
all been there at one point or another
yeah it's interesting that like the
positive feedback loop you describe it's
hilarious yeah I think we've all been
there at some point or another something
interesting that you just referenced is
like it's it's so impressive that you're
able to cut down the flowering time to
you know like 70 days-ish because those
strains often go a lot longer but
something I specifically wanted to ask
you in relation to that anxiety feeling
is I think I'm one of the only people
who says this but I get that feeling
from the C5 and I love it I like I love
anxiety and juicing weed I know it's a
very like non-popular opinion to express
but I think I'm the only one who prefers
the C5 over the A5 where do you fall on
that one do you prefer one over the
other
um I'm more of an A5 guy because I like
that pissy kind of
[Music]
um
yeah Colombian where the C5 is kind of
more of that floral tie and which is
nice
um but I get more of the Psychedelic
feelings from from the A5
um yeah and I guess you know the
combination of the both would be you
know equivalent to the Neville's Hayes
yeah gosh I guess that's that's one I've
yet to try but it would be be really
nice I'm betting you know I mean I've
been able to try some good samples in
the past and you know the the real good
ones you kind of get a blend of both you
know surprisingly enough yeah and um
yeah that's the only way to describe it
yeah lovely stuff there lovely stuff
okay to bring us back to sort of the
original question about like sort of
what are you smoking and you mentioned
the facilities I guess another question
I'm interested in asking you is if a
facility was to come to you and ask to
use some of your genetics what are some
of the genetics that you think would do
better in a facility as opposed to say
just like a home grower where you know
certain factors aren't as big of a deal
what are the ones you go to straight
away for facilities
well I mean you got to go to you know
the the store dogs the guavas the
original New York City diesels you know
a lot of that a lot of the stuff that's
been a staple you know of the brand for
for for the you know for a long time
um you know and it depends on what
direction they want to go with it you
know a lot of it depends on you know uh
what the facility you know like the guys
that I'm working with now are more into
Fino hunting and looking for
um phenos that that are going to produce
Terps and hash and good flour and so
they're doing some research and
development you know so
um you know each play you know not a lot
of places are really willing to do that
they want to you know they have a
certain amount of space dedicated to to
their canopy and really uh they want to
you know match maximize you know every
square inch of that and so you know
depending on you know
um
you know it really depends on you know
the the business model of of of of the
business you know of of the businesses
itself
yeah that's that's so promising to hear
that they're willing to do that Veno
hunting because I mean I think a
sentiment expressed by many guests in
the past is that by doing that you sort
of create your own brand image because
you've got this unique thing that like
no one else has because you you went and
found it and then on top of that it's
you know like a star dog from JJ like
what more could you ask for
right and it becomes almost an exclusive
so it'd be become your own exclusive
house
strain or phenol of that strain and so
you can call that your own and be
exclusive with it and you know you know
as well as I do you know if you get you
know really popular uh phenotype that's
really special that you know and like
just say just like a GMO for for example
you know if you're able to find
something of something of that magnitude
and keep that you know in-house as your
own now obviously you're going to be
able to uh attract that you know you
know that market to you because of that
so and I think that's really going to be
the the future of cannabis is really
going to be branding
and and strains and really kind of on
the level of wine and beer as in micro
brewing and you know you really you know
as a as a cannabis brand you know you
really got to Define yourself on who you
want to be who who are your customers
who your customers want to be do you
want to be a Gucci or do you want to be
a Walmart you know so I mean you know
each each model can be profitable and
you know so
um but you know you have to you know
um Define on who you want to be and you
want to be a you know the on The
Connoisseur you know and attract
knowledgeable people or do you want to
be the kind of business that's just
going to you know attract people that
they're that are not you know that are
not regular smokers they come in in
their one and done and you'll never see
them again and so and a lot of it is you
know based on
um price point you know so you know a
lot of people are just beast on you know
they only want to spend so much money
um maybe they only smoke once or twice a
week so you know quality to them is not
going to be a big difference where you
have a guy that's you know smoking every
day and or if they're a medical patient
so you know it you know when you really
you know break down the customer pull uh
it gets quite intricate in in the
different type of people that can be
your customer so you really got to you
know think about who you want to be
yeah most definitely that's a nice run
down there and I guess the last sort of
question before we move to a different
topic is we see um a few different
breeders working with facilities
nowadays do you suspect that not just
for you but sort of across the board in
the industry that this will be the way
breeders move in the future where they
try to pair up with facilities or do you
think it's maybe not a big Trend per se
um well I think you know it's really
going to be up to the facilities and how
they want to Brand themselves
and so
um you know if you know if they just
want to create their own brand
you know and which is quite difficult
but possible you know built on quality
or whatever your selling point is going
to be
uh you know otherwise you know you're
going to have to go with a recognized
brands in the industry and
um
you know you know I've said this before
you know uh you know good weed comes
from good strains good strains come from
good clones and good clones come from
good seeds
so you know a lot of you know the a lot
of corporate people don't really you
know understand this concept and just
think you can just go out and get get
some weed get you know get whatever you
know weed is weed and
so you know you know it really gonna
really goes down to you know the the
type of people that are running the
business and you know do they smoke pot
themselves or they connoisseurs
themselves or are they just you know uh
a corporate fund just you know just
counting the money so you know there's a
big difference between the two and you
know when you're in touch and out of
touch with the culture so
um you know it depends on you know who
you want to appeal to and but you know
for me I see you know like I said I see
as being as branding as being uh you
know like like you're gonna go into you
know like the New York structure is
going to be
um you know it's it's not going to be
integrated so you know as a dispensary
you're going to be able to buy wholesale
from anyone across the board
so you know so and you know so if that's
the case now you know you know what's
going to separate each each brand from
itself you know it's just really going
to be the name and reputation on how
good the product is so you know in the
end that's really you know you know
what's going to win out is you know who
has the best product consistently and uh
so you know so I mean and that's the way
that I see you know the market you know
eventually moving to because you know uh
you know you know when I go shopping you
know in in a dispensary you know I'm
looking for the Diesels the cams the
kushes you know anything uh with the
fuel the high end you know and so you
know that's just the kind of and I'm
willing to uh travel and that's just a
kind of customer that I am and I'm
looking for certain types of strains and
certain types of quality so uh you know
it doesn't pay for me you know just to
get some average you know some average
stuff for for cheap you know because you
know it doesn't matter how much I smoke
of it I'm not going to be satisfied you
know but when you smoke some cam or some
uh some some fire you know you could you
just got to take one or two good Puffs
you know once you blow that out you just
get that warm fuzzy feeling and it's
almost like that you know warm blanket
you know over you know over you and you
know it's just something that you know I
can't really you know get from something
else that you know even if I smoke you
know a pound of it I I won't you know so
it just does not have the same effect
for me so
yeah great sentiment Express there so
I'd love if you could take me back
what's your first experience with
cannabis
um I was about 13 years old
and it was it I think it was it might
have been Christmas day and it had
snowed and when we were kids we used to
go out
you know shovel sidewalks and driveways
for money so we had snowed you know in
my next door neighbor called me up you
know and again let's go out you know
let's do some shoveling so you know we
go out you know we had our regular
people that we used to you know shovel
on a regular basis so we were heading
over to the one people's house and we
decided you know we cut through some
woods and we stopped and uh he pulled
out a joint you know and he had older
brothers and so um and I was the oldest
one in my family so
um you know I had never seen any you
know weed before or anything like that
so you know we uh you know
he he lit it up and and we smoked it and
you know I was kind of feeling a little
silly and everything and we started
shoveling and
uh we couldn't finish the job you know
we got like you know we were just so you
know kind of silly and you know it was
just so much work we just kind of bailed
out of it and just and just walked away
uh from the job so um and then after
that I don't know I might have been in
like seventh grade and you know uh and
you know I was in Middle School so
um I you know there were maybe a couple
other times that you know we had gotten
weed I remember uh we had bought a
nickel bag from someone and that was
like five dollars worth and so
um we all you know there's three of us
so we all you know chipped in bought
this nickel bag from an older guy in the
neighborhood and you know we smoked a
couple bowls of it we were down by the
river and you know so we smoked a couple
bowls and then a bunch of these older
kids started you know
um coming around and they were having
this big party down where we where we
were hanging out
and so you know we were started hanging
out with them and so we were smoking a
little bit and some guy was like who's
got some weed and so and we were like oh
we got some so we showed them the bag
he's like I'll give you 15 bucks for it
and so we were like yeah sure you know
so we had already smoked you know like
three or four bowls and now we sold it
for 15 bucks so you know we we each
wound up you know getting high for free
and getting five bucks each you know and
so we were really psyched about that and
so you know that was one of the other
um you know early experiences I had but
I really didn't start using regularly
until I I got into high school you know
when I got into ninth grade and once I
got there I mean there was like a
smoking area on the school grounds and
there was a tree there and it was on a
little bit of a Knoll so it was like a
little bit of a whole a little bit of a
hill there and so all the kids used to
just you know gather up in the morning
before school and everyone used to smoke
cigarettes there and everyone used to
just crowd it was like a circle around a
tree and so you know you can get into
that Circle and everyone would be
smoking cigarettes and then you know
back then
um they used to sell joints for a dollar
and they would and they would have them
in cigarette packs so you know someone
someone would come out and they'd
[__] open up their cigarette pack and
be like dollar joints and so you know
they would you know everyone in that
Circle would just start buying joints
you know so you would get up with your
friends and be like you know um
you know yeah we got five dollars and so
you know you make a deal be like all
right give us six for five you got a six
for five so you know we would plan all
right we're gonna smoke one one joint in
the morning we'll smoke you know one at
lunch time one after school and then two
you know so we you know we would have
all that weed like planned out for for
the whole day on how we were gonna smoke
it and you know we were only kids back
then so when you had you know three four
five kids you know and you each put up a
dollar or two you know all of a sudden
you had you know five ten bucks now
you'd be like all right give me 12 for
10 or you know so you'd be able to cut
deals and so uh yeah that's how you
survived when we were kids you know
going to school we did this with our
lunch money and you know we didn't work
and just got money from our parents and
yeah we were just trying to get high
great answer what a nice little stroll
down memory lane I mean I don't fault
you if you don't know the answer to this
but do you know what you were smoking at
the time
um early on
um you know there was really no names
you know there was really kind of like
Mexican and Colombian and you know so
that was like early on but there was
always uh some Hawaiian and there was
exotic around you know uh it was really
hard to get uh there was a lot of uh
blonde hash uh the the red hash black
hash
um but around in the Earl I'd say I
don't know 81 82 and that's when the
real first uh we call the Christmas tree
sense so that was really when the first
real kind buds started coming around and
I remember I think it was used to be
able to get it for like 200 bucks an
ounce you know which was a lot of money
back then and uh you know people I mean
you could maybe sell a gram for 10 bucks
back then you know so you know it wasn't
really you know you know much of you
know of a profit margin uh because you
know back then you know like I was
telling you there were dollar joints and
you know uh half ounce it would be like
twenty dollars an ounce would be forty
dollars and that would be kind of this
year typical
commercial type of weed you know out of
an ounce you can maybe you should be
able to roll I don't know 50 to 60
joints depending how big they were so
that's how people would sell and you
know for a dollar each you know so um
so yeah the Christmas tree scents used
to you know come around and used to be
good Hawaii and and stuff like that but
you know and I also remember
when I was in school the janitor start
was selling weed and he used to get and
he had his brother uh lived in Harlem
and up in New York City and I know that
he used to get the weed was coming from
Harlem and he used to get this stuff I
think it you know and it was I think it
was fifty dollars an ounce which they're
either 50 or 60 I forget I know that it
was more expensive than your regular you
know standard commercial stuff and
originally he came in and he started he
handed my friend a packet
um you know a pack of joints to sell for
them and there were these little tiny
like Pinhead joints I mean they were
ridiculous you know I mean like people
used to laugh at him because there used
to be this guy stying me and he used to
sell these joints and I mean people used
to we used to know his route to school
and they would like they used to wait
for him to cut they cut him off before
he got onto the grounds because when he
used to get stymy joints there were
these big huge bombs and you could
actually unroll them and get two joints
out of the one you know I mean so you
know so you know so but you know I had
these little skinny pin heads and like
you know that people used to ridicule
them they're like oh that's a toothpick
this and that you know but when you
smoke that man it [__] you up so you
know a lot more than than the regular
stuff and so you know the the janitor
was you know you know then my friend
showed me what he was getting from the
janitor and then I hooked up with them
and so I was just getting like you know
I was just getting ounces from them and
just selling it myself and I remember I
just pulled that rainbow weed and but it
had all different colors and it had like
some red some green some brown some gold
and all different colors but I suspect
that was some type of Thai weed or
something like that because I just
remember that just being you know some
of the strongest stuff around like I was
explaining to you you know once people
smoked it they were just like oh let me
get some more of that stuff so uh that
was you know another memorable you know
strain a day and also I remember getting
like some some real gold some real
Colombian gold the Santa Marta gold
um a friend of mine he had an older
brother
he had two older brothers and so
um yeah I guess one of the older
brothers I I think it just came down the
line of Brothers the older brother got
it gave it to the gave it to the other
brother and then he gave it to the
younger brother who was my friend so we
wound up getting like I think we got an
ounce of it and we split at half and
half and
um yeah I remember that just being
bright gold like you know like and back
then there was the real gold and then
the fool's gold which they called so the
the fool's gold was the stuff that
look gold but it was just trash it
didn't get you high so I used to call
that fool's gold with a real gold was
kind of
um hazy it had like this hazy type of
um you know tip to it and so I just
remember that and uh I just remember it
being a seedless and this kind of bright
yellow gold and you know just kind of
having that real sativa type of look to
it and um if you ever uh if you're
familiar with Lawrence chernak he has a
cannabis book and he actually has a
picture of some some gold in there and
it looked exactly the same you know when
I saw that picture I was like that's
what you know we got back in the day and
I was only able to get it once but it
was memorable and that's how things were
back then you know you would see some
something you'd get it once and
that was it you know and uh
so
wow what a great little history lesson
right there I mean something people
probably notice when they look at the
collective work done by Top Dog and you
can see that there's obviously sort of
this Indica side of things with you know
the chems and whatnot but there's also
the sativa side of things do you think
that this sort of exposure to these
really sort of quite legendary strains
at the young age instilled in you as
sort of a love for those sativas or is
it more so you just want to provide a
bit of everything
no you kind of you know hit it on the
head you know I really built the brand
on things that I like and experienced
so you know I know that I'm a little
older than most of the people so I was
like be able I was able to experience
you know a lot of things early on you
know I was able to catch kind of what I
call the the late 70s Cheech and Chong
air era of what I explained to you of
you know twenty dollar halves and forty
dollar ounces and all that kind of stuff
where that kind of changed in the early
80s or in early to mid 80s once
um you know the drug War uh really
stepped up and that's what really
cultivated the whole indoor scene
because in the early 80s you know I
remember that's when Ronald Reagan came
into
um he came he was the president you know
and I was in high school from 80 to 84.
and that's when he first took over
so you know within the first two years
you know uh things started to change and
by the last two years you know you know
like I said things you know started to
change a little bit more and you know by
the time I got out of high school uh by
um the government really put a halt on a
lot of the Imports that were coming into
the country
and that prompted a whole a whole shift
in the drug trade to where they started
importing cocaine instead of bales of
marijuana
so by 1985 1986 the streets just became
flooded with imported cocaine and uh and
there wasn't much import marijuana
coming in and looking back at that time
in history you know
um up in the Pacific Northwest that's
kind of like when
um the indoor grows of Seattle
uh Greg McAllister the NL guys up there
you know they they were they started you
know those indoor grows in the in the
early 80s during during that during
those times
and uh
yeah so that just really kind of
prompted the whole indoor thing where
you know that's where that's where it
began because of the the pressure you
know of you know of the Imports so
people just like well we'll just start
producing it ourselves you know to the
point you know to where you know we you
know uh we just started to become a self
a self-efficient you know uh producing
company uh country ourselves a lot of
people have never uh experienced what I
uh a drought you know meaning where you
couldn't get weed I mean like I said you
know back in the 80s it was easier to
get cocaine than it was to get weed and
so uh yeah it became very you know
difficult uh
yeah so I mean and that just kind of
prompted the whole indoor the whole
indoor scene to you know to where it's
kind of evolved into today you know to
where you know it's kind of amazing if
you you know really kind of look back at
the history of it or really know know
anything about it
what a fascinating sort of way to view
back on things and it all makes perfect
sense right with the rise of the drug
war and whatnot if we think back to when
you were talking about uh you know how
to saw you befriended the groundskeeper
and you sort of got access to the better
quality stuff it's it's clear that
you're quite a good networker which I'm
sure has helped you a lot over the years
do you remember any of the strains that
you were seeing from those indoor grows
say before chem came out sort of you
know like 80s super early 90s were there
any memorable ones that you can remember
at all
well I remember seeing my first grow and
uh this was a guy who was in Times
Square in New York City on 47 46th
Street and he was in between Broadway
and uh Sixth Avenue so I mean that was
like a block away right from the center
of of Times Square and he was a weed
dealer and
um so you know I I had hooked up with
him in the late 80s
um yeah mid to mid to late 80s and so
you know I was just that's where I used
to go and buy my weed from you know and
he would have you know regular
um Mexican weed that which was green and
and sellable you know and like an upper
mid we used to call them and then he
would get you know exotic strains and
different stuff like that
but you know he wound he wound up like
monopolizing his building and wound up
getting like I don't know like the
building itself maybe had only like
I think it had an apartment on each you
know I had two apartments on each floor
and so there was one guy that was in the
building and he rented one of the places
but he also lived up in Albany so he
wasn't in the building much and then
there was like a music uh repair store
downstairs and then he wound up getting
the next three Apartments all the way up
and so he sold weed out of one he had
one that he's had storage out of that's
where he stored his weed and then the
other one he had a little grub and so uh
this was probably like in the late 80s
like 89 90
somewhere in that range and so these
guys were going to Amsterdam and getting
uh the Early Skunk
uh the silver Pearl uh a lot of the
Scentsy type of strains and they were
growing them you know and they had this
uh little Hydro set up and so that was
you know some of the first uh indoor uh
you know stuff that I had seen and uh
yeah and so most of that stuff was seeds
that came over from Amsterdam and so
they were going back and forth and you
know I you know back then you know I was
really green and wet behind it years and
you know I I didn't really have a lot of
knowledge about it but I had an interest
in it and so it was probably about that
time that I actually started collecting
seeds you know I would get a bag of good
weed and find the seed out of it and and
shave it and I was like yeah maybe one
day I'll be a grower and so um
yeah unfortunately that that seed
collection I got seized by by the police
and one of my many uh brushes with the
law
but uh yeah and that was even before I
really decided to be a grower too so
okay I mean I guess the next question
for me is what was it that stimulated
you to start growing as opposed to just
sort of being involved in it all
well you know
um you know so you know I'll go back you
know even a little bit farther than that
you know I mean like I said I had this
guy in Times Square who was my pot
dealer and everything so
um
you know when everyone from my town was
going to this guy and everything so uh
and then I had heard that
one one of the kids from our town was
was selling weed up in Central Park
and I was like really I was like if that
kid can do it I was like I can do it too
because the guy was a total loser you
know so I
so I went up there and I checked out the
steam you know and it but it was late it
was late it was late in the summer so
you know I went up there and it was up
in sheep met up in Central Park and it
was just the open free drug Market
that's the only way I could describe it
of people just walking around selling
acid mushrooms
weed hash uh there's it would sell beer
I mean you could just sit down and this
you used to be able to smoke and people
used to you know they'd have Circles of
kids just all around different Circles
of people some people would bring uh
guitars and drums and have little
circles and it was just it was just a
really cool scene I was just like blown
away I was like wow I can't believe this
you know but it was it was late in the
seasons I was like well I'm gonna come
out next year so
you know I wound up you know getting
um some really good uh you know some
really good green came in and we used to
call it pretendica because it was almost
like real Indigo but it had a few seeds
in it you know I mean so the real Indigo
was seedless but this stuff was like
kind of like
squishy and like spongy but there was a
little bit few there was a little there
were a few seeds in it you know it was
more expensive than your regular
commercial but it was well worth it
because you know the price you can kick
up the price out of it and if you can
find you know someone that wasn't really
in the know and you could squeeze all of
them seeds out of it you could you know
sell that off as you know as you know as
kind buds so you know you know I was
able to get you know I think like five
pounds of it you know and I uh and I
just squirreled that away thinking all
right this is going to be what I'm going
to bring out to the park in the spring
so that's what I did so you know the the
day came you know
um you know I might have scouted out you
know and went up there one day and seen
it was happening then I was like all
right I'm gonna go out there so and I
got I had all my my you know had my
pretend to go with me you know and I hit
the park I you know I go through one of
the side Gates and I start walking
through and I see some guy sitting under
a tree with a guitar with his girlfriend
listening to the Grateful Dead on on a
little radio and I think to myself oh
wow this guy's got to be cool you know
what I mean so I go over to him and then
I try you know hustling them and I'm
like yeah you know I'm trying to sell
them weed this and that and then he says
to me well let me show you what I have
that when I'm selling and he he whips
out some real kind bud you know I'm just
like whoa you know I'm blown away you
know so I'm like you know so I get
friendly with the guy and everything and
so you know we've become friends and and
so you know and I was you know just
trying to learn the ropes out there so I
was kind of hanging with him and he
would tell me you know this guy's but
watch out for this one or that one or
you know so um you know we were sitting
there one day and some guy come
strolling up and the guy's name was Ben
he's like hey Ben he's like you know and
I guess that someone had sent him out
there to look for Ben because Ben was a
known kind bud dealer in Central Park
so uh this guy comes up and he's like
hey you know I got some kind bud that I
grew do you want to buy some
and so you know Ben he's like yeah I
only have you know x amount of dollars
for x amount of weed you know and then
he looks to me and he's like do you want
to buy some and I'm like yeah I'll buy
you know I'm like I'll buy some you know
I mean yeah because back then like
trying to find someone you know to try
to find a grower was just like you know
I was like hitting a gold mine you know
because it was just so you know you know
there were people out there were doing
it but finding those people were just so
far and few in between that you know uh
you know it was very hard so you know
when I really got the first chance other
than the guy that knew in central I mean
in um Times Square who grew but you know
I was you know really excited you know
to be able to buy some so you know maybe
like a week or two later I'm out there
by myself you know Ben's not around but
who do I see walking across the meadow
is the kind bud guy and I'm like yo man
come on over you know and he's like yo
where's Ben I'm like I don't know he's
not here today I'm like what you got
some kind and he's like yeah I got you
know whatever and I was just like well
you know what I'll I'll take it all I
think he used to come in with quarters
there were like six grand quarters where
he used to come in with you know so uh I
was like I'll take them all you know
what I mean and so you know
um you know I hooked up with a guy and
you know unfortunately for Ben he wound
up
um getting all [__] up on drugs and so
you know I was just out there on a
regular basis just grinding away and
started working with this guy
and so you know this guy wound up being
the weasel you know this was this was
the guy he came out originally which um
uh he used to call it the RFK skunk and
the story behind that was that him and a
friend had gone to a dead show down and
down at RFK Stadium down in Washington
DC and bought a bag of kind and they had
some seeds in it and they uh they split
up the seeds and then they both decided
to grow so you know they both started
growing
and they needed a place to get rid of it
so they came out to the park you know so
you know his original product was the
RFK one two and three and
um after that he wound up
um going to a fish uh
and meeting Greg chemdawg Greg
and so I guess you know uh they uh you
know back then like one grower meeting
another grower was another big thing
because all right now I have someone
that I can trust
trade uh genetics and information with
so uh you know that's you know Greg was
growing the chem 91 in the super skunk
and you know my friend had the RFK and
you know I don't know if you might have
had some stuff from Amsterdam but
um he wound up driving up to
Massachusetts from Staten Island uh
bought you know traded enough for the
chem 91 and super Mass super skunk and
then he brought that down to uh to
Staten Island you know and um and by
that time I had kind of you know uh
cornered that whole Market meaning like
I told him listen you know I'll buy
everything you got I got cash I'll pay
you Cod you know what I mean so he he
loved that you know idea so he was like
Hey listen you know doing you know
business up here in the park isn't
really a good idea we should go down to
Wetlands and so he's like down in
Wetlands you know it was a bar and you
know on Tuesday nights you have Grateful
Dead night you know and so you can go
downstairs and they had like drum
circles and guitars and stuff like that
but they they they let you you know
smoke weed down there so you know we
would you know meet up down there and um
you know we wound up meeting AJ down
there and you know he just kind of just
sniffed us out because you know I would
I would wait for him you know and people
you know people knew who I was and
they'd be asking me for weed and I'd be
like you know wait wait wait wait you
know and so I I'd be waiting for him
they would see him come over to me you
know we would do our business you know
what I mean and you know and once you
know when we were doing our business
obviously you know I would take a bag
out and open it up as soon as I would
open that bag I would just permeate the
whole room and so people would just be
there like standing there like staring
at us you know the whole time you know
and then eventually that's how kind of
AJ caught on to us and then you know I
reached a point where he'd be like Hey
listen that's going to the back office I
have access to it let's go back and do
do do our deals back there so you know
so we you know all started you know
getting friendly and we used to smoke
back there and it became exclusive
and so you know I was able to you know
um
you know that was just the beginning of
the whole you know the whole chem story
when I you know when you know he you
know he started
um
doing a little bit of breeding you know
he created you know the under the
underdog which was you know NL Super
Skunk times chem 91 and uh he had that
and then you know he was running that
um he was also running some others some
other strains in there
and you know that's where we suspect the
you know the sour diesel came out of
because you know I told you earlier that
I you know I used to collect seeds so
you know once the chem started coming
around I used to collect seeds out of
the chem and you know once I started
growing when I first started growing I
had to pop some of them chem seeds and
they came out you know very sour you
know and I remember
um I wound up giving remember I sexed
the plant and knew it was a female
and
um and I gave it to my friend and I told
them that you know that this is a female
and you know we didn't we were we
weren't able to finish it and so when he
finished it you know he wound up uh coin
that the guava cut and so you know that
was that was the original guava but not
the guava that we know today you know
and uh
so you know the story you know uh you
know behind that is uh
that wound up just coming back you know
as in like a as in store dog so he
referenced he thought that was the
closest uh thing to the original guava
that he remembers but it was it was it
was chem genetics but just a different
breeding so uh yeah so that was real you
know I was lucky enough to um
to me you know my you know the weasel
and uh
really you know and really what really
started to have you know so I was just
you know out there selling weed and once
I met Mike and
um you know he got me interested in
growing and so
in like 99 you know I decided I was
gonna you know I decided I wanted to
start growling and what I did was I
rented an apartment up in um
Washington Heights up by uh uh
the George Washington Bridge
and I put a hydro Cable in there and a
couple lights and Mike wound up giving
me some
um some some some cuttings of the Oasis
he was running the Oasis from Amsterdam
so those were the very first cuttings
that I got of Oasis and I put them up
there in that apartment
and went what wound up happening was
that the electrical box burnt out you
know somehow you know I I over Juiced it
and so you know uh yeah it was it didn't
work out so I I you know I walk in one
day and the lights are out and I'm like
what am I going to do I couldn't fix the
Box myself I called the super he's
saying well I got to get into the
apartment you know I got all my gross
[__] in there and I can't let him in so
what am I going to do I was in a dilemma
and so right at that same time some
people that I used to sell weed to uh
there were two brothers
and uh they had a spot down on in a
building on Fifth Avenue
and they knew the people that owned the
building and they were like the
maintenance workers of the building
and they had
charged all this money on on uh
credit card like fifteen thousand
dollars worth of gross stuff they bought
lights and tables Hydro all this stuff
and they were uh you know they had seen
something in the High Times magazine
about or Perpetual sea of green Harvest
you can Harvest every week blah blah
blah so I mean that's you know what they
were trying to do and it was just
failing and so uh you know they asked
you know and I had told them about what
I was doing and so they didn't had known
that I had a little thing and so
um when my apartment went down I told
them Hey listen you know
um
you know I you know I I have a whole
bunch of plants they're gonna die and
they're like well just bring them bring
them down here and he and they were like
and then we made an agreement to where I
was going to help them you know get that
room turned around and try to help them
get their money back so we we you know
formed a partnership and so I moved
those plans down to Fifth Avenue
and they had
um
this maintenance area
that was a pretty big space and it was
like they made it into like a locker
room but they made it to where where you
open one of the lockers you walked into
through into another room and that's
where the grow room was so they had
built a wall and then they had these
lockers that you walked through and so
that's where the grow room was and you
know it was just kind of like
improperly put together and everything
and they were splicing into the electric
all over the building and eventually
what happened was
I helped them get their money back and
everything and you know what we were
having problems in a room it was getting
too hot during the summer time and you
know working out the bugs and they you
know had ran some new wires and and
tapped into the
um the hallway electric which was on the
other side of the wall they spliced into
that
so I go in there on a hot day and it's
really hot you know and I you know I
turn on a an air conditioner and walk
out
you know not knowing anything that I
just you know overloaded to Circuit you
know so I'm in the city
down at my apartment or office and then
I get a phone call saying that the the
fire department in front of the building
and that there's a fire in the building
so you know I hop in my car I drive past
and sure enough the fire department's
out front
and um so lucky for us you know uh they
located you know I guess in the hallway
where the fire was and it was up in the
ceiling and uh lucky for us it wasn't on
the other other side of the wall and
that's where the grow was so they popped
their head up there they saw where the
fire was and so they didn't discover the
the grow but you know but needless to
say that was kind of the beginning of
the end to that spot uh you know they
were we were getting complaints of
people in the building that were you
know like 20 stories up and they were
smelling weed because we were just
exhausting out we were on the bottom
floor and just exhausting out of a um of
a window and this is before uh charcoal
filters and all that stuff so we were
just you just had raw exhaust is going
up and the thing was it was like uh they
had like Courtyards and in these in
these buildings and so where the
buildings kind of like they all kind of
come together it almost becomes like a
shaft in between so and it just goes
straight up you know until it you know
but there's like a little space in
between you know the buildings and so
that's where we were pumping out of so
the people upstairs it was just it was
just shooting up so when they opened
their Windows you know they could smell
weed and I had a kid in the building
that that I used to sell weed to and
you'd be like yeah you know I know that
there's someone's growing weed in the
building because there's these these
Russian mobster guys are down on the
first floor he's like and I know I know
it's got to be them you know but you
know he didn't he didn't know it was
actually us that were that was doing it
so uh yeah uh so that was really you
know my first uh my first real
experience in in in in in in growing and
then and then after that you know that
was like a 99
uh you know that lasted like a year or
two and then I think and after that
ended you know it took me like a year to
get my [__] back together on my own and
I just wound up going uh Upstate uh New
York I rented out a house
um up by Hunter Mountain and and that's
where I had my first uh my own my first
Grill myself
and the people you know that I was
um you know and then by by this time you
know the the circle of Growers had had
evolved into you know a few more so the
circle had wide in Widen and
um you know I I told them like yeah I
want to start growing and they're like
all right we'll help you you know so
they helped me you know uh build my
first room you know uh you know did it
correctly the rate set up you know gave
me uh gave me Sour Diesel clones which I
had given them originally because you
know I was I was
selling the weed so you know I would be
like all right I know what streams sell
I know what people want you you do what
what I tell you if I give you these
clones you've grown and not it's gonna
it's gonna help us all so you know
that's what I ever you know that's what
I had started to do was getting you know
I started networking and I was able to
get the sour diesel and so I gave that
to them and then they gave it back to me
and that was one of the first strains
that I started growing uh well on my own
was the sour diesel and then um
and then eventually I wound up meeting
uh chem dog Greg and I wound up trading
him the sour diesel for the candy
and so uh and then when I first you know
and then once I got my own place you
know and I had been you know uh
selling weed all these years and
and like I was saying I would tell these
people what to grow
and uh
a lot of times
I'd be like you know we'd have certain
screens I'd be like well what happened
to this kush or this NM they'd be like
oh we lost it you know we don't have it
anymore I'd be like man that [__]
[__] you know I was good what happened
you know well whatever whatever reason
we lost it so once I started growing
myself and getting these Elite clones
that's when I decided I wanted to start
um in you know preservation and it was
really you know all right I got this
Sour Diesel and I was like all right now
you know the Clone only strain you know
so we don't have no there is no sour
diesel now so you know so I was just
like well you know I was just like well
I'm gonna make my own mail you know so
you know so I was growing the chemd you
know all these different scenes so I was
like well if I'm gonna make my own mail
I'm gonna use whatever the best weed the
strongest we read that I have you know
and back then it was the chem weeds so I
decided all right chemd is what I'm
gonna you know Beast my mail off of and
so you know and then I was like well
what are you going to use for a donor
mail
so I had a guy going to to uh Amsterdam
and I gave him you know a bunch of money
and I'm like you know get you know I
gave him a whole bunch of lists of
streams to get me from Scentsy seeds and
and that's what he did so he he comes
back and he had he had the Hindu Kush
the Afghan one
um skunk
NL a whole bunch of different ones but
you know I you know I was like no I'll
I'll have to grill these out to see what
they are how and how they grow so I I
grew all you know well really I just
grew the Hindu Kush and Afghan out
and decided that the Afghan would be a
better choice uh of a male donor because
it was uh it wasn't very dominant in in
taste and smell it kind of had like a a
Piney uh you know like a yeah like a
kind of like a Piney kind of um
I'm trying to think of the different
word to describe it but
um
yeah it wasn't really dominant you know
it was kind of blandish you know it it
grew really thick stemmed and single
Cola you know it's just a really big top
single Cola and so I decided you know
that would probably be the best you know
uh male donor for you know the cross
into the chemd and so that you know
that's what I did like I did the first
cross the Afghan candy and then I uh
back crossed into the uh chemd again and
made the double dog and then did the
third uh cross which would have been the
second back cross would would have made
the trade dog and so once I made the
trade dog you know I decided that you
know that that would probably be a good
representation of the chemd a good you
know strong male and so you know I
decided you know one of the first you
know breedings that I was going to do
um I had just gotten the chem four at
that time so I was like well you know
combine two different chems and see what
what happens
and you know that eventually became a
store dog and when I made those seeds
um you know I just wound up you know I
grew some out myself and found the
Quarry cut within the first I think I
only I only pop like maybe like 4 four
or five seeds and I found a quarry cut
and then I wound up
um giving some seeds to people that were
affiliated with high times and some of
the seeds got into the hands of Carl
Cushman he grew up the store dog found
his Fino keeper which he entered I think
it was in the San Francisco medical Cup
in 2010 in one second place with that so
that really kind of you know put the
star dog you know on the map people
started noticing it
um some some of the other seeds got into
um Andre Grossman he was a freelance
photographer who had a farm in New York
City he was affiliated with high times
and he held the and always grew the
strawberry cough and so that was Kyle
cushman's strain that he brought to High
Times and that became the the office
strain so at any time you know you could
used to be able to go down to the park
avenue office and they might even have
had a mother of the of the Strawberry
Cough in the office and you used to be
able to get clones from it and they
didn't have it there they had it like
really close by so you you used to be
able to go down there and be like you
know yeah I want some strawberry cough
and they would get it to you within an
hour or two
so Andre started growing in the guava I
mean a star dog and found a guava cut
and so uh he brought that into the
office and that also became an office
stream and accessible to people uh to
High Times and so
um when Andre started growing it you
know he started obviously taking
pictures of it they did a a centerfold
of it they did a write-up on it and
everything
and so uh getting back to the the
original guava thing so that that
cutting started getting out around town
and my friend who I had given the
original guava to wound up
getting that cutting and he calls me up
one day and he's like all excited he's
like I got it I got it back I got it
back I got the guava back and so you
know I first saw the guava from him not
knowing that it was my seeds that I had
given to uh you know so it was like a
whole
eventually it all came full circle and
we figured out everything and and that's
been kind of like the the the story of
of the chem dog and a lot of the stuff
that's been on the internet because a
lot of it has come full circle because a
lot of these people have popped up on
the internet and we've been able to
connect and we've been able to figure
out you know the chem dog story and you
know all of that now that's really
become Legend
wow what a phenomenal answer I think uh
everyone's gonna have to go listen to
that a few times you just hide so many
pieces of the puzzle together for me so
thank you so much I guess one of the
first questions and I'm gonna have about
a million questions for you I think I
read somewhere that you were involved in
being able to help reconnect peabut and
Joe brand with chemdog is that correct
yes it is originally
um
well my original
um interaction
with uh the internet was you know I was
sitting in my office one day and a guy
comes in he's like hey
he's like you see on the internet you
know where this guy is you know taking
credit for the sour diesel and you know
back then I wasn't very internet Savvy
or didn't really you know it wasn't
really really of my interest at that
time so
I wind up you know going on this site
called overgrow and I see uh this guy
res dog talking about
Sour Diesel
and I'm like Sour Diesel I'm like that's
that's us like and I'm like I I know
what you know the whole story you know
of you know I have all of this knowledge
and all this stuff so
you know um
you know and at that time I had been you
know I had been growing already a few
years and stuff so you know and then
that's kind of like when Soma came out
with the New York City Diesel which we
were you know quite offended by and
um so you know I I you know I decided to
you know to create uh an account and set
the record straight so you know that's
where you know I I I became uh JJ uh NYC
uh I logged on there and my very first
post was just this kind of a rant that
just kind of you know kind of set the
record straight and called out Soma and
you know people are kind of like shocked
by it and being like who the [__] are
you you know what I mean and so you know
eventually you know um
uh the you know the whole chem thing
started you know started out on over bro
and and all that and then um and then
and then it went down it got it got shut
down and you know I got all kind of
freaked out by it and I kind of dropped
offline for six months to a year
and you know and then you know decided
you know to pop back on and you know
found out that everyone had moved to
icmag
so you know I started you know uh
posting on I see mag and uh this was
probably right around the time that I
had gotten the chemd and
uh so you know I remember the you know
the very first time I I did a search on
chemdog and this guy this guy's account
popped up it was called Joe brand and he
made a post saying does anyone know
anything about
chem or dog or I feel what it was you
know I mean so
you know I started a whole dialogue with
him you know I mean and uh
yeah I mean eventually it just kind of
led to the you know
um
you know getting those guys back
together now we figured out the whole
you know I mean and you know when it was
coming you know when it was happening it
was you know it was really it was really
incredible to really you know start
piecing all that history together and
figuring out the puzzle
um so yeah I was able to you know we
figured out that you know it had you
know that you know that Greg had gotten
it was Greg and uh that Greg still had
some of those original seeds left and so
I had you know I hooked those guys up
and they reunited and and Greg wound up
sending uh Joe uh for the original siege
that he found in in that dog bud and
that wound up being the chem one two
three four
so yeah I was uh you know very
instrumental in in doing all all of that
yeah wow it's it's so impressive how
interconnected all the relationships and
stories are
if I could just go back a moment to when
you were talking about you know how the
the Staten Island crew first sort of
linked with mass G and all those sorts
of things I guess something I'd love to
ask you is what was your first
experience like when you first smoked
the camera 91
uh it was just kind of game changing
because we've never saw anything like
that you know and even like the super
skunk too I mean when you when you would
crack a jar of that super skunk it would
just it would just permeate the room it
was just something that you know it's
just something you just cannot find
today you know and so when people talk
about roadkill and all this other stuff
you know you know I I know what it is I
I experienced it you know it was
something at one time and why it's
changed and and it's gotten lost
um you know no one really knows the
reason why and a lot of it you know is
people you could say it's genetic drift
um you know and and which could be a
part of it uh I think it was really hard
for people to really hold on to a lot of
these genetics because they were so loud
so many people had gotten busted uh with
those genetics over the years and
um I mean yeah I mean if you if you
really think about it you know a lot of
the streams that we have today were are
really responsible
because they're one person you know I
mean if you look at the chem the cams if
it wasn't for Greg we wouldn't have the
cams you know if you look in and you can
go down a list of different strains that
people are associated with and enough so
if it really wasn't for those people who
who preserved and then shared them you
know we wouldn't have what we have today
so I mean you know we did have those
genetics were you know plentiful at one
time but unfortunately you know that was
during a time of of the drug war and
heavy prohibition
and a lot of that stuff just got snuffed
out unfortunately
yeah yeah it's a real shame isn't it and
I guess some of the more smelly stuff
before carbon filters is obviously just
logistically hard to sort of manage long
term I had a question or two about the
sour diesel for you that I was hoping
you might be able to shed some light on
back when around that time when you know
the sour first came out were people
running primarily just like one strain
in a room or where they're multiple
because I guess I'm trying to figure out
is it more likely that it was just an S1
or like some sort of cross pollination
and then as a little follow-up do you
accept the versions given by people like
weasel or vondo on say the Adam Dunn
show when they talk about the sour
diesel history or do you think it would
maybe went down a little differently to
what we see online
well I I do know you know what he you
know what what he was growing at the
time because I was selling it you know I
know that he had the 91
he had the um Mass Super Skunk uh he had
the RFK stuff I think he had the the DNL
and so you know uh you know that's you
know you know what you know I suspect
you know something in the room hermied
and got into the into the 91 obviously
and uh that's where the sour diesel came
from
now I mean there's a lot of speculation
on
you know is a super skunk is it DNA you
know or but you know the the one thing
that I can point to is
um
the skunk VA and he's very adamant and
I'm sure you're familiar with some of
his early uh Super Skunk photos that
kind of show big stretchy kind of sour
like plants
and
um
from what I remember in what's also
documented in High Times when they did
the
um photo shoot of the mass super skunk
and of the chem dog uh from Greg back in
the day that that plant was more of a
more medium squat plant you know the the
plant that that the the weasel had was
the same exact one that Greg had and I
mean I sold the butt of it I saw it grow
and it was not the big super stretchy uh
Fino that skunk VA
um
uh had so I don't know if it was the
same genetics I know that you know
um you know there's a whole different
story on that super skunk
um it was down in Virginia originally
um it I think that it yeah I think it
came there was a trade me the super
skunk came up from Virginia to
Massachusetts
and then the chem dog was picked up from
and brought out to California to skunk
VA and that was the 91. and so
um yeah I don't really know what if that
was a the a different Fino that they
gave him or what you know I know at that
time I think skunk VA was out in
California I think he set up the deal
with his friend
um so what was actually brought up and
traded I mean is anyone is anyone's
guess because I think there's a big
discrepancy between the super skunks
that Greg had and then the super strong
the skunk VA had because they were two
totally different genotypes I mean if
you want to do your research on Greg's
Mass super skunk and and you know find
out the characteristics of it you can
but you will find that it's not that
really tall stretchy sour like Fino that
skunkier had so
who's right who's wrong I mean we'll
never know I mean I mean I guess if you
can really get into some uh
sequencing and and stuff like that maybe
some of that stuff
could you know come out in the future
but you know uh you know it could to me
it's just speculation and I can only go
by with what I know in in new at the
time so
um I mean I have my doubts on it just
because I think they're they're two
different femos I mean I could be wrong
uh there's another a whole nother story
behind that which I don't know so I mean
there's more I guess there's more
investigating
um facts that need to come out you know
from I guess the Virginia for the
Virginia Beach Crew in Skunk VA
yeah look I think you might be on the
money there because when I've spoken to
skunk VA more recently he's sort of said
to me that now that he thinks back on it
the the skunk cutting he got back from
Greg years later he goes I was so
excited to have it back you know like
I'm like oh the super skunk's back and
he goes but now that I really think
about he goes I'm not sure it was the
same plan which is sort of what you're
saying that the plant Greg got might not
have been the original one skunk VA had
it's not
and so that's why and I and I S and I've
seen fianos that came out of that skunk
you know that that Underdog it was NL
Scott NL Super Skunk times 91 and that
was not a big stretcher it kind of grew
kind of kind of like the Kush but not as
stretchy uh it was more of the bud
structure it was more of a medium Stout
plant uh it didn't yield very well but
unfortunately
um that that Underdog uh we killed it
because of genetic drift uh it just
petered out after a while and we had the
original cut and it just changed I I
mean I I've seen it with different
strains over the years not only strength
strains that I've grown but strains that
I've sold you know and I can remember
the stuff the wheelchair used to be in
in the city and uh I mean the early
wheelchair was exactly that wheelchair
we I mean you would smoke that [__] and
you you were incapacitated uh towards
the end it just kind of gotten like
Bland and just kind of petered out and
so uh yeah I I've seen genetic drift in
in in strange just kind of just dud out
[Music]
foreign
part one of three done and dusted what
do you think
the major history lessons being dropped
on the East Coast scene there and huge
shout out again to JJ for taking the
time to come on the show and a huge
shout out to our amazing sponsors for
helping us to make the show happen see
here now best seed bank in the game go
hit him up for all the hottest drops
from all the Breeders you know you love
guarantee on satisfaction at the end of
the cycle not just guarantee on
germination why would you go elsewhere
likewise go check out proper biological
systems with all the most Advanced
Technologies these guys have got you
covered and will keep the passive back
check out the appip RM or the spydex
vital both of them incredible products
gonna help you overcome any infestation
you have or more importantly keep away a
potential infestation nothing better
than being proactive and getting on top
of a problem before it even exists guys
go check out pop it biological systems
incredible sponsors we really appreciate
them and last but not least Pro mix
connects your number one mycorizer
product in the game you know Pro mix
you've probably they're paid before
guess what they've got killer
mycorrhizal product now and if you check
it out I promise you your plants will be
better off for it no questions are
better resin better flavor better yield
you know mycorrhiza is fantastic got any
of the celery on it go check it out Pro
mix connect number one microrizer
product in the game
furthermore huge shout out to Charlie's
cannabis your number one family owned
small bats craft cannabis producer out
of Oklahoma providing you incredible
sizes chemical Sunset star Pebbles so
many more on the horizon check out their
Instagram to see what they've been
hunting at the moment I'm really excited
to have these guys on board I think
magical to see what they produce going
forward you need some high quality smoke
you're in Oklahoma go check out
Charlie's cannabis you'll be tough and
good I promise
finally a shout out to the patreon gang
I love you I appreciate you you are the
best if you want to get access to
unheard content Early Access to
interviews giveaways so much more go
check it out we recently got a Discord
guys I'm a bit late for the Discord
party but I tell you what I love it and
some good chats going on there be sure
to check out patreon if you want to help
support the show and ensure content
continues to be made
[Music]
that's it for part one guys I'll see you
back for part two and part three
thanks for hanging around
[Music]