thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast book
buddy
as always this episode was brought to us
by our phenomenal sponsors we could not
make the show happen without them please
go check them out and support them seeds
here now your number one shop for all
the best genetics all the hottest
breeders and a guarantee on satisfaction
not just germination why would you go
anywhere else they're promising you're
gonna have a good grow because they only
stock breeders they know and trust
likewise in order to evaluate your
genetics you need to ensure your plants
are of optimal health and happiness and
in order to do this we recommend you
check out our friends at coppet
biological systems they have all the
latest predators and Technology to keep
your garden happy and healthy exploding
with growth and achieving its clinical
performance please check out their
acuparam or their spidex vital to
phenomenal predatory Technologies
designed to be implemented in the
Cannabis setting that are going to help
your garden to remain happy healthy and
productive likewise check out our good
friends at promix with their phenomenal
product promix connect you now have
access to the highest quality
mycorrhizae available with more
guaranteed Spore count than any other
product you can ensure that your plants
are getting the highest degree of
nutrientucting mycorrhizal symbiotic
relationships and all of the benefits
that flow on from that including
increased yield increased resin
increasing Vigor growth right it's all
there you know mycorrhizae get the best
in the game promix Connect guys you
can't go wrong
finally shout out to our friends at
Charlie's cannabis these guys are the
best in Oklahoma family and Veteran
owned small bats craft produced flour
they're now producing their own rocket
free rolls as well as concentrates all
in-house single Source you can be sure
no materials passing from one person to
another no dodgy PM stuff going on here
just the absolute Pinnacle the small
scale craft produced product please
check out cut please check out Charlie's
cannabis if you're based in Oklahoma I
guarantee you'll be blown away with the
quality of their products
and last but not least the patreon gang
we love you guys so much thank you for
your support you truly helped make the
show happen if you would like to help
ensure that episodes continue to happen
please go over to the patreon
www.patron.com the podcast and consider
signing up in return you'll get early
access to additional content unheard
interviews giveaways Discord access and
so much more please check out the
patreon
on this episode guys we have the one and
only Ed Rosenthal the ganja Guru
the man who paved the way for many of us
and just an all-round lovely
knowledgeable guy to chat with Ed was
able to swing by talk about his newest
book that's dropping soon the Cannabis
Growers handbook as well as old history
culture law so much more
let's get into it
hello and welcome back to another
episode of the podcast and on today's
episode we are joined by one of the
biggest names in the industry a true
Pioneer who wrote the marijuana grow
guide back in the late 70s with Mel
Frank someone with a plethora of
publication since then including the big
book of buds series Beyond buds ask Ed
and so much more a huge welcome to the
guru of ganja Ed Rosenthal thank you for
joining us
thank you for having me
not a problem the first question I love
to ask our guests these days what have
you been smoking on recently
uh I've been smoking some G4 and then a
proprietary variety of a friend of mine
j27 that's pretty good as well that's uh
in fact that's my favorite it's a very
socializing and upbeat
and G4 tends to be that way as well
nice would you say that in general you
prefer more sort of uplifting varieties
over the relaxing ones
well you know uh uplifting and relaxing
are not mutually uh exclusive
so does something can be uplifting and
not make you nervous or paranoid and
those those are the kinds of uplifting
but you know everything depends upon
mood there are times if you want if
you're if it's evening you probably
don't want wouldn't want to smoke
something you know that's too uh upbeat
so you wanted something a little more
relaxing
and there are a lot of wonderful
indicators that have that one of the
interesting things about what you just
mentioned about your friend's
proprietary blend is it got me thinking
I read on your website recently you
wrote a nice article about Paradise
seeds and one of the things that stood
out to me was Scentsy star it was such
an amazing commercial hit and it was one
of those strains where they never
released the genetics behind it and it
got me wondering do you think that we're
going to see more things like what your
friends done where there's sort of
proprietary genetics
well there's a way of solving that
problem and there are these uh firms
that uh do genetic mapping so you could
send in a sample and they could place
where it is on this genetic map
so uh so those sent so low Paradise
hasn't released re released it anybody
could send in uh a sample of it and then
get see where it is on the genetic map
yeah certainly the technology today is
fantastic in that regard I guess more
from like the commercial success point
of view do you think that that sort of
thing would fly or do you think Growers
are so like pedantic about what am I
growing I want to know the lineage or do
you think like it could work
commercially
I think that it all depends where you
are and either the industry or the hobby
and
um do you really have to know the
progenitors if you have a high quality
uh but does it really matter to most
people I don't think so
yeah certainly a good quality bud is a
rain Supreme doesn't it you know what
else about good quality bites they're
more popular than any politician
whatever there's an initiative in in the
United States for for marijuana and you
see the politicians 58 46 or something
and even in Oklahoma the most
conservative State uh medical one by
seven seventy percent
that's why politicians hated it's more
popular than they are that's a good way
of viewing it I hadn't thought about
like that I like that a lot
so I I wanted you to take me back if
possible what was your first experience
with cannabis
uh you know that was a long time ago
and uh
what when I met cannabis within a very
short time I knew it was going to be a
great friend and Ally and that it would
be a long-term relationship
and it's lasted any of my uh my romantic
relationships
that's a good way to view it I like that
as well true friend
so when was it that you decided you
wanted to dedicate yourself and your
life to cannabis law reform and to just
cannabis in general well it was a
specific answer I was hitching
hitchhiking from Florida to
um my home in New York and I had in my
suitcase a bamboo pipe that uh we smoked
that somebody gave me and we smoked out
of once
and while hitchhiking I was picked up by
the police and they searched the
suitcase and they charged me with
possession and all kinds of other things
and um
we went to trial and the judge said to
the cop I don't want to ever see
a
I don't ever want to see a case like
this in this courtroom ever again
really wise judge and that was before
the drug war really was heading was
hitting its hardest so then um
I was leaving the Cardinal with my
mother and my aunt on either side of me
and the uh so the sergeant who arrested
me and who testified against me Sergeant
Edwards of Bowling Green Virginia
he's uh marijuana people have a lot to
thank him for well he came and stood in
the way of our path and she put out his
hand to shake hands with me or something
like that and I said to him
get out of my way Pig
and my aunt who's very polite person
said Eddie you shouldn't talk to the
officer like that and I said but NLC he
tried to put me in prison
for and she said she looked at the cop
and she said officer could you please
remove yourself from that path
but that was it
the making of an activist but I mean I
was activated before but not the way
that that got me
so yeah and you know and I really felt
that cannabis was an ally from the very
first time that I uh that I used it and
so um
I mean but he he uh he confirmed what I
should be doing
yeah I love that sentiment you know we
we all have a lot to thank that officer
for getting the the stone rolling on
that one so how did you progress from
that point up until you first started to
learn about growing and you sort of
thought to myself God I've got to write
about this
well I had always been interested in
Horticulture and had taken classes in it
when I was a kid
so I was not I was familiar with plants
and growing plants and growing plants
and doors
so
um cannabis was just another planet I
mean well
it is because it's a green plant and it
observes the same uh natural
uh laws that uh other green plants do
and so uh
so I had a spare bedroom in my apartment
and I decided to convert that spare
bedroom into a growth space and that's
how it started and then
I wanted to make little grow tents for
people to grow their own and I got some
publicity from the newspaper
no woman was in existence for a long
time called Village The Village Voice
and then at the same time they had an
article about how to grow by this other
uh uh
well they well um so they gave me a lot
of publicity and then I got some
publicity in Rolling Stone and at the
same time they had an article on how to
grow by another fellow and they asked if
we would like to meet and when he you
know we both decided to meet each other
and then we decided to write a book
about how to grow indoors
and that's what we did and then that
book was a great success
and after that book came out you know if
if you're success if you enjoy doing
something and you're successful at it
you tend to stay doing it so
and I really like being around the plant
and
being in in the whole movie every part
of that mail you around the plant
including and cultivation is a big part
of that
yeah hugely and I mean what a meeting of
the minds you know yourself and Mel
Frank one of the questions that was
really itching my brain when I was
thinking about our chat today was when
you were writing this book did you have
any sort of inkling that it was going to
cause this Mammoth you know change in
the scene and Inspire millions or did it
just seem like you know sort of the
average book
well
you know
um people's goals change and this was a
long time ago but I assured my author
that we would be able to make
about 200 a week each
which at that time
um was a lower middle class salary or
something
from writing that book and little did I
realize that it would be much more than
that
and that was the first book indoor
outdoor marijuana growers guy and it was
a it was a thin book and then we wrote
the thicker book the marijuana growers
guide that people recognize all the time
and that that book was um
that book was a huge success because it
uh
was more scientific than any of the
other books and had more substance to it
and so
um
I stayed on that half
yeah fantastic and out of curiosity back
you know when you were first writing it
what sort of strains were you growing
back then did they have names
well well we were in New York City it
was all either Colombian or Mexican or
Panama and it was all these Imports so
the first plants
um that I grew were from uh seeds in
imported marijuana
and the on the west coast there was more
of a culture and we became acquainted
with it when both of us moved Mel Frank
and I both moved to uh uh to
um first Berkeley then Oakland and that
was a different value
where there was already breeding going
on
and uh
uh the skunk band uh uh
uh
who is a fellow who invented skunk
number one and some other varieties he
was in the area as well
and 10 other people
yeah it sounds like you were in the hot
spot when you got to California
I'd be interested to quickly ask you did
you have any personal interactions with
Sam the skunk man he's a very mysterious
figure in the scene
yes
yeah yeah but now and I were good
friends with them and then when he moved
to um
uh when he moved to uh oh to uh
Holland we saw each other quite a bit
when I was over
I haven't seen him much in recent years
yeah yeah I think he has been a little
more active in the past than he is
recently
well if we fast forward a little bit
your newest book has just been released
the Cannabis Growers handbook which our
listeners can purchase from your website
at rosenthal.com so first of all huge
congratulations on the new book and
secondly what sort of topics does the
book go into what can people expect to
be able to read about
well it follows the template of the last
book of marijuana growers handbook
but it goes it covers things in a
different way for instance um it covers
light in terms of uh the uh Radiance of
the light you know how how intense it is
in terms a more scientific terms and
before for instance indoors we would say
a 60 watts or 600 watts or so many watts
but but instead of using an input
measurement for instance we use uh the
actual light measurement and then there
everything about the book has been
upgraded and we have uh we have a lot on
different ways of growing sustainability
uh changes and you know changes in
scientific thought it's it's not like it
was updated it was totally Rewritten
it's a major difference now
yeah what a fantastic answer I was gonna
actually ask you that question you know
what was the difference between the
Cannabis Growers handbook and the
marijuana growers handbook but there you
go you answered it for me a perfect
segue into the next question is that you
know many technologies have evolved over
the time since your first book was
published in the late 70s and I think in
recent years most notably the lighting
technology has really come a long way
with the Advent of LEDs and whatnot
what's your preferred lighting Source at
the moment or do you prefer outdoor
I like to grow so uh
um it you know it depends on the area
for instance I'm helping some people in
Jamaica and for and a lot of the
companies there
um are using greenhouses all the time
and I don't think that
that that's as useful as mostly growing
Outdoors
in that situation but then if you're up
in Canada if in order to extend the
season you're going to want to grow on a
greenhouse on the other hand I know
people who grow outdoors in the Arctic
and they have about 95 days of uh
favorable weather and they uh they grow
within that period of time they they
start indoors they used to start indoors
and put plants out I think they still do
but now they're using autoflowers which
makes their life a lot easier
but so you have to you have to there's
one has to look at what the situation is
if
whether you have space Outdoors whether
you have Greenhouse space indoor space
but whatever you know growing is is a
lot of fun and also
you know I've mentioned this before and
it's in the last book in this book that
it is a warning that using marijuana may
not be habit forming but growing it's
addictive
and so anybody who just puts that seed
in the ground soon enough they'll be
addicted and they'll always have a plant
in their life
here here I can I can certainly vouch
for that on a personal level very
addicting indeed and heck it's a one of
our other guests said uh cannabis is a
gateway to just gardening in general so
I thought that was cool too that's true
you know I I've met a number of people
who uh they started with uh cannabis and
then uh before you know it they were
working and what uh agricultural area or
another not necessarily uh with cannabis
but you know what kind of you know what
marijuana is a gateway drug too
well hash
hash
that's a good one I hadn't heard that I
like that but but you know in New York
City
uh uh you know where they have well all
over the United States is this big
opioid problem but in New York City they
said that if you have a prescription for
opiates any kind of well-being you can
use it to go to a marijuana dispensary
so you know how they used to say
marijuana you'd see these hard drugs
well what they're saying now is if you
have hard trucks how about trying pot
so
I like that a lot that's good that's
good but it's true you know that
the weirdest thing right we do that all
along right we knew that
everybody had known people who had
serious drug problems who saw them but
with marijuana but but the
um the
um medical professionals just could not
they they just couldn't tolerate that
you know
give them give them some kind of pill
that's addictive instead you know that
their policy oh no that's not addictive
but you better take it every day
yeah it's quite shocking when you read
about some of the early you know farmer
reports about the uh you know opioids
like percocet and all that and they were
like oh it's just it's not addictive
well um
you know the the people who perpetrated
that their corporations are coming to
agreements to pay back a lot of the some
of the money that they I feel that they
stole from the American people but the
problem is that the the people who
perpetrated it the handling it
corporately and they should be handling
it as a criminal matter and these people
knew that a certain percentage of their
uh of their victims would die from it so
they should be charged with with some
sort of homicide or murder charge
and you know what any district attorney
in the United States could do it they're
not bound to any agreements that the
government they they could just charge
any of these people criminally and see
and see where that goes
I mean if you put
like you would think
in both Australia and the United States
it's a serious criminal penalties for
for murder right but is it not for
executives is that it they gotta get out
of freak out I don't think they should
yeah hugely hugely and I I was thinking
to myself even if they pay adequate
compensation whatever that is who knows
that there's still yeah this this
pandemic of people addicted to opioids
and like how do you clean that up it's
it's a tough one but I guess while we're
on the topic of sort of drugs and the
effect on society I'd be interested in
hearing your opinion on it seems as
though Federal legalization of cannabis
in the United States is becoming a
possibility I know that there's been
some back and forth from Biden as to
whether he wants to do it but I guess in
general you could say it looks like
we're getting closer to the War on Drugs
at least for cannabis ending do you see
that in the future or do you think it's
still too hard to say
hmm
well I
you know in the year 2000
um
the uh the cat the Democratic president
the presidential candidate
um
who use pot
we're familiar with pot went to Grateful
Dead concerts with his wife
right said that marijuana had no medical
use
and uh of course he lost
and uh then
uh Clint uh Hillary Clinton refused to
endorse cannabis on any level like
saying well maybe we should investigate
medical use and you know she won lost by
a few votes supposedly she she would
have
uh she would have won if she had just
said we should have you know we should
legalize medical use federal
so there's no reason to believe that the
Democrats won't shoot themselves in the
flood again by refusing to
to go positive on the issue now they
have on a local level but not on a
national level
and basically it seems to mean
everybody's predicting tremendous losses
for Biden and the only way out of it is
marijuana legalization
it saw so many people's problems you
could solve the problems of the
Democratic Party
um
yeah hugely hugely and hopefully we can
see that happen in the coming years I
just want to look back for a moment a
few questions ago you were talking about
you know people in the Arctic with
limited time frames for growing and just
in general you know people in sort of
more specific grow environments we've
had guests in the past talk about how
autoflowers might be a good solution to
some of these interesting climates that
have short windows of you know favorable
weather and whatnot do you what's your
thoughts on Autos in general and do you
think we're going to see them
increasingly become more popular
well they uh when I was talking about
the audit that's what people were using
because if they didn't use autoflowers
they would have had they were growing
some acreage if they weren't using
autoflowers they would have had to do
light deprivation and that would have
been arduous and costly
and so
you know I I've never
smoked in Autoflower that I knew was an
Autoflower that I thought was a super
duper
hi
but
um I think that they would be very good
for concentrates
and uh
and let's see something or nothing let's
see
so I could have something that's okay
you know that I could concentrate or I
could have nothing
let's see
it's a hard one there
that's that's interesting you you raised
that question because one of the it's
sort of not related to orders but that
underlying principle is at play we're in
Australia where being given this medical
system which for a long time was very
restrictive and non-functional at all
but basically the idea is
you're never going to be able to grow at
home they're just not going to allow it
but you can buy like sort of mid-tier
products from one of the registered
dispensaries like it's not a dispensary
they're just producers and you get the
bud from the pharmacy so the question
sort of becomes
do you see that right to grow yourself
in order to get access to the mid-tier
government stuff or do you hold out and
sort of grow your own and be like no I'm
not making that compromise like I want
to be able to grow at home where would
you sit on that one
if there hadn't been home Growers
violating the law
in the United States so I would never
have changed
so
I think that people in Australia should
take a hint from them and overgrow the
government
as much as the government tries to Stamp
Out you know and nsw
although they try to stamp it out and
they have those campaigns and everything
but they seem to supply Sydney okay so I
mean it's the equivalent of Humboldt
here in California
now here's the thing but it becomes
legal those people on nimbin will be
sadly disappointed because
that's not really an agricultural land
and it's very tropical and has very high
humidity so it's not the ideal place to
grow and so I think that
um what's happened in the United States
is more of it it's growing when it's
being grown Outdoors it's being grown on
agricultural land
I I went uh I met a fellow in nambion
who uh took me up to his garden that was
in um in one of the national parks in
nsw and it was a joint you know his
route was exhausting it was just I mean
totally exhausting and he'd have 10
plans here and 20 plants out and he
figured that even if the government saw
other plants they weren't going to
Grapple down you know down from a
helicopter to get them so
that totally changes with legalization
and one negative thing about
legalization is this that as it is now
to to a great extent the money stays in
the commit within the community
you know you're buying a good part of
that community of consumers and small
time dealers and Growers and you know
do you have more commonality than that
maybe
um you have a cultural commonalities
also but what's happened in the United
States and Canada is that it's become
legal they've become billionaires from
this many the number of billionaires so
obviously the money is falling out out
of the community I mean it's a larger
community so you're getting more middle
class people into it but still there's
money flowing out of that you know that
money isn't circulating as much so
that's a negative sign in legalization
and so somebody asked me well how do you
deal with that and I said oh it's simple
make it illegal
so Creative Solutions yeah I like it I
like it I mean on the topic of
legalization
um you know since recreational laws have
passed in the states we see a wide
diversity and volume of clones being
swapped and traded certainly more so
than back you know in the the prop 62
days or 64 days one of our Canadian
guests who was on the show recently
Kevin Cullum he commented on how since
there's all this trading of clones and
genetics he's certainly noticed an
increase in the emergence of the
Cannabis specific aphid and I guess I'm
sort of wondering from your point of
view do you think that Growers need to
be quite mindful of the fact that with
this increase in volume of genetic
material being traded we could very well
inadvertently generate more cannabis
specific pests and things that are more
resilient the more milder forms of pest
treatment
well that's happened the the some of the
new races of
of uh
powdery mildew you know a much more
dangerous and for all the races of it
and I think that either cannabis
specific or may have evolved on on I
think they transferred from pots to
cannabis and then now they've gotten
more very young and yeah the rush at
night and that you know
that that I'm not saying it's specific
to cannabis but it really
feasts on it and so um that is that
always happens it's you know as I said
well when you're dealing with the plant
issue of cannabis it's just like any
other plant the problem with the same
rules and that's going to and same thing
in the industry there's no way to stop
the spread of these uh
of these
diseases and pests parasites
yeah so I mean you just touched on it
you know things coming from hops The Hop
latent virus is like a very you know
popular sort of buzzword in the
community at the moment I think I read
an article that said it has knocked off
like up to a billion dollars off the USA
market value over the past few years
just due to like plants underperforming
from it and whatnot
how do you think we overcome what is
sort of comparable to like the covert of
plants like do you think there's a risk
it could ramp up to pandemic proportions
where like just all plants have it or do
you think it's probably not that serious
you could become serious I I don't
really know that much about it about
uh that particular thyroid but I think
that
um
we talked for to develop plants with a
resistance providers
much harder than let's say to fund yes
or
certain bacteria
so it's very it's very serious it also
depends how
um how
uh
how uh effective it is at
um
spreading
I have it
although uh people Outdoors
I know that a number of phones have
really suffered from and I don't know
what the solutions yeah there isn't you
know it's not like a fungus where you
can say oh spray this or do this or
practice a different cultural technique
as well as you know that but you know
you can be living in clean healthy life
and still get
a virus right okay
I know that I I there are people that I
know who said oh I'm you know taking
good care of myself and
um avoiding any way of getting it in
multiple means in ICU for six weeks
so you know but he up until the point
where we got it he was sure that he
would be able to resist it because of
his helpful lifestyle
and I don't think viruses respected
in humans or in plants
yeah certainly some some wise words to
heed there I mean if we just talk about
General pests and pathogens I I see in
all the growth stores I go to your Zero
Tolerance product which is you know
really good General strategy for Pest
Management I'm wondering what are some
of the general strategies you advocate
for Growers to help keep just general
bugs at Bay
well it's it's um you know it's
isolation strategies especially indoors
because in indoors and greenhouses once
in an insect or a disease gets in there
there isn't the uh
the natural resistance that nature
provides in that situation
so
I'll show the main uh main things I
would do is you prevention method which
is isolating the the growing area and
the cultural area from the rest of the
world and that's done through the you
know there are a lot of things first of
all change of clothing and spirit Nets
uh having people in actually in the
garden and as little as possible so if
you have a garden technique which
requires constant Care by humans we
might consider getting a different
technique because there's a good
possibility when something occurs that
it's occurred because of it was carried
by humans and then you know of course
isolation of uh
um isolation of any new plants coming in
uh you know uh if you're importing plans
um also uh preventative spraying
um then then we get to the point of uh
uh when I say spraying I'm not
necessarily talking about pesticides as
much as with beneficial bacteria
beneficial fungi and then um uh through
inspections all the time isolating any
plants that that seem to be diseased get
getting rid of any plants that are
performing well let's take it
you know every once in a while you get a
plant in Australia you can thrive
removing
don't don't wait to see how it does in
three weeks
so um
those are some of the similar things
fantastic and I've got a bit of a tough
question that I give to all our guests
because I think the answer is we're
still looking for an answer but if
someone came to you and said hey look
I'm in week five of flower and I've just
noticed a pest infestation what sort of
strategies do you think people can use
in those situations or do you feel like
it's a bit too far and anything you do
is going to be pretty detrimental to the
crop
well it depends what the test is
you know it really depends what the
question is uh and it depends um the
second thing is it depends how uh
widespread the past is you know within
the how big a population is next so it
might just remove a few plants
if it's in a very specific area you
might want to move a few clouds or uh
and um
then
um there might be you might be able to
use some sort of bacterial or fungal
spray against the breasts
uh that's another possibility I will I
wouldn't
um advise on
bringing in
bringing in uh beneficial uh insects or
other creatures like that because
they'll they usually take too long to
develop but the population where they
can handle the uh the past so
um I would go with um
with uh so also washing you know it's
like let's say you were week six or
something you may be able to
um and you see your population you might
be able to watch the population off
that's thank you you know it's not going
to eliminate it but it's going to bring
down the stress on your plant
yeah really really great words there
that's something which I've always say
to people myself you know people always
buy predator bugs and I'm like before
you release I'm like just try to get a
damp cloth and like wipe off the
majority of the bugs you can see right
like it's only gonna help
but I guess yeah not not as commonly
known as maybe we might expect well
especially Outdoors you know if you're
it's a sunny day outdoors and you have
mates you know the best thing that you
know you're not going
if you have a lower population to
control it's easier to do it so the
first thing to do is to get as much as
many of them off as possible
you know get rid of you know and uh also
I didn't mention herbal sprays like zero
tolerance but but herbal sprays are
pretty good they'll knock down the
population not
nothing eliminates you're not going to
eliminate your problem with that problem
but you are going to get it under
extreme control
and in a lot of greenhouses that are
that are open you know they're
constantly getting reinfested from
outside especially in mid-summer and
admitting late summer so uh so people
might take preventive reaction for
instance
um
uh people I know use uh take to zero
take zero tolerance and dilute it down
and filed it into greenhouses a couple
times a week
and that also repels your insurance
yeah some great advice there
so if we change topics for a moment I I
really enjoyed reading your Beyond buds
book a few years ago at the time I
remember thinking this is really sort of
groundbreaking because there really
isn't another mainstream book for
Growers to learn more about concentrates
and like the very finest specific points
you touch on you know producing and
consuming them it got me wondering
overall are you more of a flower guy or
a concentrate guy
um
you know
gee I love cannabis so much uh
uh it's the quality of the product
so I I don't like low quality
concentrates nor buds but love the high
quality behind
that's that's a good answer I really
like that one and as a follow-up we've
seen a lot of uh rise of uh the common
consumer I.E people who don't live and
breathe cannabis but maybe just enjoy it
every once in a while there's been a
really big uptake of this sort of
consumer especially around the use of
like vape pens really easily accessible
devices like that and it has me thinking
where do you see the future of cannabis
consumption going across the whole
population do you think we're going to
see more concentrate style ingestion or
flowers will always be Supreme
I
think that it will float back and forth
um
with different both with with different
Technologies and just Trends you know
but
people always like novelty so if you
have if there hasn't been much action
with uh but at some point people will go
back to it you know everything
everything life is retro
no I'm not just talking about
but you know but something about
life
everything repeats
with a little bit of change
yeah isn't that the truth
so one of our viewers submitted
questions was they they wanted to know
uh do do you still combust cannabis
these days I think a lot of people as
they get a bit older they they move away
from combustion and look at that right
on cue he hits a hammer I love it
why would people do that when they can
take comic damage I mean why would
people you know
burn cannabis I just can't understand
how people would do that
laughs
uh look it was like you were ready for
that one you hit it out of the park
that's brilliant that's brilliant
so likewise if you check out Ed
rosenthal.com you can see there's a
really touching tribute to Frenchie
cannoli who sadly passed away not too
long ago and it really got the brain
juices flowing for me and I was thinking
is this the last true hash Pioneer we're
gonna see you know a lot of people talk
about the the fine hash Market becoming
harder and harder to find good quality
products in do you think Frenchie might
have been the last of the true hash
pioneers
well
I think that um
the market
will determine what
products are out there that that
you know it's not it's not theoretical
when when people are at the counter they
make a conscious decision about what
they they like and so you know as with
any consumer product the trends go one
way then they go the other way and they
go back and forth
okay
so I think that you know
there'll be a market there'll always be
a market for telling a certain house
and when there's a market there'll
always be somebody there who is willing
to make it
and I think that he did lead the way in
many areas he had left a lot of videos
and uh he did leave with appreciation in
people for fine quality houses
hugely hugely
and I mean while we're on the topic of
the market one of the common discussions
I'm having with a lot of smaller Growers
at the moment is how they feel like with
the opening up of new markets like say
Oklahoma for example as well as just the
existing markets growing really feels to
them like there's a bit of a race to the
bottom in regards to pricing and a lot
of them are getting quite concerned
about how they will continue to to make
a livelihood from this if price has
continued to go down do you have any
advice for people who might feel like
they're in that position well
I want to take it in another way I think
it's really good that prices are down
for the consumer I think and frankly I'm
more interested in the consumer than uh
big corporations and
um as far as prices being down well you
know the only reason prices were up was
because of the risk factor factor
dealing with
um uh dealing with uh the legality of of
the product so that so farmers who were
growing it were making an economic
profit from that risk factor and that
that risk factor uh
you know that that was like a price
support system for instance let's say
you know Australia the government said
it was going to fire bomb one wheat farm
one refund and all of us right all the
farmers would get out a week wouldn't
they
weed prices would go up right
so anybody who was still in wheat would
be doing pretty well
well some marijuana Farmers had that for
40 years
so
they were being one way or another they
were being paid for the risk they were
taking not just for their farming
ability
so you ever hear any songs about how
wonderful it is to be a farmer or are
they all laments
sadly no
you know like
yeah and you know the foreign
so nobody said marijuana farming has to
be profitable
and frankly what I'd like to see is some
of the big corporations doing the
farming to see when they really have the
metal to to do it whether the people
that they hire really have the ability
to grow quality product or not and in a
free market like that so I think that a
lot of the big corporations were looking
left behind
yeah yeah look I can understand that and
hopefully with that scale you know they
can sort of bring the price point down
and make it accessible I guess as a sort
of general question I'd be interested to
hear your thoughts on whether you felt
the change from the old medical system
to the new recreational system in
California has been an overall net
positive or do you feel like there's
been pros and cons
well the big net positive is fewer
people in jail
and but by any
uh by any measure that
any any way that you want to measure it
that's in that positive that has to make
it net positive could it be could it be
a better system it could be but here's
the other part of it
being sold in California it's estimated
or more than half of it
is
not coming from
registered funds
so the reason why prices have gone down
so much in California is this
that for instance
you know Mendocino and Humboldt
marijuana it's outdoor marijuana and
it's grown in an area where the weather
is not
really agricultural weather not in the
way that you really like it so indoor
and uh and Greenhouse marijuana
is considered by most Californians who
Preferred Quality so most of the humble
material travel of East that's why
how about got such good reputation of
people in New York
to Californians oh look I have some
beautiful Humboldt weed and you know the
California we go here and say well uh
why don't you try some of this instead
you know and uh because uh and so the
humble it was like explore quality like
it couldn't be sold in California so we
have to export it so now
all that weed
um you know now that New York is legal
and Massachusetts and you know all of
these states were formerly illegal where
in which the California pot was filling
uh filling the surprise sign well now uh
people can grow their own or and you
know corporations and flowers are
getting into it so there's not as much
market for the Humboldt weed and that's
why those humbled and Mendocino weep
that's why those prices have fallen
precipitously
so
um
you know
it's a problem but
you know nobody said that you have to
make a living I mean
farming for most farmers who are not
following cannabis sometimes it's a
pretty rough road and with legalization
in the normalization of cannabis I could
see that because uh
like prices are falling when you do you
have gun control over it so it's a
marketing
yeah I think sometimes people are quick
to lose sight of the fact that yeah the
trade-off is less people in jail and
that is undeniably a net positive no
questions there there's a lot of people
get to use it because not everybody
knows somebody who can give them
marijuana and also
medic it's really good for medical users
because they might want something
specific and even
um well even if you grow your own
Tomatoes you might buy some Tomatoes
once in a while
that's true isn't it very few people are
entirely self-sufficient even with the
crops they grow
well sort of an extension of this topic
is the the generalization uh or maybe
you could even call it gentrification of
the Cannabis industry it's it's a
persistent topic that comes up on our
show the idea of how the industry is
being morphed to cater more to the
Casual Enthusiast as opposed to in the
past where you could maybe argue it was
more for the Growers and the hardcore
enthusiasts and I guess this is most
evident by going to dispensaries you see
there's a lot of sort of mid to low tier
Brands not as many high tier Brands
anymore and even some of the events like
the emerald cup which are sort of
Shifting to be more of like a half Music
Festival half cannabis festival and not
just about breeders selling seeds for
example do you feel this shift yourself
and do you have any thoughts on how this
might play out long term for the
hardcore cannabis community
well I think that that Community is
served by uh independent dealers right
so it's not it's not that
uh it's not that that product is now and
it isn't that people who want it aren't
getting it it's at the dispensaries and
shops are catering more to people who
don't have connections and who are
casual users but the the heart for you
know the chronic users they're usually
going to Independent dealers because if
they're buying because your product is
so much cheaper
you know a few grams every month or
something but if you're using
uh 10 grams a day then price does matter
yeah hugely I mean another related topic
that gets brought up in these same
conversations is how the market is more
largely becoming dictated by the
cannabinoid percentage numbers
especially the idea that a larger number
is synonymous with better quality do you
think we need to move away from this and
how might we try to do that well in
California uh most dispensaries that I'm
required to unless the threatening
percentages and so that's been some of
the major factor both the both the um
the cannabinoids white cannabinoids are
in there and the Terrapins so people are
looking at it more politically
yeah hugely hugely and I will touch on
terpenes in in just a moment I just had
one final question around that which was
do you think that the labs are being
honest when they give their testing
results because we're starting to see
results that are you know really high
30s low 40 percent cannabinoids for like
a flower sample and it makes me wonder
like there's this huge variability do we
just need to get a standardized testing
model or are some of the labs maybe not
quite being as truthful as we might hope
well I think there's been I think
among the people that I know who do
testing I think that they want to
produce accurate results
but I think more standardization is
required
yeah certainly certainly
so recently we've seen the re-emergence
of some really old school genetics
coming really to the Forefront of a lot
of modern breeders palettes they're
looking to work with things like the nl5
haze with the skunk even the pure Haze
for example do you think these varieties
are really as good as the current ones
or maybe a bit of Rose shaded glasses at
Play
there's two complex a question it
doesn't seem like a good thing but
answering it gets really sticky so to
speak because
there's one thing that uh that I'll
mention
that years ago
you would sometimes
there'd be a bag of cannabis that was so
fragrant it would
smell up the room and you remove the
Cannabis from the room you open up the
windows and that
odor was still there for a while
I haven't experienced anything like that
in more than 10 10 15 years
there you go that's maybe a hint
but you know you speak with with older
cannabis shoes you ask them if they've
ever had that experience and they'll
tell you that in
you know before the turn of the century
they've had they had that exposed
experiences
that experience you mentioned we we hear
other people talk of similar events
specifically often related to the
roadkill skunk have you ever smelt what
you think is the roadkill skunk
well there are a lot of variations on it
but yeah where it's actually spunky
yeah I mean something more
uh people from
um uh the Americas would be familiar
with in
Australians or people in Europe but yeah
that's right I
discussed Scouts come visit my
um
my garden at night every night
there you go no not right now but you
know just forever
but uh shots of Parsons that you know
that's uh more like so many uh animals
that you have with my Superior in the
apartment
and uh
raccoons you don't have raccoons you
know but I you know they they've made
their peace they're living in cities now
you know
they figured out how to do it
yeah they're smart are they they've
adapted yeah
while we're on the the topic of terpenes
you know as you alluded to a little
earlier terpenes are becoming a more
focal part of what people are looking
for in high quality cannabis however
from my point of view it still feels
like there's a fairly large ambiguity
around the language we use like I might
call it sweet you might call it floral
do you think we need to try to get some
sort of standardization and if so would
it be of any benefit to customers or not
really
well I think better than that would be
an actual test
that would you know so people wouldn't
have to rely on them support
and um and as I said in dispensaries and
uh and stores in the U.S now uh that I
mean in California they listed the
turkeys and the percentages so and
people are becoming more familiar with
the effects of different track meetings
so it is uh presenting that information
um is useful to the knowledgeable
consumer
this one might be a little bit left of
field to answer but I've had discussions
with people in the past and we're trying
to figure out what is it that makes a
certain strain feel the way it does one
of our past guests said you know I've
got a an Afghani that's 20 THC and a tie
that's 20 THC and they largely smell the
same both sort of mango smelling but
obviously one feels like a very sedating
sort of feel one feels very uplifting
and it begs the question you know what
is It ultimately in your mind that makes
us feel like a cannabis is a thin Leaf
variety or a broadleaf variety do you
have any thoughts on that one well it's
like yes you know your friends who have
those two varieties that smell the same
so that the chemistry producing the
mango owner
was probably masking other other
that causes different effects
and that's what I say the only way to
really
[__] well what's in it is to test it
hmm
yeah certainly
and I mean while we're on the topic
I feel like the Instagram platform
itself has done huge huge work in terms
of getting cannabis out to the consumers
at least in Australia I feel like a lot
of people realize there's really good
quality Bud out there just from seeing
it on Instagram and being like Oh that's
possible the trade-off though is that on
Instagram things can look really good
but you can't smell them or smoke them
so you can really only go off the
visuals and some people criticize this
and say you know it's caused things to
shift to things that look good but maybe
don't necessarily have the terpenes to
back it up have you noticed anything
like this
well
I'm not really in the um
in the buyer mode
so so I don't get as affected by things
like that
perhaps so I might not be the right
person to answer
no understandable I it's probably been a
long time since you've had to purchase
some cannabis
foreign
in Holland
that's a few years ago and uh with a
friend we were temporarily out and we
went into Greenhouse coffee shop and you
know we spent about
I don't know fifty dollars and we got
this little bag and the two of us
started laughing
uh but it was just really that that's
fifty dollars
there you go times are changing my my
final question sort of related to
Instagram is that in the past two years
or so we've really seen a big clamping
down of Instagram on cannabis related
businesses sometimes even Banning their
accounts
and it feels as though the platform
itself of Instagram is quite vital to a
lot of Brands it seems like it would be
hard to exist without it so my question
is how do we navigate this space given
we're so heavily dependent on it but
they're also not necessarily looking to
play ball with us as an industry
well Amazon said that they're not
testing their employees for pot anymore
well maybe the maybe the uh people uh on
the
Department of Transportation maybe truck
drivers or something but in general
they're not going to
test their workloads so isn't that one
step away from saying Amazon is going to
deliver
so
um and so Amazon does that then what's
instant Instagram going to do
so I think they're all going to perform
online but but you know those companies
have had
um you you know that they uh earn a good
part of their living either off of drugs
or or porn and yeah you know the show uh
straight at least about especially about
drugs it's it
you know if they had uh given a little
more support to legalization we would be
much further ahead than me on that
it's really a shameful to you know it's
natural that they
should join you know to tell make it
legal all over but but then we've been
doing that
yeah as soon as this body to be made
they want to get in on it yeah I can
understand that
so as legalization rolls out worldwide
over the coming years do you think that
we'll see more institutes like the
oaksterdam university sort of pop up
around the world
oh yes and I think that there are a few
other
universities like that there's one in
Colorado and I don't know where others
are but there might be one in Michigan
but also
um
uh colleges and universities are opening
up degrees in there so UC Davis which is
perhaps your best agricultural School in
the country
UC Davis has a curriculum in Canada so
that so that's that's going to happen as
well
and
so now here's what is we hope that they
use this particular growth as their
textbook
cannabis Growers handbook that
and uh it just came out we're shipping
it out to people who pre-ordered
so
there it is
I don't think you could go wrong if
that's your prescribed textbook yeah I I
think it will be because you know we we
had the three co-authors but we also uh
uh we collaborated with for specific uh
areas
Hydroponics
nutrients
air air quality we we uh we collaborated
with University with a lot of professors
University professors and people in the
industry so there are three authors
listed there were probably 30
people who uh also put contributions
into both
it's more than one person's opinion
yeah it sounds sounds quite
comprehensive which is always reassuring
I mean on the question of sort of
getting into growing a bit I'd be
interested to hear what sort of style of
growing do you like to do and what do
you advocate for are you an Organics
person assaults or is it just not really
meaningful
oh uh
you know really depends on the situation
but uh for instance uh
this year uh well for the past few years
I've been growing all my tomatoes uh
hydroponically and I really like uh I
live really like Hydroponics of growing
for indoor and some Greenhouse
situations because uh you can
there are two things about it uh that
not dealing with the crop or the yield
but the input one is that it really
conserves water tremendously the amount
of water used to produce an ounce of
cannabis goes way down when we grow
hydroponic when you're growing in a
sustainable hydroponic system
and then the the other part about it is
that
um
uh it's very change you can change
you can change the situation really
quickly with it for instance when you go
from vegetative to flowering it becomes
very easy to do that when you have a
hydroponic system and they're very easy
to shut up
and uh they appreciate music and you
know
as I said I've been growing hydroponic
tomatoes and
uh
people love them so
proof's in the Tomato yeah and I have
this theory about cultivation which is
this so you know uh
so basically
during its lifetime the plan allocates
your carbon that it captures from the
air you know it captures carbon dioxide
that's your carbon that contains your
carbon and then it allocates its use so
let's say
um so if let's say you look at a plant
and if the plant has grown uh all these
branches and leaves and everything well
in terms of calc carbon allocation for
the yield we're looking at we're not
harvesting the branches or the leaves
we're harvesting the buds right
so
um what percentage of the carbon is
going to blood production and what
percent is growing to plant
infrastructure
and so when you look at that you realize
that if you grow small plants that don't
have much infrastructure but for
instance single stem plants
then a much higher percentage of the
carbon that the plant is allocated is
using is going to bug production and so
and the plant spends a greater
proportion of its time in in bad
production is compared with vegetative
production so really into growing these
small plants really close together
and one way to do it you know like let
it you know like lettuce wraps
growing in like like they were single
stem plants on lettuce wraps and then
won't be about 65 centimeters
tall when they're done with no branching
and so the other advantage of that is
that there's very low
very small amount of
um of manicuring
so that's a money saver as well so
that's industrial that's how I like to
grow plants
so interesting I mean the the sea of
green method you know really proven
itself over the years as far as I could
tell there wasn't a ton of people still
really doing it do you think it's
something that's going to get more
popular
well uh my writing partner uh Rob
Flannery we we uh have been doing a
little bit of future we're planning to
do a little bit of Consulting on that
and we think that
um the problem for it is you need a
really skilled
um manager and uh not so much staff but
but management and Excellence SLP so
that everybody knows what's happening
because there's a lot of action in that
because you have the
um if
if you're growing clones which most
farmers will do then you need a large uh
you either have to have a good cold
supplier well you have to have a large
um
mother room to produce your clothes and
a lot of action in that room and most
most farmers
they don't understand it
they just even though they might have
done sea of green you know in a smaller
setup they can't see it expanding it you
know when they upscale but I I think
that's the way to go
yeah maybe I'll watch this space sort of
thing
yeah well um you know there there are
companies you know that are doing it and
it's just an incredible system for them
because
um they don't have they don't have any
uh plant care during the vegetative and
flowering Foods what's what they set the
plan they don't have to do anything
so as compared with you know people that
go deleafing and all of that and the
reason that they you know and uh a lot
of that even if you were delicious what
you wouldn't have to do as much of it
this with this system is relatives and
it's faster
yeah it'll be really interesting to see
that sort of come to life more so if we
fast forward to the other end of the
grow cycle when you're harvesting I
remember a discussion I had with someone
for a long time was they uh they read
your books and they were like oh did you
know that Ed says you should uh you
should wet trim and I said oh I didn't
know if I'd read that I'd be interested
to hear you know do you believe wet
trimming is better than dry trimming do
you fall one way or the other or do you
think it's sort of situationally
dependent
well it depends it situationally
dependent uh certainly it's easier to um
take your if if you've
um if you've um it's easier to run uh
but uh through uh some of the trimming
machines when they're wet although they
do have a
they do have other models but the thing
is when you trim when you drop when it's
dry you have more brittle rest of the
crumb of the trichomes so that you're
going to have more forward from tritone
to draw each other
yeah there's certainly sort of pros and
cons in each situation isn't it but you
know uh
the way that you uh the way that you um
uh dry and and cure has a significant
uh effect upon your
um the the amount of uh terpenes that
are present at the end and the
method that
um that seems to be most effective seems
to be uh
uh freeze drying
so like the cryogen
where the bud is dry and
[Music]
um
you get a higher percentage of
Therapeutics left
bottom double like from normal Drive
yeah that's that's hugely become a major
discussion point in sort of the the
recent year or so especially for the the
bigger commercial producers if we focus
on the smaller home grower for the
moment I'd be interested to hear your
perspective what are some of the big
mistakes you see Growers making that you
think are holding their cultivation back
from you know being that really next
level
well one thing is being too ambitious
about it I mean uh
can't don't build the system that you
can't take care of it's so big that you
can't take care of it
that you're always behind because you're
going to lose quality
happens to me all the time I I have
bigger eyes and my effort so so you know
so you're
so you shouldn't do what I what happens
to me especially if
you know
if I do an experiment and it doesn't
work out it doesn't really affect
whether I have thought or not right so
so I have a different
way of looking at it on a personal level
but you shouldn't do something that's so
ambitious if it has good chance of
failure it's better to do something
smaller really perfect and that's number
one that I mean that that is number one
and then
the most important part of growing
uh for the most important factor in
growing is the quality of the genetics
because no matter how could our garden
you have if you don't have the genetics
you're not going to have good product so
genetics is number one
yeah and what a brilliant segue you've
just given me because I wanted to ask
you a little bit about popping seeds do
you think specifically that it's sort of
important for Growers to be popping
seeds and keeping the wheels churning on
things finding new clones or do you
think that there's not really an issue
with people just growing the same clones
repeatedly
well
let's go back to tomatoes
so you might try new varieties and then
you might grow some of the same old
varieties because you like them right
so I don't see Canada something
different
and so I guess the next question would
be do you have any advice for any
aspiring breeders out there how might
you advise them about how they go about
creating their crosses or collecting
their seed stock do you think there's
any tips you might be able to offer
tag everything and keep uh keep
Immaculate records
and don't wait to tag something don't
tag it tomorrow
what when you work on the project right
then you're not done until everything is
tan and I would even tag things as
you're doing the project you know like
don't wait till all you know
don't avoid all mixture by
keeping accurate records at the time
that you're doing it don't don't say oh
I'll write it all out tomorrow
let's see
was the yellow one the G4 or was it
it's conflicts
yeah
oh right and you know and and don't
smoke to George before you you start
doing it
that's some great advice that's some
great advice there's someone myself
who's very particular about getting the
lineages corrected I can throw my weight
behind that one
so I'd be curious to know are there any
breeders who you really back the work of
like who are your favorite breeders
well uh
there are there are some local people
who are
migration I really like his stuff
uh shavensky he's he's stuck you know of
course everybody loves it
they just met him very briefly uh
three weeks ago of all places that sell
Asylum conference
but he was leaving as I was coming in so
but that was the first time I met him
yeah very nice I'm a huge fan of that
gelato 41 really nice stuff yeah
one of the fan submitted questions as we
sort of get towards the end of our
questions was they were hoping you might
be able to give us a little bit of the
back story on the Ortega clone that came
from you you know like what was it like
how would you describe that and was
there any backstory behind how you found
it
was given to me
uh by
the fellow who said he was just passing
through and uh then I never saw him
again
he came he came up to give out varieties
to different people different varieties
to different people
and a friend of mine got another plan uh
a sort of uh another Indica that was
very good and um
I don't know
I think she lost that after a while but
and and I don't know where the
entertainment is but the j-27 it came
from a different group but from that
time you know I was saying that
that now proprietary variety it's not my
proprietary well
it it's that you know how there can be
complexity to things but it was
originally my variety and then the afro
was rated I lost it and then somebody
gave it back to me like 20 years just a
year ago 20 years later
and and now it was the same plant it was
it's a very
its quality is good but it's a very weak
plant
it's been a clone you know clone to
clone from and so um
uh would we just
using genetics to strengthen the plant
and I hope to get that plant down to the
market so
that's that's amazing stuff right there
it makes me wonder what's the oldest
clone that you're aware of
well
um I would say these j-27s that I was
talking about I know that that has only
been a throne plan for over 20 years
quite some time yeah yeah more than that
probably 23 24 years
so yeah I mean it's prone to clone to
clone but it yeah but what I saw that
plant I I recognized it immediately you
know uh from from that time
yeah wow that's beautiful to hear I'm
curious to hear because you you must
have seen so many plants over the years
are there any old varieties that we
don't see anymore that just really hold
a special spot in your mind
well Romulan was pretty good
and you don't see that anymore
and then I had a plant uh well I mean
there are so many good plants out there
now but really what I'm looking for you
know I mentioned that those plants it
could smell up their own I'm I'm looking
to find those
over those original plants put something
close to them yeah
just get in touch with me
please reach out that yeah that's great
we've heard other guests talk about how
the focus of breeding going forward
might be to try to produce some of these
thile rich plants which are hypothesized
to maybe be the plants that you know
really stink up the whole room have you
done any research or looked into thile
Rich plants at all
you know it's finding the Champions that
uh that contain that because it was
within the terpenes
yeah
okay sure but but uh
my most recent Studies have been on um
industrialization processes
so
growing methods that um
that can be integrated with growing
methods that can be integrated with
Machinery to uh like for instance for
harvesting
so I've been spending my time on that a
little bit I mean one of the questions
we got from one of our listeners was are
there any current grow technologies that
you think are going to become outdated
quite quickly or at least we'll look
back on and be like man why are we doing
it that way
big plans see the reason we had big
plans was because of prohibition if
you're only allowed to grow 10 plants
you want to grow the biggest 10 plants
you could ever grow right but if you
have but if you don't have those
um but that is totally an artifact of
prohibition
so you wouldn't naturally grow big
plants if that is if plant count wasn't
de facto
so I think that especially with
industrialization the big plants are
going to go
and those first those regulations
chapter
will be eliminated
for instance I was from a farm called
Roswell news in Colorado it's about 30
acres and they're limited to something
three or four hundred plants per acre
and so
um so that was not I mean it was a very
productive Garden but it would be much
more effect efficient ways of doing it
um yeah certainly it'll be interesting
to see how those changes roll out over
the coming years especially if we get
the abolishment of plant numbers we've
just got a few fan submitted questions
before we get on to our final five which
are you know pretty quick yes no type
questions so one of the questions our
listeners were interested in hearing is
are you able to give us a bit of the
back story or at least demystify what is
the real story behind Durban Poison
Okay so
[Music]
um
before the turn of the century early on
in the
um
in the 80s there was a coffee shop in
Amsterdam called transvault and your
trans vowel is one of the provinces in
South Africa
and so uh and sure enough it was run by
South Africans and they were importing
South African wheat and I bought and all
of the Wii came with g
and I bought
all their varieties
and that was
planted a number of them and just and
the German poison was outstanding and
relevant and that's how it happened and
I've read in um
in uh different
um
uh different things on the internet that
I've traveled to South Africa and got
that and everything and that sounds
really good and I wish I had but I
traveled to Amsterdam and went to the
trans Mall
there you go and were there ever any
additional genetics mixed in with it or
it's just pure South African as far as
you know
well when I
when I presented it to the world it was
pure self-help
yeah awesome what a what a cool story
one of the other questions we got is
sort of along the same lines and The
Listener asks are there any early or
modern varieties that Eddie's likewise
responsible for bringing sort of to the
community well
um
um the old uh J1 and J2 but they're not
really available anymore
Romulan which I uh I wasn't the
originator of Romulan but
um it was you know it was obscure until
I started cloning it
so those varieties but it's been a long
time you know it's been uh I haven't
been doing that for 20 years and so you
know
not many people drive a 20 year old car
look I adore J1 I think it's one of the
best plants ever and I don't know why
it's not still popular
well you know uh it it was it was a
harder plan to grow because it had a lot
of sativa
so it was pretty hard to grow you need
the best place to grow would be like
Spain or Italy something like that
Outdoors
the day two is much more manageable
because you've had a lot of vindicating
yeah okay sorry what's the J2 is it J1
crossed to an indica
no it was uh day two uh two and two
indicators were crossed and then they
both crossed with this
see I'd have to look in my records I
forget what they were crossword but it
was
um it wasn't enough it wasn't an
outstanding plant that they were crossed
with there was a plant that had certain
other qualities that made it uh made it
a valuable time they've increased in
yield
and um the the other plant uh had a lot
of um
hidden stability which made it it sort
of stabilized your day too and like once
it was hybridized it was pretty uniform
which was very unusual
you will usually have that usually you
know when the F2 you know you
the the
you know the F1 generation is uniform
and then the F2 Generation sorts out
into all kinds of ways but but with the
J2 it remained pretty uniform throughout
a little unusual
yeah it does sound unusual doesn't it
yeah
so the next question we had from one of
our listeners is where does Ed see the
Cannabis scene in 10 years time
um I don't think people will regrow the
Cannabis anymore
I think that they I think that
most uh I think that or you get were in
addition to growing cannabis they I
think a lot of the collaboroids are
going to be produced by growing beer and
that the uh the genes for the
cannaboroids and food Terrapins will be
transferred to uh uh to yeast and so
that you know people say oh that's
terrible but just think about it no
lights
right because you don't need lights so
sugar water and a pail
then you're in business
I mean and the east and then seven days
later or a few days later you you know
the yeast have expressed the
cannabinoids that uh have been
transferred to their
uh to their chromosomes and so that's
much easier than
um
growing your own I mean growing you you
don't have the light set up you don't
have the time set up the space
be a game changer won't it yes yeah
well that's that's something to to look
forward to seeing how that works that'll
be interesting indeed and you know yeah
you know a lot of our medicines you need
that one so what point uh
why not cannabis yeah hugely
everybody will have to wear a white uh a
white lab jacket it would definitely
change or the producer image
well it will it will be something
totally different I mean
I went
I visited uh Genentech a few years ago
and
you know that we're just sprawling
buildings and everything but you know
the actual place where they uh make the
where where the
the actual place the space where the uh
the medicines are made
are basically
um uh it's basically a
Brewing
the bromine either either bacteria or
yeast and then then they refine them so
um I think that we'll be able to do that
as consumers
yeah exciting times ahead for sure
and then the big thing will be
um uh uh by the yeast Sports you know
the yeast so it will all depend upon
what yeast you get because Japanese will
have different cannabinoid and terpene
recipes
so um
they become the strains they are the
street yeah exactly yeah
that's cool that's cool
uh enough topic sort of question we got
from one of our listeners was
could Ed tell us a little bit about what
was some of the worst advice he believed
to be correct for the longest time
before realizing it wasn't true
I'm not going into that
because because somebody will hear it
and they'll
take that advice so
it's better to let it lie buried there
you go good answer good answer
so the listener was wondering would Ed
be able to tell us a little bit about
how Sensi came to offer the Ed Rosenthal
superbud strain were you involved in
that or was it a namesake sort of thing
well I actually had given them the
original seeds from that many years
before
you know before they introduced it and
so
um
I gave them the original genetics but
they worked on it for perhaps 20 years
before releasing it and the thing about
the uh superbride is that it comes in
very early it will come in a month or
earlier than your other varieties and so
you know in northern areas in a woman
it's uh the the weather threat
um
yeah hugely advantageous for cash
croppers yeah and for everybody I mean
uh no home Gardener likes to see their
Bud turn to Marsh overnight because the
weather changed so this eliminates that
problem in that case certainly
and so also you know uh in that line
there's a Jack Jack Herer which is very
popular and there's the Michigan line
for Michigan and France so there are a
number of people in that in that series
yeah certainly certainly I mean while
we're on the topic of cash cropping or
sort of in that general area this was an
interesting question someone was
wondering what's the most you've ever
seen yielded off one plant indoor
I don't know uh I I haven't seen
gigantic I know a friend of mine used to
go grow these gigantic plants indoors
and but they were sure they weren't
yielding that much so uh I I haven't
seen any really giant plants to dream
about not endorsed
sure so I can understand that
so the second last viewer submitted
question was they say oh about a year or
more ago I remembered seeing a post
about Ed creating his own bagged soil
blend alongside vital Garden Supply is
that still going ahead or is that paused
for the moment
well it was paused for this season
because of supply chain problems
but we're planning to go ahead next year
ah exciting so they can still probably
get it next year yes
fantastic and the final viewer submitted
question before we do our final five is
how do you feel the effects of the older
varieties versus the present day Elite
Cuts Fair many people nowadays talk
about modern cannabis as having a
similar sort of feeling or effect
whereas the older varieties it's like
they had their own sort of personality
do you feel this sort of sentiment is
true or do you think that there's still
variance in the modern varieties it was
incredible amounts of variation
yeah I mean
um especially if you go off the beat and
try track because there are so many
breeders
there are thousands and thousands of
breeders there's no other crop that is
bred the way this one is you know with
so many people treating it so there's so
much variation
yeah that's great to hear all right well
that brings us to our final five quick
fire questions that we ask all guests so
the first one is what is the most
memorable cannabis experience you've
ever had it might be smoking hash it
might be smoking flour what's the one
that just stands out the most in your
mind
well I was with Neville and I was
smoking some nl5 Haze and it was like I
was tripping
on his face now
um maybe that wouldn't have the same
effect now but it was extraordinary
marijuana we were at his mansion
you know in my making
I'm so jealous
that's beautiful okay so on the other
end of the spectrum was there ever a
time when everyone you knew was like oh
you got to try this new thing it's so
good and then you finally tried it and
you were like ah is that it
I try to remember the good experiences
yeah that's a good that's a good rule to
live by so next one was if I had to drop
you off on a desert island with just
three strains to cultivate and to smoke
for the rest of your life which three
would you take well definitely take the
G27 I might take the superbug
and
I would probably
um I go after a sativa variety one of
this one of the modern sativa varieties
as well
yeah it's a nice little palette you've
got there to mix and match yeah
so was there ever a variety that you
really wanted to get your hands on but
it just always eluded you and you could
never get it
the original White Widow and there was a
fellow who had it and sold
the seeds to a number of different
companies
but but he never saw the exact PRC
itself
there was some variation but he had a
pure variety of it and I don't know what
happened to him
people didn't like him because he saw
this same variety to everybody
exclusively very exclusive then he
disappeared was his name was that
ingenmar yeah all right yeah
yeah there you go yeah you read his
names on the forums but as you said he
just completely disappeared right
all righty well it won for the ages well
on to our final question before we wrap
things up for today if you had a time
machine and you could go back anywhere
in time anywhere around the world
presumably to collect some seeds or
maybe even a clone where would you go
and what would you collect
well
you know
um
the original area where a plant or an
animal uh
uh started usually has the most
diversity
so I would like to um so I would
uh I'd like to go back into Bhutan and
uh a little further east of that
and uh
maybe 50 years ago
because
um
that was before there was uh before all
those uh
uh land races were contaminated
yeah a brilliant answer a brilliant
answer
so I think that just about brings us to
the end of things
um just a quick reminder to all of our
listeners head on over to Ed
rosenthal.com pick up your copy of the
Cannabis Growers handbook before we wrap
up were there any comments or shout outs
you wanted to make
this was a great interview really
enjoyed it be happy to do it again
likewise thank you so much for your time
the guru of ganja Ed Rosenthal we really
appreciate it thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
and there we have it friends what'd you
think pick up said Rosenthal for taking
the time to stop by please get on over
to his site check out his book cannabis
grow his handbooks
likewise please consider supporting our
phenomenal sponsors who helped make the
episodes happen seeds here now you know
him you love them hottest jobs they got
a new tricome jungles drop I just saw
there's some freebies on there for Duke
free The Dukes
so much more check it out
[Music]
likewise huge shout out to Copper
biological systems your number one
source of beneficial predators and all
Technologies to keep your garden happy
healthy and free from unnecessary
pathogens have you tried the spidex
vital phenomenal get rid of all the
spider mites in your garden please guys
check it out no one wants to see Cloud
riddled with spider mites likewise no
one wants to see flower that's
underperforming our good friends at
promix have the phenomenal mycorizer
product connect which is going to help
you to have a productive and very
profitable Harvest thanks to increased
yield increased biomass increased growth
rates increase residence all of the good
things that mycorrhizer brings to the
game now offered to you by a company you
know and love Pro mix and with a
guaranteed viable sport count you simply
cannot beat the quality of their product
if you're trying to produce the highest
quality it's a no-brainer Pro mix
connections
Charlie's cannabis producing the highest
quality small batch family-owned
veteran-owned craft none of this if
you're sick of going to dispensaries and
being disappointed by the quality check
out Charlie's cannabis I promise guys
some of the best out there you're not
going to be disappointed go check them
out
likewise patreon gangs you're the number
one we love you so much thanks for all
your support I hope you enjoy getting
early access to this episode if anyone
wants to help support the show and
continue to ensure that episodes happen
please go check out patreon.com forward
slash the podcast and instead of signing
up
otherwise guys I'll see you for the next
one
we'll see you
[Music]
foreign