[Music]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts this episode was
brought to you by 420 Australia for all
your clothing and lifestyle needs as
well as mad farmer genetics you go to
purple cannabis breeder on this episode
we're joined by the mad farmer to talk
about all things purple oh cool some of
his strains as well as some of his
future breeding plans alrighty so I'd
like to welcome mad farmer on to this
episode thanks so much for taking the
time to join me no problem yeah no
problem
so let's go back to the start so how did
you get into weight you know I think I
know the answer this one but you know
was it was it a friend influencing you
was it more of a family thing and and
what were some of the strains that were
around when you first started smoking
well I've been in it I've been in it as
long as I can remember I was born into
it
it was something my mom and dad had
always done my whole family all my dad's
brothers sister they you know they all
smoked it wasn't something that they hid
from us it was something back in the day
that we knew not to to talk about with
others but it was a family affair
and my parents were honest with us about
it back then it wasn't questioned called
medicine it was it was basically called
getting high but we knew it as what we
knew it and you know the 70s were kind
of a different generation and I grew up
in the 70s and 80s and being around it
it was a different experience my brother
and I both kind of stayed on the path if
you will I kind of deviated from the
path for a few years because I went to
school and tried to go mainstream with
things but it wasn't my passion and I
could tell I wasn't happy doing
mainstream work and the nine-to-five
that most people most people do and at
plus I I was diagnosed when I was 24
with SLE and so that kind of changed my
life forever and I went back to my roots
because I knew the benefits at that
point it had become more of the topic
about them the medical aspect of
cannabis and I was taking so many
different medications that everything
would make me nauseous all the time I
couldn't keep food down it's just I felt
sick all the time and there were certain
strains that really really were
beneficial and finding certain strains
sometimes weren't as easy even in the
circles that I have it wasn't the
easiest thing to find certain strains
and so I decided my wife and I after
long discussions we we sat down and we
just decided you know what I'm going to
leave my job I couldn't do any more I
had become addicted to Big Pharma's
wonderful narcotics and it was just it
was killing me my kidneys were shutting
down my liver wasn't working properly it
was down to 20% and I couldn't do that
we had a
we had a daughter on the way and it just
it was a time it was a time that we
needed to make a decision and when I
look back now it was the best decision I
ever made
and I I have my dad to thank for that
because it was him that you know really
really showed us what what what pot was
about even before it was the medicinal
factor it was a way of life and that was
the reason that was the reason I was was
born into the family that I was born
into this is this is something that's I
like it wasn't when an artist paints and
then he says that when he's doing it
it's just something that he loves it's
it's it's an expression of himself and
that's how I feel about what we do is
when I'm with the plants I just feel
they're an extension of Who I am and I
express myself through the plants
what a what a kind of you know a
powerful recount of how you got into
this you know so thanks for sharing that
no it's amazing if you look back at it
now and you think everything was meant
to happen the way it happened and I'm
just a firm believer in in that it's
because things that have happened with a
cannabis and without cannabis have all
led me back to cannabis and I just know
that that was the start and I think
that's why that's my what one of my you
know clearest recollections is the fact
that it was meant to be and that's why I
remember it being only five years old
and just having that thought I mean
it-it's it's like a picture in my mind I
can see it I can smell it I mean it was
a giant enormous outdoor calli skunk
plant and I mean it the entire house I
mean everything everything smell like my
dad had just brought the skunk into the
house and I it's a vivid pungent pungent
memory in my head nice so so it sounds
like the whole family was growing kind
of the whole time you're growing up at
what point did you decide to transition
from grower to breeder or maybe more
should I say back in those days was
there the distinction where people just
farmers and a lot of people made their
own seed for the following season or you
know was there still a somewhat of clear
distinction as there is today between
say growers and breeders and if so when
did you decide to make the transition
well as as far as it was back in there
was no coin term of a breeder when my
dad and I won't I won't say his name but
my dad had a best friend and between
those two
they were the best growers they were
doing things back then and this is in
the mid to late 70s that people are just
now starting to do
now with the no-till experience that it
was kind of when I look back now it's
mind-boggling but when they needed to
continue the lines that they had it
would be a email that they would have
from the same lines that they that they
had and they would have one and it would
pollinate you know the surrounding
plants and then that would be the seeds
that they would continue on you figured
they would do one pollination and they
would have enough seeds for years of
growth and so there was no coin term of
breeders back then it was just farming
and and they were farming cannabis and
as far as for me getting into the actual
art of breathing it was specifically for
my my medicinal benefit I wanted to I
wanted to create strains that were going
to help me with my the symptoms of my
lupus my SLE
and that's what led me down the road of
doing it of getting into it because
there were certain lines that were more
beneficial for me and it was the reason
why I am so heavily involved with with
purple pot is because of the the
medicinal benefits that it it offers me
for my particular disease so that was
the reason that I got back into breeding
and then it became as much of a passion
as actually growing and it was something
that I just absolutely fell in love with
and it just grew from there and it just
blossomed from there yes so on that same
idea I was actually wondering do you
think that it's possible to predictive
we breed a strain for a specific need so
we here you know certain strains are
good for say IBS or you know in your
case you just mentioned you know certain
strains are good for SLE do you think
that you could say I'm gonna cross this
strand with this strain and I predict
that it will be good for Crohn's or
something based on the parents lineage
maybe or something like that or do you
think like Knights it's not a really a
predictable thing it just turns out
certain strains are good for certain
things but I doubt we'll ever be able to
predict it
oh no absolutely absolutely I for me I
said the two strains that come to mind
that I have personally found the most
medicinal benefits from our lavender and
purple Urkel they just have a quality
about them that it with nausea for
instance and that's been my biggest
issue is the nausea and the stomach the
the cramping in the the pain with the
IBS and the Crohn's because I've had 13
surgeries so it's been a rough rough
road and the idea of entering
medications and everything so the
lavender in the purple article I can
pick him up and though I've been smoking
him for so many years I don't get stoned
on him per se anymore I mean I'll have a
nice little relaxing buzz but I don't
really smoke those two you know to
really get high i smoke those for a
purpose and I don't really go anywhere
without them but I can take either one
of those and I can work those and the
progeny from those eighty percent I
would say of the time are gonna carry
the same benefit as as the mom as long
as you're male selection is proper and
you're staying either within the line
or as close to the line as you can
you're gonna carry that trait and that's
the reason why I had stayed within those
lines but for me that I cannot be
without those those two strings and I've
had those two strings for over 16 years
now oh wow
so I was actually gonna say yeah I read
online that ye the Oh Kolkata has been
in your family's possession for over 25
years that's really impressive if it is
true how how did you get the Kolkata and
you know if you did know kind of a bit
about its history that you wouldn't mind
sharing you know it's one of those
strains where it'll speculate about the
genetics but you know it's kind of hard
to know what's true well it's not been
25 years that we've had it it would
probably be closer to 19 around 19 maybe
maybe 20 still yeah
yeah well it's anytime you can keep a
plant that's designed to have one season
it flower sentence then I'll live for
that long you've done something right
and we have we have quite a few moms
that we've had for 10 plus years 12 plus
years but my babies have been with us
for the longest time and we've kept them
alive
herckel is a she she has a mystique it's
it's it's just what she is and that's
true the true identity behind purple
oracle truly truly isn't known and the
reason is is because the name game
wasn't this huge oh I have I have this
line or I have this line it was you know
we had sensimilla you either had
seamless or you didn't and my family was
known for producing the best seedless
marijuana that most people had ever had
ever seen so if there wasn't a name
so back then and a lot of the land race
the land race crossings were starting to
come because you had South American weed
that was really into into parts of
California especially in the Central
Valley having really long summers that
you could carry all the way into
November so you were able to flower you
know indoor strains that would be 19 or
20 weekers with a little assistance and
help you could push them to full term
and you know a lot of especially with my
dad he really liked the the the speedy
weed the ampie weed if you will and the
only thing that he didn't really care
for what's the really long growing
season and that's when a lot of the the
Hindukush was starting to make its way
over over here and then you had the
Afghanistan and Russian conflict and my
dad had friends in the Peace Corps that
were bringing seeds back from from from
different areas and that's when a lot of
the real true land race hybrids were
being started you had pure sativa lines
for the first time being pollinated by
super short you know stocky wide indica
plants that a lot of people had never
even seen before and they were they were
using them in and what we have coined
breeding projects now and thus you know
that's where a lot of it got started was
was us-backed in but with herbal there
was no name you know so that's that's
the biggest reason that there's the the
big question mark as to the lineage
because when it was created there just
wasn't a lot of names I think one one of
the lines had and
down the road becoming one of the
Northern Lights by type Ross's I want to
say that it was the male side that was
the indica the indica side of things on
the article and it just it wasn't you
know it just wasn't a conversation it
would always be about the plant for the
plant with the plant and it was it was a
trait expressions that's what you were
looking for that was the biggest thing
it wasn't so much in the name and that's
why when people asked me hey why don't
your crosses carry names certain ones do
and they carry their names after the
fact that they've been grown because
it's a name that you can actually see in
the plant you know this one was called
this because this is what she smelled
like that's what she looked like tasted
like that was the name and then I tell
people not to get caught up in the name
because it's meaningless and so it was
uh it was about the traits about the
expressions of the plant you know it's
just the idea that you know this one was
done by the end of September and and
this one over here we were carrying into
the middle of November and probably
could have given her an extra two weeks
and the idea of putting them together
just made a whole lot of sense and
that's how it got started and then the
hybrid craze really got started and then
you had old school skunk lines that you
know were powerful and and it's
supercharged satima lines and now you
had indica lines that were released when
they had the same turf profiles the same
expressions the same smells but they
they looked completely different and you
would always try and find things that
that in your head you could just put
them together you could actually see
them being well matched together and
with Arkell there was a lot of Northern
Lights
well what ended up being cleaned is
Northern Lights and ty going around a
lot of Ty and those two ended up having
a party and then they became a single
line and that's also when you started
seeing a lot of color a lot of the
Afghans that were that were coming over
were worth turning black about the final
month of flower temperatures had a lot
to do with it but you just didn't see a
whole whole lot of it at the time and
once we started to see well we have more
of my dad and and crew but once they
started to see those expressions it was
just a whole different realm of weed
that you know they were now getting to
experience and it was a no-brainer
working with it for them and then that's
when you started seeing the purple lines
really started to pop up the sativa
dominant purple lines from the hybrids
the the indica dominant purple lines and
purple Urkel was a product of that she
just was something that was really
really special yeah so just kind of
going back to a point you made a few
minutes ago about um some hybrids in
relation to Oracle you know this kind of
has a bit of a bigger underlying
question but you know how do you think
ocol has managed to stay within kind of
the mainstream of weed culture or at
least kind of always peripherally
present and by that I mean like to me
granddaddy purple is one of those
strains where it's good you know like I
don't mind it but I always like I have
to remind people like you know the
speculated genetics are local Cross Big
Bud so you know if you look at big but
we know what its job is
so the extrapolation would be that oh
cool it's going to be like the con
granddaddy purple so is that true and
why do you think our core has managed to
stay kind of present in mainstream
culture because it is one of those ones
that it's always popping up but it's
never the flavor of the month so to
speak yeah well with Oracle I think
there's there's three reasons you have
the mysterious factor everybody wants to
know what exactly it is - it is an
amazingly gorgeous plant - to grow just
everybody complains that grows her that
she's a slow Vedder and she can be a
slow veg er I grow a lot of pot that's
extremely painful painfully slow in veg
and the third I think would be her
intoxicating smell and for me her taste
because the true herbal cut the actual
herbal cut is a hazy smoky if you will
great flavor that is very unique and
it's it's one of those things that
really goes well with food I think a lot
of people make the relation to cannabis
and food and I think you put those three
factors together and I just think that
she's just carried carried on that way
everybody everybody everywhere I go with
with friends you know I I don't go
around advertising Who I am I'm a very
recluse individual probably one of the
most recluse individuals which you know
but the circle of friends that I have
even the same guys will ask me you know
what what do you think it is what do you
think it we just had this conversation
three weeks ago what do you mean what do
I think it is and I think it's the the
mysterious factor and just that that
it's just a gorgeous gorgeous plant when
she fly
hours I just think that's what it is
it's a for me obviously I've already
stated that it was the medicinal factor
that that she serves for me but she's
just one of the most beautiful plant to
flower out and and I won't be without
her
I'll have her it'll be something that
you know when it's my time to go I'll
turn over to my to my child and you know
explain which she already knows that
it's what you know I've always been
honest with her and she knows what
certain things mean to me and how
special they are obviously plus my wife
and they know there are certain things
that like your name you want to carry
out you'll want to do everything you
possibly can to continue on and that'll
be something that I turn over to them
and then and I'll make it clear that you
know keep her around as long as you can
and when you're tired of her pass her to
somebody that will do the same thing and
but that's just what it is for me of
course I can't speak for everybody else
but even if she didn't have the the
medicinal effect for me that she does it
would still be one of those plants that
I keep around just because she's that
unique she she works well with others
and it's all about her expressions
she's just let's put this way she's
intoxicating to the eyes she's
intoxicating to the nose and she's
intoxicating on your taste buds and when
your body is into something that much
with that many of your senses it's a no
brainer and that that's why she stays
with us and I think maybe that's why it
is something that is so highly sought
after by others is those three factors
is the the fact that it is a mysterious
strain but besides that it's just she's
gorgeous and she's it it's explosive
with flavor yeah so just to move on to
some of your strains because actually
wanted to highlight some of your strains
for people listening so the first one
what I think is maybe kind of your
hallmark strand away the Triple E wicked
you know this one is obviously made from
the lavender which we mentioned earlier
as well as it's earth what you said is
the the male side of the purple opal so
I think you mentioned that was the what
eventually became in the Northern Lights
yes Erin or the lights both I yes so so
how would you describe this strain to
someone and why you know like from from
what I can see it looks like the one
you've kind of worked the most with why
did you sit decide to work with it so
extensively and you know and yeah and
how what would be your kind of sales
pitch to someone you know well what's
the tripoli wicked first let me say that
I refer to her a lot as t-dub a lot of
people especially here on the west coast
when they hear the turn term teed up
they have automatically assumed train
rights and it's not when I'm referring
to I don't like T that I don't like
train wreck it's not it's not my cup of
tea she's a [ __ ] to work with very
unstable the buzz isn't that unique she
just grows erratic she stretches so she
just wasn't my cup of tea like I'm not a
real big og fan either but that's when
you hear me refer to see them it will
never be trainwreck it will always be
triple e wicked that and I get asked
that question a lot so I wanted to to
clarify that
Jenny worms t-dub is uh she's she's a
very special very special
strain the mail that we got was actually
when my dad had passed away
a family friend which the friendship
unfortunately has kind of degraded
because of the popularity that was
gained by the three strains that we used
to create with the mill that we were
blessed with was it was in honor of my
dad because my dad had a love for purple
pots and originally it was gonna be the
lavender and the Urkel and the Mel was
noted as Triple E when we're working
Lestrange usually they'll be documented
as a letter and a number depending where
they are in the garden it's just easier
to track them with with letters and
numbers because of the rows and the
placement and so we went ahead and
labeled said Mel as Triple E it was a
kind of an heirloom line and it was from
the the male side of the responsible
party for creating the Urkel and it is a
very heavy Northern Lights leaning
Northern Lights by Ty hybrid line that
really expressive it carried a heavy
heavy heavy which we didn't know at the
time had no clue a citrus herb profile
and when I say citrus I guess I should
just say tangerines because it literally
smelled most of the the plants even the
Mel's on the stem rub you could smell it
would just the three or four weeks in
the flower would start to smell as if
you were peeling a really really sweet
tangerine and we didn't expect that at
all and so we got the mail which was
Triple E it was an honor of
of my of my dad we wanted to do
something that was gonna be unique
something that had had to my knowledge
had not been done and with we were
blessed with the mail and so we went
ahead with it and we used him to
pollinate our our lavender which became
Tripoli wicked in honor of my father our
purple Arkell which became purple Jackie
again in honor of my father and then
those were the two we were we were going
to use in the beginning and then it was
a last-minute decision that we threw in
our esidisi that one really wasn't
specific for my dad she's probably been
with us out of all our elite mothers
she's been with us the least amount of
time I think we've had her for around
eleven eleven maybe close to 12 years
now um and we we put her in late and she
became the triple deep Crippler and we
and ended up becoming just the things
that end up happening that you can't
control and how a person is gonna react
you you know you can't control and it
became such an issue that we ended up
just killing the one male that I to this
day wish I would have just wrote out the
turmoil and and kept kept the mail
itself because he was the most
expressive mill speaking on on turps
term profiles the most expressive male
that I've ever worked with and we ended
up killing him just to you know kind of
try and keep a relationship a friendship
what she ended up failing anyway and so
we did away with him and we decided to
carry on with the three we
kept our end of the bargain we didn't do
anything more and we had the three lines
the t-dub the the PJ and the TVC and
just the the triple II was so dominant
so amazing and now that I look back and
I've grown literally probably a thousand
of of these the the three that we
created I have seen how predictable of a
male doesn't matter the female how
predictable he's gonna be and anytime
you can find a male that is predictable
in what he's gonna do it makes your job
easy because you know what to expect and
Tripoli was that male and the reason
that you hear the most right now about
the Tina is because when we work aligned
we don't just create the line and then
you know put it out there and then move
on to the next we create the line we
work from within the line because I just
feel that you now know that line you now
know what she's capable of what she's
capable of doing the predictability
factor there's just so much about her
that you now know why do you want to
just jump into something else that's an
unknown so we continued on for a while
a few years with the t-dub and that's
why you continue to hear about the Teva
but we're now moving in to the PJ aspect
the purple Jackie and it is the same
it's the triple email but instead of the
lavender mom it's the Urkel mom and it's
it's probably more expressive with the
Urkel's then he was with the lavender
and that one well it's gonna raise some
eyebrows I think
because again it's hi citrus expressions
in the Terps the the buds are a little
more chunky if you will the the calyxes
are a little more small and a little
larger the hairs are a little brighter
orange they just stand out a little bit
more the the potency factor is right
there with the t-dub that was the reason
why too with the tea that we stayed with
it for so long because it had amazing
medicinal effects but she just was a
little bit light in in the power aspect
and and I just felt I could I could
bring that out a little bit better so we
we just played with the line for a long
time enjoyed it thoroughly and created
many hybrid lines with with Athena but
in the meantime we were working with the
TDC and the PHA just not you know openly
and dumping a month on whoever we like I
said we like to stick with a single
project as far as our focal points but
we always have at least one most of the
time to other projects that were we're
kind of doing in the background and tea
that was just the first one from the
what we did for my dad was the first one
that that we brought mainstream and that
we we allowed to you know to come out to
the masses so um you much like one of my
favorite breed is dynasty up here to
work in kind of a methodical way in that
uh what you do is you've got kind of
your pool of base strains and in your
case it's kind of the Clementine and the
t-dub cool and spaced queen and a few
others and you kind of mix and match
your flavors from the
and I like this approach because I mean
for one that Clementine I mentioned
isn't the DNA Clementine it's a
different one it's one you made so a lot
of those are actually your own strains
yes
so it seems to me like you've made a lot
of the possible combinations there are
so my my immediate thought was what's
mad farmers next move are you gonna
bring some new genetics in and then make
some new combinations with that or maybe
refine some of the old genetics by yeah
I know that you took the t-dub to the f2
you know maybe do that with some other
strains and then begin reworking from
there or what's your plan well like I
said you know here with us it's about
what first and foremost what my
preferences as smoking material so I'll
always go with that first and foremost
I've never been one to breed with the
cut of the month strains like a lot of
people will get what's popular you have
the cookies and the the gg4 and now
archivists come out with a dough see
though and those are all amazing in
their own right and I would never ever
try to dick somebody and say hey you
know you're working with [ __ ] or you
know you created [ __ ] never because
that's somebody's passion and I'd never
do that whatsoever
my point is simple I'm not a cut of the
month breeder I am really methodical
it's kind of OCD and so when I'm on
something I stay on something until I'm
completely satisfied with it and then
I'll move on but what's coming next is
the is the PJ and you'll see if PJ
hybrids the the male that we have that
we're working with was chosen
oh my over three seasons I think it was
three seasons that we we took the find
um a lot of times yes yes sir a lot a
lot of testing I mean when you have a
field of just males it's you know it's
it's just like growing females you're
looking for specifics you're smelling
for specifics you're documenting flower
times people ask if you really smoked
them yes I do
I I don't enjoy it but some of the
male's you can actually get you can get
a bit of a buzz on I I've had like with
our PJ I have Mel's little produced
resins good amounts of resin to the
point to where you can turn them into a
concentrate I mean you you can actually
extract I mean your your percentages
aren't gonna be anything close to what
you're gonna get with the female flower
but it is it's there it's a possibility
and you can't just say well this line
produced this smell so this smell looks
like he's got everything I'm looking for
for me that's not good enough my brain
doesn't work like that
for me I I I have to see him I have to
touch him I have to smell him I have to
smoke him I have to know what he's gonna
give me and with our PJ it's it's
everything that I wanted from my PJ male
he has the the blood-red PT old he has
that citrus font on the stem rub he has
the quicker flowering time he has the
little bit further node spacing he has
that gorgeous double serrated leaf edge
just everything about him his pollen
sacks are vivid violet and let's put it
this way you put him in the field of 25
other males and he's gonna be the one
that stands out he's gonna be the one
that screams Here I am choose me and
typically we don't if or you know post
pictures of our males or so
Mel's but he has impressed us so much
that I've actually posted a couple of
pictures of him just because he's caught
my fancy like I don't know if I've had a
mail that has as excited me as much as
as this pj mail and that's where we're
gonna go we're gonna work the pj line
we're gonna ff2 in the line first and
foremost bring out the the f twos and
then we'll take him to you know to what
we consider our elite mothers our you
know our brood and then we'll start to
introduce him to you know like our
heirloom Clementine
we don't ever bring in outside cuts for
one yeah it's it's kind of a bad
practice because it's sanitary issue
even the most clean gardens can carry
hitchhikers that are unknown you know
you can go down to your damn bro shop
and bring home hitchhikers because
there's so many farmers in and out of
the shop that they you know the spider
mite will follow him you know be honest
shoes or pants and then they're jumping
onto a product that you bring home so
and yeah you can quarantine and you know
there's plenty of methods to eradicate
anything possible that you can bring in
but again we're really Rekluse our
social circle is small and we just we
don't bring in a lot of outside cuts and
if you look back just in the last three
years at at what popular cannabis
strains you've had a lot of them come
and go you know here in california you
go back just a few years and you had
lines like a snow cap and train wreck
and you know a lot of the lines they
come and go cookies this seem to have
stuck around for a while but healing
cookies now is kind of starting to
expand out and
hybrids you know everybody now has
cookie hybrids where before it was just
straight cookies everybody wanted
cookies GG for now you're seeing a lot
of hybrids and I'm just I'm old school I
guess um it's not that I don't dig those
strains it's just that when it comes to
my work so what I'm doing to what my
vision is I don't know enough about
those lines to feel confident when I
bring them in that I'm gonna create
something that the growers are gonna get
and say damn you know that's all I want
I I want to know what I'm working with
and I want to know the ins and outs I
don't just want to know its name and
what it smells like and what it looks
like and tastes like I want to know what
it's doing on week six on an indoor
flower run I want to know what it's
doing in September on an outdoor flower
run I want to know you know how big is
she gonna get in an outdoor patch how is
she gonna do on organics house you're
gonna do on synthetics I I want to know
these things and there's only one way to
do it and it just takes time and a lot
of people bite me for you know only
having what seems to be a small set of
lines that we work it's not because I
don't have access or I can't acquire I'm
you can get whatever I want it's just
the fact that this is how my brain works
this is this is my commitment I'm a lot
like my dad in that sense I know what I
like and that's for my personal
consumption and then when I'm working
with something it needs to be more than
what I like I need to know like I said
what she's gonna do in September on an
outdoor run on synthetic nutrients I
need to know what she's gonna do
in September out or on organic nutrients
and that's that's just how we are so it
seems like we're we're really simplified
in in what we're doing but in reality
it's an
simplifying it off there's a lot going
on that most people will never know you
know
yeah I mean the a quick little caveat I
would chuck in there is that I'm from my
experience from talking to people and
just personally breeders like yourself
and other people who do have that kind
of limited base and mix-and-match they
tend to be able to give by far the most
accurate descriptions of their strains
so you know I think that kind of speaks
for itself in a lot of ways but anyway
moving on
so are you organic or synthetic and and
you just mentioned before that you might
consider taking the purple Jackies to
the f2 yes would you would you ever
consider doing a cubing process or do
you think now doing bat crossings not so
much what I'm looking to do what yeah
what what makes f2 is an ideal thing for
you you know do you aim to refine
characteristics in that process or you
know like why choose the f2 over say a B
X no with a PJ we are we're going to
cube I want to get as close to the Urkel
in seed form as I can I want the growers
to get a 10 pack of seeds and have seven
of them come out damn they're spitting
images of purple purple and that's our
goal in the PJ is I just fill and this
is no slight on lavender I probably
should have done it with her but there's
just so many other things moving with
her that we just didn't get around to
that but one of our biggest goals with
the PJ is to cube her I want to see
Arkel dominance I want people to be able
to experience you know that true purple
in its its form not not some s1 not some
oh this is in quotation marks purple
Oracle that we got from the club that's
[ __ ] it's some purple strain that
you can clearly wanna I don't know how
many times I'll be thumbing through
pictures and this guy will state yeah
and this is my er Kolkata I'm like
that's not even close
verbal verbal you know and it's just I
feel bad I I do I feel really bad and it
just drives me to to produce some seed
that is gonna show people what the
purple or chol is is truly all about and
and the PJ is that's that's where we're
gonna go so we're gonna do F two lines
we're gonna do some hybrids but for me
which is the most important factor is
I'm going to bring it full circle I'm
going to draw the Arkell out and it'll
be cubed it will be 75% or higher
Arkel dominant in every female or I
won't be satisfied and that is
definitely our goal with with that there
be other projects that we do with it but
the goal with the PJ is is to allow
people to experience true in every way
for political and it's exciting for me
because like I said I see people who you
know they really do they they they
invest a lot of their time and money and
and they've they've they've been Sham
dan and you'll see their pictures and
they're so excited and and you know I'm
I'm not gonna be the one that breaks
their heart and just it pulls the dick
move and tells them dude you're not
you're not growing purple purple bud
your growth you guys want to watch your
Crooklyn but it's not article you know
I'm not gonna do that but it does it
pisses me off to see that because it
just tells me how many people are out
there that are just doing it to turn a
dime and it's just you know it bothers
me and this isn't what it's about
it's everything especially in this
industry if you look around everything
is about the almighty dollar again and
the money's great
money's great I wish I had more of it
but that's that's not what it's about
for me it's it's about producing the bed
cannabis that I can possibly produce and
putting smile on smiles on growers faces
I want them to repeat our name I want
them to tell their friends have you
grown any of this guy stuff
no well then look I'm gonna get you a
pack because that's how you know that's
how strongly I feel about about his
lines is there they are what they say
they are when he gives you information
on you know the packaging or whatever
when he tells you this is what you can
expect that's what you can expect that
you know it's a like I said it just
pisses me off to see so many people that
think they're growing the actual herbal
cut and it's it's not and we're gonna
cube the PJ we're gonna bring out the
Arkell and that's all God that's the
best thing about her is from the Gekko
just the the initial females that we
were running from the initial cross of
the herbal and the purple Jackie I mean
you're already seeing extremely fertile
dumphy knows regularly without even
trying
just the expressions and it's exciting
it's really exciting to see you know
something coming to fruition and I can't
once I get to that that fourth cross I
can't imagine what what we're gonna see
I I don't even expect it to have to be
cubed I don't think I'll have to go that
far I truly think you know we'll we'll
walk search our initial F one's for the
brother and sister that represents it
well enough and and then our back cross
with our goal the selection process I
believe by the third time through a
you're gonna see full herbal dominance
in the seed and and you know not that we
won't take it to the to the fourth I
can't say that at this point but I'm
absolutely 100% positive what you're
gonna see from from the PJ
hybrid the PJ Oracle hybrids is gonna be
very very very herbal very Oracle
dominant and that's the goal I mean you
know that's the goal as far as the dua
growth synthetic do I grow organic yes
we have to
we do use synthetics my my personal head
stash is organic
I do believe in a very clean pot i I
want nothing but why - I I don't want
any you know
pesticides I don't want any [ __ ] in
my pot for one I do have lupus and I
have to be very specific in what I
intake ingest breathe so my head stash
is organic but to be fair to the growers
I have to grow and sit with synthetics
as well because you're still over half
of your growers you know are using
synthetic nutrients and you'd be amazed
at how many people I still come across
so that will come up and send me an
email or a message and they'll say hey
you know my plants doing this and and I
don't know why I'm only four weeks in
the flower and the first question I ask
is okay well tell me a little bit about
what you're using and their first thing
they'll say is well you know my miracle
grow it's just that I'm beating it as
the bottle label and then it rhythms are
you can [ __ ] with me it's like you're
Syrian and I can't be asked about it
because these you know these rowers
they're they're they're really they're
trying they're committed and they don't
know any better and this day and age I'm
suppressing with what the way everybody
knows Monsanto as much as they do
they're people that are still growing
with the [ __ ] and you know so I do I
have to use synthetics and I have to I
guess I shouldn't say I
- but in my brain the way my brain works
to be fair to everybody and and to give
them a product that I'm I'm confident in
I do I I have to grow synthetically and
I have to be able to say you know how
they're gonna perform with synthetics
with organics outdoors indoors light
that greenhouse um you know it's it's
just if if your goal is to produce the
best and and you know be confident in it
that's that that's all part of the game
yeah yeah completely makes sense
so um in terms of your strains you use a
really good descriptive and categorical
way of describing them to customers you
know you lose things such as the number
of phenotypes and what to expect from
each phenotype as well as you know your
standard flowering times and rough
stretch values and things like that
there are a few other breeders who use
this same general layer and it's really
good do you think this type of
information is it's not only like just a
service to the customer by giving them
more information but it's also almost
mandatory these days because in a way
you're showing people that you've grown
out the seeds you've you've taken note
of all these traits because something
which seems to come up more and more is
like this idea of like you know I don't
know if I should call them breeders but
you know quote breeders who make seeds
and like they don't even test them and
they're just like straight to market so
like in a way you're indicating that
like no that's not me you know like I've
done the testing I've done what I need
to do or in your opinion is it not so
much that it's it's more just like for
the customers benefit oh it's totally
for the customers benefit I want to know
you know because a lot of people they
don't have you know five thousand square
feet of space to work with most growers
have 1/10 most growers have a corner in
a bedroom or crawlspace in an attic
you've got growers that have five foot
ceilings
and so you need to be able to tell them
this is not the strain for you and the
only way that you can do that is by
having grown the lines yourself and it
pisses me off to no end to see these
guys and I'm again I don't do the whole
and I'm gonna call this guy out it's
it's usually it's the bigger outfit that
they run the pollination they process
their seeds they cure them they're in
the package and they're out to market
there's no testing you know where's
where's your viability rates um you know
what what percent of the parent lines
are gonna show what's your male to
female ratio they can't tell you I mean
they'll they'll make some [ __ ] up yeah
of course and they'll put some warning
on a package because it looks good but
the fact of the matter is they're not
testing their own products out and I
think it's [ __ ]
III it hurts me tremendously because
again it comes back to the almighty
dollar and the quicker you can get
product to market the quicker you're
getting a paycheck and I'll go broken
poor doing what I love making sure that
the customer knows exactly what they're
growing before I ever do that I've been
doing this for a very long time I
haven't changed my ways I've not gotten
close to being rich financially I've
gotten rich in other ways that most
people will never get to experience in
their life I've got to share it with my
with my daughter and my wonderful wife
of 16 years and that well to me is more
important than any wealth I can put into
my wallet or my bank account and I want
the growers to feel confident in the
strains that they're giving um you know
and of course there's gonna be
exceptions it's a plant you're gonna
have recessive traits that show up from
lineage way way way gone by and it's
it's always going to happen
always have the growers that are like
hey you know this plant was supposed to
stay short and squat but it grew a
single Cola even when I topped it and it
was wanting to grow 8 9 feet in my
little space it's it's gonna happen it
will happen there's no way around it but
I want that to happen as little as
possible and the only way I can assure
myself of that happening is growing out
my own product and that's why it's a
slow tedious task but anything we create
is tested is tested thoroughly we I want
to know what it's gonna do in a small
space I want to be able to tell the
grower you know if you're growing with
this style maybe some LST it works great
in the sea of green or in a screen and
the only way to do that is by you to
actually doing it yourself and I it's
it's a constant testing process and
there's a lot of times that I'm growing
strains that you know that aren't
specifically for what I was looking for
for my personal use because I'm growing
am i I feel it's probably gonna kind of
kind of sound lame but I'm growing it
for other people and not in a sense that
I'm providing to the dispensary I'm
growing so I can tell other people what
they can expect from this line or from
this line and I want to be able to make
recommendations when when somebody
approaches me and asks me ok this is my
circumstance this is what I'm using this
is this is everything and this is what
I'm looking for in my pot I want to be
able to tell them this one this one or
this one will be right up your alley
this is this is gonna be what you want
for your space for the way you are
growing you you you don't want to have
an you know a less experienced grower
have to change the their comfortability
and grow
to suit a plant that it's gonna be such
a pain in the ass that it's gonna turn
them off or growing for a while you
don't want them to experience headaches
and hassles you want them to be able to
to grow in in their realm and in their
their comfortability factor you wanna
you want to keep it in there you know
and that that's the goal is is you can
you can produce strains that you know
that are potent that that are very tasty
that yield or or the specifics that
individual growers are looking for you
can produce strains that fill the needs
of growers and and it you know and them
not have to adapt to a single plant each
time they want to change and grow
something else and a lot of people don't
have confidence in seeds because it's a
crapshoot you know a lot of people
prefer to grow cuts because again
growing from seed can be a crapshoot so
they like to stay with cuts which like I
said you bring in cuts from a dispensary
and it has its own different set of
headaches
you got the powdery mildew issues you
know any kind of fungus or diseases they
don't really you know not oh I don't
want to lump everybody into a big circle
but a lot of dispensaries you know they
don't they don't take the time to do
what needs to be done the cuts they get
them in as fast as they can think in the
routine as fast as they can in it
getting them out the door as best they
can they're there as a business they're
not there to suit the needs even though
that's what they want you to believe you
know of the person who is sick that is
growing there their medication I mean
you know and and trust me I know a lot
of people that I do help that they grow
pot because they are sick they're not
growing pot to be stoned I mean I'm open
for everything I mean if you want to
smoke weed because you want to you know
that's your form of relaxation and then
it's like you know crack in the cold one
yeah I'm totally fine with that I that
was me before I got sick and I still can
to myself a STONER for other reasons but
most of it now is for proper medic
medicating and if you just don't want
they're already dealing with the hassle
of life with the circumstances that
they're under you don't want them to
have to deal with issues from plants and
growing from clones and you know it has
its own hassle these people will get
spider mites that are resistant to -
organic pesticides so then what are they
left to do I mean its nuclear its its
nuclear war time because if you want to
keep the cut or now get your grow room
back because you brought in some sheisty
cuts from such and such this both it's
the only way to do it you know and and I
it just bothers me because I know this
industry could be so much better there
could be so much more compassion in it
and it all revolves around the damn
dollar and it I don't know it just it's
bothersome to me that's why we do it
different that's why we always have done
it different we always will do it
different and that's I just I I just
want a person to know when they're
getting our label they're getting those
ten seeds their germination rates are
gonna be high and it's gonna do what
they expect it to do it's just plain and
simple it's that easy and the only way
it's gonna happen is if you your self
are growing them out and I'm not saying
oh yeah we we tested we tested five of
those strings you tested five so you
yourself than you test the whole pack is
something you created that you're not
selling to the masses no we tested a
hundred and five you know I mean we went
through fifteen packs of ten to make
sure the consistency was there you know
how many times did we see a recessive
female how many times did we see the
targeted female how many times did we
see you know the exact one that
everybody is after I mean you document
you documents you test you grow and and
that's that's called knowledge that's
that's called knowing your product and
that's one thing I am very proud of my
wife and I I I feel that
we set ourselves apart from everybody
else because though we're not you know
trying to work with a hundred different
strains we're working with a base and
I'm working with that base because I
know that base better than anybody knows
their base because I've been working
with these for years not for months
didn't just bring in the cookies and now
I'm working with it now I'm releasing it
to you guys
I've been working with my lines for
years I'm creating hybrids from my lines
and I've been working with them for
years I'm selecting specific traits to
work into hybrid form because I know
what those said traits are gonna do in
hybrid form one grown out and I think
that's a direct reflection on who we are
and what we want for the growing
community and you know it's just how it
is
okay so moving to a bit more of like a
macro topic for a breeder what's it like
the years kind of you know like I hope
not to offend you with this but as kind
of a more smaller breeder what's it like
to interact with the seed banks you know
like your gear is out there but it's not
like on attitude or seedsman like you
know like those all Cultra big name seed
banks do you not want to be on there or
do you think I it's a bit hard to get
noticed by them at times or do you think
like no I've got you know kind of like a
niche I'm looking to fill and I feel
like I'm kind of doing that at the
moment and I don't need to be a part of
any of that
oh god that's such a large question well
first I loved being known as a true
mom-and-pop if you will because that's
how I see us again for us it's it's not
about the the bulk the mass of it it's
about the refined search product
knowledge and and and keeping it real so
to coin the term mom and pop it
suits us fine no we don't mind being as
smaller well we'll say smaller known
size-wise I don't know I wouldn't say
we're small when it comes to the space
but size-wise and and how we're known
yes yes sir we are we are a definite
mom-and-pop now as far as the notoriety
factor and being on the attitude we've
attempted to go that route we've been
approached time and time again by the
the big seed outfits and both times that
we we thought we were going in those
directions we did everything we could to
stay on the down low to get the seeds
into the hands of the bigger will say UK
guys that are going to do the the
distribution or the Spain the Spanish
seed outfits and both times I've lost
I've lost quite a bit to him and it has
taught me a lesson for instance with one
of them that's now defunct I lost 90
packs of one of our of our lines and
it's because I put trust in the people
because I'm I'm a trusting person
because I know when I tell somebody
something they can trust it 100 and I
oftentimes believe that the same with
the person that I'm dealing with in
often times it's not and I've had to
learn that lesson the hard way and so
we've done it and like I said I've been
taken and it's it's it's it's not about
the finances it's it's it's the it's
about just the idea that you were just
used and so right now we we've kind of
moved far enough away that it's not
fresh in my mind so we are open to to
you know to giving another try but there
there will have to be stipulations
there's there's there's only one way
that we're gonna do it now because we've
had to learn the lessons and like I said
you put trust in two people and it's all
lies and you end up finding out later on
that it was a big pyramid scheme and
somebody is making a [ __ ] ton of money
off the backs of people that are doing
the real work and it's you know that's
not kosher with me and it would be very
nice to get to get on with with the
right crew somebody that's gonna
appreciate us the way we'll appreciate
them you provide me a service and I'm
going to go even further out of my way
to make sure you're happy because that's
how we work that's how we've always been
we'll provide our own freebies that you
can give out and there's a lot of things
that we we go above and beyond with ya
it's just that fear factor of you know
dealing with an [ __ ] who's just out
to screw you in the end you know that's
that's the reason behind that it's not
that we don't want you that's not that
it's that's not the ultimate goal
because absolutely that is I mean for
the last 10 years it wasn't my wife
wasn't real keen on the idea for one we
didn't want to jump into that pool and
and worry about you know is somebody
coming for us all the time yeah and once
we moved out of that and the fear had
subsided and and then it was now we've
gotten screwed by an [ __ ] that was in
this for the wrong reasons and now we're
kind of getting over that and the ideas
is appealing we're we're ready to expand
the horizon for ourselves we're ready to
make the label more known and that's the
goal
is I myself I'm ready to put myself out
there a little bit more because my
daughter is getting older she needs to
go to college in two years she say honor
student straight A's
never gotten anything less than three
days thank you and something else I take
great pride in um she's in all AP
classes which in the states are college
college basically pre-college courses
yeah exactly and you know my wife and I
that's our pride and joy and she wants
to go to Humboldt State and it's gonna
cost mom and dad about 75 K a year and I
want to fulfill I want to fulfill that
for my daughter um you know III want her
to get her degree and my plan is for her
to come back and run run the company one
day but she's really not interested in
that at this point in time but hey you
know there's always that chance and I
think if she's wanting to go to Humboldt
State that's a great start so the next
question would be what would be your
advice to someone who's trying to become
a Brady and maybe they've been doing
their own thing is a bit of an amateur
for a while but they're ready to try to
you know step it up what's your advice
you know one thing I've heard is you
know you really need to get a social
media presence what do you think of some
things people need to do well um it
depends on what what aspect you're
looking at them my biggest advice is is
somebody who is wanting to to truly get
into it is is and know what you're doing
obviously but know your lines you're
working with know your product the ends
and outs of it be confident in what
you're doing and then once you you feel
confident in in your product then yeah
then and if you're willing and that's
what you want to do put yourself out
there go to like here in Cali we have
the emerald-cut do meet-and-greets like
we just we just did one in the Bay Area
San Fran we announced hey you know come
meet with us we ended up on the beach
it was cold as hell great great people
great times you know just put yourself
out there and and smile be friendly you
know be a good person and and and the
rest will follow
you know just it's it's it's not so much
about the notoriety as it is about your
personality and who you are and how you
treat people because if you do it right
people are gonna like it and and and
they're gonna do the advertising for you
and you you know that just just be good
to the people that that are obviously
being good and supporting you and and
just be who you are and don't be a
tight-ass you know give give give you
know like us we probably still give away
maybe not so much now but there was a
point in time when we were giving away
two or three times more seeds then then
we were selling seeds and that's great
there's nothing wrong with that but if
you're dependent upon the income that
can't be a bit of a struggle and you
know if you're paying for all the
postage of everything going out and
everything and and you're you're
covering all the expensive in it hey you
know like it can be a it can cost you a
bit but yeah I just go to events
socialize make it clear what you're
doing be able to have full-on
conversations where you can be asked any
question and and you know the answer
know the ins and outs of what your
product is and and be be passionate
about it don't don't get in it for the
wrong reason don't do it because you
think
gonna get rich and famous that's wrong
to think you know you you do it for the
love yes oh you you know you do it
because that's that's what you love
doing
yeah so on that same kind of idea I've
often heard people you know kind of tote
this idea of like oh man it would be so
good to be a breeder and I've literally
heard this quote like I would just smoke
weed and look after plants all day you
know so yeah is that like this
idealistic description like from what
I've seen breeders seem to work like the
longest hours of any like yeah yeah give
us a true picture of what it's like to
be a breeder you know a day in the life
of it is so not like that do i smoke a
lot of weed yeah do I get to smoke as
much as I want no I'm too busy doing
other said they get to constantly stop
and medicate well let's say you don't
have scheduled days off things are gonna
come up that you wouldn't ever expect in
a million years your workloads always
gonna be greater than expected or
anytime you make plans you might as well
cancel them in advance because it's not
going to take place you know your your
days they start when they start and they
end when they end
there's no I'm working 9:00 to 5:00
today I go in at 9:00 I'm you know might
be home by 5:30 no you're done your task
is done and get used to late nights and
I'm not talking 10:00 or 11:00 I'm
talking 3:00 or 4:00 in the morning we
didn't get to sleep last night because
obviously when at work because we've got
plants on different different cycles
somewhere in the dark in the day some
are in the dark at night so it's it's a
constant remembering who's where and you
know I get used to working on two or
three hours of sleep or we're doubling
up and
and and and not having sleep and then
this time of the year because it's a
harvest season
I get really used to being on basically
on-call because it's it's just what it
is it's not it's not the lifestyle that
people think it is
we actually don't get to go to as many
harvest festivals or competitions that
we would like to or get to do things
with the growers out there that we would
love to get to do because we're working
I mean you know just to get the to do
the meet and greet that we did last
weekend it's I guess a month of
coordinating and planning and and and
and you know I've got a really good
friend
thank God was able to get all of us our
spot arranged and and help me get the
directions and and the times and
everything out there because it's you
know there's there's no eight-hour days
it would be nice to have a five day a
week if I can do what I do and have it
be a five day a week 40 hours a week
type of thing oh my it would be heavenly
it's it's not the the the glamour and
the glory that that people tend to think
that it is especially if you're if
you're committed to it it's transplants
its watering it's feeding it's you know
and then if like I said running
synthetic nutrients you you're
constantly adjusting and checking ph's
and how much it's sterilization of
containers and drip trays and and
cleaning of hoods and it's I I could
write a book on the workload of the list
of things that don't have to be done and
socialite there is none not not for true
breeders you know and and we're not like
some of the bigger outfits that have a
crew that that they are able to pay to
do to do the the grant work I mean it's
my wife and
we do the grant work you know and I
wouldn't have it any other way this
isn't a complaint it it does wear on my
body because like I said I do I do have
lupus and sometimes it's really bad my
13 surgeries due to my disease and and
sometimes it it can be overpowering and
and like I said my wife is the most
amazing person I've ever met she's
probably the hardest worker I've ever
known and she's able to do things that
I'd still to this day I still get blown
away by what she's able to accomplish
she's one of the best growers that I
know and I'm just very thankful to have
a partner in life and the partner in the
business that I have or else this
wouldn't be and I'll never complain yo
you'll never not see me smiling or
joking and even when I have a hospital
visit due to my disease I'm cracking up
with the doctor and the nurses just
because that's that's just kind of to
use a more modern term that's how I roll
that's how I roll yeah so basically
you're saying you just want to smoke
weed all day and not do a bunch of hard
work should probably be a rapper
[Laughter]
yeah so in the recent kind of six months
or so we've seen a lot of I mean it's
probably been a bit longer than that but
a particularly on line we've seen like
this rise in crowd mentality around
strains you know the big one you know
the Big Blue Dream hay wagon yeah you
know you know as a little side note I
always have to remind people like like
Blue Dream like it did so much for so
many people like like it's just all
disregarded in this whole argument but
anyway so with that being said though
how do you feel about the crowd
mentality you know and you kind of
alluded to it earlier you know like as
much as blue drink it's a negative
Rapp cookies gets a positive rap and
Juji fool gets a positive rap and you
know does it does that sit okay with you
and if regardless you know do you not
feel like maybe in a few years time
we'll see this big you know the same
hate that's getting on Blue Dream you
know that's gonna be on Girl Scout
cookies and there'll be some new thing
which everyone's all over at the time
you know what I mean like it's just a
family changing thing yeah well the one
aspect will just take cookies for
instance the one aspect about cookies
that blue dream didn't have well is the
fact that you've got the rapping
community that you've got burner it's
it's kind of lifestyle
I mean you now have the cookie spam who
they've got an entire clothing line I
mean it's a complete lifestyle so that
one I see carrying carrying itself
longer-term if you will then say the
Blue Dream I mean the hype with the Blue
Dream was because it was an amazing
strain of cannabis that they might talk
[ __ ] about now but you know two years
ago that's all anybody was smoking
that's all anybody wanted that's all
anybody was growing but it didn't have
that whole lifestyle um cookies has done
something I never would have imagined in
in the cannabis community with the all
the choices that people have and and
everything and you it's kind of like I
said it's a lifestyle it's influenced
its own industry it's just all of one
started out as one pot stream and that
I'd never have seen anything like that
so as far as that one how will that one
carry a year two years from now I'm not
really sure on that I see
the gg4 I see that one fading as you
know maybe the blue dream
I don't even know if that one will will
carry as long as as the blue dream did
for one gg4 in the outdoor scene here
she's not the yielder that the blue
dream was if you look at the blue dream
from the grow aspect you could get you
know done right you could get primo pot
and yields that set records even six
seven pounds off of outdoor outdoor
plants of you know lower a grade for
outdoor weed it's it's we consider this
scale on just outdoor it's an A grade
but even the dispensaries in the Midwest
that are bringing an outdoor Cali weed
and trying to pass it as as indoor it
would be a high be a low a so that was
one of the reasons that Blue Dream had
the the the weight that she had because
she was an all-around strain she was a
growers dream she was a toker stream so
you know she was a dispensaries dream
because everybody had it but it's it's
it's like with a particular type of food
at once everybody has had it and then
that's so popular that's all you can
find it becomes a burden and then nobody
wants it so then it tanks and that's
kind of where you know the blue dream
went and I kind of see that with a GG
for show she'll burn herself out That's
not me knocking these dreams that's just
me saying that's how society works when
it comes to these dreams and people want
variety you know people want in the
morning they feel like maybe having
something that's a bit of a earthy in
sake coffee like you know with with
their breakfast or with their with their
their coffee and in the evening they
want something fruity you know so
there's there's gonna be variety and you
know there's ice I see it being any more
like that but again I'm not I don't know
I I'm just
big on the whole the this the strain
name game in the cut of the month I mean
you look at sherbert cherry pie and
they're all great they're they're all
really great but just to gain the
notoriety that they do and and to have
people do the things they do to try and
acquire it it's it's kind of crazy you
know but III see it you'll have
something else that comes out that takes
its place it's how it's work and it's it
you know it's a cycle and then they
always like go in and they will always
cycle out I think but like I said the
one I I I don't know what to expect of
is is the cookies and it's because it's
got its own it's a it's gonna sound
following and and its own lifestyle and
it's almost like I guess I've been
ii-i've been checked by the whole
cookies thing why aren't you working
with cookies why aren't you you know
making any cookie hybrids it's a
personal choice for one I've never grown
cookies I've never grown the forum I've
never grown any of the cookies so now my
brother my brother's grown probably
every cookie that you can imagine my
brother likes to play the strain game he
loves that because that's what was his
clientele that's what they demand of him
and you know he's that's kind of his
business is taking care of what they
want with what everybody wants and he's
really good he doesn't like no other and
that's what he does and I'm polar
opposite of that it sounds like you have
that more kind of organic artistic
approach where you know where it's like
it flows from me and it's not I don't
want it to be influenced or like
commissioned or yeah anyway so kind of a
a little left-field of what we were just
talking about
who is a breeder who you would want to
do a collaboration with and if there
isn't any
or maybe just as a follow-up who's
someone who maybe look up to is not the
right word but you know who's someone
whereas a breeder who's currently around
you look at their work and you're like
yeah man like you're doing the right
thing like everything you're doing I
completely agree with that for me
there's only one name that truly stands
out that I'm and I hate to say but I
think because he's become so in demand
that and then he's done so well at it I
think it's even kind of changing his his
attitude towards things I don't know if
the attitude is the proper term but it's
it's kind of changing the way he views
things a little bit it's it's it's kind
of changing that that's the type of
person that he is and I'm I'm I don't
want that to sound like I'm I'm dick in
him that I'm I'm not whatsoever because
he's he's what he's just one of the the
best people that you will ever meet it's
just a really down-to-earth sensible
understanding committed guy Bodhi yeah
Bodhi is a hell of a guy I knew you were
gonna say that
[Laughter]
he's he's in it for the right reasons
he's committed to his work and he's an
artist
he he's passionate and he has a keen
understanding as well as an eye for what
he's looking for and what he's doing and
the guy is a master and he is you know
he's well known and that doesn't doesn't
really affect him I think he's so well
known now that maybe it's it's starting
to kind of alter it a little bit you
know
I was saying and I think again this
isn't a negative response at all because
I love the guy
and I hope to god if I were to become as
successful as he is that it it wouldn't
change me you know is something I think
that's out of our hands I don't think we
can necessarily control it I think it's
a product of the environment that that
you are now in because your life will
probably change you know everybody's
wanting your time and and you know I
mean I just think that you can't help
but but that changing you and I kind of
think that's what is is kind of taking
place a little bit with Bodhi but as far
as who he is and what he stands for
he's the best guy in the industry you
couldn't ask for a better person um he's
a kind soul
he gives he's another one that gives as
many as he sees does he sells and you
know not just that but even in the the
flower he gives there he's uh he's he's
committed and I've never heard him say a
bad thing about anybody and he's never
gonna be one that talked [ __ ] about
anybody and to what you you have to to
really really like about Bodhi is
there's so many people that are now
making a name off of his work all the
work that he's put in that he himself is
busted his ass and spent so many years
dedicated to you now have people that
are using that and and not having done
any of the damn legwork themselves and
they're now using that and they're
they're becoming really successful with
it because Bodhi himself and and his
creations are so popular that the
and that's only gonna change on that end
of the market the buyers they're gonna
have to be supportive of their of their
favorite breeder and they're gonna have
to say wait a minute I'm gonna boycott
this guy because you're making the name
from somebody else's work and somebody
else's name and I'm not cool with that I
mean if they don't have a problem and in
most cases a Bodie he himself has no
problem with it so I don't have a
problem with it per se but in many
instances I do because you got some you
know dumbass that's never done anything
and he just happened in two years to get
extremely lucky and and put together a
couple of binos that he found out of
somebody else's hard work and he's kind
of now made himself into something and
and it bothers me because I'm one of
those guys that have put in years not
not one or two I put in years of my life
into this and I you know I've should I
probably grown more plants and in five
years than most people will grow in a
lifetime and and you figure I've been
doing this but it feels like forever to
me so I put in a lot of work and and
it's not that I don't care if people use
anything that they you they think that
they get of mine to do whatever they
want I'm absolutely fine with it but
when it comes time to now you're gonna
start using it to you know create your
own label and your own name and now
you're profiting off of the work that
you know people like Bodie have put into
it then it pisses me off because it's a
commitment by wood you know again we'll
use Bodie it's a commitment by Bodie
that you're able to do this and I mean
yeah we live in a capitalistic
capitalistic society and that's the name
of the game but that doesn't make it
morally right and and and yeah you know
that's that's where I'm bothered by it
but that's the guy that that
I do I look up to him and you know III
just bode and I are similar in a lot of
ways he's passionate about his work and
that's that's that's how I am and Bodi
would never say anything bad no one
would bode ever come out and tell people
hey don't use my work to do that it's
gonna take the growers out here that are
committed to this and that are
passionate to not support those that are
only making money me no profits off of
somebody else's hard work it's gonna
take them but the problem is is these
guys are willing to do it and they're
willing to lowball you know and and and
just so they can turn a profit and and
that's what ends up happening and and
you know Bodie already tries to be
compassionate and you know and and put
his overhead you know into everything
and then his bottom line and I don't
know he's just he's one of those guys
that's never gonna say anything and and
he's put in years of hard work and and
though it is a love and a passion for
him I just don't like to see things like
that happen for for those that that I
admire and I think so highly of and and
a lot of people are doing that with with
his work right now yeah I totally agree
and it's sad to say that you know I like
I think it's like one out of every three
breeders or something you know and you
see their genetics it's like you know
one parents the bow tie strain the the
others like a top dog or TJ strain you
know that's their whole menu it's just
all that and it's just like what is this
you know exactly exactly and energy said
you know but I such a nice guy bode
sorry um he'd never say anything you
know and just forever listening we have
actually been talking to him and we do
have an episode coming up in the
not-too-distant future and yeah I agree
totally one of the nicest dudes you'll
ever meet
I don't think you could get him to say a
bad word about anyone as you said and so
this maybe kind of brings us to our last
quite
but maybe the most interesting one in my
opinion for someone like you who's got
such a you know a depth of history to me
it's cannabis I often compare it to
cooking in that you know like you'll get
these smells or these flavors and
they'll animal take you back you know
like they're they're attached to the
memories and and so for someone like you
who's got such a depth of memory you
know you must have all these different
flavors that can take you back to these
different points in time and stuff like
that and so what I love to always ask is
what's the most standout to you you know
like was there a flavor profile or a
terpene profile that maybe isn't really
around anymore or something which was
just really you know so for example when
I read about the Clementine you know how
you know it's essentially an Afghan
email with that tangerine smell and and
that's really unique you know like that
that would have blown my mind back in
the day you know what was the standout
for you for me it's always been the
citrus expressions and it's more common
now but when we were creating and mind
you selection is key and and then
selecting you can find that Fino that
you now have and it's it's amazing but
it doesn't mean that it's it's going to
pass on into the progeny you that you
you know you hope for it but there's no
way maybe in the future we'll have tests
that that can determine how DNA is going
to pass and and who's going to be the
dominant parent but it's um it's it's
not that yeah I think I can pick up
citrus in it it is the sweet sweet
presence of tangerine when you close
your eyes and you break the but open or
you walk into one of our rooms or one of
the the outdoor patches and you close
your eyes and you take in a
deep breath you can almost envision
yourself standing in an orange orchard
and just being amazed that when you open
your eyes it's cannabis that that and
then the well actually there is another
one too and and though you can you can
still pick it up like sometimes heavily
in our in our in our clementines
especially our our lavender Clementine
crosses you can pick it up but one of
the things my dad was known for was his
gums and the most pungent
I just got sprayed in the face by his
gun turret profile that you can imagine
and wasn't like I think it was my
brother and I that were just talking
about it dad skunks were so rich so full
so complex it was it was like being
sprayed in the face with the skunk and I
think we might have been the only only
kids at the time if we were you know
riding around and we'd come across a
fresh roadkill of a skunk
where everybody else is covering their
face gone oh my god my brother and I
like well I love that smell it's so
great everybody's looking at it's like
that's disgusting
I've got to congratulate you you've
unlocked the bonus question so the
reason why I asked that was because I
was digging around on some forums on the
specifically the breed Bay and I found a
comment years and years ago and someone
essentially asked you what I just asked
you know like what's what's your
favorite and and your answer was I'm
still loyal to the skunk family give me
those nose burning eye-watering funk of
it the skunk and I'll fill my lungs
further than capacity I thought I was
that's right comment and so the bonus
question is where's all the skunk
crosses well skunk it's it's almost just
been so diluted it's that heavy that
threw it
as to your eyes what onions will do is
really hard to find and a lot of the
stuff that that dad was growing back
then you know we still have have seeds
of but the germination I mean you're
talking seeds from the late seventies
early eighties the viability of them is
you know 10 20 percent and then finding
them in this election it's it's it's so
heavy in work that it's it's them
they're impossible to spend the time and
it's one of my goals um it probably
should have been my first goal you know
as a tribute to my father but I just I
just I didn't because I just felt that
the the work involved and the purpose of
what I was doing were at that time or
were just they were too far apart to
make it a viable option that it's it's
there it can be found but the gene pool
has become so muddled one of the
expressions that's the hardest to find
is the true roadkill skunk it is now
one of the most highly sought after and
it is one of the most difficult
expressions to be able to define in
plants and one of my goals is to someday
to find the classic roadkill skunk and
like I said by my father was responsible
for for some patches that you could if
you were in a certain part of the of the
valley and if the wind was just right
you could literally be a mile or two
miles away and you can smell fresh skunk
and that was always the biggest
influence for me I grew up loving that's
not I I don't I hope people don't judge
me for what I'm about to say and they
thought about it and I'm gonna go ahead
and say it but the first experience that
I had and
puffing on a joint was actually a non
let that my dad was my dad was so happy
about that he looked at me turned away
and was explaining it to me the profile
and and the natural oil of a and why it
smelled the way it did and and and and
why are our olfactory picks it up the
way it does and understands it the way
it does and he looked at me again and he
goes here sure I hit this just don't
tell your mom and I put it to my lips
and I did and it was it was an
experience I'll take to my grave and I
think I was nineteen nine years old I
want to say and I kind of Tears him up a
little bit but I did it and it to this
day I've not been able to experience
that again and it was his prized skunk
and it just was uh you can have some of
it yeah it was it was amazing and even
just talking about it now it flashes the
memory so vividly in my mind and even
the smell the smell was the taste was so
strong and so inherit into the bud I
could smell it as I was tasting it
almost as if my senses were all working
together and my dad was trying to
explain that to me and I was so proud
that they just like my dad's is here to
dry it with me and it just was an
amazing moment in my life and my dad
passed away when he was 58 though I
didn't get to experience you know a lot
of the things that I had planned on as
as he grew older and sharing the things
that I that I would have loved to share
with him but it's that scone it's dad's
eye watering nose too
throat tingling skunk and to this day
that's that's my favorite it's that one
that you know I mean you know before it
comes out of the bag wonders you know if
your buddies bringing it over before he
comes into the house when he's got its
that and that was the experience that
that comes back to my mind that was you
know I'd been around it my whole life
but that was the first time that my dad
knew anyway that I had experienced you
know at the try hit and the fact that he
got to be with my dad was it's a moment
a petal that I'll cherish I'll cherish
it forever
yeah for sure whoa that brings us to the
end of it was there any comments or
shout out you want to make I'm just
gonna make quick shout out to our mutual
friend Gerald for lining this interview
up oh yeah absolutely that guy's is one
of the most sincere guys I've talked
with online it's just such a great guy
so upbeat and yeah I don't personally
know him but yeah yeah III yeah they I
would like to thank him as well for for
getting this put together because that's
awesome this is this is this has been a
real fun experience like I said I've
never done anything like this before and
I was nervous I was I was pretty nervous
but your interview has been just so
awesome so it's so great
um from the very first question that you
asked I just kind of sat back in the
chair and was like this is gonna be easy
this guy's made this really really easy
so yeah thank him and I would there's um
there's two guys that I add that I would
one it's just kind of a newer buddy of
mine he goes by the name of doctor yet
right and when he listens to this he'll
know who he is
hell of a guy he's just one of those
guys that you don't find and him and
I've quickly become friends that I've
adopted into my into my circle and the
the other one actually there is there's
there's there's two more as my wife
she's she's the most special person that
I've ever met and she makes me a better
person she makes me the person that I am
and then my brother smellin mad the guy
is one of the most funny people you ever
meet I could do anything for anybody and
I love them to death and those those
those are my those are my two right
there great well thanks so much for
taking the time to sit down with us and
I personally think that everyone should
be keeping their eyes out for the the
purple Jackie cube project because
sounds like it's going to be a
game-changer for especially purple seed
game I mean you already do that but you
know what I mean it's just me we're
hoping to finish testing and have it out
around around February and hey you're an
incredible person man just by this
interview you just you just seem like
you've got a great personality
and I thank you for giving me this
opportunity and making this so easy it's
been a pleasure been a pleasure meeting
you and maybe someday our paths will
cross and we'll get to share a tote
thank you so much to the emissary humble
and kind Matt fama also a big shout out
to his wife
[Music]
4:20 Australia mad farmer genetics
forever
[Music]