foreign
[Music]
welcome to the next episode of the
podcast a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts as always you're joined by
your boy heavy days here from the upside
down Library
and we are incredibly grateful to all of
our sponsors
seeds here now number one feed Bank in
the industry or the greatest breeders
the hottest drops the latest strains
anything you could want they got it and
they offer a guarantee on satisfaction
not just germination
check them out guys they got what you
need
[Music]
likewise huge shout out to her friends
that coppet biological systems with
everything you need to ensure that your
Harvest is pumping on all Pistons firing
on all cylinders and giving you the
highest grade Harvest to date free of
pests pathogens with their wide range of
beneficial Predators including the
active RM and the spiderx vital they'll
keep your garden happy and healthy
huge shout out to our homies holding
down the fort down under top shelf seed
bank and organic gardening solutions for
all the greatest breeders for all the
best organic gardening products check
them out it's the organic products I use
and the seed bank that I sell my stuff
through
and last but not least the patreon gang
thank you thank you thank you the one
and only this could not make episodes
happen without use
if you would like to get early access to
upcoming episodes exclusive unreleased
content bonus episodes with bog Hemphill
Mean Gene body 707 seed bank track home
jungle the list goes on please consider
checking out the patreon
www.patreon.com the podcast
hello and welcome back part two of our
chat with the crew from White Buffalo
seeds
talking all things Canadian history
[Music]
land race strains and so much more
let's get back into it guys
I notice you you work with seed banks
but you also sell via your own site and
I've seen that this is becoming a more
increasingly popular option for a lot of
breeders and I'm sort of wondering do
you think we're moving to like a direct
sales model eventually with breeder and
customer or do you think seabanks will
always be sort of the mainstay
I think that um I don't know I hate to
say it but I think eventually it's going
to be an all-legal model
it just it'll be uh at some point it'll
be a lot easier to get uh you know get
into the system and create legal seeds I
mean it's already there like you can do
you can create legal seeds in Canada you
just gotta go through and get a
you know you have to have a little bit
of money to invest I think uh yeah at
some point it's going to be more like
um garden seeds or whatever
weed won't be valuable to grow it'll be
like a tomato you know when we get to
that spot when everything is [ __ ]
have fiber and my hemp bricks everywhere
and weed plants everywhere and you know
it'll be like a tomato or a strawberry
or anything else yeah it's just gonna be
like think of how
there's so many um there's been so many
new breeders in the last 10 years like
it's just exploded like the amount of
breeders
um and you know there's only only um you
know you only need so many
uh like there's only so the Market's
only buying so many seeds
I don't know I think at some point it's
just
it's just going to be all legal because
it'll just be the path of least
resistance
um there really is no
you know most countries there's not a
way to sell seeds legally but in Canada
there is and I can see how
uh in the future that'll just be uh the
model for everywhere
like they'll be
I think I know most places now most
countries now they're um that are
legalizing or whatever have a med
program
um there's a way for to get cannabis
into the legal seed registration program
like there's a
I think it's like United Nations seed
program in every country in in the world
has their version of it
um and they just have to put cannabis in
there more or less but then
um
like there's all sorts of complications
with politics from what I understand
like uh uh you can't uh
like right now you can't really export
stuff around the world because
everyone's got quotas
for like in the recreational side of
things like the UN won't allow
a recreational expert but there's
medical export and eventually I think
eventually there's just going to be like
everything's going to be open at some
point but we're just like going through
Growing Pains correct well growing pains
are really extreme Growing Pains
and do you think you'll be able to
continue your operation in approximately
the same sort of way it is now going
forward with legalization or do you sort
of fear the big AG moving in type of
thing uh well what's happening is like
we were talking about pink Kush the end
of pink Kush the end of the like
Kingfisher
um these guys when they hit the wall the
pink Kush is not selling anymore well a
lot of them are saying well what do I
got to do to become to get a legal
commercial license and like it happened
a decade ago in the medical side of
things
um all sorts of guys were you know
growing Black Market had no intention of
joining the the system and getting a
like a medical license because at that
time it was like at the at the very
beginning you could only get it you know
it was hard to get it more than a few
plants
um
uh like a license license yeah yeah
there's the licenses were by basically
by plant count so but like over the past
10 years that is like things have
loosened up and docked you know there's
like these
uh like gray area kind of doctors that
are or even like nurses Nurse
Practitioners that you know they
understand how the law works and how we
have to do to
to
um get licenses for like a bunch of
people
um with you know
like
like a much higher plan counts than what
was previously possible
um
so
anyways like the
the whole like
um
pinkish thing exploded these guys need
to uh figure out
like they they were hesitant back in the
medical days they were hesitant about
getting licensed through the government
um but eventually everyone did
eventually there's like no even the
holdouts they were like I'm never gonna
do it yeah yeah they're like they all
got their lunch the hardest the hardest
uh these Old-Timers that would like they
would you know like the most
uh anti-uh like establishment guys like
they all went and got uh licenses
because
it's like uh um in California when they
had the you know their medical program
um they just the doctors figured out how
you know how to
disseminate a whole bunch of licenses
and get a bunch of money for it it's the
same deal here so if there's money to be
made
um you know you can sell out you know
get a bunch of licenses
um
to people and uh
like it was you know it all comes down
to like how easy like how much of a pain
in the ass is it you got a license
basically and they've just made it like
really easy to get a license though so
there's really no reason not to get a
license uh
but uh
like in the future I think that it's
going to be the same way for commercial
uh micro like commercial cannabis
licenses in Canada
um it'll just be
like they've we've already seen it in
the past uh the program started in
our legal uh Recreation like our legal
like uh
no no no no no yeah it was MMA
originally yeah or like it was basically
our legal commercial framework started
in 2013.
and uh like initially those first guys
that that got into the system
um like there's a bunch of big guys that
gone into the system initially and then
um like a bunch of those early guys that
got into the system had no idea or they
were trying to get into the system they
had no idea what the hell you know like
what they needed to do because they like
everything was kind of like big
like they had um you know it was just a
new system it was hard to get
information yeah yeah like the
um there's a lot of like money that was
wasted
um and it was just costing millions and
millions of dollars
um but now like nowadays for fifteen
thousand dollars uh
for like fifteen thousand dollars
basically you needed to have at least
fifteen thousand dollars
for one year uh to get your like micro
cultivation license
um and and a facility that's like up to
spec but the
for the micro guys the um
requirements are a lot more relaxed so
uh like it took a while to get these
micro licenses as part of the Canadian
system but you know
now that they've introduced them and now
that they're
um like pumping out the licenses um
it's a lot easier like
there's and you can there's guys selling
like out application
uh like an application uh template
basically
um you just like fill in your your stuff
and uh go get your license
they're pumping out uh four to eight
licenses a week that's like standard and
micro cultivation in Canada so there's
like 800 or some licensees right now
um so yeah eventually like I can see
but I mean it's going to be the same
thing like
is I don't know there's only so much
weed that can be grown and sold like
within our market and we can't do
recreational market account right now
they can't export any of it
they can only export
medical uh stuff and it generally has to
be like EU compliant
because a lot of it's going to uh Europe
and then there's some going to uh
Australia
yeah yes there are definitely a few
Australians who have been the uh the
beneficiaries of the Canadian system but
I think nowadays uh there's there's
quite a few facilities online in
Australia so there's some options out
there
I did want to take a moment to jump over
to the legendary Roberts Creek Congo
a lot of questions relating to this one
I believe it originated from one of your
good buddies Vision creator
and he's pretty tight with you guys
would you be able to give us a bit of a
back story on it yeah I'll start off the
story um
when I was working with reefer men
when we were in Amsterdam we were um
hanging out with uh
uh doobie and uh kaiki from kind of
bioin and uh and uh AC
um and um
we had like we had established uh like a
bit of a you know friendship there
previous to that and uh we just uh
decided to trade some seeds and uh
when we got back to Canada they sent uh
some seeds and uh the Congo was one of
the varieties and um
reefer Man passed it along to Vision
Creator and
uh scabby was actually working with
vision Creator at the time so they
started those seeds
and uh yeah we were like doing big
outdoor girls at the time doing like two
three thousand plants at a time and
grabbing all kinds of genetics and just
going through Bam Bam Bam the whole
basement was filled with different
fennels and I'd wake up every day and
like grab a different menu or something
to try it was really fun time
but that Congo plant the game it was one
of the best in that year with um
uh the Trinity cut was something that
really reminded me of like in the same
kind of Realm like we did them the same
year and they were like back and back
like that right
yeah and uh the rest was history I guess
uh Robbie has uh spread the word of the
Congo and it I mean it's a really good
plant to grow it's easy to grow it's got
a pretty wicked uh beginner sativa High
I like to call it and uh you know people
like that lemon boot policy it's sexy
people like that and uh yeah it's a good
plan I think more people should grow it
definitely
yes it you know what I'll be honest I
actually wasn't familiar with it until I
was at a good good friend of the show Mr
Bob Hemphill I was at his house and he
pulled out a jar and and he only really
has good weed so to speak you know like
really cool old school stuff and I was
like what's this he's like oh it's the
Congo man like it's it's the real deal
and um I remember being very impressed
by the bud structure very very bulky and
he said to me that like he had heard
rumors it might have been crossed with
in Afghani or some sort of Indica well
we we uh we submitted that one to philos
and it didn't link up with anything so
kind of like and when you grow it out
and you grow the crosses you see you're
like you see what's in something like
you know you can tell if it's been
crossed with enough yeah we've probably
we've crossed it with so many things
like so many sativas like that if you
know if we grew up a bunch of them you'd
think we'd hit something like that but
we've never never yeah and like all the
seeds we put out there with uh Congo
sativa crosses like we never get anyone
coming back saying hey this is the
shorts
well sure so you think like it's just
really truly like a a special fast
flowering and the structure just it's
like you know just really One of a Kind
well like after growing a lot of
Africans it's in that time frame you
know it's like really really high on the
terpene which is different you know like
the terpene right but you know I'm sure
there's [ __ ] everything out so what
were what were the um
the uh siblings of that like
oh God I can't even remember honestly
was there like really really crazy MP
Thanos oh yeah yeah yeah definitely
there were there were some minnows that
were uh very uh Medusa headed and spread
out for sure yeah and like uh stuff with
running calyx's anything like that yep
definitely
but the like the the high-end terpene
content of that plant is what makes it
really special definitely
and why do you think it's like got this
real cult following but hasn't quite
truly broke through to the mainstream
quite yet because I remember when I
tried it I was like this is some of the
best weed I've ever smoked
um but yet I myself hadn't heard of it
like 10 minutes prior to that you know
and I I was a bit like you know I'm I I
know a lot of strains you know what I
mean like it really makes me feel a bit
caught out
um why do you think it's not more well
known
I think it's got its own special Enigma
like it it decides where it wants to go
and uh who wants to grow it and uh
people that aren't supposed to be
growing up maybe they lose their plants
or something I don't know like
we've been sending cuts down to the
States for years and it should be all
over the place
um
but you know one thing I figured out
about Canada over the years because
we've had this uh you know more of a
protective environment or more of a
tolerant environment like in the past
um and and because uh everyone like it's
more about indoor a dominated Society
we've just got it's more conducive to
saving cuttings because there's
everyone's pretty much everyone's got a
room or like a light going year-round
you know or during you know at all times
when it's needed
so I think it's just uh it's easier for
uh cuts to circulate in Canada
like I think there may be in the states
uh you know it's more there'll be more
outdoor Growers
um
it just seems like uh
there's just more Cuts being held
or just like you know for the amount of
people what we have here you know our
populations
10 of the states
um I think we have a high proportion of
you know people holding Cuts just
because they can you know you got a spot
to hold them
uh there's less Cuts being lost
basically what I'm trying to say
yeah nice and out of curiosity have you
guys ever uh grown out any like s1s of
it and sort of seen what that had inside
it
um no but that's like a dream that's
like right here in front of us right now
at this moment in time so we'll get
there soon
oh you're doing FM right now
I'm just um
I'm just uh starting to uh experiment
with some uh
some feminization like I'm
I did some feminine I've done some
feminization in the past and I just
don't like the
the chemistry of silver thiosulfate
because it's got a bunch of sodium in
the mix like the actual uh chemistry
e-mix
um sodium thiosulfate and silver uh
silver nitrate and the molecules swap so
you have silver thiosulfate but also in
the same solution you have sodium
nitrate
so every time you're spraying your
plants with it's not like I'm not
um I'm not trying to like be critical of
it it's just for me like
um
I'm into I'm interested in chemistry so
I want to try uh
I just want to try some other
um alternate formulations like I've
tried um I just tried um instead of
sodium thiosulfate I thought to myself
well let's try calcium thiosulfate
and so we made um
silver thiosulfate and then the other
molecule is calcium nitrate that it
makes in the same solution because
you're like when you make sodium when
you make a silver thiosulfate it's a
cool it's like a co-solution there's
like two solutions going on in there
like you don't separate out the sodium
nitrate
so
and just I'm just wondering um in my
mind I'm just curious you know maybe we
can maybe there's uh because like from
what I understand like I don't have a
lot of experience with the reversals but
I did enough just to like to know how it
works
but yeah in my mind like
um I want I just want to try uh a bunch
of different other silver molecules
because uh like the
the basic theory is
um that you're trying to get as much
you're trying to get a bunch of silver
loaded into the plant and when you get
re when you reach a critical
uh amount of silver that's when the
plant starts uh like the hormones start
flipping and they start producing uh
hormones or you know to make male
flowers
um so yeah I'm trying a bunch of
different uh
silver formulations
uh I just made made silver citrate so I
took silver nitrate
converted it into silver oxide with uh
like a
with lye sodium hydroxide
and then mix that with uh citric acid
and then it made uh uh silver citrate in
solution
um so I'm you know I'm just gonna try
making a bunch of these molecules and uh
I think the um
the first one I tried this silver
thiosulfate calcium nitrate solution
uh worked out pretty good but it's uh
calcium nitrate is a double it's a
double vegging nutrient so calcium is a
veg nutrient and nitrate is a veg
nutrient
um so it's like hitting a flowering
plant
with a double veg nutrient is not really
helping it want to flower
so I want like I'm gonna try this uh
silver citrate next just I'm just going
to try it just to see what it does
um and then I'll just spray the other
stuff as well
um just to compare the reactions
are there any specific concerns about
using a standard STS solution that you
hope to overcome by using this
alternative one
well the in my mind my concern is uh by
spraying the plant with silver sodium
the plant does not want to take up
sodium so maybe it's going to be like
not
you know it's not fully going to be able
to upload that silver
um okay and it's also like it's just not
healthy you know if we have the option
of not spraying sodium onto the plant
and we you know can we choose that
option is that possible that sounds
pretty reasonable we I actually had a
discussion with a friend of mine the
other day and we were linking some
papers to each other and there's there's
actually a few different chemicals you
can use you can also use a cobalt
chloride solution yeah that's all true
yeah if you're okay with chloride if
you're okay with um Cobalt and chloride
there's also another molecule it's like
three methyl heptinone or something yeah
yeah I know I know which ones are you
talking about those ones are um
yeah I'm not interested in that other
stuff
oh what what about just just straight
out colloidal silver
yeah I don't know like I I've heard that
that's not super reliable yeah I think
it's lesser less effective you've got to
spray it more often and for longer yeah
you got to spray it a lot so the other
molecules I want to try are um
what was the next one silver
silver by glycinate
it's never been
as far as I've under uh as far as I
understand it's never been it's never
been synthesized before it sounds like
it's chelated with two glycines which is
amino acid exactly yeah exactly exactly
so it's like uh
you can go to the health food store and
get all your minerals now as by
glycinates
calcium bioglotinate magnesium so um I
figured out uh
I think I figured out the path like I
think you gotta you gotta make silver
oxide and then and then uh do a swab
between silver oxide and glycine in
solution
I've also heard you can use just
gibberellic acid
that's right but that one's also not
super reliable from what I understand
and but I've like I've heard something I
heard like back in the day is
um you spray your uh your GAA before you
spray your silver
or after like one of the two and it like
gives a boost it gives a boost to the
silver that's what I've heard
yeah I've heard that it can increase the
pollen rights because a gibberellic acid
you know how you've got like a pollen
cluster it like it causes it all to
elongate yeah and it'll shoot it'll
shoot the like it'll spread the uh the
this diamonds apart and it probably
helps with the ejection of the pollen
too to get it out of that stamina like
uh like when I was just doing some
experiments there I
um one of the plants I sprayed it wasn't
like ejecting pollen so but when I dried
it and crushed in my fingertips
there's a bunch of pollen there on my
fingertips and I looked at it uh on your
scope I was looking at the inside of
that stamina and the inside of the
stamina it's like super cool it's like a
geode it's like a crystal geode but just
covered with pollen grains
so like the whole inside of those stamen
are growing uh it's just like a a a
layer of pollen growing on the inside of
it that's awesome the one one of the
plants I sprayed they just weren't
detaching so they just didn't have
enough
to finish the like to finish the
maturation and like crystallize so that
this this [ __ ] can like detach
yeah sure and out of um interest for our
listeners are there any specific sort of
feminized projects you're hoping to do
like any like cut like you know so I
think you've alluded that the Roberts
Creek Congo you're gonna reverse that so
we might see some hybrids with that in
the future
uh well basically we're going to reverse
everything and cross it to everything
okay every permutation possible that's
my goal with everything that everything
that uh everything that's tested you
know like tested cuttings that we have
in our collection
we've got like uh 50. we keep like 50
cuts at a time generally
and I like we like to get like
occasionally we get rid of you know
we'll Purge a bunch of stuff that uh
um
you know like just I just like to get
rid of stuff I'm like yeah this stuff is
good but uh like you know we have other
stuff that's better in that particular
category
um or like it we did some breeding with
it and wasn't a good reader show like
yeah get it out of here so given you've
got this like incredible collection of
females but not necessarily having been
able to cross them together but now
being able to which two females are you
really excited to see like The Offspring
of
for all of them that's a silly question
yeah you never know man once you start
doing this and you realize that um you
can make good uh good choices by having
good goals to go towards you know
getting used to knowing the plants and
what you're doing and how they grow and
what you want to add to that or take
away from that so yeah it's really uh I
mean you got to do everything yes yeah
and the other thing is like the coolest
[ __ ] comes out of the most unexpected
places yeah definitely like should you
just got to grow everything like
basically that's what you got to do as a
as someone that's looking for stuff is
you just got to grow everything you can
get your hands on yeah throw away throw
it all and uh smoke it all and then uh
like keep the best and then grow them
again you know like you got to grow
every single game
several times yeah
smoke it all again before it gets into
the house that's a good recipe say out
of curiosity I noticed you guys have got
the Congo Creek Haze it sounds insane
would you recommend it for someone like
myself who loves the Congo and wants to
have something similar to that or do you
think the haze is like you know quite
dominant and maybe there's an
alternative cross you offer where you
get a bit more of that Congo
uh if you don't mind uh like they can go
between uh like 11 to 15 weeks if you
don't mind running that long I would
highly recommend the Hayes Congo
definitely 100 bro yeah because it's
actually way it's actually well in our
we like it better I like it better than
the cargo picture yes extra extra
special yeah
it's like the Congo for me has a short
high uh the duration of the high isn't
very long I and I think that might be
like something to do with plants in that
time frame not sure yeah it's a faster
finishing plant you can't exist yeah
like yeah so yeah that makes sense for
sure yeah
but uh so the other days it has that
longer leg tie on it right that longer
creative high for a musician or a writer
or a drawer or a dancer or whatever you
know to get into that place yeah nice
yeah and it's a bit more complexity into
the flavors too but I mean there's
there's such like if your Congo has such
a cult following that people they just
want the Congo like a lot of people just
they just want that Congo they don't
want like no if you said Congo Haze to
them they would like slap you and they'd
be like no I just want to come
uh that's all right I'm not that much of
a purist I would be interested to know
though given you guys have grown such a
wide diversity of you know equatorial
strains and various sativas do you have
any sort of tips for people to grow them
indoors like I know that I've got this
friend he's an older guy and he grows a
lot of Thai and he puts heating mats
under his pots and he's like when I
asked him about it he goes oh I think
I'm replicating the soil temperature of
the equatorial regions I was like that's
kind of interesting any weird fun
creative tips you've got at all I don't
necessarily agree with that because a
lot of the equatorial stuff is growing
on elevation so are they sure sure
they're going to be yeah and like uh
like they might they might be some of
those spots like Colombia it's not
necessarily super warm there like you go
into Bogota it's [ __ ] cold as far
yeah
um I mean not close black but it's like
uh what was imagines like uh all the
Eternal Spring right oh so yeah but it
did get pretty cold there in the 90s
right so those Colombian uh the guys
that are growing are like up in the
hills yeah definitely up in the hills
those Colombian genetics add a lot of
hardiness into anything we throw them
into so that's one of the things the
biosphere of Colombia is presenting
great genetics or our use
yeah nice okay well I mean do you have
any other tips for people to do indoor
sativas I think uh DJ Short says he
likes to do instead of 12 12 like 11 13.
do you do anything different like that
or you just approach it straight forward
you know what I like to do is
um
do the first eight weeks on a 12 12
schedule and then after eight weeks flip
it down to uh uh 11 13 and then uh and
then for a couple weeks and then and
then go until like uh 10 to 14 to the
Finish
so like yeah because you know they're
not they're not going to want to finish
uh like
in uh eight weeks early you know there's
no real advantage to look in my mind and
flipping the light down until like
after eight weeks
yeah so that makes sense
yeah so
the tip is
to try and get your plants down to 1014
um because otherwise they're just going
to keep spitting out pistols below those
tropical plants
that's a good tip because I hear that a
lot from guests that they have strains
that'll do that yeah you just got to get
you got to get it down to 10 to 14 or 11
13.
more it wants to keep flowering the more
you have to reduce it basically
but like some plants they just want they
just need like 20 weeks or 22 weeks and
there's just nothing you can do about it
the slow burn
one of the questions I like to ask all
of the guests we have on who have like
you know quite diverse seed libraries is
what seeds in your library are like the
most special to you and what ones are
you most Keen to run
well for me I was like I have these
seeds called Rapa Nui uh Easter Island
and I've always like fantasized about
something special coming out of that in
a weird way but yeah but for me yeah
that's something that would really want
yeah it's like really hard to
like I was saying the weird the coolest
[ __ ] comes out of the weirdest places so
I just don't I mean definitely the
tropical stuff
um because that's what we like to grow
yeah gives the great eyes and the great
creative eyes and and uh yeah it's just
the I think as we move forward as like a
people you know we'll evolve a finer
Taste of cannabis kind of like the way
we do with wine and it'll become more
socially acceptable and you know we'll
get to share these things more often you
know as people
proliferate those genes more and more
yeah for sure so while we're on the
topic of growing from a a question or
two ago I haven't asked you guys yet
what uh style of growing do you use are
you soil are you soilless cocoa Hydro
what's your preferred method
uh Coco two-thirds cocoa one-third per
light and we make our own compost and we
um
pre-mixed accomplished uh like one to
ten or one day or whatever
into that mix and uh test it get a soil
test
and um
just uh just do basically water only but
uh maybe throw in a few
things that might be needed along the
way
try to keep it as simple as possible
because um
because we grow so many plants and we're
we're growing everything in the same mix
from like the craziest sativas uh to
like the most like sensitive sativas
um to like the most uh the hungriest uh
Indigo things
um but but what we figured out is we
just got a
the more sensitive stuff we'll just put
less compost into it
but like they all seem to like uh the
the plants like people you know plants
are like people they all seem to like uh
a certain uh
type of food
like they're all they all seem to be
reasonably happy with the same like meal
yeah I just we just try to keep it
simple
our compost is made from uh
a bunch of the old cocoa mix as the
Balkan Medium as the like the Browns the
carbon and then we um
we had a bunch of like uh Alfalfa uh
soy meal soybean meal yeah
like six Rock phosphate
lime high calcium lime
gypsum
[Music]
um and then a bunch of the old compost
we'll throw that in there like five
percent as an inoculant
um
and we were using uh we made some imos
like knf style I'm always to inoculate
the compost piles before with just like
uh indigenous microbes yeah I am almost
from our forest around here and then and
then trace minerals and uh lately we've
been we take a bunch of like sulfate
trace minerals and dissolve them in
water and then mix them into biochar and
throw that in there it's pretty like
pretty complicated
um I don't really it's not like a method
I recommend that people try as you know
unless they really want to experiment
but uh we've been like
experimenting for uh like 15 years on
various recipes but we're finally like
right now the latest recipe is like
super close to um to where it needs to
be and uh
I think the last uh three years we
figured out how to like the like where
the recipe needs to be to to um totally
uh impervious to powdery mildew like the
like our plants don't grow like they
they won't grow powdery mildew because
uh like we basically we figured out when
you get a soil test there's something
called a base saturation for the the
cations cation-based saturation that's
like your calcium
there's the cation exchange sites and
they basically they
they measure
um how much of each of those ions each
of those cations is on the those cation
exchange sites like the ratio and uh
really they measure calcium potassium
magnesium uh sodium and hydrogen and uh
uh what we figured out is
to like what worked for us is to to get
that calcium number is like insanely
high as possible
and and to use a bunch of different
calcium sources we've got like seven
different types of calcium in our mix
which includes the The Rock phosphate is
a source of calcium and the fishbone
meal like the stuff that has a lot of
calcium in it so
uh according to Carrie Reams
um he was saying that there's
so many different calcium molecules so
it's like nice to have all those
different calcium molecules available
for the plant
very comprehensive but yet still organic
and thus a man after my heart I love it
when you opened up with uh Coco I was
like okay here we go here we go we're
getting ready for it and like uh fish
this time of year you know we're on the
coast we'll take some fish and throw it
in a bucket and make some for a lot you
know let it eat up and you know so yeah
the local stuff is good you know we try
to get our stuff as local as we can
yeah we're trying to um
trying to close the loop as much as
possible
I love it I want to quickly ask you
what's the back story on the BC mango
because there's a breeder in Australia
whose name's ski mask seeds shout out uh
he's worked at a few generations and
he's doing some fun stuff with it and so
I was sort of interested to hear uh the
backstory on it and what sort of traits
do you remember it having
uh well I've never grown out that
particular hybrid but uh
I've seen test scores of it um it is the
cross is terminal please
the female was
Dutch Passion mango was a Dutch Passion
that had the mango I think it might have
been Casey Brian's Casey brains yeah
Casey brains that's right Casey brains
that was a uh a BC like a BC selected
cut or like a Vancouver Island selected
kind of of the mango and then a guy
named detox
in like a mid Vancouver Island
uh he crossed it with cream sodaka we
grow out a bunch of those and we just
seriously those things are all over the
place like like I said that cream so
okay will give you every variation of
color possible Leaf color Bud color
uh all sorts of like they're really
dense there's cream sodica crosses so
they're they're really nice like they
look nice and stuff
um but uh
we've selected out uh a semi-auto fan
all of that that's like super hard to
keep and it was super hard to keep in
veg and when you would put it out it
just wouldn't it was it was like the
mighty might you'd put it out and it
would only grow uh like three feet tall
or whatever
for all intensive purposes it was
autofiring
um but I classified as semi-auto
so anyways that was that was the female
side and uh we crossed that with uh
Northern Lights that came from Steve
tuck
and Steve tuck used to work in Holland
for I believe he worked for uh Scentsy
uh
Dutch Passion one of those
so he he claimed he had like a a good an
online didn't seemed to be all right
nice yeah but like that that particular
NL line I grew it outdoors in uh BC and
it actually like this should actually
worked Outdoors so
yeah it actually uh had good mold
resistance and was relatively early
interesting stuff another another
cutting from back in the day the UBC
chemo that was like a real famous
Canadian clone
um and you occasionally see people bring
it up today but not too many people have
it
what what made that cut unique you know
and and how would you describe it to
people I've never tried it or smelled so
I've got no idea what it's like I would
call it a wheelchair weed like it didn't
have a lot of character but it had a
good uh medicinal properties like very
uh narcoleptic and uh you know green
apple sour green apple kind of yeah and
it was nice uh they're kind of like they
look like it looked like a Nepalese
definitely I'd really like uh
serrated sharp uh thin leaves and there
was two fennels there's a short minnow
from Montreal and then the West yeah but
that's not that's has nothing to do yeah
there's there's another chemo in in
Montreal that like kind of confused the
city yeah yeah but it was like unrelated
but ironically it came from BC from some
some dreddy dead man island is that what
they said yeah yeah
at Denman Island or Deadman Island but
the French guy kept saying dead man
Island and I'm like oh Denman Islands
that's great are there any other
Canadian genetics that you think deserve
more of a rep but have never really got
the attention they Merit
well a lot there's a lot of stuff that's
extinct that we can't even say you know
like that Queen who knows like and some
of those hash plants are pretty cool
they're just not like a lot of this
stuff back then was a little bit rougher
like it's not the same it's you know
it's like tops out at 20 or uh 20
whatever percent THC like the
that's the difference like the the you
know the stocks the the trichome stocks
are smaller you know like they're not
the this really flashy read from today
with really long trichome stocks that
like bend over and reflect the light
really well and like cover all the
foliage so all you see are like these
shiny trichomes you know trichom stocks
like so
yeah just on the like the cannabinoid
ratio and the way it looks and you'll
not as
um it's not as uh nice in the bag
yeah it's definitely evolved for sure
and like uh the flavors were different
back then like the hash plant was really
uh uh rancid yeah it's like around said
um like uh popcorn parts and and uh
um
it just reminded me of like something
like rancid oils or something like brown
said uh
socks I think you all around this box I
was gonna say pee pants but I didn't
want to bring into it so yeah yeah they
got they all got but it's kind of a cool
one yeah the uh the Jordan godbud yeah
yeah
and that's uh it's like off County uh
perps that cross like he had like a
Scentsy Afghan Afghan one or something
like that um
that uh they had there was an old cut
called Perks that was uh from the island
it's like Afghani or Pakistani or
something
um and it would finish outside but it's
like not uh it's it's good it's really
good it's got uh nice medicinal
qualities but today it would just be
like whatever you know people would
more or less would pass it over
you know because it's not like a super
uh
flashy and type Buds and harder to grow
yeah it's it's not like super loud or
anything but anyways uh uh Jordan uh I
believe you crossed did the cross in the
back cross with Afghani and then came
out with this a selection called called
the Jordan Scott bud and um
that one's like super stinky it was it
was popular for about five minutes
before everyone realized it was the
stinkiest plant going and everyone's and
it was a really uh really a little
bigger
it's a Vegit out it was just took a long
time to veg your plants up yeah
um but it was it was super uh stinky and
it had a nice
rancid uh old man pee pants with uh
with grape it's a nice great flavors in
there
yeah look I've had some nice God but
before uh just grown from seed probably
not the select clone but it was nice
stuff I gotta say but I did want to ask
you because I've been wondering about
this forever this is a bit of a
throwback one for you see Ray but um the
gorilla gold that's that's an
interesting strain I think you were a
part of the creation of that were you do
like if if so can you give me some of
the back story on it and as just a quick
follow-up
I read rumors online that it involved um
Mighty might in the breeding is that
true
actually uh uh scar be nice more about
that one um yeah yeah Mighty mate Afghan
would be money made Afghan early gold so
there was uh money made Afghan and just
to talk about the the mighty mate Afghan
seed line oh okay yeah like uh I guess
the mighty mate was uh thrown around
here a lot it's very very tiny little
short plan
and uh yeah it would grow like three
feet it was uh semi-auto so you keep
your mom and veg make a bunch of cuts
throw them out and they'd only grow like
three foot one big stick
and you could grow it in a bunch of pots
and put it in you know like uh a drip
system Outdoors
um yeah I finished really quick it was
one of the quicker ones that people did
so they could get it off to the market
but it didn't last very long and uh the
guys were throwing the afghanis around
uh at the time and it uh yeah they they
had that was it you think it was a
um the auto Afghan from Scentsy seeds
that they threw into that
or was it just because it was a mighty
might
it's hard to say yeah it's hard to say
because they were like dead grateful
Head Grateful Dead uh you know hippies
that just use various names like this is
Afghan but it could be you know oh yeah
anyways they had it they had us there's
a seed line
that was circulating around the the
northern Gulf Islands yeah of Mighty
might afghan that they inbred
and then it get crossed into this uh
early gold cutting which was a Himalayan
and it flowered really quickly uh a very
sparse Bud uh and it would be one of the
first ones we would cut down and you're
talking about their early goals yeah the
early goal talking about the Himalayan
side of it and where did that come from
a guy in Ontario that's all I know
that's all I know about it but I all I
know is Himalayan and it made one of the
uh most uh soupiest hashes like meltiest
ashes you've ever seen it like stick to
everything and yeah so the guys were
just trying to find stuff that would
finish outside here and uh mixing all
this stuff together at uh yeah the early
Bramble became oh yeah the first
generation of gorilla gold was called
early Bramble really ramble by Texada
Island Seed Company
yeah but it was it was Texas I don't see
so many patches that oh yeah Patchwork
seeds Patrick seeds uh through
Montgomery seed and kind yeah
yeah so that was the first generation of
the gorilla gold and then it got passed
to breeder Brad in Ontario and he did
some work with it
um and then he passed it to a guy in
Manitoba
uh we went by Greens on
a form called unleashed the the green
um
and then and then he said he uh sent me
some seeds and I did some work with it
which is kind of funny because it's
originated here and then it went across
down right back to the same [ __ ] spot
yeah pretty weird yeah they were right
we're pretty close to Texas
interesting stuff interesting stuff
I was also curious to know you're in one
of your crosses you use an island purple
Indica do you happen to know is that the
same one that goes around like
Washington and Oregon the it's just
called Purple Indica I don't think so
yeah I think that one's different
because I was looking at it uh uh uh
inspect uh grows it I think yeah yeah
um it's different I'm pretty sure
but yeah they call that they call it the
perps or the Vancouver Island groups or
the Vancouver and purple Indica but I
think it's just it's just a generic name
you know purple index I'm sure there's
like a thousands it's got really awesome
candy smell and taste it's really
beautiful like but it's yeah it's just
um it's one of those plants that's just
um real hard to grow it's a pain in the
US to grow and it's just there's a lot
of easier things to grow and it was like
a later finishing outdoor plant back
then so it's just too late of a finisher
nowadays here
but still it's still around
it's one of the old ones it's probably
from the 90s if I had to guess yeah I
mean there's still people growing up
speaking of ones from the 90s early
2000s
I think you're involved in the Willie
Nelson with reefer man is is that true
at all and and I guess as a general
follow-up whether that's true or not
it's a pretty popular strain from
everything I read but like no one really
seems to hold on to it anymore do you
know why that might be
uh well when you grow the seeds you know
there's um
variation
um but we we got the we got the cup
winning cup out of like growing a few
f1s like a couple bucks or two or three
packs at one so
um there's some good Cuts in there
yeah I like the lemony ones the the yeah
the the sort of like beautiful Rusty
lemonade or whatever yeah there's some
uh there's some ones that I classify as
old lady perfume
they've got this uh like uh
very floral you know smell but with this
electric like lemon juice smell in there
there's definitely some good ones in
there um the PM resistance wasn't the
wasn't the best on those so you know
that may I don't know if that's part of
it but also they're uh you know they're
was people don't hang on to stuff that's
more than 10 weeks flowering you know so
I said probably a large part of it and I
never liked that Vietnamese black mother
yeah
they're they're all right um there's
definitely some good ones in there um
but we you know we also sent around that
uh the the
the the cup cut and uh like I don't you
know that was a long time ago
yeah things things get lost over time
and like I was saying in the states uh
um it's hard I think it's harder to keep
that's
around there
certainly so from the breeding point of
view how do you go about testing your
males one of our listeners was wondering
and specifically they wanted to know
like with the haze is because you can
see on your Instagram that you flower
the boys out and you really like to look
at them and that's great and I guess
they're sort of wondering given that
some of these hazes can go a long time
is there another way you do it or do you
just like rough it out and you're like I
got a flower this thing that holds by
well we uh when we initially grew those
there was six males and uh
like we we like to do a good flowering
of them and then just and then
constantly smelling them because those
males are just constantly changing
smells
um we just like get it right get right
in there and smell them like try and get
in there at the peak flowering um like
just constantly smelling them every week
and uh it's pretty obvious like when you
grow the females like the whole the
whole idea
um doing selections and uh inbreeding
and like trying to pair the ones
together that you like is uh
you grow the females first and you find
the females you like and then you try
and like get a good handle on what the
smells coming off those are and then you
go look at your males
and uh try and just try and match up
those smells I mean as for the
from the point of view trying to find
the best uh you know the best smells
that might correlate to
it was like the highest or that you're
looking for
but yeah so we uh we had six initially
and then we selected three out of those
and then um
we just cross those like those three
males we cross to some of the others
um but then we um we still had the
original three males and then we we
stuck the three males outside they were
basically those those six males they
segregated into two there was two types
I would say two types
um one that was more lemongrassy and
grassy like the lawn smelling
and and uh those were the ones that we
didn't favor and the ones that we
favored are more uh citrusy uh
uh like tropical flowery
they also had like this crazy onion
smell in them as well
um which apparently I've been told
that's that's a sign of a true like a
good Haze how's that onion smell in it
so there must be some weird uh terpene
so yeah we stuck those three uh males
like clones of those males outside
um in like September um just to see what
they would do
and uh
there was one that was just like it
looked like it actually liked it outside
the other two were like yeah no this
sucks we're not uh meant to be growing
in outdoors in the coast of BC
um but the one guy was like yeah this is
all right
uh and they were like we like we grew
out some of the the crosses with all
three males and they were all like good
like the ones that you could tell which
ones came from each male just on the
nodal spacing
and like the bud structure
um but the ones that had they had like
really nice bud structure outdoors and
they were flowering like they're the
males were flowering pretty decently and
they had they actually had pretty good
uh mold resistance
um
they're just uh like it's just a
superior growing plant like the highs
were the same and the player like the
Terps were pretty similar but yeah the
the structure and everything they're
just way Superior for growing and
they're like uh fought a little bit
faster finishing
um So eventually we just uh we got rid
of the other two Haze nails and just
kept that one to
to breed with
and then we eventually
um
we cross out with uh there's a local
cutting of the seedsman original Haze
um from one of our buddies back in the
day that he gave us and we crossed out
with the uh
original Haze our original Haze stud
mail and we've just started growing out
some of those and we're gonna like
continue forward with that as a line
and we just did a
50 oh we grew at like 50 seedlings and
uh there's like 30
emails in there
and from those 30 we selected out two
but one is like Superior for a high-wise
um they're both like they both smell
really good
um one's a little bit faster but uh like
a little bit longer flowering one that's
the one we're gonna use for um
we were doing some feminis crosses
so like we've done a bunch of these
crosses with
original Haze males so now we want to
replicate those ones that worked out
good with uh
with the female feminized Style
nice that's exciting you you actually
managed to bang off a few questions I
was going to ask you about what can we
look forward to in the near future so
that's exciting
I guess we've just got a few patreon
questions before we get to the final
little quick fire ones we do with
everyone I'd be interested to hear your
answer to this one because you've got
such a vast experience with it what is
the best outdoor variety to you and what
makes a strand good for outdoor from
your perspective
it's worth growing
like it's good enough to smoke like a
lot of outdoor stuff is
in this day and age just like the
standard is the standards are way higher
than it was for us back in the day so
like we're in a tough spot for growing
and really we should just be growing
everything in a greenhouse
um
but it's
you know we're it's also nice to be able
to breed or like grow something not just
grow straight outdoors and gives you a
really nice quality product but it's
like really
really hard to pull that off here
you got to grow a ton of plants and
like you need you need to grow like a
thousands thousands of plants to also
like to come out with a good like really
good outdoor strain that's where it's
growing
that ticks all the boxes like a lot of
outdoor stuff is just
developed just to be uh mold resistant
uh like good enough to finish
and make it you know a good looking
product and
the good like don't get me wrong it's
good medicine and stuff but um it's not
what people expect in the standing yeah
people are just are over yeah the whole
outdoor thing died it was like a really
big Community thing they want their
quads and their their pants it's all
kind of just faded away with the market
yeah
definitely a sentiment we've heard from
other guests as well ironically in the
legal Market
there's now eight hectares of outdoor
growing grown for every hectare of
indoor
so the legal Market is uh
I think a lot of it just gets turned
into oil and edible so there's uh like
the carts
the carts are huge in the legal Market
and the like the markups on carts are
insane
so in your opinion what are some of the
best varieties you guys offer for flower
and what are the best for Harsh we've
got some concentrate enthusiasts in our
patreon crew and so yeah what what would
you recommend for flour and what would
you recommend for hash just in terms of
your personally what you like
well all the uh all the new Irene um
sorry all the new Iraqi crosses are
getting good reviews so
we grew a bunch of them they were all
pretty awesome
um like it all depends how I when people
ask me
um you know would you recommend I always
ask first uh how many which you know
what do you like to smoke and would you
like to grow
um how many will weeks are you willing
to go
if you're into longer flowering stuff so
we're just you know we try to
have a little bit of Indica like froster
flower and stuff but our main focus is
uh like longer far and stuff
um
so I don't know I feel like the question
is you know are you
um
you willing are you a sativa Enthusiast
or you know are you
sativa are curious
or you could break it down like this you
could break it down like uh sativa
strains and hash they don't yield very
well so they're not going to be put into
the market at all people aren't going to
try them a lot you know it's like a
labor of love kind of thing and where
you have these fancy glossy cushions
that make really good Ash returns you
know and uh so you could you could break
it up like that kind of thing yeah but
we haven't like we haven't washed uh
we haven't watched any of these Iraqi
crosses yet yeah
but we're going to do um we gotta we got
a GMO and uh Forum cut so we'll do Iraqi
uh gml form process I'm sure there's a
wash yeah they can probably count not
much
I like that but we don't we don't uh
like we're not like we're not making
hash so
um we're not washing stuff
so that's not really our Focus
we do a lot of live resin right now so
we get to uh yeah but at some point like
it's it's definitely uh
something that we have to do is because
a lot of people are asking for it so you
have to start washing a bunch of stuff
and like I'm trying to get stuff to
people that want to do those test washes
so yeah there's people out there that
want to do test washes so maybe we'll
slip you some test seeds
yeah please everyone if you can get in
touch uh one of that listeners said
um be sure to ask see Ray what's the
backstory on his Jamaican
uh that's uh uh scavy's story
um it came from a friend who was at the
first Jamaican Cannabis Cup and it won
the first Jamaican Cannabis Cup by 2006
or 2006 or seven somewhere around there
probably yeah Negril uh uh the seed came
out of the bud it was came back to
Canada this guy's name was uh Biggie or
something like that yeah on the beach or
something yeah I think that was it yeah
I can't remember right now yeah he's
brought it back to Canada
um there's a bunch of minnows and they
all really had that pineapple skunky
smell but one of them had the high too
so ended up keeping the one with a good
high and the Funky smell and it's the
only plant that like really stinks and
veg for me like really really [ __ ]
reeks you know
um yeah it's got a really complex
interesting smell but the beautiful
plant not a big Gilder but
um this really good bug man if you if
you want to experience something
different you know uh super potent super
potent too yeah yeah I'd whacks you
right in the third eye it's like getting
hit with a baseball bat yeah check that
[ __ ] out it is good like that cross with
the Pune hands some of my favorites
you're making me remember now yeah
that sounds lovely you like they're
really um for skunks they have some
really beautiful uh uh fruity and floral
uh there's smells in there like uh like
Berry smells and uh
nice uh
rotting uh like watermelons or something
or not watermelons but super strong weed
super good weed and if you ever get a
chance definitely grow it you know and
just to confirm because I've seen you
describe it on the side as uh with the
word skunk in there the pineapple skunk
do you think that it's like uh a
Jamaican quote land race that sort of
happens to be like that or do you think
it's some sort of hybrid European
influence something
there's not there's no such thing like
nowadays as a Jamaican language no yeah
yeah yeah there's a
I mean from what I can tell us
guys save seed there and uh you know
they don't um
there's not a lot of stuff left over
from the Glory Days so they take what
works and what they like and they keep
moving forward with it you know I think
that's the major mentality and uh yeah
there's like some of them had the kicker
high and some of them didn't that's what
it boiled down to really I mean yeah
yeah okay sure it's probably a mix of uh
you know various hybrids yeah I would
imagine
foreign
[Laughter]
so another one of our listeners asked
would they be able to tell us a little
bit about the Highland Nepalese father
that was in the ganja wise crosses I
have to admit I'm not familiar with what
they're talking about
uh ganja was there um some friends of
ours that run some of our stuff
so yeah it's uh it's just the same male
that was used for Willie Nelson back in
the day I mean not the same but it was
like done
but yeah I'd say um
skunky
um it's very hashy like skunk uh like uh
and kind of uh
I think
it's it's really good it's like a really
good uh representation of the of the old
school uh Nepalese shoe house if you've
ever had that
um slightly uh citrusy
um
but it's one of the best it's one of the
best traditional hashes I've ever had is
The Nepalese uh like they call it shoe
hash because it came
the first part of the shoes to uh
like the
what do you call the heel of the shoe or
something they would put or the yeah to
press it yeah so let no like they'd
smuggle in shoes I think they were
smuggled as shoes or something like that
that's interesting cool to hear cool to
hear I've asked you about the original
Haze and the gorilla gold the one other
strain that got brought up a few times
by our listeners was the Whitey can you
tell me anything about that at all yeah
it's uh
came from a guy called THC development
and I got a he was on uh like unleash
the green form and uh but he was selling
it through um the the uh retail side of
unleashed the Green Farm
um uh and it was uh said it was a white
S1 but I like we grew out these Whitey
uh like they're called Whitey and the
guy said it was uh the white s ones
um that he like he made like he wrote
some weight s ones and he found a male
in there
and uh he did a back cross back to the
white he was able to get then this is
his story
um like that as I recall
yeah he he got a white the white uh
cutting and yeah that crossed it with
this male that came out of Kelly
connection the white uh s ones
um
and uh apparently like a lot of best
ones if you grow enough there'll be
males that pop out like one out of every
three or four thousand so
yeah I mean I either it's like a like
one of those males which I wouldn't be
too surprised because it was kind of
weird there's some weird things about it
so yeah we grew uh some of those they
were male female seeds
um but I mean it could have been just a
pollen contamination too
but yeah it's a white it's seven it
would be 75 the white uh cut
yeah we grew out uh
I got like three or four packs of those
wrote a bunch of them and we like out of
all those we only found like uh
a couple like a male and a female that
we were that we really liked of those
and we made more seeds
but yeah the cool thing was this is a
kind of an interesting story
um we had this carport uh that we were
just keeping uh
a bunch of our uh mothers
um well like in the winter time
we just had a carport with a light and
like we just keep the light on
um and that was enough Pete to keep the
thing in the winter like it would go
down to uh
goes down to like -10 here in the winter
um anyway so I was uh we were growing
this cardboard and uh one day I was in
there and I'm like oh bummer there's
some plants getting PM um and I just
kind of ignored it and then I went back
I'm like damn like there's like PM
starting to spread here
and I was just like uh so busy at the
time that like I just uh like it wasn't
a priority because I it was just like
some extra cuttings that we didn't need
but we had like most of our uh
collection in there
anyways I'm at one point I was like yeah
this is kind of a waste like I was just
gonna chop them all down start over but
then I thought to myself like why don't
we just like Let It Go and uh see uh
like Let It Go and we can see
um which plants have the best resistance
like we can kind of see as we go along
um which plants are more resistant
because they won't get like they'll like
what are the plants that don't like that
get PM the loud you know
the like at the very end which plants
can hold out to the very end it was like
a very um
very it was like the epitome of a
stressful environment so
it's like it was good it was good in my
mind when I saw what was happening I was
like yeah [ __ ] let's just let's just
test all these plants and then see like
the very the like the
the various uh amount of PM resistance
um
and so yeah we were able to like uh to
to like classify all the various cuts
that we were holding and uh you know
figure out like what's the where the
upper echelon plants for PM resistance
like if you just let these plants go off
anyways in the end
there was a what our white email was
completely PM resistant there's like so
much PM in there like
I was just like I was like so impressed
I was like this this is like 100 PM
resistance at least to the the like you
know like powdery mildew um they have
what's called races
so if you look at the uh Washington
State they have a hops powdery mildew uh
breeding program
and they've uh what they do in their
breeding program is they have a culture
up
their various hop powdery mildew races
so it's the same same uh subspecies of
powdery mildew but various like
ones that they've collect off various uh
like the different hubs hubs cultivars
and they um when they're breeding new
hops they introduce all those six or
however many races and they say okay
yeah they can like
classify those plants and say this one
is resistant to race one two three and
five
um but not to six and four whatever but
yeah this is uh this Whitey was uh like
is like completely impervious I'm like
damn this is [ __ ] crazy it's like I
never would have I never would have
figured that out if I didn't do that you
know if we didn't do that
that's cool
Only the Strong Survive we sent uh that
we sent uh like some stems of that to uh
Kevin mckernan of medicinal genomics
and he did a full
uh genome
um
what do you call it genome scan uh
sequence yeah genome sequence on it it's
like plant
number 48 of
until you have its full uh genome
sequence so that was kind of cool
um and it's like public domain you can
go look at it on the database he was
part of a paper uh I believe like three
years or four years ago now with the
like the
like it had 47 we were like just we just
submitted just after that and he did a
like he sent us the whole um
the genetic like the heat map
that showed um like all the different
genes that they figured were linked to
him and where
the upregulating and downriggling was
going on for the sweaty plant and it was
like unrelated like you couldn't the
patterns were different than what they
had already as confirmed as PM resistant
so he was a little bit skeptical or he
was saying that um
uh people
like people were out like questioning
him about you know the various people
that submitted PM resistance
premium resistant plants to that to like
that um project
um you know like what's the
you know what's your uh standard you're
like scientific like research uh grade
uh standard setup you know like what's
your control environment what's your
criteria you know like
like I I unfortunately I didn't take any
pictures like I wish I would have had a
bunch of pictures because I would have
showed you know I would have been like
enough but um so uh just because I
didn't have any pictures
uh it was it was just like he did like
he didn't really he didn't really um I
don't know if he believes uh it was like
full APM resistance but but uh I assure
you that plant was being resistant and
still is it still exists
well yeah so we made um we made uh f2s
from those um we haven't like dipped
into those
um but we will at some point
dip into those and apparently like we've
sent those some of those out twos around
and uh
people said they're like really nice
they make
um nice fat they're kind of like uh
the Whitey kind of reminds me of that uh
South Florida OG Kush uh Style
of thought but it's not like it's
it's not really um
no it doesn't have like a super strong
flavor to it like a super
like you don't go wow this is amazing
but it works pretty well on hybrids
um and it's it's kind of falls into one
of those varieties that's kind of like
uh submissive in crosses
so it's like a good uh a good
a male for like crossing a bunch of
stuff too without like dominating in the
cross
that's really interesting stuff it
almost makes me think that like maybe
with that Pam resistance stuff you just
found a new mechanism through which it
could be PM resistant you know it
doesn't have to all come through the one
sort of pathway but there you go that's
cool have you ever seen it in any of The
Offspring
oh yeah we grew a bunch out
yeah they're um The Offspring are
perfectly like you get everything from
the
the uh for PM resistance
um you get everything from your target
uh like plant to the the male like fpm
resistance like
from
the female
you know Baseline to like 100 resistance
like you get everything in there so yeah
at some point it'd be nice to uh to be
able to like follow that line and um a
friend of ours uh Dr uh Philippe Henry
he does a bunch he's done a [ __ ] ton of
papers like you got to check him check
him out like he's done some really cool
stuff
um he was uh he wanted to do uh
like a test uh like a study on on the
Whitey
um
using uh what's called a snip tip or a
snip tip and this SNP chip a single
nucleotide polymorphisms yeah yeah yeah
um and he had uh
like he has like uh
a snip uh s p chip uh template that you
want like that he I don't know like I
haven't followed up on that but
basically the idea would be to uh
throw it those f2s and um
like just do another similar situation
where you just let the PM go all to hell
and then you
um take samples of everything like stuff
that's PM resistant and not PM resistant
and everything in between and like and
then try and drop all those onto it onto
one of those uh plates to get you know
to see what the upgrade lighting and
down regulating of all the genes is and
then
like it personally I don't think I think
after you're going through all this I
think the way that we selected like we
found this PM resistant plant is
the perfectly viable way to do it
um like you can do all this stuff
molecularly and and um
but I think like doing stuff like like
doing what we did on the site is like
Superior you know it's Superior in many
ways because we're dealing with the real
real world
uh fun you know fungal and occulents of
our environment
that exists in our environment full-time
yeah yeah like real what do they call it
like real evolutionary pressure so to
speak but
that's uh that's a wormhole we could
probably go down forever we've we've
actually just got one last question
before we do the quick five to wrap up
we had a listener who wanted to know if
you knew anything about the origins of
twixer
twixer they said oh is it got something
to do with butterscotch Hawaiian
yep it's a butterscotch Hawaiian F1
fennel
that we isolated we grew it in um
actually I was
I was working with ganza wise in Quebec
at that time Southern Quebec
um so yeah we grilled some butter Scotch
Hawaiian
throughout 250 of those
f1s and uh yeah it's one of the top
Thanos
the reason it's called twixer is because
twixer is Canadian slang for 26 ounce
bottle of booze
and it was fennel number 26.
I just thought it was like it kind of
had a universal appeal like uh like
it's just a common in Canada that's a
common phrase from back in the day like
go grab a twixer you know like pick up a
twixer like yeah Twix or whatever it's
just like a thing that everyone does you
know we'll party
um how about how about uh I give just a
little rundown on on our like uh
breeding slash I know selection process
because we didn't really um cover that I
mean we kind of covered it here and
there but yeah sure now let's do it okay
so um like what we like to do is we like
to start off
um let's say we're
um we were growing something that we've
that's from outside of our uh like seeds
that we haven't made or grown before
like something we bought and purchased
or um traded for or been gifted
um you know we'll grow um
depending on how many seeds we have like
if we have a limited amount if we have
three packs for instance or four packs
we grow those out
um take like cuttings of everything
um and just uh like
like nowadays we like to just hold on to
the males uh then flower out all the
females uh smoke all the females
um
like try and classify them
um select out the ones we like and then
we'll do the
take the cuttings of the males slaughter
them out
um and I try and do like a good smell
evaluation and actually what we like to
do what we've been doing for the past
few years is when we go to transplant
those male cuttings into uh to flower
them out we like to smell the roots
the roots of the males
so not only do we smell the stems we
smell the roots as well because the
roots are actually if you get in there
you'll smell there's some
um there's some really like strong
terpenes that are coming off the roots
and they might not be like a perfect
representation but
um
they just give you more information
um like about the smells
so yeah like with their Iraqi when we
grew them out
um we uh we did when we went to put the
females or the males in the flower we
had uh you know we had like 30 males or
whatever and uh
so we just went through all the males
and did like stem rubs and uh and um
root like smell it smelled all the roots
and just chucked a bunch just because
basically just smell the ones that are
like a is a the loudest ones because
that's like the old timer wisdom is
just you don't mess don't mess around
with males that don't aren't loud as
[ __ ] that's like the old timer wisdom
but and you know we'll be a little more
sophisticated and we'll try and pair up
males that um are similar to The the
females that we prefer so
um and yeah with flower out all those um
we'll collect pollen from the males that
we want and then we'll go take out
pollen
like go get our um this is all like
ideal when we do in ideal circumstances
like we're not obviously not able to do
this all the time but it's just kind of
like the evolution of like how we're
doing things and how we like to do
things
so yeah we'll
we uh we'll collect a bunch of Pawn and
like we've uh we have a
vacuum column collector that we hook up
to a vacuum cleaner that has like uh
it's got like two screens on it so
it's got a
it's just like uh just some Plumbing
stuff like Plumbing unions
um I'll make a post about it on
Instagram one day again
um but yeah it's got uh paper filter
disks to collect the pawn on that are
like 25 we got like 25 micron holes or
something but they'll collect all the
pollen
so we can like vacuum
individual plants and collect that pawn
onto paper disk and then take that disc
and put it into uh
into your like a little Tupperware
containers with some silica uh
desiccant beads color changing silica
desiccant beads um
and then just let the pollen dry out for
like a week in there and then you can
also see like
if the beads are changing color then you
got to change them out to get all that
moisture out of the pollen
um and then um takes out Pawn back like
put it in uh like make some little
vacuum seal bags and like vacuum seal
that stuff and uh like label it all
stick it in the freezer
um and trying to like before doing all
that vacuum seal try and split it up
into so you have a bunch of different uh
like mail number 17 will have like you
know like three little pockets so that
each time we open up the column there's
enough to do a bunch of pollination and
we don't have to worry about spoiling
all upon we don't have to worry about
opening up like exposing all the poems
um to oxygen Etc
um and then yeah make a bunch of seeds
um and then grow out the seeds and do
the whole thing over again
out of curiosity how long have you been
able to store pollen for successfully
in the free in the freezer um
I don't know like I think you have to
like I wanna at some point I want to uh
do kind of a
figure out with a pretty decent
microscope when you desiccate the pollen
I want to be able to look at it under a
microscope and be able to tell when it's
like look at it and see it's shrinking
down because I think that's kind of like
um be kind of interesting to see to try
and optimize the carrying of the pollen
to get it so that doesn't over you don't
overdraw it
um but like skunkman says you can keep
on it'll keep her 10 years or something
I don't know if like
um is probably point zero one percent
Vitality after after 10 years but if you
got a billion pollen grains yeah you
only need .01
um wow but in the fridge it's only like
uh it's only like six months to a year
in my experience in the fridge
um and you got to be really good about
like making sure there's desiccant and
with in with your pollen in the fridge
because it's a moisture environment
yeah certainly I've heard that I I've
heard people struggling with any more
than say six to 12 months
yeah yeah definitely
interesting and how do you go about
doing your testing of strains how many
seeds do you pop what size pots do you
grow them out in is there a standard
protocol or just sort of whatever fits
at the time
uh well we try to grow
at least one pack for testing in-house
um but ideally like two packs because
then yeah it's just a little better
sample size
um and then just uh just start them like
I just tend to start them in little like
little cells and then just go through
like a bottom
to like number one product number two
pot
um and then
it all depends like how much veg time we
have until the next cup like till the
next room is available so it's like kind
of variable but minimum we'll grow them
first for to six weeks before popping
them in flour
um this is kind of what you want to do
anyways you want to get them let them
get a sexually mature
um
and then yeah just generally blowing
them out in five gallons and up
five or ten gallons usually in like
geopods in the organic mix with water
yeah lots of water and then um if we see
it like we're looking for the major
things we're looking for when we do
testing is
number one is is this a plant where it's
growing or is this like a seed line
we're throwing is there gonna like
people grow a pack or they're gonna find
something worth throwing at least one
plant that's like worth keeping
and uh the other thing is like is there
like if we grow do we find more than one
intersex plan
one intersex plant is you know because
we deal with a lot of sativa stuff is
um I would consider it acceptable you
know if it's like one intersex out of
two packs maybe you know
um but if we get more than that then
it's like okay yeah
gotta you know it's like you know that's
too much
but generally we don't actually like we
don't see a lot of intersects in most of
our stuff like surprisingly it just kind
of blows my yeah
um so our males you know our male like
when we evaluate males one of the things
we do is we just like to keep the mail
around in like beds for years you know
keep it in beds for like a year or two
years because
um you can see a lot you can learn a lot
about the male despite keeping it around
and
um throwing it into flower you know
flowering them off occasionally yeah and
just checking for like uh because even
after a year they'll start spitting out
pistols like they'll be like oh they
just like start for some reason they
just get you know they'll get stressed
out after year because we you know we
like to evaluate
a wood plants do in Clone form you know
more so than what they do in seed form
because uh you know ultimately most
people are growing from clone
not most people but
a lot of people
definitely robust conditions there for
sure
on to our final five questions for the
episodes I guess it will maybe probably
need to get separate answers for each of
these but first one being what is the
best or most memorable cannabis smoke or
experience you've ever had
oh my God
I'll tell you when I'm I was making
brownies out of like guys maybe like uh
21 or 22 I was making some brownies out
of some sativa Bud that and I wasn't
really familiar with sativa at that time
and uh I'd done LSD a few times before
that and uh yeah I ate enough butter
that I was having a full out LSD
experience off of cannabis so yeah
memorable for sure
yeah I had I actually had a similar
experience where I was making this one
uh summer I made a bunch of weed granola
and I just uh
I just I got a little carried away uh
eating it and I was thinking yeah this
thing's all right and I'm thinking I
wonder how much of this stuff I can eat
before like you know like what's the
maximum amount and I ate a bunch of that
I like
I was high for a solid 24 hours
I remember I remember like at one point
I was just like spinning out of control
but I mean that's not I mean that's not
like super profound or anything and I
was just like
what happens in when you eat too much
THC as a younger person
but like um
as far as like
what was uh oh memorable [ __ ] would be
like Vancouver and like around the like
around that 2000s era like getting high
down there with some of the people that
would come into town and stuff there's
lots of really good memories that was a
really special era in that time what was
going on there at cannabis culture with
Greg Williams and Mark Emery and yeah
lots of really good memories of like
fighting fighting Bird right
but as far as like profound smoking he's
thinking of like like 420 it brings to
mind you know just like uh being around
a lot of people and uh but what's up
like with I think maybe the question is
what's the weed you smoke that [ __ ]
popular top everything
there you go definitely interesting
memories right there and if we go to the
other end of the spectrum what is the
most disappointing experience in terms
of
something where like your friends had
hyped it up everyone's really keen on it
you tried it and you're like is that it
oh this one time I grew um some Cali
orange that I got from every seed
company and like we were I I was just
this is when I was new to the scene and
um
it was just one of the streams I was
going around so we just thought it was
the best [ __ ] ever
um because it was growing commercially
um anyways so I grew some of this uh
Kelly orange and uh yeah my grabbed a
butt and my my roommate rolled some up
and we like rolled up the biggest body
we smoked it
and they looked at each other like no
effect like what the hell is going on
here but in retrospect I was probably a
high CBD fennel like that you know it's
probably some you know I had the same
experience with that I was like uh yeah
as but maybe you're thinking of like
what's the what's the variety of weed
that was hyped up so high and then you
went to smoke it and then cookies is one
for me yeah where you're like oh this is
all it is
oh you talking for him yeah
please kind of gets old fast like if
you're smoking at Birth yeah it's like
that three-day smoke you know you smoke
it more than three days and it's no good
right oh is it for the tolerance you're
thinking yeah what about uh East Coast
Charities or what do you think of that I
put it in a similar category yeah it's
it's it's got a really like super
pronounced uh flavor and like really
strong flavor it's got a nice flavor it
comes out really well in the oil yeah
but um
the highest uh just not it's not very
like uh
like a sophistically interesting yeah I
was going to say sophisticated but
that's not the word like uh yeah it's
kind of boring it's kind of yeah and it
just seems to like it's fairly easy to
build a tolerance too
the the East Coast surveys like it's
nice to have like some other weed when
you have that stuff in my like my
experience great so the next question we
have is a fun one I'm gonna drop you off
on a desert island for the rest of your
life where you can grow as much weight
as you want but you can only take three
strains with you they can either be
cuttings or seed lines if you're
confident and you like nah bring on
males
um what three things am I gonna leave
you with
oh [ __ ] well definitely got to be a
Colombian in there yeah it definitely
has to be Colombian for sure I'd have to
have a tie and probably some Afghani
yeah yeah there you go Colombian tie
Afghan or Pakistani maybe instead
but yeah like like seed lines are the
bunch of variation in them like you know
like a nice Colombian with the more the
better yeah it was like
each bag would have like 10 000 seeds in
it yeah yeah for sure
um so on the other end of the spectrum
you're gonna drop someone else off onto
the island someone you're not a fan of
what are you what are you gonna leave
them with
oh some low rider for sure [ __ ] low
rider definitely yeah
something with a lot of intersection oh
a lot of intersex yeah but it's like it
would be like a hamstring
by the time you finally grew it out you
realize oh [ __ ] it's got no THC in that
what the heck or it's like really sneaky
intersex it's like hidden right at the
very bottom Leaf underneath or the
center of each button yeah yeah
that's great that's great all right on
to the final question for our interview
if you had a time machine and you can go
back to any place any point in history
to presumably collect either some seeds
or a cutting where would you go and what
are you collecting
ooh
uh pre uh Soviet invasion of Afghanistan
all through there in that hashmaking
area that would be super fun
um
and maybe what about going back to like
like 100 million years oh yeah and going
can we go to like the planet Syria to
like serious beasts or serious B Star
yeah I think I'd go to we'll go to the
like the series like when they were
loading the the spaceships up with
cannabis to send to to the Earth let's
go there and then we could like smoke
all that stuff and like pre-select it
before it went to Earth
what's this all about dude cannabis was
it a gift from someone else
yeah that's what the isn't that the
normal with the normal [ __ ] yeah I think
that's right yeah the princess of uh
Sirius being that's right that's where
the Cannabis game it was a gift from her
yeah
all right so we go there we go and hang
out with her
[Laughter]
I love it I love it okay so with that
being said I think that just about
brings us to the end of it were there
any general comments or shout outs you
wanted to give or make
for shout outs um we'll shout out the
whole uh like white buffalo crew like uh
ganja wise 203 grower 303 grower you
just uh just gotta look at our followers
list I guess to get the spellings uh
x-grower uh
tree frog medicine
Canada dank
um Louis pojo yeah L.D Pancho
mostly Canadians
um I'm sure there's a bunch of guys I
don't want to miss anyone yeah those are
most of our
main homies
that we collect with
that was a bad side don't worry everyone
inevitably forgets one or two people off
the list so not to not to worry too much
about that well you know again a huge
thank you for coming on the show both
Sea Ray and scabby of white buffalo
seeds for sharing all the knowledge a
bit of your plans for the future as well
as some cool stories about some great
cultivars thank you so much again
also um if you want to check out scabies
Instagram it's uh hop extracts
x-o-pxob extracts and uh White Buffalo
seeds is with a zed at the end because I
lost my uh I got uh reported too many
times that's my original account with an
S at the end and the whole hope is
pronounced hope hope with like an uh W
like uh wh sound it's not the X yeah
it's a the local word for hummingbird
around here
but yeah it's also like everyone
pronounces that differently yeah some
people say hope hope some they whoop
whoop you know some say zaps up yeah but
I like
it's Universal ho Pogue I like that well
again thanks so much guys
cheers thanks for the interview it was
really enjoyable yeah it was quite
painless it was nice nice too it's like
it's kind of nice to look back you know
like it's it's weird yeah it's weird
looking back and realizing all this [ __ ]
you know yeah like like so much has
happened
um and it just seems like time flies and
um hopefully the future of cannabis is
as big as we can imagine it you know
that's the only thing I hope you kids
you know grab those plants and get
[ __ ] growing yeah yeah it'd be nice
to um I'd like to hook up with you for
an update in the future because we got
some cool [ __ ] coming up in the future
that's like uh we got some like really
cool [ __ ] going on in in ham fiber
and uh just like uh some growing some
sativas in the tropics
and doing some like Selections in the
tropics and [ __ ] like that
and we got guys testing our [ __ ] out in
uh
like a desert Southern California and
like Oklahoma and [ __ ] so yeah there's
lots of cool [ __ ] coming up
[Music]
foreign
there you have it friends the end of
part two what a killer episode from the
Christian White Buffalo huge shout out
for coming on the show we appreciate you
so much just like we appreciate our
sponsors seeds here now best in the
industry you normally love them check
them out all the hottest breeders all
the latest drops everything you could
want if you're trying to finno hunt the
next big winner but in order to do that
you need to keep your garden happy and
healthy and to do that you need to go by
check out our good friends at Copper
biological systems they have everything
you need to keep your garden happy and
healthy Pest and pathogen free check out
the aship RM if you need to combat some
aphids or check out this fight excavator
if you've got spider mite problems it's
always good to release some
prophylactically then you never have an
issue what does that mean it means
release them before there's a problem
guys get on top of it copper biological
systems best in the game
huge shout out as always to the patreon
gang we love you so much of the life of
the show if you want to help support the
show please go check out the patreon at
www.patreon.com the podcast
you will get access to episodes early
totally unheard content from the likes
of Mean Gene body Mr Bob Hemphill
SharkBite of 707 seed banks
now I'm from trichome jungles so much
more we're giving away seeds and the
discord's popping now check it out guys
thank you so much patreon we love you
[Music]
from the upside down Library this is
heavy days checking out
I'll see you