[Music]
well well well welcome back my friends
for the epic part two with the hanbul
hero freder
extraordinaire Caleb of
CSI as always you're joined by your boy
heavy days here from the upside down
library and on this one we want to give
a massive shout out to our incredible
sponsors who helped make the show happen
as always C here in now your number one
seed bank in the industry a guarantee
not just on germination on satisfaction
meaning at the end of the growth if
you're not happy hit them up they'll
send you something to make it right the
reason why they offer this is because
they only stock the highest quality
breeders in the game that's how they
know you're going to be stoked at the
end of a grow don't just worry about
wasting your money worry about wasting
your time a guarantee on satisfaction
means you don't need to be worried about
this
a massive shout out to copit biological
these guys are the world leaders in
sustainable bio control solutions to
crop Pest and diseases if you're
battling spidermites check out cop's new
spidex vital plus sachets these are new
personis breeding sachet that release
predom mites into your crop continually
over a period of several weeks providing
sustained spidermite control now you
don't have to spread carrier material
into your garden just to introduce some
Predator mice just hang the sachet in
the crop let the personis walk out and
do the work for you trust me guys you
don't want to have to go up against a
spidermite infestation without spyx
vital plus these are truly the best
Predators on the market the best in the
game I promise you try it once you'll
see the
quality pulse sensors you know them you
love them you probably already got a
pulse unit in your garden why cuz it
helps you track all of the Hidden
variables that you may not be
consciously thinking about on the
day-to-day level and through fine-tuning
these parameters you can get a bigger
yield more tur more flavor more resin
more potency God what can it do whether
you're thinking of running a single tent
a single room a Multistate operation
it's time to get serious guys get
yourself a pulse sensor it's a
no-brainer and given they've just
recently introduced the pulse hub no
better time to get on board to be able
to fully integrate all of your units
into one Central localized Hub massive
shout out to pulse sensors we love and
appreciate you guys thank you so
much massive shout out to our friends at
Organics alive helping the homies grow
the highest quality product worldwide if
you want a powdered simple organic
fertilizer option organic salive is the
one for you people have been sweeping
competitions all around America using
organic salive cuz their products are
superior if you want an easy to use
all-in-one versatile option that has a
range of different products to help any
situation including Bloom veg transition
micronutrients microbes Organics alive
has everything you need they're going to
help you take your next crop to the next
level check them out guys quick release
because they're fine powders all organic
what more could you ask for huge shout
out to our friends at Organics alive we
really appreciate you guys getting on
board please everyone go check them
out and a massive shout out to our
newest sponsor dap I'm sure you guys
have heard me talking about dap they are
an incredible Vape company based out of
USA producing some of the most coolest
Engineering in Vape technology you've
seen for a while these guys honestly
help me get off bongs and transition to
vaping I cannot speak highly enough
about dap's products
huge shout out guys go check him
[Music]
out and on this episode today we have
the Humbolt hero the head honcho of
pirates of the Emerald Triangle The
Strain historian and breeder
extraordinaire a massive welcome and
thank you to Caleb of CSI
humbal here to talk all things
breeding his recent work with the F1
Durban upcoming
[Music]
projects how he's able to make all the
incredible lines he
does and so so much
more without further
delay let's get into
it just to to loop back you know we were
talking about the Kush 4 and its
relation to the Hindu Kush talking about
another Hindu Kush that's been very
popular for you the purple Hindu Kush
tell me a a little bit about this one
because there's now a number of Hindu
kushers purple Hindu kushers
specifically that go around you know a
lot of people are like is this the Yer
one is this a different one can you give
us any insights into the purple Hindu
Kush you use that's not the Yer
cut well so okay
um so purple Hindu Kush this the the
purple Hindu Kush I have is the one that
was made popular in southern Oregon and
it sources back to Millerville farms in
southern Oregon and
uh according to them uh you know they
got you know some seeds
um of of H Hindu Kush groom out and
there was a purple one and that's where
it started
um there's a couple different variations
I'm not sure what entirely the the whole
story is but um um one story was you
know they took a male from from those
seeds and crossed it to the purple Hindu
and that's how they made jger it's just
a it's just you know a further you know
breeding of the same thing um and then
another I don't
know uh I don't know if it's a story or
if it's just my impression but it almost
seems like the Jagger could just be a
you know a hermaphrodite S1 seed from
the purple Hindu um but anyways um you
know and then there's a few stories of
where you know what that that Hindu Kush
exactly is I don't know if it even ties
back to like Amsterdam Hindu Kush or if
it's you know something entirely
different but supposedly the SE came
from uh this Pharmacy uh or I think it
was the pharmacy in like Los Angeles
somewhere around there
um so I don't know I don't know but uh
it was extremely popular in southern
Oregon um for for a lot of years and
every time I went up to Oregon I would
buy some of the finished flower at all
the dispensaries because it has that
similar uh that
similar uh black licorice Anis uh TP um
you know like meno purple s1's
do so
I kind of liked it yum cool and I mean
just to clarify which of the two plants
do you favor the Jager or the purple
Hindu
um I like the Jager better it it's more
refined you know um the purple
Hindu
um seem seems a little broad it's it's
kind of like when you grow a meno the
meno per cut and then a meno per S1 side
by side
you know they're they're extremely
similar but then uh a lot of times the
s1's will like refine you know certain
things they won't have be so broad you
know with their their their T
profiles so
yeah yeah yeah that's cool and and do
you you know you've sort of alluded to
it already you got a bit of a soft spot
for the licorice
turbs yeah yeah
yeah yeah like I love it too and I feel
like it's really under
represented yeah um one one thing I talk
uh a lot about with the you know like uh
you know my buddy Matt right and uh Noto
dog um is uh how the meno purple s ones
this is a total tangent of course but
there's like a recessive in there um
that is some of the strongest roadkill
skunk that I've found anywhere and it's
these little runty like ABCs runty these
little runty recessive plants um and
they just wre of just skunk spray as
close as I've really found you know I
mean they smell like spray whereas you
know the Sterling skunk I mess mess
around with that's more of uh you know
the the skunk got hit you know a day day
or three ago but th this stuff is almost
spray St because it's so
pungent but uh wow you you you basically
answered the question for me but just to
clarify because it was one of the
listeners they said I've grown a number
of your meno pers hybrids they've all
been Wicked and I've been kind of
uniquely surprised by each of them is
that skunk one you just mentioned the
most surprising thing you found in them
or have you found other equally weirdly
Divergent stuff oh yeah yeah not it it
it's one of my my favorite favorite
lines to play with or s1's um and you
know S1 you know all that stuff you know
will show up if it doesn't show up in
the F1 hybrid it'll show up in F2 you
know a lot of times but uh um there's so
much variation as far as you know
tarpine profiles and just variety and
that stuff I had one that was like a a
chocolate coffee
spice you know and then there tons of
just super super some of the fru stuff
you've ever smelled you know and then
there's there's hashy nog shampa ones
and you know Blackberry ones and grapy
ones and the skunky ones and there's so
much in those uh you know it's it's
always fun to grow those things that's
really really cool I would never expect
like a Bubba type plant by the sounds of
in terms of the smells that's that's
really cool and that that plant was
weird too uh it was like a lanky uh yeah
it it was way different than the norm as
far as most of the MPS ones go but
definitely
unique damn and I I mean you you touched
on it the Sterling skunk you know shout
out and uh you know rest in peace zoi
we're all grateful that he passed that
one on when I chatted with bod um in
December when I was in the states I met
up with him for dinner and he was like I
was like is it the real deal and he was
like yep the real deal what's your
thoughts on the Sterling
skunk it's it's cool I I like it a lot
um it uh you know the the ones I
released I I put a warning on because uh
I I would not recommend these to be
grown
indoors U they they definitely can be
some of the worst hermaphrodites inside
um but Outdoors zero hermaphrodites
which is you know par for par for the
course of how things work um
but uh you
know um it's definitely a line that uh
needs to be uh worked and you know
because when I reproduced them did my
open pollination there are ones that
were just you know Rocka just skunky as
hell they they made your eyes water that
so so so strong but you know it it's a
percentage game again you know and so a
lot of them are you know just variations
of and then you know
uh yeah but as as as a standalone plant
it's it's definitely not gonna be the
ticket you know doesn't produce you know
big fat chunky nugs or this that other
it definitely is a building block to
hopefully something better you know yeah
oh look I I was going to ask you know
what would you pair it with what do you
think you would pair it with that would
help help it to be what the public are
in search
of I mean I kind of want to pair it with
a few things um you know just to kind of
start with uh um I'd kind of like to
work like some of the skunky deep chunks
in there um you know to help you know
the plant out i' I'd like to also maybe
mix in the Christmas butt I work with
that has some strong skunky chps as well
to it and it has like some super
you know pungency as well um and then
you know if if you know I was able to
get something you know more so what I
was looking for you know to hybridize
something like that with like a chmd or
something that already has you know a
nice base and the potency uh I I I think
you couldn't go wrong and and like just
to confirm those ones you were saying
you know where it's like makes your eyes
water do you think that's the road kill
smell that people are searching of or do
you think the the thing that people in
their minds are looking for it's not
it's not like as real as what they think
it is and it's never going to be like an
actual Dead Skunk but this is pretty
close well I think people have different
uh things they're looking for some
people are looking for this roadkill
smell that's like a few days it's like a
muscular smell whereas like a a skunk
spray smell is you know know just you
know blinds your eyes you know make some
water you
know makes your lungs bleed you know
it's potent that's what I want from my
roadkill you know because you know
that's that's when you first hit that
skunk dead on no fence skunk but you
know um but you know the the the few day
old Road roadkill is still pretty okay
but I want that fresh fresh but I don't
know if it translates into dry weed form
do you think maybe like whatever tpin
are involved you know the trendy word
THS um do you think that they they're
just too volatile and you lose it really
quickly you know I think back in the day
um everybody was selling wet weed and so
your your your turps are still like
super strong with that wet but then as
soon as it's dry you know um it it's
gone you know with a lot of those you
know TPS and dials and all that kind of
stuff you know um yeah I think a lot of
the stuff we're looking for is is too
volatile to stick in a bag for too
long there you go there you go I um I
wanted to ask you because we we
mentioned bod and in relation to the SK
Sterling skunk I noticed on the website
you got the mango bishe and it's always
been one that's been interesting to me
because I remember bod made an offhand
comment years ago and he's like oh it's
like the blue dream of South America and
I I never never quite understood what he
meant by that but um I've tried some
hybrids and it's nice stuff what would
you say about
it that's a good
analogy I just I mean I've I've I've run
it a few times now and uh that's not
that's not
bad I mean that's like saying it's a
basic beginner plan yeah that's probably
pretty accurate okay it's like a it's a
beginner sativa yeah but but a long one
it it it takes just as long as uh as the
Burmese yeah oh wow really yeah yeah I
mean I like the mango be but uh there's
something about the Burmese like plant
itself that uh I'm really drawn towards
um whereas the the the mango
be yeah it's kind of it's kind of a
beginner plant you know it's it's a good
one though um and is the effect like
super uplifting or it's more in like the
mild uplifting
category ah I
mean I'm I'm I'm not a a I wouldn't say
I'm a a great sativa fishan quite
yet I've been buried in indicas my whole
life so you know uh get back to me in a
few years
don't worry I I'll come test all your
sativa hybrids for you all right sounds
good oh no just the P pure sativas I'm
okay with the hybrids oh true thought
I'd snuck in there I'll share I'll share
that's good that's good um one of the
fans submitted questions was people had
noticed that there were some nl5 Haze
hybrids sneaking into the
lineup can you tell us a little bit
about the cut you've been working with
are we talking like dog [ __ ] yeah they
must be talking about that I mean it's
had a big Resurgence and you know Noto
has been pushing it for rightly good
reasons right right right um that that
that's one uh I think I well and the
chem1 you know that that that definitely
you know I think Falls kind of into that
category a little bit um as far as any
uh other nl5 Haze hybrids uh those those
I'm not at Liberty to discuss right
yet we have to keep our eyes open and
ears listening well you know sometimes
the politics out there are
strange I'm actually impressed you have
been able to navigate the politics of it
all because you know you you do work
with a lot of different strains and that
sort of lends itself to people getting
butt hurt how how do you navigate that
space do you think it's just about like
when you do a project as long as you're
doing it with Integrity like people
can't really get too upset or like how
do what would be your general
advice I mean uh I wouldn't
say I navigate very
well everybody gets butt hurt I mean you
want a
list look at all the s1s you've made and
those are all the people I know
right the only people who aren't but Hur
are you know uh the Clones i' I've
personally held 25 years or so you know
wow okay so just yeah there's no there's
no easy way to do it you just got to do
it no no and you know honestly uh most
of the people who are but hurt I'm not
going to name
names but most of them didn't have
anything to do with creating breeding or
anything you know the the these cuts
that they're all butt hurt about you
know and you know a lot of times people
I I'll I'll research stuff before I
releasee something and you know some
something will have like you know five
different companies making the same
seeds so I'm like well they can't get
butt hurt at me oh no never mind I was
wrong they're butt hurt at me even
though there's a ton of people you know
and I I could tell you many stories on
the topic but you know I I'll leave that
one be for
now there you go look it's um it's it's
a tough one I definitely get it you know
because I feel like the landscape of the
community is ever changing and you know
how do you feel about that you know
because if we look at the commercial
scene at the moment the most biggest and
most popular companies like DOA like Deo
Farms these guys who are like you know
making millions and millions of dollars
off selling you know quote Cali packs
they're not the guys who are lorded
among the he Community you know like cuz
they're they're not like a breeders
breeder so to speak how do you feel the
scene is progressing in terms of that
landscape and what do you think is going
to be the trajectory going
forward I mean those are good questions
um but I gotta admit uh I I tend to like
stay in my little humble County hle and
uh I mean my my long-term goal you know
is um I'm hoping looking to have a
couple dispensaries up here a nursery uh
you
know a pretty nice breeding lab or two
um and then grow my own flower and
basically you know be vertically
integrated and just you know do
everything myself but on a very small
manageable scale that I can have fun
with that's that's my long shortterm
goal you know three four five years
um so as far as you know outside of my
little tiny bubble here um I don't pay a
whole lot of attention to it you
know yeah understandable and golly I'm
sure a lot of people are really excited
to hear that that's what you've got on
the cards do you think that it would be
based in like Northern California mesino
type area oh I I've I've already um I'm
already working on it I've got
um my my buildings and uh working on the
licenses and you know getting hopefully
getting stuff built out over the next
couple years so yeah and and and then as
soon as I'm open and you know good for
all that you know anybody who wants to
you know come through and you know visit
I'll I'll I'll have the spot to visit oh
my Lord I think everyone will put their
hands up to be guinea pigs whatever you
need tested buddy we'll do it for
you right right that's that's really
really cool because I feel like a lot of
people have a very Doom and Gloom
forecast for the industry going forward
so it's really refreshing to hear that
people like yourself are you know I
don't want to sound too dramatic but
it's it's almost like the
antidote right I mean don't don't get me
wrong I don't I don't think there's
going to be much money in it at all I'm
I'm I'm gonna have a tough time just
surviving but as long as I'm able to do
what I like to do I I think that's all
that I really want yeah brilliant
brilliant I'd love to ask you a few
questions about creating
seeds you know part of these are my
questions part of them are the listeners
submitted questions but the first one I
wanted to ask is how long do you let
seeds mature on plants for do you just
let it go the length it would normally
go or do you like really push it to try
to get the most out of it so uh I
generally um you know once the room is
like fully pollinated I don't start
counting down until the room's fully
pollinated or as pollinated as it's
getting and then I'll I'll leave the
seeds on the plants for between six and
eight weeks and you know just to make
sure they're you know nice and solidly
ripe and then uh um I've seen other
people
you know they're they're they're selling
seeds you know next day as soon as it's
down I'm like uh okay I I try to dry dry
my seeds for a couple weeks usually and
then then they get you know sorted and
sifted and blown and all that and then
they go in the fridge for
ideally no less than a couple weeks but
usually I don't like you know taking
them out of the fridge for at least a
month you know before you know I start
start messing with them but uh yeah
that's that's pretty much the the
average right
there yeah wow and and when they're on
the plants are you treating them as if
they're like a sensey crop or are you
like really pushing them with nutrients
and like not trying to avoid a fade and
just trying to keep it stocked up yeah
yeah I I definitely uh uh keep put uh
pushing them with Nitro and you know all
the other other uh nutrients um I'm I'm
not trying to flush them I'm you know
I'm trying to you know just keep feeding
those
seeds yeah beautiful beautiful and as a
followup I myself have been wondering
what do you do with your like the
material that's left over after you've
Shu the seeds you know there's a lot of
heads there do you try to like make a
concentrate or anything or like I've had
other people say oh it's usually not the
greatest material to try to do anything
with what do you do with it yeah
I'd love to do something because you
know I I like I don't like throwing
stuff away I like reusing I like I don't
like being wasteful you know if I can
help it and so you know to be honest
I'll end up with you know hundreds and
hundreds of pounds of that stuff all all
stored up and then you know realize I'm
not doing anything with it take it to
the dump or something the the green
waste I think last time I took it to the
green waste and it became some
compost yeah there you go it's a tough
one I I got one of those little purple
Pro units and um I tested some of it I
think it came out like seven or 8% so
it's definitely not like the Same by any
stretch not that I think anyone thought
so but yeah right right how do you like
your purple Pro you know so obviously I
saw the the discussion um about you know
when you and Matt not so met up and um
you know the the gist I got was that you
guys weren't really convinced about it I
think for me you know I I tested it a
lot and I think it works I think my
overall summary would be that I feel
like it really confirm it just confirms
what you already know you know like you
you you test a plant that's your
favorite plant and you know not like a
chem 91 but like a plant where you're
pretty confident it's pretty potent and
you know sure enough it will be the most
potent that you get tested M the thing
that I definitely thought was a hurdle
was that um you have to do a lot of
tests and then take the average um and I
thought that from a consumer point of
view people really want something where
you just put something in you hit the
button and then you get the accurate
answer straight away so I I think it's
something that can be used you got to
know how to use it um but it it's
definitely not perfect yet right right
yeah I'm I'm still a little suspicious
but
yeah well like I mean that's the thing
it's working on an algorithm which you
know it they they provide the paper so
you can read how they develop the
algorithm and I I trust that part of it
but it seems like there's a lot of
variables and when I've been discussing
it with some other listeners who have
one as well we all seem to come to the
conclusion that there needs to be a far
more standardized way in which you load
it in because we've all noticed if you
just you know you fill it with some herb
and you do the test if you pull that
same little puck out and just like break
it up and then repack it back in so that
it's all the particles have been moved
around you can get variation so it seems
like there needs to be a very
standardized way to test it so that when
I'm telling you what I got it's the same
as what you're getting right right
gotcha maybe maybe I need to use a
little more i' I've got a bunch of stuff
I bought at a bunch of uh organ uh
Southern organ dispensaries and they got
their numbers on them so as planning to
test him here pretty soon I mean it
would be cool to see like the
incorporation of it into a breeding
program cuz that was what they really
pitched to me and and you know the
theory sounds solid where they were
saying you can test stuff like basically
apparently as soon as you get like resin
on the plant basically you can test it
and of course the numbers are going to
be like less than 1% but they'll still
vary and they they seem to suggest when
I was interviewing them that the the
stuff that tests higher earlier will be
the stuff that tests higher later as
well and they were basically saying you
can start thinning plants out in like
you know week four week five just based
on those preliminary numbers and I
thought that would be interesting for
someone like you who you know is going
through 500
plans right right yeah interesting
interesting stuff nonetheless just as a
a follow on from what we were talking
about earlier you know you're talking
about this facility one of the listeners
was specifically Keen to know would you
ever consider releasing
clones oh definitely definitely um once
I I have my you know my vertical
integration all going um my my uh main
focus would be uh I think a lot of
people don't want to you know uh you
know select their own you know seed seed
plants they don't want to you know grow
out a bunch of seeds and make their own
selections blah blah so one of the
things you know I definitely would be
doing is
growing out these populations making
selections choosing plants uh you know
for indoor grow outdoor grow you know
bunch of different things I really want
to you know make some ABC selections
types that people can grow in their
front yards or whever and just be like
haha you know but you know make them
selected plants so people don't have to
root through a 100 or 200 seeds uh you
know that might not be the best to find
good ones and so that that that's kind
of where where I'd be heading with with
all that for sure sure and and do you
think generally speaking the future of
growing is going to be more in clones or
you think it'll always be
seed well I think they all have their
place you know um you know clone clones
can be reliable um but you know SE seeds
are easy and also seeds you know pop
them in your fridge prop them your a
freezer they're good for 10 or 20 years
you know definitely definitely they're
like a bit of a Time vault in that sense
aren't they yeah yeah so I wanted to ask
you what do you think would have a
better chance of
success let's say you got a clone and
you want to improve it you know you're
like I've got this plant I really like
it there's there's one or two things I
can acknowledge are not perfect and
would be better if they were maybe you
know bigger yield better structure do
you think you would be best to S1 it and
run through like 100 females and just
try to find a plant or two that has
those improved traits or do you think
you would be better to just try to make
some hybrids with a plant like a male
that you know maybe generally speaking
that line of the male has like better
structure and then you're just trying to
select a plant that's like mostly
leaning to the mom with a few better
traits right
um I don't know uh I think i' I'd lean
towards you know
s oneing it running running a bunch out
um and then um maybe ideally uh you know
finding a uh like an outcross type that
doesn't push anything
forward and or much of anything you know
like maybe structure or whatever but not
like Tarpin or potency or whatever
whatever and then you know make a hybrid
that you know takes the best qualities
of that you know and then uh you know
make some fairly stable SE seed lines
mhm and I guess as an extension of that
let's say let's say we're talking about
the TK CU I know you've done a lot of
work with the s1's of that TK generally
speaking you know it's it's got a bit of
stretch to it it's certainly not like a
squat Inda thing do you think if you
hunted through enough s1s you could find
something that is like quite squat or
there's like a limitation like if the
plant you're working with is very
stretchy like you're going to sort of
struggle to find a plant inside of it
that is like the same thing but on a
short
body yeah um with TK um I didn't really
find anything that was you know squat or
um you know Stumpy like that um outside
of you know just plants you wouldn't
really want to keep at all and I don't
think they were squatting Stumpy because
it was a good thing I think they were
just you
know you know uh inbred type runs you
know which you're going to get with any
S1 types you know you're always going to
get a population of uh recessive just
garbage and sometimes the garbage is
good though yeah that's true that's true
I mean not not talking about the garbage
can you tell us a little bit about the
TK 5750 cuz I've seen it popping up a
lot and uh I'm I'm interested you got my
ears peaked oh 5150 sorry the
5150 yeah no um so the
um um I uh I sprouted a bunch of uh the
the first time I ran a bunch of TKS S1
seeds um I sprouted a bunch of them and
then my buddy comes through and he's
like um I I need some plants and I'm
like well I got all these seeds and uh
you know you could have all these seed
plants so he ended up running all these
TKS s1s and I just you know sprouted you
know another hundred you know the next
go around um but uh when I went over and
you know checked out his run of them
um my favores were number seven number
14 and number 50 and number
51 and uh I think the seven was like a
white you know the white it was like it
looked like the white um and then the 14
looked like a green Girl Scout cookie
plant right and then uh the 50 and 51
they were both OG Kush types you know TK
types um and you know chunky Frosty just
you know really nice and so you know I I
I got samples of you know those four you
know the four favorites from his his run
and uh um took them home and smoked the
you know smoked them all smoked the 51
it was just like H decent but whatever
but I smoked the 50
and um that that that one made every
time I smoked it it made me dur like
little little
crazy and you know I'm pretty good with
my smoke you know most of the time um
other people smoked it and they couldn't
function because you
know whatever
whatever so um it it you know it's the
number 50 but I started calling the 5150
because it was the 50 and the 51 that
were were were my Prime selections and
uh anyways so ended up keeping the cut
and you know working with it and it
breeds breeds pretty okay that's
brilliant you know cuz I I was going to
ask you are you really hunting like
6,000 plants or something
oh no no when I saw 5150 I was like [ __ ]
he's going next level
now and and the other one I uh kept from
uh my my uh next run which was another
hundred and something or so was the 677
but that actually stood for bed 6 number
77 okay it wasn't it wasn't from another
700 plant run 5150 there you go every
keep your eye out for that and just as a
quick followup I might have missed it
does it have the same flavor profile as
the TK or is it like different in a way
it's it's pretty close to a traditional
TK nothing too too too impressive it's
just uh you know TK you know it's high
as what it is but th this one just every
time I smoked it it just seemed to you
know uh yeah do the trick that's
brilliant I love that I love that and
just you know while we're on the topic
of the TK do you have any thoughts on
you know Marty from TK Origins you know
has come out and said what he said about
the origin and you know the speculation
that it's like sort of Hindu by Hindu
roughly or you know whatever the Emerald
Triangle strain is what's your thoughts
on all of
that h i mean that's a that's a tough
one right there
um I mean um
yeah
uh uh that that's a good discussion
um I mean the the story has been
variable since the
start and um Marty uh he he posted uh on
icy mag years and years ago
um the same story but
different and so the story's been a bit
flexible for probably the better part of
the last 10 years give or
take um you know so are you sort of yet
to be
convinced I mean there's a there's a
good bit of truth to it let me put it
that way I that's a better way to phrase
it there's a good bit of truth to it but
I think some of the details might not be
a
100% um you know uh I'm I'm cool with uh
you know who who's who's the one who you
know uh found the OG Kush um and you
know sprouted that seed and that the
seed he sprouted does tie back in to you
know Marty and that whole crew so there
is a lot of truth to it it's just I
think some of the
details um I just I don't know if some
things that shouldn't be solid are being
made Solid now you know like it was a
mystery of what it could be but now it's
we know exactly what it was no no no I
don't think it changes that much I would
like
to um find out who the guy Marty worked
for back when he was a
kid um because Marty was just a water
boy back in those days and I've had
plenty of water boys I've never was a
water boy except for my own
[ __ ] but anyways uh i' I'd love to find
out who you know he was growing for
because obviously they should know what
that Emerald Triangle
was and I mean Marty thought it came
from Washington Seattle
area
um but um I mean the Emerald Triangle is
you know humble meno and TR Trinity
County you know so I don't know it's
it's it's interesting you know yeah I
mean could you just in isolation could
you believe the general formula of like
a Hindu cross to a Hindu type plant or
do you think oh that does like what
based on what you've seen that's not
really what you think it it could be it
could be a Hindu Hindu Kush type hybrid
um when my buddy grew out uh all those
uh TKS S1 seeds
um his room was a little over Nitro a
little too much nitrogen he he grows in
beds just like I do um and his room was
cold probably colder I think and his his
TKS S1 plants looked Jurassic like I'm
like how did nothing in that room look
like OG kush or triangle cush at all but
then then uh um because it I think it
was like a Winter Spring Run it was
probably a winter run and then he took
clones of all those plants and did
another run you know with the clones and
the whole room it was like you know 50
or so different uh s
s1s uh but from clone you know and it
all looked like triangle cush or OG Kush
the whole whole room you know from from
the Clone room but from seed it looked
Jurassic it was just old School Hindu
Kush type you know plants just you know
I don't know about ciny Hindu Kush maybe
maybe not but definitely some some
version of Hindu Kush yeah I believe
that totally yeah interesting Okay cool
so just a bit of an unrelated question
which I I love to ask all of the
Breeders who are a bit prolific what's
your advice for someone who's looking to
get into the breeding game and do their
own thing because as I mentioned earlier
there seems to be a growing sentiment
that people feel like it's hard to
differentiate themselves and you know I
think the majority of people who get
into breeding they're doing it for
passion and there's a part of them that
doesn't want to be perceived as you know
just producing a run-of-the-mill thing
that's like everyone else you know
everyone would like to produce something
that's unique and is going to stand up
do you have any advice for how someone
might be able to do
that well you know uh just recommend
that somebody you know find something
they they really like and just focus on
you know like one or two things because
uh um you know for example the way I do
things
uh it it's it's difficult it's it's not
entirely fun um and you know I think uh
I am gonna you know eventually here be
changing to you know just focusing on
you know a couple few things
and just you know really really try to
you
know you know work those things until
they're just amazing you know what I
mean versus you know all kinds of
different things e you know it gets
watered down so as long as you're
focused on something that just you know
is really you you're really passionate
about that that that would be that would
that would probably be the best bet
yeah definitely I I feel like if you're
passionate about something chances are
other people will be passionate about it
also and and even just from the
perspective of if you're passionate
about it people would be like oh like it
must have something to offer if that's
what you're really focused on you know
right right right you know interesting
okay one of the new favorite questions
I've been asking a lot of people is
without being being able to know
anything about the individual cuz
obviously you'd prefer to know specifics
but without being able to know anything
about the individual if you could only
recommend one pack as just something
where you think majority of people are
going to be pretty happy with what they
find inside of it what would be your
go-to sort of offering for the general
public um I mean uh uh there there's
there's a there's a few but uh I think
uh anything uh from the big bad wolves
th those are you know kind of tried and
true um you know shout out to Nato for
sure uh you know his headband times
KMD that that one I don't think
anybody's found found a pack that hasn't
had all kinds of gold in it so you know
um I mean both the KMD and the headband
breed really
well um yeah those ones are pretty tra
and true that's music to my ears because
I as soon as I got my hands on a pack of
that cemd headband I put it away I was
like this is the
one right right beautiful stuff
beautiful stuff I um you know you you've
sort of touched on it and a lot of
people are getting super hyped for the
fact that uh you have some fun collabs
coming up you know some with Noto some
with Matt are you able to touch on some
of the finer points I specifically one
of the fans was Keen to hear a bit about
the upcoming gel project or
gel yeah yeah yeah yeah um I mean uh you
know here's hoping to it reverses all
[Laughter]
right oh you know you never know you
never know I emphasize that pretty much
always you know
uh total total tangent um
I I just recently reversed a cherry
pie and wow I fig I figured that one
that one was like you
know kick back relax watch the pollen
fly right because you know Cherry Pie's
a Herm you
know it's it's gonna be easy uh complete
fail I the the run is drawing right now
but if I got 1% seed yeah I'm lucky
so you know I don't I don't count
chickens or I try not to and every time
I do I get
slapped wow I mean you know I've got to
ask what sort of plants would you be
most interested in pairing cherry pie
with um I I I definitely you know wanted
I always want s1's that's my main goal
every time I do a reversal because I
like digging through the s1's and you
know pull pulling plants out um but uh
um I I had a a Bed full of granddaddy
purple uh purple Urkel Grape Ape uh some
of the Urkel s1s um and then uh I had
the you know the opposite end of the
spectrum you know uh you know ogs you
know uh TKS sour D's you know that kind
of stuff so you know and then you know a
few few Inbetweeners you know
um you got you got me thinking now when
you do these reversals is it all very
Ultra methodical in terms of what
females go in the room or is it the case
that because you got so much going on
it's sort of like you've always got a
good rotation of moms and you just sort
of Chuck in what's ready to go oh no no
no it's it's methodical um I I I try to
do uh I I I try to you know do multiple
different you know pairings like pair of
things that are like kind pair of things
that are opposite kind you know and then
you know pair of things that are you
know whatever whatever you know that I
just think might might be cool um but uh
I overdo it on on clone production like
you know in an average month I'll
probably you know end up taking I don't
know couple thousand
clones and then so I always or usually
have a really you know broad pool to
select what I want to put into these
rooms and so you know I usually get what
I want in my rooms not always but
usually that's beautiful and I mean you
you open the floodgates I feel like how
on Earth like what's your clone Tech how
on Earth do you do
that just uh just just plugs and I also
I use uh like big plugs
um you know 50 per tray but they're like
2in plugs whatever and uh
um and that that allows me time because
you know the plugs are big enough so the
you know the Clones can sit in those
plugs for you know three four five you
know six weeks you know sometimes and so
uh you know I'm able to have you know
clones on deck for you know because if
you're feeding you know five different
rooms you're always trying to you know
you need that stuff ready sure and do
you have like a go-to rooting stimulant
or is just variable I just use basical
clonex um liquid you know uh and and dip
and grow so you know neither of those is
organic my cloning is not organic
folks yeah no that makes sense so if we
loot back you know you mentioned that
you're trying to reverse first the jel
what sort of plants do you think would
pair really well with the
jel I mean uh you know definitely chems
ogs uh you know um diesels you know
they'll kind of compound but you know
everybody does that too the ones that
you know are uh um you know a
little a little bit of a mystery
definitely would like to have some hash
plants in there you know some p some
hp13 that kind of stuff um you know I
tend to with so like with Gil you know I
would generally tend to stay away from
fruity stuff you know like Cherry AK
Strawberry Cough you know that kind of
stuff um and I don't know if jel would
be the greatest thing to you know slap
against Girl Scout cookies or wedding
cake or fritters or you know that kind
of stuff like I don't I don't I don't
think think Skittles would be in you
know a gel run I don't know uh that
might just get
weird I mean it sort of makes sense like
when you're saying it out loud I'm like
yeah I I get the impression it would
like dominate them and and like sort of
model it a
bit yeah yeah um so you know I
definitely try for for like kinds but
then you know something like you know uh
some of the hash plants mixed with it
you know they def only can you know make
something decent I'd imagine yeah
beautiful beautiful and you know if we I
mean in my mind I sort of associated the
the jel collab with Matt and I've heard
you may be doing a headband collab with
Noto is that correct oh uh well I mean
uh it it might be a different type of
collab of sorts uh you know we're we're
we're still working out the details
let's put it that way beautiful I know I
know everyone's really really really
Keen to to see that that take off you
know cuz I mean I'd be interested to
hear how do you compare that headband
the LA Kush to other headbands is it
similar is it different what do you like
about
it I mean uh NATO's headband is like a
strong uh like diesel plant um other
other headbands you know there's there's
multiple OG Kush type headbands there's
the 56 day head band there's Loompa
headband both of those are you know just
straight up OG cush types um then
there's the 707 Headband which was like
a OG sour diesel type you know um that
was popular around here you know like 15
years ago or longer
um but uh um NATO's headband is is
really similar uh to this this cut that
circulated around
um like I don't know 15 15 to 18 years
ago and uh multiple people uh had this
cut as like a chem dog 91 but it was a
sour diesel type plant you know I mean
docta of archive you know got got this
plant as chem 91 and then uh I think
Loompa Loompa got it as chem 91 too and
the it was these
plants like a sour diesel type plant
just like uh NATO's
headband
um so I don't know I don't even know how
they they got named as chem dogs or
headbands or what it was
just uh little strange a little strange
but good quality
plants do you do you know is that the uh
the the JB Kim 91
cut oh no no no no no the JB uh um I I
got that that cut uh I don't know maybe
15 years ago um or so and the JB was
like uh I actually ran the JB next to um
that other that sour diesel type chem 91
cut um and the chem 91 was like this big
Burly diesel plant whereas the JB was
like this skinny little sad sister to
sour d i mean just just in my side by
sides you know
one person's experience but I didn't
have a whole lot of respect for the JB
the JB
one there you go yeah look I mean it
goes to show just the sheer amount of
cuts that are incorrectly named Kim
91 right oh it was it was bad it was bad
and it still is I mean you know there's
there's tons of chem 91s going around
you know right on the on the topic of
purple strains I wanted to talk to you
about the pink and perss this is one you
did you know it's it took place in
between now and our last chat so we
didn't talk about it last time right I
remember when you first started posting
about this the first thing I wanted to
ask was what is it about this line that
really captivated you cuz it seems like
you were really interested in it and I
was like it looks cool but you know I
can't smell it I can't taste it what did
you like about it okay so pinks and pers
kind of started out as a mystery for me
um I was I was touring my buddy uh Shiva
I was touring his farm in
mesino and he had made uh this hybrid
that was like dogs Waltz the the purple
dog um that was you know pretty popular
around here for a while
um he had made a hybrid with that um and
uh oh what did he oh he he crossed it to
Afghan number one right and he had
crossed a bunch of different things with
that Afghan
one um
and everything else was just
green and this dogs Waltz this you know
purple dog bud or purple dog purple dog
um every plant in his garden pretty much
of that that cross had dark purple
almost black flowers and pink
hairs you know like bright fluorescent
pink or almost red hairs
and I'm like well all these other
hybrids with the Afghani one are green
so they probably didn't get any of this
you know purple and you know pink hairs
from the the Afghan one and I'm like
I've grown dogs Walts I've grown that
you know purple dog
and this stuff doesn't look anything
like it it doesn't purple like that it
doesn't have you know pink hairs and so
I backtracked and our buddy
Blaze he had made a hybrid um of this
Killer Queen uh meno purple cross to a
Hawaiian and that the Hawaiian had pink
hairs and then the meno Pur in that uh
you know uh pushes its purple forward
and he had actually made it F2 and he's
the one who had given the the dogs Waltz
to
Shiva and so I was like you know I think
I think I think you uh might have given
him the wrong cut you know and uh our
our buddy NCGA was the one who made the
the Killer Queen meno perss and now you
know we're we're backtracked all the way
to like 200 what3 or something
2002 um anyways so I I had to
investigate this all the way back and I
you know finally figured that it wasn't
what it was supposed to be it was you
know this totally different thing um but
uh you know I I liked it when I saw to
his farm and he gave me a huge you know
container of seeds and I ran out like
180 of them and made an open pollination
made a bunch of selections blah blah
blah and then I ended up finding one of
my favorite plants I found in a few
years
you know out of that which is uh the
sweet
16 what's she
like she I mean no two people I I
brought her to the the party uh that
that Matt threw and uh no two people
could describe her the same I mean I
think she's like mango pineapple other
people are saying like apple this um
some people said mango some said
Pineapple some said Apple it's like no
PE no two people smelled smelled her the
same but she was like one of the few
that was like a green one in the whole
bunch out of 180 um and full of seeds
you know after just sitting for you know
months or whatever just drying because I
kind of neglected the the finish on that
run um she rre and usually Mo most
things don't smell you know when they've
just been sitting
forever and so she holds her tpin really
well which is which is prettyy rare you
know especially as strong as she was so
you know um definitely one of my recent
favorites yeah wow it sounds like a
really unique profile as well like
because you don't hear a lot about Apple
profiles I feel like that's also a very
underrepresented
flavor right right kind of like the
XP yeah you know what I forgot about
that you know do you do you find that
tpine commonly in the
x18 I mean when when I grew her yeah it
was it was nice but that smelled like
apple to me where I I don't get the
Apple from the sweet 16 but other people
do so you know okay interesting what so
you're you get more of the uh the mango
pineapple I guess yeah yeah yeah yeah
wow everybody different yeah sure and
and do you feel like it's like a hybrid
sort of effect is it more indicia
leaning um she almost seems a little bit
more of a sativa effect to me yeah yeah
I I honestly think she might be like a a
throwback to uh the Killer Queen which
is a Cindy 99
hybrid um I think it's like a G13
c99 but I mean that's that's a lot of
lot of generations past that yeah I
guess I was thinking about you also
mentioned the Hawaiian I was thinking
maybe it's sort of coming from both ways
yeah it could be it could be wow all
right that's that's more higher on my
list to to give a good run because I I'm
always keen on
sativas yeah yeah yeah I mean on that
topic you know you mentioned the uh the
pink 16 one of your favorite in the past
few years and earlier on in the episode
you mentioned being really fond of the
lemon tree I wanted to ask you a few
questions about it because I have had a
few people message me and say you know
is is lemon party lemon tree that's the
first question I
guess um so I think um I think lemon
party um might be an
S1 possibly hybrid but uh either a S1 or
hybrid of lemon tree um I think it might
have come from like straight Organics
and
um it it it's like a a tall lanky plant
at least it is for me it's a tall lanky
plant and it's it's like just as pungent
as Tangi like just over the top you know
Candi just you know fruit but more on
the lemon lemon tur profile um and uh
then then lemon tree is like this short
you know Stumpy Kush type plant um with
just you know super pungent um just
strong strong like lemon oil type
turs
more I'm terrible at describing this
kind of stuff but that's that's kind of
as close as I can get um they're both
great plants but you know quite quite a
bit different and yeah i' I've heard
from some of the some of the guys uh you
know that are real familiar with with
lemon tree is you know you you do get uh
some of the um some of the lankier
sativa type plants coming out of them um
there there's a bit of mystery to it I
don't know if you know because uh some
of them say it might might might have
come from a orgon and it could be like a
old Oregon Lemon
Diesel I don't know yeah interesting
okay and then so in that case which one
do you like more
h i
mean I kind of like lemon
party you know I mean that sort of makes
sense in a lot of ways and I mean when
you described it that sort of checks out
a little more with the common lineage
you hear which is like this meant to be
what like a sour diesel Lemon Skunk sort
of
thing yeah yeah so something like that
um it it's definitely one of the the
most pungent plants um I've come across
you know you run it with 50 other
different hybrids and it's the only
thing you can smell in the room you
know wow that's beautiful I got a a pack
of yours of the um the Melvin cross to
the lemon party I was like man that
one's going to be a
hitter right right right now that one
could be very very good yeah like what I
was thinking it should be like citrus
Central right like just exploding oh
yeah yeah no definitely definitely yeah
yeah that's cool okay and then I guess
the final question on this one for me is
I guess in a sense the lemon party s1s
are essentially lemon tree
S2s as long as the lemon party is like
an S1 you know
definitely yeah that's cool man I I know
I feel like you're one of the only
people who really gets into the S2s hard
I love it right right oh I'm I'm a huge
fan of them you know yeah there we go do
you do you offer any S3s at the
moment no no and I haven't even offered
any of my S you know legit S2s I I mean
sure I probably have a few S2s but you
know I'm they're not marketed as as S2s
because I can't you know claim 100% that
they S2s you know sure I mean and
honestly
most people I don't think would be
extremely thrilled running out some S2s
or S3s you know or the very least S3s
you know yeah yeah true true it's
different they they're sort of looking
for that Vigor yeah the lack of vigor
just might not be the ticket so yeah
okay I mean while we're on the topic I I
I don't think we asked it earlier so I
definitely got to ask it because it was
submitted by three different fans what
is the most interesting thing you've
ever see come out of an S1 like really
just unexpected left of field huh um I
think I posted pictures of it uh years
ago on a on ID um uh I had this
plant uh I think I I posted pictures of
it was tight it might have got to two
inches tall and but it was on its like
20th
node it was like a ball was like a
little blue blue green
ball it was like I had it for like six
months and it was two inches tall at
best I
mean not the mut most people would
want yeah and when I tried flowering out
it
died I was all sad it was not meant for
this cruw world no it was it was a sad
little ball of a plant
oh wow I love it that's so cool you just
reminded me of that incredible photo
that uh Noto posted of that Mosaic Plant
in your garden can you tell us a bit
about that one oh that was in a a garden
he was working with um but uh um I mean
you know he's he's way more familiar
with that uh there was a huge debate I
never even ended up reading all the
comments because it got a little too
crazy um but but I mean a lot of people
you know think that's a um you know a a
virus or something blah blah blah but
it's just as likely that it's just a
genetic you know mutation as any virus
so um you know hyp told me years ago you
know when when when Kim D first was you
know getting into circulation he was
like you know that's just a genetic you
know blah blah blah and not no stink
virus and if if something's a virus you
kind of expect it
to pass on somewhere and when they don't
like pass on I think it's probably just
a genetic something
something so what what's your verdict on
variegation you know because there's
still some people who are really adamant
in their belief that it's a form of a
virus and then other people are like no
I think it's just a
trait yeah I think it can be either or
you know I I think you know if if you
have a something that's variegated and
you know it's in your rooms for x amount
of years and then it passes on or it
passes on um obviously it's a a virus
but I mean I don't take any more you
know time with a chmd cut you
know you know taking clones or any of
that kind of stuff and it's never passed
on on so that just leans leans towards
it's just a it's just a genetic trait
you
know I mean so yeah interesting
interesting and you know it's been a
while since we chatted so although it's
sort of old news we just going to touch
on it quickly how have you been affected
by hopl and
vroid um so um back in like 2011 2012 I
think it was um
I uh I had gotten you know um I was
doing some heavy trading with people and
I'd gotten a bunch of cuts from you know
jungle boys that you know before they
were jungle boys and you know a few
other cats I'll I'll let them name
remain
nameless um but I got just tons of this
you
know these messed up you know plants and
uh I got the white fire uh the uh jungle
boys you know five keeper plants of
white fire the 43 the 80 the 28 you know
and I grew them out and I'm like who
would ever keep these plants they're
complete garbage right they they all
Herm they there's no Frost you know they
look like crap and you know I have my
the rest of my room looks great and
anyways fast forward found out you know
it was some kind of something you know
they didn't figure out to years later
but I figured out get rid of those
[ __ ] plants you know and so you know
I I quarantine everything you know
especially more so now you know ever
since like 2014 I'm like uhuh you don't
come in unless you you got
papers uh but uh you know uh so uh you
know i' I've definitely had had plants
that you know were were positive but
they've always in you know I've always
quarantined them knew they were and so I
either throw them away or you know uh
um or keep them segregated um so I I
haven't had any any HP uh whatever
whatever any of that virus in in my room
and probably a damn near a
decade do you think that it'll be like
um it'll be a a virus that sort of just
dies out eventually cuz I feel like when
I talk to people a lot of people are
like you and they're like I now know
what I need to do and I I don't feel
like I've had it for quite a while do
you think it'll it'll die out or do you
think it'll be like the flu with humans
where it just it just sort of circulates
around and it's always there but it's
sort of in the
background it's really easy to not you
know uh keep it from not
spreading um you know uh just don't
bring it in your rooms you know and it's
really easy to spot I mean um ever since
I got rid of you know um all the plants
that had it you know years ago um you
know and it started doing protocol you
know of not introducing stuff you know
straight into my rooms from strange
Gardens um you know I haven't had a
problem with it so you know I I think
it's going to stay around because a lot
of people are sloppy you know you know I
mean I I I have plenty of stories of
bringing the wrong plant into the garden
so
yeah definitely definitely definitely I
wanted to ask you about it because I've
been wondering for a while the ruthless
runs Cuts how is that different to
normal runs and is it really connected
to the rbl
posy yes it is and uh um I think I
should just like um you know
uh keep quiet on that
one I mean rbl is gangster rappers so
you you probably don't want to tell them
what their cut
is um what what I will say though
is uh for what it is it's a great cut um
it um is one of the most stable cuts um
that I've S1 and bred with um it uh is
very potent and passes the potency on um
and it's very
uniform um but uh I have a hunt that
it's an S1 of something else and there
might not be any z in
it so I mean do you feel like runs
really expresses a ton of Z generally
speaking cuz I've felt like whenever I
tried runs I was like this is just
gelato uh so um I I have runs as well or
just regular runs and yeah there's
there's plenty of z in it okay yeah so
maybe I just been having ruthless
runs yeah essentially
essentially makes sense it makes sense I
mean out of curiosity why do you think
like I've noticed that like the sherbet
profile has really really come back into
popularity and it's you know that creamy
gelato sort of vibe seems to be very
popular with people right do you have
any suspicions about why that's come
back around because it's almost like it
had its time in the sun then it got
pushed out of the way but now it's back
again right obviously people like it I
don't know I
mean h yeah yeah yeah it's a good answer
right know on on on that one uh um uh
I've never actually run the the cookie
fam sherbet I've always uh run the the
green sherbet which was you know real
popular around Humble at Mendo all that
which is the one that you know seems
like it's probably related more directly
to
Skittles you know whereas the sunset
sherbet from cookie fan that's that's
the one that's you
know uh you know more more jaw aesque I
think
yeah that's certainly the flavor profile
I think has been really popular
recently yeah
yeah y well we've got an interesting fan
submitted one here they say this is all
hypothetical but I suspect it relates to
them um but they're saying you know if
you were to live in like a prohibited
State and the market there's no good
weed you know no one even really knows
what OG is what cookies is you could
probably give them anything and say it's
OG and if it was good weed they'd be
like right right on um so the question
is if you live in such an area what
strains that you offer in seed form
would you say would be a good thing
where like you know it it's going to
give someone like a quality end product
they're going to be able to offer
something that's sort of not currently
available what would you offer to
someone who's in like an environment
where it's just ample playing field to
pump out some nice
herb I mean I you know I always I always
recommend the the the big bad wolves
just because they got the potency you
know super strong they stink and and you
know they they've got pretty good yields
too you know I mean when when I first
ran the the one big bad wolf I mean if I
had to kept that that cut uh I could I
could be doing some four pounds of
lights right
now beautiful beautiful okay since we
last spoke have you changed your mind on
co2 you using CO2 at all or still not oh
far too
lazy I I keep it simple I keep it simple
no it makes sense it makes sense have
there been any major changes to the way
in which you grow have you switched over
to
LEDs no far too cheap I mean far too
poor far too
poor what are you rocking just metal
hlid HPS oh that would be nice that
would be nice no just still uh still
same
Dees yeah oh
ni in the S yeah um I'm not too amped
about upgrading to anything in anytime
soon is that do like do we just need a g
up sponsorship for you like fzy if
you're listening send my man some
LEDs maybe maybe no uh when when I when
I get back to you know some flower
production uh for my dispensary then
then I'll be buying some new equip
you know yeah by the way do you have a
name in mind for the
[Laughter]
facility oh yeah I have one
um I'm I'm gonna hold off and touch on
that next time how that be no worries I
I'll leave I'll let you keep your
secrets um so I'm I'm Keen to know what
sort of projects are you currently
excited about what seeds are you Keen to
Pop um so uh um my next uh uh flower
round um I'm running through uh a ton of
Bubba s1s I'm I'm finally gonna do you
know work on my bubba S2 project you
know I got bomb threat you know ready to
you know get up in there um and then uh
I also have a handful of lemon party
hybrids lemon tree hybrids um and uh
some sweet 16 hybrids
um you know of course F1
derbs um and a few other things a few
other things but uh you know get getting
away from the whole uh uh dessert I
think the the last time I I did mostly
dessert dessert
products I want something a little
different this time yeah understandable
for sure understandable um I guess I'd
be Keen to know you know this is
probably going to be a weird question
happy to happy to cut it out if it
doesn't fit um what has been a line of
yours that you thought would be really
popular but like it turns out it just
hasn't quite had as much traction with
the general
public I mean pinks and purposes are
perfect perfect example um you know I I
really like pink pinks and perss um but
you know I also you know I'm not great
at marketing either so you know I really
didn't push it like you know I could
have should but yeah well very very few
people were like woohoo woohoo you know
so you know we got to change their mind
I think yeah yeah
yeah that's all right you'll see it on
my Instagram
soon on uh on the other end of the
spectrum what's what's one of if not
your most popular lines if you just had
to think off the top of your
head um I mean uh
every everybody still I
mean o overall people tend to like the
s1s over the hybrids in general and I
mean the TKS ones the chem DS ones those
are those are always at the top of the
list so yep even even though I I I do
recommend just for solely growing you
know hybrids are you know better than
s1's but s1's are better if you want to
you know breed your own stuff with them
make your own
selections yeah sure sure sure sure
that's that's really interesting okay um
and how much value do you think we we as
a community should place on feno Hunting
you know like I understand that you know
everyone everyone wants to just run some
keep clones and make some head stash
every so often but me myself I usually
try to have some new stuff in there most
rounds to just sort of be at least
slowly injecting some stuff in what do
how do you feel about that do you feel
like we should try to impart some
impotance that you know there is value
to always sort of having some new stuff
rolling in oh yeah I mean it really
depends on where you're at you know what
what you're you know
um you know what what what's important
to you whether it's just personal smoke
or you're you're doing it commercially
or whatever um but I mean
you know uh I don't know honestly uh I
think it's always always good to you
know R run some new with the old you
know yeah definitely definitely I mean
while we're talking about new and old I
had no idea how I was going to slot
these questions in but this is it right
here we're doing it um you know I was
specifically interested because you'd
got this experience with the
nl5 part of me was wondering is there
any way in which this or just in General
how your thoughts of Neville and his
accomplishments have changed over the
years you know now that you've had
experience with some of these lines he
was working with for example has
anything changed at all I mean not
really um I went through a phase through
through probably the mid late 90s um all
the way through you know probably the
mid
2000s where um I grew up in Humble so I
wasn't really impressed with anything
from
Amsterdam you know so you know you
factor that in it's just like you know
but since then you know I I I've
realized that there's tons of stuff from
Amsterdam I like I just hadn't you know
I was too stubborn to grow you know a
bunch of it based on you know early
formed
opinions sure look I think we can all
acknowledge that one way or the other
you know maybe the opposite way for a
lot of Growers you know they they they
end up lording DNA genetics only to
realize it's not as good as they thought
on in that same sort of school of
thought what's your thoughts on Shanti
would you ever consider buying and
growing Mr Nice Guy or is there a bit
like too many concerns about the current
gear versus the older
gear uh I have so much to grow H it
would be very hard to you know
experiment with you know you know new
new stuff other stuff yeah so with that
being said then who who were some of the
Breeders who you at least now you know
have held in high esteem from Years Gone
by that's a good one
um I used to really like DJ
um but you know then I talked to
DJ so
I mean I don't know
uh yeah
um I I kind of
hoped I would have learned more from DJ
sure he's he's very much an enigma isn't
he yeah yeah yeah yeah and uh I'll
probably cut this out but what what's
your thoughts on um JD and the whole
blueberry Bubba
clams JD's ENT tning that's all I'll
say right definitely definitely he's
he's a character he's a
character see now you don't have to cut
cut it out you're too good to me you're
too good to me um I think that just
about brings us to our final five
questions and they've evolved a bit
since the last time we spoke so the
first one is if you had to restart your
company let's just say you know one of
those horrible fires rips through your
property I hope that never happens but
let's just say hypothetically it did you
had to restart your company from scratch
with just one packet of seeds that
you've made can be regular can be fem
you can do whatever you want you know
you could find a female and reverse it
what one pack of seeds are you going to
pick to restart the company with damn
just one pack yeah it's tough
damn huh
uh how about pinear Kush oh that's a
solid Pig Tom i' be
happy no I love pinear Kush when I ran
it
out I want to revisit that one because I
swear uh I can I can make some stuff
with pinear that'll remind me of uh some
of the old old stuff I got from my dad
that you know he he got back in the
early 80s and you know reminisce a
little bit yum that sounds epic cool
okay so next one we're going to drop you
off on a desert island you can only take
three strains with you for the rest of
your life which
three oh three strains how about
uh sweet 16 you know because it's a
desert island we need some tropical
um uh oh damn how about purple
Indica right for for our strong Indica
Dom and then uh may maybe a nice select
cut of a wait do I get a pack or just a
clone you can do either either or well
I'll I'll definitely take some some
burmes and then with with with that I
think I could breed you know uh whatever
I want that's a nice mixture I really
like that okay so on the other end of
the spectrum you're going to drop
someone else off on the desert island
you're not particularly fond of this
person what are you going to leave them
with
Australian bastard
cannabis oh no I play I
[Laughter]
play they wouldn't know if they could
smoke it or not that's it right it's an
ornamental
yeah that's awesome that's awesome okay
um which out of the chem clones are your
favorite and is that also like in terms
of smoking and then is that also the one
you like to breed or work with the most
I think my favorite was the number four
until I lost it um and then I I I like
the the D um overall I think um but I
think 91 is like my favorite
breeder yep solid answer solid answer
final question for this interview what
gives you hope in the Cannabis Community
or what would you like to see happen to
help things steer forward in a path that
you think would be best for us
all uh I think uh I'd like to see more
people homeg grown you know I mean I I
want to see more people just you know
growing their own plants you
know a brilliant sentiment I think that
just about brings us to the end of it
are there any comments or shout outs you
wanted to make
oh I think I'm good for
today no problem as always incredibly
grateful for your time The Man Behind
CSI Humbolt the fem wizard himself
blazing a path forward incredibly
grateful as always thank you Caleb of
CSI for coming on thank
you and there you have it
gang the end of our second installment
for our epic second part with Caleb of
CSI true hero of the Emerald
Triangle we're incredibly grateful as
always to have him stop by and share
some of his knowledge what did you guys
think I hope you enjoyed it as much as I
did as always we want to give a massive
shout out to our sponsors who you will
equally not be disappointed with C here
now number one seed bank in the industry
a guarantee on satisfaction not just
germination check them out guys you will
not be disappointed all the coolest
breeders the hottest drops everything
you could want and more Under One Roof
seeds here now we appreciate you so so
much likewise prop biological we love
your Pest and predation technology
please guys don't wait until you have an
active infection to release some
beneficials into your garden do it now
stay on top have peace of mind knowing
that your garden is happy healthy
pumping on all cylinders huge shout out
to cop biological
systems likewise a huge shout out to
pulse sensors if you're looking to keep
your room dialed in you need to go no
further from VPD to ppf to all the other
measurements Under the Sun they got you
covered and with the introduction of the
latest pulse Hub you know you can
integrate all of your information into
one centralized unit whether you got a
single tent a single room a single
building a multi-state operation it's
time to get serious guys increase resin
yield flavor
potency get serious get a
pulse huge sh shout out to Organics
alive you want to be giving your plants
the best nutrition available and you
know me I'm an organic guy so it's no
surprise that I am stoked to have
Organics alive on board products ranging
from Veg to transition to flour any
problem you're in they've got a product
specifically designed to help you out
don't just take my word for it check
them out online guys there have been
sweeping cups all around the country
from homeg Growers like yourself winning
incredible cups there's never been a
better time to get on board Organics
guys check out Organics alive massive
shout out we appreciate you as
always and a massive thank you to our
newest sponsor Dino VAP if you're
looking to get off combustion and give
vaping a go I highly recommend you check
out dinov VAP they have small discrete
units easily accessible both in price
and convenience with hits that replicate
bongs and Joints I cannot emphasize this
enough guys if you're thinking that you
want to get off combustion please
consider dyette I truly believe in this
company they produce phenomenal products
that will give you a hit unlike any Vape
you've ever tried before massive shout
out and thank you to dinat we appreciate
you
greatly that's about it for this one my
[Music]
friends I'll see
you
[Music]