foreign
[Music]
we're back for another one
as always you're joined by your boy
heavy days here from the upside down
Library
as usual we want to give a massive thank
you to all of our sponsors seeds here
now number one seed bank in the industry
all the hottest breeders all the latest
drops and a guarantee on satisfaction
not just germination there's no reason
to shop anywhere else gang I promise you
if you're not happy at the end of your
grow hit them up they'll sort you out
they've also got some cool heavy days
genetics check it out
[Music]
likewise a massive shout out to our
friends at Pulse census you know them
you love them they've got the best unit
in the game to help you track all of the
parameters to ensure that your next grow
is the best today whether you're
tracking temperature humidity VPD ppfd
or so much more the pulse unit will
ensure that your next grow produces more
resin more turpins more to flavor more
yield God what could you want guys
whether you've got a single tent a
single room or a multi-state operation
it's time time to get serious guys get a
pulse
massive shout out to Organics alive
helping all of the organic Fanatics out
there to grow the most incredible crops
today with their amazing powdered
organic products they've got products
specific to each stage of the growth
cycle whether you're in veg transitions
bloom or need a specific calcium or bud
booster they've got everything you need
check them out guys Organics alive truly
one of the highest quality organic
companies on the market massive shout
out Organics alive
likewise a big big thank you to our
friends at dynavax
if you are looking to improve your
respiratory health I recommend you give
vaping a go dinovap is The Vape that
helped me to get off bongs and I cannot
recommend them enough if you want
American-made and engineered vaporizer
technology that's not battery dependent
grab yourself a dynavap m series I
promise it hits like a sledgehammer you
will be left asking yourself what is
this
truly an incredible Vape brand on an
awesome Mission American made and design
check them out guys dynavat we really
appreciate your support thank you so
much for your incredible vaporizers
last but not least a massive shout out
to our good friends at copit you know
you love them the world leaders in Pest
and Predator technology if you've got
spider mites you need to check out the
spiderx of idol plus guess what guys
covert have changed the game yet again
they've now got breeding sachets which
help you to avoid having to spread carry
your material on your crops you hang the
sachets in your garden and over time
they release high amounts of the
predatory spider mite by the silliest
person Ellis into your crop and ensuring
that you keep spider mites at Bay if
you're battling a heavy spider mite
infection you've got to check out the
spydex vital plus the reason why copit
have become the international Powerhouse
they are is because their products are
so amazing I promise you if you're
battling spider mites check it out guys
huge shout out to cope but we appreciate
you guys helping to keep our Gardens
Pest and pathogen free huge shadow open
then finally a quick plug for the
patreon if you love this show and want
to ensure episodes keep happening please
go check out our patreon at
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast you will get access to a wide
range of unheard patreon exclusive
episodes you'll also get early access to
upcoming episodes where like three or
four episodes ahead on the patreon we've
also been giving away genetics every
Fortnight on the smoke with heavy
Discord sessions where we chat about
genetics do presentations on molecular
biology give away a whole range of cool
swag and just catch up in general with
like-minded budding enthusiasts as
always a massive shout out to the
patreon gang you guys are the lifeblood
of the show we appreciate you so so much
on the episode today we got a special
one
I was asked to join skunk VA and Staten
Island for an old time catch-up
lots of bands between these two guys
some cool old school stories a bit of
History
and some plans for the future
so without further delay
let's get into it
alrighty welcome welcome everyone to a
special episode today we are thrilled to
have a reuniting of Two Old Friends
sharing some old stories some memories a
massive welcome to the chem Kings the
incredible skunk VA and the infamous
Staten Island AKA Gabby Garden spout
thanks so much for joining us today guys
thanks for having us thank you for
having me what a whirlwind it has been
over the past few weeks seeing you come
to the surface of the scene I would love
to hear what you've been up to recently
oh go ahead Gabby um well I've recently
been hired as the cultivation director
at Green Brothers Farm in Lockeford
California
it's not fully complete being built
um right now we're putting in the racks
and the lighting and have to get the
final approval you know from the city
that everything is proper so we're
hoping that we're operational
July 1st or July
15th and so I'm extremely excited about
this project because
it's uh it's quite a large one
and it's it's been being put together by
a group of people that I've known since
the beginning of the garden spout and
they're hiring people that they know and
trust
and so that's how I was brought on to
the team and you know so far everyone
else is being brought on the team is
people that I know and people that I
love
so
it's exciting because normally like a
big project like this is gonna be super
corporate and you know
this one isn't although I'm you know I
know it's got Financial backing it's
still a family business yeah so I'm
excited about that right on incredible
how about you Jason of course Jason is
making the the chem dog feeds of the
future with his company Lucky Dog
thanks Gabby
thanks
so yeah that's what I'm doing same thing
I was in December except for the new
news is I don't know if I mentioned it
as we're back open here as of January
6th the whole state shutdown license
transfer thing is over and I'm really
happy now we're just trying to get
people back to the door and now we got
some bigger things we're making a
solventless lab right now we're getting
inspected on the 25th uh we're going to
be doing all solventless products there
and and me me and me and my buddy Gabby
have some good news too we're uh we
decided to uh team up and and start
working on providing some genetics
focusing on clones and we're going to do
some seed collaborations together with
uh some breeding projects chem dog heavy
of course
um and so you know I'm super [ __ ]
excited about that I'm super excited to
be working with Gabby we've had in
literally 30 solid years have known each
other as of February this year we met in
February of 1993. all those years ago
and so it just I mean we talk a lot more
now and it just feels good and
um I'm [ __ ] excited I know my friend
Gabby's excited and you know everybody
just get it going on and kind of you
know put the put the old school and the
Kim and the Kim kind of stuff the gas
back and what's available out there for
folks you know they're definitely hungry
for it so
yeah that's it
wow this collab that sounds really
awesome when did this first uh come into
life you know when did the wheels start
turning on that one 30 years yeah 30
years ago that's exactly what I was
saying
we planned this ball up 30 years ago
we're just waited wow you know just
wanted to make it right so I think we
got it now but uh but yeah sometimes
there's a pause in the middle
you know but yeah Jason was actually the
first person that I ever partnered with
in cultivation really yes I mean I was
growing prior to that but I was doing it
on my own
and Jason was the first person that I
ever helped grow and that I you know
were Partners initially at the beginning
so
I I think and Jason's memory is much
better than mine but I think the
arrangement that I used to make with
people when I would set them up is that
like we would share the first harvest or
the first two harvests and then they
were on their own is that what I did
with you Jason do you remember no no you
had a much a much sweeter deal for me
you had a
so whatever we grow in the in the
bedroom I sell to you and you alone that
was the deal
[Laughter]
mine is my headstands for both of us
yeah it was pretty good deal yeah yeah
you know and I was already at the time I
was already buying every bit of aircraft
like I actually had a little piece of
paper in my wallet with phone numbers on
one side and you know these cases of
paper fall apart you have to redo it and
then on the back it was uh
um your Harvest dates that you kind of
would whisper out to me you know so I
could make sure to get and touch you so
when those buckets are super skunk were
ready I could go ahead and get them
because you always had a it was always
Tupperware so it was never bags it was
never bags anymore perfectly cured weed
and tupperwares brand new tupperware's
and the Tupperware of course came with
the weed you put about a quarter pound
of whatever it was
um in a tupperware and I was always
making sure that there was no reason to
sell anyone else because I would show up
they'd smoke with all my friends you
know
I was listening to the podcast number
two where Jason was telling the stories
about how we met and I hoped that you
know not to be too redundant but I hope
Jason will tell the story again because
if not for everybody else I just love to
hear it you know for my own selfish
reasons
you know I mean like he'll tell the
story to be way better than I can okay
please be surprised so awesome you'd be
surprised how often I get to tell people
that story and I actually [ __ ] love
don't be that story because you know my
memory the way the way my memory kind of
works is like I get visuals like I
remember like you know moments and like
very detailed moments almost sometimes I
can even smell
you know like the smells you know like
the Panhandle park it smells like
eucalyptus you know what I mean it
smells like San Francisco and that's got
a very unique smell to it like that jogs
my memory and I love that you know but
yeah so back in those days between you
know Grateful Dead tours was for three
times a year and I was uh at this time a
permanent you know on tour I was you
know would be called a lifer I was on
tour you know there was no place for me
to go after tour
so is the van in San Francisco and when
you're you know you're when you're in a
Grateful Dead Land money's just in the
air you just gotta you know you know
kind of do what you got to do reach up
and grab your bit it's a it's a
Marketplace you know a lot of people
kind of don't know that and the the ones
of us that were there kind of Overlook
it maybe we don't like to talk about it
because maybe what we were selling was
probably you know not legal still and so
but when you left tour you know making
your money was a little difficult so we
would end up in San Francisco
um mostly because the next shows are
probably going to be Jerry at The
Warfield and also that's just kind of
where everybody landed I mean also
because the Grateful Dead literally told
you to go there
yeah but anyway so you go to the
Panhandle and if you're if you you know
while you're there you might as well
sell a little herb to strangers to get
your head stashed and that's kind of
what my day was like every day
for those periods of time and I'm
sitting the thing about it was there was
a spot where everybody would hang out
and that was where you know there was a
rail there for skating and you know it's
like a big black top and the Panhandle
well if you hung out there the problem
was the cops would come sweep the park
every now and again and they would roll
up on dirt bikes and you know if you
were holding you know you might have a
problem and we're talking like an
instant felony this is you know 1990s
so we I would always stick away from it
because it wasn't really fun for me it
was kind of like stressful I don't think
it was fun for anyone a real stressful
so we just strangers and uh so I'm
sitting on the bench in the Panhandle
and the panhand was like a long straight
thin piece of the park of Golden Gate
that's why they call it the Panhandle
and I'm sitting on this sidewalk so you
can see people walking from very far
away and here comes this guy with this
big old grin on his face you know he's
got a hip sack on he's got a ponytail
and he definitely looks like he wants
some weed I'm like wow man I slow down
buddy like don't be so loud about that
the cops are everywhere you know but um
so when he got to me I was ready to
serve him and before I could say
anything he introduces himself in this
sick New York accent and he asked me he
says uh you know I asked him if you want
to buy some herb and he goes actually
I'd like to I was gonna ask you the same
thing and so I was like well what are
you talking about and so he's like I you
know he told me basically what was going
on he was very open he's like you know
I've moved to California I came out here
to see the Jerry Garcia band as much as
I can at The Warfield which I totally
understood it was no need to explain
that any further and he said that you
know he didn't know anybody which I
didn't know anybody either really so I
understood that part and he I was having
a rough time you know getting his ends
met financially because he couldn't sell
the weed let's go look at the weed so we
walked all the way over to uh the
Central District where he had his Vance
Park and I guess I'll just tell all the
details he had the band he had this long
navy blue van uh that's kind of hard to
explain but the only way I can explain
to your audience is you know if you see
a van like an old like uh you know Dodge
van or Chevy van and you'll see the
extended band you can see the line on
the back where it actually got extended
well this van actually had another line
with another two feet behind it I don't
know how long the thing was Gabby you
might build a number but it was like it
had to been like 16 feet long 18 feet
long it was incredibly long and we piled
up in that thing and we kind of leveled
out his scale and he pulled all this
amazing indoor weed out the Francine
and I don't remember the fluffy sativa
one but that was the one that really
crushed it that day
um I think those are the only two and it
was very little Francine and Gabby had
mentioned earlier in episode two on your
podcast that I mentioned that he was
filming the chemdog and he was writing
pointing out that that would have been
no way out he showed me Kim dock so it
was Francine and some fluffy sativa so
yeah
you need to leave me every opportunity
possible to put you in your place okay
so don't just don't just admit that
you're wrong before I get to tell you
that you're wrong okay all right all
right you got you got it I can do that
okay all right just don't rock it at the
moments you're gonna you're gonna have
most of the moments and there's just
like a couple here and there that you
know I just I need to be able to you
know have that for myself too
yeah you're the big star over here and
I'm you're the big star and I'm just
like the up-and-comer and everything you
know what do you mean you're the
legendary you're the legendary Staten
Island it's just you just didn't know it
until the other day
I didn't know it I I mean honestly at
first I'm just like I was so offended
that people were calling me Staten
Island I'm like what the [ __ ] like you
can't think of anything nicer to call me
you know like I mean you said such nice
things about me on the podcast how I
like grew the best indoor weeds you'd
ever seen and and this is but then
somehow I'm just known as Staten Island
like the [ __ ] place that smells bad
I did not name you Staten Island but I
have called you that because the public
led me to call you that but I did not
name you that I promise you however you
do know that once you're when you're
inside New York and you're a New York
native like you are Staten Island's one
thing but to the rest of the universe
Staten Island is just New York now I
don't know call me New York call me New
York New York yeah like a [ __ ] baller
yeah then I sound like a baller Staten
Island I just I just sound like there's
something wrong I don't know if you
remember a few years ago there was like
the Garbage barge that was stuck they
had nowhere to like put the garbage
because they wouldn't take it anymore on
Staten Island but it's just like
is literally just never ending garbage
I remember that it felt bad it smelled
bad
well it's a double muscle unless you
unless unless you were right outside a
Brother's Pizza it smelled bad so
go ahead continue the story
oh yeah the story um
oh so you know so back story what was
going on in the city and you know the
February of 1993 was you know so you
know you're gonna find some outdoor weed
October November December January
especially but around time January comes
February it starts to dry up especially
back then and those years for some
reason it was just so hard to get like
good weed and you have to get weight so
weight is what that means is you get
weight means you're going to get 28
grams for that ounce right weight is
what you get and then you go break up
some hates like eights but hate streets
of hate hates is where you get 10 if
you're nice 11 or 12 if you're kind of
Stingy eighths out of an ounce so 4 8
for you eight for the crowd you know
that's how you make a little bit money
on a 425
ounce and that's for your buddy this
isn't like tax this is just what it is
you know and so that's what's going on
in the city at the time it's you know it
makes things very difficult like the
money you don't make enough money to you
know barely get by or survive so there
he is Gabby we're in his band he shows
he opens up this duffel bag and I'm like
holy [ __ ] that's [ __ ] beautiful
indoor we haven't seen any of that
around here in a while you know most
people's like out throwing weed so
he said I was like all right well here's
the question how much you want for that
and I can't remember exactly but the
number 285 tops of my head or 325 Pops
in my head either one of those numbers
would have made me holy [ __ ] is what I
would have said because that would have
definitely helped and I said listen if
you just stay here and give me a minute
I cannot walk around this duffel bag in
this neighborhood that won't last very
long
but if you stay here and just bear with
me I got a lot of walking to do but I
can get rid of all that and so that's
what we did he just hung out there I
just want to interject something that
you said on the previous podcast I want
to make sure you don't skip it here you
said in that podcast that it was the
greatest indoor you've ever seen I think
I think we should focus on that just
like for us you know not for too long
the greatest indoor you've ever seen and
he had seen some at that point
I have yeah so you know 20 year old JK
that's me 20 year old JK uh walks you
know his whole deal in the country was
to find the best weed that was what it
was all about I mean it was the music it
was the good times but really you know
the weed is right there it's at the top
so in order to do that you know back
then you kind of had to like you know
network with Growers and you know I was
happy to meet a new one and I mean I
can't disagree about it being the most
high quality indoor I've ever seen I
mean the guy puts his Gabby grows
incredible wheat he always has I mean
this is the man who taught me everything
I need to know on day one
cuts and all and so you know I was so
like elated I couldn't believe it it was
like my lucky day so it was you know it
helped me out so much but um that day it
was a rough day it was a rough period
like you know I just gotten off the
green tortoise coming from Eugene Oregon
left my girlfriend my dogs up there to
come to the city to make money I mean it
was it wasn't always easy it was really
hard actually a lot of times being on
the road and this was a hard period
um the cops rough on us I remember a few
of my friends were missing when I got
there who were in jail for selling weed
and you know so it was rough man so this
was like a shiny spot this is like one
of those moments though when you're
traveling around you know it's like [ __ ]
man what am I doing man like I don't
know what I'm doing like I can't make it
another day I'm like I'm in a park
practically homeless you know and where
I'm on the road and I you know I can
barely afford gas to get to the next
show and they're like I think it's time
for me to maybe go get a job or
something and go back home right then
you know something like this would
happen like meeting Gabby in a park or
acting them millions things where it's
just like it just gets you one more day
and that's all you need is just one more
day just to remember like hey I belong
here this is okay I can make this you
know so this was one of those moments
for me you know I was contemplating
wrapping it up and maybe going home and
trying to find a little easier way
and uh so anyways I sold all that weed
and when I was done you know Gabby
expressed to me that he was very
grateful and you know that he was
actually thinking about the same thing
he was thinking about maybe he'd made a
mistake by coming to California and that
he was hoping that and I think the quote
was his his uh
I don't know if it was you that told me
that's the Grateful Dead uh Grateful
Dead dream continue I'm so grateful that
fantasy continue one more day you know
um because he wanted to stay in the city
and see Jerry Garcia band that's why he
moved there that's what he told me so he
expressed to me and like I said I could
totally understand that
so I was there too and uh so in saying
that he also he wanted to show he by his
words he wanted to show gratitude he
said listen you know when you come to
The Warfield shows I always get this one
particular table in The Warfield I get
there at 5am I think he used to get
there and be first in line and just sit
on Market Street all day long
until you know six o'clock at night when
it would open up it wasn't exactly it
wasn't exactly 5 a.m it was more along
the lines of 2 P.M
sometimes it would be like we we would
compete with like it was like maybe 10
people there that would always try to be
the first in line and so like you know
it started off as three o'clock and then
somebody would show up at 2 45 and you
know by the end of it we're showing up
sometimes at like 1 p.m but it wasn't
like the back in the day when we used to
wait for Grateful Dead tickets at like
the ticket trip box office yeah we would
win the night before or five in the
morning but to see Jerry if you wanted
to have your spot you had to show up
like one or two o'clock
it was general admission on the floor
yep
yeah well so well he so you know he said
I always get the same table it's the
thing I do
um and I'm and and you're always welcome
to come hang out with me there I'm like
wow okay yeah great
and so sure enough I mean it couldn't
have been too long for everywhere it
could have been that month I don't
remember 1993 shows that much but
um I went through the Warfield Jerry
always came on stage at let's just say
20 till 8 you know 7 30 he'd make us
wait for 10 minutes well you know I
would come in I I came in at like closer
to eight you know the place is already
shaking people's dancing the dreadlocks
are swinging and I don't know what it
was but I looked clear across the floor
because I was looking for him you know I
went onto the floor I had to sneak on
the floor
um and instead of being up in the
balcony anyway they're making the story
too long but
um I saw him some clear across the floor
in the dark
people dancing like crazy as they do
with these things and he's looking right
at me and he and he point he points to
the chair next to me and he's like come
on over here Justice need to come on
over I'm like wow so I go over there and
you know I sit down at the table and
it's like the best seat in the house the
best weed in the house for sure is being
smoked I mean this table became kind of
legendary there I mean you had Bob
Snodgrass and Maria come down and smoke
I remember smoking out of the Dragon
there I remember Dan Healy swung by at
one time and not to mention like pretty
much all the good [ __ ] indoor weed
you know that made it to San Francisco
for these shows would somehow make it to
the table you know that people would
stop by
and uh it was [ __ ] amazing
um so the next night the same thing and
the next night and then pretty much
every night until until Jerry you know
kicked the bucket and said goodbye to us
you know I hung out with Gabby at the at
The Warfield at his table and it was
amazing it was like a bar right in front
of it and just a few just a perfect view
of the fat man up there just rocking it
out it was amazing like I always tell
people who weren't around this I I would
give I would give like the right hand
almost for just one more night there you
know and like I don't really want to do
that but it's like that yeah I would do
anything I'm sure God feels the same one
more damn night's worth it I would do
anything you know
at least give a stub of my finger like
like Jerry had all
had a lot would take a little piece of
my finger off
that would be an easy trade yep I'd do
that yeah
wow that sounds legendary let me let me
ask one quick question I'm sure there
was some incredible different samples of
weed going across that table over the
years were there any particular
standouts to either of you
well
I mean mostly it was big Gabby's weed
you know that was the best at the table
I mean one other we would show up and be
like I mean you know all those people I
mentioned they came by because they knew
that he had the good lead there you know
like if they were going to come back
behind the stage or make their way
across the floor you know they were
gonna they were gonna come to that table
people just knew when the word got out
and you know Gabby was always so
generous with his weed and like
um you know I always wanted to turn
people onto it so a lot of people did
get turned on to it and they swing by
the table you know there was one famous
herb that I don't think I used to get it
at The Warfield but I used to get it
like on
Grateful Dead Tour on the west coast
that to this day I can remember the
taste and the way it looked and
um was the Big Sir holy weed
oh yeah and and they had one Gunk and
they had a haze they had the skunk
I know which one you like both of them
both of them were out of this world
and they were I remember like
at the way I found that weed was the
family that was selling that herb
that used to sell it a quarter ounce at
a time I think it was like 125 bucks for
a quarter ounce on on dead tour
and it's kind of similar to the stories
that you tell about the the skunk and
the chem dog I used to just buy it all
up you know like they wanted to sell in
his quarters and I was like [ __ ] it you
know I didn't buy that chicken the best
weed ever and then kind of similar to
the story with the chem dog is
only family and friends would get that
weed
you know because
it was already too expensive and too
rare like this wasn't the type of weed
that you went and sold for random people
that you didn't know on the deadline
exactly you want to share with your
friends you know you would wait and be
patient until you bumped into them you
know
yeah it's funny see you you say you have
no good memory you remember the Big Sir
holy weed though you remember those two
skunk and Hayes sometimes people bring
that up I mean I just have holes I just
I just have holes in my memory it's not
complete and you know I just wanna a lot
of people are telling this story to the
best of their ability
and I don't think that this is an issue
of like
people are lying and making [ __ ] up and
like you know not so dog he believes the
story
and
like you said how you realize you made a
mistake on something you said on the
other podcast like when I was teasing
you and making
this is what it's gonna be like for
everybody and you know we're dealing
with something that happened
a long time ago
your not so dog puts it you know put it
pretty clearly none of us knew how
important this history was gonna be so
we didn't keep detailed notes
you know and
you know
I don't think you or I or not so dog
there's really nothing to benefit from
the little mistakes that are being made
or discrepancies that are being made in
these stories
you know it's not like by saying this
this person's gonna make a have a big
payday
it doesn't look like anyone's trying to
do that you know so I think we should
have healthy debate about what we think
the story was and enjoy telling the
stories me particularly if I enjoy
listening to the stories from you guys
because your memory even if there's some
mistakes
it's so much more detailed than mine and
it's for me it's the most beautiful
thing to hear you tell the stories
I love that I love you brother I'm so
glad to hear that I love you
I'm glad that we're able to even like
share the story you know because it's a
miracle that any of this like it's like
I always tell people you know 30 years
later
um just from my viewpoint of all this
it's it's like it's a unique thing to be
able to look back and kind of see the
whole thing at least from my perspective
you know and and just to watch he like
kind of appreciate like all the little
twists and turns all the little nudges
in a certain direction you know
and and to like it all just kind of
seems like what the hell is going on
here like it seems like a like a divine
intervention almost you know what it is
the plant you know it has a divine
intervention it definitely does it
definitely
somehow it works with us whether we
understand it or not we don't and and
you know it's amazing that you know
she's still here and and then all the
different people and none of us knew
each other that's the other thing like
so you know like Gabby new Greg but I
didn't know I never even heard of the
guy you know it's like all these little
details I'm like if you take one little
piece of it out and she may not make it
and she's here and then we're here still
and we get to talk to each other now you
know now you know we all get to know
each other everybody who is involved
with what happened back then with this
particular plan or a few plants and to
me it's just like
I mean it's it's a it's it's hard it's
difficult to explain it to someone to
give them the perspective that you know
like I or Gabby has you know to see like
you know like what's really going on
here you're like you know this wasn't
about anything except for having the
best [ __ ] week that's all it was
there was no motivation so you know not
so dog and Gabby you know like he said
are correct it's like
um you know like you know it's it's just
it's to me it's just it's just amazing
that we can still tell the story you
know and that we can all talk about it
amongst each other none of us saw it and
like like those guys said like we
weren't like none of this was part none
of this was important it had no
importance whatsoever like not one of us
you know I know Gabby and I we didn't we
never like even once considered like you
know what's gonna happen 30 years later
you know it's just like let's smoke the
best weed today and laugh and have a
good time and go snowboarding and skiing
and watch Seinfeld like we used to do
you know and so that's what it was all
about and so it's all so delicate in
that sense you know like nobody was
trying to get to the Finish Line we were
just trying to you know have the best
weed in our pocket which we did and
maybe that was what that maybe that's
how it worked the plant gives us what we
want and we give the plant what it wants
and look at us all surviving you know
that's I think that's still the goal
today right so very uh full circle I I
want to quickly take us back a sec
because you I I agree with Gabby you're
doing such a good job with this story I
want to quickly rewind a second and ask
Gabby a question tell us about the
Francine this is one that a lot of
people are interested in mostly because
when that trade for the skunk eventually
went down that was what those VA dudes
were more interested in and I think a
lot of people are sort of like what like
why was it the Francine like what was
going on there and I think in the first
episode Jason said that it was sort of
like a Northern Lights thing but I'd
love to hear from Gabby like what was
your take on the Francine in terms of
like the flavor the effect how do you
remember it
okay so I hope this story isn't
disappointing to everyone because you
know
the ending isn't so great but so the
Francine was just bag seed that I had
acquired on Grateful Dead tour
and I have no idea what it was you know
we could speculate that it was Northern
Lights just based on what we thought we
knew which was limited about you know
other stuff like that and you know
photos we had seen but it was bag seed
and uh and you know I think not so dog
mentioned this
you know before and in multiple podcasts
a lot of the stuff
that was done back then
it was accidents
you know and you know you get a bag of
weed you find a couple seeds back then
you kept them
today most of the time if I find
backseat I don't keep it you know unless
it's like something that's truly amazing
but you know I don't try to plant
accidents like but that back then that's
all I had I didn't have access to clones
this was in a highly secretive New York
Market
you know so at the time I didn't really
have anyone uh I forget what his I think
that he goes by weasel
somebody named them weasels which could
be the only name that's worse than
Staten Island
I mean like I felt bad about Staten
Island and I found out they call him
weasel I was like oh [ __ ] this could
have been much worse he was he was
growing some seed grown stuff that that
he had uh you know from Bad Seed that he
collected as well
from like we went to a a dead show at
RFK
and I don't know if you guys heard of
the RFK but he had the RFK one two and
three three different females that he
kept from seed that he found there but
you know I wanted to try to wow
get something else from seeds that I had
I had been going to a lot more shows
than he did and
um
you know I uh I felt like I could uh
maybe find something nice out of my seed
and what I did was I named every six I
named every single one of my seeds a
girl's name
okay even this is prior to knowing what
their sex was just as like positive
affirmation everything had a girl's name
okay and and so you know I had Francine
I had Irene you know Michelle whatever
you know just like just because I didn't
want to name them one two three I wanted
it to be more personal than that
you know so I gave him a lot of girls
names
and um
the Francine ended up being the best
of those seeds that I planted
it was really I think partly what was
attractive to it was it was a very easy
plant to grow
it used to put out really big chunky
buds
and at the time
you know we were growing organically
and it was way hard to get those results
it was hard to get really big chunky
buds when you were growing organic in a
container
particularly with the limited knowledge
that we had at the time so the Francine
was a really easy plant to grow
I think it had like a mildly fruity
slash hash plant type taste and uh it
was really impressive to look at
you know kind of like the market today
how the visual look is so important back
then you know I was able to sell the
Francine based on how it looks now
when I think about it compared to all
the other weed that we had gotten after
and all the weed that we have today
it's not on that level
if not some I mean I wish I had it just
for
you know posterity and you know to say
I've had this strained for as long you
know but
it really wasn't as good as everything
else that we got and it used to have a
problem getting moldy
you know so once I started having
because the budget was so dense
yeah you know so they're very wet too I
ran away from growing it yeah
so I mean
now the best part of the story about the
Francine was that's how we got the
chemdog right like he was so impressed
with it I hope I can say his name
um because I just did you did I I don't
know what his stage name is do we need
to edit that [ __ ] out
um
he's the most paranoid [ __ ] I
ever met in my life
hey okay we could just say yeah we could
just say if that's his real name we
could just say that my memory is garbage
his real name probably isn't even
it is
well I mean it doesn't
yeah hey if you hear this this is Jason
we've been looking for you for 26 years
where are you at come on now I'm just
kidding I'm sorry sorry I just outed I'm
sorry I just outed you I'm only sorry I
can't see the look on his face if he
actually heard that
don't worry about it Gabby don't worry
about that damn now I got a fear for my
life
so okay so something else about the
Francine was I used to have a a bubbler
Bob Snodgrass custom-made a bubbler
that instead is Francine on it and that
was the only herb that I ever smoked out
of
and when I stopped throwing the Francine
I stopped smoking out of that bubbler
never used it again and luckily one day
I found some girl her name was Francine
and she was a smoker and I was like yeah
you need to have this I love it I just I
just gave it to her because her name was
Francine and
yeah I was like if not it's just gonna
sit in the drawer forever I'm never
gonna use it now Francine can can use it
forever
so yeah right there that story
encompasses why I I just adore you
because you're so [ __ ] generous and
like that pipe you could have carried
out all the way never smoked out of it
again you know a lot of people would
have you know it's part of their life
but to give it to someone like that
that's I love that about you that's very
very cool so you want to hear something
funny about you saying how generous I am
not so dog in his previous podcast
he said how stingy I was
he was like I'm super stingy he was
talking about he was talking about the
chem dog and he like mentioned it like
three times that like she just didn't
give everybody the chem dog you know
yeah and what I pointed out to him was I
gave it to my friends I gave it to my
group
you know like I gave it I gave it to you
I gave it to him I gave it to others too
so like just because I didn't like stand
on a street corner peddling chem dog
clones doesn't mean like
you know I was stingy you know I I you
know you said before you know I like to
share my weed and you know Francis puts
it out to the universe Staten Island's a
stingy [ __ ]
there's there's so many incredible
details around this short period of time
I'd love to quickly check in on a few of
them I'm not sure if Jason said it
earlier but when you guys had that
initial first meeting did you have any
chem dog with you at that time or not
yet
it's funny that you asked this question
because in the previous podcast
Jason said that I had a little chem dog
during this encounter and like when I
was listening to it I texted Jason I'm
like you're a [ __ ] liar
you know because I
and you know basically I was just making
a point that like it's possible for any
of us to get this story wrong
right and Jason made a mistake when he
was telling the story and he said that I
had the chem dog when we first met but
the reality is I got the chem dog
after going to New York
and I got the VA skunk and I traded the
skunk for the camera
so I'm not sure what year it was I think
it was 93 like you said earlier
um yeah but yeah so like
Jason's connection to getting the chem
dog
is pretty crucial you know he likes to
give me all the credit but I can turn it
around and give him the credit because
um chem dog you know G he would not have
given me
the chem dog if I didn't have something
you really wanted like the skunk
yeah I wanted to quickly ask you about
that like firstly how did you meet Greg
and then as a follow-up was he holding
out because he knew the chem dog was so
good and he wanted to trade or he was he
just like a recluse dude and just didn't
really trade
um no he was willing to trade just not
the chem dog because he knew it was
super valuable that he was the only one
had it but you know I lived in
California he was mostly working it on
the East Coast so he didn't see me as
much of a threat and like because when I
lived in New York he didn't want to give
it to us
you know but
um so did you meet him through klopping
that or did you manage to meet him some
other way I did
I I met him through Club wow okay so
like that that's another thing is like
people discount
weasel or clops you know placing all of
this you know I know they do but like
if it wasn't for klopp I don't meet
chemdogs and none of this happens either
and it's funny because like you know
people give you Jason and clap [ __ ]
saying like they're making up this story
and but and you know it's like he was he
was critical in me getting it I wouldn't
have got it and so were you if I didn't
have the skunk Greg was being tight Greg
was the one that was [ __ ] cheap not
me I Greg was being stingy I had to have
something to trade he wasn't gonna just
give it to me you know finally when I
had something that good to trade you did
it yeah do you remember I don't know if
you've ever even told me this but do you
remember the first time you ever smoked
Kim Dong yeah it was with Kemp it was
with the G damn dog
was it like before you moved out or
before you moved out earlier
yeah I think I had moved out already I
had moved out in 91 and that's like when
he had first got it so it was like on a
visit to New York or you know
and what was it like was he was he
growing it really good back then or was
he still figuring it out
man I hate to throw people under the bus
but like his growth setup in my view was
pretty pathetic it was like I mean he
had this Garden called the Emily's
Garden are you guys familiar with it
no
okay it's a prefabricated hydroponic
garden which is just like a little
Reservoir with a lid on top with like
four holes for like baskets or rockwool
cubes
and then it's like deep water culture
you just like have a air stone in there
um you know and that's how he was
growing the chem dog
and one part of the story that I like to
tell us he called it the chem dog he
used to say you can't grow it organic
that's why it's the chem dub
and at the time I was the biggest
organic snob there was you know like if
you were to give me a pound of
hydroponically grown weed that was the
best ever
I would just like turn my nose to it I
was I was just snob
and so I tried to grow it organic and we
did grow it organic and you know
it barely survived before Harvest you
know it was like almost dead by the time
it was time to cut it you know it's such
a hard plant to grow particularly
organic and then and I told this story
on the other podcast too but I think
it's important for me at least
I had this moment
where
um I read something in a pamphlet from a
company that was selling hydroponic
nutrients
and what it said is Organics are mineral
compounds
that contain carbon
and need to be broken down into them
more common mineral form before they can
be uptaken by the plants
and minerals are the building blocks of
all life on the planet
and when I read that
I was like oh [ __ ] like maybe I should
try growing using minerals
and I did
and I never turned back you know so now
I've seen you know if you're growing in
a container indoors or outdoors and
you're trying to you know do it organic
you got your work cut out for you you
know it's not really
and and generally I don't think you get
as good of a quality now I add Organics
to my mineral nutrition you know I'll
add some seaweed I'll add some other
organic additives
but the base of what my plants eat
is mineral nutrition and you know
there's like a thing right now where
people are trying to do living soil
indoors they're like this is no-till
indoors I'm like bro that's just like
what a stupid thing to say in my opinion
no offense you know to the like really
you know popular Growers that are doing
that but
thing that you don't till indoors like
how are you gonna [ __ ] get that
tiller indoors anyway
oh man yeah
that's a good point that's a good point
I want to quickly ask you before I
forget in the first episode Jason was
talking about how when you were growing
organically you had like these really
sort of Cutting Edge methods for the
time and what was it the vat like the
the living compost tea tell me about
that quickly
it it was cutting edge and crude at the
very same time like
you know I used to have a couple of
trash cans
that I would fill up with organic
fertilizer it'd be one that would be for
guanos you know so I'd make guano teas
and it would have some seaweed in it and
stuff like that and my logic was I never
let it get more than half empty
and it's always being aerated
and so I thought like it was kind of
like a starter for like yeast like for
sourdough you can't get rid of it
because that's what you got all that
life in that thing so you always want to
just like do it halfway
and I would literally keep this vat
going for years and if I moved from one
location to another I would like take
the starter with me you know and then
the other thing that I tried doing which
was super disgusting was in another vat
and I had to do this outside eventually
because it was so [ __ ] gross
um I would put food scraps in the water
and you know just aerate it and agitate
it and then I would water that to my
plants so it was pretty disgusting stuff
when I when I started scooping one
teaspoon per gallon of mineral
fertilizer
you know people like Hydroponics that
shit's so dirty I was like you think so
you should see them so again
you know like [ __ ] blast the
pneumonia like
and if the if the pump if the aerating
pump would die for you the power outage
I don't I know Gabby's the same way the
first thing you think about is the vat
because it would just be a matter of you
know hours before you'd start to smell
the decay of the background or uh
bacteria and I knew that because I would
take my hand and Stir It Up I was the
same thing Gabby taught me this and this
is what I did and it worked amazing like
sometimes I'm like maybe I should do
that again but I would take my hand and
stir it up because it would be a lot of
sediment on the bottom and then if you
know if you like you know how you're
working you always got little cuts on
your fingers they would get like
infected in seconds and like get on red
you know like oh [ __ ] that hot it's
ready to feed you know and same thing
always when they get you know take half
the trash can and you know hey gab you
remember the other day I told you about
your buddy who took that Horticulture
class with you in Santa Rosa well that
the second thing he mentioned was the
bat
well it's funny I was going to mention
that before how we were talking about
how small world it is and you run into
one of my college buddies when you're
just around what a crazy small world
what a small world
can I can I bring us back for one second
I I love that point about how Gabby you
mentioned that um you know in a sense
the chem dog coming out to the east
coast could equally be attributed you
know to to skunk via to Jason and I
remember in that first interview I did
with him he made a comment he said you
know this this guy was really impressive
you know he was a real good networker
and I guess it I just want to sort of
confirm because it sounds pretty
impressive that like you were able to
Mastermind this plan to get the chem dog
through this through the skunk trade had
you been thinking about like how can I
get this cam dog off Greg for a while or
was it just like a spur-of-the-moment
thing and you
oh yeah Greg didn't want to give it up
you know yeah he didn't want to give it
up so
so then run us through how the trade
went down how did how did it all go down
logistically well so I don't have the
exact details of like I don't remember
the exact conversation that made it
happen but
I think Jason got it a little bit wrong
but again it doesn't like change any of
the stories at all so what happened was
uh our buddy that we're not supposed to
say his name from Virginia well how
about we how about we call him not so
loud does that work
that works
I think that's way funnier
um he came out to see Jerry at The
Warfield
that's when Jason introduced me to him
he saw the Francine and was interested
in trading the France scene for the
skunk
and and I do believe we were also always
trying to get the Beatrix Choice which I
don't think we actually ever got
yeah but uh yeah so he wanted the
Francine and he wanted to trade for the
skunk and then somehow I arranged to
trade the skunk with Greg
for um
for the chem dogs and that's how I got
it and
I um I went
first to New York City
where I met not so
and traded him the Francine for the
skunk
and I believe he gave me a couple clones
which I took up to
Massachusetts and I traded one of them
for I think I got a couple of clones of
the chem dog from G
[Applause]
and then I went back down I did leave
one with klopp because
again if it wasn't for him none of this
happens
and
um then I drove West and
I you know I told the story on the other
podcast as well I had it in a Burger
King cup with a lid at two Burger King
cups one with skunk and one with the
chem dog
and you know when I was driving down the
road if a truck was coming by or if I
was scared of police I just put the lid
on the cuff
and when that wasn't happening you know
it was getting sunlight through the
front window and then like whatever
light I could give it in the hotel room
to get that [ __ ] across country
so
I mean that's the short story I don't
know if you want to ask any more
questions for me to make it more
detailed but no that that's incredible
so that oh I got one last quick question
and then I want to start talking some
more about the skunk but I heard mixed
reports about some people say oh you
know weasel was the head of that New
York crew and then other people are like
no it was JJ he was the head who was
sort of the head honcho in your eyes
well I wasn't there right so like you
know I I certainly wasn't the head
honcho because I wasn't there
you know and JJ he used to buy the weed
from klopp
this is prior to him growing
you know JJ was the was the connect to
get rid of it
so I mean I don't think anyone any of us
ever thought of us as the the leader or
the Kingpin you know but but cloth or
weasel was the one
that you know started all this stuff
getting grown on Staten Island I've
mentioned before he should probably be
called Staten Island because he lived
there longer than me
um but whatever at this point I'm gonna
embrace the [ __ ] nobody nobody would try
to pick that name away from me
but uh yeah and so he also gave it to a
couple of our Staten Island friends
so you know if I had to answer your
question I would say yeah it was weasel
that is really responsible for all that
growing on that island and
he was the first person that I ever saw
growing cannabis indoors now I I can
tell you that story briefly
um another one that I told on this other
podcast but
um
so me and my it's like an old girlfriend
that I had at the time were literally
sitting outside of a subway station on
Staten Island
there's like a few like you know trains
on Staten Island and we had just like
come back from
I think seeing a dead show at the Garden
or something like that and so we're like
sitting on the street like on the curb
smoking weed
right outside this train station
and weasel's like hey what are you doing
down there and we're like uh
it's like smoking weed and we're like
yeah he's like oh well come up here and
smoke it with me
you know like he smelt some good weed he
wasn't used to seeing weed like that
okay like I I believe that was the first
time he ever encountered kind buds
and so we showed him this weed that we
were getting on dead tour and he was
like this shit's grown indoors like you
can grow this indoors and we're like
yeah
and that was the point where he got
inspired to grow weed
and I remember like he first like
dropped a couple of seeds in a 10 gallon
fish tank and his like cat used to dig
it up all the time you know before he
like made it like more secure
and then he had rent eventually was
growing with just normal T5 for not T5
it's like T8 like the regular fat tube
fluorescence in his closet
and that was the first time even though
we had gotten kind bud and indoor on
tour that was the first time I ever saw
indoor was growing
and that was the moment like you know I
inspired him to start it and then he
inspired me to like stop being a gypsy
to get a house where I could grow weed
too
okay and so that's when I got an
apartment in Brooklyn
and that's where I grew my first weed
because
um
I was inspired by uh
by Mike
wow that's a cool backstory I would love
to hear tell me about you got the skunk
to California and you harvested it the
first time I want to hear both you guys
opinions slash Recollections of what was
that first skunk crop like when it was
your own homegrown
I don't get this day
to this day
people call me up or message me and ask
me about that weed and tell me that it
was some of the best weed ever
so a very respected breeder out here his
name is Shiloh and he has a seed company
called Shiloh massive genetics so I have
um
I have some of his genetics
you know I was doing some Nursery work
and I have so much genetics and I asked
him I was like hey do you want copies
of this stuff you know I just sent him a
message I wanted to know like hey I've
got some of your genetics I don't know
if you if you still have it if you want
it
and his response to me is do you have
any of that VA skunk
and I
said to him I was like you heard the
podcast because I had just done this
other podcast and he's like oh no that
was just the best weed I've ever had in
my life
so yeah I think we all I think we all
had that same
you know the same feeling about that
herb is that that was some of the best
weed we ever smoked in our life
like to grow it
was way better than growing the pemdom
you know it was you have to remember
like we weren't that skilled Growers
like Jason earlier said you know is the
best indoor weed he ever smoked I mean
there wasn't a lot of really good indoor
being grown there wasn't a lot of
knowledge on how to do it it was still a
pretty
pretty new thing you know I think about
it now like a lot of the [ __ ] that we
were doing it's like
it's amazing that we got the results we
did
yeah it was it was it was like that that
super skunk the number six it was it's
hard to
it's hard to like explain to someone
these days like how amazing it was like
it's difficult especially when they
start talking about you know skunk
itself you know
I mean this stuff was more skunky than
skunk you know it was it was it was
incredible you know and the high was
perfect you know it wasn't it was like
it wasn't great it wasn't very strong
yeah
yeah it wasn't overpowered the Kim dog
was like you know I can't I'm just gonna
stare at the wall and drool whereas the
super skunk was what you smoked all day
you could do your thing you could go do
your errands you're gonna run to the
store whatever you got to do you know
but the flavor and the other and you
know the thing that the super skunk and
the chem dog and probably many other
strands but at least those two haven't
comments like every single time you
smoke it you got stoned there was
something about it where you couldn't
really build a tolerance I mean we were
smoking bong heads bubblers and fatties
and [ __ ] all day and every single time
it just hits you just right I don't
really think there's a lot of herb like
that in my opinion you know there's not
a lot of herb that just hits you just
right every time you know and chem dog
is definitely on that list and Superstar
plus too and I wish that you know more
people could enjoy it
but
it was all about that it was so good it
was so good easy to grow uh it just gave
you a lot big Yoder you know it did
stretch out a lot like the sour diesel
does but
um you know sticks of weed you know just
tons of sticks of meat it was amazing
that's beautiful and I know that there
was two iterations of the Superdog can
you tell us about the first one the the
original chemdog cross Super Skunk seeds
how did they come about and what were
those seeds like when you grew them
um well
there was many iterations of the
Superdog
you know it would make you know we were
trying or what I was trying to do and
this was
um me and not so dog
we were trying to make crosses that had
that had chem dominance
you know like we we tried to cross
everything we had
hoping hoping that we could get I mean
we obviously you know we wouldn't have
crossed it with everything we had if we
didn't want diversity right
but yet we really wanted something that
had chem traits and that grew better
than the chem dog because it was such a
difficult plant to grow
and
I had gotten seeds from Scentsy
and we had gotten super skunk from
Scentsy
based on the fact that the this VA skunk
was so good we felt like this is the
best thing you know to buy from Scentsy
in order to cross
with the chem dog I don't know what year
this was and I do know that there's been
a bunch of confusion over whether like
what what we made to cross the camp the
Superdog with but like at the time I was
dead set against using any seeds that
you know although
you know everything we did was made from
bag seed
I would never germinate purposefully
something that I knew that was grown
like from a Herm right so we tried to
buy thieves
from Holland because we wanted true a
true male
that we could cross with the temdog and
the super skunk was the obvious choice
we wanted to get that [ __ ] back and
um
you know that's how we did it so we got
the the seeds from Scentsy
you know Scentsy feeds
you couldn't count on many things but
one thing you could count on is if you
bought the super skunk that [ __ ] looked
exactly like the catalog we used to like
grow the flower and then hold the Sentry
Seed Catalog up against the buds and be
like yeah that's it you know it was
incredible
and so we crossed those males with the
dog and everything else we had
many times and I tried to do inbreeding
with the chem dog so the first time
um you know we did it
you know we called the the super dog and
then we crossed it back to the dog again
and did it again I think we did it three
times
and honestly the the skunk genetics was
so dominant
and our knowledge of selection
was so limited
that I never got anything
that was like what I wanted
you know there's a ton of great things
that you know the stuff was nice but it
wasn't I never produced what I wanted
ah can I quickly ask I could be wrong
here I I thought the the very first
integration of the super dog seeds was
the VA skunk on to the chem dog am I
incorrect was it actually the first
integration was just the Scentsy seeds
and it never had the VA skunk in it
what are you asking about is when you
made the seeds when you were over at a
water trough you know and so I answered
that question already when I said I
wouldn't do a perm right and the the
super skunk
the VA skunk that we had was a female
plant yeah I wanted to do what I
considered legitimate breeding
and to me breeding with seeds that could
potentially have hermaphrodite traits
wasn't legitimate breeding so we had to
get ourselves males
from a reliable source in order to make
any of this stuff happen yeah yeah
certainly I can appreciate that you
wanted males to work with so exactly and
like this part you know who knows so gab
when you were over at water troughs um
you may not totally remember this
because it was kind of a blip in your
room you know like in your timeline but
you actually had some NL uh five hay
seeds and I don't know exactly
yeah this was like 1997. and you you had
uh what happened is you had bought those
you crossed them with either the chem
dog or either the super skunk the number
six I don't remember which one and then
you took a mail you found the mail in
that you did this pretty quick too I
remember that was the one thing looking
back now knowing what I know I'm like
damn that happened quick and then he you
cross that back with the chem dog and we
started calling that super dog
um it was a very small amount of Siege
and I don't really know what you did
with them all I remember is that one
time you went out of town and you'd
harvested as the first the reason I
remembered so clearly is because it was
the first time I'd ever seen you know
cannabis right from Steve you know and
you had that cardboard box thing and you
harvest it and you were calling super
super dogs like super skunk dog
um but they definitely had that nl5 Haze
because we discussed it I remember
sitting in your bedroom in that bathroom
where you grew in where you showed me
the pack and you know we looked at we
actually had some pictures you had a
catalog I think or or I don't know how
he saw the pictures but we looked at
pictures and he discussed it with me I
was like you do you Gabby but and then
the only thing I remember was when we
harvested that or you harvested it you
went out of town and you asked me to go
over to the cardboard box and box
everything up you know like put it in
tupperwares because it was on the lines
drying in that box and it was [ __ ]
dank it was so good you know it was a
nice blend of super uh super skunk and
chem dog actually and of course I wasn't
familiar with the no5 haze then but you
know I don't I can't in my memory I
don't remember seeing much of that in it
you know what I mean
too probably
you know I'm pretty sure that I did get
NL seeds but I remember getting the
super skunk seeds because the thing is
the NL seeds were almost like an
afterthought because hey if we're gonna
go order seeds from Amsterdam we're not
just gonna order one pack right right
and so the super skunk was the like main
thing that we wanted you know and then
we picked up some other [ __ ] too
yeah yeah beautiful
memory's a funny thing this is the way I
I remember the story
but you know
it sounds like you guys did a lot a lot
more extensive work when you guys
started working with those Scentsy seeds
Super Skunk seeds
what yeah you know because he had a
whole bunch of genetics
you know he had the Mendo perps he had
the Maui he had
a ton of [ __ ] that we crossed when we
did this
you know and he was the one that I
remember coming up with the name not so
dog
you know he reminded me of this when we
talked and the reason why the [ __ ] we
call the [ __ ] not so dog the original
ones we called them the SD the super dog
the original SD right
um but then after doing it again you
know one day Francis says hey you know
what this is not so dog
and we're like oh [ __ ] that's what we
got to call it the not so dog because
because it was great it just wasn't the
dog
you know that's brilliant so yeah so
tell me how long were you growing the
original skunk six the VA skunk for
before you lost it
I think Jason might know better than
that yeah I have no idea I remember that
so well so I guess you would say hmm if
you got it and
you must have got it in 1993.
um so yeah we can go back to the
beginning so
let's [ __ ] your name
is so much funnier
you can see that yeah I'm gonna make
shirts uh we're gonna Hey where's that
where's not so I loved it because he
disappeared my best friend died in 2002
the last time I saw him was at the
funeral and you know like we felt like
there was law enforcement there and
there had there was reason for law
enforcement to be at my friend's funeral
and
saw that and we talked about it and that
was the last time I saw it
never heard from him again never saw him
again but anyway so this is the one that
came out but also that night when I
don't know what you guys talked about I
wasn't part of the discussion obviously
but there was some other Brokers from
Virginia uh the night where you guys
talked about trading you know like
talking about superstars
no I was there but I wasn't part of the
discussion
well I was there I wasn't part of the
discussion so I was there and but there
was some other characters there from
Virginia who were kind of more like you
know uh not Kingpin like you guys called
but like more more in control of those
cuts was you know it was kind of like
the guy who can maybe get the cuts you
know
um but those were the ones that were
keeping holding the cuts and they were
there too and you know so that's why I
was so surprised by all this because I I
don't even know those guys and I was
surprised I acted like I don't know who
they were because I knew that would make
them more comfortable although I grew up
smoking their weed in Virginia you know
the weed they actually grew and um so
they actually asked to ask you you know
about that you know they've been talking
about it you know they were there I was
there and they actually asked you and
then they actually asked me
as a [ __ ] kid you know what I thought
about it because that's just how people
are from there and that's how those guys
were and I was like dude it's none of my
business you know I just want to hang
out with the good weeds you know and so
that's how it all went down they agreed
to to share that cut you know on to give
Gabby that cut and I guess they would
have gotten I cut it up Francine at
least I hope they did but uh so
um
we had it from that point Gabby had it
from that point on and he passed it to
me in 1995 just right before Jerry
Garcia died you know like so July of
1995 when I came up to Sonoma County and
got a house up there and uh he told me
he would set me up and he did
um
going to see Jerry right when you put
Jerry yeah right
here
when he decided you don't want to see
Jerry no more yeah well you know we
talked about that earlier what you meant
what you were saying was is because you
used to always be like you were hard on
the vents and of course everybody was
you know but uh you're a little bit
older than me too so you know it's
easier for you to be in this position
you know and you said uh to me is like
you know Jay can't Jason when this whole
grateful when you're done with this
whole Grateful Dead thing let me know
and I'm gonna hook you up with some
clothes I'm gonna show you what I know
and we'll get you growing and when you
told me that you were like fulfilling my
big dream because
A Grateful Dead tour but all the whole
thing is like you know I want to grow my
own weed and sell some weed out of the
you know my house that I'm growing you
know what I mean and kind of grow the
best weeds you know the whole thing it's
like the big dream so anyway we
lost the super skunk don't really you
know it's easier to remember like an
event that's catastrophic it's hard to
remember like the events that led up to
that and I do admit that I have a hard
time admitting or not admitting uh
remembering why like what has happened
up to the point where
um the story so you had a outlet it was
uh right left your toaster oven in your
kitchen and you're having a lot of
trouble with it it was causing problems
in other circuits in the house not
necessarily your grow room but like you
know your living circus so you like your
laundry room and your kitchen and you're
using a vacuum to suck water out of it
and you were convinced that the water
that you kept getting out of it had
something to do with it
so you know eventually you know you had
me look at it and I wasn't electrician
yet but I knew a thing or two I couldn't
figure it out and so you had to call the
landlord and so the landlord had to call
an electrician and they also had to come
over and check it out and
um at that point you had to take down
your grow room you had to kind of box up
your broom and you had the boxes through
plants the part I don't remember is how
is it that we only had one mother of
that you know I don't think we really
coordinated like like super like
organized on who had what mothers to
make sure we didn't really think about
it much you know we just knew we both
had it because me and Gabby and it was
an emergency situation
not and it was an emergency and it had
been going on for like a week and it had
become a bigger emergency like oh [ __ ]
we got to deal with this you know it's
hard for people to understand these days
it's kind of hard for me to even express
it or anybody probably like how
stressful a situation like this can be
you know because of the way things are
now compared to this could like wreck
your whole deal you know this could be
like the end for you at least that's our
perception you know and so he had to put
that thing in a box or along with all
his other mothers and probably had to I
don't remember this but knowing him he
probably had a crop going in he probably
had to chop some [ __ ] down you know and
toss it
but the models were in a box and I don't
know exactly what happened but that's
where the super skunk died and it was
I want to say 1997 or 1998 but I'm I'm
like more like 82 or 89 sure it was
actually 1998.
um and that was there we lost it right
then I had passed it to someone in
Humboldt County
and those people are different they're
up in white Thorns oh man I shouldn't
say that in Tumble and they um
the guy I gave it to pass it to his
neighbor and his neighbor was a friend
of mine now but at the time she was like
super duper private person and you
couldn't you know like she didn't come
over and hang out when the one you know
anybody besides her neighbor was there
um so he passed it to her and you know
we we thought we had it for a little
while after we lost it probably in early
2000s we thought we had to hunted down
when me and her became friends and then
we lost it because she had passed
someone back into Sonoma County and then
she set up a meeting between me and him
and he had lost it too so and that was
the end of it but it was 1998 and that
was the end of it you know and it was a
bummer you know so so let me say we were
just let me say something real fast
yeah so you know you reminded me of this
story
earlier today
and it kind of like brought light to
something that you know maybe it's going
to be upsetting to some people including
not so dog okay and I'm gonna talk to
him about it but so you know he asked me
when I did the podcast
he said well you know was it the Scentsy
skunk or the the ace Gunk and I was like
well I don't remember you know like I I
hadn't been thinking about it I don't
remember right but so now
when Jason's reminding me of this what
I'm realizing is that what I must have
given Francis
and breadwisk I know that we've read
with it was the census seeds not the VA
scum
you know Francis never had the VA skunk
because I had lost it
prior to ever meeting him what I want to
say is this doesn't make Francis a liar
no you know like you like you know a
bunch of trolls on the internet are
gonna you know be like oh Francis was
lying about this vote no it doesn't make
Francis a liar
he's just
you know mistaken about something that
happened so many [ __ ] years ago and
like
you know
I called her shut up he knew yeah he
knew that we had the connection and you
know I'm gonna go and talk to those guys
and maybe do another podcast with them
where me and Francis talk about it
you know he has no incentive to make
[ __ ] up
it doesn't it doesn't benefit him in any
way to say that it was a VA skunk and
not the Scentsy seeds Gunk and
you know so so many people get so worked
up about this [ __ ] and I'm just laughing
I'm like why like why does you know
maybe I could understand Francis caring
and you're caring and I'm caring but
like all these people getting so worked
up and calling people liars and fakes
and that they don't really know Staten
Island and it's just like it's crazy
it's crazy nonsense spirit
well you know it is crazy welcome to
crazy but you know the truth is your
perspective and so your perspective is
you know larger and or different you
know and so that's what it is I mean
yeah I mean of course you know like
nobody here is trying to and that's what
these conversations are that's what
these conversations do
that's what this conversations do right
they change their perspective a little
bit I mean like
maybe me you and Francis you know
talking together on a podcast you know
that's the best I have no connection
with him at all
I just want the super skulls back I
don't actually care yeah but we got that
we got we gotta we have to we have to
give up on that one and just make sure
that we never lose the chem dog right
because like oh that's what's lost is
lost
yeah you know
I don't think anyone now
I've seen some stuff that looks similar
you know so maybe it has enough of the
traits in it and you know with some of
your uh quality selection maybe we can
find stuff that reminds us of it more
but also you know yeah that's the best
we can do folks you're right and like I
said there's no disagreement it's just
perspective you know of course like it's
nice to be able to talk about it and
hear like like like make it make sense I
guess you know from my perspective
because I you know like these things are
just plants I mean well they are just
plants but they're not just like they're
not possessions they're friends they're
allies they're like they're like my dog
my cat my kid it's family that's what
they're family it's family to me so to
find out a member of my family's out
there somewhere and I've been missing
that member all these years I mean it's
going to affect you if you have that
kind of love I do or you do and so you
know but as you work through it you
understand it like okay there's
obviously some more stuff here that's
not you know
make you know it's going to make sense
to me at some point and now it does you
know and that's good you know not that
it's important that it makes sense to me
but it is to me you know because like
that's how I go to bed at night because
you know I remember what happened and
like it's a shame would happen it's
terrible and
um it's also a learning time a learning
like a lesson point in my life because
that's why that's why we don't lose
anything else
that's right that's why we don't lose
anything else because of what happened
there
and that's how I took it you know and I
and you took it that way too you know
like
you know it was a rough time
the VA skunk is to us
what like the previous generation to us
they used to say oh I remember back in
the day there was the Colombian gold in
the Panama Red you know like now
yeah
this is the Panama Red of our lifetime
That Got Away exactly yeah like years
later years later people like Shiloh go
that was the best food I ever had in my
life
yeah you know I mean there's a lot of
great weed around but if that one still
rolls around your head I mean that tells
you everything you need to know and the
more years that go by the more it says
you know because it was that good it was
just that good people just don't
understand like when people like oh it's
so stunky and I just I want to believe
it but I also roll my eyes because I'm
like you just
yeah you know it's like now they have
roadkill skunk skunk spray they have all
these different ways of describing
skunks back then it was simple skunk
because that's what it smelled like it
smelled like a [ __ ] skunk
yeah that's amazing you know however it
happened it was amazing and I I for what
I'm grateful to have been able to enjoy
it and kind of remember it and
but at the same time everything that I
come across in my life including
anything I make or anything that I enjoy
you know
immensely these days it always is going
to get compared to that you know because
it's hard not to it's so unique you know
so
you know the guy who made this number
six I just talked to him you know
yesterday and the day before and he
heard your podcast and uh you know he
was he reached out to me it's like you
know those guys they got some cool
stories but they don't have any of the
back story you know and I'm like I know
you know and I and I told him Gabby I
said I said hey I'm one more closer to
my uh to one of my fantasies I don't
know if I use the word fantasy but it is
kind of and he said what's that I said I
want you me and Gabby to sit down smoke
a joint and talk about [ __ ] let's talk
about weed he's like we can make that
happen at least
and I told you that earlier
yeah he's an unknown Legend as they say
you know and uh you know that might
change pretty soon here I'm working on
it but
he's a good guy it means a lot to me
just like you do Gavin you know his his
work needs to be you know it should be
you know kind of recognized you know
because he wasn't doing it for the
[ __ ] Fame of the money either believe
that you know in the late 80s so he was
just like Gabby and I just trying to
have the best [ __ ] weed in his pocket
you know that's the game there's no more
to it than that right take a quick
moment to sort of ask a quick question
which is oh there's someone else here
there's someone else here besides Jason
tonight
there is um who is it do you I thought
we Jason and I were having a private
conversation
do you feel at all Vindicated that
essentially the goal of what you were
going for with the super dog is
essentially the genetic combination that
led to Sour Diesel as far as we can tell
so we'll have the sour diesel
conversation in a second but what I was
going for was something that had the
structure and the Vigor of the skunk
with the terpene profile of the chem dog
and you know when uh not so dog talked
about it in his podcast he was like well
we were looking for was the high because
the chem dog was the most potent weed of
its day
and what I disputed that I said what I
wanted was [ __ ] that tasted like the
chem dog you know I've always been like
you know the potency is nice but if the
weed's that good I want to hit it twice
anyway
you know so I'd rather I'd rather smoke
more of something that tastes like the
chem dogs than be concerned about
whether it was 15 20 or 30 THC and I
still feel the same today
as far as the skunk uh excuse me the
sour diesel
what I believe the sour diesel was
an accidental cross
that clock made
you know I don't believe that it was a
breeding project
or weasel I you know and you know we can
talk to him about it but I didn't make
it you know and it was out there East
with
um JJ and AJ and
um weasel
and you know that's you know kind of why
I assume it is what it is
but
yeah it's just my best guess
that's what I think it is but we'll have
to get weasel and Jade AJ on the podcast
and
you know we'll see what they have to say
because they they really were more there
at the beginning than I was look at that
I I would say you know the way you know
individuals speculate about what a
strain is nowadays when they have no way
to like you know there's no evidence of
it you know it's just speculation so
like if you look at the super skunk and
you taste the chem dog and you taste
Superstar and then you just try the sour
diesel it's it's hard I would you know
of all the speculation there's only one
that I would agree with and that is that
that is probably true the super skunk
and the chem dog since those guys were
growing it too both of them and we both
know the chem dog harms every time and
the super skunk certainly few bananas
too early if you even had the slightest
uh lightly it's been well documented
many people talked about it
um you know it's pretty it doesn't take
like a large jump of your imagination
say yeah that probably is what it is you
know it came from that area at the same
time
but you know who wants to get involved
with that conversation argument or
whatever not me because I wasn't there
and like a lot of people do a lot of
people left a lot of people are spending
their life having that conversation and
arguing about it and I just think that
it's going to be speculation to the end
of time you know and that's you know
that's right yeah you know people go
which headband cut did you use what's
your you know master cut Kush cut using
it's like I would love to answer you
that but when someone hands you a cut
and says this is the Master Kush I'm
supposed to add on another you know
adjective or pronoun for you for the for
somebody out there on the internet like
I I can't do that like what it's told to
me is what it is I understand there's
more of one cut ahead then I understand
there's more than one cut of Master Kush
but when someone hands that to you you
know you know obviously you're basing
your experience with this cup in the
past which I do I'm not going to rename
it you know just to suit somebody on the
internet and how they feel about it and
I can't do that and what difference does
it make you know Mike I don't mean to be
an [ __ ] but sometimes I ask the
question back so how many sour diesels
have you smoked and they're like well
i've smoked this one I'm like so what
difference does it make to you you only
smoked one you know what I mean so keep
it as true as it was when it's handed to
you you know like leave the speculation
out you know because that's all it is or
if your game is speculation be really
clear that that's what you do you
speculate you know I think that I think
that's a legitimate thing to do is to
speculate as long as that's the way
we're putting it and not putting too
much you know into it you know and there
certainly shouldn't be like heavy drama
and arguments over it because we should
just be saying yeah I really don't know
this is my best guess
and I'd love to ask did either of you
guys ever really get into or try any of
the other clones to come out of G's
Library like the uh the diesel or the
snow dog I think some of that work was
done by Bundy but did you guys ever try
interested in it at all
I've grown the diesel out yeah
what was your thoughts on it because
it's meant to be the same genetic combo
as Sour Diesel right it's meant to be
like chemd skunk
it is and but I can't imagine anyone
would put on that same level of course
not many people have tried the number
six but
um it just didn't do it for me
um it was Standalone but it's it goes
back to perspective like when your
perspective is oh this says Super Skunk
in it well your your expectations in
some areas have risen without you even
wanting it to your bias has risen
without your any you know effort on your
part and therefore it becomes
disappointing you know unfortunately you
know just like the mass superstroke
which I've told you about before you
know I got that sent to me and you know
I grew it out when you gave it to me in
2006 and I was expecting the number six
because that's what I told it was that's
what he said would be and I mean and I
believe he thought that that's what it
was but it wasn't and you know
who knows maybe in some Gardens it would
have been a winner but in my garden it
was just like a point of disappointment
like a massive disappointment you know
it's like so couldn't do it
that makes sense
yeah interesting how about you Gabby did
you ever try either of those
I didn't but what I did try were the
other cams like the chem sister
and the cam d
and I never thought any of that stuff
actually matched up and as a matter of
fact like
I told the story you know with Francis
that
I don't really believe that and I'm
saying this with all due respect to Greg
who produced some of the most important
genetics of a Lifetime right
um when he says that like five years
later he popped more seeds from the same
batch and then five years later he Pat
you know I question that because like he
only had like 10 or 12 seeds initially
and if you had 12 seeds of the most epic
[ __ ] ever
and you just pulled the chem dog out of
it
and you lost the chem dog which he did
would you wait five years and then five
years more to plant those seeds like
that doesn't seem like a logical story
you know and the one thing that Kim does
said many times is that he called the
chem dog whatever he was growing at the
time
you know so
I really don't think that those are
actually
close cam crosses they might have the
chem dog in it somewhere kind of like
the not so dog or the Superdog
but
um
yeah I don't believe that's what
we were all looking for at the time
I mean I would say I I can't distribute
that I just I can't you know like Kim D
doesn't look anything like chem dog and
like of course there's variation in F1
that's the most controversial [ __ ] that
I say that's the most controversial [ __ ]
that I say well you know I mean I try
not to get it it's not really conscious
you just said it's your opinion it's not
controversial and you know you you you
were a standalone too and you get to
have your own opinion you've had a lot
of experience with this stuff you know
just like myself and and you know I I
would agree with you you know like you
know I've told the story a dozen times
where you know like I saw the Kim's
sister the one that I wanted in a
magazine picture you know in 2006 that's
the one I wanted
to kill sister I hold currently is not
the same plan however it was handed to
me as the Kim says so I still call it
the Kim says now everybody wants to call
it the Bundy cut I'm okay with that you
know I kind of know this backstory a
little bit on that but I still just call
it the chemist you know
um but the kimdi and especially the Kim
one two and three and four they don't I
don't know you know they're definitely
like well definitely in my opinion I
would say they're probably related but
not directly related as in the same
project right it becomes that's what I
think
yeah but yeah
we'll never know for sure you know
interesting and just probably not to to
get a bit of a baseline I wanted to ask
you both how did when when OG Kush first
came out you know in sort of the early
2000s how did that change your
perspective did you still think that
like the chem dog was the best [ __ ] or
did you think like oh this OG really
stands up to it like how did that change
things
I definitely felt like OG stood up to it
because it's in the same you know like
range of profile I guess might be a way
to put it that I am attracted to you
know as the chem dog like that deep
earthy a lot of painting you know a lot
of like certain similar serps you know
similar effects you know I was
pleasantly surprised to find out that
you know Kim dog wasn't the only good
weed around
you know I was happy to hear that you
know so
that's my take on so the way my take on
it is pretty similar is I wish I had
made that [ __ ] because that's what I was
trying to do
I was trying to make [ __ ] that was
similar to the chem dog but more robust
plants and and those plants were it
you know and
you know I remember
look I don't think I was stingy but I
did keep the chem dog close to the vest
right and when it got when it got out
I was a little bummed at first
right and now when I think about it I'm
grateful for that
because because it got out
a lot of great [ __ ] was made
you know not just from you know Jason
and
um the others that have read with the
chem dog you know
um you know lots of people got it
however they got it and made some of the
strains that I think are my favorite
[ __ ]
you know
till today you know so I
like I said at the time I was a little
upset when the [ __ ] got you know
completely out there now
you know now I don't even have the chem
dogs you know I know I can get it back
from Jason and and others but
um I'm grateful it got out
you know so
yeah
effective on that
when I got to Kim dog from Gabby he told
me never give this to anyone ever you
know and so I did give it to three
people
a couple of them more than once you know
one of them a lot more than once and uh
you know I'm grateful for that you know
um and I didn't I the third person I
gave it to I barely knew and he's
probably the number one reason why it's
everywhere now
um you know breeding or just clones
available you know so and it's still
hard who's that first but his name's
Shea bud and he runs a company called
seed bank and I was a little high on
acid one night and he came by the
apartment to buy some weed and we
started talking about breeding and I was
like man this [ __ ] there's a lot
about breeding and so I was like I have
this notion just to give him the cut you
know it's like I want to say 2006 come
in 2005 and I never really saw the guy
again I think we talked on the phone
um but anyway so that's and then it went
from there to Humboldt County which they
spread it amongst their their circles
far and wide and then eventually it went
to Colorado
um and then a guy there gave it to
peabutt and then he was responsible for
for spreading it around p-bud gab I
don't know if you know who he is again
is the guy that sold the weed to Greg
yeah he's one of the guys yeah so he he
was uh coming back into cannabis at the
time I guess you could say and
um you know the connection had been made
and so you know that's how that got
around but honestly at the time I was
like I was on probation I was looking at
like serious [ __ ] you know uh you
know law enforcement issues that I had
had from the bus that I just had when
all this started happening in 2014
15-ish 15 16 ish and but now I look back
and I'm like I'm really you know the
plant does what it's going to do you try
not to get in the way you know and
that's that's where we're at you know so
she's an amazing plant and in light of
all that and then looking back and
seeing like what's available today what
people are in love with today I'm really
glad it happened because it'd be shitty
if it wasn't part of that conversation
or equation you know what what cannabis
is today right now you know so I'm glad
it's there I agree with you 100
that's brilliant so we've chatted a lot
about some of the things in the past but
I'd love to chat a bit about the future
you know at the start of the episode you
guys revealed there's an exciting collab
in the works where can people find the
clones and and what can they expect
going forward
well me and Gabby been talking and um
you know it was 30 years ago when we
when we kind of had that fateful day and
met and you know it's like where he's at
right now where I'm at right now it just
made a lot of sense and you know we
decided after talking and back and forth
and going back and forth I mean me and
GAP talk it's usually just laughing
about stories and stuff like that but
every now and again these things come up
and you know gab's got a good uh
extensive lab library and like I
mentioned my partner you know she has a
way to sell clones through her website
um we here at Lucky Dog cannabis and
Lucky Dog Chico are going to start
selling our own clones you know we're
gonna start uh selecting other breeders
stuff
um and so we started talking about all
this and I don't really think it was
anyone had to push it was just kind of
one of them ideas was just sitting there
for the taken and we decided to just
team up and we're gonna do some breeding
collaborations we're gonna do this
cologne collaboration
um and kind of just work together and
share all of our [ __ ] amazing
genetics with anyone who's interested in
this stuff you know so
um I'm [ __ ] beside myself excited
this is like a dream come true for me
um I just you know Gabby means the world
to me he's had a huge impact on my life
and how my life has turned out and I
just turned 50 years old and I'm you
know I'm able to I just you know we just
had dinner together a month ago I had to
pass through town unfortunately for a
memorial but I was able to hang hang
with my friend Gabby and eat a meal for
the first time and God knows how long
and it's just like this is what's so
precious about life this is what the
good stuff is you know and dinner's
amazing and hanging out in conversation
but be able to work and kind of
collaborate with you know only you know
Gabby's one of my mentors you know like
he's someone who means so much to me
like you know we're only a few years
apart but you know when you're 17 20 19
20 21 like those three or four years
that's that's all there is and you know
the guy's giving me so much knowledge of
course he shared the genetics with me I
always will have the respect that he was
brave enough to drive that [ __ ] across
country I know people who you know they
pat themselves on the back all day they
don't have the balls to do that you know
so I have respect for that and I love my
friend Gabby I respect my friend Gavin
to be able to work with him in any
capacity is like a dream for me you know
it's like full circle I guess they call
it you know and so you know you can go
to you know as of tonight you can go
tonight is not when you hear the steeple
but tonight is as in Friday May 12th
you're gonna be able to go to breeders
direct seed
co.com and Gabby's Library will be
available there
um and we're going to be collaborating
on all this stuff and
um you know so we have like we don't
know what to call it yet we don't know
if we should name it but uh you know
it's a collaboration between two old
friends who give a [ __ ] about weed and I
think the whole world who gives a [ __ ]
about weed is gonna [ __ ] love it I
really do so that's my take on it
well I I appreciate what you said Jason
I'll add to that by saying so um
these other guys from this other podcast
they reached out to me saying that
people wanted to clear what I had to say
and I was kind of like why
you know I was confused because
I've you know
like I felt like I haven't really done
anything with the chem dog or with the
skunk
in a really long time
you know that's that's what Jason's been
doing and and I've been doing other
stuff I honestly I I do you know Jason
is gonna get me the chem dog back and
we're gonna do some breeding together
with it but you know for a while I kind
of just
wasn't doing that I had other projects
going on
and when people when you know it was
mentioned to me that people really want
to hear what I have to say and I'm this
like known person on the internet as
Staten Island
you know I
I you know said to myself you know maybe
people actually do care about what I've
done it like it was like surprising you
know like because I haven't been in the
public eye the way others have you know
I've just been trying to get my work
done
you know and but you know it's also was
presented like I'm a super shy person
and I don't want to like like people you
know were scared to ask me including
Jason for some reason didn't want to ask
me if I wanted to do a podcast like this
I was like bro I'm I'm not that private
particularly about like [ __ ] that we did
you know 20 years ago I'm not really
worried about like that coming back to
me right now you know
so
that discussion led into like hey you
know maybe people would be interested in
a collaboration between
you know skunk VA and Staten Island you
know and so
that's you know
that's what we're doing and like I said
we have been working together for 30
years
you know doing breeding and other
projects and yeah you know took a little
time off
but now our
our friendship is rejuvenated
and you know like like I said
Jason was the first person I ever went
into business with
you know he's the first person I ever
worked with that way you know so it
seems like a perfect thing for us 30
years later
to get back into it and do another
project together
and
honestly when Jason mentioned to me that
he wanted to do this
I was honored
because I consider him the big dog
you know I consider he's the one that's
doing all this great work with the chem
dog for years now so the fact that he
wanted to collaborate with me is
it was an honor for me as well
same here
it's amazing are you feeling are you
feeling the love partner
me oh [ __ ] yeah man I've been feeling a
little I'm so happy yeah this is I mean
I've lost so many [ __ ] people that I
won't be able to reconnect with in this
life to be able to reconnect with you
and to be able to have what we have at
this very [ __ ] moment it's it you
can't put a price on it you can't you
can't put anything on it it's everything
to me this is life this is what it's all
about you know I've I've lost all the
different people that are listening are
saying right now people that are
listening are saying you guys need to
get a room
well you know I don't need a room maybe
they need to get it yeah that's that's
what I would be thinking if I'm hearing
this conversation about anyone else yeah
I know I don't care that's the way
that's the way I feel you know I'm Latin
I'm not going to express express love
with my fellow man you know yeah me
neither dude me neither hey like that's
what I'm saying we're lucky to have it
it's so precious like I mean people say
it and they talk about it but they
almost sound cliche it really is any
second she laughs you know and to have
people you love and the ones that you
mean the most to you in your life on a
you know any kind of like like present
basis you know daily or whatever basis
it's a gift you know and that's how I
feel and you know when we talk about me
and you for 30 years and friendship
that's what brings it reminds me it's
like all the [ __ ] that I've been through
in my life and all the [ __ ] [ __ ]
you've been through the good and the
[ __ ] bad yeah you know that's why we
can be who we are right in this moment
and we've talked about this you know
like you know life will come and kick
you in the nuts you know and remind you
that you know who you really are and I
know it's done for myself and I know
it's done for you because we've talked
about it and like this is the gravy part
to me this is it there's a lot of hard
work ain't scared of hard work neither
you this is the gravy you know this is
the this is the time where we get to
enjoy it you know and like really be
able to put it all in a frame and see it
and just be like [ __ ] yeah you know and
that's what this collaboration is going
to be you know it's gonna be that and
it's going to be a way to celebrate all
this crazy [ __ ] you know yeah I'm corny
I know it I'm [ __ ] corny but that's
who I am I'm Corey I'm a big ass corny
[ __ ]
that's why Jason and I get along so well
I'm not either
now what what a beautiful sentiment it's
all full circle it's all love I really
like that and I was gonna just quickly
mention you know shout out to the the
breed of Syndicate podcast for getting
you on I know both Jason and I have
listened to the episode and enjoyed it a
lot and uh just certainly not trying to
avoid saying the name so I wanted to
give kudos to not so and Matt for for
helping make that happen otherwise we
probably wouldn't be chatting right now
and I wanted to quickly follow up you
know people have heard they can get
Gabby's clone library in the near future
the question is on the breed of
Syndicate you mentioned you were smoking
on the orangutan titties I think we all
collectively got a laugh when we heard
that one what other clones are you uh
vibing on at the moment Gabby what are
some of the things from your collection
that you'd be excited for people to try
so the three strains that I'm most
excited about currently are the
orangutan titties which is Grease Monkey
Time Skittles it's extremely Skittles
dominant and Skittles is making a big
comeback out here in California at least
it's really beautiful weed it actually
won the emerald Cup last year for the
personal use category
and the personal use category for those
that don't know it's the most
um
the most respected category because it
includes everything so the emerald cup
they break everything down by
um chirp profile whether it's indoor
Greenhouse outdoor they break it down to
a whole bunch of categories and that's
where all the licensed stuff
and then they have the personal use
category which is just like anything
goes anyone can enter and the license
facilities enter as well and my buddy
Parker Mozelle
um Fino hunted it
and entered it into the emerald cup and
was the winner with that strain it's
extremely rare and it's it's super nice
so that's one of them that I'm really
excited about the other ones are the
slaps which is Grease Monkey times runs
um I just
I just received some flour from
a cultivator that's just finishing it
and it's just it's unbelievable it's
really beautiful weed
and then it's it the it's it is rainbow
chip times gelato
and out here in California everybody's
asking for candy gas
and what I think the
um if it is is gas candy
because it leaves with the gas but
there's a little bit of candy there and
it has color
so
you know those are the strains that I
I'm currently most excited about
um being able to release to the public I
do want to add since you uh you thanked
Matt and the breed of Syndicate I wanted
to do the same thing
um I did want to mention them and I'm
you know I'm glad it's not an issue
because if it wasn't for them we would
not be having this conversation because
you know that's what convinced Jason
that I'm not a Herman you know scared to
like talk to people
and you know if I hadn't done that
podcast you know because Jason was like
yeah you know like we should we should
do something I was like yeah we should
do something like this why the [ __ ] not
he was literally there when it began and
one of my closest and uh
you know I I've known him longer than
I've known anyone in California
you know so when I moved to California
I was scared to talk to people like who
lived near me
about my growth
you know so that's why you know I lived
in Sonoma County I would drive down to
Golden Gate Park to try to find people
because I was scared that you know local
people would know that I grew
so you know meeting Jason when I first
moved to California pretty much you know
maybe a year or two later
it was a
it was a critical part of my life
that I I want to keep fresh in my brain
you know that's why I like Jason to tell
these stories to remind me
you know of everything yeah same here
dude definitely obviously huge Junction
in my life you know meeting you in that
Park that day and for that plant too
don't forget about her and the other
ones we've been involved with too you
know
so it's it's worth noting for sure even
though we didn't care about it too much
until really but
straight up it's worth noting
I appreciate you uh
helping us with this podcast too
oh look the pleasure's all mine it's not
what we do yeah one more little one more
little stupid story so like yeah before
you before you do let me just say one
thing I hope this is just part one
okay I hope I hope we can do this a
bunch more
because uh
you know there's a lot more for us to
tell yeah I mean Gabby you and I talk
about it like
you know people may or may we think may
find it entertaining just to hear our
[ __ ] conversations we have outside of
a situation like this you know an arena
like this where we just talk about life
weed stories and everything else
involved you know like yeah this is
definitely not the end of that you know
and that you know that's what I was
going to say it's like I I told uh and
his audience just December
um yeah he asked me do you think we'll
ever get a chance to talk to Staten
Island and you know I only call you
Staten Island because that's what they
call you on the internet just so you
know and so you know I'm not gonna name
drop you if uh if everyone else is going
to Staten Island
um and then uh and then was I told him I
said hey no he's very private and then
the other day I told you that story and
you made the [ __ ] you made the
funniest point you said my name is Gabby
I'm from New York I'm not private
there's nothing private about me which
you know and so you know I don't know
where I got that idea from but yeah yeah
that's what you said to me than what I
thought
that's brilliant yeah I mean it's funny
I used to have a commercial
on the radio in Mendocino County
and you know for my grow shop
and it used to go hey what's up this is
Gabby from the garden spell mendocino's
Premier indoor garden shop and so and so
on and like
I put myself out there so hard I feel
like I'm the least private person in the
world like I don't I don't know many
people that put them at least that early
you know and to be to hear that like I'm
this private guy I was like man news to
me you know like I you know and I was
really so
just blown away that
people wanted to hear what I had to say
yeah people wanted to hear what I had to
say I I um
I couldn't believe it you know like when
when Matt from The Syndicate called me
up and said you know people really want
to hear what you have to say I was like
what I why does anyone want to do what I
have to say you know I just and so it's
a good feeling you know people have said
a lot of nice things about me there's
been very little shade thrown in my
direction
um actually zero shade thrown in my
direction and you know you know the most
respected Growers out there like Jason
are saying that I grew the best weed he
ever saw in his life at the time you
know like
it's all super nice [ __ ] you know and
I'm grateful
that's beautiful look and I I think on
when you say you know you're surprised
people are interested to hear from you I
think honestly it just speaks to one of
the points Jason made on one of the
early episodes I did with him which is
that you know fact is more interesting
Than Fiction most of the time you know a
lot of people have these weird stories
about chem dog on the internet and I
think the real one is actually by far
the most interesting
he had said to me he said well people
find so endearing about you was that you
didn't Flex
and I said to him
I don't know what I have to flex about
like like you know and actually I
corrected him I was like you know there
are things that I will Flex about
I'm really proud of how many people I
taught to grow and inspired to grow and
you know help take their grows to the
next level and you know I had the first
indoor garden shop in Mendocino County
and I put grow lights on on Highway 101
so when you were driving you know from
Mendocino County North
you saw
you saw my grow lights in the window you
know and
you know so like I'm proud of that and
that and that's
that's my Flex you know like
what I did for the Ken dog like
maybe I didn't see enough value in it
maybe I needed other people to like
tell me how important it was for them to
for me to put more value but I I always
felt like if I did a big Flex about the
chem dog
but I'd look like an [ __ ] because
really all I was was the delivery driver
and somebody that grew it you know like
Greg was the one that you know grew the
seed and you know VA Jason here he's the
one that made all these subsequent
crosses afterwards
and so what's my legacy I'm I'm the bus
driver I'm I'm the the delivery driver
like
I just didn't see what my Flex was you
know and I appreciate
being told that it was more important
than I I give my you know give myself
credit for I'm still not gonna Flex
you know I'm still not gonna be like
yeah that's right this is me not yet you
know when I will after me and Jason put
out some legendary [ __ ] that changes
things and changes the way people think
about cannabis
then you know maybe I'll Flex
but I'm not there yet
you know gab the thing is about flexing
and I don't really understand exactly
what that means but I'll tell you what I
think is that just coming out here and
like talking to people and saying your
stories showing your point of view
that's all the flux is needed I mean
it's it's it's to us it's just our life
and goodness but to people who you know
you know who are paying attention I
guess and care it's [ __ ] amazing it's
a cool story it's legendary [ __ ]
people [ __ ] appreciate you sharing it
you know let's get enough well I
definitely I definitely appreciate the
opportunity
um it has made me blush you know has
given me an opportunity to tell some
good friends that I really care about
them having the opportunity to tell
these stories and more listen to these
stories with my friends like Jason and
not so dog
it's brought me so much pleasure the
last couple of weeks and then like all
these people messaging me saying how
much they enjoyed the stories and how
much they appreciate me and literally so
far I've gotten zero shade zero hate
it's made me feel really good and I'm
I'm super grateful for you guys and for
Math and for not so dog for giving me
this opportunity to feel
to feel good
I hope to return the favor
of course of course well before we wrap
things up I want to ask you guys a few
quick fire questions as we normally do
before we end the episodes so first
one's for you Gabby what's the most
memorable terpen profile in your mind
there's two of them
the first one is the chem dog
and then the second one is the
the holy weed the big star holy weed I
can still smell that weed and and taste
it in the back of my throat and I
haven't had it since the 90s
wow beautiful what sort of smells does
it have or is it hard to describe
I mean the skunk was truly skunky and
the haze is like what the original type
of haze
when I think of haze I always think of
that big sir holy weed so it's
everything else that I would be
comparing it to that
because that was my first experience of
haze weed yeah beautiful beautiful and
Jason yourself most memorable top end
profiles
I I mean you know Superstar for sure I
can't forget it it's the same thing I
can feel it in my nasals I could feel it
in my you know that coating it does in
your sinus I still feel that earthy
sharp skunk
um
I would like to go back a little long
further to the Beatrix choice that deep
uh great bubble gum flavor but it's
starting to fade now to be honest with
you
I had it for a long time so the super
skunk is still in my mind you know the
way it would break up into that cotton
it's really soft much like the sour
diesel when you twist it up it's like
it's not like hard it's kind of smooshy
you're fatty you know it's earned
perfectly it's like that cotton
so for me it's that
I think if I had to add a third one it
would be the Super Skunk
but you know but I mean I I was already
stretching it when I when I did too
you know I felt like yeah for one and I
I gave you two
um that's a tough question you know yeah
the Big Sir holy weed
um yeah that was just I remember like I
had gotten a batch of it sent to New
York City when I was living in New York
and growing it and it was this was
outdoor weed full-term outdoor weed not
Greenhouse grown
and to this day I think like man that
weed stood up to anything today
you know and so that's an herb I'd like
to to connect with again
beautiful beautiful stuff well for the
last question before we wrap up if you
could only have one strain to smoke for
the rest of your life we'll go to skunk
VA first this time and Gabby second one
strain for the rest of your life what
would it be
can I answer first
yes
yes didn't
didn't you just ask that question
it's the same answer
yeah yeah it's the same [ __ ] question
Honestly though I think the Kim dog
because the effects of the chem dog just
shoots me much better but it's tough I
mean it is the same question Gabby's
right but I would say that Kim dog
because it works all day long every day
all night long all night it's just
perfect for me you know I don't even
like getting high
for me I just smoked a lot of weed so I
don't get high
you know for me it's strictly about the
term profile of the chem dog
that's just the [ __ ]
yeah my buddy and I you always like like
that Panama Red
yeah my buddy and I he lives in
Barcelona we always joke around we say
whoever comes up with the [ __ ] The
Strain with [ __ ] seven percent Terps
it has that drippy gas flavor it doesn't
get you high that's the person who wins
the game right there
and I agree with that I agree because
you know you can only smoke as much as
you [ __ ] head can take you know but
just your mouth your that that flavor
that mouth coat that um in the back your
throat on the back your teeth you just
you want more and more and more of it
you know what I mean so when you're when
we were young and daddy gave me the
Kindle he's like two rules first off
you're not gonna like don't get the same
one but you're not gonna really want to
grow this one it doesn't root well it's
hard to grow
secondly don't smoke it in a bubber
before 11 A.M right which was funny at
the time because all we did was Smoke
fatties all [ __ ] day well that was
then I could smoke chem dog fatties all
day when I'm like 20. nowadays I'm like
I start to like drool and stare at the
wall but I still want to take another
hit it tastes so [ __ ] good so
you know I'm not gonna like tout less
THC and more flavor but kind of yeah I
am that'd be amazing you know what I
mean
you how about you answer the same
question for
familiar
look at you to get you more involved in
this podcast you've barely been involved
uh I was enjoying being a fly on the
wall did you fall did you take a nap
for periods for periods um look I think
that I uh I would struggle to match you
two guys I think if I picked the chem
dog I would that would be like a
non-functional for the rest of my life I
I would need something a bit more sativ
or I'm a bit of a sativa guy maybe like
uh a nice Super Silver Haze hybrid or
like maybe that's what we got to do the
the Chaska Super Silver Haze cross chem
dog yeah
I love that one yeah you're gonna love
it it's good have you ever done that one
no but I've smoked it at your house and
it was brilliant yeah it's really good
it's perfect it doesn't make your
forehead sweat but it's almost
The Best of Both Worlds
that's it I love it I love it well with
that being said does either of you have
any general comments or shout outs
before we wrap it up
well I think you already did it the the
little shout out to the Breeders
Syndicate because they were uh they were
really responsible for us thinking about
doing this yeah so thanks to them and um
you know I'll thank both of you guys
again I'll thank the people that are
interested in hearing stories from
Staten Island
whoever gave me that name [ __ ] you very
much but I guess I'm Gonna Keep it now
because [ __ ] nobody knows who Gabby is
Staten Island is this famous character
nobody knows who Gabby is
so my new ads would be like hey what's
up this is Gabby oh excuse me this is
Staten Island
coming to you from Lucky Dog Seed Co
CK that's funny so yeah but really thank
you guys very much I appreciate you both
and I hope we get to talk much more
of course wow I think that just about
brings us to the end of it as always a
massive thank you to not just the one
but the two chem dog Kings the
incredible skunk VA and Staten Island
Jason and Gabby thanks so much for
coming on the show today
[Music]
there you have it my friends a massive
thank you to Gabby Gardens about AKA
Staten Island
and a massive thank you to skunk VA for
joining us on this episode
as always a massive shout out to our
incredible sponsors who helped make the
episode happen cope it you know him you
love him number one in the world for
pests and Predator technology they've
just recently launched the incredible
spydex vital plus it helps you to avoid
having put carrier material over your
crop if you've got a Spider-Man
infestation check it out guys slowly
releasing the Predator might
phytocellus per semilius into your
garden to ensure ongoing release of
beneficial predators to get spider mites
out of your garden for good huge shout
out
likewise huge shout out to our friends
at Organics alive you know them you love
them they've got the best organic
powdered fertilizers in the game if
you're looking to take out some cups you
need to get on board because guess what
people have been taking out cups left
and right with their products they got
everything you need from Veg to flour to
transition cow mag anything under the
sun organic they're going to be able to
give you a solution shout out to our
amazing friends at Organics alive we
appreciate your support and the amazing
products you're giving to the community
yourself
if you are sick of smoking joints or
bongs and want something a little more
healthy check out our good buddies at
dine about these guys have the most
Sledgehammer Vape you have ever tried if
you feel like you've tried vaping before
and just didn't scratch that spot give
the dynavap M series a go it's cheap
accessible non-battery dependents a very
versatile and it is the very unit that
helped me to quit smoking bongs
got a track record of customers loving
it and made by a bunch of passionate
people out of the Midwest of the USA
American-made American design what more
could you ask for incredible products
dynavat thank you so much for your
support
huge shout out to our bodies at seeds
here now you know it you love it if
you're looking to grab yourself some
heavy days genetics cruise on over the
seeds here now and grab some before
they're all gone I promise you they only
stocks the hottest breeders the latest
drops and their satisfaction guarantee
means that you can shoot him a message
at the end of your grow if you're not
stoked and they will get you right check
them out guys seat here now number one
in the industry we love them our longest
sponsor thank you so much James Dean
we're so appreciative
and then last but not least a massive
shout out to our buddies at Pulse
sensors I'm sure you've already got a
pulse in your garden guys but guess what
the pulse Hub is now out a central unit
to integrate all of the parameters in
your garden to ensure you're producing
the highest quality crop to date
whether you're running a single tent a
single room or a multi-state operation
it's time to get serious get a pulse
thank you to you for getting this far
and we'll see you for the next one
we'll see you
[Music]