[Music]
hello and welcome to the second episode
of the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts this episode was
brought to you by 420 Australia org be
sure to use the discount code the
podcast all one word to get a special
five percent off discount at the
checkout as well as lucky dog seeds who
can expect to see some amazing chem 91
crosses from in the near future
[Music]
in this episode we're joined by skank VA
who was kind enough to give us some
in-depth history on the scene as well as
a killer account of how he came to
acquire the ninety one cutting his
general plans for the future and some
general thoughts on the scene so without
further ado I'd like to welcome our next
guest on to the show skunk VA you know
thanks so much for taking the time to
talk to us today and so before we get
into it I'm just gonna basically remind
everyone that for this interview we're
gonna refer to the man chem dog as mass
G or just G and the strain has chem dog
or 91 or the VA coding just so we can
hopefully avoid some confusion because
that's something which comes up a lot
when talking about this type of stuff
and the other thing I was gonna say is
for this interview I think kind of the
most fitting way to start it would be to
actually kind of start at the middle and
then go back to the start just so that
people kind of have an understanding of
where you fit into the whole scene so so
far the story online seems to be what I
gather pretty inaccurate but this is how
it goes
essentially you met mass G online on
overgrown the to use chatted became
friends use ended up trading clones you
got the ninety one off him and he got
the skunk from you or the super skunk
some years later Kim got raided
he lost his clones eventually you guys
met back up and you gave him the ninety
one back and here we are a few years
later how accurate is that story in
general there's definitely pieces of
that that add up or that are true but
that's not really the timeline uh I
didn't meet G until 2006 I got the chem
dog in in 1995 a few days before Jerry
Garcia died nog
in July of 1995 rest in peace Jerry yes
absolutely
yeah it's a been a big way I'm going to
see going to Maclaurin Park tomorrow in
San Francisco it's Jerry Garcia day at
the amphitheater that's actually called
Gerry Dorsey amphitheater pretty excited
about it but it
yes rest in peace Gerry and thanks for
everything out there of course but um so
what happened was I'm just gonna start
from the beginning
how I came how I came into the chem dog
it was you know I'm from Virginia
originally and lots of us people lots of
us young folks from Virginia my age we
ended up on Grateful Dead tour because
that's what was going on in America at
the time you know like 1988 1989 1990
seems like every time they passed
through they would take a whole nother
wave of us with them you know and uh and
for some reason when you were on tour
there was a lot of people from Virginia
I can't really explain it to you but
for some reason and I found myself
following the Grateful Dead around and
and pretty much left Virginia to do that
and it was kind of a full-time thing for
me and what that means is and of course
there's not a show every night there's
not a you know a tour going on
constantly there's three or four tours a
year and then a bunch of other Jerry
Garcia Band a Grateful Dead shows that
you would I'm Jerry Garcia Band shows
you might catch and those were always
centered around San Francisco in the
early 90s and so you know in between
tours you would find yourself in the Bay
Area California um you know waiting
around for the next show basically and
and you know one of the ways that we
would kind of put food in our mouths and
you know when when you look at the
Grateful Dead show is really easy to
make money when he was in the air I mean
anybody who's you know 35 or 40 or older
knows what I'm talking about and but
between shows life could be kind of hard
and you know I found myself in San
Francisco hanging around the Panhandle
Park and back then of course marijuana
was very difficult to find at times
especially in the summertime before
harvest and there just wasn't the type
of endured volume going on you know as
we have today obviously and you know odd
prices could be anywhere
you know 400 to 450 dollars for Wade
outs and to get away doubts for that
price you're you're getting cooked up by
your friend you know so what we would do
is we would get ounces and we would
break him into what we caught hates
which were like two point eight grams
and get a couple little extra ones out
of there and then basically find
customers in the park who were honestly
80% of those people were ill you know
you could see sometimes it more than
often that there was something going on
with them and that's where they would
come and there was a shady transaction
every time because the you know selling
marijuana was a felony and was we were
just kids in the park it was we were
like you know fish in a barrel if you
know what I mean and basically that's
what was going on so I was down there
and when I was grown from Virginia we
smoked stuff like the Super Skunk it was
called the 86 Super Skunk later on which
was also later called the mask skunk the
mass Super Skunk I'll get to that a
little bit but so we the things that we
were growing were a lot of things out of
the super sativa seed bank catalog from
you know he put I don't know one that
started coming out forward but I've got
a few of them digitally archived I'm
really happy about that because they had
the numbers and what they were and that
was the fella who went all around the
world and you know bloodied up with
people in the Jewish mountains in
Afghanistan or Africa or you know even
the United States and somehow he had
this network of readers all over the
world and I think in Virginia that was
probably one of his seed producers
because you know we always seemed like
we always had like the cream of the crop
of what the stuff was coming out of this
out of this uh catalog and there was
some even for instance the Beatrix
choice which is was always my favorite
before I left my hometown and it was
very brittle it was like the Holy Grail
you know it was like oh my god you got a
bag of Beatrix choice and even in the
catalog I think in the 87 version he
actually mentioned central Virginia so
but anyway so yeah in between so ninety
like I think you were
it was it must have been January of 1993
I was in the park and I was kind of
always away from the crowd I was kind of
a I don't know kind of morph I was I
didn't like doing this kind of thing it
may be very uncomfortable but this is
kind of what we did you know to make it
get a hotel that night get a four space
that night get us some food in our belly
whatever you know just kind of make it
to the next day so we can you know be
around when the next show start and
basically I was sitting on the bench and
this guy comes walking down I'll never
forget this moment it was a big moment
of my life and I knew it at the time but
this guy comes walking down the sidewalk
and and he's got this grin on his face
he's got a ponytail and he comes back
and he's got me locked in his eyes and
comes walking through the Panhandle
walks right up to me I knew I was like
this guy either really really needs a
sack of weed or maybe maybe just maybe
he's got one and he did he offered me he
goes hey and he had a heavy heavy New
York accent and uh we started talking
and he didn't waste any time and he and
he I asked him I said hey uh you know
Dini any sack of weed or something and
he says actually bro I was gonna ask you
and this guy was like the quintessential
heaviest net New York accent it's kind
of funny and I was like wow and I just
knew so because he had that he had that
look I had growers all over the nation
you know I every where we went you would
look for those familiar faces the guy
you saw somewhere in that area last time
you know a little you know set of shows
four or five or six in Ohio area you see
this guy you know maybe even don't
remember his name but you know his face
and he's always got the kill and when
you were on tour that was really a big
part of your day was you had to make
some money you had to get a ticket for
the show and these are not necessarily
in this order because the ticket always
came first
and you had to find yourself some heads
- and it was the heads - was always the
most challenging part and if you were
like me and he didn't really have your
own ride you had to find a ride to the
next show you know he saw anyway so he
we started talking he goes listen man I
just moved out here from New York City
in Sonoma County and my electricity is
getting ready
turned off tomorrow I don't know anybody
I moved I hear being my girlfriend from
Staten Island and you know if you could
help me it would be I would really
appreciate it and I just like dude you
have no idea I think we're gonna help
each other both you know mutually a lot
right now so what do you got and so he
takes me back we walked back to his van
and he's got one of those he's got one
of those extended you know like when you
see an extended van like one of the big
old cargo vans and it had like the line
at the back of the van where you could
see where they extended it to get the
extra three or four feet yeah this line
this van actually had another line with
another set of two feet you know behind
it this thing was like 17 18 feet long
it was a biggest fan of ever seen and
we're parked you parked like on a pretty
sharp Hill in San Francisco and we get
in there and it's like I'm like well
first off you know man how much how much
you're gonna be you know how much would
you sell this to me for I'm like I
mentioned cannabis marijuana it was
going for $450 announced that day from
your buddy and you had to wait for him
to get up you had to wait for him to get
down to the street it was a magnet and
and also we had to divvy it out because
everybody need a little bit it wasn't
like you're the first person they got
seeing you wanted two ounces you know he
would just give you one ounce so that
made to make sure you had other routes
for you know somebody else not as other
friends who's gonna say you know there
was always a hassle and so this was
unbelievable I couldn't believe it you
know and this guy's charged pulling out
this amazing indoor I mean and in the
end or you know you would find it down
there in the city at those days but it
was extremely rare even in California in
the early 90s like this and it was
mostly outdoor beautiful outdoor I would
say even nicer up to where then we see
these days but but still indoor was very
rare and he had a string called Francine
he had a very small amount of Kim dog
they told me about and and and and I was
very impressed with it he didn't have
any for me to to buy or anything like
that but he had so we smoked a little
bit while we were chit-chatting and
talking about you know Grateful Dead and
no because all the things you talk about
when you meet someone you know people
Kendrick people me like this you know
yeah and he had
what else do you know yes oh he had this
other really fluffy one and by the way
fluffy was the way to go if you could
get the fluffy we'd like cuz it just
looks bigger when you're only ran 2.8
you know grams out you know and or I
walk it out so and and he was like I was
like alright so what what do you want
for this and I mean because I'm ready to
work I mean if he wants four hundred
fifty dollars an ounce then we're gonna
go up to the street and we're gonna find
everybody nude some we're gonna solve
for 450 bucks enough is I don't know do
you think 300 would be good and I was
like I almost kissed him you know and I
was like yes I think that would be great
I think that'd be perfect and but you
have to do me one favor you have to stay
right here don't leave like don't go
wandering around and every single kid
that you see with a backpack on a
skateboard
don't walk up to him and ask him cuz you
know I'm gonna you know let me take care
of it so I would appreciate it you know
and I'll make sure that you know you get
your money and you go home and pay your
electric bill and so he's like no
problem he had no problem and he brought
himself up a few joints and we we got
some books and some other things we
found his van and we made a can ice
little level spot we started weighing
the bugs up and so the thing went well
all day long I just kept running back up
and forth down the street and I hope the
statute of limitations has run out on
that crime but I think this was I think
January I I have our time with this
particular Dayton in my own little
personal timeline here because but I
pretty sure it was January 1993 and so
anyways I made a pocket full of money
and a big fat sack of killer and or head
stash and this guy really had some of
the best enjoyed I've ever seen so far
am i right and I'd seen quite a bit I
was fortunate enough to see quite a bit
and he told me he goes man I I'm I'm so
appreciative he was I was very
appreciative but he was tenfold
appreciative I mean he was like I it was
out of proportion how appreciative it
wasn't he kept talking about and I'm
like man it's no problem do you I was
like I'm gonna go sleep it down downtown
and I'm not going out to the marina and
crashing on the floor I'm gonna go get
my own damn room the night you know and
so anyway he said listen to me I live
here
because Jerry Garcia pleased the worker
that's the whole reason I move out here
I don't you know California is a dream
to me but I came here to see Jerry
Garcia as much as I can and you know
just in case you Brown doesn't know what
that means like Jerry Garcia at the war
field was like church to a Deadhead
that's that's like that's you get you
get as close as possible back then you
know concerts Grateful Dead concerts for
big events you know three days in a
stadium with 90,000 people in it you
know no problem sold-out and probably
another 20,000 people who don't even
have tickets it was a mayhem so to see
Jerry Garcia at a roughly I think I
think the war fields like twelve to
sixteen hundred people maybe it's a
pretty small theater it's an old theater
in San Francisco it was a very special
thing you know and playing his music
that he wanted to play us I mean it was
amazing and you know he would play on
average there three to six shows of
every month it I think if you average it
out you know so it was a lot you know
and they had these tables there and he
said living he goes hey I haven't ate I
get up in the morning at the crack of
dawn at 5:00 a.m. I go down in the
Warfield I sit in line I have a whole
group of friends that I know just from
sitting in this line just so I can get
this table and if you'd like to come I
will always save you checks I'm just
that appreciative I will always say save
you chair you're always welcome to come
down and I was like sure man
and I'm sure there was some shows coming
up and any and so I did I went down
there and sure enough the man he it was
almost like you couldn't wait to see me
you know and I get there and that's my
spot you know for for the rest of the
time the Jerry was alive I always went
sat that chair next to him and and it
was it was an amazing experience just
being there because you know this guy
was quite the networker himself as far
as growers around the nation and went
you know deadhead just travel well
obviously you know we'd go all over the
place to see the stuff we did still and
growers from all over the country would
come and they would link up with him and
come set the table or bring their wares
bring their their ganja you know like
there's their best buds you know and
Steve Parrish
come from behind the stage he was Jerry
Garcia's tecsound guitar man probably
his bouncer or you know every he was
everything to Jerry and the professional
setting you know he was the guy who
wiped down George guitar between
separase and he would come out right
and he would smoke this ramrod came out
a couple times he was visiting to see
Jerry show he was a another roadie of
the Grateful Dead and Bob Snodgrass and
Maria Snodgrass would come out also late
there Bob Snodgrass is the guy who
probably blew the very first glass
marijuana pipe you know and this is
where I get the time line I look
confused because it might it seemed like
back then we were young and I probably I
would imagine everybody feel this way
but back when we were young like a month
or like a season could seem like a year
in your memory as you look back in your
life you know you're like how could that
much stuff happen in my life and that
short period of time as I got older I've
always kind of tripped out on that you
know yeah and so it wasn't too long
after I met him though and like I said
Jerry was always playing there that I
asked I asked this guy I said hey yeah
hey man it's okay my friend I'll be
telling about the super Scott that's
what it was
I would tell about the Super Skunk oh
yeah you know it is you'd like yeah this
is nice but you should see this stuffed
in my hometown or you know it's always
like the fish that got away you know
what I mean I tell him what the Super
Skunk and he'd he heard about it he knew
about it you know he had like I said
friends all over the place and he was
like well you got to get me some you
know I want to check it out man you're
always talking about his super Scott so
one night or one weekend or a week or
whatever excuse me some of the UH some
of the people that I grew up growing
some of the people that grew the weed
that I spoke when I was growing up came
out to see Jarrod the word field and
they linked up with me and I was like
hey I asked my buddy see if you guys
want to come to the table man that'd be
kind of cool you know he amazing puffs
of a good time let me just ask my friend
so I asked the guy the table guy you
know and I said hey man would it be cool
if these guys came and you know they got
they brought some Super Skunk wouldn't
you get a chance to try it he's like
hell yeah definitely so you know I was
just a pretty much a kid I mean I was
you know what 19 at the timer 20 21 21 I
guess and you know these guys were grown
men most of them even the person I'm
talking about with the that share
deceived the table with me and you know
they were all growers and they had their
own discussions you know to me and they
started chit-chatting and the thing
about people from Virginia and I don't
know if tonic diligence or yeah I guess
he lived it you don't really need that
he doesn't need to tell you but it's a
harsh place for people who who uh you
know involved with cannabis and they'd
fit any facet smoking anyway I mean it's
you can get yourself in a lot of trouble
there
with the law yes so of course that leads
to culture of a lot of quiet you know
reserved you know you gotta watch who
you talk to you've got a really watch
your step and keep your business to
yourself if you want to you know even
just grow some head stash for yourself
there and that's how those guys work
they didn't talk about with anybody and
that even the right I knew they smoke
they didn't talk about with me you know
meaning and and I was okay okay with
that cuz I understood so I was surprised
that they you know they opened up to
each other and it was cool you know and
you know they came back out for another
set of shows we got to all know each
other over that weekend and uh finally
some of the boys from Virginia said to
me they said hey listen your body from
New York he he asked us stuff about if
we could get him Super Skunk cuttings I
was like oh yeah what did you tell him
and he goes uh you know we kind of kind
of didn't really answer we wanted to
talk to you I want you know this guy and
I was like well you know I haven't known
abroad long but he you know I know a lot
about him I know that you know he's an
all right guy and they took my took my I
feel like they went out on a limb
because they took the 20 or one year old
you know advice that hey this guy's okay
man it's okay talk come a little bit and
get to know and exchange phone numbers
and stuff which was a really big deal I
mean today it seems silly to think about
that but it was a really big deal at the
time and so they did and uh you know
quick-quick order you know the action
went went went in the process and and
what the plan was was he was gonna bring
a couple of cuttings out from Sonoma
County fly them out to New York where
he's from
and get a couple of Khem dog cuttings
and he was gonna meet them they were
gonna drive up from her genuine some
super skunk cutting as a couple and then
and then make an exchange and they were
gonna take the chem dog back to Virginia
or I think you know what they could back
I think they were actually going for
this thing he had called the Francine it
was I don't advant see in years it was
the only one ever shared it's really
nice it's beautiful like a Northern
Lights kind of thing and they really
liked it that's the one they wanted and
when he went back there he got a couple
of Khem dog cuttings this is in 1993
still it had them in 1993 and and he
took a key went back and got a couple of
Kim dogs local locally from that area
and he was tied into that whole Kim dog
family that was there they used to grow
kim dog and apartments using peters and
had these killer like 10-pound harvest
from just a few lights you know and they
would so they would sell the stuff from
Central Park for $800 an ounce and it
was legendary you know what I mean it
was crazy but he was tied in that to
that crowd so somehow he got some come
to out cuttings and then they came up
with Super Skunk a name in exchange and
then in order to kind of pay whoever
helped him out he gave them a Super
Skunk cutting there and then so he
brought back the Kim dog and the Super
Skunk back to the west coast the guy the
New York guy right yeah so that's how he
got out here and that's that was the
trade that that eventually as far as I
know and the way I understand it is
that's where the mask on became the
mascot was that Super Skunk coat cutting
that came up from Virginia right yeah so
and then I don't know all this because I
wasn't there for that you know I I know
that's what happened because you know I
knew our people grow but I don't know
what happened with super Scott a hundred
percent but I'll definitely have seen
pictures of the master Super Skunk and
without a doubt that's the mask um I
mean I'm sorry the Super Skunk the 86
super sativa C Club Super Skunk
without a doubt it was the most
distinctive bud because it always had
this one little pregnant belly that
would pop off on not all around the bud
only on one side and not necessarily on
the side the light was on but only on
one side and if you look at its a in
that 86 catalog or the 87 one of the two
it's very distinct that picture it looks
exactly like the seed that was popped to
where I grew up and it was the same one
that they called the mascot no I saw
later on I mean all this stuff you know
I like to say that like you know back
then like of course we didn't really
have cell phones we had sky pagers was
the brand new thing where you could get
a page anywhere in the United States it
was cutting-edge revolutionary you know
what I mean but there was no Facebook
there was no Instagram there was no
email there's no cell phones obviously I
mean it's amazing what the Grateful Dead
did to connect people around the United
States and to you know keep these things
alive that we're trying to be stamped
out by the government at the height of
the drug war the United States and it's
just you can't
it can never be like overemphasize like
how much that community had a role in
making sure that cannabis kept evolving
through those years those dark years in
the United States you know that was
actually with that sorry I was gonna say
that was gonna be the next question I
was gonna actually ask was you know in
the end of the day how much do you think
the Grateful Dead did influence the
cannabis scene you know like when I look
at it I tend to think that if they
weren't around you could almost argue
that you know like none of this would
exist in terms of you know I mean you'd
have your skunk number one and that but
you know in terms of the cam dog and all
the og cush and everything that
delineate it out from it you just
wouldn't exist
do you agree I totally agree it's no
doubt about it I mean anybody my age or
order or even younger a little bit knows
that you know it had there was nothing
going on in America like this I mean
there's nothing wrong I mean the drug
war had a huge when an act like it's
over it's not over but it's definitely
we're on the other side of it now it's
waning now like our side has now made
its case that hey man you know you're
destroying people's lives you've taken
people whose family and crushing them
and it's just for a plant we're
definitely got her we've definitely got
America's of attention now about what an
atrocity occurred during those years but
you know from from this 1970 from the
early
seven days when this home when they
basically scheduled drugs in the United
States and put cannabis in the schedule
one category meaning it has no medical
value whatsoever and they still work out
to that day you know all the way through
until basically until 9/11 I would even
say because I think maybe that took a
lot of the resources away from the drug
war I mean it was dark in America it was
hard like you you had to really be
committed to these types of things there
was no you know there was no you didn't
take these things lightly because I mean
if you did you were playing with fire
and you know you really could be find
yourself in for a big surprise you know
and there's a wonder there's one saying
you know as far in grateful to Atlanta
is that in the land of darkness thought
the the carriage of the with them in the
land of darkness the carriage of light
is drawn by the Grateful Dead you know
that's kind of what it was like you know
yeah they literally they're mister their
mission from the get-go was to go into
the dark [__] corners of the United
States and the world but really United
States because this is this is about it
this this band and this culture was
about America it was about you know
where's the freedom you know like
where's the adventure that we all read
about like is it over and we're just
we're just spectators of the past you
know like it just it was right now and
it was happening and it was it was they
took this circus into every dark corner
of this country and they found kids like
myself who were just like really this is
it this is your freedom that I've been
getting caught about in fourth grade
this is [__] you know like they
really think that you know when I say
they I'm not talking about a guy playing
a guitar I'm telling the whole thing I'm
talking about me everybody who was part
of that you know and the movement and
the band of course was atlest and people
who put it all on the line because of
what they believed and that's really
what it boiled down to it was never
about money it was never about it was
just about you know I don't really know
what is about it's about just trying to
make a more free world where you can be
yourself you know and I think that's I
think that cannabis played it was a big
part of that you know I think that was
just a it was all it was a you know it
was in the background but it was also in
the foreground it was a big part of that
you know I mean that's that's where
growers met each other that's where you
learn
that's where you met a guy in the park
you know that's how you meet a guy in
the park in San Francisco and you're 21
who's eventually gonna give you the chem
dog that's how it worked
you know yeah and so I'm sorry for
getting sidetracked yeah no it's not a
problem
getting back to this story just to
clarify because I think some people may
not have picked up on it when you said
the New York guy that's how he got the
Super Skunk that's master you're
referring to right no no no this this
guy I'm gonna leave this guy's name out
of it for now because I haven't talked
about you know talk yeah that's no
problem sir I just wanted to clarify for
everyone so yes I knew a friend has got
this super skunk now yeah and so and I
and he like I said he brought one
cutting back to the west coast and he to
hit with him so because that's what you
know he's doing it for and he left one
with the people his friends in New York
right yeah and then eventually that got
up to Massachusetts as the story goes
that that eventually got up the
massachusett I think I think G has
talked a little bit about that I'm not
sure he could probably tell you more
about like what how did that get from
Staten Island let's go ahead and say
Staten Island up to where he was there I
mean he was tied in with those folks
because their whole thing was the chem
dog so I don't know how he was connected
to those because I didn't to those guys
I just don't know you know yeah like I
said I've ever met that guy until 2006
so I want and then going forward from
there so he brings it back and he's like
man you know he starts growing it here
in Northern California and he basically
I'm like look the only thing I ask
because every time you harvest sell me
all the week and he would sell me these
stuff wears a week not even in a bag and
me and my friends would just smoke at
all I was no it was just for us you know
and it was it was amazing it was like I
can't believe this have what a great
life I'm smoking my favorite weed the
Super Skunk and I'm like you know it's
just too many grew up better than
anybody you know this guy knows what
he's doing so anyways yeah so we became
closer friends and then as we got a
little closer he said to me one day good
hey when this whole Grateful Dead thing
ends you know I just want to tell you
like I want to offer to you that I will
give you genetics and I will show you
what
thing I know about growing marijuana and
and I was like great cuz that's what
exactly what I'm gonna do when this is
over the plan all along I was like
Souza's that was always the problem with
tour to me because I was like man I
could be grown marijuana somewhere and I
hadn't really I had only done it once
and before I love Virginia and but it's
just I knew that's what I would have
wanted it to did it was perfect you're
always at home that's where I want to be
I love kind buds you know you're gonna
have plenty of those there's a win-win
how you know yeah so Jerry did die a few
years later and I went to him and you
know I said alright man I'm coming up
there I'm gonna move to Sonoma County
and I'm gonna get a place and and oh no
I'm sorry
reverse I met a lady it ended up being
my wife at one point and she had
convinced me hey let's uh let's start
settling down a little bit you know she
was still in college and then you know
she was going to Sonoma State University
and so we were gonna move up there and I
you know I've got ahold of my buddy with
one way the other we were getting a
place up there now this is before Jerry
Garcia died and it was that it was that
summer of 95 like June and we went up
there we found a place and I I called
him up and I said hey you know I'm here
to come over you know he came over the
house and we talked and and I was like
look man I'm selling it I'm out we're
gonna made a little money recently I'm
gonna go buy some rights and whatever
you sell she think I need and you know I
want to get this I got this bedroom here
and I'm gonna start growing some pot in
here and he he's like alright that's it
I'll bring it over to you and so they
bring me over my super Scott you know
and he brings over the ken-dog and that
was it and I already brought over like
with some her niece Edie pop that was
the other thing back then we never ever
the one of the things was that the first
thing I heard was if you ever find any
seeds in your pot from way eat them
don't grow them there will always be
[__] you know of course they'd only
found out that's not necessarily true
because he goes through and he does all
that he literally this all happened like
the week before Jerry died he died on
August 9th 1995
he brought all the stuff over to me
these plants and and he filed three
showed me what to do and we hit he had
some pretty even today cutting-edge
methods of organic growing you know and
he showed me everything and and the
stuff came out the first one came out
just like it's you know there's my
precedent he was a good teacher and
thought the number one thing you taught
me I'll never forget was don't ever
think you know it all always pay
attention everyone else's do you know
who's willing to tell you anything no
matter what their skill level is no
matter how long they're doing this
always always try to keep learning
because once the minute you think you've
got all figured out
is the minute that when you'll have a
problem and you won't have any idea what
the big you know yeah there's really
good advice and yeah I got the books and
started it out and so he always told me
he told me what he gives me the Kim dog
he says alright and you know he never he
only it always had like a very small
amount of its he never had like like I
said he would sell me a quarter pound of
head stash would all be Super Skunk you
know all the tops the best buds and then
he would any he would like smoke a few
joints and give me an up chem dog that
was always a thing you never had like an
ounce or two of it or whatever you know
and I asked if I was like what's the
deal with them and it's the best one
clearly I mean he's a killer you know
all the strains he had he had some
really nice ones this was the best one
and he gave us dude it's it's a [__] to
grow it's so hard to grow it won't root
you know it's thick heavy accident you
know it doesn't yield you can't count on
it
and I was like whatever man he goes I
was like in in other words he was like
you know really want this when he gave
it to me is like you don't really want
this you can have it but I know you're
not gonna be able to do much with it and
because I can't really do a whole bunch
with it and it's just it was like that
you know and I was like whatever dude
that's the best one that's the one I
want and it gives do me and the first
one was a was a crop of Super Skunk all
hundred-percent Super Skunk and that
little harmony learn that he gave me and
then and then the next one I was gonna
you know take a bunch of cuttings off
that got this Kim dog mother going
pretty good and he told me he goes hey
man I'm telling you right now you know
it's better to stick with this
Super Skunk at roots in ten days and you
know it's got a quick vid by blah blah
that's like man I'm just gonna give it a
shot you know what's the worst thing out
so I took a bunch of cuttings out of it
and made sure enough it burned in like
14 days and I was like well so far so
good so far what he told me is not true
and another thing he told me I'll never
forget he says the chem dog is for the
night he goes and his heavy accent he's
like and never smoke in a bubbler before
11 a.m.
I just got a smoked joint after joint
after joint this is advice to me right
I'm like alright so I probably pulled
out a bubbler right then loaded it up
and smoked in his probably before 11
a.m. I don't know but anyway so and it
came out really nice like I did I grew
and it came out really nice and I was
like all right you know the super skunk
is definitely a bigger Guilder
that was very important to me and you
know so I'll just have a few of these
and that's the way it went so the years
went by and you know that's the way it
wasn't like I said you know we we
weren't very connected back in growers
it was it was very sparse and sporadic
and unusual and rare when you would get
a chance to like trade things with
people and of course the other thing he
told me I should say was never ever ever
give this to anybody I'm giving this to
you and I shouldn't be you know I'm
doing it and as I'm giving this to you
I'm violating my French trust me not to
give it to anybody and I'm telling you
don't do that to me
don't ever give this day by and I was
like alright yeah no problem you know my
word my word is my honor so yeah I'll do
that and and the years went by
you know kids came and you know life was
pretty settled down and you know life
was really different when Jerry died and
I was a lot of adjustment for people
like me and just kept on growing the
killer and trying to learn as I was
going wrong and then in 2005 fast
forward 2005 I looked at a high Times
article a friend recommend he goes you
won't believe this but this guy okay so
let me back up a little bit I met a
fella on tour who we became French to
the pot you know like talking about this
blood talk about that book showing each
other broads would be fine you know
you know kind of sore type things and uh
you know he became a good friend of mine
he started talking to me about
coincidentally you know before Jerry
died he started talking about this hot
chem dog you know that he would grow
that he that he would smoke when he was
young you know the same kind of way I
talked about the super Scott put up in
New Hampshire and Massachusetts area
where he's from and you know it kind of
went in one ear I went out there at the
out the other at the time but I
definitely remember that
well we became really good friends and
even better friends after Jerry died and
he's actually still really one of my
closest friends to this day and and I'll
see how it was when I started like when
Jerry died there was a big disconnect
like we lost contact with each other
like I said we didn't have cell phones
and stuff and for a minute for you know
a year it was like it took a minute to
get ahold of everybody and find
everybody because there was no events
going on it was the next thing didn't
happen so it just took a while and I
link back up with this fellow who I'm
talking about
and uh he I had the kim dog now and I
smoked it with him and he's like dude
this is the [__] chem dog I was like
oh yeah that's right that's right you
you smoked this when you were young you
were always told me about your friend G
and I was because he knew G I guess you
know I mean I know he did they were
there real close actually you know back
when I guess they met at a Phish show or
something like that you know back in the
early 90s and or late 80s and had become
good friends and so it was kind of cool
as a little connection and and uh you
know he lived up in Tahoe he moved up to
Tahoe and and I'd go up their business
snowboarding and bring him dog and you
know he started a little thing and he
you know I give the kid I gave him to
Kim dogs I'm figuring hey you know that
guy who cracked the seed cuz he told me
the story he's like yeah my friend
cracked this yet he had the 13 or the 12
whatever the seeds and you know I
started to on this tour and I'm like wow
that's what a coincidence if I actually
ended up with this cutting you know so
so then I guess gee at one point made
these t-shirts right and he made a Super
Skunk and a chem dog and we're at these
it was like this light green almost the
color of the chem dog's shirt and had
that this dog with the joint smoke this
dog on the back smoking to join this
little emblem he made for chem dog
instead chem dog since 91 and then they
have Super Skunk and it said Super Skunk
since 1993 because that's when he got it
you know yeah and they were kinda cool
yeah and so one day I got there to go
snowboarding my friend gives me this
chem dog shirt and a super scum shirt I
was like wow did you make these he's
like no my friends G made these back
east and and he sent me a few and I
think he's like you got to have one I
was like yeah me I love it
still got to the day you know and so
that was probably like in 1998 97 when
that was going on and then fast forward
now to 2006 2005 I see this High Times
article and it's a it's a it interview
of Qi talking about the Kim dog right
and they had actually gone into his
garden or and taking pictures of his
plants and they were like in 5-gallon
like Home Depot bucket type buckets you
know and and really beautiful plants you
know and they were showing some pictures
of the sister what they said was the Ken
dog but clearly to me it was not the
same plant that I had and then and then
some Kim something else I might have
been to Kim D but it was definitely the
sister the Syst they called it his
sister I'm sure you've heard of it it it
was it called my yeah it's like I went
to my buddy's sister is um actually the
number I write I think that's it yeah
and I was like I gotta have that so it's
my buddy I was like and they talked they
were they were they were good friends I
was like dude I just saw this nautic
with your buddy and I was like what do
we got to do I mean what can I do for us
to go out there and get that cuz you
know I'm not sure he's even got the chem
dog anymore we could give him the chem
dog back and then you know maybe he'll
trade and actually I'm sure we'd
probably talked about going to get other
strains before that time but so I I was
having a problem I was uh I was the
first time I'd ever seen powdery mildew
right and I was had it on my plants and
I and I was like what the hell is this
so I started like kind of searching you
know now we have computers now and cell
phones and [__] but not like we still
not like we do today
I got on the computer and I started like
kind of trying to find out what I could
find out about it like someone said it's
called mildew or powder no doer downy
mildew and I started you know trying to
figure this stuff out and it led me to
this website called overgrown calm and
it looked like a completely it look to
me look like a [__] you know like a
police trap or something you know this
is kind of cool man like I all these
people are anonymous and they're sharing
knowledge here they really are I was
learning stuff I'll stay up late at
night and looking at it and it's sort of
naturally I goo not Google but search
chem dog and this guy came up chem dog
right and and you know looking through
what he was saying I could tell holy
[__]
this is this guy gee this is my party's
friend right here this is the guy that I
was looking at his pictures flat you
know last month or whenever it was you
know of this High Times article so I was
like I'm gonna I'm gonna reach out to
this guy so I got that t-shirt that he
made out and I took a little picture of
the emblem cuz you had to have like a
like Avatar just like yeah I have with
all the things we use today
and I called myself skunk VA you know
super skunk Virginia made sense right
yes all right
I sent and and you know the over girl is
a serious thing like that you know now
when you go on those forums you know
there's a lot of [__] and
know-it-alls and but people are really
open and willing to share back that
overgrow they were a little bit more
cautious they were converse with you
they wanted to see pictures and stuff
you know they didn't want to just start
talking with anybody about growing and
all it giving you all their little trade
secrets or even asking you questions so
if you put on a few pictures I saw if
you put a few pictures up you know you
could get a better conversation going
people saw you're serious you're not
joking around here you know you got you
got some you're growing some pot you
know so I put some pictures up of Khem
dog and uh and then I put that little
avatar on there and immediately he like
sends me like one of them little you
know private messages like hey where'd
you get that shirt I just gave the first
letter of the of our mutual friend and
he's like oh you live up in Tahoe
I said no but you know we've known each
other for you know 10 years now we're
really close to the set and the other he
tells me he goes I don't I don't have
the Kim dog anymore and I was like I
know you don't I saw that you know and I
was like but today's your lucky day
because you know Phil let's just alleges
the bass player for the grade for that
and he was getting he was playing and
this was like in December of 2005 and he
was planted February of 2006 in New York
like nine nights and they kind of just
planned just like almost just
materialized I was like listen I will
come out there check out Phil and I'll
bring you your Kim dog back and I if you
could just give me like trade assists
for me the sister and he was like
absolutely you know and of course you
know we didn't it wasn't right away we
chit-chatted for you know like a week or
two a little bit you got to sort of make
sure that we knew who are talking to and
I'm sure he called my friend and made
sure that you know it all lined up and
it did so I took a couple of chem dog
cuttings in New York put him on the
plane with me and flew him out to New
York and got a place the Soho Suites
down in Soho and and the night I got
there
biggest snowstorm they've had since like
1953 or 43 or softened it was amazing
and but it did delay our meeting and we
eventually met up and he brought me over
he didn't give me the sister and I'm not
really sure never really got to never
have still this day never talking about
that but but he did bring me to CEM deep
you know and then and then to my
surprise and to my joy he actually
brought the Super Skunk which we had
lost out here we had lost that like in
1997 my buddy was getting a house
inspection by the landlord and he had
the one mother not my friend from Staten
Island in New York the guy I was talking
about earlier at the work field and he
he basically had this plan to box and it
just didn't make it through the
inspection you know you so we hadn't had
it in a while
and so he gives that back to me and I
was really happy you know and it was
really cool so I take that back and then
at this point me and my friend in Tahoe
his our mutual friend
mutual friend we had our own place and
we were you know we were we grew the Kim
D now we had to Kim D on the west coast
you know it to me it wasn't it wasn't
like it's not really my I don't love the
Kennedy as much as I think the public
loves I'm more of a Kim dog guy but uh
but it but nonetheless the Super Skunk
was back and it was the Super Skunk it
was the same exact cutting definitely at
age cuz the Super Skunk got that seat
had gotten cracked in 1988 so it's
actually been around longer than the
chem dog you know if it's still out
there I don't have it I don't know
anybody who's got that cutting anymore
per se but I definitely you know this is
what we're the side story goes off
because the guy who cracked that seed
that super strong seed in Virginia back
in 98 he's one of my closest friends now
you know and he was well a friend so I
know it's a really it's a really special
thing to me because that's actually a
Facebook story you know like a Facebook
modern-day kind of computer store that
link back up to him and I'm really
grateful to have that man back in my
life because he he was he's older than
me you know he's like an elder to me and
I look up to him and it's just really
special but it's like I can't believe
the circles you think you've come you
know all the circles are all now
complete and all of a sudden boom one
day you got this whole other part of
your past is back in your future back in
your present and especially you know but
yeah but what the reason I was jumping
that's because he actually has not the
Super Skunk but we we now have back the
parent the Super Skunk was that I didn't
know this until recently but the super
Scott actually wasn't just a crack from
Neville seeds from the super city this
evening it was actually cross that he
made with Super Skunk and that he got
he's actually croc took to Super Skunk
season crossing together so did
something else it might have been I
don't know the exact detail I don't want
to get quoted on that quite yet because
it was something like that but he has
one of the parents to that Super Skunk
which to me is that's awesome you know
we'll see what we can do with that too
you know sorry I was gonna say maybe
we'll get back into that I just want to
go back to the camera
for a second so when you said that um
you saw immediately the chem sorry
Master II didn't have the chem dog that
was what now is referred to as the jobra
and cutting him I write this this is
this is before now you'd have to ask Jie
about this but I I'm under the
impression that this would have been
before they went back up I'm not sure
100% sure about that but it might it
might have been you know link back up
after their original meeting back at
Deer Creek in 91 yeah yeah it wasn't it
to me it looked like it might have been
Kim D I'm not really sure what it was
but I can't really remember I'm sure the
High Times article still around but I
don't remember what it was and it was
just I just noticed that either there
was a picture that wasn't actually Kim
dog or also it could have been it was
just conspicuously missing from all
these photos you know what I mean I
think you might even been that okay
as my memories a little frog cumin I and
probably actually still have it the
pictures are beautiful like the sister
just unbelievably nice you know I was
gonna say so if we were to compare say
the chem sister and the chem D and the
chem 4 and the 91 you kind of mentioned
earlier that the ninety one was your
favorite
why do you think it is then for example
that people like JJ and Rose choose to
work with the D kind of as their you
know to work those lines out over say
the 91 I made a guest from what I can
see is that I think that I mean I'm
going on a limb or saying that maybe
they didn't have the 91 you know yeah I
mean I have to say that's probably what
it was you know or they had that fake
Jill Brandt 91 which you know I knew
even I was even around when that
happened so yeah you know that's my
guess I don't know I mean I also it may
be I'm so biased that I have to come up
with something like that because I can't
understand why I mean I have the Kim D I
think it's it's guys place in life but
it's it's so far different than the Kim
dog it really is you know it's not I to
me it's not even close to this
same not not just the level of quality
but the same type like in the same
ballpark like comparable even you know
what I'm saying like it's way different
like that that fuel smell is really
different on the chem dog 91 compared to
the Kennedy to me it's just you could
put totally be in bubbles want to not
even care about the other and I guess
what I'm saying is maybe the it's just
the opposite for other people maybe they
just see a different I understand I met
people later in life here too lately
like the Instagram and I think he
mentioned that to me that he likes the
chem dog be better the chem d better
than the chem dog too so I think it's
just I'm so heavily biased about chem
dog that I love it so much I think that
maybe it's hard for you to understand
why that would happen you got upset yeah
so I'm I guess it kind of goes without
saying cuz you kind of alluded that you
weren't fully aware but I guess just to
kind of rule the story straight when G
did go down from all that res business
were you aware that you were the only
one with the 91 cutting or it wasn't
until you saw that high Times story and
then it kind of dawned on you that you
were the only one who had it I don't
think I was the only one with it because
there's like back to the Staten Island
crew I I got to hang out with him one
point in Tahoe when they came to visit
interesting crowd and they they I think
they had I'm pretty sure they had some
chem dog and I have no idea what any of
those guys are up to these days but they
definitely had it so I never really feel
like I was the only one that had the
chem dog during those years you know to
me yeah and I didn't really know what
happened to gee like it wasn't like my
buddy even though he was closely and it
wasn't like he was sitting around give
me the blow-by-blow what's going on that
guy cuz that was our only encounter he
came to my hotel we hung out we traded
some stories we going if I had to do it
over again we would have had a lot more
to talk about I just didn't know how
much how much in common we had with
people and things and stuff in life but
um but that's all that's all we did we
did the trade and I came back and
brought the Kennedy and the Super Skunk
back and and I gave him two really
beautiful cuts of the chem dog you know
and he was just as happy as I was but
yeah
so that was the only reason I did that
thing on overgrow though that was the
only reason is to try to get that trade
just to do it but you know it seemed
like an opportunity for me to get some
other genetics out to the west coast in
my life and I I you know that was the
whole reason I did it to me like I said
I'm kind of an introverted person when
it comes to this stuff I was trying to
break out of my shell and step into the
right so to say and and to start like an
internet account and like give myself a
name and put pictures of my garden on
the internet that was like insane to me
that was my perspective that was the
most insane thing I could do but it
worked you know and I never really went
back over to overgrow and I was I wasn't
blown away by the kindy and I still
didn't have the sisters maybe I was kind
of had a little bad taste in my mouth a
little bit it was no big deal I think it
was pretty cool how it all happened and
it happened and you know we ended up
having to Kim D on the west coast we
didn't have that before that was cool
you know it got spread all over the west
coast you know so so that that's what
happened and then and then over girl of
course got shut down I don't know the
details that story but I know every girl
got shut down and I think the government
shut him down and they took their
servers and all this other stuff and so
just compounded my belief that hey you
need to keep your business your stuff
and certainly don't go to the internet
with it you know yeah so
2012 I had another problem obviously in
my garden I couldn't solve and you know
I had these plants that look like they
were being poisoned with salt water you
know and I'm flushing home and I'm
looking through the see the root balls
with a microscope and you know now I'm
going back to the internet now it's back
six years later I'm back on the internet
and and I I Google like you know
cannabis for them and you know what's
the one that they have several of them
popped up but I went with the I see I
know what's he yeah that's what I'm
jumping up and I give myself a name and
I start up the whole thing and I'm going
through there and I'm looking to I'm
looking through bugs and you know I'm
researching tobacco mosaic virus I'm
way way deep in this and well it same
thing uh pictures on there and uh and I
put basically the same pictures probably
because I have a hard drive my version I
don't have a lot of pictures but I got
some of my favorite pictures and I'm
sure I put my favorite ones on there
well I know I did and uh immediately
I like 100 people message me and they're
like where did you get those pictures
like kind of Stern with me you know and
I was like I took them they're my
pictures I got from our hard drive
what's the deal you know how you doing
and they're like those are skunk those
are some cookies pictures where did you
get those but you're like an imposter I
was like I'm an imposter they all click
back in my head I'd completely forgot
about this I mean really like I had not
really thought about this overgrow thing
and years at this point
hey it's went right into my head and I
started talking this one guy who was
clearly paying attention to the chem
dog-bite ah you know telling me what he
knew about the story and stuff and he
was repeat and he goes are you skunky
and I'll say I mean I guess so because I
mean that was that's you know I was on
the overgrown skunk bein it all pop back
on my head and I was like holy [__] cuz
it freaked me out when all these people
started texting I was like or you know
messaging me on this thing you know and
and it was kind of it was really funny
was really surreal and so anyways ended
up that I had broad mites and you know
had to go through that and learn that
and you know take the brunt on that so I
could tell everybody else well learn
about it how to get rid of that [__] so
and there anyways that's kind of that's
kind of were yeah that's where I met G
and you know now we're all kind of
getting linked up and it's really cool
it's a really special thing to be part
of you know it's and uh for me this year
of the 21st year I've had it the chem
dog cutting and you know she's been in
my care every single day every single
one of those days and I ended up giving
I think I counted on my hand I ended up
giving it over these years I ended up
giving it to five people several of
those people a couple of those people
more than once a couple of those people
a bunch of times and then a couple of us
gave it to a once no reason ever gave it
to anybody because
I took that very seriously and I and I I
you know I had friends question our
friendship because I wouldn't give it to
him that time but I
it wasn't anything because I told my
friend I never worked you know and then
in the end that are you know that that
seemed kind of silly now so I mean but
that's that's really how it was I mean I
really felt that way you know I told my
Shore Network man I would you know you
know through brewer's yours you know
like from from that 2006 up until like
2012 time and even a little bit longer
actually I would say no it's still a
couple years ago and Kim dog was it was
a muddy thing because no one had the
chem dog and everyone had to Kim dog I
mean it was everywhere so all the clubs
you could get cuttings of it but none of
it was Kim dog you know you know I spent
I spent spill summer 2008 going from
garden to garden you know people would
call me up hey man you know friends
would call me up and say hey man I'm
running the Kim blog out here on my
property mindo I need you to come and
it's not really looking like it's me and
I need you to come up and check it out
and go up there and see you know a giant
forest of giant outdoor 150 outdoor
plants you know and then after tell them
said no I'm sorry I mean this isn't the
Sour Diesel what it looks a lot like two
Sour Diesel but it's definitely not the
chem dog it and turns out that that was
that that Jobi thing that happened you
know uh my cat hole makes up I I have
the whole details on how that happened
because you know my my good friend was
there and and it was a big mix-up there
and and but I think I'd rather leave
that out of it because I haven't really
talked him see how much he wants people
to know about you know how that happened
stuff like that and yeah whatever so
I'll just leave that but uh but that's
when that's what as I understand and
according to him and he knows he knows
who he gave it to and what the mix-up
was and and and he knows how that
happened and I guess that was that Joe
be cut with chem dog that was out here
and probably elsewhere too in that two
thousand seven two thousand six or seven
or a tear right there and so put but
when I'm saying
like so you might you know as someone
who loves chem dog and you're growing it
you know trying to get by and life and
stuff you know you're like hey I've got
some chem dog would you be interested in
looking at that you know whoever it was
would it eventually got to the point
where people would didn't want look at
it because they had already seen it and
liked it but they never saw it got so
bad sometimes where I would show it to
people you know finally said no this is
chem dog and in their mind they had
already made up their mind about what
they thought Kim dog was and their
opinion about it and they would just
brush it away and I'm like this is
killer pot what are you what's wrong
with you you know so for like four years
I was the only one who write kim dog you
know maybe my couple friends you know
and then recently because of the
internet or or because breeding is
becoming you know a more prevalent thing
in the United States maybe the chem dog
is making its comeback now and people
are more willing to stop and pay
attention to the deal with the come down
and you know how how what it's it's it's
the backbone of contemporary camp
cannabis and you know I think in the
world now I mean I live here in
California and you know it definitely is
I mean every strain that you see has got
something to do with ken dog at some
point you know and and then you know a
2003 I had a short-lived partnership
with a person and here in Sonoma County
and and this person had Sour Diesel and
this was the first time I'd seen Sour
Diesel I was like good lord this stuff
smells familiar you know I mean it had
all my favorites in it come to find out
most likely you know as the story goes
some point back then one of those guys
in Staten Island somehow I don't know
what happened I mean I've heard so many
different versions like I said I wasn't
there but somehow someway the Super
Skunk that they got from my front of
Virginia and that Kim dog got tangled up
in a harming fest and and I think that's
how the Sour Diesel came about so I
thought that was kind of cool I I really
I think that because I mean it clearly
that's it's not the I mean that's got to
be the most you know famed
strain of we don't you know on the
planet you know yeah sir I was actually
gonna ask you do you ever feel like you
kind
don't get any credit where you should
for that because I was gonna say you
know a lot of people don't realize that
yeah the Sauer D is the 91 getting
thrown a bit of pollen on the Super
Skunk do you feel like you should get
some credit that or do you think you're
kind of too far removed because when I
think about it both of those strains are
very much attributable to yourself in a
lot of ways but I would give I know this
sounds like some hippy [__] but I would
give the Grateful Dead credit because
like I said I I just I just introduced
some a couple of my favorite Gro first
with each other that's literally all I
did you know I mean they did all the
hard work they flew out met each other
you know they did all that stuff so I
don't I'm not I don't really want credit
but and I'm not you know I understand
that there's another story out there
where they went to Amsterdam and got
some Super Skunk so maybe maybe they had
another Super Skunk who knows you know
but I definitely know that my my friends
from New York he he definitely left a
Super Skunk behind with them and and
like I said I got that cut that they
think that the Sour Diesel when I got
that one the super Scott from and
actually he didn't she knew somehow he
knew that that was the same cut he
somehow he was kind of the one that even
told me you know what I mean that yeah
the super sculpey he was giving me was
the same one that he that he got back
then which was the same as the mascot he
says to you I'm calling the Super Skunk
but they call it the mask on cure you
know Sam and then coming home I grew it
and sure as [__] it was a super Scott no
doubt about it
all the little features were there like
I said that pregnant belly
the smell is unforgettable you know it's
it's loud like the Sour Diesel it's it's
it's unforgettable I mean it smells just
like stuck on the road from about a
hundred fifty yards you know it's it's
son I'm just unmistakable I don't know
exactly happen out and I don't really
want any kind of credit for anything
like that but like I said I would give
Jerry Garcia the Grateful Dead credit
cuz man what a what a what an amazing
connection that is you know but those
guys made in the Jamaicans trade because
if they didn't do that and if he didn't
bring the chem dog back I hear my friend
from New York he gave up on the Kim dog
and then I really was
the only one in my world about it you
know to me yeah and that's why I ended
up giving other people because I wanted
to make sure I wasn't it's something
happened to me you know or my place I
didn't want anything that and I didn't
want that I understood the gravity of
the situation that this could go away
forever so I always made sure that
someone else had it you know and then
you know ended up being over the years I
gave it that I think five people total
and only really one of them ever really
kept it and he's my my good friend who I
knew from Tahoe like I'll talk about
earlier you know so yeah I was gonna say
so when we see breeders these days you
know notably we've got a body and also a
swerve of the Kelly con claiming to be
breeding with the skunk VA cutting that
I mean I guess you've kind of already
alluded to the answer that that they're
obviously not getting it directly from
you do you think that when people see a
breeder claiming to be breeding with the
skunk VA cutting they should kind of
view that with an eye of caution or do
you think it's probably legit just come
through someone through someone well
I'll say this I'll say that you know the
way I look goes like this because you
know you could go and you could you
could get into this tit-for-tat with
this and it you know it does matter
you know the truth matters it really
does I truly believe that I believe that
what you say and the truth it you know
it should line up you know and if your
story is is that you did some stupid
little shady deal in the back room to
get the cuts you have or whatever it is
you know you know that's your story you
know stick you gotta you got to go that
it's gonna come out at some point you
know and and the way I look at it is
this is that as we go forward I do think
it matters because you know at some
point we're all gonna be completely it I
believe this this is my opinion I
believe that all of us here in the
United States we're gonna be completely
you know out in the open and you're
gonna have your story you know how did
this happen to you you know why did you
choose to do this why did you choose to
risk your freedom to do this and then
and then what are the details it is
interesting I mean this is really cool
stuff I mean it's like prohibition is
ending and it's taken a while for shirt
and vote I got to say back when you know
I turned on the lights for the first
time
I didn't I never ever thought we would
get this far so this thing's going
quicker than any of us thought and you
know if your stories of lie then you're
gonna have to pay you're gonna have to
you're gonna have to deal with that it's
not anything for me to have a big
opinion about you're gonna have to deal
with that if that's what's going on in
your life you know what I mean not you
of course but whoever does you know I I
kept it above the board you know and and
like I did my part you know the thing
that people don't realize I think in
this you know world of marijuana growing
consultants that we live in and that's a
joke is that you know like you know we
don't we don't we don't this plants not
doing this for us you know like we're
not we're not the stars of the show here
you know what I mean we're that we're
tools our toolbox for the plant the
plant doesn't have eyes the plant
doesn't have feet for certain you know
the plant it needs protection
and the reason cannabis of my opinion is
evolved so quickly in the last 20 years
30 years is because you know it's
speaking to people and we're listening
and we're doing what we're being told
you know we're following the we're
following what needs to happen to make a
and B happen you know make the thing
happen and the plant thanks us for it
and it gives back to us and that's what
I believe I think that we work for the
plant you know that's that's what I
think i think that the kim dog needed
somebody kim dogs a powerful plant you
know my friend from new york he used to
tell me I don't know man he used to say
to me
I think it's tied into the stars cuz
sometimes he'd have really good luck and
he was just like this guy was skilled he
made he grew fast and sometimes he
didn't work out with him the kim dog
just like for me it doesn't work I mean
sometimes like what happened here you
know it's not going like it did the last
time what's going on
it's finicky a little bit you know and
he used to tell me he used to be
convinced as a very like you know
mechanically minded like nuts and bolts
kind of guy he was telling me I think
it's lined up with the Stars and I would
look at like what are you talking about
because I don't know it's just it's you
never know it's just gonna I think it
has a lot do with the star alignments
and and the moons and the cycles of the
you the galaxies and the solar system
and it's affecting the ken-dog and I'd
be like dude you sound like Sean like
you're on drugs man what is American
but that's kind of how it is though you
know what I mean it's kind of it's a
very very powerful plant and it's it
found it's safe havens it did you know
I'll share a little story with you you
know uh you know like the chem dog right
so it's it's it's being grown at house a
I'm gonna keep this like non personal
this part it's growing in house a right
and then you know and then the guy who's
in house a he has like you know he
hasn't seen a lot of his friends for
years or maybe he hasn't seen some key
friends and some years you know like
life gets busy and then they randomly
bumped into each other right at like
that one of those cannabis cups the
Emerald cup you know yeah here in Sonoma
County right and they reconnect change
phone numbers you know phone numbers are
changing and sometimes you lose connect
with people especially if they're not on
social mediums though
and then hey man I don't have the chem
dog person B says the person a can you
give it back to me of course I can you
know what I mean of course I'm glad you
asked come on over as soon as you can't
I have cuttings for you so person
becomes a person days house he gets the
plant from them super grateful thank you
and then person a gets arrested a week
later and they kill off his chem dog
plants that's a true story you know I
mean that's that's magic to me you know
that plant had some sort of like in my
opinion this is some hippie [__] but in
my opinion that plant had some
forethought of what was getting ready to
happen and somehow someway somehow
cosmically it found itself out of a bad
situation you know what I mean I mean
yeah that's a true story
you know that was a recent story that
happened that long ago and I mean you
know so what I'm trying to say is I
think that you know we should be more
humble when we talk about our
contributions to this and just remember
that we're we're just part of the puzzle
we're just part of the toolbox of this
plants using to a ball because you know
cannabis and cannabis use is you know
it's it's through the roof I mean
everybody uses cannabis now I think they
got President Obama's kid on phone the
other day smoking a joint it's it's a
big cannabis to me is in the
relationship it has a human's it's
symbiotic it's it's uh you know we live
in a stressful world we're pull
yourselves we've got we're bombarded
with negative news and bad media and
just you know it's just a weird world we
live it's not I love it here the let
think planet Earth is an amazing place
but we got our challenges here and it's
stressful yeah of course stressful just
put food table I think that cannabis
really truly helps people get through
that make it okay and beyond now we're
now we're doing cancer research with it
and you know they're doing research and
Alzheimer's all the things and I think
that it's a big part of our evolution
and in the end as we look back in
history for many years from now say 30
40 50 years we're gonna I think
society's gonna recognize that that this
plant you know evolved quickly at the
right time for us so that it become a
useful tool for us in the world that
we're creating for ourselves if that
makes any sense you know what I mean
yeah it's the people who the people who
are doing the things say me and gee you
know meeting the guy in the parking lot
that's some Grateful Dead [__] right
that's what I'm talking about meeting a
guy in a parking lot and you know 25
years later we're sitting here talking
about chem dog you know what I mean it's
amazing you know but I think the plant
is the the motivator and all that and a
you know it's like any symbiotic
relationship in nature in the universe
is you know one organism needs the other
so it does what it needs to help that
organism that organism benefits from
that aid so it returns the favor back to
the you know in this sense the caretaker
the other organism and it just keeps
going round and round and then in that
process and it's an evolution of two
organisms becoming better beings because
of that relationship and I think that's
what our you know but to answer your
question you know I I don't I I don't
know those guys have never met those
people before you know I don't I don't
know what their motive is I don't know
what they're doing but I do know that at
the end of the day when we're all
sitting around the table and this war is
finally over
raaah gonna have stories and some of
them are gonna be a lot more interesting
than others so I can tell you about that
you know what I mean yeah
so the ninety one is cutting over the 21
years you've had it do you think kind of
on that same theme of evolution we're
just talking about do you think it's
fair
typically kind of changed at all like I
guess kind of when you took it back to G
D was it just like he just instantly
recognized it or do you think it's
trying to kind of change just a little
bit over the years you'd had it and when
you took it back like he knew it was the
91 but it was just a little different
when he had it what do you think it was
the same I think that I think that I
would agree that there's definitely been
some jeneggener it over the years a
little bit there are definitely some
traits that have waned the drug traits
as as as Duke would call them I like
that I like that phrase I could stick
with it but the drug traits have not
changed that they're as strong as
everywhere the the the flavor trait is
definitely taken back a step over the
time it has now sometimes I've noticed
I'd done because like I said there was
other cuttings out there and they are
one by one every now and again I don't
know how many there were
clearly there wasn't very many but every
now and again you'll see something
you're like that's the Kim dog and then
you'll smoke it you go that does not
taste like the chem dog you know like
the one I got you know what I smoked so
I don't know how that works I don't
really know how that works I'm actually
it's something I'm really interested in
right now is is is is what we can do
about that to slow that process down or
even hopefully repair that process and
you know I'm working on that right now
but I did some digging around on your
Instagram and it was approximately 63
weeks ago someone asked you were you
gonna release the chem Doge to the
public in seed form and your reply was
I'm working on it you want to tell us a
little more about that well yeah sure I
you know I got a company it's called
Lucky Dog seed company and uh you know
I'm in the process of basically what I'm
doing is I'm developing a mail that I
feel represents the kim dog and that i
can breed with and makes make hybrids
with and and then every now and again
release some some backcrosses with
itself you know and i'm pretty I've
gotten I have had a lot of luck with it
and I've gotten I think you know project
like that could if you really do it I
think most breeders would tell you that
could take ten years
to get that exactly right and lots of
testing and the thing about testing but
all that I've learned because this is
new to me this I haven't really done a
lot of reading before it but it's it's
going really well I really enjoy and I
had a little like kindness come back to
me in seed form from some things that I
did in the past I gave it I gave the cut
to someone many years ago I'm just a
wimp it was a it was so I when I said
only one person ever gave they were they
I got a backup that would be two people
cuz he definitely he was breeding and he
was talking to me about breeding and he
was like blah oh my it's like 2004 I
think and I gave him a car the chem dog
and then Sears it
two years ago we ran back into each
other we lost contact and he actually
gave me some seeds that he worked with
that cut of chem dog I gave him and had
some good success with it he gave me
some stuff back that I could get going
with and it actually it actually was uh
was really helpful it got me gave me a
good head start on what I was trying to
do and so it was kind of cool to me it
was really it was kind of cool cuz I
never expected that like it was just I
knew he was gonna do something good with
it I gave it to him and then you know a
bunch of handful of ten ten years later
he gives them back some seeds back to me
and it's really it's turning out to be
something so uh yeah I don't want to put
anything out there that I don't 140% you
know stand behind and and but I feel
like I feel like by the beginning of
this next year we're gonna have
something going here no we also we don't
wanna just have two or three things I
want to have a nice meal that I can make
a bunch of hybrids with with so my
favorite strains and then you know give
that to the public and yeah so that's
where that's at
yeah also that was actually kind of
leading into the next question I was
gonna say it's kind of a two-parter so I
noticed you had those seeds which were I
think you said you used a silverback og
male if we think about res dogs work and
JJ's work they use the Hindu Kush and
the Afghani respectively what do you
think is the ideal male to compliment
the chem one because the thing which
stood out to me is that I know that JJ
and rez
is the chem D but there was still kind
of that commonality within the Afghan
land race they decided to use for the
mail do you kind of agree with that or
do you think maybe the more cameo cheese
is a better suited mail for this well I
think that's the same thing because I
look at that I would agree with that and
I feel like I'm doing the same thing in
the sense that the in my opinion the og
pushes is uh there's an Afghan occur
type of strain just like the Kim dog is
it's a clearly I think it's a high
elevation cooler nights lot more used to
withstand like a lot more UV light than
a lot of the lower land strains would be
something that grew at a high elevation
you know the very bright Sun was a lot
less protection making its own
protection I think that's where those
Afghan ACCA's strands that's where they
get that glossy dark green leaf I think
it's uh I think it's protection on the
natural environment that they came from
where they were exposed to extremely
we're not hot days definitely not hot
days and certainly some cool nights but
also some very intense sunlight you know
yeah so I would say that I agree with
that
and but I think that oh gee cush falls
into that category I feel like it's
clearly an Afghan ik you know cush
strength and uh so I think that that's a
good place to start and that is kind of
what I'm doing I'm working I took the
back cross og cross og cush back cross
that I've been working on it and now
that's what I'm working on developing
this male with you know so like I said
just released uh well I'll just name
this dream
it's called kim crush with a k and it's
it's a nice marriage of OG cushion Kim
what heavy heavy chem flavor and smell
to it you know a very chunk it's
beautiful pot and it's got that gloss on
the on the families that I was looking
for and and everything and and and to
back up a little bit it's actually the
silver back of OG you're talking about
the silver camp that's from our icy
collective here in the oak Oakland and
the Bay Area that's a plant that that's
a strain to develop that's actually a
femine
seed that was a chem dog feminized cross
with a silverback og which I've never
seen I've never seen the silverback og I
think that's what that's silver silver
chem is it's a it's a it's just a one
single plant from some feminized seeds
my friend made I see collective yeah
okay and so if you did I get this mail
what would be some of the other clone
Owen leaves you'd want to made it with
like what are some of your favorite
clonal is we kind of haven't talked
about that's a good question right there
well it's not very it's not very I don't
have a lot of favorites you know like I
really only smoke chem dog I smoked my
new one is my favorite one the chem
crushes turned that's what I've been
smoking all summer it's my favorite one
but after that it's chem dog and then
you know I'm going to experiment with
cross and with some of these feminized
seeds like taking some like for this
instance the silver cam and then there's
another one called the chem Scout I'm
definitely going to try that but I'm
gonna be really rich or a bit cautious
with that you know cuz I want out I'm
gonna be worried about Hermes although I
don't see any harm ease on those plants
I'm learning as I'm going here and I
understand that the community is
concerned about you know feminized seeds
in that regard you know so but that and
then you know the ultimate goal really
is to get the back cross the Kevin dog
back cross in the sim form that's really
what I'm shooting for so I can release
that to the public and say this for sure
100% in my is Kim dog you know whatever
it ends up being a back cross blah blah
blah and this came from a chem dog 90
wanna cut for sure you can guarantee it
there's no question mark about there's
no weird story behind where you're gonna
find out later on they don't have that
that's exactly what is I think that's
what the public is would like to have
and I and I think certainly by the time
I get this thing where I want it to be
that's gonna be the demand I think so
that's you know to to name off a bunch
of strains I have a bunch but I don't
really know where I'm gonna go with that
so I can't really tell you yet you know
what I mean
yeah no problem and so um kind of the
inspiration to start all of this did
that kind of get lit up when you kind of
notice that um some of the older people
from the overgrown forums for example
we're getting more active in the same
like for example we've seen Oregon kid
and mr. Sol they're both getting things
slash have gotten things back underway
was that kind of a bit of a catalyst for
you to think iock now is the time for me
to get my head in the seed game
absolutely yeah i it's it's it's it's
interesting to me like the the
possibilities are endless and I I see
that it kind of clicked with me and you
know I just feel like that it's it's
just the next step for me it's something
that I can contribute back and and
that's what I want to do you know and
and I feel like I've you know I can I've
got the growing of cannabis down I can
it's it's it's like a machine you know
there's not much more I can do to tweak
it I mean of course there's always gonna
be some new things that come along new
technologies I would guess and things
like that but it's there's really not
much room for me to grow in that area
I'm getting what I want from that and
and I just want to take it to the next
step and see what I can do you know I've
got the tools and like I said you know I
have to you know a bunch of years after
two decades of doing this I I can see
when this is leading me in a direction
you know ya know and I've gotten I've
gotten the signs that that's where this
is going and I'm just kind of going with
the flow I feel like I feel like
genetics when I was a kid in the early
eighties I feel like genetics the
old-school genetics I feel like they
were in some ways a lot better than what
we had these days and I don't know if
that's perception necessarily but it
definitely is my perception and I don't
know that's all it is but I would like
to get things more isolated again and
that's that's for my more my
contribution to do it to be is to get
things more isolated so that you know
you know when people in you know
whatever people in the next state that
legalizes wants to grow their six plants
or whatever their big brother allows
them to grow I want them to be able to
like not have to spend 20 years or ten
years or five years
trying to find what they're looking for
you know they should be able to get what
they want you know they should be they
they know what they like they like og
cush they would they want to get that
they like that flavor they know what
they're looking for you know and so I
want to get that I want to I would like
to try to get that to the point where
we're isolating things back you know I
want to get those skunks back those
skunk smells back there I think they're
missing I don't think that we're really
there's big notes when I feel like
someone shows me what they are talking
about skunk and I'm using this
countenance example because I think that
we all when we were young I think that
was all you know our favorite we do we
kind buds that we fell in love with you
know and but I don't smell that
specifically anymore when I smell when
I'm out in the world checking total
plants out beautiful pot not saying it's
not great strange super high THC and
those things are great but I also think
we need to isolate those flavors and
those smells back out so we don't lose
them forever and they're still in there
they're in there and it's if you work
hard enough I think and if you go
through enough of it I think you can
isolate and a lot of luck of work I
think that you can isolate those traits
back and we can we can reintroduce them
back to the population and and if people
want to get a muddy back up again that's
their that's their business they can do
that but you know I think that somewhere
it needs to be you know in other words
like taking those memories I have of
that mouth-watering cannabis that I
haven't seen in a while not to say like
I said that we don't have a lot of great
things these days because man people are
making some amazing things I've seen but
getting those things and I slid in the
back to where you know we can kind of
reset the button and start over and
start working them again and see what we
can do when we're not you know hiding in
our basements you know from from the Big
Brother you know what I mean and and at
each other even you know what I mean
yeah that makes sense but that's that's
kind of my vision that's kind of my goal
that's what I want to do and that's that
I hope and that's what I can my next
step can be in this kindness in this in
this process you know yeah well I mean
as someone from Australia who's in that
position of where Big Brother is kind of
looking at the possibility of letting us
do some things it's it's definitely
great to be able to have people like you
who are looking to kind of get things
back to kind of their true breeding
forms in that same kind of idea of how
things were better in the pie
if we go back to kind of the the Super
Skunk and where it originated from the
SSC do you think that like breeding was
so much better back then that like the
the clone that is now that it was the
Super Skunk that was just kind of a
common occurrence like if you got a
couple packs of SSC you would likely
find something that good or do you think
it was like a one-in-a-million thing
because these days to get a clone only
it's considered like one in a million
but back in the day people talk of SSC
for example as though like it was just a
common thing well yeah I do I think that
well I what my take on it is is that
when the man traveled around the world
and he collected all this stuff for our
enjoyment to to make his business and to
break that catwalk I think what he what
he was finding was what evolution you
know God knows the way I'd kind of the
way I look at would helps me kind of put
it in a visual pictures imagine going to
Afghanistan right and and during by the
way not to mention during the U at the
Soviet invasion and teaming and you know
kind of befriended like you know guys
who are hiding in a mountain or like
their life is war and their families are
producing hash and cannabis to survive
right and they are doing breeding their
breeding up there they're making seeds
for every year just like farmers have
been doing for thousands of years and
somehow this man you know befriends
these people to a point where he takes
into their village to their homes and to
their stash spot and they've given
things to take out into the world I mean
so I think that maybe just by default I
think that the people that were you know
we're all these original land race
strains or whatever you want to call my
think that the people who were
caretaking informed for god knows how
long their families have been taking
care of him for 100 years maybe who
knows you know for as long as you can
imagine I mean I went to Ireland want
someone to the Guinness Factory and you
know they showed us the vase we'll take
that I'm sorry the safe where they keep
their 30 string and it's the same thing
it's the same
we got a starter and they have the same
one going back to the beginning of the
Guinness brewery or to the last fire or
whatever and they keep it under
safekeeping you know and it's don't
their business and their you know people
all over the world drink Guinness beer
for whatever it's worth and it all comes
from that strain of yeast that they have
there at their at their facility so I
feel like I look at that the cannabis
went through the same thing it just
didn't have the benefits of of safes in
Dublin Ireland it had the benefits of
you know maybe arm you know dudes not
Afghanistan who you know we're trying to
keep their families fed and do something
that their fathers or mothers showed
them and grandfathers and others showed
them so I think that breeding had been
done it was just done differently wasn't
like on this fast-paced thing like
trying on everything you can and hope
now you catch the right thing
that were kind of caught up now it was
more of like you know this this village
and family was isolated from this family
in the Lord so maybe they just never
crossed their strains they just did the
families were working on their own thing
you know maybe they had products that
their own that whatever whoever powered
was working with her or consumed
themselves or selling it more likely and
making hash with it and selling it more
likely you know they were looking for
traits and so they were breeding you
know just like humans have learned how
to do for years so and I think that when
the world got smaller and everything got
moved around you know I think we did
what we would normally do we would try
to take two of our favorite things and
cross them together and make something
better and the results have been you
know they've been kind of hit or miss a
lot of myths you know so I think that
you know when we when I was young and
throughout my life you know I've smelled
cannabis tasted cannabis and there's
traits that I fell in love with and
that's imprinted in my head it's in
praying and my brain just like every
other you know pot head and you know I'm
I have those those things in there when
I come across like I talked about the
Beatrix choice earlier I actually that
friend that I'd befriended that I ran
back into in life lately he actually
gave that back to
and so I just took it down for the first
time and I'm trying to now I'm going
through files in my memory from 1992 was
the last time I smoked that stuff you
know I got a sack of it as I was going
up to Buffalo New York to this summer
tour and it was the last sack of it I
ever got was my favorite my favorite
weed when I was a kid growing up in
Virginia and now I'm just sitting there
going is it it I'm smelling it I'm
looking at it and it's got like a heavy
grape like artificial grape bubble gum
flavor to it which I love that excuse me
that uh just makes my mouth water I love
it you know having smoked the exes it's
drying right now but I'm smelling and
I'm like I sure [__] smoked great
bubblegum in here I sure [__] you know
it doesn't look like it to me but my
memory of what it looked like I just
don't have a very you know developed
memory that I have a more developed
memory of the flavor of it so I'm really
excited I can't wait to smoke it you
know what I mean so yeah that's kind of
an example I'm talking about it's taking
those those memories of those traits
where I formed the opinion that yeah
that was better than what we got today
and trying to like recreate that you
know just based off a memory because
that's what that's all I got
you know that's yeah I don't know if
it's gonna work out I guess the world I
mean you you have to tell me in me out
on that we'll see I hope so
so far so good don't worry I'm keen to
go out so be sure to let you know so did
you ever happen to have any run-ins with
the infamous roadkill skunk well Duke do
we call him Duke is that what we like to
call ya he's been talking about the
roadkill skunk and I never heard anyone
call anything particular gone Virginia
the roadkill skunk now we had like skunk
number one and then we had what what
they called the basic five if I recall
that was the heaviest gunk one the super
skunk and then we had Northern Lights
which the Northern Lights to me if I had
to say the Kemp like people compared the
chem dog to the og cush that and other
and ways and say they must be related I
don't really feel that way I don't feel
like I see I don't get the impression
there's a direct relationship between it
too
my buddy swears to God that the og cush
came from a bag of might like a bag
seeped out of one of my units years ago
and I laugh out of murders you might
hear that but I don't I just don't I
don't really feel that that they're that
connected but there's Northern Lights
that I used to smoke that came out from
the catalog I want to say Northern
Lights number five but I don't really
know if that's what it was we just
called it Northern Lights it had that
same color as the chem dog and it's had
that loud like molecule penetrating you
smell that the chem dog has so whenever
when I when I first smoked the Kim dog I
immediately that memory of that Northern
Lights popped up you know that we used
to smoke and so you know had that same
color
I don't even where else going with that
but what was your question again I'm
sorry did you ever get to run across the
road kill skunk no no I never actually
ran anything called roadkill skunk in my
life I have they do kind of turn me on
to that that term and he talks much
about it and he's told me a lot about it
you know and for the skunk's when I was
a kid that super skunk was at the very
top of the list mainly because you had
more exposure to it and then right after
that if you were lucky this the basic
skunk or there are the skunk five I
think is what they caught it and and
then there was a skunk number one which
was similar to this basic five or
whatever but those were pretty much the
skunk strains when I was that I've been
it's that I've been around exposed to
yeah no worries so if we keep with that
same theme of like kind of comparing
some of the older strange to some of the
new ones on your Instagram there was a
nice frosty looking photo of some Girl
Scout cookies but one of the hashtags
you use was hash tag yarn is this kind
of a bit of a reference to how you feel
about some of the new strains versus the
older ones do they stand up or the old
ones just crush them I think that I
think that I don't understand how the
Girl Scout cookie got so popular I
really know it to me I think I've peaked
it I've grown it and I've peaked it out
you know and my friend at IC collect if
he made the the Kim Scout which it got
really popular really quick especially
here in the Bay Area
he won a couple of it and stuff like
that
I like that one better of course it has
chem dog in it but it's really really
much more similar to the Girl Scout with
just a lot more just I want to say a lot
he's got a couple more notes of odor to
it and flavor too I just I just never
was impressed with that and I'm like I
think you I'm sure you know it's like
when I hit the streets here in
California just was like wow you know
like you know you were selling units
someone would could be so units like I'm
a wholesale market for say in California
they were getting like 22 to 26 but they
at there was a period a couple years ago
for two years even where the Girl Scout
was on that same market going for 35 and
I was like wow I can't wait to see this
stuff finally a great stream let's see
it you know because people show you
streams you know and you're like wow
it's real nice and then you pull out of
the psychic m'dog and they're like holy
[__] you know they're like wow that's
like ten times better than this earth
it's just so much better it's like you
know so I couldn't wait to see it and I
gotta be honest I was disappointed with
it it's not it's not my it's not that I
don't think it's good I understand it's
good I actually think it's great for the
daytime if you guys you know business
meetings or whatever people do in a day
time but i think that uh i don't where's
the taste where's the smell I don't
really get it you know I'm missing
something there you know I feel like
I've made up traits to justify keeping
in my life you know and that's that's
not what I'm going for that's a great
great example you know but yeah that's
exactly what there was it's like
whatever you know I don't get it you
know it's not but everyone's got their
own I respect and understand and clearly
seeing that everyone's got their own
opinions about these things and blue
dream it's another one so I I mean I'm
not gonna smoke that you know what I
mean I got I got so much space in my
lungs for smoke in my lifetime here
however long I get to be here and I'm
not gonna waste it on weed it doesn't
have a good taste to it you know I mean
just half and I smoke weed is the flavor
I love the flavor that's really the main
thing I get out of it you know yeah yeah
I can completely agree with that so I
guess just to be fair what would you say
are some of the downsides of the 91 then
like we've already brought up that she's
you know she's inconsistent and things
like
one thing that's commonly brought up is
she heard you know because a lot of
famous strains are born from that how
easy she'd actually heard me she like
any other strain where like you do need
to actually stress her she quite
temperamental I would say that like I
said the first time I grew it was in
1995 I think I think the first bit I
smoked was the first first week in June
the first week in January of 96 and I
found a seed in there and it was there
was no seed in the Super Skunk but there
was a seed in the UH and the chem dog
and I'm when I say a seat I'm saying
like there was like one or two or three
it was very and it was shocking because
I was learning at the town I was like oh
my god what did I do wrong
I explained to me everything about how
her bees happened you know everything we
knew at the time and I went through my
whole process - I got a lay leak in here
I mean what's going on do I have enough
air flows or really choking in you know
what's going on and it just I think I
had I think I had seeds in every single
and I'm saying like say you had five
pounds of weed you'd find five seeds you
know very very and then every now and
again you would see one bud that would
have just be I would say full seeds but
relatively speaking you know ten seeds
and bud and you're like holy [__] what
happened here and then you start you
know going through the whole thing and
see where else there and then you never
find another one
so I usually don't ever see the males
the the her me flowers I it's very rare
that I actually see the her me flowers
it's usually I see a seed which I'm
assuming there must have been a flower
at some point but I've tried to go
through and see if I could find them to
pick them off and I've certainly found
them in like dried flowers I've
definitely a few times I've found them
in there but it must happen real quick
and they must go away real quick as it's
really hard to see it happen you know
I've scoured them but uh the down points
on the chem dog you know I mean you
could get that don't know it depends you
know like you know if you get up in the
morning and you smoke em dog rosin or
dabs all day you know you're gonna
you're gonna have it's it's need to
personally that's kind of hard you know
what I mean like they had to have a life
and do that
that's really strong it's medicine and
I've had lots of patients telling me
that it you know people consume cannabis
because they wanna the wasting away
syndrome or they're having a heart you
know just or stressful or they're having
you know a lot of people in they get
stressed up they can't eat they lose
their appetite and they you know
cannabis helps with that I've had lots
of patients over the years telling me
that not only did this Kym dog help with
their appetite but they really felt that
it changed their metabolism and that
they were able to put more weight on
without eating much more food you know
what I mean that their body's metabolism
changed where it actually was converting
energy to you know to store so you know
I don't know that I don't say it's a
negative but that's it that's that's not
recreational you know when you move
people are you know seem a little heavy
on the front because they're smoking too
much chem dog but yeah as far as the
traits of the plant itself or the buds
go she looks like a [__] to trim I'm
just gonna say that it you know if you
get it right it's the worst thing I
don't like is the foxtail thing it's
doing that more the last few years than
it used to do it used to be more rounded
than what I write so you have one of
those rounded buds I try to get a
picture of it you know cuz it's tough
for some reason to get them like that
I'm like I always think I figure out
what I can do to make it so they're
consistently all that rounded top which
is just a lovely you know visually it's
just lovely when it turns out like that
but I say that like you know I've got it
down to the point where you know they're
minimal but I don't like that you know
and I wish that the one thing I've
noticed with the chem dog is that what
it's always done is that the it has this
funny thing like people will tell you oh
the chem dogs died day 79 you can let it
go further in fact when my friend gave
it to me he told me that you can let it
go forever but you can't you gotta take
it at some time so take it at day 63 and
that seemed like a pretty reasonable
thing to me it's like okay yeah that
makes sense this plant can keep on
getting butter the peak no one really
knows where the peak is well you know
now we know what the peak is because we
can test it but it turns out the peak is
ways
sooner way sooner as far as the THC
levels and oh the the white hairs you
know like so what the Kindle do is it'll
look perfect on day 48 right it'll look
perfect picture-perfect but obviously
that's not you know that's not you you
could take that and you got what 19% Tia
who knows I mean you're not gonna take
it right yeah so you're trying to get a
little closer to the peak and you keep
going and then after day 48 it does a
little Fox daily and then it puts out a
whole new set of white hairs right and I
don't like that I bugged me that's the
one thing I don't like about the Kindle
you really bugs me because you know I
would have a lot more pictures to share
the Kim dog I just can never get happy
with them because well cuz I'm weird and
I'm like you know I don't know I'm just
kind of weird about I want to look look
perfect you know yeah you're perfect
I mean you know you know I'm a control
freak for sure I think I think every
grower is a control freak event or
they're doing anyway because that's what
we're doing and but but yeah I don't
like that because it did visually it's
hard but by the end of the whole thing I
mean and you dry it you curate I mean
there's nothing like it I don't I don't
have I I personally haven't smoked
anything better than the chem dog or
stronger has a better flavor as she
stands today
you know that's my opinion but that's
the way I feel and you know the other
thing is like it's much harder to get
the giant chunk nugs than it used to be
certainly can do it you know certainly
can do it I just got to point 12 I don't
know if I'm allowed to say this but I
just got to point 12 pounds per a
thousand watt light and it was not
because I you know was grown trees it
was because you know the buds were
chunky really nice shaped and they came
out perfectly you know sounds really
good aural yeah yeah and you know when
and when you smoke it you know like you
know my fiance she smoked cannabis daily
for her for whatever reason she does and
you know we've got all kinds of weed
around here and that jar is always the
one that gets open I mean so she she's
not biased like me she didn't talk til
she met me so it's just that's just her
favor one I don't know to me it still
I hope that we have one day soon a
catalog of strains that are on that
level in my perception at that caliber
you know you know me and my buddy at IC
collective we were talking understand is
like a we don't only people who really
love the camcorder like what you know
because if you seems like it's sometimes
like arena bubble did we create a bubble
where this is the queen of all cannabis
and that's just what we think and we
think the whole world agrees with us and
and the wrong would you agree that there
has seemingly been more success breeding
the chem dog as her me then as with a
mile I mean I know it's kind of early
dies but it seems like whenever the chem
throws some pollen whatever it hits
turns to gold whereas whenever you hit
it with an act like for example that no
anyone with a male maybe not as
consistently producing really Stella
Klein's what do you think about that
that's what I've seen you know I've been
around a pretty extensive chem dog
feminizing object and you know
feminizing the chem dog hitting so many
different shades and they were all
winners I mean it was it was I I I don't
think that that's how it normally pans
out you know like like I said the silver
can to come Scout the sky the sky cam I
mean that's the Skywalker with it and
there was the cheese I mean then there
was needed that that sherbert he crosses
me every single one of those you know
randomly pick out five seeds out of a
huge bag Andrew single one of them you
could keep and does and the clubs that
sell the top shelf in California and the
Bay Area take it you know what I mean
so like yeah it looks like to me like
you know that has to be explored a
little bit more in further you know and
I don't really I don't like I said I I'm
not the one to be able to articulate the
community's opinion on feminized seats
you know I'm I had the jury's still out
on me I haven't seen any problems yeah
that's the thing I I'm wondering
what the because well I guess what I'm
saying is to me my understanding of the
perception of thieves is kind of a shaky
thing or some people are like against it
you know what I mean yeah I would agree
a lot of people seem to be against it
but I'm the same as you I haven't really
seen too many problems to be honest I
think a lot of the time people who don't
want to face their own growing problems
yeah I think that's that is definitely
you know I've seen when I first got the
candy for an example and I grew it like
I was doing things at the time and at
the time I was over feeding my plants
that was just where I was at in my
evolution you know I was the last person
to to use and my circles to try to use
any kind of salt mixtures you know and
uh spaces and I overdid it until I
understood you know what I think the
sweet spot is and I got [__] tons of her
me flowers on my candy right now I don't
get any Hermes you know I don't have any
Hermes there's no literally no Hermes on
the candy that I grew recently you know
so I'm using as an example that the
growing methods have a lot more to do
with that than I think people realize or
give good credit for you know yeah I
like I said you know I've been around
this this project and I'm watching it
unfold and I'm watching the seeds as
they where I'm talking I've been
watching it for three years now and and
watching the seeds come out and you know
the chem scout did we were suspicious
the kind of scout was creating some
hermie but you know the Kim dog was
always in there and that definitely
certainly for surely puts you know some
some Hermy banana types flowers out so
you know I never saw one on the Kim scow
and and and even then even in that case
we when I was helping my friend get to
the bottom of things we did find a
problem in a section of his groin that
could have been causing some extra
stress you know there was a hot spot in
the corner that wasn't getting the
proper airflow you know and I we know
for sure that could cause a plant to uh
to try to propagate itself you know so
yeah I haven't seen it is it clear it's
been like
why not you know but but but I think my
approach I'm gonna do both I'm gonna
because I think there's a lot of promise
there and I think you have way more
control and I think that in some aspects
you can you can actually go and get the
traits you're looking for a little
quicker than going through the
traditional methods yeah and and so I'm
gonna do both because I my goal like I
said I want that male or those couple of
males that you know is like Dennis's
yeast where that's okay this is where
this is our base right here from this
point everything either gets better or
it goes away it's not gonna we're not
gonna very eat for this I think as I'm
learning to breed and I'm learning you
know I'm learning out what it mean
really is just knowing the plan is I
think is we're bringing all this is
knowing the plant and being able to at
any point in the plant's life stages in
each age the plants life say you know
I'm feeling like this plants got this
trade or this trade of that trait you
know I think that's really what a good
breeder can do really you know I mean
what else is what else are you really
doing besides that you know yeah so in
order for that to be successful that you
got to really know the plant that you're
working with you got to really know it
you're not just met it but really know
it you know so I think for me what I
want to do is take that knowledge I have
my favorite strain the chem dog and and
put it in the seed form and oh and see
where it goes from there but make
hybrids and eventually release back
crosses with itself that are you know
cubed to the point where it's guaranteed
you're gonna get what you want you know
or the berries or the variation
yeah for sure so I guess kind of my
ultimate question in regards to the 91
in terms of both working and breeding
with it is do you think for this plant
specifically I think the answer might be
a little different for other plants but
do you think for the 91 working with it
is more of an art or a science because
it seems to not behave quite like the
regular plan in some aspects let me
think about our stairs and there do you
think yeah so do you think that like it
you can consistently get results from it
or do you think it's it's not the type
of thing where you can have your kind of
playbook and know if I do this it'll do
that do you think it's it's a bit
unpredictable in some ways I used to
think that and then as my understanding
of what I'm actually doing let whatever
method I'm using at that time I tried
different things at different times to I
don't always do the same thing you know
I definitely feel like I've got a you
know a process that is guaranteed to
produce what you want I don't really
have very much variation anymore from
crop to crop with chem dog in the
beginning what my friend told me about
the hit or miss and the Stars it
definitely was true but as time went on
in my understanding I want to say skills
that I don't really know if that word
applies to what I'm saying but those you
know learning from my experiences and
applying what I'm learning to what I'm
doing I think that just that kind of
went way it's very consistent now it's
consistent like I said you know I had
these new ones to kim crush i had you
know a sour band in there which is and I
had beatrix choice and some silver kam
on one side say half that and then on
the other half had chem dog and I
crushed it on the chem dog side you know
I got more of a yield on the chem dog
side you know yeah I got you know it's
always better pot to me so I'm not gonna
say that but you know it's very
consistent very nice you know it's
tricky it's very tricky planted it's
a-you know the nuts and bolts of it or
is it consumes itself at the end of its
life it really does and and you have to
let it do that because that's what it's
going to do anyway and you know time is
of the essence and you know this is just
the clock of the plant well it's hard to
watch you know it consumes itself you
know it takes every little bit of its
nutrient out of its body and eats it you
know and you can watch you do it it's
very interesting right next to it you're
like you know if you're the first time
you ever come walking into a grown
you're gonna go and without using your
nose okay you're gonna be like what the
hell happened those plants and then
these over here they're all Russian
green and stuff but you know the Kim dog
is just you know for whatever reason and
it does do that more
than used to going back to that question
you asked earlier about the changes it
does do that more like the best chem dog
I ever grew was organic and I think the
reason that was was big it is because
you're never ever really just running on
water you know when you're doing it that
with the method I use with that I always
had like this certainty I was making
this like I used to make so we didn't
call it compost tea we called it the bat
katieb of that bat and I had like you
see yeah like this net this is this was
the whole thing you know you take your
back Alana's a couple different kind you
know you take a seabird guano high fiber
Senor high phosphorus bat guano you put
in a little maxi crop you know you had a
little sugar and then you put one of
those not just an air bubbler in the
bottom but and these things were really
hard to get back then it was really hard
to find his but I would go find these
fish pond or I'm sorry these big
saltwater fish tank pumps where they
actually sucked the water up at a very
high volume bring it up to the top of
the pump head which is kind of hanging
on say like the edge of a trash can or
whatever you got the VAT you know and
mixes it with air and actually had a
tube going out of it I think it's just
like a I don't know what they call them
but and and the idea was it was creating
like a vigorous and a you know actually
sucking action so it's got its like
agitating the our waters agitating right
but it's adding air to it right this
thing when the power would go off this
would be the first thing the generator
would get though this would be the first
thing that I'd plug into the generator
was this pump right because when this
thing was Harmon and I would never use
more than half of it was the rule this
is all the stuff my friend originally
showed me this is all his tricks and it
man it was i got 72 ounces of chem dog
off with two 1000s on light tracks a
long time it was I I brought everybody
ID over to my house people drew from
four hours away to come see these buds
you know what I mean it was crazy you
know I would go every time I water my
plant so I would stick my hand into that
now would only you just sing once every
two weeks
right and and do a lot of table
dressings and I would take my hand and I
you know I'm an electrician I work with
my hand I'm always doing some sort of
physical project messin with tools I've
always got some sort of nick on my hand
always even right now and I would take
my hand I would stir it up and then by
the time I would be done by the time I'd
water my plants just with the with their
regular regiment the regular water that
little cut on my hand would be nice and
red and looking like it's already
infected just 20 minutes later you know
to me I'd be like all right tomorrow at
its ready you know and then I will only
use half of it no matter how I had to no
matter how much I had to spread it how
many plants I had to spread it over I
would never use more than half of it you
know and then I was held back up and I
was very careful of course to make sure
that the water was you know not letting
him chlorine or anything like that and
it were great and it was basically some
sort of compost tea action we were
getting with it you know but um but the
end consistency thing it doesn't really
happen anymore you know it just doesn't
it just it pretty much comes out say I'm
not saying it looks as pretty on day 56
as silver Kim does but it definitely
it's still my favorite man and a lot of
people around me it's their favorite
ones too you know
so yeah cool so if we keep on that same
topic of like our kind of technology in
the garden what are some updates what
are you running nowadays have you
converted over to our you know your nano
locks / kavita mm bulbs or are you still
a simple man with just your tents and
your HIDs no I'm usually not the
computers but I'm using the the
Hydrofarm what they called phantoms same
same double-ended yeah it's just a
different uh I didn't have you know the
reason I'm doing that is that they have
the right hood I guess you'd call it you
know the insert the reflector they have
the right reflector for my space so I
can't go up I can't raise like I would
need to for the good Vitas to get that
high over the canopy so I use the
southern was just a more open pattern
and then I put it on light movers just
because I mean why not you know yeah
seems to work good it takes the shadows
out I've always said I've always really
liked those things I got away from using
them I started off with them and and I
really liked them because you know it
you know you see some of these these I
don't really have the type of grower I
it's a small thing that I have and I
can't like cover the whole thing with
light there's gonna be an are way over
here there's gonna be a cabinet over
here so you know I used the light movers
to kind of try to compensate for that
lack of total coverage I've got you know
yeah so besides that you know I do
different things at different times you
know it depends on what it is you know
we do sometimes we're doing work and it
can sometimes you're doing a little
mostly some some custom salt mixes we've
got going on and you know just over the
course of the bunch of years you know
you just you some things work and some
things some things help you out some
things are just literally a waste of
money you know and uh and I've anybody
out there who's growing or learning I
did the only thing I could tell you is
less is more and keep it simple you know
because it's it's really it they call it
weed for a reason you don't really have
to do that much to it you know it's sick
it's got to give it a little food and
enough though no tell me what time it is
and that's pretty much it you know and
then I think that I think most of the
skill when it comes to growing cannabis
isn't what you feed what your plant your
your you know your regimen is or
whatever I think it's really on how you
train your plants on how you treat them
in an indoor situation especially I
think it's how you train your plants and
you know how you shape them I like to
sculpt them you know you have to get
them to where they're gonna bring you
the most for their little space that
they're gonna have with the idea that
that lights directly above them and not
to the side and you know it's not gonna
move from this point of sky as the
season changes it's always in the same
spot with that all taken into
consideration I think that that is the
thing that you can you know give
yourself better results with more than
anything else that I've seen you know I
don't really see you know people going
on using this now look what happens
wow I don't see that a lot I see people
use what they
comfortable with their their recipes and
their regiments you know they're you
know Duke who uses all kinds of stuff
over there he tells me things I'm like
you do what now I love these I love that
guys I've met him recently in life night
he struck him he's an interesting cat I
like and I like his attitude I love the
story and I can tell he's good people or
not but yeah he tells me some stuff I'm
like you do wrong and that sounds like
some how would eat [__] but I guess I
think it mostly has to do it with
remembering that you're in a sprint when
you're growing cannabis you're not in a
marathon you don't get today twice you
only get today once so if you didn't do
today we had to be done you don't get to
do it tomorrow you just missed it and
maybe you should jot it down and they
see them the next time you get a chance
to be sure you do it you know whatever
it is and and then along with that just
you know keep it simple and and like you
know watch your plants and see so you
see which way there's what they're
trying to tell you and you know they
respond quick you know they don't you
don't it's not like you have to wait
half your life to figure out what you
did work you know you get you know a
short period of time you're gonna find
out what your results are
and I don't beat keep your mind open and
uh and really look at everything you're
doing
you know don't turn your eyes away from
some things because you thought it
worked in the past you keep it all on
the table under you and try to make sure
that you're fine-tuning everything not
just one aspect like am i feeding my
plants the right thing I see so many
people that get caught up in that and I
just think it's like it's a dead end it
doesn't really matter that much really
you know you know you can use any of the
tools that are available to so we got so
many of them and if you learn how to use
them properly I would imagine that you
know you're gonna get good results if
everything else is working my god my
buddy said it's light air and water and
food that's it more complicated than
that I mean yeah so um for this next
part we just might move on to some kind
of less growing based questions some
kind of more cannabis scene slash
community related questions were you
quick to jump onto the as like a medical
or were you kind of a bit hesitant and
you just kind of did your own thing
without really engaging in the medical
community so much and furthermore do you
think that the kind of the medical scene
in America is working for the people in
general well me I I I'm kind of hardcore
about all that it when I when I went to
15 I remember one proposition 215 when
the petition was being passed around I
remember I went in front of this gross
Safeway or saw him and this guy asked me
for him to sign it and I said I said no
and he goes why not and he goes because
I think it should be legal for everybody
I don't think he should because I my
mind I was like you know and that was a
really foolish thing I was when I look
back that was so serious dumb youth
right there but that's that's how I felt
about it I was like you know it should
be legal for everybody and so when
proposition 215 happen I think we all no
matter what our feeling on it was I
think that the way that the proposition
was written I think it was amazing
because it was so basic and simple and
it was so vague that it could be
turpitude to mean basically that you
know there was no limits you know it was
just
I've not planned limits was just no
limitations to this the way they were so
masterfully vague you know so I think
that we all rejoice when that happened I
mean it was like I think it was amazing
moment and I don't think that me
personally I don't think I took it in
for what it was worked at the time and
the reason being is because I feel like
I just didn't believe it I just did not
believe that that's really how it was
you know until I was at a concert down
in the South Bay and we had a quite a
who's-who of people with cannabis came
to a suite we had there one night in
Santa Clara California and I think we're
either shoreline show and this is you
know this was just like in 2002 or three
this is much farther after Jerry died
you know this is our kids and everything
and we're all settled down but we're
anyways read this hotel and we're smoked
and it was definitely getting a little
hairy and my friend had just given me
this
this one of these hand-blown on a lathe
glass no glass pipe bongs you know like
though the ones that they spend on the
Lay's very nice piece you know yeah and
so we're that and then then we have a
the the guy with the bubble hash shows
up this is the first guy who ever showed
me bow ass he shows up and he's got his
throat melt and we're just smoking and
it's just one after another make sure
you know it's just being my buddy in the
room and the kids are in the back room
and it's separated we have a door it's
separating their sleep and then we get a
that knock at the door you know what I
mean crack crack like oh god sure enough
the police out there and someone had
complained you know we're you know we
come from a place where that's really
not that big a deal up in Sonoma County
I mean you can you can smoke weed pretty
much in public like you can in San
Francisco almost now right we're not
there we're in Santa Clara it's a much
more conservative place sure enough
there was some police at the door and
they opened the door and I went outside
and like we're coming in I'm like not
without a warrant we go through this
whole thing and next thing you know I'm
in handcuffs sitting on the floor and
they're search in the room they find
some pie they find a you know maybe a
scale or something like that it was
nothing much was but it was a big deal
of them you know yeah and they dressed
me and and and you know the next thing I
know I'm sitting you know later that
week I'm sitting in front of an attorney
and the first question she asked me is
so do you have your proposition 215 and
I'm like it was like the most
embarrassing moment of my life I think
practically I said no she's like well
and she's very professional she's like
what can i - do i and that was like it
hit me right then I was like this is a
real thing like I'm sitting from an
attorney that I just paid money and her
question to me is why don't you have
your 2:15 like I'm paying her to ask me
like well what a fool I am you know what
I mean and I mean I got a little pot
plants and I got it you know my garden
of course then I got a couple of outdoor
in the garden up at the house you know
and at the time and I don't know I feel
like a fool so this was like in you know
proposition 215 was in 1996 Malia and
and I didn't get my medical until I was
in 1999 so I was good three years later
and that's how it happened she basically
you know it was like you know you need
to go see a doctor and you know Michael
I don't really I'm not sick and she look
you don't understand how it works it's
not you don't have to be sick do you use
it for anything besides like you just
get stoned S or no I mean I mean you
know traffic irritates me I smoke weed
you know and like life gets to us and
she goes that's that's a reason that's
it right there go see a doctor and to me
it was such an alien idea so I went saw
the doctor II talked I mean he was like
you know he asked me all the questions
how much do you smoke we slowed the
floor
and I tell him and then I suddenly felt
like a patient you know and I was like
so legit then we took all this to the to
the you know we she did her thing you
know I don't we didn't go to court or
anything and you know they they ended up
dropping the charges and all that kind
of stuff so that's how it happened for
me it was you know I've you know in my
my years traveling around the Grateful
Dead and everything else associated that
we we learned how to survive in the
shadows in America you know and and I
kind of got comfortable there and I
think that I think even those things are
you know as we're recreations come
online here in America I think I'm still
dealing with that a little bit because
sometimes I see what people are doing
out there I'm like God dang man you guys
are over the top and I know what they're
actually really successful and they're
putting their dreams together because
they came out of the shadows to do that
and I just I struggle with that you know
so I think that when I that's it took me
a while to get my medical because of
that so and I think as far as medical in
America I want to say yes but I don't I
I don't know if I have the whole view on
that because of my lack of really
understanding completely what's how CBD
works and how it helps people with
various things and not just my lack of
understanding of just in general so my
answer would be that it would be great
if we would just open this up and and uh
in America here and and and try to
figure out what is helping people in a
in situations a B and C and
try to understand it because you know
that's how I I think that you know I
just want to see everything from a
science-based
point of view when it comes to the
medical side of cannabis like what
exactly does this help but being careful
with you know we're getting pretty far
away in America here I'm just
remembering that it's just a [__]
plant you know like you know everyone's
so hype hyped up on yeah yeah regulating
tax the cannabis you know producer like
you put an alcohol producer and you know
I and then that brings up that same kind
of militant attitude I have me it's like
it's not like alcohol it's a plant it's
different it's like it's more like
velarium or it's more like you know you
know it's more like an herb or something
it's not like alcohol I'll call this
poison you know I mean yeah you know I
like glass along with it I don't want it
to get and if and if and since we're
already on this road because you know
reality is reality since we're on this
road where we're gonna regulate it taxed
like alcohol that's the phrase that
people are comfortable with okay well
then treat me like you know treat me
like a small brewery treat me like a
winery or something you know don't treat
me like I'm making meth or something
you're making like you know oxycodone in
my basement you know to me like treat me
like I'm making out that's what you're
gonna do and let me have the same rights
as those people do because they got
pulling your right side I'm looking why
in the country I see about what they get
away with you know what I mean and or
you know just let people leave would be
like it's a tomato plant you know which
is the way I would prefer if they were
just even long let let the market sort
itself out you know yeah sorry so I was
gonna say so what are some of the the
pitfalls that other countries could
learn from America like surely there
were some things that happened after
legalization which in retrospect you
realize we're negatives but maybe
initially you thought they were
positives like what what should we be on
the lookout for I was a good question
well
see I guess the one that we asked that
that comes to mind is uh dispensaries I
mean that's just that's just part of the
fabric now as part of the see now but in
the beginning and even the people who
wrote proposition 215 that's exactly
what they didn't want you know they knew
that if we allowed if if we allow people
to so you know cannabis in like a
dispensary situation that's exactly
where the federal government would get
involved right there you know right when
you do that transaction that they would
have a problem with that you know and
they never intended and actually my
doctor was in the room when they were
brainstorming 2:15 and he explained list
I mean he said that uh you know we never
intent we never saw that happening we
assumed that then when he said when I
say we am talking like I'm family he
said we never thought that that would
happen we thought that as soon as that
happened and we that the feds will shut
it down and that wouldn't be a problem
and that we would be left with is you
know farmers market type things
exchanges and and but mainly everyone
having the right to grow their own pot
you know that was really the main goal
so I think that you know as when
legalization happens the you know did
that they weren't being realistic in my
opinion because you know not everybody
can grow the wrong you know I mean
that's just that most people can't
they're on the space they don't have the
physical capabilities especially if
they're a medical patient they don't
have they don't they don't want to learn
their skill just to get something
they've been using the whole life you
know what I mean just because the law
says that's what you have to do now but
I think as when legalization happens in
places where it's beginning to happen
and hasn't even gotten this far like
maybe where you're at or anywhere else I
think just keeping an eye on that you
know making sure that the structure of
how cannabis gets from the grower to the
end-user just making sure that that's
done right and don't don't let any
because that's where all the shady shady
characters have popped into this
industry you know in my opinion I think
that that the lure and and that whole
infrastructure and apparatus is allow
people who really just want to end for
the money that's given them the door and
you know you know they've controlled
that basically gave them the keys to the
market you know they decide how much pot
costs you know and I don't really think
that's I don't think that could have
been we've gotten away with it here and
it went okay but I think that part could
be definitely organized better as it's
growing in a place where marijuana is
become legal you know I mean yeah for
sure so I'm just touching back on a
point you made earlier on in terms of
how you were saying we need to figure
out whether it's you know maybe the THC
or the CBD for example which is actually
giving the medicinal benefit on your
just in your personal experience and I
know you mentioned earlier your fiance
uses for medical reasons do you find
that the high THC strains are actually
for the most people the most effective
because what we're seeing in Australia
for example is that there's a big push
to tell people that CBD is what's the
benefit out of marijuana and that THC is
just this recreational side component
that you don't really need you know like
do you feel like that's a total
misrepresentation absolutely I think
that there's no possible way that anyone
could purpose and tell you exactly what
any given individual whether it be a kid
with seizures or someone who's going
through chemo what they're getting what
in cannabis is giving them the benefit I
think that it's an entourage effect I
think is what we agree to the phrase we
agree on you know I think that there's
simply and now with the introduction of
you know I was breaking all the terpenes
and isolating them all out understanding
that like these are powerful powerful
substances terpenes terpenoids and and
we and now we're trying to fit that into
the puzzle so we started off with the
taking the THC out you know you got yeah
I mean I don't know anybody who's ever
used marinol been raving about it you
know so that's not what it was and then
then the CBD and you think oh man we
just saved the whole world of CBD and
now that's turning out not to be the
case when we isolate it and give that to
people certainly helps with certain
things I mean there's there's some other
great
I'm not cover or probably even aware of
but I think that the whole plant
concentrated or just the whole plant
consumed I think seems to be the
universal you know kind of helps with
everything if you know what I mean like
it seems to me that the people who have
the access to the high tea and see stuff
they seem to be the ones that rave the
most me in my experience from what I
hear my perception to me about the
benefits that they're getting from it
you know what I mean yeah
yeah cuz only I think that I think that
that's a big misconception I think the
THC is a very important part of it I
think that you go back to what I said I
think that you know these things need to
be broken down in a scientific way and
understood before we start telling
anybody anything about what you know
what I mean in the meantime millions of
people are having positive effects on
their life and smoking cannabis so they
should in the meantime while the
government catches up to a society which
is basically what we're waiting for is
you know just the other day in the
United States I'm sure you know that the
DEA after a bunch of fan for the summer
they decided and and I gotta say like
how do how did what my democracy turn
into a place where some bureaucracy
decides what's dangerous and what's not
isn't that I mean couldn't we at least
have a vote on that in Congress or
something but yeah you know this that's
labor rat and they just denied they just
you know almost in a joke you know came
out and said that they still think that
there's zero medical benefit to this and
they're gonna keep it remain they're
gonna keep it under schedule one you
know as opposed to schedule two which
would be a recognition cocaine isn't
scheduled to you know yeah they think
that that has a medical benefit as
whereas cannabis doesn't along with
heroin and PC and LSD for instance you
know I mean it's
we're so our research and our main and
especially our government is is keeping
this stuff moving at such a pace I don't
know if we'll ever know what what the
deal is with cannabis and and what it's
trying to help us with and and what the
what the the goal is here with that
plant you know and and really break it
apart I mean here in America
that's what we're good at I mean I feel
like that's what we've been always like
we take something and we get down to the
bottom of it scientifically we always
have in the past that's what we like to
take tell ourselves when we when we look
at our history you know like we've got
we put the man on the moon we figured it
out you know and so you know I would
love to see us go in that direction I
just don't see it happening and you know
for obvious reasons because it's more
profitable right now to cage humans than
it is to you know take less meditate
take people's medicine cabinets and
empty em and and putting a plan in there
instead you know for many many different
things is so for some reason it makes
more sense to society right now
officially to demonize this and
continuously put people in cages and
lawyers and judges and kernel clerks and
the whole the whole thing and you know I
just don't think that I like Florida
comes to mind the way to what they're
doing in Florida when you talk about the
CBD thing that they're trying there's a
lot of states where and at the beginning
it was a warm fuzzy thing oh we're gonna
have CBD like South Carolina for all
places that you can you can have CBD oil
there you can even import it into the
state I understand my family some of my
family lives there it's like and it's
like the most backwards conservative
place and then Florida and Georgia and
to me it's like they're jumping the gun
I understand what they're doing and I
respect that they're trying to help you
know I think that that when a when a
small child is having seizures and is
having a horrible life it compels even
these guys who can't see past their own
biases towards this plant they can see
past it just enough to help those people
but they're making laws you know and
those laws will have to be changed
they're gonna have to be you know
rearranged they're gonna have to be you
know revisited it sometime in the future
as a science comes out so and I just
think yeah be cautious with that you
know because we don't really know you
know THC is it's powerful medicine and
you know it's it's our bodies receives
it well so it's got to be something to
it right yeah so do you think that um
for new countries that are just kind of
writing their own legislation
think that the most important thing to
maintain is that you need to be able to
grow your own medicine or do you think
that you know it's maybe okay to forgo
that right just to be able to say get it
from say a mass supplier because just
for it to give some context to this
question Australia currently the model
proposed is looking like you won't be
able to grow it yourself but you know
some big Philip Morris and tobacco
conglomerate will probably be producing
a ton of it do you think that we should
compromise for that or they at the end
of the day growing your own needs to be
the end goal I think that well and
you're saying that they're talking about
doing this in a medical aspect not
recreational yes no recreational only
medical yeah I I and as I get older I'm
more this way I truly believe that
self-reliance is is one of the highest
of human qualities you know like growing
around food making sure that your your
location the place where you call home
that's good clean source of water and
figuring out how to make it clean if
it's not clean and growing your own
cannabis as part of that so I I can't
see it any other way I cannot I you know
companies that you're speaking of like
that not just feel remorse and those
types of comments but even like just
bigger companies that provide things
that people use every day in life safe
food and things like this I'm to me it's
really important to get away from all
that and to find more local sources and
and more importantly produce things that
you can for yourself you know because I
think that I just think that if we all
do that life the Machine slows down to
the point where we can maybe have a
sustainable spaceship here on earth
you know and that if if people spent
more time trying to take care of their
more basic needs on their own not like
oh no you've got to take care of that
not in a mean way but like as in this is
what I'm you know this is what we want
our society to be like people you know
families take being self-reliant you
know and learning how to like be healthy
and
feed themselves without help from the
companies the corporations and the
government and all that so with that in
mind there's no other way for me to
think about I I really think that
cannabis plan is no different than the
tomato plant and they you should be able
to grow either one it's just something
you're consuming you know what I mean
all right with that being said yeah like
I said before not everybody's gonna be
able to do that various reasons and I
think that you have to have that right
to do that though I feel like you have
to you have to it's just a plant and and
by the way if you have a system where
you're not allowed to grow but you can
buy it from whatever people are still
gonna grow so what did you really
accomplish you know I mean you just made
some more laws you just you just and
without even trying you just made some
more penalties for people in life you
know cuz people are still gonna grow
their own pot you know I can I can get
you know [__] I don't even know we're
trying to think of a good example eggs
right I can get eggs from the factory
farm at the state ethics store but I
have my own chickens and I get my
excellent chicken so I can eat GMO free
eggs you know what I'm saying I should
have well right you know I shouldn't
have to be forced to go deal with some
company that has different values of me
you know yeah exactly
so if we just kind of sorry going I was
just say I think that's really important
actually I think that's really important
to fight against that in it and I think
that they're they're just at one little
addition to what I was saying I don't
think that you should make that
compromise I really don't I think that
you know here in California 2010 we had
a legalization thing I think it was
called proposition 10 or 20 or something
I can't remember but it failed and it
failed because it was wrong it in
legalized cannabis but it also created
other laws that more penalties for
things that people were doing like for
instance there was uh there was some
sort of clause in there where you had to
have your you know your cannabis there
was extra there was new penalties for
for people who had children or children
around their cannabis grows or a
cannabis situation in some way and it
lost you know it surprisingly lost
because you know the voters of
California look took all this into
account and many people in California
girl Canada
says you know and it failed because you
know we couldn't make those compromises
just to have legalization we just
couldn't do that now here again with a
um a proposition 64 coming in November
you know it's not doing so well in the
community because people are having the
same kind of questions or like does this
protect the small growers or not and and
in the answers are really unclear so you
go to where the money is and who the
backers are and it gets even more
unclear so now we don't know and I do
see you know to your point of the
question that you know there is a
compromise that has to be made I mean
you have to like you know you use going
to be a compromiser it's gonna be
winners just gonna be losers right you
don't want to see new penalties and I
think that anything that says you can't
grow is a terrible idea because it's you
really you're really just creating more
criminals when you do that you know if
you can't grow plants you're creating
environment whether it's criminals you
know and when I say criminals I mean
dudes like me I ain't a criminal but you
know people who were breaking the law
you know what I mean yeah and so this is
kind of a little bit of left field
question but I wanted to ask what's your
thoughts on the concentration community
and maybe the possible kind of negative
impact they have on our image in our
last episode Duke reference that you
know some of the people who are you know
really heavily on to concentrates these
days more resemble crack addicts than
marijuana users do you think that that's
potentially like a negative thing or do
you think on the whole we should just
try to push the stoner image and make it
more mainstream I know you're saying
about the image and I think it's kind of
I think it's kind of funny too I it's
big it's gotten big it's kind of hard to
I don't even know how to put my whole
opinion on this yet I don't think I've
even formal opinion but I think that you
know it it's that's that's not going
away I can tell you that much you might
get more refined in better processes and
and standards but it's not going away
that's definitely popular thing you know
I I smoked the rosin I really like that
and that's it's not because of Vernie
it's not like I'm
tie solvent or anything like that it's
just I really love it goes back to being
self-reliant you know I mean like I
don't have time to make hash hole or
anything like that no I don't really
have a desire to I've messed around with
it and it's not that interesting to me
really like I feel like the ceiling of
what captivates my imagination about
learning something new I hit it really
quick it was like oh okay and so Rosen
it's like a self-reliant thinking I love
the fact that I can take my favorite
strain you said it's smoking someone
else's trim that's been made into a
concentrate right or even luckily if
you're lucky enough smoking they're
fresh frozen live resin I think they
call it they've made into the contrary
which I love that stuff you know yeah
and there's amazing products coming out
they're just mind-boggling it's like wow
this tastes so good how did you do this
and then but I love the fact that I can
just take one of my own buds
stick it in some paper and smoosh it and
then do a debt because I really like the
ritual of doing a dab I enjoy that it's
something I've learned I enjoy night I
don't like smoke I really have a really
strong I feel like I have a really
strong sense of smell and smoke even
cannabis like it a grenades me it really
I had allergies in the spring and so I
got like a sensitive I feel like a
respiratory system and smoking anything
is not my favorite thing to do you know
I mean so now I'm not saying I want to
eat because I don't like eating cannabis
as much as I like the instant smoking
the instant effect I like that
instantaneous effect so I feel like it's
it's it satisfies me in the way because
it's self it's just so for lying like I
I have everything I need right in my
kitchen just to quickly make up a DAB
and I think it tastes great I love it
and you know it's not you know and
people who were hearing us who make dabs
or slabs are gonna go oh god not the
rosin because it's so they're so hard on
it but it's actually you know it's
pretty damn good and uh you know I get
to smoke the flavors I want to smoke
instead of settling for some other
strain that somebody else you know did
it with and I get to slow you know Kim
dog you know so but thus far as the
image goes you know it doesn't look good
but it's definitely so mainstream now
that I think that
the public's perception of its changing
and it doesn't look as bad as it did
three years ago as long as people don't
blow up houses continuously that which a
lot of us can go yeah so in terms of all
the recent breed is kind of coming out
of the Woodworks what's your feelings on
this and I guess more specifically how
do you feel about kind of companies
using the chem dog name as a way of you
know trying to boost their product you
know do you think it's like you know do
you ever want to call these people out
or do you just think like look the end
of the day everyone's always going to
try to say they've got like you know
quote the highest quality ingredients in
their product and you know by the
natural extension people are going to
lie and say the chem dog is the real kam
dogs used in their strain when maybe
it's not or heck I've even seen strains
that don't even have chem dog in it and
they've got like chem dog references in
the name oh yeah yeah I got you know
yeah there's some there's some companies
that have used that name and they've
really done well with it you know you
mentioned earlier and I can think of one
other one and when I first saw that when
I first came out of the shadows and you
know looked at an Instagram or you know
went to one of the we'd carnivals as
Duke calls it you know I I was shocked I
was blown away I was like oh my god I
was like man these people will say
anything they're just lying it's not
even it's not even close to true and
then the stories you know like when I
you know I got back on the internet in
2012 you know you know some people asked
me that what you know some of the same
questions you asked me about the Kim dog
and then they're like that's not what I
heard and I'm like you know I'm telling
you about my life bro not repeating some
story that I heard at somebody's house
or whatever I'm telling you what
happened in my life dude this is the to
please understand that you know so I was
really frustrated first know when my
friend showed me the picture on the
package that was definitely my picture I
was like you gotta be kidding me I was
like this is nuts it's like a
free-for-all
but you know and of course it made me
feel a certain kind of way and it was
like you know I was angry about it I
liked it I was like that's not right man
I've put my [__] blood sweat and
freedom on the line for this [__] I
don't want to be [__] you know I
don't want to see someone making
trillion dollars off of
I you know but you know at the end of
the day I'm not really it's not my mo to
go around calling people out on their
thing like I said it will all be sitting
around you know at a table so to speak
you know figuratively speaking and we
all got stories and your stories either
a [__] lie or you really you really
put your heart and soul into this and I
put my heart and soul into this and I
still to this day so like you know I
don't like it but it's a waste of my
energy to go around and police that or
whatever you know what I mean like I I'm
just gonna you know what I wanted when
you when you described the situation you
are my the only answer is just to go
blow blow them out of the water you know
what I mean you know like you got the
chem dog no you don't look good I mean
how many times does that happen where
you like you smoke a joint someone tells
you can dog here like here dudes hit
this instead and they're like what is
this you're like it's the chem dog bro
you know that's the chem dog I don't
know why you just smoothly left the
killed oh so that's kinda what I'm
saying it's like you know do your thing
and make you make it happen
and and if you just tell the truth man
you know like live live live by the
golden rule and then you don't have to
lie you don't have to make up a [__]
weird story for everyone to believe you
know just you can just tell the people
the truth if you lived your life right
away you know what I'm saying yeah I
think you know I think in the end it's
all it's all gonna sort itself out are
those people crushing it they are there
definitely are will they be crushing it
five years from now I don't know but you
know I just think that you know I think
that the truth in the end of the day you
know is it's what people are interested
in you know they don't want to hear the
[__] a lot you know I mean there's
some of these people we've talked about
you know I mean I'm not here to talk
[__] about anyway but some of them you
know some of them you know they [__]
played and Lily lied and known about it
and and they've gotten really successful
and I practically famous for some of the
you know for their company whatever
their thing is in their lie or whatever
and I think it just sorts itself out end
of the day you know I really do I think
if you're a customer say some dude and
like you know Illinois and you know you
want to get some
or something are you gonna go that guy
that's got funny reputation for her me
seeds and doesn't really can't really
tell you exactly where he got this the
the stuff he says he got you know I mean
are you gonna go where you know you
definitely know this dude is like been
doing this for whatever you're probably
gonna if you want the chem dog you're
gonna go where you know the chem dog
came from you know what I mean yeah I
guess yeah no don't worry
people will there be an exodus episode
so this is a kind of a last extended
response question then we've got some
kind of more short answer ones so it's a
bit light-hearted when when talking to
people about chem dog and all the
different varieties what do you find is
the part that gets confused the most is
it the fact that there's you know
there's the D the three the four the 91
and and people just confuse the names or
do you think like it's all the different
aspects of the history which people
confuse more so like what what do you
find kind of maybe it's not frustrating
but when you're trying to talk to people
about it what do you find gets kind of
you have to correct the most the volume
of it there's just so much [__] that
it's hard it's almost tiring to hear you
know let me think
I was just gonna say if you if we
actually look at Leafly at the Mona
which is kind of you know the go-to
website for people to look up strains it
says that chem 91 was a strain created
from the original chem dog cross to
skunk I mean I understand that don't
they have like a big joke about them
saying that the Sour Diesel is an indica
or a hybrid and they say it's a sativa
and iha is trying to get them to make it
a hybrid yeah yeah that guy so I guess
there already are like kind of then been
notable for getting things wrong yeah so
I feel like they're they're getting
their own kind of reputation in a way
they're kind of making their own
reputation they should probably check
their sources i remember remember that
canna bible do you remember that book
that was coming out of California that
was yeah you know they had they had the
chem dog story wrong in there anyway
we're you're talking about a coffee
table book you can pick up and I mean
I'm looking at right now it's oh my my
fiance is uh it's on her bookshelf
right now and they got the chem dog
store
I think that it's I think it's it would
have been more useful if people would
have taken their first-hand knowledge
and spread that around as opposed to the
story they want to believe or the best
version they heard or however they came
to these things I think it would have
been more useful to the whole community
if they would have just used the
first-hand knowledge and maybe now as we
move forward and people can come out of
the shadows a little bit more who
actually you know know what's up do you
know that were there then maybe that
will sort of fix itself too but I I find
it it doesn't it used to be used to
bother me more than it does now now it
to me it's a slight it's more
entertained than anything you're like
what you know well it's it's like it
goes back to the truth is way more
interesting than fiction it always it I
mean it's true like the best craziest
stories you've ever heard are true
stories you know and it's the same thing
it's like why why do you gotta make up a
story there's the original distort what
actually happened it's so mind-blowing
ly interesting when you look at the
different the coincidences and the
chance happening the chance meetings and
just like the once-in-a-lifetime events
you know like how could that have even
happen that's so much more interesting
than you know what everybody's opinion
about business I can't tell you like how
I felt when someone questioned my story
when I when I finally told it to him
they asked me and they and they uh any
question like directly but they were
like well what I heard was this it's
like I just told you like I said before
I just told you without why are you
trying to tell me that verse and then my
one of my favorite one was when the chem
dog was being passed on that hold Jew
Joe Jade Joe brand thing happened and
that faint chem dog that whatever that
was it to me I think it was a res dog
Sour Diesel I think is what it was and
uh it was a chunky Sour Diesel I saw a
lot of it cuz like I said I had to go
around and give a lot of bad news that
summer and oh you know I would I would
people that were I don't want to say
close to me but people that were in my
outer circles you know I would come in
contact with them people who I was
well enough to talk about this stuff
with they go look I got the chem dog
check it out and then you go this is not
the chem dog and then then you have to
give them a little bit of background
about how you know that of course right
yeah this is the chem I know this is not
the Kin dog because of a B and C you
know like some of the things we've
talked about and then they still call it
kim dog it's like dude you literally got
right from the horse's mouth
we're told the dis is my chem dog and
but and for some reason I mean give it
another name
just name it something else now you know
I'd make soaked them up man you know but
that's not the kim dog that was really
that broke me down because those were
some hard days for me because i'm
telling you man like talk about units
and where they got to go man like hi
boys the kim dog has always been my
thing so if there's some sort of
confusion there man it really hit me
hard you know what i mean yeah it was
frustrating
no one point where I was like what do I
you have this plant for you know what I
mean oh my let me I mean I know I had it
but as far as the other things are like
you know besides smoking it know like
what am i banging my head against this
wall for if you know what I mean you
know so there's other stories and stuff
you know I hear I'm gonna and I and I
try to try to see like where they got
how this do you know like when you're in
kindergarten and you pass a secret
around the room and the story's
different when it gets back over here I
try to figure out how did that story get
to be that way and sometimes I'm like I
think someone just made this up this
sounds like a bunch of [__] to me I
don't know and it's always always less
interesting than the truth there's no
doubt about that I haven't had one story
that was like wow let's just change the
story to that that's way cooler yeah
okay so for the last little bit it's
just some kind of light-hearted
questions so the first one being if you
could go to one place on earth at any
time you know presumably to collect some
landrace seeds where would you go and
what era the era that would be hard I
would say I would say I would like to go
to the Hindu Kush region in Afghanistan
the high the high mountains of
Afghanistan and
and see what they had up there cuz
that's that's my favorite that's the
cannabis that speaks to me the most you
know I would have liked to have been I
there's a legend that uh the skunk was
found in in the wild you know in the
Ohio River Valley somewhere in Kentucky
or Ohio and I would have loved to have
been there when that happened you know
when not necessarily in the wild as
legend goes but knew that it was uh that
the people that that had it that passed
it on that's what they found it and that
that there that the legend that they
were going off was that the Native
Americans there had been working with it
and they there was a sacred plant to
them I would love him known for that
see and they're the streets that moment
when that whole realization you know
happened and and then when I looked at
the catalog and I see the man standing
in the you know like bunker in front of
all the hash and and I'm looking around
and I'm and I hey like you got this
white dude you know and and he's like
standing there with like these you know
these these soldiers warriors you know
the family men the Warriors fighting the
the the Soviet empire and somehow some
way this guy gains enough trust to go
and look at the big hedge - you know
look at the spot when they're keeping
all the hash you know that be I mean
that's that couldn't imagine a more
powerful moment than that as far as
Garrett was because I mean that's just
that's some that's some serious
networking that's before email yeah I
mean that's just like how did that
happen that's amazing what a
contribution you know yeah I could only
hope that um one day I'd be out of chat
to Neville about how that'll happen and
hopefully he'd share so everybody know
where he's at
yeah he's um he's currently in Australia
so not too far from me but unfortunately
he's actually battling some cancer at
the moment so I'm not too confident he'd
be kind of up to feeling out to doing it
interview but I'm you know we obviously
send our best wishes to him yeah you
know I like what's out there for sure
because to me that guy he made the
biggest contribution to contemporary
cannabis that there were there won't be
a bigger contributed contribution than
that you know just collecting all that
working
and and giving it to the world and to
heat it in the height of the drug war
was just I mean thank you you know he
only yeah he certainly I mean him in I
think shanti barber was also done you
know some comparable amount of work but
yeah i think they definitely have done a
lot especially in terms of like just
laying the groundwork for future people
if nothing else yeah i mean certainly
something to shoot for you know no doubt
about it
yep so on to our next question this one
more you might have to struggle about it
cuz i think you might want to give more
than one but if you could only change
one thing about the 91 what would it be
i would want it to go back I would
it's last I thought talking notes it's
lost a note or two on the flavor since I
got it I would like there was this deep
dark dark earthy flavor that you get it
but it's it's diminished somewhat and I
would like for that to come back and but
overall without going back to something
that maybe was lost with it I don't know
I would it's hard for me to say cuz it's
a it's you know I would like it to be
more you know chunky and you know the
shape to be a little bit tighter on the
tops and the edges like we were talking
about earlier you know I wished uh I
don't think it's the prettiest spot in
the world you know I don't think it is
so I would say that you know I think
that on all the things we judge cannabis
on I think that's probably gets more
attention that deserves the look of it
you know yeah but uh opposed to the
flavor and the smell and of course the
drug traits but I would say that that
would be the one thing that I would want
to look look just looked a little bit
nicer you know like more shaped more
shaped buds and more uniform on that yes
okay so when you I'm a big I'm a big fan
of the chem dog i there's not it doesn't
help answer because i really don't see
how you can make something much more
better than that you know yeah yeah I
understand
so um so when you do get the seed
company up and running I know that
you've obviously got
and personal goals to get done have you
however considered possibly doing a
collab with someone have you ever
thought like I'd love to get my own
stuff going and then you know like Dukes
got some cool stuff going on maybe we
could do a collab or something
absolutely yeah
Dukes actually he's uh he's really
inspired me when it comes to the to the
breeding like he's opened my eyes to the
different possibilities with it you know
and it's really kind of inspired me so
you know I would certainly be interested
in doing that absolutely I think that
those kinds of things are gonna that's
where the real magic is gonna happen
when people with their own views get
together and make something like
basically a new thing you know like I
think that's where a lot of the mag's
gonna happen I look forward to that you
know as we go down the road here yes
awesome so what do you think are some of
the most overhyped / worst Raelians
you've ever had / you know biggest
disappointments oh no you're gonna
you're gonna hate the answer the Kim D
was definitely my I don't really I'm not
impressed with that one I'm just not I
don't get it
it is very medicinal I will say I it's
really good for anxiety the people who
are the patients that I'm in contact
with they Kim dog is is Kim dog can
actually if if you're if you're not in
every user Kim dog can actually make
anxiety worse and in the short term it's
just really strong but that they can the
Kim D have noticed that the patients
that I'm in contact with who have
anxiety problems which is you know
you're talking sixty percent of the
patients you come to that's they're
understandably they're emmaus they're
their number one concern with their
health you know was regards the cannabis
is their anxiety and that one really
does seem to help because it's I don't
really know where it comes out on the
THC scale and of course you know I don't
think THC like we were talking earlier
is the whole picture I think this dr. oz
you know you could have a strong THC and
not have a real psychedelic type of
cannabis like say the can of the chem
dog can be to people so I don't know how
that's tied and for some reason my fee
back from people is that it's really
good for anxiety to me it's just
disappointing I don't like that smell
you know when you got people describing
Kim Kim D smell as rotting meat garlic
it's like I've had a description a lot
yeah I'm just like why I don't
understand that one but but then of
course I smoked something smells like
you know fuel to people some people
smell fuel and I don't really quite get
that but I I kind of understand it but I
think that the fuel you know
characteristics that come from cans I
feel like the fuel I think that kind of
comes more from the name but actually I
don't really know if people smell diesel
when they're smelling it and I don't I
don't I don't smell that you know so I
guess it would be a pinion thing but as
far as other strains that was really
disappointing that I grew they were
mostly there were mostly things that I'm
not so sure they were worth what they
said they were there was a master push
that I got so and that was nothing good
and then and that cherry pie that I got
I liked it I loved it but it did it put
it put ball sacks out early in the
flowering and it was a problem for me I
didn't I didn't enjoy that you know
because it I didn't really have much
control over it and going through with
this style that I was growing picking
through that was kind of tough um trying
to think I don't know some of my
favorites that are outside of the chem
dog family were like the super Silver
Haze I really enjoyed that one and that
was kind of out of my zone of what I
like you know what I prefer a cannabis
that was kind of outside of it and I
still liked it a lot yeah that's pretty
much I you know I I think that as far as
growers go that I've been doing it as
long as I've been I feel like I've
probably grown less strains and most of
those people have you know I'm saying I
could the actual count of different
strains I think is smaller for me when I
hold it against you because you had the
best weed on earth I love it I just what
I meant I got lucky you know
but so I don't really have me there's
not many there's definitely something I
haven't met the cut like there's
definitely been some some that I'd felt
like I had enough space enough to keep
but um you know we'll see I don't really
have too many to say on that one really
yeah they can't be I really I really
don't love that one as I much as people
do and I I gotta say I really don't get
it and I'm not speaking bad about it I'm
hoping that it'll dawn on me at one
point and I'm keeping it for breeding
because I I think that there's it does
carry its traits to pretty dense heavy
I've actually seen some crosses that
were supposedly done with Kennedy that
more chem dog notes came out of then say
the chem D itself had so I'm keeping it
around this time for for that reason I
don't know if we can work something out
with it you know yeah that would be that
on that list for that answer okay so
would you ever consider putting any
feminized lines yourself oh yeah
absolutely
I'm gonna go stand before I'm gonna I'm
gonna go take both roads on this I'm
gonna do I I was all about it and then
as I got more around the the breeders
and the breeder are the people who are
buying the stuff for the readers and
what their opinions are just kind of
looking I like I said I got this
negative that I had this feeling that
there was like a negative thing from the
community on it but to me it's just to
me it's just like you know I yeah you
got to you know what I mean so yeah I'm
gonna check that I think for some people
that's see sorry going I was just gonna
say I think that you just have to do the
proper testing and yeah I don't think I
think when we started if you got a rough
finish that says I think what I've
learned in this is that you can't just
give seats to people out and call that
testing and get feedback I think that
that's useful but maybe I'm wrong but it
might I'm starting to get the feeling
you got to do your own testing like if
you really are looking for what you're
looking for you gotta be the one looking
for it you know what I mean
yeah we certainly say that with the
likes of Brothers Grimm and swamp boy
seeds now doing all in-house testing
just kind of bringing us to
same point of what the people kind of
want and talk about we often hear this
talk about people saying you know like
we need to return to our land race roots
do you have any kind of plans to to work
with land races and say the cam dog for
example or is your plans more so to kind
of stay with more mainstream things and
not necessarily looking to reinvent the
wheel governor look in the reinvent will
as long as you know I'm trying to I want
to see I would like to have a catalogue
of things that are available that that
remind me of of the strains that I
smoked when I was a kid the Nigerians
and half the the Afghan crosses and you
know all those things that we were
smoking out of the catalogue when I was
a young man I I want to get all that
variety of flavor back into it I do
think even with the highest the highest
quality strains that are out now they're
all so similar they're also you know let
me half of them are over G crosses you
know the half of them there's some sort
of variation on og cush you know and and
I think we need a little bit of more
variety on that and that's on that level
of quality if you know what I mean
not just more variety but more variety
on that level of quality where like
instead of having Kim dog and og or and
whatever other ones that would fall into
that category maybe if we had another
handful of flavors that you know like a
skunk you know like I don't know a lot
of people I can't say I can't say the
last time I smoked a isolated skunk
strain you know like I really can't tell
you the last time I really smoked a good
quality one you know yeah and I think if
there's I think it's like everything
everything people keep running to one
thing everyone runs to one thing at the
same time all the time I think and so we
keep getting we're kind of running
around in the same circle I think at
this point you know we've got all these
different pushes and they're all great I
mean and there are differences and same
thing with the chem dog crosses that
we've been making it you know they're
they're they're very similar to the chem
dog but they are different you know like
the chem crush it's it's uh it's it it's
funny because the thing I like about it
is that
it it does bring back that dark deep
earthy tone it I do taste it in there
and it really inspires me because I feel
like hey this is possible though jeans
are dirt that there's genetics they're
still in there somewhere we just got to
get them an isolate and stabilize them
you know and and I think it could be
done you know I feel like we have
everything you know everything our
disposal to get this done you know so
that's what I want that's what I want to
see I don't want to read that's the way
I don't think I don't think I'm even
able to I think that I I just want to I
want to do what I'm able to do what I
think I'm able to do is is to find those
traits that I love that I think that
everyone really loves and isolate them
you know cuz I I have a the one thing I
feel like I've got going for me in this
and davier is that I have those memories
I have those memories of those smells
and those flavors I can tell the
difference between the Suttles of what
we have now and the hints of those
things and the actual thing I can tell
the difference it's kind of uh I don't
know it's like reading or riding a bike
or something like it's in there you know
like the Beatrix choice like I told you
earlier so that's what I want to do
that's what I think my most interesting
you not intervene or reinventing the
world but you know bringing back the old
school stuff you know yeah for sure
so what's your opinions on organic
Vasanth etic you know I think you've
kind of already hinted that you're more
of a bottled nutrient guy do you think
it's just like a preference thing or do
you think one kind of is better than the
other I think that one is better for the
other in certain environments if if in a
perfect world everything I grew be
organic everything I eats organic you
know I don't put funny products in my
body in my in my head you know Tim
health-conscious kind of person and like
I said I was the last person in my
circles to grow with bottled nutrients
you know to even try it I was so against
it I was like there's no boss I was
having moderately at the time very good
success at the time at today's bar of
what success is I don't know because I
I didn't I didn't put myself up against
that but I think that when you're
growing indoors and you're growing
organic you're still growing with Bala
nutrients aren't you I mean I don't see
a lot of people like creating their own
compost and bringing it in and that's
truly what organic growing is when
you're growing with organics you're
you're not just using products that just
came from the earth I mean they mined
minerals out of caves in Jamaica right
but they mined bat guano off the side of
a cliff where bat we're I'm sorry bird
guano off the side of a cliff where
birds migrate to to breed you know
themselves you know it's it's
destructive in a different way so as I
got older and my view the world got
bigger I realized there wasn't much
difference that the difference is that I
was holding on to weren't real it wasn't
like one was more ecologically conscious
than the other so then you're left with
you you're your own health which one's
healthier and then after that I would
say you're talking about flavors and
variations in the quality of the product
and when you're growing indoors the
reality is is that it's a sprint it's
not a marathon it's a sprint things have
to happen now it moves quick the plants
life cycle is extremely quick and
growing in organic indoors it can be
done in a file you see people have
really good success with it and then you
see people a lot of people grow on it
organic and you're like well you think
you're having really good success that
but honestly this shit's burning my
throat
it tastes my heart and I must be missing
something because that's not what it was
supposed to do and so I think it's like
I said if I'm growing in if I was doing
a like depth it would be organic I
wouldn't I wouldn't use though and it
would be for various reasons one one
being because I can I can bring compost
into that situation the other reason is
because you know actually growing
organic on a large scale I think is
actually more cost-effective you know
yeah I certainly think so in terms of
the cost-effectiveness on larger scales
yeah so I think that when you're
controlling the environment like you are
an indoor growing room where you have
complete control over every
err like water food I think your you
have to be realistic about the plants
demands which are gonna be I know this
doesn't make sense they're gonna be
higher and on the endure situation as
far as like potential goes in my opinion
and there's plenty of people are gonna
disagree with this but I think your
potentials higher and that you had your
with as far as what you're feeding your
plants you're really just playing
catch-up to what everything else is
providing you know know the sun's night
the Sun is way brighter than your grow
eggs but this the sun's not sitting
right over top of the plan is perfect
situation all all day long either you
know what I mean it's there's a lot more
variations the temperature is always the
same
so the potential in my opinion for
quality is higher so you're really just
trying to keep up with that potential
when it comes to what you're feeding
your plants and and then going back to
the fact that I don't think you're
really growing organic unless you're you
know you're making compost and you know
like I used to grow in peat moss with
organic but the back like I was telling
you earlier but that's really hydroponic
growing you know that suppose it was a
lifeless medium you know and I'm feeding
a little life into it every every once
in a while but you know I don't know it
was amazing I mean it did quality was
amazing and I often ask myself once you
give that a shot but you know the life
life moves at the speed of light around
here in California and you're kind of
just doing what you do and I really like
the product that I come up with it's
super smooth and high flavor and it
gives me everything I want so but I
definitely want to check it out on
experimental little bit more bring back
some of those old methods I had and take
what I know now and apply it and see
what else I can come up with you know
what I'm saying yeah for sure and so on
to the next question kind of tying in to
that what would be kind of the biggest
mistake you see people making in growing
or maybe another way to put it would be
what would be your tip for people
growing you know do you know for example
Dukes he always sees people over
watering what's your kind of take on
things
well it's one thing I see a lot of is
that when people find a problem they
come at it like they're they bum rush it
you know like they and then it ends that
the problem might get slapped but they
didn't learn anything you could come in
a problem with like an arsenal of things
and methods and try this and that amay
there's all kinds of [__] people try I
mean blows me away he'll make sprays out
of tobacco for God's sakes I mean I
could sound that sounds ludicrous to me
so and and instead of just take your
time do your research think about what
you're doing and and like try to stay on
point with the problem don't just try to
come out with everything because if it
happens again guess what you're gonna
have to come up with everything because
you don't know what you actually did to
fix it you know I'm saying so I would
say that that would be the thing I see
that happens the most is that people
panic when there's something goes wrong
and instead of just taking their time
and just breaking it apart plan ahead
make sure you're not gonna hurt lose you
know like a strain or something like
that I could genetic or something but
you know figure out what the problem is
and fix it and then then they throw at
Robins again you can just fix it you
know so that's what I would say about
that yeah what specifically I think you
wanted something more specific
specifically I think people over feed
their plants way too much organic or
otherwise I see people like it's just
throwing money down the drain you know
yeah yeah I see that alone as well
actually so what in your opinion is the
worst thing to happen to the American
cannabis community since the
medicalization happened so like one
example would be kind of the new laws
being proposed in California you know
you'd be well aware of this you know a
lot of people are kind of saying that
there are step back in a lot of ways you
know what is your what do you think is
the worst thing to happen since
legalization worse things happened since
to medical legalization well I don't
like how this I don't like how the the
grower the small-time grower is just
pushed around you know as far as like
what the what the product goes to market
for I really think that that it's
unfortunate that the person who's
producing the product that everyone's
you know interested in right now is the
one that you know oftentimes is the one
that's working the hardest to make a
living and I think that it's there's a
lot of factors that have caused that and
I don't think that's the worst part you
know I think that I wish that we were
lived in a situation where growers could
kind to unionize or create like
associations where we agree on
you know what's fair and what's not fair
for all of us and then and then apply
that to the market you know I wish there
was more of that and I think that you
know you basically got growers competing
with each other trying to get their
product to market and you know everyone
who came to the cannabis industry lately
has taken a huge advantage of that and
you know I've watched families you know
struggle for years on end doing what
they want to do and I feel like with all
the risk to take and and the and all the
work and it's a lot of work you know
this I mean anyone will sue this knows
it's a lot of work grown canvases know
nothing easy about it it's a lot of work
you know if you want to come out right
it's a lot of work and I see families
that you know good good people good
families that work really hard and they
struggle because they're they're at the
mercy of this of this dynamic in the
market where it's like I'm not saying
that you know cannabis should be priced
at this or whatever like that I'm just
saying that they have no control over it
and I think that's unfortunate and at
the end of the season or you know yeah
at the end of the season especially
because those are the ones that really
get hit you know they end up competing
with each other like in a cup for a
banner and I and I think legalization
had a lot to do with that and I'm not
really sure why but it definitely seemed
to have gone hand in hand it's got to do
with the dispensaries and it also has to
do with the fact that everything's more
on top of the table now so it's easier
for people to take advantage of that you
know yeah like shop around for the best
prices and everyone will pass this on
for less
yeah just so they can feed their
families and keep the lights on you know
I mean you keep to keep the roof over
their head and I just I don't like that
it bums me out but I mean I guess
everything in life's like that I guess
you know so yeah that certainly does
seem like a negative so kind of bringing
us to our last question what do you
think is the best way for a kind of
emerging cannabis medical community to
develop you know do you think that we
shouldn't go gun ho on trying to
legalize everything do you think you
know what what would be your advice just
you know take things slow look to find
the best clones first you know I mean
there's a whole variety of answers I
think that I think the whole term
medical is kind of I think it's kind of
a it implies something that we got to be
careful with because when you start
talking going back to the here in the
United States the DA to de 8 deciding to
keep cannabis as a Schedule one drug on
the flip side of that if they try if
they chose to keep that as a schedule 2
drug right with medical benefit well
that sounds rosy that sounds great
that's what we always wanted the problem
with that is is that all that really
means is that you know this is the
United States of course you know but all
that really means is that the DEA can
give universities research institutes
basically pharmaceutical companies
permission to work with cannabis to
research it so they can develop their
own products right so it's a the medical
thing itself is still common if you
think because if you start if we start
talented this is actual medicine well I
mean I'm not allowed to make tylenol in
my house I'm not allowed to make
oxycodone or or statin drugs in my house
there's a company that's only allowed to
do that and they're allowed to do that
because the DEA gives them permission to
do that so we have to be careful with
that because you know that's in one way
it's an open door it's also another door
that can close on us pretty quickly you
know I mean if we're not careful and
they could say whoa buddy I mean you
know whiskey's easy to get but you're
not allowed to make that and if you are
you certainly are not allowed to sell it
you know what I mean you got to be very
careful if you decide to make that and I
know we're talking about two different
things but but but it's for
medical only whiskey's not a medical
anything that's the same that's
regulated in the same way only certain
people who've gone through certain hoops
can produce something like whiskey or
oxycodone or statin drugs or whatever
they are that they give people you know
so it's a it's a it's a dicey thing I
mean it's definitely a backdoor it's
like I used to always tell people it's
like they kept the front door closed for
so long and let achill marijuana it's
just us coming through the back door now
we're just in the living room what are
we gonna do now but you know that door
can be closed too based on the term
medical you know so cannabis is a plant
and and it definitely gives people
benefits and I wish that instead of
trying to isolate okay what does
cannabis help people with and I wish
that society would just accept that
cannabis just over helps people overall
with their hope health you know what I
mean in many different ways there's not
one particular way so you know it's kind
of like what would be another thing like
that I mean you know we all agree that
vitamin C is good for store that's not
really good but like eating fruits and
vegetables is it's a the same thing oh
it's a good thing it's healthy for you
some people juice vegetables to cure
cancer some people you know consume mass
amounts of CBD have you know cured
cancer so I mean you know they're not
gonna start regulating you know
cold-pressed vegetable juice just
because you get some great benefits and
I could start regulating that like
alcohol or tobacco or anything so you
know it's got to be careful because
we're inviting I think that we don't
have no choice that regulations coming
and it's gonna be really unfair there's
gonna be in some aspects there's gonna
be winners and losers and I I wish that
we could get around that and just
legalize it as a plan say hey you know
what we have you go around the farmers
market you can buy some broccoli the guy
next door it's got some cannabis for
sale I wish it could be like that but I
know it's not going to because we've
already gone so far down this road and
and so that's about it I think medical
you gotta be careful with it's a
double-edged sword you know I think you
know now today it's rosy but I think in
a few years they can shut the door again
on us if they want if they give
the pharmaceutical company yeah okay so
I think that that um kind of brings us
to the end of things actually was there
any shoutouts or general comments you
wanted to make no not really I can't
imagine it was uh this was this looked
pretty good and it was good to talk to
you and I appreciate it
awesome so yeah everyone needs to keep
their eye for I think you said early
next year they'll be able to get their
hands on some chem crush was it that's
that's that's that's definitely one of
them that's kind of just something I'm
finding along the way onto the end goal
the thing that the vision is is when I
when the release happens there's gonna
be four or five decent hybrids with
strange that people are already probably
in love with and and then what I cross
with the chem dog mail that I've
developed that I really feel like I
could stand behind that's pretty much
what it's gonna be so and yeah I think I
think that you know things have sped up
a lot quicker and I thought like I I got
into this a little late I decided to do
some of these things a little late and
uh and I got a little lucky I think I
jumped ahead a little further with some
luck so yeah
maybe January or February I think we
might actually have some December to
early so I would I was hoping for
December at their mock-up in Sonoma
County but uh we'll see probably
sometime in early next year awesome
well everyone needs to keep their eyes
out of that for that and yeah just
thanks so much for taking the time to
come on the podcast and chat with a
skunk be a yeah come check out the
histogram we got the skunk underscore VA
you know with that sign in front of it
and you can see some yet there's a world
where people are doing this will go
along here see some awesome chem 91
photos that sync so much
[Music]
so there you have it thanks so much
again to our guests gunk VA keep an eye
out for lucky dog seeds and 420
Australia see you
[Music]