foreign
[Music]
welcome to the next episode of the
podcast you're joined as always by your
boy heavy days here from the upside down
Library bringing you all that inside
information but guess what we couldn't
do it without our amazing sponsors huge
shout out to CT now number one seed bank
in the game all the best breeders all
the best genetics and the latest drops
if you're not satisfied at the end of
your Harvest hit them up they'll sort
you out best in the industry CT now
thank you so much
but in order to be able to properly
evaluate the crop you got to make sure
you have a good harvest free of pests
and contamination and for that you need
to check out the good people at coppet
biological systems these guys have all
the latest and greatest predators and
Technology to ensure that your garden is
Happy thriving pathogen and pest free if
you got spider mites check out the
spydex vital with proof of predation
technology built in they turn orange in
front of your eyes to show you that
they're killing bugs what more could you
want well you've got Alpha to check out
the acuparem another killer product both
of these specifically designed for
cannabis products gonna help you to have
the most successful Harvest to date
there's nothing better than knowing that
Garden is free of pathogens guys get on
it you won't regret it
likewise huge shout out to our friends
at promix you've known them and loved
them for years they make the most killer
mediums in the game already inoculated
with micros trichoderma mycorizer but
guess what now you can get their
Standalone pro-mix connects a mycorrizal
product design to improve the yields
increase the resin increase the weight
turkeys flavonoids all of it's going to
the Moon
don't do your Gardener disservice by not
using a high quality mycorizer products
truly the best in the game guaranteed
score viability is going to improve your
crop no second thoughts about it produce
connect thank you so much get on board
guys it's gonna make a huge difference
finally shout out to our friends at
Charlie's cannabis you know I mean you
love them oklahoma-based better known
producing some of the most fire top
shelf commercially available cannabis
you've ever seen they've recently
started making their own missiles you
will not believe the quality of these
products Fino hunted from scratch using
new exciting genetics all in-house any
products you get from the uses of
material they've grown none of this pass
into a million hand stuff made from trim
from God knows who's grow everything
in-house high quality Charlie's cannabis
just remember guys Charlie's new Birds
finally a huge shout out to the patreon
gang you are the lifeblood of the show
you guys helped to ensure the episodes
continue to be made if you want early
access to content you want to hear
unheard interviews get access to
exclusive giveaways prizes Discord so
much more go check out the patreon
www.patreon.com
[Music]
welcome back to part two of our chat
with Todd McCormick of AGC Co
hope you're excited to get back into it
[Music]
let's do it
speaking of that joint you're obviously
aware you're quite lucky to be smoking
original Haze you know not many people
are able to say they've had that I guess
the question is how would you describe
it like how do you describe the effect
what's the flavors you get and um do you
think it's the sort of thing that's for
everyone or it's only for a certain type
of smoker
um I think if more people had access to
it they would really enjoy it uh it's
spicy it's like uh an incense almost
it's a not really sweet but it has Sweet
Tones but
um the high is really energetic I mean
the part I like about it is if I smoke
Haze in the morning it really
invigorates me to want to go do the
dishes you know get to work you know
jump on my tasks uh I don't really know
what it is because I've tested it like I
I I've tested Haze and tested OG Kush
and I would have thought the OG Kush was
more potent than the than the haze but
the OG Kush that I grew that time I
think came back like 21.66 and the haze
that I tested was at like 24.9 and I was
just like and I and they were growing
same soil same system same same same
everything
um all by me so
you know you don't I don't know I don't
know like it's not just the THC in a way
that's that's something in the Synergy
of the terpenes uh and the terpenes
played this really important role
um Skunk Man Sam uses a really good
analogy that when you get high it's like
getting into an airplane when you get
into that airplane the cannabinoids are
the engines that bring you up to your
height and then the terpenes are the
Rudders that that will shape the flow of
it the softness of your Landing the
whole thing and without the terpenes the
cannabinoids don't really feel as good
and anybody listening to this can can
actually uh try it themselves they
literally could take a good bud smoke
half of it leave it on the coffee table
for a couple days let it dry up all the
cannabinoids are still present but the
terpenes will have been lost and when
the terpenes are lost it won't have the
same high it won't have the same taste
it won't have the same flavor and it
changes even though all the cannabinoids
are still there so I think it really
shows that there's this true importance
on when it comes to the Synergy between
the terpenes and the modulation that
they create with the cannabinoids so I
urge more people especially the ones
that buy my seeds to start selecting uh
on organoleptic testing rather than
analytical testing because at the end of
the day the machine's not the one buying
the weed you know it's the human so if
if something doesn't really
you know have that Allure to it you're
gonna pass on it and I think that a lot
of breeders are going to find out that
the Market's going to drive the product
towards the quality that the market can
get so you know it's going to be about a
fact more than it's about bag appeal or
anything else and or about more than a
name more than anything you know when I
started selling pot when I was 12
everybody would always ask me what's it
like you know is what's this one like
and it's
it's like it's a little different to
everybody but the haze is really not
narcotic uh more Spacey more of that
like you get high you get high and you
get high some more and you get forgetful
and you get Giddy and you're like
looking for the ice cream and I don't
know it's it's the fun high uh the
Northern Lights is more heavy more like
whoa you know like more go sit in the
hot tub and grab the remote control and
relax or go to bed early like that more
narcotic like effect and um
so the haze to me is
I don't know I think more people are
gonna love it and I think more people
are gonna breed with it I've sold quite
a few seeds in the last two and a half
years of it and um I'm hoping more and
more and more people start introducing
it into their uh crosses because it's
been kind of long enough now about two
seasons since I offered it in 2019 that
people have been able to know you know
grow it and work with it
so I personally think we're going to
start seeing more and more of it
um you know my kind of my joke when I
started doing this was I want to Haze
the world
you know that would be cool to see for
sure and it's something that I noticed
about the photos you'd post on your
Instagram was that the buds were sort of
a lot more plump and I guess just fatter
than I was expecting I think in a lot of
people's minds like myself you imagine
sort of like you're gonna get one tiny
piddly little joint per Branch I guess
the question arises do you think maybe
it yields more than what people expect
or it is very much like what
no it blew my mind uh that's a great
that's great you know I I actually
hesitated to post all the variations of
photos I was getting from the variety
because some of them look so unlike what
people think Hayes is and they get set
in their mind there's an old quote that
I used to write into all of the Emperors
no clothes books that I used to give
away and there's hundreds of them and it
was by Daniel borenstein and the quote
is the greatest obstacle to Discovery is
not ignorance it is the illusion of
knowledge
and I used to write that in all the
books because I felt it summarized the
message we were putting out about
cannabis being in Shroud and lies that
only the noble could see and that was
the whole mission of The Emperor's no
clothes for those people listening the
book was named the emperor is no clothes
from the the Fable The Emperor's New
Clothes where the emperor was sold cloth
that only the noble could see and Jack
felt that cannabis was in shrouded in
lies that only the noble could see and
he named the book The Emperor wears no
clothes because it was really anyone who
looked at this would see that it really
wasn't what they protected to be so
that said
um
I feel as if a lot of people have these
uh pre-existing Notions about original
Haze and because they haven't had
experience with the variety uh only
hybrids of the variety for the most part
uh they really don't know what it's like
and I I say to people that uh original
Haze and skunk one are like Polar
Opposites uh skunk one is a relatively
true reading super uniform super
consistent uh original hay seeds are
like inbred F God knows what at this
point you know I asked Sam he's like who
knows f11 who knows and how many
generations of times he's brought them
together but he was doing so because he
wanted to maintain the variety within
the variety so that he could come
through it phenotype wise and pick
things to work with
um which makes pure sense to me and uh
when I grow them out I found phenotypes
that go from literally eight nine weeks
that are I would say mid uh like leaflet
but back again I've grown a greenhouse
micro fairly big plants I mean I I
posted so no light sleeves that were so
gigantic biggest I've ever seen in all
my years growing uh this last run with
Northern Lights Number Two it was also
the one that morphed into looking like
Duck's foot but the more I research it
Duck's foot has a narrower more like
dare I say sativa but I hate to but a
more narrow leaflet um and this one was
just plain fat is just ridiculous so um
but
the haze itself has a lot of variation
and you get everything from these like
16 week narrow narrow narrow leaflet
very few florets on the on the on the
stem to stuff that's pretty beefy uh one
of the females out of the entire
Greenhouse turned purple and it wasn't
because it was cold my Greenhouse has
completely environmentally controlled
and I was just like damn and I had Rob
Clark here visiting during the Harvest
and he was down there taking photos and
just enjoying the [ __ ] out of it because
you know this he was he went to the
University of Santa Cruz in the 70s he
was around the he used to trim Haze when
he was in college like he's closer to
this than any of us really and I don't
doubt he had his hands in making the
seeds that I was given because he worked
at the time at you know and he was in
charge of the greenhouses so he knew
exactly what I was growing because I
don't doubt he made the seeds with with
Skunk Man Sam so uh he was just having a
blast and when he saw the purple when he
was the one that was like oh this is you
know people used to love this one
because it had like a silvery kind of
purplish to it you see color expressions
in them um start to come out
um I I love it and uh I had Mishka hair
you know who used to be Neville's
girlfriend a little bit and she was
sitting at my desk and we were talking
about the origin of haze and I I sold
her straight up I said it's not with
Neville it's with Sam it's with Santa
Cruz I says come downstairs and touch
these plants they were not in flower at
the time and you tell me what they are
and me and Mishka went downstairs and
she touched the plants and she
immediately smelled it went oh yeah yeah
and I was like right I got these from
the same person Neville did
you know is there any surprise because I
guess Scentsy named a variety that has
Haze in it after Michigan in the last
few years so that's what she was
wondering about this and she was the one
that showed me uh she gave me a pre-copy
of a book before uh it was released and
it has the interview at Neville and it's
interesting because in the interview
Neville
isn't listening to himself because in it
he says that you couldn't improve A's by
breeding it together that's what Sam
told him so the only way Sam would know
that you can't improve it by breeding it
together is if he did it
so when Neville was talking about these
seeds from 1969
the original siege that I have are from
that 1969 cross that Sam kept isolated
from all his other work and reproduced
as that 69 cross the seeds or the plants
I believe that's that Neville was given
to male plants in 1987. those came from
these original Haze seeds from one of
those Generations you get what I'm
saying so the the seeds I got from Sam
were also from that IBL preservation and
are basically brothers and sisters
cousins sort of of those original seeds
that go all the way back
um and
you know they they kind of are what they
are if that makes sense you know and and
what I find unique about the original
Haze is out of everything in my
collection they are the only seeds that
I have that have no Afghan influence in
them
um yeah that's that's a really
interesting point to make and you sort
of touch on the broader topic of the
genetics within the strains we discuss
and there's a lot of for a long time I
used to hear people talk about Haze as
though it wasn't until the tie was
crossed into it at the end that it truly
became Haze and then in more recent
discussions with people in the know I
realize that that obviously wasn't quite
correct because a lot of people talk
about Haze as like the real Colombian
Rich sort of psychedelic high that those
cultivars bring to it all I guess what
I'm wondering is at what point did you
think it was Haze do you think the
commonly discussed Indian genetics are
actually in there at all and finally
what are your thoughts on the different
phenos you just reference you know the
blue the silver the purple were they
were they real things or was it just
potluck uh according to skunk band Sam
the original hitters was a three-way
Colombian combination uh that was based
around three different there was
controversa which meant red basically uh
and then there was a silver and I think
a blue and uh and I sucked for some
Stone right now
tell me the same damn answer every time
but uh but at three-way Colombian and um
and every single year what kind of
ruined Hayes and by the mid 70s they had
outcrossed that 1969 first hybrid uh so
many times that it really wasn't hazy
anymore uh it had a Mexican crossed with
it it had Thai cross with it every
single year was a different outcross
because they were trying to improve it
um and you know by 76 77 according this
company and Sam they gave up growing it
because he introduced skunk one which
was two-thirds tropical one-third Afghan
uh Colombian golden Acapulco Gold but it
was coming down late August early
September and it changed the game I mean
and you know if you're a commercial
Cropper you gotta wait until November
December to get down what you could be
pulling down at the beginning of
September same location there's no
there's no question so they didn't want
to expose themselves to get busted and
they started switching over to this
amazing [ __ ] weed that was some van
Sams and they stopped growing Haze and
by the late 70s Hayes was was nothing
but a legend on a lot of levels in the
genetics world but lost
even by the people who originally held
them because they didn't preserve them
like Sam did
yeah wow that's so interesting I had
another question sort of similar but I
think you sort of answered already where
I was going to ask you about the photos
we see on your Instagram where it's like
Hayes cross to tie and I guess I was
sort of wondering like is that an extra
tire Cross or sounds like it's the first
one I don't have a Thai cross I don't I
well wait a minute I have skunks uh
skunk ears Ty uh he calls it thunk Thai
hey skunk called stunk uh but I'm not
growing that right now I have seeds of
it I have grown that in I think I grew
at like 2014 or 2015. I have a lot of
seeds of it he he was very generous back
in 2012 and he he sent me home with
enough to play with for a while and for
the first few years I would just grow
some of the seeds and just do fennel
hunts and then save a planet and throw
the rest away
um it wasn't really until I started AGC
code that I uh considered IBL in them
and trying to bring them back to the
community I didn't feel like it was my
variety to do that with especially
really after the story he told me about
uh how he viewed his relationship with
Neville and why Neville didn't have all
the seeds of Hayes and Neville made up
the story it like it kind of made sense
and uh so I didn't want to be that guy
and uh and I wasn't and uh so but I
think that trying to get these out to
the world is a good thing I think that
you know trying to you know save these
and spread these around is a good thing
um Sam himself uh did too I mean for I
would say late late 80s early 90s he was
still selling seeds by the kilo probably
to a lot of the Dutch breeders and uh by
that time uh the green team which was
which was Bernard and positronics which
became positronics he was our Bernard
was clearly
you know knocking off remaking f2ing
f3ing f4ing everything that he had ever
got from Sam which was quite a bit you
know what I mean he he got the whole
collection it's clear to me that Bernard
and the Green Team uh Bernard had Hayes
before Neville did Bernard had Hayes
probably right from 85 onward but had
very little interest in it you know what
I'm saying because it was again did you
know his favorite variety was something
called Citron which I would it was like
a little bit uh it took a little longer
than maybe B-52 which at the time was
like a chronic which was like a a big
bud like a like a super skunk time super
Cropper type thing uh wasn't my favorite
but you know Bernard was looking for uh
stuff that fit what he was trying to do
which was you know promoting door
cultivation and you know a lot of little
lollipop plants and you know and I love
it I mean the first time I walked into
positronics has and and saw all those
little plants in the perfect little you
know square meters and you know I I
immediately thought to myself oh that's
how you're supposed to do it and my life
was never the same I I never grew I
never grew the same after that once I
realized how efficient it was to grow
smaller plants that had less veg time I
was no going back you know what I mean
just so that's also why I got busted
with so many plants I mean there's a
picture of me staying in front of a wall
of clones on the back of my book and I
got busted I think with like 4 100
plants or whatever at the time uh it was
just because I you know see green it's
the most efficient way to grow and uh
that's why I think that uh these
tropical equatorials have come back too
because one of the tips Neville gave me
and my friend Tom was don't give it any
pre-grow if you have plans that take
over 10 11 weeks to finish flowering
move them straight from rooting into
flowering and allow them to grow and
flower simultaneously because even
though uh they're in flour they will
um they will grow continually as they're
flowering and you'll still get plants
that are almost a meter tall after 11
weeks if not taller even though they
started off you know
you know barely a few centimeters tall
in comparison where they ended up so
it was good advice and I still pass that
along to people to this day because if
you take a bunch of Equatorial Tropicals
and put them in when they're you know
just a day or two after rooting and pop
them next to each other you can get
fantastic harvests you know 20 plus
grams per plant you know in a tight
close uh grouping that way exceeds what
you would get from you know six weeks
ago and letting it go up and then having
a bunch of wasted space at the bottom
it's way more efficient
yeah some solid advice there for sure I
guess just to quickly wrap up the haze
part I was wondering there's obviously
no notable Haze cuts that go around but
there are a few uh nl5 hazes that have
got a bit of a reputation I guess I was
wondering if you had tried any of the
notable ones like the A5 the C5 or even
like the Cuban black Haze by any chance
uh keeping A's I have uh I think it's
nl5 uh you know when you look at the
dating of it I believe that late 80s
early 90s nl5 was a hugely popular
variety and that a lot of people were
growing at and
um some of the others tend to disappoint
a bit uh I like Cali Mist a lot I think
that uh but you know it was funny I was
having a conversation with Simon once
and he didn't think that the long
flowering female that he used in the
original combination was Haze and I was
just like what did you think it was and
he said Colombian and I went well
I think it is you know like but you know
I it just it's interesting how
the names change and people don't really
realize what they have sometimes and
even though they're using it
successfully and you know I think Hayes
has been amazing I mean my two favorite
Haze plants when I lived in Amsterdam
was I know five days uh Neville's Hayes
wasn't out yet
um or you just started to to release it
actually uh at the tolstrock greenhouse
uh if I remember correctly and and the
Cali missed you know I liked now those
Haze though over nl5 by Hayes nl5 by
Hayes was great but it was more known to
lights when he crossed it when he
crossed the nl5 by his back to that his
a I think it it made it spicier made it
more hazy and I liked it better yielded
less and it took I think a little longer
but it was worth the wait and worth the
loss of yield do you think we'll ever
see Neville's Hayes make a comeback it's
something which is really always popular
among the heads
I have a lot of stuff close
um I
you know it's funny because like I have
the genetics it's like bacon brownies uh
and then it comes to selecting the
proper salt and the proper sugar and the
proper molasses the proper wheat you
know to make your your cookie just the
way you remember it and I think that
this is similar and I mean we can't go
back and smell those phenotypes that he
had but for those of us that have been
around the genetics I mean we can test
The Prodigy and see if it reminds us and
you know for me I mean I already have a
lot of those hazy combinations most of
the stuff I'm smoking uh would remind
you or anybody who wasn't familiar with
like oh that this is that Haze because
it's overwhelms the uh gassiness of the
NL with the spicy uh overtones of the
haze you know what I mean so like if you
came over I think you would be in Haze
Heaven over here because I've I've
touched it to damage everything
um but now that I'm growing the NL and I
have a lot of stuff that has not been
touched to the to the NL but
you know it's been hard to resist I was
doing the room for my head and I I was
in the middle of flowering the um
meaning I was doing a room for my head I
was doing a room seedless because I only
use one male at a time at my facility
because I'm I'm not trying to [ __ ]
around and uh and I had the NLT going in
the greenhouse
and I took a branch of it and I brought
it into the room that I was going to do
seedless and shook it over the plants is
because even though I had original Haze
going and I had these skunk Haze crosses
I had going and I had these super glue
uh I crossed with on Hayes and then did
a selection across that selection to
original Haze to try to pump up the haze
again kind of going for that Neville
Haze Vibe if you will
um I liked it but then I just hit it
with the ml2 because now I can't wait
you know I was like frigate instead of
getting the sensimili I'll just get to
play with the seeds because the nl2 is
so impressive and I want to see what the
effects are with this male against a lot
of these other genetics that I'm so
familiar with to see how it you know how
it dominates The Prodigy that comes off
of it and how it affects it like what
kind of sense I get what kind of body I
get from the buds what kind of like
width I get from the leaves and things
like that and I just did a combination
of original Haze as the female crossed
with NO2 as the male in this and it's
hanging up right now and it's funny
because I keep going down there and I
keep I just can't I go downstairs
sometimes just to go to the ace plant to
just smell them because they they you
get an upper from smelling them it's
weird like I get happy just smelling the
[ __ ] thing so
um but it's that unique everything else
I mean I don't know the skunks that are
down there smell sweet the super gal
smell gassy but that haze just I don't
know man calls my name
that's special that's cool to hear I
think it's going to be a neat
combination because the genetics are
dissimilar and the we'll see we'll we'll
see how it comes out but it's kind of
close to what Neville was doing back
then with the NL depending on which but
I think he used the nl2 a lot I think NL
did because it was the one that was
spectacular and um
and I just did the opposite of what he
did instead of a nl5 female CrossFit
behave male I went with the original
Haze female and called it with a NO2
male uh so we're gonna start seeing how
some of these things pop up and you know
I already like it one of the Super Glue
by on Hayes was on the cover of Girl
magazine a lot of the people has grown
it love it because it has that Afghan
but it has that spice interesting so I
mean can you give us a little bit of a
rundown on the different smells and
effects from the different airlines you
have
um uh the purest indicus heavy the nl2
is heavy the nl5 is a little more light
uh meaning like when I say light like
uh for more tropical plants I get more
of a like a I don't know like a like a
light High I don't know how to put it
like it's more in your head and you're
just kind of like happy High uh a lot of
the stuff like the NL is more physically
relaxing I I my neck pain recedes more
but I can't say that the haze doesn't
make my neck pain go away it's just that
I guess so high I forget about it but
the NHL feels like it actually looks
like I don't forget about it but I feel
kind of chill you know so
um I I think there's the
you know the NyQuil compared to caffeine
effect I I would consider Haze is more
like in my body acts as a caffeine uh
and the NLS the purest Indica is just
very resony and it's when I broke up the
buds it my fingers smell like import
hash like if you've ever been a hamster
and you smoke like Ching Hassan hash and
[ __ ] like that like it it just like it
just had it smells like [ __ ] hash man
it like smells like old glass and I love
it and then the flowers smell kind of
skunky stinky when they were growing
which reminds me of the 80s too because
you know that's
you know that's what it kind of smelled
like and when the when it would cure it
would it would depend on when you you
got it so like depending on how fresh
the flowers were gonna depend on how
much of the terpenes they were emitting
at any given time so if you were getting
pot from your friend it was growing in
their closet they probably weren't
waiting that long uh for the dry and the
Cure because we were all so excited and
you were actually getting cannabis it
was probably two or three weeks from
being cut down a lot of the times and
when you smell it smell it was so
overwhelming and so strong
um but but now with the legal Market we
get Pockets like [ __ ] months old you
know what I mean it's like cured and
dried it wasn't even handled well and
they you know like it's unbelievable and
it's different so I I just think uh
and not the best at describing the
flavors and tastes and stuff but more of
the highs and the excitement I get from
it but I like the northern lights and I
like feeling relaxed but I like the
hazes and I like feeling creative too
yeah look they sound fantastic and I'm
I'm with you I think I'm more of a
highest guy than a Kush guy so to speak
but as a follow-up question to that can
we ever expect to maybe see any
feminized work from you or specifically
s ones of any of these lines the NLS or
the purest indicas
yeah actually totally uh so the plants
some the plants in my future uh are to
start collecting a lot of these clone
only cultivars that are floating around
um you know and as one of them so other
people can experience green crack and
train wreck and other things
um Mel Frank already does that he not
only makes us ones he's been breeding
with female pollen uh for a long time
and he makes Crosses by so uh he'll take
his females that he likes and then he'll
reverse them he will collect the pollen
he will stall the pollen and then he
will administer that pollen on another
plant that he likes and he will do
female feminized breeding
so
you know but he's I mean this is Mel
Frank I mean I expect him to be a little
ahead of the curve when it comes to what
he does first time he he showed me
something it was S1 F1 and S1 F2 and I
went
no this isn't how it could be and he
goes well I don't know what else you'd
call it I collected a pollen from one
plant and I brought it to the other and
I was just like
really and I was like and that's why the
name's like this he's like well I put
the the plant that I collect the female
plant that I collected the pollen from
as the second name because it would be
the male right it was like right and he
was like and it was the second time I do
it so what do you think I should call it
other than enough too I was like
I get it I get it so you know you pop
those seeds you've read those seeds
togethers here you get like it dealing
with them is so much fun I'm the first
person in his whole life that he's
allowed to sell the seeds and it's kind
of an honor to say the very least and um
and I learned something from him every
time we talk which is fortunately for
you know quite often but
um he's been releasing us I've had S1
seeds of his since I've been selling
seeds because he's had them for a long
time and we have the bread uh feminized
bread so we he's still doing that he's
making more feminized GDP seeds I
couldn't keep him in stock last time he
gave them to me I'm expecting more soon
um but then what I'm also going to do is
uh the guy that's famous for GDP
actually gave the seeds to him back some
years back and I know the guy myself his
name's Ken and I'm gonna try to get the
cutting that's been floating around of
GDP and then ask when that there's a lot
of plants that are on our Hit List to
kind of collect and ask one because I
think they're great breeding material
and people have this you know deserve a
right to work with them and I don't want
to cross them with something because I
want them to be
as close to what they are and the only
way I can like put them in a seed form
is to ask one of them
um the plants that the seed varieties
that I got from skunk band sand that I
can't reproduce like thunk Thai hey
skunk
um I'm just gonna go through my seeds do
selections pick the best examples and
then S1 those so that people can
experience those as well I asked them if
I could do that and he was totally cool
with it
um because I don't know another way of
releasing proper representations of them
except to this woman you know you know
what I mean so
um I think that's going to be fun I mean
at this rate with the seed collection I
have and the plans I have I could only
hope to have like three more lifetimes
at least
if I'm lucky
watching the grass grow that's all I
want to do
stand around work and watch the news
it's a good life it's a good life so
sounds like you got a lot of exciting
breeding projects sort of in the mix my
question is which one are you most
excited for and are gonna start next not
hasn't started yet but it's gonna be the
next one to get the wheels churning
um well I
well breeding projects are going to
supersede me uh I I don't feel like I'm
breeding when I'm when I'm f2ing uh you
know through permission uh some of the
original Haze or the skunk or or or the
um northern lights I don't really feel
that's breeding
um I feel it's preserving and I'm and
I'm grateful I'm part of the
preservation of these genetics and I'm
asking them onto other people I'm gonna
do that again uh with nl5 because I ran
out of nl5 seeds and everybody's
freaking out over them um then I'm gonna
do it with the purest Indica because
Greg really wants to see more people get
purist indica and experience the
medicine and it's the best Afghan I've
ever grown in my life and I think people
deserve it it's so beautiful it's so
nice it's just like leathery leaves and
just crusty crusty buds of flour of
resin and I just I'm in love I'm in love
with how it smells I'm in love with how
it smells after it dries
um after that
um my goal was actually to spend more
time going through uh more hay seats and
selecting more phenotypes of haze and
and spending more time with these
because uh all the seeds that Greg sent
me I've cloned and uh so I have all
those genetics and I want to just spend
more time going through all of the
different sister phenotypes and and
really getting to know them for for
their differences and then I really want
to spend more time breeding together
with original Haze because you know I
mean I think the real key to f1s is
dissimilar genetics if you really want
to get some fantastic hybridization and
so that's kind of you know I'm trying to
do what everybody else isn't doing which
is breeding together closely related
plants
you know so uh and I have that unique
opportunity to do that and I'm not
trying to be a joke about it I'm trying
to give the opportunity to other people
so that they can also
um experience these genetics and I I
think there's a lot of artists in the
world you know I wrote in Neville's
article I saw him as an artist you know
even though we didn't invent red blue
gold he what he created with it was
beautiful and we can appreciate his art
you know but it doesn't mean other
people can't come along with the primary
colors and recreate similar combinations
that maybe are even more spectacular
yeah certainly certainly so I'm just
going to change topic for a moment I was
curious to know how was it that you came
about to be the editor of the emperor
where's no clothes did you have a close
relationship with Jack before that or
was that the start of the relationship
it was 1993 and I'd read his book uh and
I was living in San Diego and political
Pacific Beach
and the book really blew me away it
reinforced a lot of the decisions I'd
made for a while I'd have you know
hippie guilt about you being a pothead
and you know kept it secret like I was
you know less than someone and not less
than Society you know and uh frowned
upon and when I read his book it was
like Liberation and I called the number
on the back it was January of 1994 and
this girl named summer answered the
phone and started explaining to me that
they were doing an initiative to
legalize marijuana in Kemp and I should
come up and help and I was stunned and
uh I wanted to maybe go say hi to him
buy him lunch I don't know like I had
I had had good money at the time so I
could afford to go buy them lunch in L.A
or something and I hope to just say
thank you and when I got there I saw
what they were doing and I was sitting
there one day and uh it was lit
literally the first day I got there and
then Jack walked in the office and he
goes on who the [ __ ] are you
set up who the [ __ ] are you and he was
like ah I'm Jack Harris what are you
even wondering and uh and uh he liked it
he said what are you from the East Coast
I said yeah and he said you want to
smoke the best goddamn part you've ever
smoked in your life and I had a I had a
cannabis collection at the time and I
had a duffel bag full of different like
eights and quarters maybe 20 to 30 of
them and I said sure
oh the headphones died
uh one minute let me get my phone I have
another set of headphones what's that
I followed him in a group of hippies
into the back room and he sat down and
he showed me this really great pot
probably a Hindu Kush grown in Northern
California by a gentleman named Richard
Davis and um through on the traveling
hat museum
and it was great and then I started
pulling out all these different types of
weed that like some of them would stick
to the baggy and [ __ ] and Jack is a real
pothead he wanted to smoke all that [ __ ]
he wasn't gonna let me out of his sight
till he smoked all my weed and we sat
there getting high and um and then he
brought me over to his place uh like
because because he was like you're not
driving back to San Diego I said no he
said don't go get a hotel you can crash
at my house I have a couch and I said
okay so we went to his place and uh he
whipped out the Bible bro and starts
teaching me about the etymology of
letters and words and [ __ ] because this
is what he was tripping on at the time
and we sat up all night long literally
reading the Bible and and and him
teaching me all the different
interpretations of what he thought it
really meant and uh really deep [ __ ] and
uh that morning we went and got food it
was the last time in my life I ate
chicken and um and we were inseparable
after that that day we became best
friends and uh we started just I started
working on the initiative I became the
San Diego coordinator and uh I worked
with him 94 uh into 95. um he's the one
that introduced me to Dennis prone and
Browning Mary and Chris Conrad Mickey
Norris and they're the ones that you
know helped uh put together Ben dronkers
um
Museum in Amsterdam
um he's going to introduced me to Ben
and the whole Holland scene and high
times and you know traveling around with
Jack was like you know having backstage
passed to everything we did and and I
made a lot of friends and um I was
really inspired by everybody I met and
that's why I started the San Diego
Compassion Club in 1995 because you know
while we were meeting all these people
it was just really heavy duty to meet
people that would legitimately really
sick and not be able to give them some
weed I would always give them whatever I
had I just couldn't say no I mean when I
was a little kid my mother didn't charge
me before the medicine I needed you know
she just gave me the thought and uh I
just can't imagine
denying somebody
something that can alleviate their their
their ills if you have it just I don't
know maybe it comes from being a little
kid being sick all the time but I have a
lot of empathy for people so uh when I
started the San Diego Compassion Club we
did not sell marijuana we redistributed
donated cannabis uh to people that were
sick you know and um we made Edibles and
gave them away and
you know everything we could do to to
you know I don't know it's just when
when you're on the front lines of the
activism you end up meeting people that
have cancer and that have AIDS and they
have these different conditions and I
don't know how you feel inclined to help
and uh so I started the San Diego
Compassion Club
in April March April of 1995 and I got
busted shortly thereafter and
um
you know so it's been a struggle the
whole way through I ended up getting
busted in Ohio with 30 pounds of
cannabis heading to Rhode Island because
I was gonna start another one I wanted
to do one in my hometown
um and and so I got busted in Ohio along
the way but because I had uh and this is
a Twist uh when in 1994 when I was in
Holland I got a doctor's uh prescription
for medical cannabis from Rotterdam
physician named drusel and he saw my
spinal fusion and and felt like my
medical use canvas was quite legit so he
wrote me an actual prescription for 10
grams a day and I didn't believe that it
was legitimate until I went home and did
some studying at the University of
California they have a law library
that's really good and I was able to
look up things like this the uh
a single 3D Geneva Convention the
psychotropic substances I was able to
look up Customs laws believe it or not
they did not prohibit the importation of
medical cannabis because if you look up
the way that internationally cannabis
was handled it fell under the Opium
rules in the um the
first treaty and because of that if you
had opium prescribed legally by a
country you could bring it to another
country under the prescription rules so
it was really unique and cannabis fell
on to this but nobody was doing it
um so I was one of the first people that
actually challenged it uh the laws that
is it and went back to Holland and
brought back medical cannabis I um
I'll be musica is a woman that gets
medical marijuana from the federal
government she's got glaucoma she's an
old activist she's in her 80s now she
does no longer gets cannabis from the
government because they're given her
swag but
um she was one of my first friends as an
as an activist and it's a real big
inspiration and
um LV would would get in trouble with
cops but she'd have her prescription and
they would not know what to do with this
crazy old lady you know she was crazy in
a good way but she was very boisterous
and loud and wouldn't give up and get in
her face and they just wanted to get
away from her and I saw the prescription
as a real important thing so what
happened is I came back from the
Netherlands with no prescription well
with the prescription but with no pot
um and then I was driving up from San
Diego to L.A and there's a checkpoint uh
it's supposed to be for immigration they
say but it's really not but so they they
they would it's at Santa no Fray it's
right before this military base called
pan Camp Pendleton
um and it's like this random checkpoint
that goes up between San Diego and la so
they stopped me
and I had pot on me and I had my
prescription and I demanded to keep my
pot or arrest me and they didn't know
what to do with me so they the cop has
this human moment and says listen man I
just want you to go away
and I was like really and he's like yeah
he's like can we come to like a truce on
this like you can have some of the pot
like you got to give me some pot so I
can go show my boss that I can't skated
your weed and I was like okay I know I
was like leave me what's in the backpack
and take what's in the bigger bag it's
bigger anyway and because I had I hate
to say it I had kind bud and then I had
Mexican import wheat I used to give away
the Mexican import weed and share the
kind of Bud with Jack so he did it and
uh I went up to Jackson I was just like
dude he didn't know what to do with this
[ __ ] piece of paper and me and LV
with Elvie was there at the time and we
were all like this could be huge so then
uh LV and I and Richard Davis the guy
that threw that pot went up to the
Sacramento law library and did all the
study and we could we came to a
conclusion that there's a lot of
legitimacy to an international
prescription uh so then LV went back
home to Florida and she used to
routinely debate the DEA crazy as it
sounds but um she invited me and Florida
normal which stood for the National
Organization to reform marijuana laws
invited me out to go debate the DEA with
LV I have this on video and I went out
there and I debated the southeast
quadrant leader and I basically asked
him will you asked me if I go to the
Netherlands and pick up my prescription
to fly back and he said no and I said
really okay and I said it was like 300
people there I said you're all my
witness I will fly to the Netherlands
tomorrow I will pick up my prescription
I'll fly back and we see if I get
arrested and he looked at me like if
looks could kill kid I would zap you
right now and I went back to Ellie's
place I called
uh at the time Martin Airlines which was
owned by KLM is Dutch owned and uh they
allowed smoking on planes and when I
called they said would you like smoking
or non-smoking I said you can smoke on
an airplane I said yeah International
flight's over nine and a half hours and
I said well I have a prescription from
my Dutch physician from medical cannabis
and I'm supposed to smoke it about every
two hours would that be acceptable and
she said are you willing to provide a
copy of your prescription to the
stewardess I said oh yeah and she said
then I don't think it's a problem at all
so but you have to sit in a smoking
section so I literally smoked weed from
Florida to the Netherlands in the
smoking section legally after giving
them my prescription it was [ __ ]
great and uh I felt like Freedom was
happening and I flew back and they
didn't arrest me I declared it
um they freaked out a little bit they
wanted me to sign this for him that said
hmm
that I uh that I failed to declare a
controlled substance and I said no no no
I want the form that says I declared the
controlled substance and you're taking
away my prescribed medicine I'll sign
that form but I don't think you have it
and they freaked out and they let me
walk out they didn't even search my
other bag they would just like go away
and the guy actually said good luck to
you and secondary it was amazing he
walked me out the double doors and I
realized wow there's a lot of power to
this so that's when I came back home and
I went right back up to Dennis and and
really Dr Todd mccarria who was one of
the OG doctors that wrote the the hemp
drug commission report and was really
one of him and Lester grinspoon first
real First physicians on this in America
and um he saw it too so he prescribed me
he gave me a recommendation for cannabis
as well and then I got busted and uh
it's interesting because as soon as Dr
Todd mccarria gave me a prescription he
started giving a lot of people
prescriptions like but they weren't they
were recommendations or they were
letters of condition because at the time
all that Dennis required wasn't a
prescription wasn't a recommendation
until 1996 it was just a a letter of
your condition that was it you know
um but that's kind of like I don't know
it's a little much you know you don't
want to go to Silver hey I got AIDS hey
I got cancer it's none of their business
you know so it's a little invasive
um but Dr mccarria was one of my good
friends and he started writing me
prescriptions and for a little while in
California at the very beginning of 1995
I was the only person that I knew that
had a doctor's note in California that
was using it to try to validate their
their their controlled carry of cannabis
LV did have a prescription but she was
getting her [ __ ] from the federal
government I was not I was I was just
trying to assert that my doctor would
back it up and then what happened is I
got busted in Ohio and the public
defender was more like a public
Pretender and I got flustered and the
the judge saw that and he asked me if I
had something to say so I stood up while
I was still Chained and explained that I
was a medical cannabis patient and then
I had an international prescription and
that they should look at this on the
merits of the law and not on their
opinions you know and base it all on
fact and he liked it and he accepted the
the single treaty Geneva Convention he
accepted the the
Customs laws he accepted the the second
79 psychotropic substances because it
also you come to the realization that
they were not trying to prohibit the
medical usefulness of cannabis or opium
they were trying to prohibit the
potential narcotic nuisance of it so
they really never intended to uh inhibit
medical use per se and they couldn't
have if they wanted to because everybody
would have met what the [ __ ] is that you
know but but realistically that's how it
stood so the judge in Ohio said if I
could get one American doctor to
validate my judge positions prescription
he'd let me use cannabis while I was
incarcerated and I went home and called
my good friend who's a lawyer in Ohio
and he called Dr Todd mccurria Dr John
Mogan who wrote marijuana Miss marijuana
facts and he called Dr Lester grinsman
development I want to be considered and
everyone medicine and all three of them
wrote me notes that at night and said
that they had personal you know
knowledge of me and they've met me and
that they were friends with me and that
they all backed it up Dr John Morgan who
was a professor at the City University
of New York actually called the FDA and
said question If a person an American
goes to Europe and picks up a schedule
and substance under prescription can
they bring it back they said yeah three
months Supply he said interesting what
if it's cannabis they said well I don't
see why not but what country is
prescribing cannabis he said the
Netherlands and John told me later he
said it was funny because the guy
laughed and he said I guess he found the
hole in the dike and they laughed on it
and he wrote that in the letter not the
part about the the hole in the dark but
that he contacted the FDA and they
assured him that the importation of a
schedule one substance under
prescription from a foreign country for
30 days prize most absolutely legal and
the judge in Ohio didn't know what to do
so it's been released me and it was
amazing because the AP Associated Press
sat in on this and when the judge didn't
give me the pot she released the story
and the front page of the newspaper said
inmate smoke pot at ccno and then the
USA Today picked it up and made this
great editorial about why medical
cannabis should be legal they started
off with Todd McCormick left his home to
help seriously ill people the only
problem is to help he intended to
deliver is illegal and then they ended
it by saying sick people deserve help
not a ticket to jail it was [ __ ]
great and then after that the New York
Times picked up the story and the truck
in Ohio just dismissed the case was like
go away and when they released me they
told me you have to leave the state it's
really quite funny and then I was like
what about my pot and he goes I knew
you're going to say that it was my
public Pretender he goes I don't have to
handle that for you that's a civil
matter and I only do criminal work so
you're on your own with that you can go
sue the city and I was just like
hmm and um so I left and then High Times
flew me over because then I basically
showed 60 minutes which is a pretty big
news station uh around Amsterdam and
brought him to my doctor and everything
and had like the more serious side of
the ha of the High Times event and they
were so impressed that they actually
didn't add any of that to the story
because they didn't want to discredit
what I was doing because they really
thought it was valid it was really quite
cool
um so I'm only in a clip of it uh which
is funny
um but and I spent days with them
um High Times literally flew me out
there so I could spend time with Molly
Schaefer uh so but while I was there
um the judge was deciding on whether or
not he gave me permission to go back the
judge released my passport let me fly
back to the Netherlands uh he was
deciding if he was going to let me
basically
um if he's gonna prosecute me or not and
uh so I while I was in Holland ended up
getting a job for High Life magazine and
became their first uh English editor of
their English edition of high life which
was really an honor and really cool so I
put out an issue with them
um but I hated the winter and I hated
the cold and I hated the rain and all
the hash and Holland couldn't make me
want to stay so that's why after a year
I ended up moving back to California
mainly chasing the summer and um
it was quite an experience but that but
then I went to LA and had the most crazy
experience because I met a
multi-millionaire publisher who had
actually contracted AIDS in cancer and
he was working on a book about medical
cannabis and he titled it a question of
compassion and ironically I named my
place the San Diego Cannabis Compassion
Club and in the media I always used to
say that it was a it was not a question
of capitalism it was more a question of
compassion you know are you going to let
somebody suffer if you can help them
that seems rather you know mean and he
liked that and when I met him and I was
in his office and I said well the
question of compassion where did you get
that
uh title he said oh I stole it and I
said really and he goes yeah come here
and he shows me this big computer and he
goes yeah look it up and he looks up the
newspaper article he goes see you San
Diego Union Tribune somebody named
Todd McCormick and he was like kid
you're supposed to be here right now and
it was really funny and uh and it was
like we just had this meeting and he was
just he he wanted me to write a book he
wanted me to make a grow video and he
wanted me to go around the country going
to like lectures and teaching people how
to grow their own medicine so he got the
website growmedicine.com and and that
was what the whole concept was going to
be gave me a quarter million dollars and
I went and looked for a place to live
and that's how I happened to trip into
the Bel Air mansion that looked like a
castle and just we had passed prop 60
props 215
and I was naive and thought it mattered
and I didn't understand federalism as
well at the time and I didn't understand
that it did not create a positive
conflict between the feds in the state
of California so I got some
misinformation from a good attorney that
if I didn't sell pot I really couldn't
be prosecuted
um so I didn't sell pot but then I was
prosecuted because even though they
didn't have me for actually selling pot
they charged me with intent to
distribute
so they got into my head and they knew
that overwriting books and putting out
movies and traveling around as a
lecturer that I really wanted to just
sell pot so that was the basis they
prosecuted me on and um it was crazy
initially they held me on a million
dollar bail for over 4 000 plants and um
my friends at the time uh was Woody
Harrelson the the actor and Larry Flynt
the publisher and they arrested me at 7
pm and by 6 a.m I had I had Larry's
Attorneys at the police station
introducing themselves as my new
attorneys and trying to help me get out
of the place and um
and Woody posted my bond in cash it was
lowered to half a million dollars and
Woody posted it in cash and uh which was
pretty incredible I you know never would
have expected to have that kind of
support and uh
and went on to fight them for years I
fought them 97 98 99
and uh they kind of railroaded me they
took away my medical necessity defense
they said I couldn't raise uh couldn't
say the word medical before the word
marijuana they redacted my book how to
grow medical marijuana
um it was really just like they just
the truth didn't matter and um
basically they gave me the they faced a
10-year mandatory minimum if I go to
trial and I was going to lose or I could
do a five-year sentence and retain my
appeal rights and at the time I was
naive and I still believe that appeal
could win
um or they wanted me to release my
appeal rights plead guilty and go in and
plead to the judge for [ __ ] you know
to be easy on me and it's just not me
man and I I wasn't gonna go grovel I
wasn't going to denounce cannabis I
wasn't gonna debrief I wasn't I just
wasn't going to play their game so I
accepted the five-year sentence with the
hopes that I could appeal the sentence
did and I lost
um and then while I was traveling to the
airport in December of 99 I got a
traffic ticket and they used the traffic
ticket to revoke my half million dollar
Bond and uh pulled me back into jail
and uh I started my five-year prison
sentence because really they just wanted
a pound of Flesh they didn't care how
they got it if that makes sense and um I
self-surrendered on January 3rd 2000 and
started doing five years it sucked and
then after a year and a half they sent
my lawyer in to ask me if I would
debrief it means cooperate and I said
[ __ ] no and I sat there for another
three and a half years because if you
don't cooperate
you do time which really boils down to
it that simple so I just ate [ __ ] and
you know sat in prison but I'm glad I
did I wouldn't have had been able to
live myself if I hadn't so
you know I mean it was
it was difficult
but I'm grateful at how it all worked
out you know like there's a line in A
Grateful Dead song where they sang
sometimes you get Shone the light and
the greatest
and then sometimes you get shown the
light in the strangest of places if you
look at it right and that's exactly how
I felt like even though I was being
prosecuted I had a lot of support and
love from my friends they were there
when I got out and
you know you never want to [ __ ] up and
and find out you don't have friends
there for you but to have something
happen and find out you're surrounded by
people that care about you is really a
beautiful experience and um and I'm so
grateful for it for that element of it
to this day as weird as it may sound
I've always felt like cancer was
a beautiful beneficial experience that I
had a hard time appreciating while I was
going through it but I'm grateful that I
went through it you know because I think
it made me the person I am today and I'm
proud of myself so
but you know would you want to see a
little kid have cancer never mind over
and over and over again [ __ ] no you know
but if somebody had a magic wand and
said they could wave it over my head and
take away my cancer experience I would
break the wand
yeah wow what a what a beautiful life
story and the way you've gone on to
accept it or just uh almost
inspirational I guess after you got out
at what point did the idea of AG seed
code cross your mind was there a
specific moment where you thought God I
gotta do something with this when did it
all start
my intention when I came home in the 90s
was to start a seed company because I
had been collecting genetics in
Amsterdam and I had been collecting
genetics from California for years and I
had a lot of great connections in
California for genetics so when I came
home
um that was part of what I was doing was
was growing out varieties and and
starting breeding and making seeds I was
trying to convince my publisher that I
needed at the time like a quarter
million dollar gcms and a technician to
run it because I wasn't educated and how
to run it but I needed the output I
needed the data that would come out of
it as I was working because I needed
continual monitoring of my genetics uh
because I saw them as little
Laboratories and I wanted to look into
the laboratory window and see what the
chemistry was that the lab technician
was making on that day because I feel
that the carbolic acid profiles build up
and break down over the course of the
flower and instead of just taking it at
one point and looking at what and Peak
and saying there it is I didn't I wanted
to test daily if I could afford it
um and looked at it all the way past
Pete to you know Rejuvenation and and
just take an honest look at the way that
at the time the Terrapins were not part
of the conversation but just the way the
carbolic acids built up and broke down
um I I I I came home
when I was working in Amsterdam and I
had the job I became good friends with
Robert Clark who was a historian we all
know and he was working on hashish at
the time and he schooled me on so much
so I came home a student of Rob's and I
was very enthusiastic I I had first
tried CBD in Amsterdam when he gave me
some cannabis that was CBD and had no
THC because he wanted to see if it
helped my neck pain because he felt like
my medical condition was obviously
legitimate and he just wanted my
feedback so the first time I ever used
it was
from Rob and uh he taught me so much
about the complexity of the cannabinoids
the profiles the resin glands he was
working on hash Asian if you drive
hashish it's just such a [ __ ] awesome
book and um and I I was right there so I
hadn't the professor as my drinking
buddy almost nightly for quite a long
time while I lived in Amsterdam I can't
count the amount of nights that we spent
together and between spending time with
him and old dad because he wanted to
spend time with all that Holloway
because Ed had come to Holland before
Rob did and Ed was already legendary
when he left and you know he was one of
the old-timers there wasn't many guys
like Greg that were actually growing
cannabis in the 60s that are still
around and had turned 80 in 1996 so he
was [ __ ] old and he was a really
smart guy dude he was
he was on the team of Engineers that
broke the speed of sound out at Edwards
Air Force Base in the late 50s and he
took an early retirement from
um either General Dynamics or one of
these big companies and when it in the
early 60s his kids were coming back from
the First tours of Vietnam and his wife
he said was drinking and she had what he
called the empty nest syndrome because
their kids were gone at college and now
at War and he when his kids came home
they brought him some Vietnamese and
Cambodian cannabis and Ed wasn't a drink
or any [ __ ] loved the weed and he
told me that after a few years he
couldn't stand his wife's drinking
anymore and he left her everything but a
couple of his favorite airplanes because
he owned his own airplanes and
um he started flying around going to
military bases in places where cannabis
was indigenous and he could land and
just say hey I'm doing research and they
didn't question him because he had
clearance from his job that he still
kind of worked for it because he was an
engineer and he collected cannabis
genetics through the 60s until the 70s
and old Ed then met Bernard Bruning when
Bernard started the Mellow Yellow and Ed
was credited with teaching Bernard and
all these young hippies at the time how
to grow seedless cannabis and how he
helped them improve the quality of
cannabis they grew and at the time they
called him old Ed because he was already
in his 40s and 50s when they were still
in their early 20s and when I met him he
was 79 turned 80 in 96 when I was with
him and then when I left and came back
to California we had a very good
friendship he left and he went to my
house in Bel Air and he went home to his
family and got a cold so he didn't come
back to the mansion right away and I got
raided and he fortunately wasn't there
when I got raided
um but we still were friends even after
that he was that he didn't come back and
live with me while I was prosecuted of
course but I did pick him up and he did
stay with me when I was in uh various
places in LA because one of his
daughters lives out outside of La so I
go pick him up and hang out with the old
man I absolutely adored him I would I
would squeeze cannabis and hold it to
his nose and he'd give me countries of
origin not names it was [ __ ] awesome
I love I loved spending time I started
martial arts when I was 12 and I've
always appreciated uh our elders and I
see guys like skunk man Sam and and Greg
and and old Ed and Rob and Mel Frank and
you know they were they were the people
I looked up to when it came to
you know information and experience
wow what an incredible story I uh I
didn't know any of that that's that's so
very enlightening and you just mentioned
Mel Frank there I was wondering what was
the first seeds you ever got from Mel
and funny enough
a weird thing you say that because uh in
1996 when I met him at the at the 96
Cannabis Cup
um I told him I was coming home I was
coming home to California and I would
look him up when I got there so when I
came back and I got that place in Bel
Air
um he was invited over but he never made
it and he invited me over to pick up
some of these skunk seeds that he had
made the summer before which is this
1996 skunk seeds so I drove over there
and I picked them up and I drove home
and I got busted like two weeks later so
I lost them uh and then I go to prison
I get out of prison uh years go by I
move out of LA and Jim would always come
visit me uh I I don't know I just always
had hangout houses so he would just make
his way to come see me and then when I
moved up here I have a really big house
and he would come and stay with me and
we'd go to cannabis cups and the other
cannabis events so we would always be
buddies
um so
I I get this idea like the AG Seed Co
happened when the farm bill passed and I
realized that you know hey seeds are
legal you know because all plant parts
of the plant that contain less than
three tenths of a percent THC were now
taken out of the CSA and seeds contain
zero cannabinoids so I saw an
opportunity there as well as maybe maybe
take other people a little while figure
it out but seeds are legal so
um I was like hmm and uh because we
passed prop 64 here in California I'm
legally growing the seeds everyone in
the state of California over the age of
21 doesn't even need a doctor's note
they can legally grow six plants
cannabis and you can get could amount of
seeds off of six plants cannabis so
technically you can legally grow your
seeds in some ways because they're not
federally illegal or anything like that
they're much like heirloom tomato seeds
where it's you know you can grow tomato
seeds and then sell them on what we call
eBay and it's not really a big deal and
I I think the same is with cannabis
seeds now because I don't know of any
prosecutions are going specifically for
seeds I mean there's no drug content it
they're not really manufactured I mean
they're a product of nature to say the
very least and I think it's a difficult
case for a prosecutor and I don't think
a prosecutor really wants to prosecute
somebody for like a few grams of seeds
so as long as you pay your taxes and
you're not you know
getting caught selling kilos of butter
hash out to the world I don't I don't
think it's that dangerous to sell seeds
anymore
um lots and lots of seed companies have
popped up believe it or not if you drive
up what we have called Interstate 5 up
in Oregon there are full-size billboards
with 1-800 number websites for seeds so
it's changing really big over here and
uh so I started selling seeds and when I
contacted Jim I was already in contact
with Jim but I made a catalog and I sent
it over to him and like the dad he is he
corrected my grammar and sent it back to
me and uh I only messed up like a comma
and something else it was really pretty
good like I got like pretty much a 99
and uh and I was just like and I said to
him I said you know man you should let
me sell your seeds too they're not going
to do anybody any good sitting in your
refrigerator
and he said you're right he said come
over and get some so I drove all the way
back down to LA and uh when I got there
I had a Deja Vu because I hadn't visited
him and it felt like a long time and
said hey man how long you've been living
in this house
he said I moved into it just a couple
years before you first visited it and I
said really he goes yeah and it was cute
because at the time he had some cheese
on table he goes yeah remember you came
up here to pick up these exact seeds and
I went wow talk about life Interrupted
he goes yeah you know because here we
were 23 years later and I was just
picking up the seeds just to do the same
[ __ ] thing I was gonna do in 1997 and
um they were still sitting in the
refrigerator for me which was
kind of a touching thing I know it
sounds weird but like sometimes it's the
little things in life that
just blow you away and uh he didn't
particularly save those seeds for me
but he still had someone I was able to
come back and get some so
you know he's just I don't know man I
absolutely adore Mel Frank he's I think
one of the nice coolest kindest humblest
best historians best photographers his
cannabis photography back in the 70s is
stunning his use of the camera is is
magnificent and I don't know anybody
with as good a photos
from the 1970s and early 80s of cannabis
as as he as as Mel Frank his real name
is Jim Goodwin of course but you know so
I I that's kind of how it all started
really and I didn't expect the skunk one
seeds to smell anything but sweet and
when I grew them I he gave me multiple
he gave me 2010 seeds too that he made
in 2010 and those did sell smell sweet
um
but when I stopped and started thinking
about the genetics I kind of found it
kind of like not too particular because
him being friends with Skunk Man Sam and
them both being old heads he would have
most likely gave him seeds from the
selections that would have been more
like what what Jim would like rather
than the newer stuff which was more
fruity you know what I mean so kind of
not surprised that it was more Afghan
dominant rather than the uh the Acapulco
Gold slash Plumbing gold because as he
was doing his selections I think that
there was a certain amount of time where
skunk one was uh
evolving we would say you know what I
mean from from really stinky and and
accurate probably a lot more thiols than
it has now to a lot less thiols and a
lot more fruity kind of uh you know that
passion fruit kind of yummy terpenes
that you smell and you just want to keep
keep smelling at least that's my opinion
of the evolution after talking to them
both but they're kind of old and when
I've asked Skunk Man Sam what he gave
himself I don't remember and then you
know when you asked
um now you know kind of you know they
know there's skunk seeds they know
they're the skunk one seeds but
we're along the line I don't know and
and I don't know how old they were in
1988 but I would easily think that they
could have predated Sam moving there in
85 because by mid 88 he'd only been
there for like let's say two and a half
years you know part of 85 86 87 and now
you're into 88 so it could have easily
been seeds that he had had that pre that
goat went back to Santa Cruz since
before he went over there and started
doing more selections and redefining
what became skunk one
because you understand the evolution of
species in a way you get exactly what
I'm saying you know a lot of people
don't they think it was like a light
bulb turning on and it's like it doesn't
work that way you know I think we slowly
moved away from the files you know what
I mean like I think that it's still
present I just think they're present in
my nude amounts
yeah certainly I mean I've I've
considered that sort of thing for a long
time but it's good to hear that
validated by your similar thoughts on it
at all I was interested in asking you if
you could give us a little rundown of
the skunk you offer I guess I hear a lot
of people in the past few years talk
about skunkers though it's cool because
it's this good strain but it's also like
one of those older ones which like
tended to yield quite nicely and a lot
of people these days are really over the
lower exotic plant yields do you think
that skunk could be something for those
type people
I think a lot of people yeah I've I've
saw quite a few skunk seeds since I've
released them these uh these seeds that
are currently available are the seeds
that have only been reproduced twice
since the 80s once in in 1996 and again
by me in 2019 2020
um
they are old cannabis I mean I don't I
don't know another way to put it they
haven't had any outside influence
they've been uh inbred with themselves
twice uh once in 96 months and they are
old pot I don't know another way put it
a lot of people have been growing them
out love them a lot of people have been
you know talking about finding skunks
scent and taste in Aroma a lot of people
want to shoot them down but I don't I
think it's like the haze the more people
that get the genetics the more people
are going to have to shut up and realize
they're still around and I I think
that's the similar situation with
thyal's present in the skunk they're
still around I mean it's impossible for
me to believe that that these terpene
and by all combinations that were
existing 30 years ago just disappeared
it's not that they disappeared it's just
that we slowly bred away for them in
favor of higher cannabinoid combinations
with sweeter more aromatic scents it's
really that simple and as we did that it
made our Gardens easier to hide because
now it took on a sweet floral a
fragrance rather than a stinky skunky
nasty what's that dead [ __ ] in your
backyard fragrance and and that made a
big difference in the way that we were
able to cultivate cannabis in urban
communities and I think a lot of people
don't get that
um and until you know the 90s and Beyond
when carbon filters became the norm a
lot of people were staking up their
rooms in their neighborhoods trying to
grow this stuff I know I did you know my
friend once who used to sleep over all
the time he used to say to me bro now
when I smell a skunk he's like I like it
because it reminds me of your bedroom
and your garden and I was like oh that's
kind of funny you know but you know when
we're a teenager we used to sit up in my
bedroom and smoke weed because my
grandma used to let us so it was the
hangout spot you know you know what it's
like when you're 14 15 16 years old you
got nowhere to go and um it was funny
but you know and it's funny how you
start to like scents like now when I
smell skunk I like it it I like it
they're like on the side of the road it
makes me reminds me of old weed and the
skunk I have still reminds me of will
read there's still files present in it
you know I just tell anybody that
doesn't believe it just freaking grow
them
you tell me after you've flowered it you
know
yeah I agree it's interesting because we
don't see files in any other mixture
other than like on their own like it's
like you know people talk as if there's
one roadkill skunk and then nothing else
like it do you think we'll ever see it
mixed with other things
yeah you know the the rks that I got
from Jaime in Alaska to me is just very
Afghan
um it it's a decent smoke it's a
beautiful bud I've taken high quality
photos of it and shared them people
loved it my girlfriend likes to smoke it
it's peppery uh it's not my favorite um
but I'm a haze head and um but it's just
not overwhelming and and you know I have
to them and I saw the small batch of
them and people that have grown them
have agreed with me but you know people
are still condemning oh you can't have
them like it's the Holy Grail or
something silly but you know you still
see these skunk problems in hemp Fields
so when I say problems make the
overwhelming scent of skunk or something
rancid or acrid
um so there's still files in high
numbers so you know these people that
are growing large amounts of of low THC
cannabis are also having neighbors
complain about the smell of skunk and
it's just not from a small batch it's
from [ __ ] Hempfield
um so that just tells me they're present
uh it's just a matter of us breeding
them up if we really want them back
um I I say this though you know just
like there's a Synergy between the
terpenes and the cannabinoids there
might be more of a Synergy between the
dials and the cannabinoids and the
terpenes that we know right now and we
perhaps are underestimating so it might
be worth it for people to take the time
to try to detect files and to try to
bring back that funky musty stinky smell
like I say it in two words because like
I I I feel like it's already very
present in the skunk one seeds that I'm
offering and that I have and that people
are reporting the same thing I am
um
but you could do more with it you know
if somebody were to take tens of
thousands of these seeds or thousands of
these seeds and start really going
through them you're going to find the
Einsteins the Real Genius plants in
there and you're going to find the
tripping combinations that are one in a
thousand or one in a whatever you know
one in whatever your lottery ticket ends
up being and you and if you have the
ability to clone it and carry on those
genetics maybe the whole Community could
share them because I have a feeling
unfortunately a lot of times when these
good plants pop up they may fall into
the hands of people that are not making
cuttings are not making seeds are not
sharing it I've had a lot of my great
friends in Northern California hand me
one of the best buds I've ever smoked
and then I say can I get a cutting and
they say oh dude that's that's the plan
I cut that down I don't have cuttings of
it and I do like really he's like dude I
had 100 of them and it's like I get it
and then they're not home to take care
of the cuttings it's not there it's not
the way they do their they did thing
back in the 90s you know what I mean hey
they leave and they have to go sell
their weed it gets cold up there there's
no point of being up where you don't
have electricity and you have outdoor
Plumbing in the winter if you don't have
to be and a lot of my friends used to go
up open up their places in the spring
crop out leave in the fall and spend
their Summers down their Winters down in
LA and Southern Cal selling their pot
and enjoying the beach and taking some
time to themselves before they went and
worked their ass off and trade the
helicopters didn't find them that was
the life of many of my friends for a
long time
wow I one of your earlier answers you
you mentioned how you're from with woody
house and Harrelson yeah and I've seen
on your Instagram you've also you know
you've been in photos with Tommy Chong
and Willie Nelson and Hugh Hefner it's
it's quite quite a good mixture you got
there I guess what I'm interested in is
they're all Stoner yeah Hugh Hefner Hugh
Hefner gave the money to found normal in
1970. Keith stroke presented his idea to
the Playboy foundation and half liked it
gave them five grand and then gave him
50 and then funded them through the
early 70s and used to even let
normal use the Playboy Mansion for their
parties and when I met half it was after
I got raided and I was in the news a lot
and when he met me he shook my hand he
wouldn't let it go and he started
telling me about his involvement with
normal
and I said half I know I'm friends with
Keith and he said really he goes let's
have them out for dinner and I said
and uh he invited me and Keith over for
dinner and I went and uh we sat in the
backyard and smoked weed together and he
talked to me about how he first smoked
cannabis in the 1950s when the beets the
beat the Beats brought it to him the the
beatnix the the pre-hippies and uh the
Allen ginsburgs and those poets and and
he ate cookies because he couldn't smoke
weed comfortably around a lot of the
people that were in the magazine so he
had cookies made and he would secretly
eat cannabis Edibles that was his trip
and I was the amazing experience man I
mean I met him
97 I guess and then started going he
allowed me to come over I guess the
first time I had dinner with him was in
98 and then he let me come to all the
Playboy parties 98.99 which was a lot of
fun and um it was really quite touching
um I actually have a picture of him and
the woman that was his assistant on the
wall because uh Joanie was her name and
Joni took a liking to me
um she was a cannabis user and
unbelievably she came down with cancer
in 1999 and during the summer of 99 I
was the one bringing her her medicine
and spending time with her and
um she passed away in September and I
attended a funeral at the Playboy
Mansion it was pretty heavy and I spent
my last weekend at the Playboy Mansion
uh 1999
to 2000 uh that's where I was for the
New Year's Eve and then I had myself I
didn't even tell half I had to go to
prison because I didn't have the heart
to ruin this evening I just felt so bad
about projecting my sadness onto my
friends that only the few people I was
there with actually knew that I had to
go to prison on Monday because I just
didn't want to ruin anybody's New Year's
Eve I mean it's [ __ ] 1999 2000 I
didn't want to be a wet blanket you know
and um
it was sad and uh when I got out of
prison actually I had the opportunity to
use the Playboy Mansion to raise money
uh for the legalization effort and I
produced parties at the Playboy Mansion
in 2007 2008 and 2009 it was a total
honor in 2009 I even received a Lifetime
Achievement Award or a lifetime
dedication award from marijuana policy
project on stage at the Playboy mansion
and I my mom was there like I let my mom
come to the [ __ ] Playboy party it was
pretty funny and uh it was in a Playboy
party it was a marijuana policy project
party at the Playboy Mansion but I was
one of the producers of the party so I
couldn't invite anybody I wanted
um but it was pretty funny to have my
mom have sauce while I get a freaking
Lifetime Achievement Award like who
would have ever
it's weird the whole experience pro has
been so strange as you said earlier you
know the truth is much Stranger Than
Fiction you know and uh my first party I
had uh Joe Rogan M seed Blues Traveler
played and uh the gentleman named DJ
Pooh who's one of my best friends to
this day uh who made the movie Friday
and produced all the albums with Snoop
Dogg a nice Cube uh he DJ'd for me he
was my DJ at my party because I didn't
know anyone else so I asked DJ poo and
it was really [ __ ] great and uh my
second year Perry Farrell of Jane's
Addiction played for me because back in
the 90s we were on this thing called
Spitfire tour together and uh even
crazier than that in July of 1999 I got
to open up Woodstock I got to walk out
on stage at 11 35 a.m on uh Friday the
23rd of July and say welcome to
Woodstock my name is Todd McCormick I'm
with Spitfire tour and I I talked about
legalizing cannabis and I got to do that
uh Friday with uh
oh come on Andy Dick and then uh and
then Kennedy and she got booed off stage
and I had to do 20 minutes at Woodstock
improvised
because the other girl that was supposed
to speak made it two minutes and she got
booed off the stage the people at
Woodstock were going they were screaming
show your tits show your tits and she
was the girl that was the VJ from MTV
and she's like I will not show you my
boobies it was [ __ ] a moment and and
I looked at her like do you want me to
get the mic because I was kind of emcee
in our little set and she went like this
and I went and got the mic and everybody
started cheering and I was like uh and
my manager's like yelling
keep going you have another 20 minutes
and I was like
who wants 20 more minutes of me and
everybody started cheering and I was
like oh my God and I had to go out and
do 20 more minutes of like let's end the
drug war which wasn't really hard for me
to do I mean me talking about cannabis
is really quite fluid but uh it was
quite the experience and then the next
day I got to do it with Mickey Hart of
the Grateful Dead me and Mickey Hart and
this girl Julia butterfly was [ __ ]
great Mickey Hart and Rosie Perez uh she
was there too she spoke about AIDS
active activism Mickey Hart spoke about
uh deforestation and why we have to stop
deforesting and um it was really cool I
was actually pretty blown away like the
[ __ ] I grew up listening to Woodstock on
my mom's albums and here I was like
meeting Michael Lang and [ __ ] wearing
it all access pass and going out on
stage as myself talking about weed and
nobody knew who I was which was really
quite strange you know because I'm not a
musician I'm not famous and any on any
level but I showed a short video of me
getting busted and a little bit of
History of cannabis and then I started
talking and people just clicked and they
loved it and the whole little thing went
over really well but uh while I was
being prosecuted I really turned it into
a soap box believe it or not I tore it
around to almost all not all of them but
quite a few of the major universities
um speaking about legalizing cannabis uh
we created this group called Spitfire
which was a active musicians and
activists it was the idea of Zach de la
Rocha of Rage Against the Machine and he
had the idea of like putting rock stars
and activists together and going to
colleges because then the kids would
show up and listen to the rock stars and
maybe you know get a little bit taken
away from the activists so it was cool
man I toured with Woody Harrelson
um you know Chris novacelle of Nirvana
he spoke about
um censorship and music Amy Ray of the
Indigo Girls she spoke about gay and
lesbian rights Kennedy she spoke about
conservative issues Jello Biafra of the
Dead Kennedys he was just [ __ ]
Dynamic and spoke about everything that
blew our behind
um we had quite a few people Andy Dick
was on tour with us on Mickey Hart
joined us for an event it was really
quite cool because the women that put it
together was normally a music uh
industry like she would produce concerts
so she knew all these like Red Hot Chili
she knew everybody and she so she so she
could just put put us like you know what
the [ __ ] am I doing touring around with
a guy from Nirvana but but it was great
and me and Chris became good friends and
still friends still friends last time I
checked I mean so I I think the world of
them really he does this thing called
fear vote and he's trying to get uh
ranked Choice voting passed in in North
America where your vote always counts
meaning that you pick your favorites and
then if your first one doesn't win all
your votes go to your second choice and
then it just creates a situation where
every vote counts it's really cool uh
the politicians are scared [ __ ] of it
because it's not just 50 50 at that
point it's like you can't be an [ __ ]
because if the person you're you you
would you wouldn't you would get the
votes from as their second choice if you
don't do good it's really cool I love
the work he does politically but it was
[ __ ] Dynamic and I got to do a lot of
fun [ __ ] uh when I got out of prison I
was really more determined to be an
activist than I was ever and uh I met up
with some guys from Canada we made the
first documentary called the union the
business behind getting high that did
really well for us and then I got the
opportunity to produce Playboy parties
and that went really well for us and
then I rented a hundred thousand square
feet at the Los Angeles Convention
Center in 2009
and I held the first THC Expo I had
almost 300 companies and I had over 40
000 people show up that first Saturday
uh that the fire marshal almost shut me
down multiple times it was really quite
amazing and um
Tommy Chong is somebody I met in the
neighborhood of La when I moved to Bel
Air I started meeting celebrities and um
kind of strange like that but you just
meet your neighbors and if if you are
friendly with them you never know you
make friends in the strangest places so
Tommy and I became kind of buddies like
shared numbers and would talk and um
Tommy was very supportive of me before I
went to prison because he felt like what
the prosecution was just [ __ ]
horrible and then they prosecuted him
for bongs while I was in prison I
couldn't believe it Tommy and I went
through the same halfway house within a
few months of each other and stayed in
touch after we got out of prison and um
and he was helpful with the Playboy
parties in the way that he was helped
trying to help me connect with other
celebrities because
we were just trying to get them to try
to speak up and get involved I mean
we're not rich like Nike we can't just
hire Michael Jordan I gotta like sit
down with Kareem Abdul-Jabbar and try to
like guilt him into saying good things
about medical cannabis even though he
uses medical cannabis for his own
headaches
um and um true story actually and uh but
the funny part is is realistically the
the party wasn't the point it was the
networking that was important you know
what I mean because it gave us like a
hey can I talk to you about our activism
and would you donate or would you help
out Tommy was always down to help out
but he never wanted to come to the
parties because he hated being like
signature mode and he just hated it but
he always came to the pre-planning
parties which was really more like
touching to me that he was like
he cared he's a great great person I can
adore Tommy Chong but I called him up
one day and he has an electric hot rod
and I said uh I was high I'm always high
but I said um
hey Tommy do you still have your
electric hot rod and he's like yeah and
they said hey can I borrow it and he got
real quiet for a good minute and he's
like
yeah yeah I suppose you can he's like
where is it you want to go Todd I said
oh Tommy I'm not trying to go anywhere I
rented the LA Convention Center and I'm
gonna hold like the first indoor
cannabis convention on the large scale
here in North America and I want to put
your car on display because I'm doing
this whole hemp education it's good for
the environment thing and I and I and I
love what you're doing with your
electric hot rod to me it's like the
environmental side of you that nobody
knows like he drives a blacked out Prius
like he he's he's not a flashy dude he's
not wearing Rolexes and [ __ ] gold
watches and he's not that dude he's like
environmentalist like politically cool
like he's just like they say when you
meet your Heroes you're often
disappointed if you get to meet Tommy
you'll be nothing but blown away because
he's just such a good person his
family's so cool his kids are so cool
he's just amazing and um
and he let me borrow his car man I I he
he hooked me up with hippie Motors and
they delivered the car to the lake
convention center and he came down that
day to see what I was up to and I opened
the doors and the place got flooded and
he was so proud of me it was [ __ ]
great I got countless photos of him like
giving me hugs and being happier than
anything because it it felt like
Vindication you know like here we are
standing here as a demographic that
can't be ignored and um it felt good it
was a real powerful moment Woody flew
out from Ohio from Hawaii just to come
to my event
um you know it it was really quite
touching like my friends
have been great friends like I feel
nothing but blessed for the people I've
had in my life and so so fortunate and
you know not just because they're famous
just because they're such good people uh
on such a spectrum of of doing good
things in the community on different
levels and um it's been beautiful and uh
and then I did my second documentary
with the same guys we did the culture
High uh which included uh really a great
cast
um in 2012 I happen to be getting the
Cannabis culture award from Ben dronkers
with uh Richard Branson and Dr Lester
grinspoon and I used the opportunity to
ask Richard Branson if you'd consider
being in our second documentary
and he said maybe and then he said yes
and then when he saw the film he liked
it so much that he took it on his own
accord and launched it for us on October
1st 2014 which was pretty incredible
when he wrote this beautiful blog about
legalizing uh can you know cannabis and
what's going on with the war on drugs
and I mean it was really amazing because
you can't get a billionaire to do
anything he doesn't want to do if he
doesn't want to do it and to have that
Purity was just incredible and uh I
think a lot of because of that he helped
us uh get a lot of international press
and then uh it was picked up by Netflix
and it was shown in 70 countries in 15
languages for three years uh with you
know various uh transcriptions in the in
voiceovers so it was it I don't know
this whole way through and then
unfortunately when Jack died in 2010 his
publisher contacted me and said hey
you're it you know we got to put the
book back out and um at that point we
only had the 11th Edition done so
um I put together the 12th edition of
the book and I reached out to a bunch of
our friends like like Woody and Tommy
and Vivian mcpeek of Hempfest and Debbie
colesbury of can
um and I asked them to write uh
memorials to Jack Steve Hager of High
Times uh Steve Bloom I think I got in
there too uh maybe Malcolm McKinnon as
well I'd have to go through the list but
uh they were all really nice to me I
mean Tommy when I wrote to him and asked
him to write a memorial for Jack Herer
he didn't answer my email with a yes or
a no he just wrote it and sent it back
that was his reply
and I was just like wow and uh
and I don't know it was touching because
Jack touched all our lives I mean I used
to say that he didn't just touch our
lives he penetrated our lives and it was
beautiful to know him and to be so close
to him and you know I I'm honored to
still be close to all of his kids and
you know I wish he was still here I love
him very much he was the father I never
had on a lot of levels I mean Jack was
great and um
yeah I wish we still had him here today
for sure and uh I think he'd be really
proud to see legalization and the
changes that have occurred I mean for
Jack it was not about you know
protecting the prophets of farmers it
was about liberating the people that
were affected by the drug war and that
were sitting in prison and
and you know he made me promise that I
would fight as an activist until I was
84 or dead
and uh I don't know I just feel like a
lot of my
passion and determination came from him
I don't know
yeah I know
he was someone that really touched my
life and and many others in such a
positive way I think a lot of us are
really activists
um would say that it was reading the
emperor where's no clothes at
kicked us in the ass and really
motivated us to do something
about the Injustice it was Cannabis
prohibition and uh yeah
and then in 2011 uh on a brighter note
Seattle had faster and 20 years old
so I helped Vivian mcpeek put together a
20 chapter book uh called protestable
which kind of stands for protested
festival and um we wanted to highlight
all the work that Seattle hand Fest had
done to to work to legalize and um
it's been a hell of a journey to be
really blunt I mean
um
I don't know I'm proud of where we are
now I'm glad to see The Liberation I'm
happy to see cannabis stories I believe
in cannabinoids that it will help
Society like it's helped me and I wish
more people had access to cannabis
because I believe that if they did you
know society would be a much more
beautiful place and less people would be
addicted to Pharmaceuticals and alcohol
and various substances that you know you
just don't need if you have good herb in
your life so
yeah a hell of a journey so
you know here we are now and I feel like
even selling seeds is a form of activism
because you know I'm you know I've lived
in the same place for 11 years I've only
been selling seeds for two and a half my
life hasn't really changed since I
started selling seeds
um
it's really not about the money it's
really just about trying to like do good
for a community that's meant a lot to me
for a long time and that's you know kind
of helped me survive I mean I don't
think
I would be where I am today if it wasn't
for cannabis or the insightful doctors
that I had that were willing to give me
cannabis over opiates
you know and I'm I'm just really
grateful it's
you know so I cannabis is my form of
appreciation and I think the best way I
can honor it is to spread the seeds
around and give other people the
opportunity of growing and experiencing
you know the varieties that have come
through me you know and I didn't invent
cannabis so I can breed it together all
I want but
you know I'm not going to be one of
these guys that thinks he's cool or
[ __ ] rock star breeder any of that I
think
you know everybody should do it and I'm
just grateful to be the bridge between
you know these old Growers these old
breeders and a new generation
what a powerful recount there of your
life story that's incredible to say the
least you know and then thanks so much
for sharing the the very personal
relationship you have with Jack that's
really inspiring we had just a small
number of questions left including our
rapid fire ones so we're sort of on the
tail end of it all I appreciate your
time sure sure it's been fun talking to
me you know kovitz kept us in the house
and I used to go to coffee shops and
meet strangers and talk to them for
hours and become friends and it was
great and I you know haven't been out of
the house in a while just meet my
girlfriend working all the time so it's
kind of nice to to have been talking to
you and going over this stuff is
I I didn't realize I haven't talked
about Jack in a while so
my own surprises in this conversation
but thanks for uh entertaining it and I
hope that people take something from it
uh
to say the least look I'm sure they will
it's been great from my position that's
for sure I it's I think I could probably
guess the answer to this question but I
haven't asked you what style of growing
do you like are you a soil Organics guy
how do you do it yeah I I organic pots
um I got LED lights and I get drip run
to waste irrigation I use dosatrons I
you know
um but
I use a Roots organic 707 as a medium I
love it I I swear by it uh I think it's
a very good company they put out a very
good product
um I use some of uh aryan's Greenhouse
powder feeding I like his uh bio line
and his his mineral line both very good
um I use those in addition uh I don't
really spray much on my plants I you
know I like extracts and I don't want
anything on the flowers other than water
um you know as far as growing tips I
would say that a long time ago I started
using
um ionized water which is electronically
ionized for its acidity or alkalinity
and you can use this water to either
degrease or basically debug and it
doesn't leave anything behind so I've
been recommending to my friends that
they buy these uh water ionizers and
they start to use like high alkaline
water in order to rinse off powder and
mildew in acidic water to deal with bugs
because
showed us that we killed the insects but
acid rain also kills the insects so if
you use an acidic water you can actually
do it without harming the plants uh the
alkaline water though I am very hesitant
to spray on flowering plants because the
alkalinity will emulsify the oils uh so
you want to use it more sparingly than
the acidic water but it works great
um
I've uh you know also if anybody's still
deep this deep and new listening
um I recommend using hemp seed oil as a
solvent to dissolve the trichrome heads
on the Cannabis flowers that people grow
20 years ago I was sitting home rather
stoned and I I was using a Marinol and I
had used an A B epoxy that day which is
you know two parts resin that makes a
hard bind and I was thinking [ __ ]
synthetic molecules suspended and sesame
oil what if I used organic cannabinoids
and suspended them in hemp seed oil so I
went and I scooped up some resin powder
and I put it in some hemp seed oil that
I had heating up in a frying pan and it
melted into the hemp seed oil and
decarboxylated and I put it on muffins
like it was a butter and I got really
high and um
I started playing with putting the
grinding up the Cannabis or just using
my
um because I have uh Siege screens you
know 60 mesh and 150 mesh and a bunch in
between so I would collect my resin
powder and uh if you just put resin
powder in a jar of hemp seed oil
um and you agitate it a little the hemp
seed oil being an oil will break down
the trichrome which is also an oil and
it will release the acids and the tri
and the terpenes into the oil and then
you can take like a like a stainless
steel strainer or whatever you want and
you can actually strain the hemp seed
oil of any of the thicker waxes that
didn't dissolve with the hemp seed oil
as easily and you can get that out and
then what you have left is
phytocannabinoid infused
non-de-carboxylated and all the terpenes
in in the hemp seed oil and you can do
this in your refrigerator it takes like
10 to 20 days sometimes for the oil to
break down the trichromes but once it
does it's so much better than all you
know like an alcoholic
um ethanol extract because you know
alcohol doesn't evaporate off to like a
buck set 170 degrees Fahrenheit and by
the time it does it's evaporated away
most of the more you know monotropenes
and it has decarboxylated the
cannabinoids
um so I had this realization that if we
could consume uh higher amounts of
phytocannabinoids without
decarboxylating them we might find that
it's a better medicine for a lot of
people who are not trying to get uh like
loopy like if you have a little kid
that's housing seizures or like me a
little kid at the time that was going
through chemo you probably don't want
them all stoned out but if you can
actually give him
phytocannabinoids in hemp seed oil
um which in itself has a perfect balance
of essential fatty acids
um then you can actually medicate the
child without drugging the child for
lack of better terminology but people
would get it and that can be very
beneficial because cancer patients have
shown that using like a thousand
milligrams of
decarboxylated THC was beneficial for
the anti-inflammatory effects of like
reducing tumor sizes and my thought is
that you can actually take thousands of
milligrams of phytocannabinoids that are
not decarboxylated and have the
anti-inflammation properties without
being completely sleeping for the next
48 hours which is nice if you you know
if you're dying you want to be awake for
most of the rest of your life you know
and not completely drugged out in loopy
so um I really recommend that people
start looking at that you know home
growing is blowing up now that it's
legal and people have the ability of of
making their own medicine instead of
going out and buying it you know eighty
dollars an eighth in a jar they can have
big branches of it for practically
nothing so you know once they have an
abundance of cannabis I'm starting to
look at hemp seed oil
and pressure serving it is is much
better because if you make jars of
phytocannabinoid infused hemp seed oil
you can keep that in cold storage for a
very long time and those
phytocannabinoids and terpenes will
remain
um very violent viable and that the oil
smells amazing man some
flower chirping combinations smell so
good with the Nutty scent of hemp seed
oil it's crazy it's just absolutely
wonderful
um
so my little bit of advice to anyone is
to listen
that's great I'm gonna have to give that
a try myself actually
we've spoken a lot about some of the
more old school strains and so I would
be Keen to hear what are your thoughts
specifically on the new stuff you know
the hype exotic stuff so you're a fan of
it are you not a fan of it and will we
ever see any of it Blended in with some
of your lines
um sure I'm I love cannabis I'm a big
pothead I mean I probably smoke four
joints but we've been sitting here
talking but I I love pot I mean the
my complaints about the pot that has
been floating around prior to me
starting AG is that it's all very
similar and I think that is you know it
doesn't it's not good for the community
to the degree in which there's a lot
more diversity in the genetics that I've
experienced that we're seeing in the
marketplace so I'm trying to affect that
um
it's just that in a way
I don't think the high is as good as it
could be in on many levels I mean I
unfortunately think that
you know unless you grow your own
cannabis you you kind of don't
understand what I'm saying but there's
so much that happens negatively to
cannabis in post-harvest it's really
handling that ruins Paul's pot and when
people get it and they don't dry it
correctly and they lose some of those
terpenes in a Flash cure or a flash dry
and they bottle it up or it was too
moist and it kind of gets that funky
little smell that doesn't go away
um if it's not handle property properly
the variety itself isn't going to matter
and and and I've joked with people that
I can go pick hemp and cure it and dry
it properly and it'll smoke and taste
and smell better than some of the stuff
I get from commercial Farms just because
if you put the time into retaining the
terpenes and the oil content and doing
that slow dry and slow cure because a
lot of people don't understand well even
what's a cure well the flour is covered
with oil and think of it like varnish on
a piece of wood if you put varnish fish
on a piece of wood and you leave the
piece of wood in the Sun the the wood
soaks up the varnish and there's no
protective layer and if it rains on it
it kind of doesn't really uh repel it
but if you take that same varnished
piece of wood and you put it in the
shade and that that coat of oil doesn't
soak in but it thickens it then becomes
a protectant to the wood and you can
pour water on it and it just runs off
that happens on a microscopic level on
cannabis flowers and when people allow
that that thin covering of oil residue
to that waxiness to harden up it
protects the humidity that that's left
should be less than 10 percent but then
the bud has body it has flavor it has
terpenes present and it's a really good
smoke and I'm you know I'm I like fresh
pot I like smoking weed a week after I
cut it down and I can barely get it to
burn but it burns perfect because
there's so much oil content but then I
also like pot that I've let sit in the
freaking you know can a troll for eight
months or whatever like like literally I
have a lot of old weed I have our chaos
from last year I smoked some of it
earlier today and I still like it but
it's a year it's September last year so
now it's a year and a month old
um so but I don't sell it so I end up
with bags of weed you know and then they
turn brown after they oxidize because
the lights cut to them and you know and
it's freaking hilarious but if if you
cure it well and those oils are still
present the quality of it lasts a lot
longer so you know a lot of how you're
going to feel cannabis is is determined
by how well it was handled and how well
it was cured before it got to your plate
and um
yeah so I think if everybody if you had
every clone that all these people were
growing all the new stuff I bet you'd
grow great weed with it I bet you grow
it and you might leave it a little
longer you might bring it into late
stage you might let the little you know
little pistols wither away and turn into
little resin Globs like you might treat
it a little differently than the grower
that you got it from and you might like
it a little you might on the other side
you might Harvest it a little early
might like like the high a little
lighter and and that dial a high is
something a lot of people don't realize
either because like if you harvest early
you get a different Sensation from the
smoke if you harvest it late stage and
you know you can I you know take things
like Haze and let it go really late
stage and it's really trippy man and you
could take like afghanis and harvest
them early like week six week seven and
they're not heavy body highs they're
really almost kind hazy where they're
like light and trippy so trying to teach
people that there's so much more than
one-dimensional cannabis it's been kind
of tough because a lot of people don't
they just don't see the Spectrum you
know like you were saying they think
there's one there's one rks there was
one skunk and it's like no man it was a
body of plants it was like I don't even
know what region but but when I talked
to Rob Clark and I talked to Skunk Man
Sam you know Skunk Man Sam has gone
through Afghanistan and collected seeds
I believe them I don't know many other
people that have been there and done
that so and he has the genetics so what
the [ __ ] you know take his experience
and you know it's what it is but when
all those Afghans started coming over it
was this region that produced these
these plants that were like that and
I think that a lot of people are going
to find them again you know I think that
if you know if ever this world goes to
peace and stuff maybe
we would find a lot of these absolutely
amazing Hindu Kush Indian varieties
Chinese varieties Afghan Pakistan I mean
these these this is the birthplace of
cannabis people this is where we need to
go back and start looking around I mean
the Himalayas Nepal I mean I every time
I I see people that are in foreign
countries like this and they contact me
for seeds I'm like no no no you should
be going out and collecting seeds and
geographically collecting those so you
know where they came from what region
y'all got to give people up but make
them available bring them out of the
bring them to Market you know because
that's what we need to have happen again
you know I would love to be able to buy
seeds from Thailand tomorrow on Amazon
and then actually come from Thailand you
know or some seeds from Colombia or some
from Michoacan or Acapulco I please you
know
it'd be great I would be thrilled that
the only sad part is that I think
there's been a lot of you know
European seed Merchant influence in
almost all the Cannabis producing
regions around the world and
unfortunately almost all of it has been
contaminated with uh
good intention genetics
so when we move on to our final
questions we have a few fan submitted
questions that I think are interesting
and the first one is how far do you plan
on taking the Northern Lights lines like
do you see yourself going to like an F5
and F6 sort of thing and as a follow-up
would you ever release the famous
northern light as an S1 I think maybe
they're referring to purest Indica the
purest Indica
um you know what's funny is Greg told me
that he didn't send purest Indica in the
Neville and uh I get it and um
I'm going to release it because it's
Greg's wishes and I feel like I'm just
like you know I was on the phone with
Craig earlier today you know whatever
you want me to do is fine you know I
feel like I'm more of a conduit than I
am you know the the
you know I'm trusted and I'm lucky I I
I'm grateful that these people like me
and I'm grateful that they've entrusted
me with the genetics I don't know
another way to put it I am going to
release pierced Indica like I released
you know instead of just hybrids I kind
of wanted people to have the ability to
have these things isolated
um and as an F2 is the only way I can do
it realistically other than S1 in them
and S1 in them kind of takes away the
mailid ability of people to breed and
I'm I'm really not trying to stifle
other people's ability to work with
these genetics I'm trying to enable it
and um I do you know something that gets
confused though is taking things F2 F3
F4 F5 does not necessarily make them
better it does not necessarily make them
more stable according to Rob and
marijuana botany uh it creates more uh
really uh
uh more variation within the prodigies
the further you get into this inbreeding
so uh you're always you know cannabis is
an obligant outcrosser just like humans
it doesn't want to be inbred with its
family it wants to be outcrossed if you
really want to make good things
um I'm definitely going to make the
genetics I have available to people as I
have been like you know F2 and the haze
the skunk and um the NL but I've been
selling hybrids of my own since I
started they were the first things I
started selling for the where the
crosses with on Haze and I'm going to
continue to be making you know I'm just
so into it like I'm going to constantly
release the genetics because you know
you only live so long and you know I'd
like to you know leave as big of a mark
on the planet as I can in a positive way
before I check out which I will
inevitably do at some point so you know
trying to get it out there is cool and
you know as long as I'm improving what
I'm doing I'm gonna keep doing it but
like trying to you know these people
that are like oh F 99 or whatever it's
like cut out with the [ __ ] really
you know I mean I'm happy with the
really good F1 inconsistency and
uniformity like you know head over heels
for the serious seeds offerings that
Simon puts out because they're true f1s
and uh and he'll always put out awesome
weed because they're true f1s and uh and
I'll make I'll always be making F ones
and S ones and when it's appropriate
like it is right now I'll be making f2s
but I don't see myself
you know I don't know you know once
you've once you have I I'll make
original hay seeds again when I run low
on the amount I've already made if that
makes sense but there's no need for me
to to replicate it now while I still
have pretty good quantity of original AC
it's for 2019
um but I will in the future I mean I you
know I have dreams of of
you know I've you know I want all the
plants all the plants I'm a gardener you
know I I you know people like how can
you have 4 000 plants and what else and
I'm like so easy like I was partying all
the time too if I had actually been
focused I would have had 40 000 flights
in that [ __ ] place I it's just you
just you want all the phenotypes you
want to go through all of them you want
to try all of them you know and what's
funny is I would have thrown 90 of those
plants away and only taken the 10 that I
really liked if I had left to my own
devices and allowed to continue on what
I was doing and now it's the same way I
go through [ __ ] tons of plants I throw
[ __ ] tons of plants away though like you
know I won't replicate anything that I
don't fall in love with you know so if
it and testing to me is not as important
as falling in love with it if
if it doesn't you know if it doesn't
appeal to the human I really don't care
if it appeals to the machine
you know I'm not doing this to have fast
quarter mile times or the highest THC
levels you know I I think a lot of
that's missing the point entirely
yeah no very comprehensive I like that
and it sort of segues nicely into the
next question which is if you had to
give a generalized answer where would
you like to see the future of breeding
going
quality over quantity
you know that's my goal I mean I'm
I I think that we're gonna see the
bottleneck kind of come off and we're
going to see cannabis varieties you know
from all weeks of its potential uh start
to surface as time goes on and more and
more and more people are going to
realize that you know there's a lot more
you know it's cannabis than just you
know quick thick buds that are full of
resin you know there's nuances to these
terpenes and these you know subtle
cannabinoid combinations that are
amazing I mean Mel Frank told me one of
his favorite varieties that he grew and
he smoked he got tested and he came back
at like sub nine percent THC and he was
like
didn't expect that you know but the way
it smelled the way it tasted the way it
made him feel felt great and
you know that's that you know if that
makes sense you know what I mean like
really I guess it isn't just THC at the
end of the conversation that matters
it's did you enjoy it and if you didn't
enjoy you're probably not going to smoke
any more of it but if you did enjoy it
you'd probably be quick to roll up
another you know second or third joint
do a second or third dab you know
yeah he hear quality over quantity for
sure final fan submitted question we
have is how did you develop your cloning
Tech with the domes and the fluorescent
lighting or did you get that from
someone else
I was all Tech I mean um so I don't use
domes downstairs right now I have a a
humidity controlled room I I monitor my
BPD levels I keep my mother room at
around 72 to 75 degrees Fahrenheit and I
keep my humidity around 70 you know uh
and if you keep your humidity levels at
high the plants don't wither
um the domes are when I was living in La
it's a lot more dry so if you were
looking at that rack of uh shells that
was from the the sake that was from
select strains when I started my Nursery
um that was one of the Clone racks for
my Nursery
um but Ellie's a really dry place so in
order to compensate for the dryness I
can't humidify the whole room and I had
hardwood floors and you don't want to
humidify a room with hardwood floors so
so I just use domes and they work rather
good
um
cloning's easy I mean I've it my problem
has been I've had too green of a thumb
you know it's gotten me in trouble over
and over again I got out of prison in
2004 and in between all the activism
that I explained I got prosecuted in
2006 2009 uh and also 2013 through 2017
uh for cultivating cannabis I was rated
in 20 2006 2009 and 2012 and I wouldn't
cooperate so
I got prosecuted every single time and
um
I think there's no other way to do it
actually but um it's been a pain and and
this is why kind of now I'm kind of
doing what I'm doing because I'm able to
kind of grow on a small scale and it is
all about quality it's not about
quantity and it's you know I kind of
feel like I'm doing a service for the
community it sounds weird but it's true
no I I don't have I don't know
I'm already happy I'm already where I
want to live I'm already you know doing
what I want to do so like I said my life
hasn't changed much in the time I've
started the seed company
you know in many cases I'm using the
same table same equipment I was using
before I had the seed company so you
know I'll just continue this I mean I
could see in the future trying to sell
authentic genetics to a bigger company
so that I could you know get like my own
Winery and and have my own crew and have
greenhouses and be able to on a much
larger scale be able to breed that would
be my dream and be able to then sell the
you know the plants the seeds that I
make through my you know sold company
because you know there's a part of me
that doesn't want to be a secretary it
doesn't enjoy the business side of it as
much as I just enjoy growing that's
where my heart is that's where my
passion is I like writing I like
creating content educating you know
sitting there you know sending invoices
and packing seeds is
rather a burden but I'm grateful for it
but it's
not exactly what I wanted to be when I
grew up you know but
it's cool I'm dealing with it for the
time being
my eyes hurt from doing emails but it's
cool now I can understand yeah you're a
man who wants to be among the clients
not the computer screens I feel for you
so with that we're on to our final five
quick questions before we wrap this one
up we'd love to ask everyone these
questions so the first one is what's the
single most memorable experience with
cannabis you've ever had
I'm probably getting my mom that first
time in the car because it was so what
the [ __ ] you know this is like I just
they never I never I never felt that way
before Giddy and hungry and like
everything was funny and I didn't have
any pain I wasn't nauseous and you know
when you're going through cancer
you're feeling pretty low you know like
you're depressed you're you physically
ache you're you're mentally strained
you're worried you're anxious and to be
able to get high
you Cannon I can't underestimate that I
was just was a huge difference you know
and uh that's probably why I became such
a passionate Advocate and activist
because
it made a really deep impact on my life
and my health and my well-being and I
feel grateful to it because of it
yeah powerful
so on the other end of the spectrum was
there ever a time when maybe all your
peers or your friends are really hyping
something up and you're getting really
excited for it and then you finally try
and you're like this is it
what is runs
no that's cute but you know Skittles was
one of those two you know I'm old so
when I first got handed a skittles but I
was like guys I smell skunk one and
they're like Skittles I'm like one it's
you know because I don't know some of
the because I've had the ability to work
with some of these old genetics and
their piriform I kind of can smell them
I could see the primary colors if that
makes sense I could smell the primary
colors coming through so yeah you can't
really hide it and um
it's happened more than once you know a
lot of the stuff that's come out in the
last you know cookies please you know
like a lot of the stuff that's come out
has been like
it's okay you know I mean I like cookies
I'll smoke cookies sometimes it's really
good uh sometimes not so great uh Jack
Harris same thing you know I used to
love Jack Herer when we first got it
from Scentsy sense of seeds when it was
really hazy but then they changed it in
1996 it crossed it with the skunk kind
of imitated the SSH
um
it was their version of SSH it was
called Jack Flash and it was a heavier
version that came out around 1996 from
Scentsy seeds and they kind of replaced
Jack hero with Jack Flash and a lot of
the Jack Hera that we now refer to 1997
on what is really Jack Flash and it's
really like a super silver hage-ish
because it's really a haze a cross with
skunk which is what super silver haze
was it was Neville's head across the
skull so it was a similar recipe done a
little differently with similar plants
um
but
and it's funny because I like the
original Jack Curry and I like the
original Neville say it's more than I
like the super silver A's or the Jack
Flash but Jack Frost xj39 a lot of these
Jack crosses that we see now are not
very hazy
um but I don't you know Jack his kids
are using the name and they're trying to
create a brand and I'm not trying to
exploit an old friend and I you know I I
I have Haze so I can make really hazy
stuff and one thing people talk about
Jack Cara really they're smelling a
little bit of haze but I have the whole
pie so I can make stuff that's way
hazier than the Jack Herer hazy hybrids
that are floating around right now so
uh it's like different if that makes
sense so
I'm definitely going to be bringing way
more Haze hybrids back in the years to
come because it's my fancy and my
fascination
and because I have the genetics yeah
exciting to see that happen
so if you could only pick one for the
rest of your life what would you pick
indoor or outdoor
I'm indoor all day I don't like birds
[ __ ] on my flowers I don't think
that's very sanitary and the problem
with growing Outdoors is that you're
you're
susceptible to Mother Nature she you
know she gives you can work so hard and
so true and so valiantly and she just
comes along and has it really damp you
know August or a really dry one or you
know [ __ ] fires and that you get fall
out and you know or some Kid Next Door
is freaking playing with some seeds and
he pops some nails and next thing you
knew you've got fertilized flowers that
you didn't expect to have because pollen
travels really easily so I think there's
a lot of drawbacks to outdoor I think
outdoor will mostly be used for extracts
um because it can be cleaned up I think
that small batch outdoor can be freaking
awesome because there's nothing like the
Sun but my favorite is mixed light
indoor greenhouse because my Greenhouse
also has led supplementation and I have
you know VPD control and Heat and the
ability to cool it off and it's you know
I'm Mother Nature at that point if the
environment [ __ ] up it's my fault not
hers I'm just you know surfing the wave
as she gives it to me on hot days or dry
days or rainy days I just readjust the
equalizer that's my greenhouse and try
to stay in my perimeters and keep my
plants happy and I like that I prefer to
have a roof over my plant's head and I I
like avoiding the winds and everything
but I still grow indoors for practical
reasons because
I got to keep Mother plants and I got to
keep clones and you're not going to do
that in the sunshine and I also
um I like indoor flowers I think they're
great and it gives me an ability to kind
of see the expressions of the phenotypes
in a controlled environment uh where
everything's equal you know where when
you're outside you know one can get a
little more sun or what could be in a
little sweet spot but when it's indoors
it's it's they're all sweet spots or
you're not setting up your environment
correctly so for testing reasons I'll
always be an indoor grower you know for
you know Greenhouse I'll always have a
greenhouse too but I'll always yeah but
outdoor I don't I like putting plants
Outdoors I've done it many times but I
don't know I feel like it's like rolling
dice with mother nature maybe you'll get
a good harvest
but she's mad maybe about
no I completely agree with you I
completely agree so I'm interested to
know if I'm going to drop you off on a
desert island and you can only take
three strains with you for the rest of
your life what three are you gonna take
I would be his for sure it would be now
Northern Lights probably
oh I don't know nl2 or purest Indica
would have to be one of those two that's
really tough that would be tough maybe
the pure St Indica but then I wouldn't
have an Afghan to make the nl2
um and then third
Ah that's tough you know for the
diversity of it it would be something
similar to to skunk one because I like
the tropicalness of it and when I say
skunk one
I I like the sweet version of of skunk
one as well as the acrid version I found
in the Mel Franks old seeds uh so I kind
of I like the fruity tropical varieties
um and and if I had Haze skunk one even
the the sweet skunk one and
uh either the purest indicator or the
nl2 I'd be pretty happy because at that
point I would have the gassy I would
have the fruity and I have the spicy and
I would be thrilled I guess and then I
could make all sorts of great [ __ ]
because
and I need a few more lifetimes on the
island just because of all the Hybrids
I'd want to make
you know and then time to test them of
course and then time to make cash with
them covering all the bases I like it I
like it on to our final question one I'd
love to ask everyone if you could get in
a time machine and go back in time
anywhere you wanted any time presumably
to collect either seeds or a cutting
where would you go and what would you be
collecting
that's heavy man
um
That's Heavy I came home from Amsterdam
with over 50 000 seats and
they were stolen from me when I got
raided and
I don't know that's tough because I had
such a diversity in genetics at that
point I wish I could have my old seeds
because I it sounds really weird to say
but I admit I it hurt to lose them it
took me up to that point a lifetime of
collecting so and then they took them
all and I just
uh that hurt and uh I don't know like
that I could still see him in front of
me I just I don't know
that's partly why people listening you
know partly how I got the the deal from
Peter is uh
he offered me 10 grand and he offered me
uh that skunk Nancy I'm calling me right
now actually
um they he
he offered me 10 grand and eight percent
of my book and I turned him down and
then I had mailed back some seeds and
when I mailed them back uh
he was there with me when I opened the
packages the boxes he had boxes too I
sent him goodies as well
so I'm sure the statue of limitations as
long as long up but uh but I started
pulling seeds out instead of hash and
grass which is what he wanted I started
pulling seeds out packages of 1 000 all
neatly marked with the varieties and he
was shocked you know and when he grabbed
a bag of seeds he was like how much is a
seed worth and I was like I don't know
five bucks 10 bucks
and he's like this little bag he's worth
10 grand and I was like yeah and there
was like a pile and a half of there was
a huge amount of in front of me and he
was like how many seats are there I sent
an excess of 50 000 and he said
no wonder you said no to my money and he
was like what are you gonna do with
those and I was like hopefully keep them
you know but I want to start you know I
want to start a seed company and he said
no you have to keep them he's like you
have to grow them every one of them
they're important and I was just like oh
my God and he was just like
would you take a quarter million would
that would that would like we I'll give
you a credit card too but like let's get
you started and I was just like
yeah and he literally turned to my
girlfriend and and he was like you still
have the keys to my car because we had
used this car and now I said and he said
yeah I said yeah she said yes and he
said let's bring them to the bank before
he changes his mind and he got up in a
robe with [ __ ] shower shoes little
[ __ ] fuzzies because he was gay he
was hilarious and a bird running around
on his shoulders [ __ ] on his white
robe and he had us drive him down to the
Wells Fargo Bank in L.A and we walked in
this dude's wearing a robe and got Bed
Head for days and we go in there and the
manager runs up to him he's like Mr
McWilliams how are you doing would you
like some organic milk we have it in the
fridge for you and he's like yeah sure
and if he whisks us out of the manager's
office and just it was that easy Peter's
like I want to put a quarter million
dollars uh into his bank account he's
going to need a company card what else
do you need and I was like I can't think
of much more now and he's like we'll get
back to you if we need more stuff it was
like my life changed in a minute and I
and that's kind of how it happened I
mean I immediately started looking for a
place to live I found the castle
which was utterly ridiculous but had a
lot of space I moved into it and I had a
[ __ ] I literally had a a
card with no limit I Peter was like
very encouraging he was very wealthy at
the time and he was like he thought he
he was dying I mean unfortunately he
died two and a half years after we met
and um he just he was living like his
life was ending and uh and I had no
limit so I bought [ __ ] Diamond lights
and [ __ ] built the tables brought
electricians in I [ __ ] everything was
amazing man I put my ballast in my
Elevator Shaft because I had this like
70 foot Elevator Shaft that went from
the ground floor all the way up and I
put massive fans in my attic and I
pulled the air all the way through fresh
air from my garage which was like a six
car garage I had 38 lights in one room
and I used to pull all the air through
up into my Elevator Shaft up the
Elevator Shaft and threw out of the
house the place was incredible it was
located directly across from something
called The Stone Canyon reservoir and it
created this little humid Zone in the
canyon I lived in and I didn't even have
to use domes when I made clones it was
like perfect VPD all the time and I was
crazy like you could put any plant you
wanted outside and it loved it I had
plants going up my staircases all over
my patios in the courtyard I had them
everywhere I took this Haze plant that
was like I'd say almost 16 feet tall and
dragged it into my elevator with a
twisty fluorescent light bulb and the
plant was like half bent over so when
you got in the elevator this Haze plant
was like really big leaves but super
thin and like it was weird it was like a
big bear hugging you that would be just
stopped in the corner and the stem was
like bent all the way all the way over
at an angle and then I put a little
table in it where you could do suit like
single bong hits as you took elevator
rides it was a kid's fantasy it was
really what it was I mean for a stoner
psychedelic pot grower it was [ __ ]
great while it lasted you know and I
don't know I don't regret it it was it
was a lot of fun I
I never planned for it to happen I I
hope nobody listening thinks that I had
some stupid dream of moving to Bel Air
and growing [ __ ] thousands of plants
in a [ __ ] Mansion but it just it's
good it's what happened you know it's
just sometimes when you're letting life
take you takes you some strange places
you know
that's it I think that's the the theme
of this interview it's taking us to some
strange places but nevertheless
incredibly knowledgeable insightful very
grateful to have been able to hear all
your insights I think that's just about
the end of it did you have any comments
or shout outs you wanted to make
no we've talked about a lot you know it
was really an assortment and talk with
you go over this stuff I mean I hope
it's inspirational to people listening
you know if anything I think that's been
the point of my life is to inspire
others and I've been very inspired so it
was great to have this inspiring
conversation with you and thank you for
taking the time and I hope people enjoy
it it's the longest conversation I've
ever had on a podcast
but I've never gone over this much
material and
you know for the history books
and there you have it friends part two
of two with the legend Todd McCormick of
AGC code
huge shout out and thank you again for
taking the time to stop by share all
your knowledge and thoughts on various
topics we've discussed and a little bit
of an idea for what might come in the
future
foreign
as usual we want to give another quick
shout out to our fantastic sponsors CTN
our best seeds in the game you know them
you love them go check them out
[Music]
copper biological systems your number
one choice for beneficial predators and
keeping any pests or pathogens at Bay
check out the appy param despite Ox
vital both killer products
likewise pro-mix connect your number one
mycorrhizal product from the good people
at promix you know them you love them
they've been around forever try their
mycorisa product I promise it's amazing
highest score count there is guaranteed
viability your plants are gonna just go
insane
and last but not least your buds at
Charlie's cannabis check them out if
you're in Oklahoma there's no other
choice simply the highest quality
available exciting genetics newfinos and
new strains on the horizons always check
them out our good buddies better known
in-house produced Charlie's a bird
finally a huge shout out to the patreon
gang you have a lifeblood of the show
you guys helped to ensure the episodes
continue to be made if you want early
access to content you want to hear
unheard interviews get access to
exclusive giveaways prizes Discord so
much more go check out the patreon
www.patreon.com
that's it friends thanks for joining me
again for this one guys making up to the
end I'll see you for the next one
Zoo