hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for buddy
enthusiasts so here we have it folks the
second part of the podium today as
always this episode was brought to us by
organic gardening solutions for 20
Australia and all think bode ID ready to
jump back into it here we go a little
bit of a two-parter how do you feel
about the idea of certain gear or cuts
so to speak having kind of bad but I
just sociated with and this is an idea
I've heard a few times I guess the most
notable example would be you know and I
could be wrong here but I think I'm
pretty correct I'm fairly confident that
Indian guys specific instructions
whether he didn't want anyone to like
kind of F to the g13 hash plant that
seems to have kind of happened you know
I know that you bury that you didn't F
to assess we're not talking about you
obviously do you feel that like in that
such situation where someone has made it
fairly clear their intentions and then
some other party has kind of done the
opposite of that do you feel there is
such a thing as kind of bad vibes
associated with that year or not
necessarily it's just a shame that that
person's intentions were respected I
think it's kind of a shame I mean I
think it applies in different ways like
I think for Indiana it's a special kind
of thing because he's kind of like a
deep grandfather of a lot of people like
he's an old-timer and he was a big seed
collector and he has a lot of amazing
stuff and he's very altruistic and he's
in giving and he gives he'll give you
know the most rare seeds effort to like
some new guy that you know maybe that
just started like he he's he's kind of
like this unique Santa Claus and I think
for someone that does that I mean I've
heard him get in trouble too of giving
out stuff that he's not supposed to but
he for him I think you know with elders
especially I think we should kind of
respect that and his whole thing was he
wanted that strain to be kind of like he
wanted to be free he wanted people to
enjoy
and you want to do it in this big thing
was yeah you can make hybrids but you
can't Hut you can't f2 it for money so
I'm pretty sure you can give it away but
you know talk to him for a while but
there does seem to be a lot of those
kind of strange cuts and it's mostly
people just kind of I understand if
they're really rare and if people spend
a tremendous amount of time or it's
enough or it's it's a family strain that
goes back generations but I think that's
where communication comes in if you know
if people are open and they communicate
about what they want to do what things
are there doesn't need to be bad blood
or things and it's sad when a string
gets that kind of energetic kind of gunk
on it because it holds that you know
just like every seed is kind of a prayer
that's just waiting to be popped open
and through epigenetics it holds not
only its history going back through time
but all the cultures that you don't
realize it like a seed is this I mean
people don't realize how amazing it is
it's this kind of dusky jewel that that
that transforms time into you know into
a tangible way to interact with it so
yeah it's it's basically like a
bejeweled time machine that holds
everything so I think you know these
seeds and clones and everything are very
sick and very special and they don't
need to have this thing around and I you
know there are instances where like I
said with families I'll hold that but I
don't know it's tricky I think it comes
down to really to communication and if
people have something that you want them
that you want to keep to yourself you
probably shouldn't give it out because
things get out you know people are human
and it's like if you give it out it's
probably gonna get out and it's it's you
know I don't know I understand it from
all different things all different
viewpoints but really it's a joke comes
down to communication I think and that's
where it's gonna happen you know yeah
sure so are there any cuts which you
don't like to work with from maybe say
the kind of the more modern elite clones
maybe not necessarily due to what we
were just talking about but maybe just
in general you don't particularly like
working with them are there any you know
kind of popular modern elite clones that
fall into that category for you you know
I veer away from work of
and breeders that I don't jive with I
would step back to everybody but at some
time I won't usually breed with clones
from someone that I are lies on jive
with so much and four clones you know
and I don't know if there's a lie if
it's a really like if it has a lot of
drama around it I kind of stay away with
it from unless unless I know who it came
from and I can kind of communicate with
them like gg4 like you know I know
either I can communicate and I could
offer up what I what I want to do and
they could respect that and I could
respect them and that could happen like
you know and people that have special
things like if there's a communication
there I think it's okay and but there
are a lot of clones that just get out
into the wild and people go with it and
if people get uptight and no no it's
it's none of those kind of communication
things it's such a strange thing I wish
people would kind of stop chasing these
clones and really just start popping
their seat collections you know and also
you know I could see kind of like a new
interesting trend it's like before I
would just be these amazing clones that
people would have that pop up like the
cams and the ojiisan now but now you're
seeing people that have that have kind
of like a good vibe and a good internet
presence like a picture later or skunk
master flex you'll have like the GMO
cookies and caps got the Mac and just
from their good vibes and them hyping it
on their up their strain that they
really like that they've created they've
kind of created their own elites and I
think so not we're not just finding me
more we're kind of creating them and I
think that I was gonna show people that
anyone can find these special elites and
then hey if people have a problem it's
like then you have a your own special
elite you guys can trade it's like I
think people should stop chasing and
start creating you know I think people
we have so much to uncover that it's
kind of we don't want to just be chasing
our tails anymore even though it's fun
and the strains are pretty cool these
days but I think there's a lot more to
really explore so with that in mind how
important do you feel it is that new
seeds are constantly being popped
because for example in Australia
I find people aren't don't really pop
that many seeds so to speak at least on
average and I try to tell them in my
opinion at least it seems like that's
what drives the progression of the scene
in a way you know like the new things
coming out that people can enjoy you
know how do you feel about that and does
that play into your philosophy of making
everyone's because it's almost a way of
facilitating that yeah I mean in
California it's kind of different is
there's a clone culture and it's kind of
changing now especially without doing
people realizing that seeds are just so
much more vibrant in the root system is
so much more amazing and they don't have
all the STDs that all the clones do but
you know California is it is a clone
culture and it's a hype culture it's
driven by music is driven by coolness is
driven by you know thing you know you
know even if a strain maybe isn't the
ultimate strain if you get rappers
smoking and rapping about it you know
cookies a good example cookies amazing
strain it's really cool but there's a
lot of drama around there's a lot of
people saying you know this and that and
it makes cool hybrids it's neat but it's
people are you know it takes for people
just people will latch onto something
and just take it you know just hammer it
to the ground and it's it's like kind of
sad for the strain itself it's like I
would love to see people popping seeds
and I think it's happening more and I
think people are getting more into it I
just worry about the future and the way
things are going you know maybe
eventually mr. Khanna's because really
cheaper and there's lots of brands and
there's lots of people pumping it out
that people won't really have the
impetus to pop seeds maybe people just
do it ornamentally or just for crafts
but I really think that yeah everything
comes from a seed and it all of our best
stuff is always that's just where it
comes from I mean that's its origin
that's where you're gonna find it and
that's where we should be looking yes I
mean if we kind of tap into the mindset
of the people who are kind of promoting
that clone community at least
subconsciously a lot of what I hear from
these types of folk is that you know the
the elite clones are just so far
superior to you know most things you'd
get out of seeds that storm is not worth
bothering with seeds with that in mind
do you find there's a big variation
between the elite
like do you find that there are some
cuts that definitely consider delete you
know they're just phenomenal in every
way then there are others which may be
considered elite by the masses but they
just really kind of don't stand up
compared to the other one for example
yeah I think too there's also sometimes
in the clone world you get a lot of
different clones like I'm sure they're
you know there's at least two blue dream
clones there's a really good blue dream
clone that I love I think where dreams
also by Blue Gene gets a lot of flack
and I think it's because people grow the
really bland quicker more indica version
of blue dream and I don't know I think
there's clones that are at least because
they have a history they've performed
for you know 10 20 years and they have a
really special uniqueness to them and
they always kind of hit home just where
you want them and then there's a lot of
the especially in the new hyper Turkey
kind of I call it kind of a pop art
breeding kind of like derivative
breeding where it's people are
everybody's kind of everything's
derivative of itself and people are
smashing everything together and it's
kind of that Andy Warhol style breeding
where it's very neon it's very flashy
it's bright it's loud you're really
hitting all the boxes with flavor and
smell and it's more for the kind of like
recreational kind of dab culture that
loves the more they love the enjoyment
of the flavors and tastes more than
maybe so the effects or the the origins
and so you know it's it kind of comes
down to it it's like if I'm an elite
spin on leap for more than five years I
think it you know like oh gee no one's
gonna dispute that that's not an awesome
plan Kim Kim as no one's gonna dispute
that but there's new stuff that comes
online and people chase everyday that
you know that and it's hard for me I
like to I find it fascinating and I'd
love to try all these new things and I
trying to keep abreast you know like all
the new stuff like the purple punches
and the Sunday drivers and the orange
trees and the lemons this and then I
love checking all those out and I loved
seeing that but you know a lot of times
those don't last more than a year or two
you know then 16 with cookies cookies is
a great well it's it's held itself up
and you know people love it and it's
probably last in the test of time but
there's a lot of derivatives kind of
one offs that pop in enough kind of like
bubbles they probably surface people get
really into it and when enough people
try it they're kind huh so I think it's
more elites it's what what passes the
test of time you know and so do you ever
have any intentions of ever delving back
into some of the really old-school stock
like you know SSS say for example we've
got the temple you know a good example
of where you've done that would you ever
be interested in doing it more and if
not is that because you know the future
excites you so much
oh no I love vintage lines and that's
kind of my one of my things for
Supernatural selections is like I really
get to get deeper into those and I
actually have a lot of stuff going on
right now that you know some of my old
stuff of like beaches choice and NL too
and you know like all these really
unique old vintage ones I have on you
know from older seed companies I have I
have a really nice friend who was
instrumental in some of the early Nevel
working since you work he and he sends
me some really cool stuff and I love
getting stuff from him and sometimes
it's old junk and it turns out funny but
I just love seeing it because it's like
a snapshot to a snapshot to a bygone era
you know it's like you really get to see
and it's neat to see what people
remember and then what they're really
the reality is you know because you know
over time people granule eyes their
memories and they change and but I love
vintage stuff it's one of my favorite
things to pop and then whenever I can I
do you know if and I have a quite a good
collection of vintage seeds but I can
only do so much and since I do kind of
have to work on a couple different
levels I kind of have to partition
myself so let's say like 50 percent goes
to Bodhi seeds and then 10 percent goes
to vintage and 10 15 percent goes to
Norika and now I think maybe like 30
percent will go to supernatural
selections so I just I have to find that
kind of pie chart that makes everything
move forward so I can pay the rent and
also explore everything I can and also
you know follow my own passion and also
create things so people can follow their
own passion but yeah I would love to see
more vintage stuff come out and I I
really get excited and I love
stuff that Mean Gene pulls out of his
hat well he has a lot of cool vintage
stuff and yeah people are just popping
on the woodwork with all these unique
lines I'm like whoa that still exists
you know it's like wow someone has that
it's I'm excited about vintage lines
yeah I mean speaking on one specifically
talked of Kabul has always been one
that's being quite interesting to me and
I think it's probably because of the
elusive any of it so to speak
what was that strain like and do you
ever plan to use it again or have you
maybe lost it you know I like talkable I
like all those rough although Afghan
ease their their little you know it
depends on what you're getting there a
little bit blend the talking football
was unique in that you know it's from
Marx Castle mark is like he's an amazing
old character guy I think he kind of
hyped it up a little bit cuz I don't
from what I don't totally agree with
what he said about it maybe I didn't
grow it to its full potential or even
outdoors but to me it's a really nice
commercial eff like modern and Afghani
like it's kind of that bland but dark
it's got the raw power of Afghani it's
got good good strength but as a breeding
plant its kind of bland and kind of blah
in a way but for where it is you know I
I'm not growing it in the arid high
desert of Afghanistan and I'm not really
making I'm sure making hash with it is
phenomenal and that's kind of what I use
it in is one of my deep line I'll coming
crosses which is kind of focusing on the
kind of like traditional plants that
were used for hash making and kind of
hybridizing those with the g13 hash plan
or other indicas and it's it's a cool
plan it's also he also had another one
called warlord that came from the same
thing in the whole deal with that was I
guess there was a was in like 2002 or 96
one of it was way back when somewhere
the Special Forces went in rated of
warlord and there was growing a lot of
really amazing cannabis for hash and it
was the big talk in Kabul everybody
loved that hash and the Special Forces
went in and raided it and someone
grabbed the seeds and brought them back
from that
so it was one of those cool kind of like
all those old it really cool Afghani to
have that backstory kind of like a link
technology has its backstory and you
know everyone I like those old kind of
things and they actually if we're
talking about crazy old Afghani style
stuff straight Fox got some seeds from I
think it's from his brother who served
over in Iraq in Rania and those seeds
are amazing like it is like a dead
ringer for like if you could take pure
Kush and cookies and put them together
like this
spicy bread II like Persian bakery smell
and like it's really beautiful heavy
body like it reminds me kind of like the
Hollywood pure cush the one or the LA
pure Krishnaji like one but the more
like feminine cushy kind of baby power
ask one like there's some amazing yeah
kind of like the LA pure but kind of
more in the kind of the bubble realm but
with but yeah there's some of those old
Afghan ease are amazing and that's kind
of what I'm excited this year I'm doing
a lot of really old weird Afghan ease
outside I'm doing like my artifact one
which is kind of like the Afghani that
everybody remembers but no one's been
able to procure like that super accurate
almost roadkill like cabbagey kind of
like a deep chunky but not as bland as
deep chunk kind of this really raw kind
of like I don't know it smells like a
prison basketball game or something I
don't know but you know I just like
exploring all the weirdest things but
yeah the taco cabal cool line cool
breeder but on its own I don't think
that the best it's interesting because
you just touched on about four or five
questions which we'll get to soon enough
first question though I'm a huge deep
chunk fan I'm a huge Tom Hill thinner I
love all of his work even mentioned
about this at the Emerald cup I've never
found a deep chunk which I was satisfied
with the flavor kind of like how you
describe the talk of Kabul it was always
a bit lackluster in my opinion did you
have you found the same like I mean I've
found good use for it as a breeding tool
because you know there's still a lot of
desirable characteristics around it but
you know have you ever found a female
where you were like damn you know this
has got a good taste as well as all
those other deep chunk traits you know
long time ago I found one deep chunk and
I was like I call it like the sativa
Fein arson by which it's not of course
it was just a little bit more stretchy
and a little bit more flavorable and it
was kind of a seemed like a throwback
that's the only other one I mean other
than that they all they're so in bred
and they're so you know I mean that
plant is like full-on dinosaur Jurassic
Park like it must have been inbred
through some families in Afghanistan for
hundreds of years like it is like
basically it's also the ultimate like
fun learning Afghani to breed with that
was my first Afghani that I really got
into and kind of bread with and even I
did some of my early lines I wore deep
crosses it turns everything into Z chunk
which is amazing but you get just like
you know what I mean it just it is like
terminator of plants and it has a really
cool effect like my sister really those
deep chunk like just makes her laugh and
it makes her feel good it has a really
it has that classic just take you home
Huggy kind of vibe I mean it doesn't
always behave indoors like you know all
the Tom stuff is more for outdoors
anyways and that's where I was bred but
deep chunk you know it's like if we were
teaching a course like it's the textbook
Afghan like you can't get any more like
textbook Afghan even like like that's
kind of like if you ever saw that
picture of Richard Evan Schall T's and
wherever he wasn't Afghanistan he's
standing by those really squat old
plants I think I was in the 40s like it
looks that basically looks like deep
chunk and that I think deep chunk is
it's pretty cool even though I don't
really enjoy breeding with it because it
just turns everything in deep trunk now
ever found that myself a lot I found one
male where kind of isn't so dominant
like it turns everything phenotypically
into deep chunk but I found this one now
where a lot of the mothers kind of the
high and the taste seems to shine
through so I'm enjoying playing with
that but like Jesus that flavor has got
some serious issues with it like but on
another little interesting side note I
found a female that had just this
amazing highest where it must have had a
really significant percentage CBD in it
but I called it the face melter cuz it
was great you know it was like having um
I mean like a warm water port over your
face it was awesome like a massage yeah
I missed those like yeah like a body
massage bud
yeah so I mean just dipping back on a
thing you mentioned a few questions ago
do you think there is you know a certain
amount of romanticism around strains
from years gone by I mean the typical
ones being you know haze ty roadkill
skunk that's a great one you know I've
never experienced the roadkill skunk
myself so I'm still a bit on the fence
especially because a lot of the people
who I I really trust their opinions they
speak so highly of it but I mean I hear
stories about you know people will say
like oh you know you'd smell it in a
guy's pocket before it even walked in
the house and it's like is that really
true like I've never had anything close
to that happen to me with modern
cannabis was it really that strong uh
you know I I think there was a lot of
really special old strains back there
and I think you know what they always
say is like if you remember the 60s you
weren't there kind of thing I think
there's a lot of there's a lot of old
stoners that have a lot of fond memories
of their youth and they kind of believe
in things but there was some strains
that really stood out and especially I
think a lot of the import from these
point of origin places where they had
all the terroir and they had all that
and they brought it through those things
would really they would really ring some
bells and you know the roadkill
strengthing I mean that's it that's
something that I've been kind of playing
with for years and I can't get it right
like I've done so many different hybrids
and so many out crosses and I can get
like it get almost right but then it it
won't cure out skunky or you know or
it'll be too pissy or it won't be strong
enough like you know it's there and I
really think that with the roadkill
stunk yeah I think it was probably a
really hideous old Afghani one of those
Afghani that was bred forever to be
super super strong for their hash and I
think it really kicked people's ass but
you know it also got people busted and I
also think that that terpene I think it
must have some kind of a lower molecular
weight or something because I think it
vaporizes pretty quick because outside
it'll smell for blocks like people so
you know of course people are getting it
busted like you can't miss it it's my
the whole neighborhood smells like a
dead skin but on the line for two weeks
it'll smell like that but week three all
of a sudden the terpenes vaporize are
they something a torch
and it doesn't it doesn't hold so I
don't know I know you know people
reminisce about that light green golf
ball super killing you smell through
your pocket and those strains do exist
but I don't know I mean I'm hoping to
have something close by the end of the
summer but you know I'm not on time I
don't like here I'm just more of a fun
thing but it's it's difficult you know
but cannabis puts out every imaginable
smell you can think of it somehow you
can get it to create that from onions to
passionflower to like fruit loops it's
there and you can bring it out and I
think it's just I think really it's a
combination of maybe some kind of
Colombian Afghani or maybe even like a
some kind of really oil cannae like
motor oil kind of Afghani sativa mixed
with a with the kind of some kind of
grueling acrid low low I don't know it's
it's there I think people can find it
and I think people will and I think
people whether they created or someone
digs it out of their trunk I think it's
still out there I think it's just it
just was kind of selected against in in
the 80s and 90s and you know mid 90s is
when all the fruity stuff came in all
the bubble gums and blueberries and all
that funny gross stuff it kind of went
by the wayside everybody wanted the kind
of you know all the groovy fruity bubbly
stuff and that even put the nail and
coffin even deeper for it so what's your
favorite flavor of cannabis I don't know
you know I I really like effects but if
I had to have a flavor you know I do
like that really bright lemon pine-sol
of OG I like the mouth I like the stuff
you can taste but you know if I had to
really pin it down I like the really
like deep roasted kind of Bubba spice
kind of baked goods and sweets and and
then I like they're really feminine like
she must like the stuff that's just kind
of really engages your neurons like
makes you like stuff that you would like
sexy smells I like that and then I like
crazy we are like the I'm also trying to
you know I make a lot of weird stuff I
make a lot of onion and I make a lot of
like pirate sweat and a lot of I try to
make a really weird smells I have like a
garlic pickle like I'm making all these
really weird lines that no one I'm sure
we'll ever want to smell or smoke in
this kind of roadkill project so then
we're going but you know I'm just like
extremes so I have a Hawaiian that I
love it smells like gardenias and it has
a really unique effect but I think spice
spices my favorite spice and really
bright fruit and so what's the most
medicinal strain you've ever had for
yourself and do you feel that you know
the quote the most medicinal strain is
going to vary from person to person or
do you think that much like we do have
strains that you know broadly treat
certain conditions it's very likely that
you know maybe the strain you personally
like the most I might as well because if
it speaks to you it possibly speaks to
me as well yeah I think it comes down to
you know our definitely certain strains
are more specific for certain things but
it comes down I think to body chemistry
and and in your own endocannabinoid
system I mean I thought I've even heard
like whoa I was a Rafael mushy lamb he
was saying that he even believes that
the endocannabinoid system is in part
responsible for our own personalities
like how we are as humans and how we are
as people because our you know it's like
a fingerprint everybody's in Oklahoma
system is slightly different in the way
it interacts with itself and then
interacts with cannabis itself and it
can almost lend to make us who we are as
humans and so I think you know it's kind
of like those people I know people that
smoke like our super racy sativa and
they go to sleep and then there's the
people that smoking indica and they want
to do like a triathlon so you know when
it comes to CBD rich stuff and stuff you
know it's pretty you know you're pretty
you know what's gonna happen but I don't
know I I think it's really comes down to
personal chemistry and finding what
really works for you you know and and
also what fine people really need to
communicate I think there should be I
don't know why there's on a website
I mean sure I'm sure there is where
people are logging that have serious
illnesses and did
illnesses logging down what strains work
for them for certain things like lupus
or MS or like really I would love to see
a strain directory for people that have
honestly have things that are going on
and really be able to correlate those
two
for some people it's you know necessary
just due to the sheer amount of kind of
Canterbury's need to ingest but do you
think the idea of making concentrates I
guess specifically in the context of say
dabs or you know those types of solvents
or solvent extractions which are going
to be ideally theoretically used through
like a dab rig so we're not talking
about like you know RSO caps or whatever
so we're talking about that do you feel
that you while maybe some people gain a
certain sense of medicinal value out of
it you're also losing a certain amount
of ability to use the plan in a
spiritual way and I guess the way the
reason why I say this is because I'm not
an overly spiritual person but I mean
there's certainly times when I've had
cannabis it felt those types of effects
however I've never had such an
experience with dabs admittedly I'm not
a huge diver but you know what I mean do
you feel it's the same like you're
almost losing your link to the plant in
a way when you do that yeah I wonder I
mean I used to same thing I'm always
like getting reeducate idli I used to
kind of look down on concentrates and
down like I know that's just like a
bunch of crackheads it's like you know
it's like plant of the Apes and monkeys
always trying to push it further you
know and then I was like and then I saw
people like in Colorado as it started
catching on and people like green dot
and all these people like really like
honing their art and I was realized oh
my god this is like this is people
basically doing an alchemical process
this is kind of like modern cannabis
alchemy of taking the vital essence and
spirits and terpenes and and volatiles
and concentrating them and I think it's
you know for people that have serious
illness a DAB is kind of like the only
thing that's going to really get enough
get enough active constituents into
their system to really find the relief
and I I find it I don't know I find the
whole deaf culture like fascinating I
love how it goes hand in hand with glass
and art and it's it's a really unique
like genre and it baffles me I you know
I don't do dabs I would probably like
explode like I'm so hypersensitive I
think I would just lose it on a dab and
and you know I've smoked hash here and
there and that you know that's pretty
good but maybe I should try it but I
don't think it's really for my system
but for people that enjoy and people
that have you know maybe smoke so much
that that's the next logical step
I like that people are being creative
and at least if they have to go that far
to really make it unique and special and
really push each other I kind of like
how people are always trying to come up
with the most most turkey and most this
and most that and try and capture all
the volatiles and and and I also you
know I like I don't know I think it's
just it's a unique thing and unto itself
and I don't judge and I really like how
passionate people are about it but I
mean personally I don't think it's kind
of the way to go for the majority of
people and I think it probably people
that don't understand it kind of looked
down on it but it is it's amazing and
even the people some of the people I
respect the most love it and I'm like
that is awesome I think that is so cool
and I love so it's a cool thing but not
my thing but it is unique and it does
have medical application but even the
recreational applications even though
they can seem excessive and and
sometimes you know I've seen people with
the cups take a DAB and like you know
fall backwards land on their head it's
like I think it comes down to being
responsible and people having the
intelligence to to utilize these really
potent cannabis concentrations in
amazing ways and I think you know you
could probably have a pretty I think it
would be like a bungee jump into the
void I'm sure you could probably have a
kind of a spiritual experience with the
dab if you once you're like what I don't
know enough about it I mean the effects
I I never taken a DAB I feel like a dork
for saying that but I just know what
would happen and you've never done a
little sneaky red-hot knife in the 90s I
know and everybody makes fun of me it's
like you know take it down Mary was
trying to give me a DAB and I like you
know it's usually at a cup or something
and that's like the last place I would
ever
out get a men's TV while you're at it
yeah people have given me amazing
concentrates and people do incredible
jobs and I love how you know and you
know the highest grade BAM he lives he's
in the area and he gives me his pen
sometimes those are so flavorable
they're so fun and they're so awesome
and they have a good spare we taking
them traveling and that's you know
that's kind of about as far as I go with
concentrates I like a little ash but
yeah I don't know I think I would just a
DAB but I would need to be in a
meditative spy would need to be in my
dome like ready they're getting there in
the lotus position ready to just shoot
into the void because that's way too
much cannabinoids for my system
bordering DMT for you yeah it is it's
like a cannabis DMT and a gung-ho I
honor all the people that can have the
that can do dabs with intelligence and
passion I think you guys are awesome
your likes your like space command house
so yeah go for it if you're passionate
and you do a good job and you make a
quality product then more power to you
and more power to everybody these into
it all the glass artists and all the
festivals like chalice that's like a dab
festival how crazy is that that's
amazing like this yeah cannabis and the
whole community constantly blows my mind
so I just try and I try and don't judge
and just sit back and enjoy the ride
that we're having cuz it sure is wild
yeah I mean certainly used to be a lot
more auntie dads and I am now but I
think the thing which I say about it
which i think is going to be really hard
to make it not problematic is a you know
the visual act of watching someone take
a DAB is quite a kin to some other
harder drugs so that's always gonna be a
hill to overcome but the other thing is
I find a lot of people just blow their
tolerance out of the water and then they
really struggle to enjoy flowers
afterwards and I think that's something
you've got to be super mindful of yeah
no of course I mean yeah I mean it's
like that with at that point it'd be
kind of comes you know it really come
becomes a drug because yeah you're
you're pushing yourself so far
bludgeoning your cannabinoid system so
hard that yeah you're creating a pretty
pretty intense tolerance
yeah oh well to get under something
maybe a little more lighthearted
what was the biggest disappointment
you've ever had in regards to popping
seeds and was it popping some landrace
seeds that you had high hopes for and
they just turned out to be duds or was
it in fact a line you made and likewise
you turned out to be a dud um I made
some deadlines for sure I made some yeah
I wonder what's the worst I used to kind
of remember I used to got it I had some
lines that from other I used to pop a
lot more seeds from other people like
some of the big companies and I've been
let down a couple of times
it's like I don't want to say any names
or anything but there was a while where
it seemed like people weren't putting
out that quality of stuff or people were
just pushing stuff out too fast or you
know or I don't know it but hmm
something that's disappointing me you
know I try to respect every plant I take
into my lungs you know and all even
weird stuff like my philosophy is
usually it's the worst lurking bud that
has the best effect you know it's
usually a scraggly piece of weird thing
that barely then I always find it funny
because I'm Instagram I'll post some of
the sativa pictures and they'll be like
learn how to grow or what is that swag
or was that you know like people and
like they don't get like this is like
such a like a rare like special
Rajasthani plant that I got from a Baba
who's like had it in his like song a
crew of just bought Saudis for like eons
and that's their special string if you
don't realize that like some of these
things that look funny they they are
they have the most amazing effect so you
know these days I try I give everything
a chance I mean my most I guess the
disappointments would be smoking
something that someone gave me that
there obviously was wasn't grown
correctly or had had lots of problems or
really gross stuff on it or grown with
it you know I mean it's just it's I
think it's the my most sad times when
people don't respect the plant and still
produce the product yeah so have you
ever had any seeds confiscated on the
way back
or maybe the alternative question is do
you sense its back my mouth or you take
it a little more L risky I used to
always I actually have been busted at at
the airport and it was kind of funny and
synchronous ting stuff but it scared the
hell out of everybody and my wife was
waiting outside with our kids like for
hours while they had me in the like
strip-searched room but one of my what
am i nepali himalayan kind of like when
i was collecting seeds there they had
collected like 15 lines and I had them
all marked and I had them all in bags
and I couldn't find this one bag and I
was like you know I hit him pretty good
and I couldn't figure out where the hell
I put it and didn't know where it is and
you know I have secret secret ways of
doing it and you know of course they
pulled me into the secondary and they're
digging through all my stuff and then in
my toiletries they find this bag of
seeds and they're like what's this and
I'm like oh it's a snack and they're
like oh it looks like you know cannabis
I'm like oh it's probably attempt seeds
they eat doesn't Nepal and they're like
and like so they call the guy over it
brings a little kit and they fill it
sees in there and they shake it and it
turns purple and all of a sudden it was
like all hell breaks loose the guy
freaks out and grabs we think he locks
down he hits a button and they're like
oh my god he's like you know and
everybody scurrying screaming like dude
it's just he sees like I guess it came
up positive so the first guy comes
through and he's like stand there and
he's like yeah you know he starts going
through all my stuff and he goes through
he's going through he's going through he
almost gets to my stash of all my seeds
and I brought over you know and then the
next tire up guy comes up and he's like
let me look through this and he starts
over any doesn't he does he does he
almost gets there you know the next guy
comes up the higher up and now they've
you know I've all these guys around me
and they're really freaking out and then
finally he is looking through everything
he's just about to find it in the head
honcho comes up and he's like did you
sir did you search all this bags and I
get all they're like they're all it's
sketch they're like yes sir yes sir
and so you know they put my bag down and
they sent me and they did the strip
search and all that and they kind of you
know they were you saying they're gonna
[__] send me to agriculture and find me
and they were you know threatening me
and doing all these things
it was pretty sad but this craziest
thing is they never got to those seeds
so I lost 1 pack but I brought back like
15 and it scared the hell out of
everybody and now I have more stealthy
ways I do it and you know I'm not gonna
say if I bring them on my person or send
them or anything just in case those
special humans that one of us we are
listening no I don't have seeds on me I
don't do anything crazy like that they
just magically get back to America yeah
that's how it should be yeah it's a very
real danger and people you know I say
say you know I do both
I say send'em get some of that
corrugated plastic that they use for
signs for when the local like City
Council they put those signs up
everywhere they're usually printed on
this corrugated plastic that'd make a
great seed shipper and you just put that
in envelope and send it back home
usually do to send it from different
places and you definitely get one I mean
when I sent my seeds back from Morocco
I sent them in to different post-office
I only got one but at least I got one
you know I put the same seeds in each
one knowing that one board probably one
they should so where there's a will
there's a way and you know you just have
to be stealthy and tricky and just cover
all your bases sadly I have experienced
that I too did the two packages and I I
lost the seeds you gave me oh well I'm
sure can figure out a way to magically
get them somewhere near where you are we
have the technology so the follow-up
question that was maybe a bit of a hairy
situation you found yourself in the
States
how about even worse in the other
countries you know what's the hairiest
moment you've been in a foreign country
oh my gosh I've been a lot of like
life-threatening things but for like
actual like getting busted kind of
things no just on vu rank to be the most
kind of intense or you know scariest so
to speak I mean we think I think that's
the Spry the scariest is when I was
collecting seeds in Nepal during still
during their Civil War it was the MAOIs
against the you know the ruling powers I
think that was in the early 2000
and I was thinking a bus to poco and we
had a convoy because there was you know
they still had a lot of problems so they
would send a military convoy with the
bus and the convoy in front of us got
blown up by the Maoist so they blew up
the car in front of us that was about
this may be the craziest thing ever but
you know I've always been in dangerous
situations via like you know almost
drowned once in this crazy boat in
Belize on the way over to Livingston I'm
trying to think what else you know even
just being in Belize and in that early
90s was super sketchy Morocco Rhonda's
not my favorite place they people really
just the mountain people are beautiful
but it seems whenever I was in like
towns I was always being swindled or
mugged or people just weren't I don't
know I'm not a big fan of Morocco but um
I don't know you know maybe four
actually busting cannabis type thing I
was in China and I had my pen with me
and they sent me through the x-ray and
it kept on popping up and actually like
what's this metal thing and I was like
oh my god if you know China is like your
death I don't think it's destined and
but you go to jail forever and sunny
it's all about the synchrony seeing the
magic the same thing wouldn't pushed it
through twice push it through twice and
then it and they couldn't find it for
some reason they couldn't find it and
finally when it came through again I
kind of like they were lucky and I kind
of pulled it out and they went it
through one more time and like it didn't
show up I go whatever then they sent me
through but I was like oh my god what's
gonna happen to it especially yeah you
know I'm like oh it's like a e-cig or
something and you know knowing in China
they don't want to try it so I'm like
okay I have five minutes for the effects
to kick in to get all the way across the
airport and into my next plane by the
time they figure out kind of what's
going on but magically I made it through
you know there there's always things but
hopefully you know hopefully that's the
thing in the past
I just want cannabis to be part of the
world again you know it was basically
our our most utilized plant source from
I mean Memorial was our very first
cultivated plant I mean it's been with
us for hundreds of thousands of years
it's like our it's so it follows my mind
that it's not part of our heritage it's
not you know he's Jordan washing is used
to smoke it was his favorite thing to
sit on the back porch and smoke some
hemp and you were supposed to grow I
mean they it was a law you as a farmer
you had to grow it like what happened
it's like it really it really boggles my
mind that that were that were in this
predicament and I'm really glad that
we're coming out of it sure so to the
last section we've got I shouldn't say
last section second last section the
last section is just some really quick
answers but second last section we've
got all the questions submitted by
people who wanted to find out the inside
scoop on mostly strains they're growing
but let's start banging through them
okay so this one go
top five traits you look for in a good
male uniqueness resinous male like if
you push it far enough lower structure
really I think the uniqueness thing
comes in to the like is just cultivating
awareness with cannabis and really
getting to know it so that you can kind
of connect with your heart with it
because you know plants have an
electromagnetic field and if you can
your heart is an electromagnetic field
and if you press if you can kind of do
that that's where you can kind of it's
this sixth sense of kind of reading
where you just know something is special
but definitely I think first and
foremost resinous males and structure
and stability and you know stem rubbing
is great I always encourage people to
stem rub before sex and after because
the smells do change you know and also
also smell rub on the collar like up by
the top and also down below you'll get a
different you get different smells you
know if you're breeding for color that's
pretty obvious just find the best
structured best stable purple male if
you're you know going for purple let's
see if you're doing for for smell it's
gonna be resinous males ProjectWise
it's just testing your females
and you're out crosses and further F
ones I mean it's it's really it's really
just kind of checking all your bases
doing the best you can with your senses
and then you know that proofs in the
pudding the best way to know if you're
doing a good job let's grow them out see
how it did see what's going on test it
testing that's a whole kind of strange
thing these days I noticed back when I
started if you didn't test you'd get a
run out of town and it seems like the
norm now is nobody test and even a lot
of the breeders that used to be so super
into testing have kind of bonnet gone by
the wayside too it's almost like it's
people want things so fast and so new
that they're willing to just risk it and
and it's kind of like people that may be
tested before don't want to be left
alone behind but I think testing is a is
an important part of not necessarily
gifting but if you're gonna VIN
something you want to make sure that it
it's stable and it has all the desirable
features that you originally wanted to
put into it so I would say people cool
you should test your stuff more please
so I mean a question which tends to mind
from that is I heard from a few breeders
that maybe they weren't being a hundred
percent serious but I get the inkling
that they were when they say things like
the demand for certain and safe flavors
of the mom thought for new stock is so
high that they almost feel like they
don't have time to test all as you said
they will get left behind do you think
there is room in the current market for
people to be able to test and stay
relevant or do you think that the time
lapse between creating a strain testing
it getting it to market is going to kind
of start to be problematic in today's
market I think for new breeders I think
there's like a impetus or a push like
they just want to get it out it's like
they don't have the time or they don't
have the back history or they don't have
the things and they just want to get
their stuff out quick but you know I
mean that's a short it's short sighted
and maybe you'll get maybe everybody
will be super stoked and hype up your
strain and you'll you know you become a
new breeder but it's not sustainable
like then what happens when you're
trying to do new stuff I mean yeah I
really think that it's part of it and
you know I mean another way to do it is
to is if you do find your niche you
don't have to deal with the strain of
the week you're kind of creating your
own new thing and people appreciate that
for and another thing is is really fine
what you think is gonna be the next big
thing and maybe I try and kind of
imagine what's gonna be big in the
future and kind of you know I try and
play a long game I kind of make stuff
I'll start about a year behind of my
projects and kind of think okay what
where is things going like what are
people into and what do you what can I
bring to the table that might be unique
and special but also utilize what people
are really into and kind of go from
there you know like the last a lot of my
newer males are more focused on chirps
and resin where some of the old ones
like you know snow Lotus was more about
bringing a sativa touch to everything
and bringing like a hardiness and the
appellation was kind of bringing in the
chem line in a different way and really
adding a special spice of things and you
know g13 hash plant was kind of to allow
to turn things into a hash belt like a
proper heavy-duty powerful strain I
think it's really I think you can get
out of the whole mindset of trying to
push things so fast so out so quick by
just tuning into yourself and really
also looking into the future and also
finding your niche and finding you know
yeah without a doubt
you mentioned the snow Lotus line
possibly one of your more well-known
ones alongside the sunshine daydream and
gosh forgetting the name and made the
other one oh yeah Appalachia and then
there's a g13 hash plant and then some
random one sorry just the earliest
trains we mentioned they're the ones
that I thought were you to trademark
sunshine daydream and maybe it was snow
Lotus anyway long story short in terms
of the information you find online about
it it's an interesting one because it
seems like you know there's little to
birds of information here and there the
thing which kind of consistently comes
up is it says you know it's blockade
cross off GUI and there's no sweet tooth
traits present what can you tell us more
about it you know what was it
specifically bringing to the table
because I mean it's obvious from looking
at the crosses it was a good model but
it's kind of hard
extrapolate what traits it was bringing
given the somewhat the somewhat vague
description yeah it was a wild one it
was one of those strain as a male it was
one of those ones that kind of like just
communicated to me like I just knew and
I kind of saw it and it you know it has
this unique trait of having that purp
you know follows through in a lot of its
hybrids it has this really purple stalk
thing that goes on well it Purple's up
at stalks and I don't know it literally
got it was one of those things kind of
like a heart breeding thing where I just
kind of connected with it and I felt it
and I was like oh this thing is special
and then you know I out crossed it to
like Bubba and a couple things that I
know how things kind of come out with it
and you know and I noticed it was really
allowing all the best rates to come
through of that parent mother clone and
then beefing up like a lot of that
potency in frost and the structure and
yeah it was a really old the male was a
really old blockhead and then it was
kind of mixed with our kind of classic
late 90s early 2000s F goo that a lot of
people grew you know there's every every
town in city and environ has these kind
of like special clones that everybody
kind of grew back then like back then we
had like s15 and banana and ask you and
all these you know
colognes and ask you was was a really
amazing like kind of Hawaiian haze
Afghani but it kind of leaned more to
the Afghani and it had it did it didn't
smell so great it was kind of like a
muted kind of berry ish but the effect
and the resin content was just like off
the charts and so it makes it makes a I
think it's a really underrated plant I
think it makes a great breeding plant
and then that that p19 or product 19 or
whatever the block head it had a little
sativa and it had whatever it was was a
call forgot exactly but it was well it
has it doesn't it's sweet tooth and then
like pea product 1990 no wasn't it from
that was a Yaqui or whatever was one of
reader Steve's friends gave him this
crazy sativa and that was the cross and
it called it blockhead because I made
these really kooky flat tops and it was
really strong and
and that mail didn't really have too
much sweet tooth going on like it really
kind of captured that kind of really
exotic and powerful and like virile
sativa aspect of it so that combined
with African just made this really
unique and special plant and what
surprised me with it was it was so like
clear and breeding like it would just
lightly put its own kind of magic into
crosses it would kind of just beef up
whatever cross but allowed a lot of the
smells you know sometimes in certain
crosses that were probably super multi
poly hybrids it would this snow Lotus
would kind of pop through and you would
get that kind of muted kind of berry
then even in the you know in like the
goji og you get you you know you get the
berry of the snow Lotus but you get the
you get that lemon pine-sol of the OG
and it was kind of this perfect balance
and that you know I tried many different
oh geez originally to trying before the
nepali to try and find one that really
kind of had that magic but yeah that was
just a really amazing mail and that's
why I kept it for so long and that's why
I always used it because I don't know it
just it was it just spoke to me and it
just did such great stuff and indoors
and outdoors you know I'm not a I'm not
a big outdoor breeder but these days I
kind of am beginning it was all indoors
you know and and it it made amazing
indoors and outdoors so I really I
really respect and loves that plant a
lot because for what it did yeah I've
made some hybrids with the super snow
Lotus and the tranquilizer and I found
snow that has comes through great in
both of a minutes really nice influence
yeah it is it's beautiful and it has in
the snow Lotus female what was such an
amazing beautiful plant like if you ever
saw pictures of it grew like a Lotus it
like it didn't grow like a normal
cannabis it made these like weird
strange beautiful flowers and it was a
dark kind of like black-ish and I had a
very like hey I caught like a heady
indica like it definitely grew like a
sativa but it had that deep body but
with the really open vast mind yeah I've
seen some photos of that one it looks
really nice with kind of the what's
would ya almost like a little bit of Fox
tailing going on that makes it look like
the Lotus yeah yeah yeah it's got like
an inflorescence like yeah almost like a
hand like a crab isn't it
so a lot of people have commented on how
nice that Kali Orange mount looks on
your Instagram we're ever gonna see any
more of that you know I I thought I kind
of my Kelly okay got doubted which is
sad but you know done it plants you can
still breathe with them and it's not a
problem the genetics are still think so
I tried to make a lot of different
hybrids with the Caleo before I let it
go to kind of work with humming like a
Wookiee Kelly oh and I have a lot of
Cali OS males that I'm kind of playing
with but you know the whole orange thing
it's difficult to get something super
just that epic orange flavor and not you
know a lot of things have that kind of
fake orange or they have that kind of a
a lot of them most of things are like
that stung key Orange so entertained
yeah so it's kind of it's one of those
on the back burner that I play around
with and I keep on mixing into other
things it's kind of like a side project
for my own self and I'm slowly making
like an orange tool out of it you know
I'm mixing it with different things you
know and you know I'm right now I'm
trying to make a couple different inbred
tools like a lemon tool and an orange
tool just so I can hit it to things and
be like oh you want this with a little
lemon here you go you know and same with
the purple unicorn I got it to a point
now where they can take turn things
basically anything purple and it still
it still creates some great things and
even now with the dragon's blood it's to
a point where I can cross it to other
plants and they're all gonna have that
blood red SAP come out like it's a
dominant trait now at about f4 f5 it's
passing that red SAP trait on to
everything so I mean that's one thing
about making your tools is you can you
can do some cool stuff if you kind of
just take time and make stuff to work
with do you have a plan to work with the
bigs holy weed again not really you know
I don't I don't the funny thing is a lot
of people asked I get a lot of emails
and people ask for seeds and I'm I
usually just give you know if someone's
really
about something and they really wanted I
can't find it I'll usually dig through
like I have some seconds and I'll try
and find it and just give people out if
they're gonna be projects and stuff but
I don't really have those seeds left and
I just have the one mom and it's a
little bit dented and my friend that
lives up you know
pretty close his big things the big sir
holy weed so I he doesn't amazing
phenomenal job and so I kind of just
like you are you're crushing it on this
one so I'm just I'm not even kind of
really go there I might maybe make some
crosses with my my female that's left
but not in no plans in the in really in
the future and you know I know there's
packs out there and I always encourage
people to make more seeds from the packs
especially the Norika like you know the
people I don't make a lot of Naraka
packs because they're kind of a it's a
pain they ask to make those seeds
because it's usually the super long
flower and Stevens stuff so if you got
any packs of Marika please make more and
give them out to everybody you know I
really encourage people to to make if
you got rare seeds make more especially
if they're mine pass them out it's like
I you know especially if their deadlines
you guys everybody can work on there's
no restrictions on my stuff on my stuff
I'd be as creative as you want to please
you know okay so who is some of the
upcoming breeders who you kind of
keeping an eye on you know you kind of
think they're doing some good stuff well
you know I don't I only really get to
interact with some of the ones I know
personally so it's hard for me to say
like I love seeing all the pictures and
where people are going and and all that
but that's a tough question you know
like some of my friends that I that I
know that I've seen their stuff and we
trade stuff a lot I really get inspired
by like doc D and J Fox and it's know hi
inspector it's mostly the people that I
kind of interact with it on a like an on
internet level is is what I get to see
and then people like out and about you
know I I love what some of the Spanish
guys are doing I like a lot of the
landrace guys I love like what Charlie
does like his he's like a super ancient
grandpa of the scene and I love
and I you know I like what a stars and I
even like what's not [__] company does
all the cool Indian jungle II stuff oh
yeah oh no real seed company yeah yeah
like anyone I like the people there you
know I really like preservation I like
people doing a land race stuff like
delicate doesn't I like people doing
like like really pushing into different
like extreme areas like really pushing
outside of the norm those are the people
that are kind of really like I like the
whole extreme possibilities I like
people doing their niche so you know for
me it's people that are pushing things
in new directions that's I think you
know and I don't know who's you know who
it's hard for me to tell what's you know
like these days is like the fake news
what's hype and what's not so until I
really try something it's like it's hard
to say but you know anyone that's
passionate and that as a niche and is
following their heart and is cool and is
humble and is really just enjoying
themselves and I think those are the
people that are like so I don't know
that's kind of vague but so next
question is have you had any experience
with the land race train known as zamel
or you know like the Reunion Island land
race strain because I've grown some
myself
it seemed pretty cool but more
importantly I've heard from a lot of
people on mind that they kind of
consider it to be the most trippy weed
there is so I'd be interested to know
you know like what for you was the most
trippy and if you've tried this a mole
or you know anything from Reunion Island
how did that compare well you know I
always wanted to go to Madagascar and
then to reunion to collect seeds so
someday but you know I think a lot of
the people that talk about that zamel as
being like one of the most epic ones it
was you know Garrett from what was he
did warlock and did OCC company he's no
longer with us but he had a cut his arm
all that went around Europe and Spain
that ever but everybody just raved about
and it was like the super psychedelic
and I've tried them all and crosses like
in the ACE crosses and he but you know
I've never got to experience my peers
them all and I know that
Sam Alito it's one of his favorites and
I would love you know I'm always growing
out weird you know crazy stuff to see
I'm looking for that kind of like
ultimate high that everybody take you
know talks about like that super
psychedelic hi and I you know I have
experienced it once and Guatemala and it
was kind of what was I always called the
tomb bud but it was like I've never
experienced anything anything like it
since it was kind of like I don't know
it came on like nitrous it came on this
weird like harmonic hum oscillating and
like it basically just transformed the
world it was almost like I don't know
kind of like if you're familiar it was
like a family of like a Errol cyclohexyl
means it's a kind of a psychedelic
family like something like that or I
don't know but it came on like nitrous
and it was so soft it was you know it
was like a cartoon world and me and my
wife smoked in Guatemala you know it
just ever since then I've been like
chasing that and I've I've had hash in
the Himalayas work you just turned
everything into the most ecstatic joyful
dream I've had flowers from this one
Baba in in annapurna range that I go
visit all the time when I want to go
back there and I don't know if it's the
prayer he said over it or as Chilam but
he has some pretty schwag looking
flowers that just took me to like
another level I've had a walk in that
was so psychedelic it made me feel like
I was like on the end of a mushroom or
an ayahuasca kind of journey but it
seems like it's always the point of
origin places that have those
experiences and you know I'm I'm always
searching I definitely have some
psychedelic strains but nothing that
just completely transforms reality like
some of these places that have gotten at
their point of origin yeah okay so yes I
would love to try again Sam okay so for
maybe a little more lighthearted
question I'm so glad we got this is
pineapple illegitimate pizza topping
yeah I mean isn't there there's like
that Hawaiian pizza everybody digs I
think you put whatever you want on your
pizza
I think it's pizzas like your own
like mandala of vegetables and nutrition
you could be as creative and expressive
e where you want I'd like to see people
get even more creative with pizza like
with crazy like Szechuan peppers and
neat spices and maybe like fruits that
don't have a long shelf like like life
like mulberries i think you know anytime
people get creative I love it so yeah I
think pineapple maybe people could up
the game and even do something more
crazy than pineapple but sure pineapples
cuts that takes the edge off well
talking about pushing it to the next
level what are your future projects in
the pipeline not necessarily relate to
pizza but um specifically in regards to
males you know what's what's on the
horizon well I'm pretty excited about
this new Afghan email that I'm working
with because it's it's so so what I've
been you know I've grown up a million
zillion different Afghan ease from
modern to vintage different companies
and you haven't you know I get close but
I've never got that one it's just I
don't even know I explained it's just
like so acrid it's like Jamie it's not
like roadkill but it's just like this
whole other thing
and these artifact one these old vintage
ask an ease that I'm finally popping
they have that and I'm so excited and
it's so gross and it makes me so happy
because it's another kind of like it's
another puzzle piece and the whole rks
thing and I think if I you know have
that one Arceus line I've been working
forever and I think if maybe maybe these
two meet I think we might have it or
maybe I have a some other of some
sativas that are kind of gross that I
think if they if they might mean I think
we might just have it but just all in
all it it just has a different it's such
a different smell and you know I always
say if it smells different it's gonna
have a different effect it smells good
it's gonna have a good effect it's like
you know I've tried to preliminary
samples and I think it's pretty special
so I'm excited about that
I got let's see what else doing a lot of
the dragon's blood work to see if I can
turn everything in my stable with red
blood as a marker so then I can make oh
geez that you know that when you know
that are identifiable like
well this one bleeds red it must be this
you know it's a great genetic marker up
see we got some old Williams wonder and
popping again to see if I can make
temple again Tiger's milk I have a lot
from an old-timer friend all his weird
old stuff some lemon and some orange e
stuff and let's see what else I'm gonna
do some dirty hippie line work and what
else I got a backyard full of all kinds
of wacky stuff so you know I'm most
excited
oh and I got I got a lot of cool it's
Tevas oh I just you know someone Charlie
stuff I'm China and I've got some old
herbaria Bush man that I revived and
then I'm doing a ton of my Himalayan
stuff for Norika trying to make more
watermelon hash plant and then some some
of the other lines I never released from
those areas else just just going for it
just anything you know every year it's
so fun cuz I suppose I have a huge CD
collection and I have a big seed fridge
and I just go what this year do I want
to just go with and you know there's so
much it can only do like this fraction
of it but so I encourage people to get a
big seed collection like really I mean
it's so fun because you can just you can
just follow your bliss you can every see
it as an adventure every seat is like
opening a book you know so I think
that's the main stuff I'm Dorking out on
the I wan Afghani is that the same is
Afghani number one or a different thing
altogether no I just call I just kind of
renamed it I got it I had a kind of an
offline old friend that owed me a favor
so he gave me some really rare seeds and
it just said roadkill and it was an old
vintage line from NorCal and I was like
oh cool this is gonna be neat like I
thought maybe be a roadkill stunk or
something but it just turned out to be a
really like vintage old super gross
Afghani I'm like okay this is cool and
so instead of calling a roadkill cuz
it's not because people get so uptight
these days if if it's not exactly how
they remember it's not roadkill kind of
thing so I just called it artifact
anyone or Afghani more like artifact one
it's a it's that true acrid artifacts
that no one's really coming up with but
I know existed okay
and so another question we got I don't
know if it was a typo or whether it was
correct so I'll just read it as it is
what can you tell us about the ae-35
clone that was used in the deep line
alchemy number three okay one of our
viewers is sent in the question saying
that specifically if you could tell us a
little bit about your thoughts on the
line and if you would expect some good
mails to come from it because he was
considering breeding with it but he
wasn't sure if it was the right type of
line to breed with and just wanted to
know your opinion as a hybrid I think a
lot of those the deep line alchemy are
more for hash making and traditional
hash making but I think they would make
great combos with other lines if you
especially because they're hybrids are
you know that those they're usually
pretty inbred plants and by making a
hybrid that breaks their dominance on
like future hybrids so you know I would
experiment the a35 was a a gift from a
really awesome guy named Black Bart and
he they were an old 35 year old Afghani
that he's had for a while and you know
he said they had some pretty skunky fie
nose and there's a lot of Denis stuff so
um I grew him out I grew out quite a bit
and the line was really cool and I found
one that was just like really just like
it looked like just someone had bred it
for a long time over in Central Asia
just for hash those super resin is super
dark super virile and it had the smells
are really kind of muted but when you
make concentrates or hash or water hash
they really come out like they'll you
get like licorice like you get these
really complex kind of oily earthy
smells that you don't smell so much in
the plants but that makes amazing
concentrate so the 80-85 has a really
great effect and it's a great plant and
it has this kind of unique liquorice
scent I don't know if I'll be using it
in this future but for that purpose it
seemed like a good thing okay nice and
so likewise we've seen some photos of
if it's the name of the strain on just
where you kind of dubbed the the
Ethiopian paintbrush as well as you know
the actual strain Ethiopian hash plan or
the watermelon hash plan both of these
sound you know beyond exotic so to speak
you tell us a little more about them and
if there's any chance we'll see them
publicly available yeah I think so yeah
I mean right now that that well the
Ethiopian was a gift from a friend whose
family comes from that area in it the
plants that came out were really special
like it definitely khatallah was kind of
like an heirloom or landrace from that
area there were sativa but they were
they had kind of seen some of the things
that you could tell they might have been
work kind of like in how South Africa
they have some of their sativa they've
worked down so that they're relatively
quick flowering kind of like the Chiss
key and the Durban some of the turbines
that are pretty quick
these Ethiopians were relatively quick
but they had really amazing chirping
signatures and they had a really joyful
kind of meditate
buzz and the two ones that I kept were
the Ethiopian banana one which smells
kind of just like bananas which I
thought it was really cool I loved that
and then the Ethiopian paintbrush smelt
just like kind of like paint thinner and
then there was another little guy too
and called the Ethiopian spider and it
just was the weirdest plant ever had the
thinnest leaves and it would like weave
its way through plants like to get to
the light it's almost like kind of like
a creeping vine and so the Ethiopian
Anna I kind of started using it with a
wiki and kind of bringing out those
banana kind of music for banana trips
and add a little more kind of an exotic
hit to things and then the paintbrush is
a little more strong it's more of that
kind of classic kind of mindful sativa
and so those are kind of just ones that
I personally enjoy and I've kind of been
slowly working with them and you know
I've given out the banana to a few
friends and they're playing with it and
it's just a neat it's any Ethiopian line
it's it's not you know always find the
greatest land right you know land races
are hit or miss and usually need to go
through quite a few to find unique
things but once in a while you get in
these lines where they
I don't know if they're heirlooms or
what or you're just lucky but you get a
lot of really cool stuff and just to cut
in just a small spectrum so I always
enjoy that and then you know the
watermelon hash plant was just kind of
my first I guess was a Bodi seeds
released but it's kind of technically
kind of like no Rica it was one of my
early hash pads I collected in the
annapurna range of Nepal that that was
just this beautiful fox healing giant
like relatively quick for the Himalayas
cache plant that smelled just like like
fresh like watermelon and so the you
know I let those out I think maybe it's
been forever maybe even like ten years
ago I don't know and I think people have
used those I think they got used in the
auto there's a famous kind of CBD line
in a Colorado and I believe the
watermelon hash plant was used in the
making of auto which is a CVD line from
there and then a lot of other people
really enjoyed it but for some reason no
one ever really made any more I've never
seen anybody give them out or make more
like so this year I decided to make some
more and they're kind of going now so
people get to kind of experience the
watermelon hash my whole thing again
it's good breeder and it really kind of
gives you the taste of the kind of
Himalayas sounds awesome and what land
race variety has left the most lasting
impression on you or maybe not way to
phrase is what's been the most unique
you know I for smoking I really love the
Himalayan stuff like it doesn't make
good flowers but it makes the most
amazing hash and I don't know I for land
races there's something about that area
in the culture and the religious use and
the people and the trails and how old it
is and all the lines and all of how all
the valleys have different microclimates
and different like variations on the
strains and families have different
things and some to feed the feed the
cattle you know some of these for
veterinary and some for they use for
chutney and some they use the Baba's
used to get high like there's such an
amazing and vast spectrum
cannabis in the Himalayan valleys and in
the cultures that utilize them that like
I don't know I think that's my heart and
that's like if I can just be myself to
heaven like it would be smoking a big
Chilam of like Himalayan hash and just
trekking into the mountains and just
smiling at all the people you walk by
and at that place if I just tell
everybody in there grandma if there's
one thing you're gonna do if you're
depressed if your life sucks do whatever
you can trim can work at McDonald's just
make enough money and just go trekking
in the Himalayas life will become clear
like you it'll really nourish your heart
and soul especially Nepal right now
because after the earthquake they had up
there having a pretty hard time I mean
some of the valleys I used to really
love I've been completely wiped out so I
mean I would say so I mean I guess to
get to it the Himalayas although I do
that that Guatemalan tomb but though
that is still number one and can some of
the walkins that I've tried are amazing
Morocco and my favorite China mm-hmm
Laos pretty awesome
I don't know wherever I've been all over
the place but yeah Himalayas and the
Guatemalan - mud and the some tree
Oaxacan awesome so any plans for any new
your tiger lions to be released from
from Jim Orr of the or or of the from
the sea lion or tiger from the seed line
well not really you know um I made the
zombie dog with that with our ticket cut
and I don't have to or take it cut
anymore but I do have I made some seeds
like some f2s and I I do have some
zombie dog seeds maybe I could do some F
gen and those those were pretty creepy
and these giant they were like these are
giant long donkey donkey phallus buds
that smelled kind of like onions and
walking dead kind of so some people like
that and it would knock people out it
was great for sleeping so maybe some
zombie dong but other than that I don't
think so I might give out some snow
Lotus Ortega freebies so but yeah that's
about it on that they're taking so do
you have any lines that you've made for
yourself specifically for yourself that
you can never vision giving out to the
public so I'm sure there's a lot of
lines which you know just sitting in the
fridge so to speak but do you have any
where you were like I'm making this and
I'm never going to give it out to the
public well you know I that would be sad
in a selfish way but you know what I
mean we maybe you were thinking like no
I need it for future projects or
something like that you know yeah I mean
I'll sit on things but I there's never a
point where I'm like that's never
getting out I have a couple like clone
onlys that I haven't even give to like
friends but I'm sure if they asked I'd
be like well yeah try this and I think
that I'm gonna some of my like personal
favorites that I don't ever let out I
might let out maybe you know there's a
couple plants like where Stevie Wonder
I've never given to anyone because it's
it's one of my earliest crosses and it's
it's such an awesome thing I wouldn't
want to see it get kind of just taken
apart and um but you know I have a
couple special things that I want to
give out eventually like I have the
access access which is a really awesome
plan it's like a Congolese Hache plan
and I have this one called lush that I
really love that's a pure crush Lao that
I think needs to eventually get out and
you know I try and just I don't mice I
have so many seeds in my fridge like I
try and just whenever I can get them out
like so I do a lot of freebies and
there's nothing really that you know
things the only things that aren't
coming out to the public are things that
I think are dangerous like maybe still
have latent hermaphroditic tendencies or
things that I went things that are more
that I wouldn't want that impact people
in a negative way are kind of like what
I hold back or crosses that I think are
too dangerous or even you know there's
some testers I won't even send out to
testers because I don't I just do it
myself cuz I don't I don't trust the
cross enough to want to even have people
put their time and energy into it so I
think everything will come out there's
no there's nothing that I'm gonna hold
on for dear life
yeah okay and so do you have advice for
people on how to best feed a hunt I
think what the viewer was looking for
was maybe things like is there like a
certain size pot you like to use where
it's kind of small enough that you can
get a lot of plants in but big enough to
get a good representation of the plant
or you know just in general what do you
were kind of tips for Fino hunting in
general if I'm trying to run through a
lot I put I don't know it's like there's
pretty tall square plots and they fit
eight to a tray what is that like a
quarter gallon or a half gallon or
something
I like those you can pretty much keep
them healthy is you go throw them right
in right when they sex and that works
really good and you can kind of just
stack those up when I do a lot of the
outdoor to indoor work I usually use a
three gallons and wait till they section
as they sex I'll clone them and run them
inside and see how they do inside I mean
but you can I mean you could I know
people that do kooky stuff like you know
dude twelve twelve from seed and and run
them in like these micro pots and just
like you know people do amazing things
with a with a not a lot of space and
I've seen like insane open politicians
and people's like showers where they
just like run things you know twelve
twelve even CTOs twelve twelve from seed
like in these tiny little things and
just put like a couple hundred in there
and I'm just like whoa and you know then
people will revenge those and I'm like
that is awesome so I think it'd be
creative but for me I usually trying
anything that fits about eight to tray
one of those standard black trays it's
good
another little off topic one what was
your favorite year of Grateful Dead
music I would say probably the times
that I would go like I know I'm not like
world's ultimate Grateful Dead
I usually just went more to get for the
parking-lot culture cuz I was I loved it
and I loved all seeing all the people
eat up people and shake down Street and
all the music and I love getting my LSD
and a mushroom supply for the next
couple
um you know I would say aye aye
I think the fur I the first time I ever
saw him as I took my mom got me a bus
pass so I could go in the record stores
and I could go to the libraries and look
at weird books about plants when I was
in the beginning of high school and I
remember I took the bus one day to the
from Huntington Beach to Long Beach to
the dead show and I think I was maybe
like 60 No and so I was like just it was
pre touch of gray when I think that's
kind of when everything turned weird for
me because I so I would say maybe like
87 or something although I know all that
everybody says all those I mean but so
just sometimes it went you know from
maybe 89 to 90 for 87 to 95 okay but I
mean away a big I'm not you know I've
been to lots of shows but I can't say
I'm like super deadhead because there's
so many people that there just boggle my
mind with like you know they're like oh
yeah that's the year where they went
trying to set its own flower until fire
on the melody like in like their minds
like how my mind has music and strains
they have the mind of like Grateful Dead
information and I think that is pretty
awesome yeah I mean the knowledge some
people have honored all these pretty
crazy the way they can tell tell the
year and the charge is from listening to
the audio yeah that's beautiful and my
thing about the Grateful Dead is I
personally more than music and anything
I honor them and I respect and I give so
much thanks for them for being the
traveling psychedelic dispersion
mechanism for you know for 50 years like
if they didn't exist the world America
would be a totally different place they
toured and took you know like
heart-opening mind-opening substances
all over the Americas not to mention all
the seeds that went out and disseminated
all over the United States they were
like this this like a circus of
awakening that moved through time and
space
all through America and without them I
don't know what it would be like today
so I give maximum props
Grateful Dead thank you for creating a
community that made the world different
yeah I agree I think especially given
Kem dog eyes its origins to the car park
scene so to speak it's yep certainly
needs to have its homage paid this is
probably gonna be the last question from
the viewers who's just managed to
squeeze it in two minutes ago Wow
a job yeah long story short he wants to
know he's got a few questions in here
but I think the best one is are you
working with any of the more old-school
clones like for example the New York hey
zo just also known as the Uptown PF
Skelly hash plan one of my favorites or
the shoreline you know I haven't see I'm
kind of funny I don't it's hard for I
mean to get some of these really unique
clones these days I kind of just do it
hand to hand so I don't get to try some
of the all the super neat stuff I kind
of have to wait for it to get to me but
I do have a lot of the old stuff
the skellies in my area but I don't I
haven't been authorized yeah yet to have
it so that maybe someday but I have
smoked it and I do think it's pretty
awesome and rad I like that I love that
the Cuban Black Keys is he's a unique
planet I work with that some I made that
bandaid haze with that which is kind of
like a my version of a picture cheap
plant and people tend to really like
that the Cuban black haze by itself is a
really strange plant cuz it gets so big
and it takes you know cut takes kind of
a while but kind of look I caught like a
tequila weed like you know how's that
certain Mexicans have that - it's like
the sloshy kind of like psychedelic slop
kinda like if you mix alcohol and
sativas it's like this really sloshy
kind of tequila like wild buzz and then
Shoreline uh I would love to see a good
shoreline I've never grown a shoreline
I've only heard cool things about it how
it's like almost like a roadkill e thing
you know those and there's the dumpster
there's so much cool neat stuff I you
know and that's
I love like I grow crazy weird everyday
you know I love to grow as many possible
clones that people give me because I
just love to check it all out I mean
it's if I get to see it just you know I
go into my room I get so excited to see
what plants are doing especially these
clones and what you know what's the hype
of the day or what's the old I like it's
so satisfying to kind of see and
experience these plants and that's what
I tell people about cannabis it's like
there's no other pursuit on earth
besides maybe being a chef where you can
be so creative and so there's so much
uniqueness and then when it's all said
and done you get to inhale it and it
becomes alive in your mind there's no
other pursuit you know you can race car
you can do all this you can cook you can
make a fabulous food shirt it satisfies
all your senses like your touch your
sight your smell your sound but cannabis
is the only thing that hits all of those
and you get your mind open to it's like
like that's the ultimate thank you
something that satisfies all your senses
and you get to bring it into your body
and experience it that way I don't think
there's anything else like that yeah I
think the food one's a good analogy I
wouldn't have thought of that myself
yeah because there's awesome chefs like
in is visceral you can make the coolest
stuff and it smells so good it tastes
good it makes you feel good but it
doesn't change your mind maybe it's kind
of but yeah so one of the last couple of
questions I always like to wrap it up
with is if you go back to one place in
history and time so to speak where would
you go you know to collect some land
rice seeds how to collect seeds I would
love to go to Iran right before the
Ayatollah kind of kicked in like before
they threw out the Shah when it was like
when it was have you ever seen pictures
of Iran before the yeah it's very
Western looking it was so Western
everybody know there's no burgers
everybody was so it was like this modern
everybody was so happy they must have
had some really awesome strains before
you know that and you know I mean people
say like Afghanistan before the Soviet
invasion but I don't know you
I don't think I'd really like to go is I
would love to go along the Silk Road
like way back maybe like you know like
thousand BC and just experienced all of
that because people talk about the
hippie trail and all that and you know
all that's where all these cool seeds
and strains came from but the hip trails
like relatively new the Silk Road was
where it was that people were you know
from China all the way to like the
Mediterranean and people were trading
you know linens and seeds and fruits and
nuts and of course seeds were coming
from China going through all these men's
seeds from that things that was like
that was like the mod I mean if there
was one age I think of when cannabis was
really kicking into gear and really
people making some cool stuff it was
back on the Silk Road when it was really
pump and yeah we're that out so which
strain has the way I normally phrase it
is which strain do you like the least
but I have a feeling you'll say you like
all strains so he'll say which one which
one kind of spoke to you the least I
mean like growing or are taking into my
body a consumption let me see which one
that I don't like hmm
I think if there's any strain that just
mainly feel like super gross
that's hard you know because they love
their personality I think it it's I
smoked so many strains I should like
really look right down like this thing
drove me nuts I can't really answer that
I don't I don't know I've grown some
strains that kind of sucked but smoking
it what what just sucks I don't know I
mean you smoking a ham pawned off as
buds in some foreign country yeah you
got me on that and I haven't I can't I
cannot answer that I don't even know
but as soon as I find something that
really sucks I will remember it and I
will get it to you not have to update at
that point that was like a stumper it's
like okay
alrighty final question I want to end on
a bit of a controversial one we're not
really for you but I'm gonna be pretty
funny so shout out to my friend art from
round table selections for submitting
this one I think the best way to end it
will be just to give a simple yes-or-no
answer okay what is it do you think the
earth is flat oh you know the universe
is a really unique and special magical
place that amazes me every day I
personally don't think it's flat but I
don't know I I get I get amazed and
every day at some of the things I
learned and I wouldn't put it past the
earth to be some crazy thing I like flat
I don't know where the water goes but
I'm down you know I'm just happy to be
here alive on planet Earth
I don't care if it's flat if it's round
it's square I'm just so stoked that I
won the lottery to be a human on this
planet in this time with all these
people doing all this crazy stuff it's
the planet of apes who cares I'm just
happy to be here so doesn't really
matter what shape or form it is for me I
guess that wasn't yes or no though so
I'm gonna say if it was like like a
scantron and my life depended on it I'm
gonna say no it is not flat but I'm open
to extreme possibilities and if it was
flat I don't really care because I kind
of dig just being here fantastic feeding
ending was very very archetypal of body
to just be exploding with happiness yeah
I think it's rad sure if it's flat
awesome if it's round yes I just feel
like being here so give thanks fantastic
so thank you so much for coming on the
show and spending whopping four hours
with this oh wow that's that's a long
time it just creeps past I ate so I even
had more stuff to talk about
well jam it in oh yeah we can jam it in
I also want to encourage people even
well not everyone but people use your
intelligence
I would love everybody to definitely do
more psychedelics I think this is very
important in a breeding philosophy to
connect with the earth the plants and
yourself but do it responsibly and do it
in nature and you think all forms of
psychedelics any particular ones like
I've got friends who particularly
advocate for mushrooms because they find
it to be a little more natural yeah I
would say I would for me I would say if
you're interested in plants and plant
breeding and cannabis
my thing is XP rants I'm gonna say if
you enjoy where cannabis takes you and
in the and what it does for you there's
many plants on planet earth that have
been strategically planted here to open
your mind and connect you into deeper
places spaces healings it's you know
cannabis isn't the only plant I think
it's our primordial I think it's like
our definitive ally plant but I think
there's so many unique plants out there
just waiting to teach you things and I
think that we can develop a greater
appreciation of nature ourselves and the
planet by going into these states I
don't have a Kate recreational
psychedelic use but I a responsible
personal or group and it's with a
positive set in setting I think go for
please everyone I mean expand your mind
get in touch you know find find that
special place in your heart that that
opens up to all creation yeah without a
doubt I'm a just out of curiosity have
you ever used salvia and what were your
experiences on it you know it's funny as
I have a I collect salvia strains it's
you so I actually have about five now
but you know so I mean is it okay if I
get it's a little bit of a story is that
okay yeah we love stories so you know
back when I was young I always wanted to
be an ethyl botanist and so my our first
big adventure my friend was really into
archeology and I was really into
ethnobotany so I brought my plants of
the gods cards and he brought all of his
archaeology books and we did our first
big trip in our 20s we landed in Cancun
and we like hitchhiked and rode buses
because of the infrastructure for
tourism was a lot different back in the
nineteen ninety and we were all through
the Yucatan all through Belize all
through Guam all through Mexico and all
the way back all the way to Tijuana and
my big thing is he wanted to see the
temples and I wanted to retrace the
footsteps of our guard and wasan in his
search for the mushrooms so after we did
all the temples we got to go up and we
went to Wow day Jimenez in this year a
Mazatec to experience that you know the
culture of mushroom shamanism and all
the other plants they use and one of the
things is we had our card and it was a
rare mint type plant that no one quite
knew about or what how it worked and
that was a salvia divinorum before
people got kind of turned on to it and
it was before they realized that it was
a masticating plant like it went through
your mucous membranes so we found a
woman that you know took her all day to
hikes the place and got it and then she
made us he's like shamrock shakes where
she just blended it in water and that
was and you know we drank those and
since you don't really it gets destroyed
in your gut we got these really light
effects from it and it was so beautiful
and so feminine so special but it didn't
really hit us and it always kind of had
a special part so when it became kind of
a thing and people started smoking it I
kind of started collecting the strains
and people don't realize like that plant
spirit is so it's so moist and so
feminine like it despises heat and fire
so all these people are smoking and
going cuckoo and running through walls
like I mean it's kind of fun on YouTube
to watch the salvia freak out so I got
in it you know you know in a kind of
weird way but the key to salvia is you
make a quid and you just put it in your
lip and you find some quiet place and
she will take you deep into her healing
garden and it is so special and so
magical but I mean I have smoked it and
I have had some very intense and
unimaginable things happening but really
key to that plant is it's very family
it's very moist and it really loves just
to you know be stuck in your lip and a
quid and it's sad that it's been
outlawed yes interesting that you
mentioned that it intense is another
word that uh I would use to describe my
own experience with it but um it's I
didn't know yeah you could just kind of
sit it in your mouth that's an
interesting one I'm kind of just
springing to mind from that same idea
have you toid around with kratom at all
you know I'm not it I have tried kratom
and but you know it's
I'm not a big opiate person and I'm not
a big stimulant and being literate she
depending on you know its its location
and if it's you know the different stem
colors and morphology how they have
alkaloids I think it's an amazing
adjunct for people that are dealing with
opiate dependence and I think it is a
really amazing healing plant but it's it
for me it was just it I don't like
things that they mess with my physiology
so much that I have I cup body
disturbances and I know it has kind of a
strange dosage response curve like or if
you take too much you can be very
uncomfortable so I never really
connected to kratom like I think my
favorite you know if I had to pick stuff
is I like cannabis I like mushrooms
those are my faves I like cactus like
San Pedro and Trico serious I mean I
mean I do ayahuasca is another thing I
mean it definitely has a place but it is
kind of kicks your ass just mushrooms
and oh we need his mushrooms and
cannabis and we're ready to go but I do
like coffee I like all plants like I I
have a complex you caught a chart or
whatever you want to call it up but you
know I I'm open to try anything you know
I look I just love all the plants and
all the plants spirit allies are just
spirit plants just really that's that's
where my my heart goes oh I'd love to
try car
it cuts great it's easy good see
they're easy to sprout I mean not really
but I mean you can do it probably great
in your area I'm gonna say I heard that
the seeds are a little hard to sprout
I'll give it a girl I'm a bit more green
thumb nowadays than when I last tried
many years ago as a kid yeah it's just
about weighting the hardest ones ever
are coca seeds like I've never been able
to do that they only have like a two
week germination period one when they're
fresh and you it's literally like they
mold out it's like it's super hard
caught you just kind of get a moist and
kind of don't look at him for a couple
weeks yeah I mean interesting you
mentioned that I through a friend of a
friend I I knew someone who had like a
single cocoa plant here in Australia
actually and funnily enough like what I
had heard from the guy who had it was
that like just wasn't even worth
pursuing because like it just you know
it kind of became to the land racing you
know he's just flipping out and the
Australian and barbed and just not even
productive at all yeah well I think
there's an Indonesian or a Javanese
variety of coconut they're growing it
might work better for your climate yeah
most likely well and people are doing it
indoors now and I know in our area we
had a coca plant that was kind of going
around underground
that was an imposture it was somebody
claimed it with a coca but it really
wasn't it had this caustic white SAP so
whenever you would chew it you're like
lips would burst into flames but I love
Coco I've never tried cocaine yet I mean
maybe some day but I loved shooting coca
like I probably shoot my weight in coca
when I've been in like South America
especially up in the Andes like oh my
god I just I mean definitely roast your
mouth with all the line but what a
beautiful plant like I can see you know
up there where there's no oxygen and
people are working hard it's just like
angels come down and touch you like you
can breathe you feel vibrant like it's
not vitamins it's such a healing crop
for those Andean people maybe maybe you
should stay away from okay yeah I mean I
don't know I like coca leaf you know you
guys have a you have the water leaf huh
you have a lot of DMT containing uh like
trees in Australia
oh yes
takes me back to being a young boy doing
the old acid-base extraction that's that
it's a bit of a sad story actually
because you there's certain parts of
Australia where it grows really well and
you go there and the trees have just
been absolutely stripped of all their
bark and yeah they're really struggling
because if people just go on to town on
it oh my gosh I know now that's a big
choco craze everybody wants it to make
their chaga and yeah it's a strange
thing I wish people got more into flares
but I guess it's just not a viable plant
for extraction you know what's
interesting is it's kind of maybe a
little peripheral but it was actually in
that extraction of the DMT from the
acacia probably about eight or nine
years ago now when I first learned about
it they were doing dewaxing you know
like you're removing the lipids from the
concentrates back then but they
certainly haven't started doing that
until much more recently with cannabis I
think that's kind of interesting how
they were like ahead of the curve in
that respect at least yeah as well I
mean that kind of just goes back into
your basic crime biochemistry I think
with us donors we don't really we never
really had that science background you
know and it seems like when you're
actually doing scientific extraction
you're kind of have to involve those
principles so I think it's donors we
just never got it but yeah that's true
they were dewaxing and then there was
that kind of like that rough extract it
was like the jungle spice that had that
kind of yellow wax and they found that
something actually constituents in it so
they're kind of pulling out some of the
good stuff yeah I actually only ever
really came across the yellow stuff
myself at least when I didn't make it
but um yeah it's certainly an
interesting one too if you were to look
at the differences I've never tried
ayahuasca personally and that's that's
the one I'm most excited to try because
a lot of people say you know it's quite
different to smoking it which is more
you know what you're intense kind like
akin to a bong here versus inedible you
know yeah yeah and it's much longer I
mean and I mean there's so many ways now
people to do are like you can do like an
ayahuasca analogue you know like a
Syrian room mushroom mixture or you know
the most hostile is Syrian rule
so many ways to kind of emulate or even
with research chemicals now they're
emulating like ayahuasca type compounds
and they even think some of the the most
ancient some soma compounds were like
were different in beta Hart karma
beta-carbolines and like DMT sources I
mean it's such an ancient alchemical
science but yeah I think you would enjoy
ayahuasca but I would say maybe do it in
its natural environment maybe get down
into the jungles and really or that or
do it in someplace that that is in
nature yeah I've heard that above all of
other things you know like sentence
setting is the most important thing with
ayahuasca because for a lot of reasons
but it is very much a ritual it's no I
don't think there's many people who
would say that it's purely recreational
oh yeah it's not recreational at all
it's very it's very hard on your system
I mean you're you're you're vomiting a
lot I mean that's kind of what I did my
research thesis on ayahuasca shamanism
and the Amazon when when I was in the
university so it's like I had to do some
grueling stuff and it's yeah it's I
always tell people it's like you know
now we have a lot of this well if you do
yoga and if you go to festivals yeah you
gotta try how I wast gets become like
the it's kind of a like like cool person
rite of passage if you're like hip but
really you know the key to ayahuasca is
like it's there to eat you're either
there to be healed learn to be a healer
I think those are really the only two
things that people should be using for
it is if you're learning to be a healer
in Iowa's Cairo or if you're there to be
healed I mean I always tell people they
should take like an interview with it
like a first everybody should interview
with it like you at least do it once and
so that it can impart its knowledge and
kind of check you out and you can check
it out but I don't it's not a
recreational thing but I think it's
something kind of like Burning Man you
should always you know you should you
should do it once
kind of like a Eclipse you should see a
total solar eclipse there's things in
life that I think everybody should try
and yeah probably one of them so my
question I'm really interested to ask is
out of all the countries you've been to
which one is left the most positive you
know kind of impact on you you know but
in terms of both you know things you're
doing in the country we're going to
so whether that be good stuff there or
whether you're able to good sense good
stuff back or just you know like a
combination of that as well as you know
like just you enjoy the place nice
people good food you know well that type
of good stuff yeah I mean number one the
Himalayas artists I can't get enough of
it I love the people I love the place I
love the culture I mean the food
Nepali food isn't that great but it's a
stall but but it's very nutritious just
being up there like just walking those
you know there's these I don't know it's
hard to explain like for backpacking and
trekking the beauty of the Himalayan
trickiness you're basically walking
along the these trails or that have been
there for thousands of years that have
gone there go all through the Himalayas
back when you know and they all connect
to town so there's always like a little
village about five hours each village is
about five hours from each other so you
can you can always stay out in the cold
you never have to pack like a sleeping
bag you never have to have food you can
just smoke enjoy the beauty and water
and then walk to the next town drink
some tea you can spend the night if you
want or you can keep on walking like I
just I just love the Himalayas but you
know second runner up
there's something about Guatemala that I
love so much maybe it's the first place
I fell in love with or maybe it's that
there there's still such an indigenous
presence like it still has such it's
beautiful culture and it has the ocean
you know as a Pacific it has the
Atlantic it I mean the Caribbean there
it has mountains it has it has
everything and it people are friendly
it's it's a beautiful place I mean those
are probably the top two Oleson it
sounds like two plays I need to go yeah
yeah you definitely need to go you know
what I would love to gives people some
information on things if they want to go
deeper into kind of some of the things
I've talked about like maybe some books
that are a good starter books or people
looking so I would highly recommend if
anybody's interested in just more of a
reading with your heart look into any of
Stephen Bruner's books or our interviews
like he is definitely connected
that style of interacting with plants
with your heart a great book that's
always fun plants of the Gods richard
evans lt's albert hofmann
awesome guys excellent book if you want
more of a lighter more meditative
approach to connecting with plants I
would say anything by Elliot Cohen like
plant spirit medicine definitely if you
torrent or anything like that
find someplace that has all the terence
mckenna's interviews like on one little
thing it's probably like a million gigs
and download every single turns but kind
of interview you can ever get and just
listen to those he is the most ultimate
dude on earth christian rat Jonathan odd
I mean Wade Davis mark Plotkin Timothy
Plowman all these ethno botanist these
are kind of like these are my heroes and
I I really think people would benefit
from that trying to think any other you
know support erowid
it sites just I'm sure I think of things
that are just so oh you know it's a
great book people I'm not you know I my
degree was in basically kind of like it
was a anthropology religion with
emphasis on plants and culture and
religion so I always wanted to be
nothing botanist but I could never
handle the botany in the science nor the
you know the put you in a box thing so I
kind of found it found a way around it
and did ethnobotany without the botany
but there if there is one book that
people if people are kind of like a
dummy like me and are more artist
artistic and don't want to try and
figure everything out there's a great
book called it's called like practical
botany for gardeners I think it's by
Josh and it's got pictures and it talked
and if you want to like kind of know
what you're talking about but not want
to know this is a great book for you
it's all pictures it's like it's like
botany for dummies it has great things
about all the classical breeders let me
think anyone else that I think is super
awesome definitely read Stephen Bruner's
books plants of the gods
oh and Luther Burbank if you want to
know of a cool
honest that's still connected to its
heart and to the spirit definitely
getting to Luther Burbank one of the
most amazing breeders on earth ever
created I think like 800 different kinds
of fruits and vegetables well from Santa
Rosa it's he has amazing quotes like his
I think one of his famous quotes is like
the most important thing to a breeding
program is love he's um was another one
of the thing is oh that I don't know but
if you're into botany and you still want
to be kind of groovy and esoteric
definitely for Burbank and travel please
travel please collect seeds please make
seeds please share seeds please be nice
to everyone let's make this an awesome
community and let's really push this
thing into amazing directions I think
that's it yeah I mean that sounds
amazing and very very good again you
know very archetypal of body just
spreading the love yeah I mean that's
what it's all about
I mean I I'm I guess i always get shy
and i get all paranoid about about these
conversations but really if it's with
good people it's just you're just
talking so i got i think you know adam
densha was different it was live and
there's a lot going on and that was
iLike that I like live because you know
it's raw but this is nice too because
you get to really kind of like um you
get to talk more and like really kind of
come from somewhere I wanna talk about
yeah I mean that's that's one of the
things we often hear about what people
enjoy about this show is that people are
able to kind of get a bit deeper into
their the Lots on an issue and not just
kind of maybe moving on to the next
issue straight away mm-hmm yeah I mean I
definitely like the dynamic approach and
I like how it yeah it's just it's
different it's more one is more like
it's more of a show and you're on the
spot and you're really getting out and
then this one's more of kind of like a
you're like having tea so I they both
are amazing they both serve their
purpose but you know it's neat to have
both sides of the coin I think you know
you you know you're kind of like is the
nard waar of cannabis
interviews you know nerd war yeah he's
like the crazy interviewer like he comes
up with all the wackiest questions and
all the guys are like where the hell did
you figure that out you'd be like the
nard whare of cannabis podcasts I love
it you know doing these and honestly
what I say to everyone is I just I just
make this show that I wish already
existed like I'm just making a show that
I would sit down and enjoy yeah I hope
this makes a lot of people happy cuz
everybody's like you know it's I guess
it's nice to hear someone's voice and
just you know I hope I just got across
some dinner my whole thing was I just
wanted people to maybe see a different a
different reality of how we can make
this work I hope that it kind of comes
through in the interview yeah I think
that they would definitely we'll have
that experience and honestly it's
something that has kind of been
necessary in a way because a lot of the
a lot of breeders do and including
myself you know do approach this very
much from that scientific point of view
so it's really nice to have that
contrast and kind of juxtaposition to
see that it's not all just you know one
way so to speak yeah it's always and
that's how I always tell people it's
like I don't care how you breed and it's
the proof is in the pudding if you if
you make something amazing I don't in as
long as you put your heart and soul into
it I wasn't just like a one-off thing
and you're like oh the real is I made
this yeah it doesn't matter
oops in the pudding and that's all that
counts science or backery
it doesn't matter yeah for sure so again
just in case my previous one gotta be
the interrupting you know I thank you so
much for coming on the show and for
spreading all your knowledge and love
with us yeah no it was my pleasure I
still do it really good to let my heart
speak you know and so thank you yeah
[Music]
so there you have it guys
without a doubt one of my favorite
episodes so far
I hope everyone is able to sponge up
everything they were looking for big
thank you to bode why what Ronnie
Australia organic gardening solutions
[Music]
bode see you
[Applause]
[Music]