uh
[Applause]
[Music]
hello and welcome to another episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts
this episode as always was brought to
you by our amazing sponsors seeds here
now best seed bank in the game guarantee
on satisfaction not just germination get
all the hottest breeders the latest
drops get all that fire you need right
now you know where to hit them up
and we'd like to welcome on to the show
copper biological systems these guys
have a wide range of products to help
keep your garden pumping 100 activity
full of life whether you need predator
mites predator bugs of any sort
microbial powders or heck even just some
artificial feet to keep your beneficial
mites alive
keep boosting those numbers hit up
profit systems they're amazing
international and we're appreciative to
have them on the show
and as always a big shout out to the
patreon gang these guys are the
lifeblood of the show helping to make it
happen as always if you want access to
additional content early episode access
and a few other little goodies be sure
to check it out patreon.comcast
[Music]
on this episode we are extremely
extremely extremely grateful
to have our friend from india
in come on give us the lowdown on what's
happening in this part of the world that
land race love magic and what we can
look forward to in the future this is a
two-parter four hours buckling
[Music]
let's get into it
alright alright alright a big thank you
and welcome to the one and only the land
race legend himself irizan of indian
land race exchange thanks so much for
joining us
thank you so much uh for having me on
the show i'm really grateful to be here
today
awesome my friend the question we like
to ask people first off what have you
been smoking on recently
i've been smoking on some douche valley
resin it's been cured for a little over
three months
has a really nice
zesty citrusy flavor on the front and
you know background is all really floral
so it's very nice combination the
effects are really mild
so i mean it really does not really
takes you out of your working group so
you can you know get on with your work
you know go about doing what you want to
do in the day
and at the same time not feel like you
want to you know indulge in smoking you
know get interrupted in between your
curriculum so i think it's a great smoke
to you know start the morning
for anyone
oh that sounds lovely you've got me
interested you said it was cured for
three months how do you find as a hash
cue as it affects the flavor and potency
oh it definitely does that i mean
especially i mean if you're going to
talk about the resin that was hand
rubbed from the plants so i mean
we have to understand i mean
if
that uh resin is
produced in a much different way then
it's going to have certain properties
which will be very different from your
conventional
hash you know that is made by water or
is made by you know dry seeding so i'm
gonna just elaborate a little bit on
that
so what happens when you're uh you know
hand rubbing the plant is that you're
also taking out
some of the plant matter and a lot of
water content okay so
your final hash is basically a
like a ball of a lot of resin which is
stuck around you know some impurities
like dust and you know plant matter
which is binding it together it's
binding the lipids together and then
there's a lot of water content as at the
same time
now if you attempt to smoke something
like that at the same time i mean if you
smell it it's gonna smell amazing the
smell is going to be amazing okay but
when you try to smoke it you will not
feel any flavor at all it's going to be
very harsh
uh your nostrils gonna burn like you
know somebody put chili powder in there
and it's going to hurt your throat as
well and that's because of the water
that is present in it you know so when
you age it or how you guys say you cure
it or there are a few different things
happening there the first thing that is
happening basically over there is that
uh the decarboxylation of you know the
resin the other thing is that uh the
plant matter that is lost in between you
know that is going to lose the taste you
know that is interfering with the final
flavor okay and the third and the very
important thing that is happening is
that it's losing that water
that you know
really needs not to be a part of the
hash because
if that hash is then taken to a humid
place you know it's eventually is going
to develop in a rod as it's going to
have mold in it
as we see in a lot of a lot of resin
which is not you know aged properly or
it's packed and you know polythene right
away and you know they don't let it just
sit
uh sit out for a while so we see that a
lot you know we break we break up pieces
and it's all white from inside so you
know that kind of tells the story so
it's it becomes very important here
uh you know to cure to age your hash and
you know without that i mean uh that
hash really is
uh not worth smoking but just after a
few months uh it becomes something
divine from something which is not worth
smoking so i think that's a big
difference
well what a great little run down on
that and so i guess my little next
question on that is
is there a optimum period in your mind
for hash like do you think you know
between three and six months is the
minimum you'd want to do it or how do
you think about it
okay so um i'm not really sure about
that i mean i haven't really thought
about it in that
way
but
within our uh within the circumstances
that i'm in i think three months uh
three four months works the best because
after that what we usually see is that
we see
uh i mean not through testing i mean
through what we feel subjectively when
we smoke it right so what we see is that
uh it becomes more sleepy i mean the
high becomes
uh in a way that you know it induces
more sleepy feeling instead of more
energetic feeling
right so and that i probably think is
what's happening is uh the thc begins to
degrade to cbn uh at a certain point
right so
that that starts to happen because
eventually after march it starts to get
really hot in india and not everyone you
know has the capacity to store their
hash and you know sealed
ziploc pouches and freezers so by the
time it's just you know if when they
take it out in january i'm sorry in
october and november december and
january it sits you know in the village
or anywhere in india it's fine because
it's still cold
and after that after february you know
as the heat begins to you know surge
i think that it's really not ideal for
for people to store the hash here i mean
unless they have a freezer and they can
really you know just vacuum seal it and
that's a whole different thing but
in india because of the diversity and
the dynamics of the season and the way
they play out because the winter is very
cold and you know when it's summer it's
so hot i mean you cannot imagine you
know that there was a winter in the same
country at some point so uh really
temperate kind of you know climate
overall so it's uh three months four
months i think that that's really what
does best in the environment and the
circumstances we're in
yeah what if what a fantastic answer
so the next question is
what was your first experience with
cannabis
first experience with cannabis is
i mean this is this is going to be a
vastly different from you know because
i've heard like some of your podcasts
before and you know uh people have these
really nice stories that yeah my first
experience was i went there and i smoked
but it's entirely different for people
who belong to places you know where it
grows everywhere so you're just growing
up
along with this plant as as you grow up
you just see it everywhere so it's kind
of is normal
until the society takes hold of you and
starts telling you that you know
it might not be a very good idea if you
you know start smoking this plant
and that really helps in actually
propelling a lot of you know teenagers
towards it because then they become
curious and you know that they really
want to smoke it
so um it's really different in india you
know uh
because it's everywhere you know it's in
our worship
it's part of our food
uh we use it for the ropes for shelter
for medicine even you know sometimes
when you know the cattle get sick we can
feed cannabis plants to the cattle and
it pretty much seems to do you know well
for for for the animals and one of the
things that i've seen for myself is if
you let those animals lose and if
they're having some you know stomach
issues or some problem they go and they
munch on the canvas plants as if they
already know i mean you know that this
is the medicine so
just
uh
i mean the whole perspective is
different here i mean so
we can't really pinpoint or i can't
really pinpoint okay this was the first
time that i said hey this is cannabis
because it's just part of your daily
affair like
you don't really uh you know realize
what was the first time uh you know that
you saw people around you because that's
you have people around you and that just
normal we don't really try to pinpoint
those
uh things
in the way some other significant things
like what was the first time you got
your job or what was the first time you
went to a beach so those kind of things
could be pinpointed because they're very
specific to your
uh you know experiences but this is just
part of your
life i mean so it's really different you
know growing uh around the plants so i'm
just going to go ahead and you know
tell really a little story and that
would i think really help
a lot of people understand you know how
things work here
so uh we don't have a we don't have a
water supply in uh you know in our
village so what we had to do when we
were kids we had to
grab a pot in the morning and just run
down the hill you know get the water
there are some spots where water comes
out of the mountain so you can get the
water and you can go about doing your
things as well so we were accompanied
with some uh you know uh
elder guys who were around like 25 27
19 20 right and we're like really kids
seven eight nine years old
so we would go there and by the time
they're you know descending down the
mountain they're
rubbing the plants making the hash as
they go down so that once they reach
there before they take the bath they can
smoke and then they can you know really
freshen up and start their day as we do
so
we were like completely unaware of what
this plant is or like what is happening
why they're rubbing it and you know why
they really empty the cigarettes fill
them back up and smoke and get crazy so
this whole thing is a big confusion for
us but we kind of enjoy that so they
would also make us rub those plants
because they think we have these small
supple hands you know because we were
kids so
it's it's kind of a myth in india that
you know if kids rub it you know their
hands are soft so they take out like the
best hash i don't necessarily think
that's the thing that's the case but
that was it so we would do that for them
and they would take out the hatch from
our hands and we have no idea what
they're doing and why they're doing it
but it was weird so it was like one of
the things that i do remember so if i
really have to pinpoint i mean
experience wise then i would say this
was one of those things and it was
happening almost every day because just
again that's part of your being i mean
as a person and where you live your
culture you see it everywhere in the
temples you know on the mondays which is
the day of the shiva you see a lot of
ladies you know just cutting some
branches taking it for the worship
so it's a whole different world out here
i mean
yeah
[Music]
yeah wow interesting and i mean when the
uh the slightly older guys would get it
off your hands do you remember how they
smoked it
yeah they would empty the cigarettes and
you know they would mix it and fill it
up and
i i was pretty much getting disgusted
hey man like they i thought like they're
taking you know what do you call
uh i'm only a body waste kind of thing
and smoking it's it's kind of weird and
disgusting but you know as as you you
grow and you understand what's really
happening and i'm not trying to say you
know that
not some part of our you know whatever
is there on our hand is not getting
mixed with the ash it certainly does
but
again i mean
this is it is the way it is i mean in
india i mean
so
yeah yeah of course and so do you
remember when you first
like can remember feeling high maybe
from smoking some hash yourself for
example
yeah so uh i started smoking i mean like
around 14 15 16 years of age i mean i
don't exactly remember like you know you
know what was the first time because it
it just happens eventually that someday
you know one of your cousins says take
one puff
and then you know the other time you're
with some friends and you know you're
also getting drunk and you take a couple
of
but um
as a whole in uttarakhand you know the
hash it does not really get you that
high
right i mean it's not cultivated or
selected for
thc in particularly like some of the
other places
so it's not that potent and
again the domestication part is not very
uh you know prolific as well so
it's really in uh nowhere close to some
of the other regions in india or
somewhere else in asia but i think
i was in college when i really remember
getting high-end that was you know some
guy who had like come down from shimla
and he had like one of the best
residents
he thought at that point in time and you
know i really got high on them because
i was just uh you know hanging out with
these guys in their hostel rooms and all
of these guys belong to himachal pradesh
which was
really close to punjab where i was in
college at that point in time
and i'm hanging out i'm smoking but
mostly it's the cheap stuff that they
can share you know but every now and
then somebody would come back from the
village after the vacation and he will
bring a little bit like two or three
joints of really good hash and i happen
to be lucky to be there
you know at that point in time and i
smoked it and you know the effects were
just
nothing like i'd ever
experienced i think the intensity was up
to a level
which uh really got me thinking that you
know this is this is an amazing feeling
i mean whatever i'm feeling right now i
mean this is a great state of mind to be
in
you know and
it just really kind of pushed me towards
you know
scouring for more of it you know how can
i find more people you know who would
have something like this which is not
ordinary but you know something better
because now i've gotten to understand
hey you know
what these are
there's there is difference it's not
just hash there are levels to this hash
and they're like many of them so you
have to find you know these people who
have the best resin which are
usually the older guys you know 25 and
above because they had really graduated
smoking by then for over seven to ten
years so they kind of have found their
places where to get the hash on a
regular basis and they usually smoke
good but at that point in time i mean we
were like 17 18 19 year olds so
we had an entirely different circle but
every now and then we we would get
something good but not regularly at that
point in time for that you had to go out
and you know make friends in other
groups and you know meet other people
so
it's such an amazing thing i mean it
just pushes you to socialize with not
only that it psychologically puts you in
a state of mind where you feel like
socializing more it also has this effect
that in order to find it you have to
connect to more people so it's just
amazing how
uh you know this plant has this
intrinsic property of bringing people
together i mean psychologically
physically in every which way you can
imagine
yeah of course and i mean kind of raises
an interesting point you just brought up
yourself where people in past episodes
have spoke about how
you know it was kind of a glue like when
you met someone who was a fellow smoker
you kind of felt like you could trust
them a bit is that a similar thing in
india like if you meet a group of people
and you say oh hey i'm a smoker you're a
smoker are you kind of able to make
friends easily or is it you still got to
kind of prove yourself a bit
it really depends on on you as a person
i mean
what kind of behavior you have
so in india i mean behavior is big
so
you're uh there's a saying in india that
your behavior is your
introduction
so
if you are humble and you know you want
to learn and you know you do some you
run some errands with those for the
other guys you know then sure i mean
they will make you part of your group
and
of course you can then make friends i
mean i think that's a very subjective
kind of uh issue you know
it's it goes uh case-to-case basis you
know what kind of really person you are
if you're the kind of person who can
connect to other people
so people don't really have
like a fixed uh
i should say this a fixed hierarchy or
something that you have to have
these many years at a certain level to
be able to smoke with someone but it's
just really
depends on you that you know how curious
you are and how resourceful you are and
you know
uh getting to these places getting to
these people and then once you do get
there i mean how good you are in making
sure that you know you're accepted in
these groups and you know
you can then contribute eventually and
become a part of it
yeah that's awesome it's lovely to hear
you know if you're kind of of good
intention heart people are accepting so
you mentioned you first experienced the
nice hash that was brought back by
friends after vacation did that
stimulate a curiosity in you to kind of
think i've got to go find a consistent
source of this for myself
um yeah absolutely
it did but not in terms of like i have
to go out and you know find the fields
pretty much
but more like that hey could i find more
people who belong to this place because
see the way our thinking evolves is
it it happens step by step i'm sure
there are some people you know who
really gifted and you know i mean they
would really you know get to the
conclusion very quickly but for most
people you know you go step by step and
really when you have uh such a uh you
know great experience on something like
hash the only thing that really comes to
your mind is hey i can i have to find
more people you know who has this kind
of stuff like i have to be you know
connecting with i ought to be connecting
with these people so that i can get
access to more of it and see how many
how much you know more variety and
diversity is out there
and you know what all experiences are
waiting for me
you know
in in terms of smoke so
yeah uh
really i mean
it didn't really i mean push me in a way
that i would go to the fields because
that really pushed i mean that push
really came later from a whole different
angle i think is when i saw someone who
was growing it in front of me because
there was this friend of mine who was
growing up and this is in new delhi
around 2015 i think
he got some seeds from milana and he
grew
in his house and you know he was able to
make hash so
that really pushed me and i was like
okay i have to now go there and i have
to get my own seats but i had no idea
what was waiting for me once i got there
and once i really got there
it blew my mind and then i collected my
mind all over again and rearranged it in
a way that you know then
i was i knew what i had to do in my life
i pretty much uh you know abandoned my
masters at that point in time that i was
i mean i was in the final year of my
masters and i thought you know what
um you know i have to wholeheartedly
focus on this thing in preserving this
because there are there were a lot of
other
things that i was becoming aware of at
the same time i mean
i i had uh at the same time i had
connected to people over facebook from
the united states a lot of people who
were growing and you know i found out
that there's a larger community that
exists
outside who already knows so much about
this plant and you know who have done so
much work for it
and
i i understood that you know i have to
play a very important role here by
[Music]
collecting these seeds and making sure
that you know before this is lost we
collect as diverse of a seed sample uh
you know make an archive as diverse as
we can that includes pretty much every
possible cannabis variety that we can so
that
people who are really putting in the
work people the breeders you know who
are in a position in legal places to do
this kind of work they can go ahead and
they can you know work with these
varieties incorporate them into their
gene pool and
take it further you know just
like our contribution to i mean because
you if you like something and you think
this thing helped you in any way you
know shaping your experiences or if you
feel that uh you know this is something
you enjoy then you
uh inherently have a duty towards
promoting that thing so
immediately uh my you know understanding
shifted and i knew that i have to go to
these other places and have to collect
connect to more people
uh to uh you know get access to
different varieties and that's
what really i mean pushed me towards
when going out but
smoking was i mean the first step but it
was not really the ultimate step i would
say man
yeah okay like what a really interesting
recount so you mentioned that you kind
of had that epiphany moment when you
went on a trip to milana was it can you
tell us about that trip
yeah that was in milan so
it was an amazing like like i said uh uh
the moment i got there i didn't know
what was waiting for me i was just going
thinking okay now i'm going to the
village where i'm going to get the hash
so i'll have a lot of options to choose
from and i can have a good time over the
week staying there sampling all these
different
resins and at the same time i was
thinking a little bit about okay you
know there will be plants as well so i
can get some seeds i mean they couldn't
be growing their plants without the
seeds right and this is the time i mean
when people are not really clicking
pictures and they're not really bringing
back pictures from milana so i pretty
much didn't have a very good idea at
that point in time that you know what i
was going to encounter there
so we we get to the milana and you know
we just uh get down i mean we're not
even close to the village right now it's
about two kilometers away and we can
already see the trails of plants you
know just leading along the way
you can see
and
they have all these different
expressions which are so beautiful they
have colors they have variety of smell
from florals citrus
woody you know
something like pine like turpentine
so it was really nice but that's what we
saw at that point in time so
we liked it we thought oh this is it
this is what they make hash of and then
you know we go a little further and then
we find wow i mean you know there are
even better plants in the village and
then once we cross the village and we
eventually get to places like watching
valley magic valley and you know whaling
valley we really understand you know
what is the full potential
of the varieties uh you know these
people make hash out of and
that i think was a profound moment i
mean it
it i mean it has to rearrange your
thinking in a way because that was the
year after which
i i started going to these different
places like i went back to my village
first of all because i realized that you
know a lot of
hunting has to be done there there are a
lot of hot spots just like you know
himachal pradesh has so many
so i went back there we did
uh you know a lot of collection out
there we went to
and we went near into tibetan border we
went near in the chinese border that is
uh at the mana pass we collected samples
and let me tell you this is
this is a different kind of thing i mean
you cannot go to those places and you
know be doing anything around the
cannabis plants because the moment you
cross
the cross into those areas you're under
observation all the time from the towers
of people uh indian tibetan border
police is looking at you at all times
what you're doing
so
being a local from that place is really
going to help you i mean because if
you're from outside then you can just
forget about it i mean you can just
forget about going to those places those
are border regions but and there were
other places which were more relaxed and
more tourist like like oregon valley
where you can just easily act uh you
know you have easy access to
any tourist anybody can go there and
collect seeds
so
we we did all of that and then you know
we went back to malana again and we
started going to you know uh started
going there at different phases and not
just during the flower and that really
made
a lot of other things apparent to us
which which you don't realize in one
glimpse or you don't realize even in a
week if you just go there in october
when you know things are pretty much
ripening
so
and those those things started happening
uh at the same time so i mean it was
just all coming together from that point
for us and you know we were just
beginning to understand you know what
has to be done and how it has to be done
because you know we are in north india
so geographically we're blessed i mean
we're close to almost every cannabis
hotspot you know within and we can get
there in less than 24 hours so that
really enables us to do all these things
in a way that you know i don't think it
would be possible for a lot of other
people
yeah wow what a powerful little
sentiment right there and i think that
yeah you're in such a valuable position
to be in
let's wind it back though for a minute
that initial trip to milana
when you got there
what type of variation were you seeing
in the plants like how many different
phenotypes were there and were they
really different or still pretty similar
for the most part what did you observe
yeah that's a good question i mean
because i i think this is probably the
aspect uh that was
most intriguing i mean from
because of course you see a cannabis
plant so you see a few things you see
the physical embodiment
yeah and you smell it
and you know and you look at how
beautiful the flowers look or the way it
grows in there's so many other things
right
but um
i so i think what was really interesting
to us was the diversity that was present
within milan i mean
i'm just going to give you a little
example the first feel that you know i
was in waiting valley and
i'm seeing this field there are about
150 or like 100 plants there and i can
see a lot of different phenotypes a lot
of different plants i mean just from a
casual look i mean i don't even have to
be an expert i don't have to be a person
who has some you know prior
understanding of you know
how plants work and all of these things
you you could just be a normal person
look at it
and be astonished and be you know
just
be in awe of you know how much
variability is present within a very
small chunk
uh because they're growing like tens of
millions of plants so if i'm talking
about 150 plants field as a sample
i'm just talking about a negligible you
know proportion
so
the variability was just immense i mean
and it just
brings you to a place psychologically
that you are bound to think if this one
place has so much diversity just imagine
what other places which have vastly
different environment like you go to
equator near kerala or you could go to
um
you know
indo tibetan border that is a cold
desert so
they have to have something you know
they have to have something different
they have to
um you know
the plans there have to grow differently
for the reasons that the environment and
the cultures are different so i think
that really started a relentless cycle
so yeah in the terms of variation when
we talk about in malana i think
that in itself was one of the things
that you know got me thinking and i
think uh that was possibly the best
thing i ever did that i thought that if
this one place has so much diversity
imagine if i could go to other places
and how much more i can get and
whether or not i can you know preserve
it because at the same time you know the
destruction of the habitat is going on
for cannabis because we don't recognize
it as a useful plant other than in the
hindu
um you know cultural practice religious
practices so the government doesn't see
it as something you know which is good
so there's not going to be any
preservation from the government's side
as a matter of fact the government has
been bent on you know taking it out
spent on taking it out i mean
in in kerala they have like completely
devastated uh you know these places used
to have cannabis fields in and these
people then are forced to go back deeper
into the jungles and what happens is
they ultimately fall
in the trap of next lights now these
next lights are pretty much running the
show for them
and what they do is they provide them
protection of course from the government
the police
and you know they also help them take
that stuff pack it up and you know get
to the metro cities like new delhi
bombay
pune you know where you can really get a
price uh for that but again i mean
the local farmer is really pretty much
getting bent over i mean he's not
getting any money
so
they're making a lot of money and you
know
they're using it for their organization
because of the activities they have to
carry out with weapons and all of these
things so
[Music]
it's sad i mean the way things are going
and the same things happening in
himachal pradesh where they're really
concerned about their you know tourism
and they have this feeling that the
cannabis is somehow is going to you know
destroy their tourism industry i mean
it's just nuts when you think about it
because most of the people who go to
himachal pradesh you know they go
because of the cannabis
but well that's how the government sees
it and you know the there is relentless
pressure from all sides from all sides
to just
take i mean take this thing out of here
and you know
um
we really feel that if something is not
done right now
then it might be a little too late
yeah okay
um so i mean earlier on you mentioned
that
basically you grew up and it was all
around you but then you just mentioned
that kind of the government's actually a
lot more cracking down on it has that
been a recent change what's the
government's actual stance on it and is
there any sort of medical program
yeah so uh there are a few things um in
the few ways the government is working
so there are places which are of more
interest to government like himachal
pradesh and places like kerala
are have been in highlight i mean ever
since the internet has become more
widespread so government definitely have
their eyes you know
stuck on these two places and most of
the funds that come i think from the
european union to eradicate the cannabis
in india is
directed towards these places but if i
talk about uttarakhand the state i
belong from one of the himalayan states
i i've
not seen much of the eradication
uh you know process except for sometimes
what they do is they would make small
local government bodies and they would
you know gather people on the sunday and
say let's go out and you know take out
all the cannabis plants that you see
around the roadside
but that pretty much doesn't make you
know that doesn't really make the farm
population or that uh the cannabis which
is growing around the road in atrakhan
is not really the part of the plants
which would go on to then make hash
those farms are safe somewhere in the
valleys
so it's all good and the terrorism i'm
sorry and the tourism is not that much
in
you know when you compare it to himachal
pradesh uttarakhand is more known for
pilgrimage it's um
it has four of the most holiest sites
for hinduism hindus and for sikh
religion as well
uh so a lot of people travel there but
for an entirely different reason their
tourism has
a whole different uh you know no
it is it happens because a whole
different region because of the
pilgrimage and when you look at himachal
pradesh or you look at kerala their
tourism is based around more like
recreation and the things you could do
there that you could not
in the
in the in the other places
yeah okay brilliant so
just quickly
was it before sorry let me re-ask that i
kind of asked that really badly
yeah awesome so i mean i'm interested to
know when were you first able to start
to link up with other people who were
kind of like-minded was it before or
after the manila trip which really kind
of solidified things in your mind
yeah that was really amazing because
before milan i was just connecting to
like i said people morph to acquire like
hash if i could get more of that
experience that i liked at that point in
time after smoking that but once i went
to milan you know and i came back and i
traveled a little bit to other places
like i said
so then i realized i mean i could only
go to so many places you know that i
have to have other people i have to you
know have friends and people like-minded
people in other states because india is
a vast country right so
it's hard to travel you know all across
the country so i thought this would be a
good idea but in in the end i mean that
didn't really uh you know work out uh
too well because uh you know a lot of
things that happened
and and it's understandable because if
you're going to involve you know if
human beings are going to involve in
something then there's going to be some
fuss at some point
so uh that was not really a big deal
though but yeah after that i mean i was
really uh you know inclined towards uh
getting connected with more people
you know who are like-minded but after i
realized that hey you know what this is
not going to work i mean i cannot trust
somebody who's sitting on internet
because i see that is the trend right
now
that you know you get hold of someone
who's on internet uh let's say he's in
you know africa and you say oh you're in
africa so you can get me african seats
well he can get you african seats but i
mean if that's how you're gonna go about
it then
i think then we're at two different
places uh you know thinking about this
thing
so i thought you know i have to go there
and the other more
bigger part was that you know that it
had started to generate some sort of
revenue and i had a concern that okay
now i have this revenue coming in from
the seats so what happens to this
what do i do with this so
eventually you start thinking about it
and you understand that you know what
you have to do all your answers lies in
one thing that you have to physically go
to these places you have to meet these
people people make them understand you
know what your program is all about what
you're doing and how it's going to help
them and you know the other community on
the other side of the world
and just
make them understand that this is
something bigger than you me and all of
us put together you know and you know
get them on board and at the same time
they get paid for the seeds that they're
giving so that makes you feel great i
mean you know that you know not only
that you're helping in preservation
you're also able to mobilize resources
to these people
who
could never imagine they can see making
money off season and for them it's the
resin that makes uh really the cash now
i'm trying to make them understand the
value of the seed and you know value of
just about everything in that plant
that uh you know they may be undermining
so
far yeah of course that's a really
valuable point to make and it brings on
a range of different questions i had
such as
do you think that money is one of the
best things you can trade people for the
seeds or what are some other things
because i remember in a previous bodhi
episode he mentioned a few different
things he likes to trade and they all
sounded really good like he'll take some
basic medicines sometimes or you know
some coloring in books for the kids and
whatnot what are some things you like to
trade do you think just money is the
best or
no i don't think money is the best uh at
least not for the villages you know
which are really located in remote areas
so for them even if i get them some
money i mean it's more like being on an
island with a lot of cash i mean you
can't really do anything with it right
so what i feel
more appropriate is i really go there
and understand their situation and you
know we look around at how could we make
you know life better for these people
but at the same time
not interfere with the culture enough
that it begins to morph into
something you know like a third thing
right so you have to be very careful
about that
so what we do is
you know mobile phones is uh one of the
most sought after things amongst the
villagers because you know they can
hardly get to those places where good
mobile phones are available and then bad
you know battery backups and
led lights which are charged by you know
solar energy
and just a bunch of batteries and you
know clothes for their kids
and of course some you know other things
that kids would really appreciate and
you know you just could not find it but
still i mean uh being very careful that
you know we don't bring something that
might lead to
any detrimental change in their culture
or that
you know
could be the beginning of something
which is not desirable
yeah so i mean to kind of throw you in
the hot seat what do you think about
what greenhouse seeds does where they go
to these places and trade their crappy
european genetics for the land race
seeds
um i i i don't really have an opinion
about that i mean because
[Music]
i think i i've seen the i've seen the
documentary you know that they came in
milana and it was really nice it was
shot you know very professionally but
uh i don't have a very strong opinion
about it but yeah i will say this that
you know uh they should not be giving
people
those seeds you know
i mean because you know then i heard an
argument from someone it was a really
stupid argument that somebody said hey
you know these are like feminized seeds
and you know it doesn't really matter
and you just begin to understand i mean
how
short-sighted and myopic uh you know
these people these people's visions are
because they're not thinking even if
it's a feminized plan if it gets
pollinated which it will get pollinated
by the males around it and sudden seeds
are going to drop you can't you can put
like an umbrella under those plants and
make sure you collect every seeds and
just takes one seed to fall down you
know which is like a hybrid uh which is
hybrid in nature and i'm not saying that
it's going to ruin everything or but you
have to understand i mean
we already have a lot of that i mean you
know we have all the hybrid varieties we
want and we have these places where it's
even legal and you could grow it and
it's being sold and being taxed you know
people are making t-shirts and trays and
i don't know what not you know so
let's just you know i think that's
enough you know you don't have to really
bring it to places you know where it's
really not required
i mean that's just how i feel about it
yeah i mean
i'm probably gonna go down a wrong path
here but just just as a one isolated
question because we're gonna talk about
this a lot more later
no problem i'm in no problem
have you ever gone to an area like a
regional area found a patch and you
thought oh my god this is all just like
super lemon haze or like something like
that
yeah of course
so uh if you go to imagine pradesh there
are certain places
you know you could like absolutely tell
what's happening there
so uh himachal pradesh is a very
interesting place let's just first of
all understand something about you know
how people are and then that would
really put a lot of other things in
perspective
so when you compare three himalayan
states kashmir uttarakhand and himachal
pradesh i'm going to say the most
advanced state and the most advanced
people are living in himachal pradesh
when you just compare it i mean amongst
these three states not just the india
and why that is well that's because the
exposure that they're getting they have
so much
tourism going in there you have these
you know israeli people who would almost
never go out of himachal pradesh i don't
even understand you know how they can be
there for indefinite periods anyways and
you have europeans you have americans
and you have you know all these other
countries like australia canada new
zealand you know people travel over
there and what
happens is that over time you know
people get more and more exposure it's
almost like those people are traveling
to those countries because the
experiences are so frequent right so
they have been acquainted with the
information that is just not available
you know to other places of traditional
you know cannabis
and these people know that there are
varieties that exist you know uh which
flower faster and can grow you know
bigger buds and you know they are
very very potent as well you know which
would ultimately you know get you more
money if you were to make hash from them
so
there are people who understand but
where those people are are they are in
manali they're around manali in old
manali especially there's a place called
that's like famous for that and then you
have nagar there's a place called nagar
that is uh that is also around
uh like old manali
so these uh these places are like really
famous and you go there and you know you
could just look at the plant and smell
it and you know this is this is not a
plant you know that's been grown here or
has been you know domesticated
from the wild populations you just
understand that you know this is some uh
this is an effect of
uh you know genetic infection
rather so yeah there are places uh but
luckily places like kashmir and
uttarakhand have you know stayed
safe from
the things like that because you know
first nobody goes there really and you
know even if they do i mean you don't
get just enough tourism from other
countries that you would eventually
start to have people who can bring seeds
over there
plus you know we've been going around
those places and you know we've never
really seen anything any sign even
remotely close to of
uh something that would suggest that you
know
there's been
an activity like that
yeah of course and i guess
the follow-on question i have is that do
you think that people trading these
modern seeds to land race regions could
ultimately lead to the extinction of
those regional cultivars
yeah this is i mean this is pretty much
how it's going to go down and it's
inevitable in a way and no no matter how
much we
you know dislike it or say yeah you know
we're going to be warriors and we're
going to stop this
you know we're all human beings and you
know
we're not even like a government
funded program or something right
so we understand that eventually when a
lot of people you know would become
aware that you know there's a global
community and you know the interaction
would have begin to happen in a way like
it happened in the iit sector you know
which is just absolutely you know
maddening then you're gonna have tons of
people you know uh selling seeds to
india and it only is a matter of time
that someone
goes out to all of these places and you
know start uh growing these plants and
start infecting everything and changing
them eventually but that's what uh you
know really
our existence is all about and you know
as much as i don't like it i mean i'm
not gonna say that it will not happen
because that's just not practical yeah
there are going to be some places which
will be saved
places like lola valley in kashmir or
because you're just you just can't go
there and i mean like it's hard i mean
and the only very few people who can go
there i mean you know we we know who
those people are so for the longest time
i think they will be able to save their
uh you know natural varieties but
uh places like malana and places like
you know even urgent valley in
uttarakhand you know where tourism is
more those places would be the first one
to fall prey to things like this because
uh they're easy to access and you know
the villagers are very friendly and
well i mean that's all you need and you
know they have an inclination towards
making more money from this plant so i
just don't see why they would not want
to have those varieties when they would
understand that clearly we can you know
make more money off this and just
make the whole situation better for us
harvest early
i mean you cannot deny the fact you know
that there are certain advantages
inherent advantages which are attached
with these you know hybrid varieties but
uh you just have to move to a different
plane to look at it from a different
angle and understand that it's not all
about that
but for the villagers who are making
money off it to them it's all about that
and as soon as they realize that they
can do something better than they would
they would do it
yeah okay and i guess my final question
on this topic is
how do you feel about the fact that
greenhouse seeds for example has never
reproduced and sold to the public these
lines as far as we can tell it's just
sitting in their seed bank
when again i i don't really think about
those things then i don't really seem to
have
an opinion or a
you know available
emotion for that that i can you know
readily express right now but
um what i think about that is
i don't know there could be reasons
because they did take milano line and
you know they made certain uh certain
varieties with it but at the same time
you're right they never really released
those things in pure form so
uh then you have to understand i mean
you have to begin to think at least that
these people
i mean someone who does not want to
include everyone into the club
basically you know
is not for the people right is
is
those people are just trying to do
something which is very specifically
beneficial to them but at the same time
make it appear as though you know other
people are part of it so i mean it's
it's it's pretty clever but at the same
time you know it's a business and you
know
uh it's not a surprise i mean you know
human beings have done
you know so many things i mean this just
is not even you know
uh
uh the systems stand in a way that it
would surprise anyone that uh
you know that
has happened that they've never released
any of the pure lines but well that's
changing because we here and you know
other people are here uh so many other
people from india right now who are
actually on instagram and they're
actually you know uh you know
interacting with these other folks and
getting these seats out as we
speak there are folks from india i know
and these are all decent collectors okay
they're good they're good guys they're
trying to do good things as much as they
can and they have partnered with you
know certain folks in america and you
know
they're going around doing these
partnerships and you know preserving the
pla
pure variety and then making some
hybrids with it and you know rolling it
out to public you know collect the funds
and then you know distribute it amongst
the grower and you know the collector
and the other people the farmers are
involved
so
i'm just saying seeing these so many you
know multitudes and
of facets you know in which people are
discovering you know how the
preservation of the land race and
heirlooms uh could could become more
prevalent and could become a thing
actually that you know if you if you are
a person of cannabis and you don't grow
a land race an heirloom variety if you
haven't preserved one and it should be
like you know shame on you something
like that you know that you
uh
seem to say that you know you spiritual
you you derive a spiritual
pleasure from this plan right but at the
same time you haven't done anything to
preserve
the source
from where you derive that pleasure so
once people have that kind of
understanding once we understand on the
spiritual level why the history matters
why we cannot ignore these people who
who have done all the work for thousands
of years who have gone out in the wild
recognized the plant brought them back
domesticated them and got them to a
point where they started to look like
the cannabis plant that we you know
look at
and then some people from europe or
america you know they went out and they
grabbed those varieties and you know
made hybrids within a matter of few
decades i mean that was only possible
because before that those varieties were
you know domesticated for thousands of
years let me just say this very bluntly
i mean if those people had to go out to
places
where
and you know get the varieties which are
absolutely wild you know they grow like
just really weed you understand why it's
called wheat and if you had to work with
them a lot of people would still be in
breeding them and getting them to a
point
uh you know where they where they have
some sort of consistency some some sort
of homogeneity in terms of their traits
that they like
and
that's really when you know
so it would have taken a lot of time and
we wouldn't be nowhere near where we are
and a big part of that is to understand
that you know the domestication part the
foundation work was done by the people
you know who are these indigenous
communities in himalayas in afghanistan
and pakistan
you know africa and laos cambodia
thailand and like i don't wanna just
like list all of these but you know all
these places so we have to recognize
them in an organic way this is not a
political way of seeing it that uh hey
you know these guys deserve it no it's
not like that i mean if you're going to
say that you know
that
i get a spiritual experience from
cannabis then let me ask you something
you know what is the essence of
spirituality i mean it lies in the
deeper
subjective understanding you know of our
own self of our
things that are around us that
makes us happy and this is one of the
things that i can think of that makes me
happy
and you know it has a deep impact on me
for that reason
so
how can you like completely or truly i
mean reconcile that spiritual experience
without actually knowing or
understanding
or even appreciating
the
i mean the magnitude of work which
indigenous communities have put
in these thousands of years before we
came into the picture
so
once those things become you know
common knowledge and we know all of that
history the cultures
that's when we can truly say that we are
able to now have a complete spiritual
experience from this plant
just that's what i feel
yeah no really powerful sentiment i dig
it i dig it so if we just jump back in
the story i just wanted to quickly ask
another question about the milana fields
you went to were they making charis or
hash from those plants and if so what
was it like
um yeah i mean
so they don't actually like stand in the
fields and rub them
what they usually do is uh either they
send the women of the house or like
somebody would go out venture into the
fields
with like a makeshift basket which is
attached to rope and you could wear it
like a bag right
so they would uh you know cut a bunch of
plants and they would just bring them to
a designated place of rubbing so
uh let me just tell you some a little
about you know the rubbing here so that
you know it becomes a bit more
understandable
so one is malana village and most of the
rubbing does not actually happen over
there most of the hash is not actually
made in the milano village because their
fields are around the village which are
these different valleys waiting valley
whaling and magic valley and a few
others
what these people do is that these
people have makeshift houses in each of
these valleys where their fields are
so they're not traveling back and forth
every day to their house during the
harvest season because the harvest
window is small and the same time police
is cracking down on them and they have
to make sure that they go get through
their uh you know
whatever they've grown their produce
very quickly so the best way to do it is
during the octobers they would move with
the entire family to these places like
uh white let's just say in wailing
valley right
and now from that point onwards every
day is simply dedicated from morning
till they go to the sleep rubbing hash
producing hash
it's a relentless process they're
speaking to you i mean you could be
there smoking or eating food or looking
around and you would just see
these people are going about it as if
like we go about breathing
around that point in time so
it it gets normalized pretty soon once
you know you get you you grow accustomed
to it because you see so much of it i
mean as soon as you get in there
if you go there around you know the
season when
you know plants are flowering that is
around october of course october and
november as well but november um you
don't see much of rubbing but october is
everywhere i mean you just get near
milana and you know the air has this
freaking smell of cannabis you know
it it drives you crazy and it tells you
you know where to go you can just leave
the smell
oh wow that sounds lovely i think i
actually saw on one of your instagram
posts that you were saying
a lot of the kind of hash and charis and
whatnot that comes out of that region is
kind of like a 50 50 of thc to cbd
and i thought that's that's really
surprising do you
like what do you think of that what do
you make how do you think that really
happened because i don't think many
people would have predicted that
yeah first of all i'm gonna uh tell you
like why i think that is the case and
like how i got to that conclusion so
um there was somebody in europe uh
who
imported
by you know however he managed it to
import
some hash which was from malana okay and
that was tested and it came out to be
like 50 percent
thc and almost like nearly 50 cbd
now you have to understand that if
hash is coming from malana it's not
coming from one plant what you have
there
is you have a small chunk taken out of a
huge chunk that was made from
so many
different plants i mean if you were to
do like a random sample
like you were doing an experiment that's
exactly how it would be done you would
just go about without discriminating
amongst the plants you just say the
first 50 plant that i encounter you know
i'm going to rub them and
whatever the hash tells me is going to
be the story is going to be the
phytochemical story of this population
right
so when that happened what we saw was
you see
you actually see a higher amount of cbd
by the way but it's still i mean almost
equal it's like 60 40 kind of thing
and then there was another incident so
this was one incident the second
isolated incident was i i gave some
seeds to uh one of the guys who who grew
it and he grew actually a few of them
not just one or two
and
this guy did something really
interesting he did not see them and you
know he
trimmed them and cured the buds and he
smoked everything separately and he had
mocked the plants and then he came back
to me and he
he said he said it look it's weird but
here's the deal some of the plants uh
you know have a great high
and then these and some plant have mild
high and there are some plants which
have no high at all no effects
and they're like this
they have all the trichomes they have
all the beautiful smells
just like the other plants but they just
don't have any effects to them at all
and that gets you thinking that what is
happening there so
basically what you're seeing is you're
seeing resin on the plant so there has
to be some
something some cannabinoid in it so if
it's not thc then what is it i mean the
only more abundant cannabinoid that you
know
actually is present in the environment
is cbd and i had already known from that
test that came from europe for that hash
that was imported from india that a
major part of the
the
you know the chemical composition is
cbd
so if you just put these observation
together and you know uh think in a you
know if in a reductive manner then you
all ultimately get to a conclusion that
look
there seem to be this
uh distribution of population among in a
way that
there are plants which are purely uh you
know making cbd and with that said they
have certain amounts of thc i'm not
trying to say that just zero
uh thc there's some thc with
predominantly cbd and then you have
plants which have a very uh
nice balanced cbd and thc content which
is close to 50 50 or you know just
various combinations then you have
plants which are dominantly producing
thc and they're uh you know they produce
very little cbd so what you see in
nature is i mean milana that you seem to
have these three varieties and their
intermix they're getting
cross-pollinated
so
uh
the population or the dominance of the
population you know it works out in a
random fashion so what you see is the
the dominant genome sorry the chemotype
is the one that produces cbd and it's
nthc and i actually fell back to one of
the studies that happened in 2003 i
think it was from america
somebody did an experiment he took a
drug variety and he took a non-drug
variety which is a hampy cross them
and what he saw in f1 was
you know from the heterogeneous
population he saw that
most of the plants
carried a co-dominant expression which
was thc and cbd and about like 25
percent of the plants close to 25
percent of the plants with cbd and close
to 25 percent were thc so it was almost
like a one ratio ratio one in f1 and and
that tells you something that if these
populations are led to mix and
intermingle then
which chemotype would eventually
be more dominant and which would be a
little more recessive in nature and
that's exactly uh you know what we're
seeing in malana when we
isolate these plants and you know grow
them separately and you know
take out resin separately and sample
them because that is just not a thing
that's going to happen in milan i mean
you can't get people to just rub one
single plant and you know give you the
hash and then a different plant although
we are going to try to
make that happen uh this year we're
hoping we're hoping that we're gonna
make this uh you know happen
uh but it's gonna be difficult because
it's hard to find you know plants big
enough that you could just rub and make
a tangible amount of uh resin to sample
for five to six people so we'll see if
we can work it uh
that way then if i can get some of the
samples out for testing as well and i
can have
uh i can have the testing done from one
single source to really get a
comprehensive report which can be you
know taken a little more seriously
yeah that's a cool little goal for this
next coming year
i guess the question that comes to mind
for me is why do you think we see this
strong occurrence of cbd in this type of
hash
compared to say afghani hash where we
just see it's primarily thc
i think that the answer lies in the way
human beings have uh you know interacted
with the cannabis plant
a big part of that is
the way they have been domesticated so
if we just rewind a little bit and let's
just start from a time when human beings
are not really uh aware that you know
cannabis is something that they need
uh as a plan and it has so many you know
beneficial properties and such a
wonderful thing to be around i'm sorry
just give me one moment
i'm sorry so
once uh that happens once a community
let's say let's take an example of hindu
kush that's a community in hindu she
realizes that hey this is a great plant
this is growing
around us and you know it has certain
properties and it's really cool so what
they do is they take that plant and they
bring it
to their surroundings where they grow
other useful plants like tomatoes or you
know coriander or anything else that
they grow over there and they would
start cultivating it
along with it so eventually what's going
to happen is some physiological changes
would be observed over time because of
you know the frequency of the nutrient
uh
you know
increasing and you know the plant would
eventually accommodate to those changes
and become vigorous right would increase
the surface level
surface area of the leaf
uh the stem is going to become more
rigid instead of the spindly spindly one
and it would of course produce more
because of all those changes uh
present in the plant eventually
so
the domestication that happened in hindu
kush basically that happened around the
recreation part because i don't think in
out of the plants i don't think they
were domesticated those domesticating
those plants so they could you know take
out seeds and make chutney out of that i
don't think those things were happening
over there what i really think was
happening there was that they had
realized that this plant has an amazing
capacity to produce
uh you know substances which are just
amazing like
you know it could take you into a
different realm altogether and you know
for someone who's more religious he
could associate it in a way that hey
this could be spiritual you know and it
it brings me closer to god
so for those reasons i think most of the
domestication that happened in the kush
that happened around the recreation part
they were more
inclined towards
you know cultivating the plants which
which had a more significant effect on
our cognition
rather than a selecting plant which
looked to be more beneficial or add like
more stem to it or you know
larger leaves or whatever but once you
come to like you know southeast asia or
central asia it's a whole different
thing central asia is in the north
indian part of central asia it's a whole
different thing what's happening there
is first of all you look at the plant
the plant has a different uh you know
morphological structure
uh how does it differ from the afghani
variety well the way it differs is much
taller
and it's
and flowers for a little longer but when
you look at the leaves uh you know
closely at a domesticated variety let's
say from uh you know malana what you see
is the leaves are not narrow they are
actually pretty broad they are actually
pretty broad leaves
it's just that the plant grows in a way
that
when you look at the overall plant you
cannot say that it's a broad leaf
variety because it does not have the
other characteristics which will
correspond to that
so
basically i mean
same thing is happening in the equation
the same thing is happening in uh malana
but what is the difference now the
difference is that in milan or in india
or southeast asia people are selecting
for various traits and not just for
recreation
they're selecting the plants because
they want to make ropes out of it they
want to they're selecting those plants
because they want to be able to you know
use that fiber or
those you know thick stems or uh
you know
yeah thick stems for a shelter or
something right
so those changes ultimately led to the
way the those plants are i mean they
have like a hemp like a hemp-like
structure and
basically they are not as potent not
nearly as potent as any of the afghani
varieties and i think the biggest
difference
uh that i mean the
the difference
between uh you know having a variety
which is
very potent and not very potent is the
way they were domesticated by human
beings and what they domesticated them
for i mean that's what the embodiment of
the plants show with of course
a lot of feature has to do a lot with
the environment as well but i think
we'll get to that later but just for the
domestication part and from the part
that you said uh why a certain variety
seem to have you know uh much more
intense effect than the other one then i
think that really is the answer the
answer lies in the way they have been
domesticated from the earliest time
and the people and the communities which
have engaged with those plants
yeah what a fantastic answer so
it makes me think then
do you think that maybe this selection
for a bit more of those hemp traits like
what we mentioned in the south southeast
asian region do you think that how they
did select for those other traits such
as the fibrous characteristics and
whatnot
added to why these plants perceived as
having a more uplifting high or do you
think the uplifting versus sedating
component was almost independent of that
type of selection
um i i think they have not really
selected for the effects very
specifically uh i mean that could be
something which is just innate to the
plant that a certain type of plant
uh i think it could have something to do
with the environment because what you
usually see and i don't necessarily
subscribe to the idea that you know the
narrow leaf varieties would always have
or necessarily have an uplifting high
energy variety or a short
you know short flowering variety would
always have sedating effects i i think
it uh
it's not that black and white first of
all but yeah even to a large part if you
feel i mean
that is the case which we see to a large
extent it is then i think that is that's
a byproduct of
uh more like the environment that they
grow in i think and i don't really
understand i'm not trying to say that i
do understand that
uh but i would i would lean more towards
the environmental you know factors which
may have contributing in the uh
you know in the way
the uh the plan makes you feel and i'll
give you a one example i mean that might
make you understand that why i'm leaning
towards more environmental factors and
that is the quality of the resin so
when you go to a
when you go to a region you know that's
that has a very dry climate and the
brain is very scarce it's it's very arid
and cold what you see is the trichomes
have a very dry texture on the outside i
mean they they're not very sticky i mean
you really have to you know uh
i mean
what do you you really have to touch
them to break them apart you know i mean
you can't just touch them and expect
that you know
like a jelly like like a saliva like you
know
thing would happen as you you know touch
the resin because it's just not sticky
but on the other hand when you go to
places which are like which have a
subtropical or a tropical environment
where rain is prevalent and it's really
wet during the flowering what do you see
what you see is that the resin has a
very
um gluey sticky texture and you know it
makes perfect sense you know because
in in a situation where it's constantly
raining while your plant isn't flowering
what you would want is your plant to
have a very sticky kind of resin so that
the water does not hold on in between
them and it just you know slides right
through the buds because that is really
going to help you mitigate those
uh environmental risk i mean apart from
that there are certain you know innate
qualities in plants which make them of
course resistant to things like mold and
mildew and all these factors but
the parent physical traits some of the
apparent physical traits are also there
which you can see as the adaptations in
the plants because of the environment
they grow in
and now
we're talking about the texture of the
resin i mean we're talking about the
thing that actually induces the
uh you know the psychological changes
when you smoke it so if
the texture of that thing is dictated
pretty much by the environment to grow
in then it's only reasonable to believe
that you could take it a step further
and you know
it probably transcends into you know the
effects as well and
but again i'm not going to say that
that's the case or i understand that but
that's what i feel about it
no that makes a lot of sense and it
perfectly segues into my next question
which is that we often hear this idea
expressed about let's just say you're in
some region and you smoke some of the
herb and it's it's brilliant and you're
able to get some of the seeds people
would often say that if you take that
back to where you come from let's assume
you're from a different country you go
back to where you're from if you grow it
out say indoors or just under some quite
controlled conditions it's just not
going to be the same you know because it
was all about the terroir and the
environment do you think that's the case
like if i get some really nice bud from
india am i never going to be able to
reproduce it even with the seeds in
australia for example
i i think what's contributing to that
sort of
thinking is a few different factors and
i'm just going to like lay it out here
um i think the first and the foremost
thing is that we have to understand if
you're in a place like india where it
grows naturally let's let's take an
example uh let's take the example of
malana because it's a known place right
so if you're in a place and you find a
plant oh this is a great plant you know
i would love to grow this plant when i
go back home to us or australia wherever
and you take out seeds but you don't
know which males went on to you know
pollinate that plant but apart from that
what you're looking at is not a true
breeding variety they're not true
breeding in nature so that means they
are not
homozygous for all the traits you're
seeing in them and that's one of the
reasons why you see so much variability
in the field i mean when you look at 100
plants and like they're like 35
different kinds in 100 plants then you
understand when there's a lot of
variability in terms of genotype right
so it becomes really hard to find that
plant that's one of the things because
it's not being you know bred by someone
it's not being narrowed down or
bottlenecked they just emerge as like
one-off plant that you may encounter and
may like
now the second thing is uh the question
that you asked that is it all about the
terroir is it going to be the same well
of course terror plays a pivotal role in
the way your plant is going to look for
example if your grow room is too hot i
mean you know your plant is going to
look like [__] pretty much right and if
you have
if you have a colder environment in your
room which is around 22 24 to 20 degrees
celsius then you know your plants can
pretty much have a very good time even
if there are some other deficits
plant would still do much better so we
understand that even in real time i mean
you know
the plant reacts to the environment it's
in and it's try to mitigate those things
by you know expressing itself in a way
that it could just
get through this somehow and produce
flowers and make seeds because at the
end we have to understand the plant is
not working for us okay the plot is
working for itself it wants to make
seats
it wants to reproduce and that's it so
now it's up to us uh you know that we
have to save it from the mail and you
know uh
you know make it sound similar or like
whatever we want to do but again we have
to understand that the environment while
it's having an impact on the plant it's
not so deep that it would change the
characteristic in a way that you'll not
be able to recognize it and i'm going to
give you an example for that let's just
say that you went to kerala and you
collected some seeds now we all
understand these are equatorial
varieties and you know they flower for a
very long time around 16 to 18 or even
20 weeks sometimes it's rare but they do
anyways so you bring that back and you
you you grow inside your house so
what you may see is that you might just
see that you have slightly broader
leaves because your indoor grow room or
your outside condition may be a little
colder you know you so you might see
that
but
you're not gonna see that a kerala plant
is gonna finish in eight weeks that is
not gonna happen i mean a change of that
magnitude would never happen
that is one thing
and then the other thing is that are you
able to find the very specific bud or
the flower or the flavor that you're
looking at now in time in terms of
flavor you can get lucky because flavors
even in you know
even in the population which have great
variability i mean you know the flavor
seems to be pretty homogenous i don't
know for what reason but it is so yeah
you can have uh you know you can find
the flavor within a relatively small
population but if you really want to
find the same plant
there is no guarantee and if somebody's
like offering you seed by saying that i
mean well then you should be very
skeptical of that person as well
i can definitely agree with that
sentiment
so i want to ask a little bit because i
mean i'm the first one to admit i could
probably be a bit more educated about
this but what's your take on
classifications because i know that
you're not particularly into the whole
city of indica thing because as you said
it's just not so clear-cut how do you
try to classify plants and as a little
follow-up how would you describe most
indian varieties i've heard that they're
more kind of uplifting how would you
describe them
okay
yeah so i mean before i really get down
to the classification part first of all
uh i'm going to speak briefly about you
know what exactly is the problem with
the current nomenclature that you know
you seem to use
so the individual thing i mean i i now
i'm hearing a lot of people you know
they they're uh they're trying to say
that hey you know this india sativa
thing doesn't seem to work i mean the
distinction is not you know great enough
and then there are a lot of plants in
between so you don't really know what to
call them so people are you know the
more they get exposed to different
varieties more they would understand
that how these uh you know labels are
just not gonna be enough to encapsulate
the whole idea of this plant
now very particularly fails is i think
in the settings that where people have
not been who are using these words so
let's just say somebody and i'm just
giving an example right so let's just
say for example and someone in america
says today says one day
i'm going to call
all the cannabis plants with narrow leaf
sativa and everything that grows with
broad leaf and stay short you know
subsequently i'm going to call it indica
and he's like okay that's perfect
because that's all i see i see narrow
leaf plants and i see broad leaf blonde
but that's really his
world i mean i mean it's not other
people's really far that you have never
gone out of your house or you've never
gone over your country right and you've
never seen that you know there's more
exist in the world so from that person's
perspective it's perfectly okay and you
know the system seemed to work okay
up to a point where other people start
to come in and you know they start
sending in all these varieties and what
you see is
uh you see narrow leaf blonde that
finish faster like you know what you
would expect from an indica and then you
have you know broadly really broadly
planned that would go on to flower like
13 to 14 weeks
and that's when you begin to
think that hey is it really i mean uh is
it really sufficient the sativa indica
level to you know capture the whole idea
and clearly the answer is no it's not i
mean at the lea at the best it creates
confusion and nothing else now another
problem with
that kind of uh labeling is that when
you go to
i'll give you i'll give you an example
of kashmir if you go to palwama
so what you're going to see is there are
farm population which are being farmed
by the farmers right domesticated ones
and
just on the vicinity what you're gonna
see is there a lot of wild population
untamed population which is just growing
like wheat and nobody is stopping those
two varieties from interacting with each
other and then you see a third variety
is stemming from that interaction that
is an intermediate variety between those
two so how do you account for that
i mean it's hard it's hard to account
for it so
that label sort of like fails us
in like so many ways you know that i
just don't feel comfortable using it
because i often get to points where
i just feel that this is not enough so
what i did as a solution because you
just can't complain about it right you
have to do something about it if you
don't like it
so what i did was i i thought you know
this uh i i think uh
i may be wrong but i think robert clark
was the person who proposed that you
know these should be labeled as broad
leaf and short leaf plants i'm sorry
narrow leaf plants which
is good i find i find that uh you know
much better because first of all those
words are self-explanatory you don't
need to tell someone what a narrow leaf
drug variety is it just explains itself
in itself and that's amazing you want it
to be simple now the second thing that
it does is that you know it effectively
classifies those two plants that we are
referring to a narrow leaf drug
producing variety and then you could
have varieties which are narrow leaf and
non-dog producing so it also accounts
for those varieties which is great
but then again you run into a small
problem and that small problem is
when you encounter varieties like
let's say from northern kashmir which
are narrow leaf
but they flower very fast they in fact
flower within 55 to 66 days
then it
seemed to uh that it then it seems like
that there has to be a little more to
that broad leaf narrow leaf section if
you could well there is a
very good answer to that so what i
thought was
you could
basically look at these plants and i'm
not i'm not talking about hybrids here
okay because those are like man-made
you know uh combinations so we're just
talking about the naturally occurring
varieties and the varieties which were
derived later and domesticated in those
regions and elsewhere okay
so what we can do is we can distribute
the world in basically four to five
different zones so initially i i did
four zones and what i did was i thought
okay so i'm going to start from the
equator
so what do i have is the thinnest leaves
like needle-like leaves
in the plants which are growing near the
equator
but they're also not at high altitudes i
mean you can be like you know
column uh like colombia you know where
you have highlands even though it's
pretty close to the equator not that
close i think it's around 26 degrees not
but still
so but there are highlands so it's going
to affect the plant in a different way
so i thought okay pure first category is
going to be the purely
um narrow leaf plants which grow in the
equator and i call them equatorial long
flowering varieties now what this does
is first of all it tells you about where
that variety is coming from equatorial
you immediately know this is an
equatorial variety comes from equator
the second thing you immediately
understand it's a long flowering variety
okay so an equatorial long flowering
variety now this is what i say that you
go around the equator anywhere in the
world
and if you find a plant that is
naturally growing or being domesticated
around
the equator it's going to have a very
long plum period around like 14 to 16
weeks which is quintessential to the
cannabis varieties which have adapted
around those regions and it's going to
have narrow leaves because it's going to
be hot and the plant would you know uh
the way uh plant tend to mitigate that
is by you know reducing the surface area
of the leaf
then we move on to the second
uh section the second classification was
um
highland long flowering zones so now if
you come to places like colombia like i
spoke about colombia or i would actually
like to talk about
uh himachal pradesh or malana
because it's around the same
latitude it's around like 29 30 uh
degrees north right so again these
places are not very close to the equator
but they're not very far away from the
equator either but at the same time
there is a very uh interesting
characteristic attached to the second
second category that is that these are
highlands these are the places which
have altitude over 1 500 meters
so anything at any region that is below
33 degrees north and i will come back to
it why 33 degrees north i'll come back
to it later
any place that is 33 degrees
which is below 33 degrees north or south
of the equator and it has an altitude of
1500 meters or above that would be
classified as a highland long flowering
variety because when you go to these
places what you see is you see a medium
long flowering varieties that it that
flowers just a tad bit
earlier than you know the equatorial
ones so your kerala finishes around 16
and your malana is going to be done
around like 12 13 so there will be about
a month's difference okay
then we move on to the third category
and this is where uh you know things
will get really interesting and the
third category is
the areas which are high latitude
short flowering zones
now the word tells you that these all
areas are situated in high latitudes
and the plants that grow there are short
flowering in nature
so we're talking about places which are
33 degrees north or above them
they seem to have a characteristic that
those varieties will finish faster
and they always tend to have bigger
resin glands and like more copious
coverage of resin
which
again makes you believe makes you uh you
know think or believe that the colder
environment has a direct relationship
with you know
the the resin coverage or the production
of resin because when you go to the
places near equator where it's hot
uh the resin is not never
in copious amount and trichomes are
really
small
which is exactly the opposite as you
move to the high latitude regions where
it's
always really cold because you're in the
higher latitudes so
the varieties tend to have these
characteristics and the last one is high
latitude highlands so there are some
highlands within the high latitude
because the third category that we spoke
about high latitude short flowering zone
that was for all the places which are
below 1500 meters in altitude but above
33 degrees north so they still have a
significant short season and the
varieties tend to finish around like
eight to nine weeks but
uh or around like 10 weeks sorry and
then you go to a different region you
know which is highland but it's again
situated above 33 degrees now now things
really get interesting here because not
only those places are going to be cold
you know that those places are going to
get the snowfall right around the end of
november around the end of october or
the beginning of november
because one they are so higher up in
latitude i mean they're above 33 degrees
of north secondly there is 1500 meters
of altitude or more involved so places
like hindu kush
you know
in the mountains or
certain places in pakistan
[Music]
you know they also have an altitude of
of 1 500 meters and more and they seem
to have completely different
characteristics these are the plants
you know which
have an insane amount of resin i mean
some of the plants have
so much resin coverage on them that you
know it could really uh you know rival
any of the hybrid varieties and we
understand that all of these places uh
you know
where where high latitude highland uh
you know regions are of natural cannabis
varieties are for domesticated cannabis
varieties all these places are luckily
you know situated in dangerous areas
where you know
your
greenhouse or yellow house seed company
could not have gone you know with their
seeds or whatnot
so we understand you know whatever we're
seeing there is a is a byproduct of the
environment
so that's how you can basically classify
for uh categories and you can go on my
website that is
www.indianlandriesexchange.com
i have written an article that was
written i think about year year and a
half ago about this and
i i need to amend a few things to it
because i'm always learning and trying
to put together you know more
information in a more coherent manner so
you guys can go and actually read that
uh article you know if i may not be
explaining it very well here
so but but that's one of the
classifications which i feel is really
complete and it kind of encapsulates
everything
uh you know that is present in in the
cannabis hot spots where cannabis been
growing
either traditionally for very long time
or has been growing naturally or has
been domesticated the only uh issue that
i had later on was with one of the
regions that became apparent to me and
that was on the cold desert regions like
niti valley in uttarakhand this is
close to indirectly in border and it's
only at 31 degrees not so this place is
not
above 33 degrees
however
the uh the conditions the environmental
conditions at neeti valley are exactly
the same as they are in hindu kush
mountain top these are
first of all let me just explain to you
explain it to you why it's that because
uh niti valley is a cloak is a cold
desert because it lies in the rain
shadow of the himalayas so himalayas has
a rain shadow and anything that lies
under it will never get the monsoon okay
it's going to be absolutely dry so
that's one of the reasons it's
absolutely dry and you know arid
and the plants that grow there they kind
of grow in exactly the similar
conditions uh
than uh compared to the plan which are
growing at high altitude and high
latitude like in the kush so they seem
to acquire exactly the same features
as plants from hindu kush or france from
chitral
and
these places except for when you go to
niti valley there is no domestication
that has happened but you can apparently
see a short stature plant you know in
the absence of moisture it grows really
tucked to the ground to keep all the
moisture intact and you know flowers are
dense the resin is really dry leaves are
deeply sedated which is very
characteristic of plants which come from
you know high latitude and high
altitudes
so you see all those features and
uh you know we have
and that really solidifies our
understanding that yes indeed
environment is that one scale that you
know we can map everything against
and you know it will be really helpful
in understanding and classifying these
varieties but
again this does not really encapsulate
any of the hybrid varieties so then if
you want to have a different system for
for referring to hybrids i i think then
somebody would have to uh you know come
up with a way to do that there was
another classification which was done
after that because environment is not
the only factor even if it is the
biggest factor in shaping the way plants
are
the
second biggest factor is the human
beings now so we did a little uh we made
like three different types on based on
how human beings interact with the
plants and the first plants are which
are completely wild primordial they have
no contact with human beings human
beings have never domesticated them they
have never fed them and that's one and
then the second category we made is of
directly affected wild plants directly
affected by plants are something you
find in the cities these are primordial
varieties naturally occurring varieties
never been domesticated but they're
getting affected by human presence
they're getting affected by the
artificial lightning by all the
pollution that we're creating and all
the other situations you know our
cattle's graze on them and stuff like
that
so those have
you know driven some changes and once
again i wrote an article on that that is
also present on my website so if you
guys want to get a little more insight
into that i would uh you know i would
say that you should read that but
coming back to the point so uh that's
the second variety which we classified
in terms of human interaction that
varieties which are also wild but
they're affected by human beings not
domesticated by them affected by them
because of our activities because of
what happened after
industrialization industrial revolution
you know the lights became widespread
and you know things had to change and if
you
go look populations at you know punjab
what you see is that a lot of plants now
autoflower because you know they are
constantly growing under different light
patterns from artificial street lights
they have figured out a way to you know
induce flowering without
uh the light hours because
that's a much better way to reproduce in
a situation where you know light
is not natural
and then you see some of the plants you
know they they have intersex tendencies
and the autoflowering tendency you know
so a lot of different things which are
and these changes are you know more or
less driven by our activities our
uh you know involvement consciously and
consciously with those plans and then we
selected third right i'm sorry we made
third category
in terms of human interaction that was
the domesticated varieties the
traditional varieties like in malana and
uttarakhand in balochistan in pakistan
in afghanistan you know
which are actually
you know
affected by human beings but are
actually domesticated not affected in an
adverse manner but are like cared for
and you know made into something which
is more meaningful
wow what a really comprehensive rundown
that was awesome i appreciate that
i guess my next question is quite broad
so i understand if you find it a bit
hard to give specific answers to but
everyone i speak to who's really into
land races has this same sentiment where
they say i've never really tried an
indian land race you know it's one of
those ones which just doesn't get as
much attention as some of the others
what other land races might you try to
compare india to if you just wanted to
try to give someone an idea if you were
like oh it's it's kind of like a tie but
a bit different like you know how would
you describe it to someone
well that's that's a great question
thank you very much for i mean framing
it in that face so now it's really easy
to you know make comparison and answer
that
now uh
like you said i mean indian varieties i
mean you know they get like undermined
big time and i'm telling you you know
even though there's a little bit of work
involved there because again like i said
and i accept this that you know the
domestication the level of domestication
that has happened in india is nowhere uh
you know close to what has happened in
places like afghanistan or pakistan i
mean right so
rightly so people are people are right
in choosing those varieties more often
over the indians or even some of the
southeast asians
uh
for that reason but i think another
reason that's there is uh really the
cultural reason and i'm gonna i'm gonna
try to you know
i'm gonna actually try to first of all
answer the other question that i would
say uh if you go to kashmir if you go to
southern kashmir or pulvaam or srinagar
how i see those plants look very similar
to
your ethiopian plants you know the ethio
the plant that come from ethiopian
islands and they're very you know
spindly and they look absolutely the
same
to the kashmir varieties at least to me
and you know that's one of them very
sought after varieties so i mean
yeah
and the south indians like kerala and
shiloh they're like pretty synonymous to
your average you know southeast asian
varieties that comes from thailand and
other places like vietnam but now coming
back to the cultural reason that i was
going to touch upon actually that is i
think
i mean try to think about this all the
varieties which are really famous in
america or in the larger world are the
ones where america had like had a war so
they had a vietnam war and like
vietnamese seems to be very famous and
you know they constantly have you know
something going in afghanistan for so
long so afghanistan seems to be you know
of uh you know
seems to be very famous so
there are a few things we have to
understand and the first is the the
psych uh
the psycholinguistic aspect of it that
if you're gonna hear about something for
so long or it has you have certain
memories attached to it right
so you're naturally going to incline
more towards those things even though
you don't understand i mean there are a
lot of people who have never actually
had a pure vietnamese and they're going
to tell you that is the best sweet in
the world
and that tells you something about you
know
how people are getting to these
conclusion i mean i'm sure there are
some killer varieties coming from
vietnam right and some people have had
them and some people truly
know that you know the these are just
mind-boggling stuff if you run into one
of those psychedelic you know
plants that induce the psychedelic
effects it's really uncanny to feel that
way on cannabis but do we really feel
that everybody has gone through that
kind of experience i don't think so i
think
a lot of the uh you know opinion that
people have about these different
varieties is just shaped by because of
the culture the way cultures have been
and they are emotions are attached to
certain places and also because you had
a war in like vietnam or let's say
somebody had a war in like afghanistan
then
there is a bigger there is a
fat probability that that person is
going to get some seeds
back right and you can only appreciate
things that you have so if you only have
vietnamese and afghani then of course
you're going to appreciate them you
can't appreciate something you don't
have
i mean in a way in a subjective way that
you've had them right so i think it's
only a matter of time as the indian
varieties become more available to
people that people would understand that
however it requires a little bit of work
but there are so much
uh
untapped potential in these lines and
you know there is no one way to really
work with those varieties i have seen
people work with them you know in
different ways some people just try to
find very nice plant out of thousand
plants and you know reverse it and just
go from there some people like to you
know select for traits and you know
eventually homogenize them and then you
know work them work with those varieties
as true breeding varieties and some
people just take them and you know hit
it with
other hybrids and that creates fantastic
plants as well requires some sort of you
know selection work later on but
all good so i i think once these things
become more prevalent it becomes like a
norm because
i have been you know doing this for
about like five years now and and i can
tell you this that five years ago you
know when i was on facebook and i
initially come here i mean people
were not as inclined you know towards
collecting and preserving language and
i'm not trying to say that people
weren't doing that you know because it
could be viewed as that and
it's it's not because there were a lot
of people who i consider to be legends
you know
like bodies there and then you have snow
high and you know i want to name a lot
of other people but you know i couldn't
but
all these people are there they have
done all that work you know so nobody's
saying that you know it wasn't done but
it was not
widespread and i don't think that you
know people were
um how should i say this people readily
wanted to to you know get these
varieties and grow them
because the culture was just not
uh you know the cultural the flow of the
market as well because you know there is
a market which we cannot ignore right so
you have to understand the dynamics are
such that people are inclined towards
varieties you know which will finish
faster and you know
uh
which are being hyped by the media or
the social media so a lot of there's a
lot of small things you know which have
contributed so far uh you know
in indian varieties not really being you
know one of the uh one of the ones which
are sought after really when you talk
about land resistant whole but i think
at the same time the same technology
helped
people from india to connect with all
across the people on the globe and you
know really get these seeds out to them
and it's only now that people are
beginning to understand that you know no
cannabis is bad or a good cannabis it's
just you have to grow enough of it to
find that great one
yeah what an awesome sentiment i mean
just to jump off topic for one second
because you kind of brought it up
yourself there how would you describe
the effect that social media such as
instagram has had over the cannabis seen
in the community within india has it
changed it fundamentally in your opinion
um yeah it has it has a lot and i think
instagram has done
possibly a lot more than youtube
facebook and all the other you know
platforms we know of put together
because first of all you know when
instagram came in i mean it gives you a
seamless
uh you know platform to just go ahead
and you know
upload pictures and talk about them so
that's basically like just being in
being in that place and listening to
that person's story so it's really
intuitive first of all so i think that
had a very deep impact on the people in
india and apart from that
all the information that is coming from
the western world you know because now
people
in india a significant amount of people
in india knows what og is what cookies i
mean they don't know about all the you
know stories behind them and all the
controversies of course because that is
something internal to the community but
they they know what cookie that there is
something called cookies and oh man it's
the best thing and
in the most basic way i mean you know
you cannot really blame someone and i'm
not trying to say cookies is not good
it's really potent i've smoked it it's
great okay
but
i mean that's how people are getting
their information they're getting it
from
[Music]
i mean i don't want to say it but from
the lowest common denominator sort of
sources you know who just brings it down
to a point where you know more people
can understand it opposed to
a
thing being more factual i mean i think
because the social media is more
inclined towards making it more
universal to wider audiences they seem
to you know lose on a lot of content
which could have been you know a lot
more meaningful and would have imparted
uh knowledge in a sense that people
would then be curious because see you
cannot teach someone in one video or in
one audio and one picture whatever right
it has to be a relentless process
from the person itself of learning so
all you can do is you can incite the
curiosity inside that person by
telling him the truth telling him you
know how things exactly are and how
there are some things we don't
understand and how there are some things
we understand now
and
i think unless you're leading these
people into a larger pursuit for
understanding the plan then we're just
creating a similar society here you know
where
people would just fall back to some of
the well-known and respected varieties
like ogn cookies and you know they would
breed with them there are a lot of
people who are actually breeding in
india i mean they're not necessarily in
india on instagram or facebook for
obvious reasons
uh but there is a lot of work going on
and all credits to
you know social media it has really
brought nothing short of a revolution if
i may say so
wow what a what a great path for us to
go down i really want to keep going down
this road so i mean my first question is
do you see what we would refer to as
cali import within india
oh yeah a lot a lot a lot i mean more
than you would think so here's the deal
i mean first of all let me go ahead and
put things in perspective for you that
in india if you have hybrid wheat as we
call it okay in india i if you have
hybrid wheat it sells for anything
between 800 to 1000 us dollars for every
ounce
about 30 grams
okay yes sir that is that is the least
price that you will get it for and then
you know there would be instances you
might be spending like fifteen hundred
dollars or twelve hundred dollars
because it's not available in india and
there is no such quality
i'm sorry there's no such thing as
quality in india okay about when it
comes to hybrid so if you have hybrid if
it looks
different enough from the conventional
wheat and you can say it's hybrid and it
would sell for seven eight hundred nine
hundred thousand dollars man like
whatever you feel like scalping off of
other people right
yeah so um yeah i mean
they love it i mean because the prices
they get from you know people in u.s
it's just insane because i know i had
some friend you know who would
send an ounce for like a hundred bucks
like hundred dollars right
so
if imagine if you could just get
announced for a hundred dollars from us
and you could sell it for a thousand
dollars
in india i mean that's just insane right
i mean you'd be
yeah you'd be pretty rich i i would say
but at the same time i mean this is a
whole different domain you know people
who self-read i mean
so but i'm just trying to put things
into perspective that that's how people
you know view
in india and that's the price is like i
mean that that's the kind of you know
price tag that comes with it so yeah a
lot of people are
smoking it at the same time but it's not
readily available for indians here but
you we do see a lot of bags of cookies
and runs you know making it over
oh my god i love that you see runs
that's so good um so
you know i got kind of like a little
triple question here for you so the
first part is do many people grow
indoors and are there any kind of
strains which are grown locally which
people are well aware of like like the
indian blue dream type of thing is there
anything like that
yeah i i think most of the people grow
indoors because of the obvious reason
it's not being legal
and some people are blessed to be in
places like one of my friends who's
actually one of the guys who breeds
along with me he
lives in a place where he can grow it
outside and you know because there's
nobody around him but most people this
is not the case for them i mean you know
we have to stick to the indoors now to
the more interesting question you ask
the local variety so there is one such
variety but i cannot vouch whether it's
simply being you know
bred out of kerala gold or whether it's
a combination of kerala gold and hybrid
that was then selected
you know which so i don't understand
that but here's the thing there's a
strain called shillabati and you can
google it and i would recommend you
google that just write shiloh in google
i'll give you the spellings later
and you would see that you know there's
so much being written about it and it's
grown in south india
and this variety is not confined to one
place it's grown all over south india
and then it makes it over to north india
and everybody knows the name so this is
one weed
everybody seemed to know the name of
because
it would get you
higher than any other v you know and it
has a dense
structure i mean the but i mean they're
not dense like the like og or cookie
dense but you know they're relatively
dense when you compare it to
kerala or its predecessors like uh iriki
gold
but it has a great smell it has you know
probably a more intense smell and the
high is better so it it's it's really
taking india by storm but again you
can't really compare it to you know some
of the varieties that you guys have been
able to
breed i mean nowhere close to that but
sure yeah we're we're getting there
slowly i guess
yeah well that's that's still really
cool to hear so when people are doing
their little indoor grows or even
outdoors how do people tend to grow do
they do it organically in soil do they
use salts like what's the most common
style you see
in india most people uh choose to grow
organically and
it is not based on how they feel about
you know different growing methods i'll
give you an example for in america
what i see or at least i feel is that
why people choose to grow with salts or
no-till or water whatever is because of
how they feel about you know
uh if it's grown organically or if it's
grown with salts but that's not the case
in india in india i think it's driven by
something else so we don't uh at least
the younger generation is not really
sensitive about this organic non-organic
thing because
we're just in a different sphere here in
india most of the things come
organically to us
and
we are more concerned about
how can i spend the least amount of
money and still pull off a growth
and that inevitably leads you towards
organic growing
so
that's really what the motivation is
behind more people actually doing
organic and very few people actually
using uh these nutrients and i'll tell
you which people do use these nutrients
and it's very synonymous to the western
uh countries the people who are growing
for selling the wheat now there are a
lot of people who are pumping units from
their houses okay they're like growing
in the tents and like big rooms
and they feel that you know if they can
use these uh nutrients which come from
europe and america then their weed would
look as good as
theirs look in picture
but that's
i mean and you know how that translates
in the end but at least that's how those
people feel
and they tend to spend a lot of money
and the other hand you know they don't
have a concern around money because
they're actually getting paid for it
they're not growing it for the
consumption
so they have a whole different financial
situation going so they can actually
think about you know using something
uh like uh you know expensive
fertilizers which come from countries
like america europe
so there are different groups but
basically that's what the thinking is in
india
yeah of course well i mean that
certainly makes sense and especially
considering most things are organic you
could understand most people would do
that so
just to kind of stay on this general
topic
what would be your advice to someone if
they've just flown into india somewhere
is there kind of like a general strategy
you would advise for them to be able to
track down some weed or do they really
just need to like ask around like what's
the way to go about doing that
well it depends i mean where you headed
to because i mean india is such a
diverse country when it comes to culture
and people and languages and so much
more you know every 10 kilometers
language changes
you know the dresses changes so does the
culture and the way people behave and
people feel about uh certain things
which also involves cannabis so for
example if you go to uttarakhand
that is
my hometown and you
you see a very relaxed kind of demeanor
towards cannabis from other people i
mean you know you could literally go to
a tea shop and you could you know buy a
tea and after five minutes you could ask
him you know if you could like help me
score some and if he doesn't have some
you know he will like let you know where
you can get some and you know if he
doesn't then you just likely say that i
don't know or he would probably send you
to another guy who would be able to help
you
um but if you're going to let's say
south india there it's not uh i wouldn't
say it's not recommended that you know
you go ask any random person but you
rather try to connect with the youth in
south india because in south india the
younger people are
a lot more into
cannabis than i would say in north india
so there's a very good probability if
you're speaking to someone you know
who's of i was between 18 to 30 years
old that he would know the whereabouts
of the wheat but in north india
yeah pretty much you can like speak to
the people who are driving you know
gokart rickshaws or who are selling you
know cigarettes
and these are the go-to people i mean
you know you you go
the best place you can go to is go to
a guy who's you know driving that gokart
rickshaw kind of thing you know the
three-wheeler
i don't know what you guys call that
over there
yeah rickshaw right so those people are
really famous and even so much that you
know when our parents had to scold us
for like or have to tell us that weed is
bad they would say that hey this is the
drug of those rickshawers you know so
you smoke it and you're like yeah you
like them
so i mean
i mean it's so engraved in the culture
that
you know it becomes something
it becomes something of an expression to
scare kids so you have to i mean
i mean we generalize a lot i mean it's
really bad but
no no no i totally understand that so i
mean
if we just kind of move on to kind of
the physical landscape a little bit more
what's the soil like to growing because
you mentioned that people tend to grow
organically is the soil well suited in
european is it rich in nutrients fairly
depleted how do people work with it
okay now soil is a very important aspect
for growing plants as we all know but i
think there is a vast difference between
how things are happening in i'm not
going to talk about europe because not
really aware of that but in terms of
america and india i could draw like this
little uh
comparison that in america i see a lot
of people buy soils and
for someone in india that is completely
insane i mean you know nobody would give
money for soil i mean
it's not in a way insulting other people
but you have to understand from our
culture we don't pay for soil like we
pay for food
we don't pay for soil ever okay it's
free and
what another reason behind that is
because most of the soil is fertile here
because
what is northern india by the way
northern india used to be a big flood
plain for all these different rivers i
mean there are only five rivers flowing
from punjab itself that used to at least
and
all of the soil that is here is actually
your alluvial deposits
and you know the minerals you know which
the rivers have
you know flown down into these planes
from from the mountainous regions so the
soil is really good it's alluvial soil
mostly like it has a clay loom like
texture you know some places it's more
yellowish you go to other places it's a
little bit dark but soil is really good
and
you know the ph is uh right around like
seven
i think like seven around like seven
seven point two it just hovers around
that so it's perfect for canvas i mean
and even you know if there are some
varieties you know which do not thrive
in like higher ph
because you're using the natural soil
you have the indigenous microbes i mean
they're just going to you know
equalize that effect i mean they're
going to count counteract that effect
but at the same time you know we have to
be very careful uh when using you know
uh things like micro razor because we're
using indigenous soil so there's already
a species of that you know which is
present and you know sometimes people
would buy micro razor from outside of
india and then you would have two
different species competing and you know
it could lead to other problems but yeah
overall we mostly have this you know
clay loam
and alluvial deposits you know
vast deposits of alluvial soil and you
know the cow dung and
is just free you can get it from
anywhere
so uh
in india i mean people really don't have
that kind of like soil buying culture or
like neutron buying culture i mean it's
certainly coming to india i'm not going
to say that amazon is not now selling
amazon is selling
soil uh but i don't think a lot of
people are buying it as of now but the
culture is due for a change things are
going to change you know because
of course the economy is also getting
stronger i mean apart from this
coronavirus thing that just happened now
apart from that things were going good
for india and i think eventually because
people are gonna you know uh gonna be
making more money and they would be you
know
more resourceful they will eventually be
able to move on to the ideas like hey
let's try to invest in soil let's try to
buy soil and see if that makes a
difference and i think it would make a
difference because you know
while the clay and the loam is great
but i i just feel there are certain
properties you know
that that could be changed like it's not
very loose you know it's not very
it's very compact so
certain properties like that but overall
the soil works fantastically and this is
the i mean north india is the mecca of
cannabis right so
all of these varieties has been
naturally growing here so i could say
very confidently that the soil that's in
northern india at least in northern
india or northwest himalayas is very
suited for growing cannabis and that's
why most people just go ahead you know
dig some soil and they're good to go
yeah well i mean it makes total sense
doesn't it you raise an interesting
point though i would really be
interested to see
what some of these cultivars would end
up looking like around harvest time if
they were put in some kind of like
american no-till soil because i remember
my first
run with that sort of
soil composition and it was quite
different to what i was using before and
it was it was a very different outcome
for the same clones but to get back on
topic for the people who are just using
the soil around them that's just free do
they try to supplement it with like
basic you know like like basic compost
they make or anything or is it really
just planted in the soil water only and
what you get is what you get
people do make compost because compost
making has been an integral part of
indian culture so it's something that
people are readily aware of so i've seen
a lot of people use uh you know
compost they have compost bins or they
have a designated place or a
where they you know stockpile all the
leaves and you know everything
so yeah that happens but again i mean
the nutrient part is people are not big
on nutrients like buying nutrients just
like buying soil but like i said if
something someone is running a
commercial setup you know he's able to
sell it for a fortune then of course
they can afford it and they they are
doing that because uh they don't want to
leave any stone unturned in making their
wheat the best
in the market right and probably make
more money off it but at the same time
they can afford it because they have
they're getting some returns out of that
and at the same time there are other
people you know
who's not interested in doing that
because at the end the
plant grows amazing in that soil without
any inputs but you see a lot of cow dung
being used which is just you know
very inherent to in people in india
so yeah i mean we use cow dung for a lot
of other things i mean we you we you
know like dry it up and you know smoke
it i mean like burn it up
so it takes care of the mosquitoes
because we you know we have a big
mosquito problem in india as you know
so
uh it's always around us so we it's only
a matter of for us it's only a matter of
time
a matter of looking around and you know
finding those things and fertilizer and
everything is
just all around us and because the
kettles are also you know going around
everywhere so they're taking [__] and
it's getting mixed in the soil so the
soil seems to be really good
overall so people are not really
inclined towards using nutrients some
people do use them but it's a negligible
portion of the
uh you know overall community
yeah of course really really good answer
to that one so
the indian climate itself you know i
know that it can get quite hot and also
quite cold
how do you feel that impacts things and
for how many months of the year can you
grow in say north india for example
okay in north india i mean if you are at
a fairly lower altitude
like i am right now i'm at near shivalik
right now at i think around 700 meters
okay so here it it does not snow at all
but it gets really cold in the winters
but not as cool that you cannot grow the
cannabis plants right so you can go
12 year i'm sorry 12 months
and you can grow pretty much around the
year but there is a significant change
in the light duration it's not like
equator that you have
a 12 hour day all around the year so
because of that reason then you would
have to supplement light or you would
have to you know veg your plants inside
if you're going to do that towards the
end of the season let's see if i decide
to you know grow my plants in october
after just going through my first cycle
then i would have to give them some
vegetative time indoors or have to
really supplement some light outdoors in
my balcony or whatever
to make sure that you know they stay in
vegetative state for a significant
amount of time before they hit the
flowering so then you can you know
eventually have something
on the plant
so that's one thing i mean uh
that 12
months are available but then you have
to look at the light the light is not
really in your favor all the time
right
another thing that happens around here
in north india is that what you see
these feral varieties which are growing
in the flatlands especially punjab
haryana new delhi surroundings
these plants grow all around the year
like you know like you would see in some
of the equators that means
um in springtime some of the plants
would come up okay and they would go on
to
they would certainly go into flowering
because the light is still less than you
know is still relatively less but they
would just kind of stretch and not
really start to flower because these are
long flowering varieties and they tend
to have a stretch before they really
start to flower
so
uh those varieties will you know stretch
and then they would again go into
vegetative state as the summer would hit
around like end of april and may
and then they would again go into
flowers sometime in you know around
august then and they would finish some
around like november ending but as soon
as the november end comes and those
seeds you know fall down on the ground i
mean they don't stay dormant like some
of the places like kashmir where because
in kashmir what happens is once the seed
fall down there's snowfall on them so
those plants have evolved different
features in them like some of the plants
in colder places like kashmir in higher
altitudes where the snowfall happens for
like three to four months they have
developed features
uh like seed dormancy which can be
chemically or physically induced like
physically and used in a way that it
could have a very thick seed coat
you know that will take a very long
while to wither and eventually it'll
take the time
till the snow is off and it would
ultimately you know pop out in spring
so one is that and then there is
chemical dormancy you know i think that
is caused because of the abscisic acid
in the seed and really the only way to
you know break that is you have to take
those seeds and put it in the
refrigerator and you know mimic what
would happen in what would have happened
in the nature like it would have
been under the snow so you keep it like
a couple of months under in the
refrigerator and then you try to pop
them and and they pop you know so
uh that doesn't really happen in uh here
northern india because here you have the
varieties they fall down on the ground
and
next week they they're out because you
know it's not snowing it's not that cold
that they're gonna die so you just have
this perpetually seedlings coming up and
plants going into flower at different
stages and reverting to vegetative
states so
it's a very complex picture i mean you
have to live here and you have to go out
and you know little notebook every day
and just look around you and it's not
that hard to understand but it's complex
and if somebody's going to come here for
like a day or two from a different
country i think it's going to be very
difficult for him to really you know
appreciate all those
little things yeah certainly there's a
huge layer of complexity to it all with
everything going on
i'd love to know though you've you've
spoken about how there's all these
different areas geographically with
india you know we've got like the high
altitudes the lower some kind of in the
middle and even deserts
out of all of them
what produces the nicest end product in
your experience
okay the well if you're going to talk
about the nicest end product i mean uh
there could be a few ways of looking at
it so some people would say a bigger bud
or some people would say more potent
resin right
so um
i'm going to talk in
in different aspects okay like i'm gonna
say that
this
region or this place would produce the
best of this certain characteristic okay
so first if we if we begin with cold
desert region a cold desert is basically
what it's extremely cold place and you
know that it doesn't rain at all nothing
at all i mean maybe once or twice a year
and all you see is just
rock withering away
in a very arid desolate you know region
so you have some plants growing in those
regions so number one i'm gonna put
those plants right up there for their
hardiness and for their survival skills
so if you're going to you know if you're
going to look for a variety you know
that has
the ability to survive in least amount
of water and in marginal conditions
as they are in you know cold desert then
that would be you know
uh the number one for me okay but then
let's talk about in terms of resin
production okay and when we say resin
production i'm talking about in how
dense the resin coated uh coating is
okay and whether it's confined only to
the floral bracts or is it also moving
on to the leaves and to the stems and
the patios okay because some varieties
do that and once again if you go to uh
cold desert regions like niti valley you
know close to uh
enda tibetan border intermole
those plants tend to have a very dense
uh you know coverage of resin
surprisingly and
the trichomes are big as well even
though the plants are really feeble and
small they have absolutely zero
you know vigor to them and they barely
look like cannabis plants by the way but
you would find plants which have this
amazing and parallel amount of resin on
them and similar is the case with
kashmir i mean the places so basically
what i'm trying to say here is that if
you go to the colder places and more
drier places places like hindu places
like chitral in pakistan places like uh
you know niti valley and you're going to
encounter uh you know populations which
have a dense resin coating and you know
the resin is abundant now that could be
because these places are higher up on
the latitude higher up on the globe and
you know also have altitudes so they may
be exposed to you know a more intense
ultraviolet radiation so we don't
understand you know what basically
trichomes are doing or what all they're
doing at least so if uh it is to deflect
you know uv radiation then certainly it
makes sense you know why those varieties
would have bigger trichomes and a more
dense coverage even on the
non-reproductive parts like leaves and
you know
patios of the plant
but if you're going to talk about the
girth if you're going to talk about the
produce
well it's absolutely zero in these
places you go to kashmir and you go to
places like niti valley the cold desert
places and again the cold is doing
something here the cold is somewhat like
a factor that is directly influencing
you know these changes that
while the resin coating is going to be
absolutely maddening on the plant the
plant is not the plant itself is not
going to produce anything
you you may even see plants that has no
bud at all i mean there's a couple of
floral bracts here and there and there's
leaves coming out of them but they're
just completely smothered with resin
so that's what you see so
they're not fully complete they have
certain aspects you know which are
really desirable to us as if we talk in
terms of like commercial production
but they don't have all of them they
just seem to have like one or two okay
so then you
you could move to the other extreme and
the other extreme is the equatorials
when you go to the equatorials what do
you see equatorial regions i'm sorry
what you see is that
the plants
produce huge buds huge yields i mean you
know it's hard to find a plant that is
not yielding a lot
but when you get closer and you try to
look at the resin
production
it's
not even closed not even close to you
know what you have seen in places like
cold desert or
uh in places like kashmir you know not
even close it's not dense it's sparsely
scattered and it's
very hard it's very hardly you see that
on you know patios or on the
leaf surface it's mostly confined to the
reproductive part
and again we don't understand you know
what all things you know trichomes do so
we can't really say what's driving that
but at least that's what we see and at
least we can you know relate it to
um you know the environment because
those results
be because those observations kind of
hold up even if you go to different
places with different cultures so we
know that it's not because of the
domestication we understand that
this is something which is inherent to
these varieties or inherent to
this terroir that they are growing in
and they've been growing in for so long
and so
then what's left what's left is in
between your highlands your uh the
places which are you know very close to
uh tropic of cancer around like 28 26 29
degrees 30 31 degrees of north
and they also seem to have a little bit
of highland so you know because the
temperature is cold but at the same time
it's not extremely cold so what do you
get is a beautiful mix of both of those
words you you get good resin content i
would say at least decent resin content
and and you can find plants which more
than often would produce uh you know
good yields so then it only becomes a
matter of you know looking for the right
plant i mean and it's growing enough to
run into a plant that you can say key i
mean you could say that yeah this is
this is it this is what i uh you know
what is good so
um if somebody is going to find that
ideal plan then either he would have to
take both of the extremes and you know
cross them and just go from there
or he would just have to look for these
intermediate varieties from highlands of
which which grow around the tropic of
cancer and you know have seemed to have
best of both worlds to some extent
yeah what a really awesomely detailed
explanation i think our viewers will
probably have to listen to that one a
few times to pick out all the awesome
bits of info there
[Music]
[Applause]
so there you have it guys part one of
two done what do you think
just buckets of information irizing
scholar what can i say i hope you guys
are getting ready for part two
as always huge shout out to ct now best
c bank in the game
you know they got you covered hit em up
you want that fire it's the only place
to go
pop it biological systems
hit them up they got their beneficials
they got the microbial powders
they've got your artificial feeds
they've got everything you need to keep
that garden pumping happy and healthy
[Music]
big big big thank you to our patreon
supporters everyone in the patreon gang
i appreciate you guys so much hope
you're enjoying listening to this early
and we'll see you for part two guys i'll
see you there
[Music]
so
you