foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
this episode as always we're grateful
for our amazing sponsors CT now number
one seed bank in the game guarantee on
satisfaction not just germination no
reason to go anywhere else why would ya
on top of that all the best breeders in
the game your number one stop go hit
them up likewise coppet biological
systems best in the business for all
beneficial bugs predators and your feeds
and microbial solutions to keep your
garden happy healthy and pump it along
to give you the best Harvest possible
get on top of it now so that your garden
produces the most Primo Harvest you've
ever had
also a huge shout out to the patreon
gang as always helping support the show
lifeblood and all we are so so grateful
hope you enjoy Early Access to this
episode and if you want to help support
to make episodes happen and get yourself
Early Access to some future episodes and
exclusive content go check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
hope you guys are ready for an epic part
two of our chat with chimera
yourself
let's get into it
yeah it's it's pretty wild
just to jump back to some of the stuff
about David Sam because we we have had
over the years a plethora of pretty
interesting questions asked about him
which we've never really been able to
have answered I guess one of the ones I
was personally interested in is that
a lot of the stories around the strains
that have come out through David have
sometimes portrayed him as not really
the active breeder but more of like a
steward and in that regard I mean like
if you look at skunk there was often a
lot of credit given to Sacred seed and
if you look at Haze you know obviously
his neighbors kind of developed that one
where do you see him in the picture of
like do you view him as the creator of
those strains or more of just someone
who brought them to the world
no he bred skunk one from scratch
anybody that says different just doesn't
know like Dave assembled that from
scratch
um Hayes you're right it was the these
two dudes that were known as the Hayes
Brothers
um
he tried to introduce me to them
actually one time in California and
there's three circumstances of the
meeting it didn't work out but
um they created the haze
um Mel Frank created or collected The
Afghani one and I think he also gave him
the turbine poison which came from Ed
Rosenthal which Ed Rosenthal actually
didn't collect in South Africa which is
the common belief of the story Ed got
them out of some flowers at a coffee
shop
um so that's the truth about where
Jordan poison came from it was out of
seeds at a coffee shop
um the California Orange David also
brought that one to California or sorry
to Holland but he collected that one
from a grower at a Harvest Festival
um and he you know Dave is is a member
of the you know the Seed Savers Club of
America like he is an insane collector
of plant seeds not just cannabis
and what he the story he told me is that
he met this grower up at a Harvest
Festival he had the California Orange
back then seeds there was no seed
business and they just didn't exist and
but because David was an insane
collector he said hey do you mind if I
get some of those seeds and can I work
with them can I breathe them out and
and play with them and the guy gave them
to him freely and he brought all those
things over to
um to Holland right so that's how the
whole Sam skunk band thing kind of
started over in Holland but everybody I
mean you look at Dutch Passion Scentsy
all their seed catalogs I mean it's
pretty clear that David was the person
that brought all those things so some of
them he created then some of them he
just ushered in
um
yeah and he made a lot of hybrids I mean
I helped him catalog his entire seed
collection which is
to my knowledge the largest cannabis
term plasm collection on the planet like
I don't know anybody that has a larger
one
and it's pretty impressive there's a lot
of stuff in there that the world doesn't
even know about
um just weird land races and weird
plants you know just with strange traits
that people don't even think about
and uh it's all it's all there
but yeah I I give credit all the David
for that you know and he's he's more
than willing to you know he'll he'll
tell you straight up you know these ones
came from from Mel Frank these ones came
from so it's the Hayes Brothers they
hate I mean Hayes isn't even you know
everybody says oh hey is as if it's one
thing Hayes isn't one thing it's many
things it's a series of plants that were
created over multiple Generations being
hybridized with one another and every
year they would add in a new cross into
the mix right so Hayes is really a
family of siblings and half siblings and
cousins
um
and there's many different types of the
haze there's the Purple Haze you know
obviously the Purple Haze there's all
these red and green hazes there's one
that was called Christmas haze there was
New Year's Haze right they were super
long flowering ones that weren't ready
until the new year
um
and they all are different variations of
hybrids between Mexican Thai
South Indian and a little bit of Afghani
at times
wow I mean so many different Avenues
again to go into the the most pertinent
question to me is did you ever get to
try what some might call the real Haze
even though you just explained there is
no one real Haze but you know often
people reminisce about Hayes but can't
exactly vouch that they've been able to
try verified Real Deal have you and what
was your experience if so yeah I've
tried a bunch of different things from
being over there you know and usually
they're hybrids of plants that were
David shared with people that were over
there I mean you know everybody's heard
of Neville's Hayes those were those were
David's non-preferred Haze plants that
he gave to Neville with the promise that
devil wouldn't reproduce them pure
right he said he said take these things
and make hybrids of them fine but please
just don't make them pure because I'm
selling them pure
and uh as people are wanting to do they
don't like to they don't like to do that
they'll tell you anything to get it in
their hands and then once they've got it
it's a whole different thing when they
can make money off of it
um but yeah they're it's just a family
of plants and really what we know now is
the hazes are mostly like you know the
Amnesia Haze that's really what you find
over in Holland
those are terpenolene plants they're
terpineline dominant plants so it's kind
of in the same family as train wreck
um or
I think the DNA guys sell it as what do
they call it like citrus skunk or lemon
skunk it's Lemon Skunk that's what it is
but Lemon Skunk actually everything so
it's high in limonene it's not it's high
interpanylene
right interpanylene to some people has a
little bit of a fresh lemon scent even
though it's to me it's more Piney
um so there's those and then there's the
the pinene plants which are a little
more rare and the limousine pining
plants as well and they all kind of fall
into that hazy family like where again
what I call equatorials right
yeah
that's that's amazing I mean you kind of
just quickly alluded to Neville in the
mix there
I've always been interested by the fact
that he was Don the moniker of like the
king of hazes despite the fact he got
them from um David do you feel like that
was sort of like a misnomer the fact he
got that title and as a bit of a
follow-up do you feel like nl5 Haze is
like a really good poster child for
Hayes because I think a lot of people
suggest that you know like the NL tames
the Hayes to the point where it's like
you can do it indoors do you feel like
there was actually a lot better but it
just you know it didn't really see the
light of day sort of thing
it made it more accessible for people to
grow but I wouldn't call the nl5 haze
like on its own Haze if you inbred it
you could pull out haze-like plants from
it but the nl5 haze is way too big for a
haze it's just got way too much biomass
and that's the influence of the
afghanica in there
um
so yeah it's the hazes are very like I
said they're very equatorial they're
they're very long flowering they're very
thin leaves they're very low yield
um small resin glands they don't have a
ton of scent like they'd probably fail
the one percent chirp test at least the
old ones were they they'd need to be
improved
um
but they did have a nice headspace right
they did provide that nice clear kind of
effect and and you know what people call
the ceiling where you could or ceiling
lists where you can keep consuming them
and getting higher and higher
I think again it's like because they
weren't 25 THC and you could smoke them
without burning out
right THC is by it's got a biphasic
effect so at small doses it's
invigorating but at large doses it makes
you lethargic and kind of feel
like I don't know I don't know if
there's a better word for it than thud
you know it just kind of like it just
kind of like takes it out of you
and if you've ever done large doses of
Edibles I mean it's kind of a similar
feeling
um and then we see that not only in
humans but also in rats you know if you
look at the Neuroscience of cannabinoids
and administration
at a certain point in time people you
know you get energetic
on a curve and you get to a point where
it plateaus and then the more you
consume that you're actually going down
not getting up anymore
so and I mean how do you feel the
comparison between Netherlands and
diabetes given that I think a lot of the
time and I'm probably guilty of this
myself people hold Neville in a bit
higher regard or maybe feel he maybe
contributed more do you feel like that's
maybe inaccurate and what's your
thoughts on Neville in general
oh can I say don't speak ill of the Dead
sure
yeah Neville is a controversial person
in the Cannabis world let's put it that
way
and
he took some risks that David wouldn't
risk I mean you remember David's
American Neville's Australian
and so when Dave produce moved to
Holland
you know he knew that the the United
States was a machine right and that they
were all these systems in the United
States that were part of the machine and
that if you wanted to stick
if you want if you wanted to throw a
stick in the wrenches of the operation
of the American machine that they're
they're going to come for you
and so David never did any business and
once he left he didn't he didn't he
wasn't involved in in doing business in
the states Neville did
right Neville set up someone in the
states and I was actually doing
distribution I don't mind saying this
now that he's passed but you know he he
actually set up seeds they were shipping
them over from Holland and I think soup
containers
labeled Soup cans and they had someone
that was actually Distributing so the
money would come from hot from the
states that would collect the money and
then they'd get the seeds would be
shipped back out of the states
um and that's why the the DEA went after
Neville because something happened and
the plot became known and they went for
him
um
he was a smart guy like I I actually
didn't know him too well personally
um I tried to interact with a couple of
times and he was
uh let's say he wasn't receptive to it
um
but same with you know same with Scott
like I I have a really good relationship
with Scott I got a lot of respect for
the work that Scott has done Shanti Baba
I mean
um for Mr Nice Seed Company
but
for some reason people people want to be
divisive in the Cannabis community so
this like they kind of put themselves
either in the the Scott camp or the
Neville camp or the David camp and if
you're in one Camp then you can't be
friends with everybody else and I'm not
like that like I you know I I try to be
friends with everybody in the space
because it's like they're all they've
all got interesting histories and
they've all got lessons to teach
and I just want to understand the plant
from their perspective because I mean
there are Elders right
um
and so George Cervantes actually
introduced me to to Scott
and I think Scott was kind of
apprehensive of me at first because he
was like oh you're that Chimera guy and
you know you're in the other camp and
you know we got past that pretty quick
he he came to realize that I you know
I wasn't any threat to him I wasn't I
Had No Malice towards him at all in fact
I respected him for the works that he
would be done and we we developed kind
of a mutual respect thing but he had
really been poisoned by Neville right
because Neville had said it had told him
all these awful stories about about
David this weren't true
um
and he's and he used to tell me oh yeah
but he works for the D.A and he doesn't
I was like Scott dude that's just not
that's not the way it is man like
you know so I think that you know and
and truthfully you know you probably
know Mr Nice Seed company which at one
point in time was Neville Scott that
that kind of went you know Neville
towards the end he wasn't involved with
it anymore
right and they they had parted ways a
bit too because well just because of
stuff that I'm not going to get into but
I think that the internet with the
internet especially you know the
Cannabis Community for a period of time
existed only on the internet right we
couldn't interact with each other
um
one-to-one on person and the internet
the internet and overgrow and all these
other
websites that we used to use you know
cannabis world all that kind of stuff
they provided an opportunity for people
to reach out and connect with each other
in a way
that we couldn't do before I mean it
just those Technologies didn't exist and
it was a really great thing for that but
the really bad thing about it
was that there's just there's become all
this nonsense stories that people have
made and promulgated I mean you can go
to Wikipedia and read about a whole
bunch of nonsense about David and you
know on the Wikipedia stuff like it's
somehow fact and it's just not
[Music]
um and for whatever reason
those things have really resonated in
the Cannabis Community right because
again we're so as a whole we're so
anti-science we're so anti-big Pharma
we're against the man right because
again we've been kicked in the teeth by
the police and the justice system for 50
60 years so it's natural that we have
all those those fears but I think in on
the internet forums they really Fester
into this like psychotic
[Music]
untrusting place of like really what
just becomes mostly lies you know I read
stuff on the internet
that I know for a fact didn't go down
that way because I was there
right but I'm reading it on the internet
as if it's fact by some guy posting it
as if it's like gospel from God's mouth
um so in a way while the internet really
helped us get the seeds out and and
spread the message and teach people how
to grow and even teaching people how to
breed and and some more advanced stuff
about cannabis
there's been a lot of negativity that's
come out of it that's that's you know I
think frustrates I know it frustrates a
lot of the old-timers and myself as
included
and it gets to the point where it's just
like you don't even want to do it
anymore like you don't want to post and
share the information because all you're
met with is people telling you that
you're a liar and that you work with a
DEA or that you know it's just all this
nonsense and it's it's really it's kind
of a shame
because it's done a disservice to the
history of cannabis right
um
and so I've I've always when I've
been over in Europe and I've tried to
meet all these different folks in the
industry I really just want to meet them
all and understand but what their
perspectives are for cannabis because
I'm interested in the history like I
guess kind of like we're doing with this
talk now but I'm interested in the
history and the reasons why people were
doing it and the motivations and how
they got their start
and
there's been in the Cannabis industry a
lot of smoke and mirrors
um and I really hope that that goes away
and now we're going to see the next
generation of people that are they're
able to be open and honest they're able
to show their work they're able to teach
the Next Generation how to do it better
and so I really do feel like quite
hopeful for cannabis and positive for
cannabis
um in the next 20 years
and I really look forward to you know I
was talking to a friend from England the
other day and Guernsey one of the little
islands off the necessity or Southern
whatever it's called the
what is it the Bay of uh Bay of Biscay
they're all
you know they're talking about
legalizing a full adult use model and
just off the coast of England they're a
British colony
or protectorate or whatever it is but
I'd love to see them legalize I'd love
to see Australia and you know New
Zealand legalize really actually the
whole Commonwealth just legalized
straight off the bat that would be a
nice Quick Start
and then the rest of the the world will
eventually catch on and I think that
that's going to be
great for so many reasons it'll probably
lessen the impact that alcohol the
negative impacts that alcohol have on
society
um and there's just so many benefits
that can come with it you know you know
all about the medical aspects and
everything I mean I'm not going to sit
here and preach to the converted but
it's you know cannabis can do a lot of
benefit for society
um
you know we we've seen this with the you
know the British soccer hooligans that
used to go you know they'd go to
different countries and there'd always
be these brawls and fights with
everybody getting drunk and when they'd
play Amsterdam or they'd play Holland
and Amsterdam that wouldn't happen
because everybody was stoned you know
um so there's a lot of good that can
come from Cannabis and Society is using
cannabis and it would be great to see a
lot of Neville's old work being grown
down in Australia I mean Australia's Got
a great climate for these equatorial
plants
um and it's a shame that it's you know
they're still throwing people in jail
there it's nuts
yeah definitely definitely and many
points resonating with what you just
said but I I feel like it is such a
shame that we do still have this kind of
culture in the scene of like being
attached to one camp and you can't just
kind of
try to be okay with everyone you know
because as you've alluded to that's
through being able to kind of float in
between the rift so to speak I feel like
that's how the truth can come out and
you can avoid these sort of issues like
you mentioned with Scott thinking that
Dave was a part of the DEA and whatnot
and it's kind of sad that the three
arguably the three big pillars in terms
of like Scott Neville and Dave weren't
able to kind of keep it all together
because it's kind of this fragmentation
sort of thing you alluded to but just to
to jump back to day for one moment
something which has been asked probably
more so than any other question about
him which I would love to get your
perspective on is did he ever talk to
you about his thoughts and whether he
intentionally ever changed skunk from
what people would say was like the
stinky early version to the sweet and
like what's your overall perspective on
that
yeah he loved the Swede I mean that's
just what he that's that was the end of
the spectrum the first few Generations
it had some stanky plants in there
um but those weren't the ones that he
preferred and so like all breeders do
they select towards the type that they
like
um gotta keep in mind the context of the
years too that was going on like late
70s early 80s we're gonna call it mid to
late 70s early 80s
um skunk weed back then man you go to
jail
right it's like you're stinking out the
whole neighborhood and
so they would he selected away from that
and that was just part of his choice
because he liked the resins from the
other these other plants better right
they made of they made what he
considered a finer hash David wasn't
David you know since many many many
years ago is not a cannabis flower
consumer he's a he's a passion
concentrate consumer and he used to have
the finest hash in the world right
everybody called the 50 and it was like
50 plus THC it would turn to liquid as
soon as you put a flame to it it was the
first dabble you know concentrate
extract that I'd ever seen that before
dabs were even a thing and and he had
that that level of quality
um
so again he selected the plants that he
liked for that purpose and that's what
he did right so that's why skunk is the
way it is everybody talks about the
Terps and skunk it's actually not a
terpene it's so there's there's there's
rare there's rare volatiles that the
plant produce that the plant produces
that have to do with smell or they
influence smell
and so terpenes everybody thinks that
terpenes is the whole story but they're
actually not they're they're one of the
major factors in the scent but there are
a few other chemicals that when they get
mixed in with these terpenes they
they're kind of like I call them scent
or flavor modifiers right and they
actually use some of these compounds
um in the perfume industry to change the
flavors of or sorry to change the sense
of different perfumes in the in the
community at the moment there's this
really kind of popular drive to find the
road kill skunk you know my thoughts are
that it's most likely gone and touching
on a point you just made some of the
smells around this sort of quote
roadkill skunk I've got to believe that
they're kind of more thile based you
know sulfur-based compounds and maybe
not even technically falling under this
strict definition of a terpene do you
think that's the case or do you think
that the other point of view might have
some Credence to it where it's that
there's a bit of like rose shade glasses
and maybe it wasn't really like a skunk
dead down the road sort of thing where
do you sit on that one
well I'll tell you a story that might
tell you I've got a plant that is very
very roadkill-like I've got a few of
them actually but one of them is a
terpineline dominant plant so it's
actually of the same flavor profile or
that what we call the flavor class so
flavor class is like they have a general
terpene profile Arrangement that is kind
of a fingerprint
and then there's like all these
different plants that kind of fall into
that grouping and so this particular
plant is a is a terpineline plant and so
up close and when you're it's right in
your nose it's got that Lemon Skunk kind
of like
um we have a product here called Mr
Clean Pine I don't know if you have that
in Australia but um it's a it's a
concentrated liquid cleaner that you add
to water to wash the floors and that's
got this real that's a terpenolene kind
of smell to it
but when you so when you have the
flowers and they're up close and you're
breaking it up that's what you smell but
I remember harvesting a couple of
um a couple of rooms of this stuff and I
I was moving it across town and my bet
in in my knapsack and there was
something going on with my car at the
time and I was like decided I was going
to get on the bus and go across town
with these with these these bags of dope
in my knapsack all sealed up really well
and I got on the front of the bus and
walked to the back you know halfway to
the back of the bus essentially got to
the backs of the doors and I remember
someone just saying do you smell that it
reeks like a skunk
and uh and I just promptly got off the
bus and walked home across town rather
than taking the bus
um but the point of the story is that
the smell that you smell when it's right
up close is different than the smell
that you smell when it's in the bag and
yeah you'd come into a room and you'd
open it up and it would be like it
smells like a skunk and it does have a
reminiscent nose of a skunk but when you
actually get it out and you grind it up
it doesn't right it's actually different
and now I I know there's going to be 100
people online telling me that I have no
idea what I'm talking about and that
know the stuff that they had it was a
skunk right down to the end of the joint
and all that kind of stuff fine maybe it
was maybe it was just higher in these
compounds but I think that
um you know I I know for a fact in
having had access to these chemicals to
make terpene standards and things when
the when you have a molecule at one drop
versus you know one one like for example
say you've got one microliter of a
substance and you put it on a piece of
paper
and you take the same substance and you
put 10 times as much on a different
piece of paper they smell different same
substance
right so there's something to do with
like
at like maybe like with that with THC
and the by phasic response that we also
have these responses in our nose right
that like you know one molecule of a of
a smelly compound is enough to trigger a
certain effect in your nose and more it
might elicit a different response again
knowing that each of us have different
neurochemistry and smell is also based
on neurochemistry right it's just a
chemical signal that's being transferred
to your brain
and uh
so yeah I think it's it's it's partly
something to do with that and I don't
know what the true answer is but there's
something in that whole thing and then
there's always something to
you know nostalgia
right the weed that you had that one
time when you were with your best friend
at the lake
it's like those things all influence
your perception of the experience
right yeah hugely hugely
and looking back on it it's pretty easy
to say no no that was skunk Weed Man I
mean it smelled like a skunk but I bet
you if you were able to transport
someone back in time and make them smile
the same thing they wouldn't smell the
same thing again like you know I don't
know if you're interested if you like
beer or anything but I know when I was a
kid period to me it used to smell like
skunk it doesn't smell like skunk to me
now right it's because that I've learned
to appreciate the different notes that
exist within the context and it's the
same with weed right like part of
part of smelling things is like knowing
how to break apart the effect because
again you're not smelling one chemical
you're smelling a symphony of chemicals
right and the total of those it like a
symphony of of musical notes like the
totality of the orchestra
is what makes the sound you're not
listening to the flute right or or the
oboe for example right it's the totality
of the whole thing together that you
hear and and being able to train your
ear you know in the context of a
symphony being able to train your ear to
pick out the oboe or the the bass guitar
or whatever it is like that takes a
little bit of a skill and and training
in time and it's the same thing with the
with your nose and cannabis like when we
smell cannabis we're smelling this
Orchestra of molecules that come
together that come together to create
what we perceive as an experience right
but
when you when you have the individual
chemicals at your disposal and you can
smell limonene on its own or osamine on
its own or beta carry offline or I can
list you know another any one of the the
really 30 major Terps that are that are
in cannabis
then we have
a language that we can agree on like for
example you know if we're sitting in a
park and we look up the sky you and I
can both point at the sky and say okay
that's blue do we agree yeah that's blue
the clouds are white the leaves on the
grass or the leaves you know in the
grass or on the trees are green that
flower is yellow right and we can have
we can have a shared experience because
we're both looking at the same thing and
then we're applying a label to that
thing that we're looking at right
we don't have that ability with terpenes
or with with scents without having the
individual chemicals and that's why
people say stuff like oh it smells
incense here it smells like roses or it
smells like you know X Y or Zed right
the rose actually smells like geraniol
right or or the lavender smells like
linole but we don't know what those
individual components smell like so it's
hard for us to have that consensus where
we point to one thing and say this is
this and only when you actually get the
individual terpenes or the individual
notes on their own can you then
we can then both share the same vial and
smell it you know in a socially
distancing manner we can both share it
and say okay this is linolol this is
limonene
you know this is osamine or whatever
terpene you want to choose
you know people are always blown away
when I show them pure limousine they're
like it doesn't smell like lemons you're
right no it doesn't smell like lemons it
smells like orange peels yes but
everybody assumes it smells like lemons
right yeah yeah I got a bottle of
limonene in my fridge and I I do the
same little thing to people
yeah it's great because then it and
what's that that's about is building a
consensus of the words that we use to
describe these things right rather than
trying to describe them by referring to
some other thing
right which again is it's on itself like
it was like oh it smells like roses well
roses are also a symphony of smell right
they're a symphony of notes that make up
the overall scent that we perceive as
one thing
right and so until you have the ability
to learn the individual components of
that smell it's really hard to
communicate on things because we just we
don't have a Common Language like that
like we do for colors
yeah of course of course I think yeah
just a point you touched on which I I
really struggle to try to get through to
people at times is how like chemicals at
different concentrations have different
smells and like I try to make it simple
to understand by talking about like um
like ozone you know the smell after rain
Patrol
um like it's sweet in low concentrations
but if you get a big jar of ozone it's
it's it's it smells horrible
um yeah but yeah I guess it is a bit of
a concept to wrap your head around
um I'd love to jump into some more kind
of technical breeding stuff at this
point because I think that's an area
you're going to be able to provide a
really great amount of insight into
something I've always wondered about is
I think it might have been a forum post
but somewhere along the line Dave wrote
an article about how he reversed some
males and got female seeds out of got
seeds out of it and 25 of those seeds
were females would you ever consider
doing this sort of project effect if say
you only had one male and you wanted to
like lie and breed it out and get some
females out of it or do you think it's
just too much of an effort
uh no it's not it's not too much of an
effort it's actually not that hard to do
um it's no harder than or no different
really than making feminized seeds with
STS
um
there's some there's some challenges in
working with the populations again you
got to understand about the plant
breeding
to be perfectly Frank they need to bring
it all to cut around the whole
discussion and go right to the end
I think
and this might be controversial to some
people I think that male cannabis plants
in the drug breeding world are probably
on their way out
um
if you make all female seeds or
gynocious seeds I don't again I don't
like to use the word feminized but if
you use gynocious seeds right you make
them right
they're every bit as good as
regular seeds in fact they're better
than regular seeds
um
for a couple of reasons the obvious
reason that in your next Generation you
don't have to worry about dealing with a
bunch of males
right I mean truthfully if you're
growing out a thousand plants and 500
that are males that's a big waste of
time and space
you know the resources to pull them out
even if you're using genetic uh
sequencing or PCR based method to
identify the males at the beginning
that's a that's a cost right like it's
not free to do that it costs money it
costs money to plant them it costs time
to plant them it costs money in terms of
nutrients and soil and space in your
grow room and all that kind of stuff
so to me males are a big hassle to deal
with sometimes I I work with male
populations but if I do I typically
don't do one-to-one readings with males
unless the plant has some incredible
unique trait that I can't do it another
way usually what I'll do is I'll combine
the pollen from
a percentage of the population call it
10 to 15 percent of the plants that I
see I I determined or I believe are the
most suitable for whatever that
population is and then I'll mix the
pollen
or or use those plants all together in
the same room and that way
because that's that's really the natural
way that cannabis breeds in a in a
natural stand okay like if you you know
call it 30 000 years ago if you're
walking through the Tibetan plateau and
you find a stand of cannabis you're not
going to find one female together you're
going to find a group of plants many
males and many females and the males are
pollinating all the females
um and that that that's a not that
natural state of of breeding is what we
call outcrossing but it's actually
called an obligate outcross or an
obligate outcrosser is a plant that
needs another individual from a
different you know genetic type maybe
our brother or sister but maybe another
plant far away to cross
um to hybridize to make to make
Offspring right that's the consequence
of having a dioecious population where
you have males and females right so it's
it's a lot more akin to the way that
humans breed right where
um humans also need to have
you know they need to have sex with
another individual to be able to leave
Offspring right you can't you can't
clone yourself you don't just have kids
willy-nilly unless you're you know the
Virgin Mary
um everybody else has to breed together
to make Offspring and there's a genetic
consequence to that meaning that the
child is actually a hybrid right of two
different parental types
um
so when you look at you know everybody's
got a mother and a father and I don't
know if you've got brothers and sisters
but if if you look at you know your
family you don't look like your mother
or your father like you don't look like
your father if you have a sister she
doesn't look exactly like your mother
right they have some traits of both the
parents and you you don't look like your
siblings unless you're twins
um
and so that state of breeding is really
much more similar to cannabis than for
example Tomatoes right if you're growing
an heirloom tomato variety you can plant
a seed grow it into a plant harvest the
fruit take the seeds out of the fruit
plant those again the next year and the
fruit from that subsequent year are
going to look like the year before and
the year before and for 10 20
Generations down into the future the
tomato is going to keep coming out
looking the same well cannabis isn't
like that
right it's began and the reason it's not
like that is because when you constantly
breed to another type
you're constantly introducing new
genetic material into the mix and you're
losing some genetic material every time
but you're also gaining new stuff
and so
you don't have this uniformity that that
starts to develop in plants like tomato
that are what we call self-crossers or
South species selfing species or
inbreeding species
um and those types of Speedy species get
to be more homogeneous and more uniform
over time because they actually their
breeding system actually purges genetic
variation rather than increases the
genetic variation okay so from a
breeding perspective it's actually a lot
more work with cannabis to make things
uniform
and through some of the work that I've
done down in the states and especially
having access to the chemical
uh to the laboratory where you know we
would grow hundreds of plants and and
every single plant would go to the
laboratory and so we would get back you
know not only the phenotypic data that
we would collect during the grow you'd
also get the chemical data from the
laboratory
um and so we would be able to take two
plants that had a very similar to an
identical terpene profile and we'd cross
those together
whereas if you took plants with
Divergent terpene profiles and you cross
them together you wouldn't have the same
level of uniformity in The Offspring
um and so because male cannabis plants
don't produce the traits of Interest or
even of import to
drug cannabis Growers right you don't
use male plants in growing drug cannabis
you only use them for making seed
those those male plants people don't
because it's like I use this expression
and you know some people don't like when
I use it but I'm going to use it anyway
because I don't care if you're breeding
humans for breast size it's pretty easy
to select the female the the female
humans that have big breasts right
how do you select a mail
individual for big breasts they don't
have that characteristic and so it's a
sex it's what we call a sex-linked trait
right only one gender really shows those
characteristics and so if you're in a
if you were running a human breeding
program which we can't do because of
Ethics but if you were running a human
breeding program you would probably look
at male plants
that had sisters with large breasts or
mother with large mothers with large
breasts and that increases the
probability that they'll have the genes
for large breasts but it doesn't
guarantee it right
whereas when you're selecting two
females and you can find a way to cross
two females together like we have done
with creating feminized seeds you can do
what I call positive selection for the
traits of interest on both sides of the
Cross and when you can do that
trust me because I've done it in the
laboratory many times when you bring two
types together that are almost identical
the chances of the plants being more
uniform are way way higher
um so what I've noticed is that you you
make more genetic progress in a
generation when you're doing it that way
you also have the added Consequence the
added benefit
of not having to remove males from your
subsequent population right like with
like I said if you've got hundreds or
even thousands of plants
having to go through and write Rogue out
half your crop or kill half your crop
that really is a pain
right it's a real real inconvenience
yeah of course and I mean gosh so many
Avenues to go down
something just to kind of follow on with
that is there's long been a discussion
within the community about whether
there's any realistic significance
between say a feminized seed produced
from intentional STS application versus
one that's just purely a result of maybe
a stressed environment some sort of
hermaphroditic event what's your
thoughts on this do you think that there
is some sort of difference or that
they're fundamentally the same thing
well it's both uh I I can't tell you
it's the same in the other one or the
other but it's it's actually both
okay sure
let me put it this way I'm just trying
to think how to put it we have a basic
tenant in as a breeders but it applies
to plants but it also applies to animal
breeding and that that tenant is like
begets like and all that means is the
plants that you you select as parents
it's it's very likely that the traits
that you selected for in those parents
are going to reoccur in the Next
Generation okay and so if you're using a
plant that go that goes intersects again
hermaphrodite's not a it's not
technically a real world word for plants
because a hermaphrodite flower would be
a would be a one single flower that had
male parts and female parts and that's
not what happens with cannabis we have
flower clusters that have male and
single female flowers together and so
that's really called intersex not
hermaphrodite hermaphrodite would be if
it was half a male flower and half a
female flower
um so intersex is the proper term for
that but so intersex plants they have
like you said some either genetic
predisposition to have both sexes on the
same plant or
in the case that you mentioned under a
specific grow room stress or
environmental stress they produce male
flowers right well if you use those
plants that produce male flowers under
that given stress
like begets like the next generation are
going to be more likely to be
predisposed to making male flowers given
that stress appears
right so by using plants like you said
that are maybe like late flowering this
is the way Dutch Passion used to do it
and Soma kind of does it this way as
well they call it rhodolization when you
use these plants that are
are producing intersex flowers
either late in the cycle or due to a pH
fluctuation or light cycle fluctuation
or whatever it is that throws off the
hormonal balance in the plant that makes
it produce set that makes it produce
male flowers if you select if you
positively select those crates those
traits are going to be more likely to be
present in the Next Generation and so
all that says is intersex plants are
going to have are going to have a higher
likelihood of making intersex offspring
whereas if you select plants that don't
have those intersex characteristics and
then you create you use you know STS or
silver thiosolvate for example to force
those plants to produce male flowers
the next generation of plants are going
to be less likely
to produce intersex flowers
right so everybody typically the
Cannabis Community you know
whatever we look for the short easy
explanations and it's like oh the the
explanation everybody comes to is oh we
sprayed this chemical on the plants
the the Next Generation had
intersex Offspring it's the chemical
that's doing that and that's a wrong
conclusion right it's the the thing is
is that they selected a plant that has a
higher likelihood to go intersex and
that trait is Amplified in the Next
Generation
right so yeah they are very different
you don't want to use plants that are
likely
to produce intersex flowers
as parents right because again like
begets like those the progeny from those
those parents are going to be more
likely to be intersex
yeah sure and this is something that
I've long suspected and tried to explain
to people that like fundamentally at its
core cannabis is a plant which doesn't
have discrete Sexes you know it's it's
actually both at the same time and we've
just bred it from like this Manisha sort
of plan to try to be more dioecious so I
guess my question is do you think we'll
ever get to a point where we have bread
cannabis selectively enough that we more
or less don't see any expression of the
other sex in the in the say a female
plant or do you think it's it's almost
genetically impossible
well it's not genetically impossible in
any given plans because we have lots of
plants that don't go intersex
um
you know it's it's like it's it's a
Continuum right it's a spectrum
um and on one end of the spectrum
there's plants that don't go intersects
at all
at the other inspection that there's
plants that are completely like you said
manishes I would disagree with you in
saying that they don't that there are
discrete genders in cannabis there's two
things there's discrete genders and then
there's females that are intersex
right so you can have a female plant
that is female but intersex and you can
have a female plant that is female but
not intersex
right we do understand the the genetic
basis now of
um of gender in cannabis
and
it it's yeah it's almost
it's it's almost 100 sure that we're
right but in the Plant World you know
you know what it's like in nature I mean
there's exceptions to every rule
right like there's there's human
children that are born uh intersex right
that they have some gender from each
the X and the Y chromosome they undergo
um crossing over so there's genetic
material exchange between
um the male and the female so you can
have males
that don't have the G you're not gonna
have genetically male people with Y
chromosomes
that have female reproductive parts
you can have female people with two X
chromosomes and no Y chromosome and they
have male reproductive parts
right so there's always going to be
exceptions to every rule when it comes
to biology
[Music]
um
and so I think that yeah as a whole
in the species we'll never get rid of
intersexuality because it's it's part of
the the thing that's coded into the
species but if you want to grow you know
one of the easy ways to do it is to grow
plants and select clones that don't go
intersex and then use those plants for
your production
I think over time in a proper breeding
program and now that we're starting to
get access to genomics genomic companies
that can support cannabis breeding
programs that we will be able to
identify genetic markers related to
intersexuality and we'll be able to
select against those markers and create
populations that are much more resistant
to intersexuality
but that's part of our process and part
of our
um
our learning experience that we're going
to have to go through over the next you
know like I said however long 20 years
yeah funnily enough funnily enough
all-female breeding is probably going to
be the way that we will do that right
because again when you're selecting
males unless you have genetic markers
it's very difficult to tell whether that
plant has
uh will be intersex because again
the males don't show that characteristic
so how do you select for or against a
characteristic in males that you can't
see
right so in fact using two female plants
that are highly resistant to
intersexuality that might be how we
breed out intersexuality right
that's which is maybe seems
counterintuitive to some people I know
that
you know there's a lot of people again
it's kind of a trait in our community
that it's like everybody wants it to be
as natural as possible
um that's not the way that cannabis
evolved well truthfully the Cannabis
that you're smoking today is nothing
like the Cannabis that humans first
encountered right like the Cannabis that
humans first encountered was a tall with
a short little plant that probably
produced very little flower and a few
seeds and no discernible
give collaborated content or terpene
content certainly not
but it's comparable to today's modern
hybrids
um
and so if you want to be if you're like
kind of hippie minded and anti-science
and you want everything to be natural
organic
you know the way Mother Nature intended
you're probably not going to be
supportive of female female breeding
but I think that if you're serious about
breeding cannabis for its chemistry
which is what we do as drug cannabis
breeders
that it's really kind of undeniable that
the
effects that you can get the the sorry
the progress that you can make using
female plants or only female populations
is uh it's pretty significant if you
actually use a lab and Screen the
samples you know from male female
crosses and female female crosses I
think most people would be surprised
that um
of the differences in the amount of
genetic gain that you can make in a
generation
truthfully some female female crosses
don't work I mean a lot of females they
contain intersex genes and when you self
them or when you cross them to other
female plants yeah you get a lot of
um
intersexuality in some lines right it's
not everywhere but it does happen
um and you just you either
do your best to pull those
intersexuality traits out or you don't
use that line I mean I said this last
week on on or a couple weeks ago on
shango's the podcast but
you don't you know in the plant breeding
world not every up you don't step up to
bat every time and hit a home run right
there's a lot of fail failures you might
fail 90 of the time
right and that's okay because breeding
plants is about taking the best of the
best of the best right you're taking the
cream from the crop
um and using those to for the Next
Generation
um
and so it's okay if things don't work
out it just means that you don't work
those lines right or you work them a
different way right and you you focus on
the ones that do work
right that's another another one of the
David's quotes he's like I love killing
plants you know I love killing cats and
I was like really and he's like yeah of
course like that's how you that's how
you make them better
you gotta get rid of all the junk
yeah
150 on that one I think pay for her
sometimes a bit too attached to plants
to realize when maybe they're not worth
keeping around just to extend on a kind
of idea you touched on I remember one of
the ideas DJ mentioned when we had a
chat with him was that he always had
this sneaking suspicion that males which
showed intersex traits might be of more
value than just what you would call a
male that doesn't do you have any sort
of speculation on maybe where that might
come from or if there's any maybe
validity to that if you've seen that or
toyed with intersex males at all
yeah so David and David also has talked
a lot about this with Hayes and
apparently Hayes is you know throws like
he's he claims up to 75 of the
population they're females it's a much
higher ratio sex ratio which is bizarre
um because it doesn't really fit our
scientific understanding
um
what DJ's talking about I think there's
probably a scientific basis for what
he's noticed right so I don't know if
you've looked into how the silver silver
thiosulfate chemical that we use for
um
for creating male flowers on female
plants what it does is it blocks a
receptor in the plant called the
ethylene receptor and ethylene is one of
five major plant hormones
um in in humans we have you know you'd
probably know more than I but with your
background but there's we have lots and
lots of
um
of hormones many hormones that do many
different things in in the plant world
there's really five major ones
um and one of those is ethylene and so
people might heard of this trick with
either avocados or or bananas if you got
a green banana and you take it and you
put it in a paper bag and cinch the top
of the paper bag
the banana will go ripe yellow more
quickly than say one open sitting on the
counter and the reason is is that when
bananas mature they give off this gas
called ethylene okay and ethylene causes
the banana ripen it also causes plants
to to it also causes plant flowers
to open and Bloom
okay and so if you're able to block that
receptor the ethylene can't do its job
so think of it like Narcan or naloxone
the anti-opioid drug the the drug that
all the police carry now to give to
heroin people that are overdosing from
heroin that molecule blocks the heroin
receptor or the opioid receptor and
therefore the fentanyl can't bind to the
receptor and cause all the downstream
problems that it does the shortness of
breath and blah blah blah
right
um and so when we do that with the
silver
thiosulfate or silver nitrate the silver
molecule actually blocks the ethylene
receptor and so we shut down that
biological pathway okay we're turning
off the effect of that
of that hormone
okay and when we do that in cannabis
the plant produces male flowers rather
than female flowers it's just a simple
one
[Music]
um one hormone receptor pathway right
conversely if you take a male plant and
you spray it with a chemical called
ethaphone ethaphone is a chemical that
is absorbed by the plant and it breaks
down into ethylene okay so if you spray
a female plant with this epiphon
chemical you're introducing more
ethylene into the plant and the male
plant will produce female flowers
and and that's what you were talking
about when you asked about uh David
making
um selfs or or hybrids or reversing
males as you call it
um so really it's about playing with
this one pathway coincidentally I mean
we were talking about flowers opening
and maturing
and and you know really there's this Arc
in ethylene production over the flower
cycle
cannabis probably goes through that too
right I don't think anybody's really
measured that and it's actually quite
hard to measure arthelene because it
occurs in such minute quantities in the
plant
um
but yeah like ethylene probably Cycles
the levels of the plant of the of that
hormone probably cycle throughout the
hormones and that actually could be very
well be why
we have uh males or some plants that are
predisposed to throw male flowers at the
end of the cycle because there's a
change in ethylene expression in the
plant
right so anyway it's just interesting to
know that that's how it works and and
it's likely that what you're talking
about with DJ is that like humans and
like cannabis does and all these other
traits there's variation in the levels
of these chemicals that the plant
produces some plant some genetic
backgrounds might have low levels of
ethylene but some plants maybe they
produce a lot of ethylene right so if a
plant produced a lot of ethylene you
might have a male plant that would show
a female flower because again
excess ethylene to the plant changes the
phenotype a little bit and makes it
produce female flowers so that could
very well be What DJ is talking about is
that he's actually unconsciously
selecting plants that have a really high
ethylene load and as such they're more
feminine males
what a brilliant answer because you you
also answered my next question which was
going to be about breeders claiming that
their seeds have a higher proportion of
females and things like that so
perfectly answered that the following
question was going to be
I've always kind of thought that this
idea that I'm about to talk about was
kind of incorrect but you would hear
some breeders talk about how you know
germinating seeds in hot environments
will give you more males things like
that seems counterintuitive to the idea
that the the the sex of the plant is
largely genetically based I mean
although there could be some sort of
like epigenetic change I guess what's
your thoughts on like after the seeds
been produced factors which could
contribute to the ratio of sex upon
germination or something like that
okay well let's just put the sex
conversation just to the side for a
quick moment and and have a conversation
about population sizes and statistics
right so
if you have a population of a hundred
people call it label them one to a
hundred Right On Any Given trade say
that they're tall to small the smallest
guy is one the largest guy is 100 and
there's one of each so there's literally
you know one two three four five all the
way up to a hundred
and you then go into that popular you
put them all in a paper bag and you
reach your hand and you pull out three
at random
you might get like say say say whatever
you don't shake up the bag very well and
you put your hand in after and you you
pull out
numbers nice 697 and 95 right so you add
the three up and you take the average
and you decide okay 96 is the average of
this population well you're going to be
wrong
right because the small subset of the
plants that you've looked at doesn't
match the overall population and that's
something in statistics we call sampling
error and people can Google that if they
want but there's a whole field of math
about that
um and I think a lot of the results that
we see in the Cannabis world is that
people are actually not doing proper
sampling or they're not growing large
enough populations upon which to make
the conclusions that they're making
right like when we do this kind of stuff
when you talk about
um
males and females there's a really basic
science thing
um that we use and it's called the
chi-squares test is it's spelled
c-h-i-dash square and you can look that
up but the chi-square test essentially
is
your observed result minus your expected
result over your expected result okay
and that
that gives you a number that you can
look up on a table and and you can base
on the number of plants that you're
growing and seeing like for example you
know we would expect that 10 regular
seeds five them are going to be male and
five are going to be female okay
and if you grow at a population of a
hundred you'd probably end up seeing
like oh look there's 47 males and 53
females or vice versa or something close
to that okay and the larger the
population you grow
the more close to 50 50 you're going to
get okay
but if you grow three plants
each it's like flipping a coin three
times right you might get you might get
heads three times by flipping a coin
well does that mean that every time you
flip that coin it's going to be heads no
right it it just means that like you
didn't flip in enough time to get an
accurate sample of of
the population right so if you grow if
you buy 10 seeds and you only grow three
of them and they're all males you might
conclude well this all this all the the
seeds and the seed line are males but
that wouldn't be a correct population it
would be an error that you're making in
your conclusion because you didn't grow
enough plants
um and so I would argue that most
cannabis breeders again working in small
spaces and closets and not working in
fields and not keeping proper records
that they're making these conclusions
based of observations that they've made
but the observations that they've made
have been on too small of a population
to actually say it's true so when you
hear a breeder say yeah well the plant
you know this population produces 70
percent males well it's like what so you
grew seven plants or you grew 10 plants
and seven of them were males right like
that's that's not a statistically
significant conclusion right
um and plant breeding happens to be
heavily stats based it's a lot about
math and numbers
um and measuring traits and looking for
population means and outliers and all
that kind of stuff and it's really
boring and not exciting to talk about
when you just want to get high and smoke
a bunch of weed and talk about Terps but
again there's a science that goes on
behind all of the Dan it's like there's
a genetic dance there's a biological
dance that goes on
Under the Sea Under the scenes of of
plant breeding and you really have to
understand that science
um and apply those scientific methods to
be making conclusions that we're making
and again I'm not trying to talk bad
about anybody else in the scene for not
having that set of knowledge but you got
to understand people just need to
understand that
um
you can't make conclusions like that off
of small populations because it's it it
many many times with small populations
you end up having this this
artifact called
um
sampling error right yeah yeah a perfect
perfect description of that sort of
situation and I remember when I was
having a discussion with James Bean the
uh the owner of seeds here now he
mentioned to me that uh someone
contacted him and was like I got 10
males in a regular packet and this
person's obviously pretty upset and
James was like congrats like you won the
lottery dude like yeah yeah yeah well
it's true it could happen right you flip
a coin 10 times it you can get 10 males
it's rare but you can't happen yeah and
you know I just when when you have that
kind of stuff with people you just give
them more seeds man like white people
freaking out they're just seeds you know
give some hook somebody up if somebody
has a problem with your seeds why are
you trying to drag it out I mean sure
there's people that take advantage it
happens but you know what what does it
cost you to give a customer another 10c
it's nothing yeah and then I think that
was his his resolution to that and he
also even made the point of saying you
know you should feel good because
there's probably you know a bit of a
like an assumption but you know there's
probably someone out there who got a 10
female pack because of you
everything has to balance out in the end
right it's all about probabilities and
so for every it's you know these things
are all graphed on what we call a normal
distribution or a bell curve right and
so for every one person that's what one
end of the Bell there's also somebody
that's at the other end of the Bell
of course so something I've always been
really personally interested in is many
moons ago when I was a wee lad I
remember reading your article on a forum
about how cubing is a myth and this blew
my mind because I up until that point I
was you know very devout to the idea of
the cube and I guess the question that I
always wondered when I learned a little
bit more about genetics was I might be
misunderstanding maybe some of the
points you wrote about in that little
article but essentially what I took away
was that you could get to where you want
to be in like a bx1 more or less would
that be a fair kind of statement to say
okay well so sort of a first back
Chronic Generation
you can get as far as you can in a third
bat cross generation but there's other
plants in that generation are still
going to be the equivalent to the F1
hybrid
right so the point that solo was making
and that you've got to remember solo was
a is or was I don't know if he still is
but he's an engineer he's not a
biologist Okay so
if you don't understand how biology
works and how meiosis works specifically
meiosis is the way that cells divide to
produce germline cells or sex cells that
become you know female eggs or male
sperm or male pollen or female ovules on
a plant
um if you don't understand that
it's kind of hard to you know if you're
making conclusions as an engineer on
biological processes then you don't
understand those things you're probably
going to make a mistake
and and so yeah in the third back cross
generation or even in the first back
cross generation yes you're going to
find plants that are like 99
like the the mother plant say that the
mother is the recurrent parent in the
back cross generation are they in the
back cross scheme sorry
the truth is is that you're going to
find another plant in that same
generation that is it still has 50 of
the the genetics from the male
right so as a whole in the population
yes the population as a whole
only has 25 percent of the genetics from
uh any from the male and 75 percent of
the genetics from the female
but that doesn't mean that every
individual in that population is going
to be like that right
and so if you're using
um a male if you're selecting again if
you if you do this poor kind of breeding
practice and candidates where you use
one plant
and that you select from your your first
back cross generation
you might choose the plant that is still
50 of the male genome right and you
cross it back again you actually haven't
gained any genetic progress over time
right to move it over time you have to
do that back cross and you're
essentially trying to drag the entire
population
towards the female the genetics of the
female now look that female of her in
and of herself
might be a hybrid plant like if that
female was an F1 plant back Crossing and
I think I was talking about grapefruit
and the Sweet Tooth you know in context
of this or the grapefruit blueberry
hybrid when you when you start Crossing
back to a hybrid you don't actually ever
get towards 100 like the parent because
the parent is already a hybrid it's
already segregating every generation and
so yeah you might get to a point where
all of the genetics came from that
one plant but they're just the
population is still segregating for all
the traits that are in that plant like
you don't actually get close to
a true breeding nature right and so in
the real plant breeding world
you don't use back Crossing in the way
that we use it or that people have
traditionally used it that have
professed cubing
you don't you don't do it that way what
you do is you use a line that is already
true breeding
and then the reason that you would back
cross to a line is you cross it you take
that true breeding line or true to type
line where all the plants look the same
and they come up the same with the same
smell
and you might want to add call it auto
flowering to that trait so you cross it
to an autoflowering plant you grow up
The Offspring and you back cross it to
the your what we call the recurrent
parent or you know in this case call it
grapefruit or princess or whatever the
plant they were doing chasing in c99
you only want that one trait the auto
trait from your pollen donor
you want to take the rest of that
plant's genome and throw it away right
you want to get rid of it
and so that is something that you can do
then that's the way they do it in the
real plant breeding world it's like it's
called trait introgression and I wrote
it about it in um
in Jorge Cervantes the marijuana
Horticulture book
um I think it's the medical Bible is
what they call it but I wrote the
breeding chapter in there and I kind of
explained that breeding program on how
to do that and so trade integration
through back Crossing is something that
you want to do with an already true
breeding population right if you took
like an OG Kush which is a little bit of
a hybrid plant anyway on its own and you
kept back Crossing to it you're not
going to get a true breeding plant from
it because again that plant's a hybrid
and those those traits are going to keep
segregating over time until you are able
to actually find the true homozygous
parents and cross them together
right so this idea that you can cross
back to a plant three times and all of a
sudden all the offspring are going to
look like the mother plant is wrong
right if the plant is a hybrid plant
then it it has heterozygosy or a lot of
genetic diversity in its own genome yeah
all the plants that come from that plant
might have the collection of traits from
The genome
but they're not all going to look the
same and they're not going to breed true
yeah what a great explanation I think
the the one question above maybe what
you'd already answered that I was kind
of wondering was that given that there
are so many different genes and alleles
and chromosomes within plants
is it fair to say in your mind that by
doing additional back crosses you could
potentially lock in additional traits
that were maybe in the original mother
in The Princess for example which
because maybe in the first back cross
you locked down like 70 of the traits
you were looking for and I get what
you're saying where like you could find
one with like 99 but if I'm
understanding this correct you'd have to
run more seeds to find that one whereas
would you um like agree that if you did
more back crosses you could
theoretically lock down more of the
trade so that they're going to express
more consistently or have I
misunderstood that no you can't because
again
the the condition that the parent has is
it already like so you're recurrent
parent let's call it let's just use c99
and we'll use princess as the recurrent
parent so
princess herself was a hybrid plant okay
and so if you were to self if you were
to cross princess to itself forget the
the outcross to a new type to bat cross
for a second let's just self princess if
you sell princess
she comes out looking like an F2 more or
less right because again she's a hybrid
for almost all the traits that are in
the in the plant in her genome she's got
heterozygosity across her chromosomes
right I mean let me simplify this maybe
for your list there's a little bit like
in every let's let's everybody think in
terms of their own themself and their
family you have half of the Chrome in
your genetic complement Heavenly you've
got half of your chromosomes from your
mom and half them from your dad you've
got 22 from Mom or you've got 20
two and an X from Mom and you got 22 and
a y from Dad
okay
so in your mind let's make moms blue and
Dad's red
okay
well if you cross those two types
together like if you were to able to
somehow breed with only yourself
there's going to be three possibilities
for every chromosome you can either have
two red ones you can have two blue ones
or you can have
one red and one blue
okay
now let's add in the the the parent that
we're going to introgress and we'll do a
back cross population so now we're
putting in pollen from
let's assume in the best case scenario a
completely hundred percent true breeding
plant and let's label all the
chromosomes in our mind as black so when
you cross the black to the to the
possibilities of either red and blue or
yeah of red and blue
you got two possibilities you can have
black and blue or black and red
well when you back cross the either of
those types to the red and blue again
now we've just got a mass of three
different types all segregating together
right and to make it uniform and true
breeding you have to have two of one
type like you want to have blue and blue
or red and red
right
um yep that's sorry that's maybe that's
a terrible way of explaining it but
the the point is is that
we all have chromosomes from our mom and
our dad right and so somehow we were
able to back cross
to ourselves
it's still a 50 50 shot whether you get
the the chromosome from Mom or the
chromosome from Dad right and it doesn't
matter how many times you back crossed
yourself if you've got one of each type
of chromosome you're never going to get
there the only way that you can get
there is if the plant that you're back
Crossing to is either red red or blue
blue and then if it if it is over time
you'll eventually get to all blue or all
red
right but as long as that initial plant
that you're using is your recurrent
parent has what we call heterozygosity
or as a hybrid plant it has different
chromosomes
you know every every plant has your
cannabis plant has 10 chromosomes nine
um
what we call autosomes and one uh pair
of sex chromosomes
if those plants have different
chromosomes it doesn't matter how many
times you back cross it you're never
going to get any closer to your goal
right
yeah so yeah so so cubing
with the idea that yeah after three
generations The Offspring looked exactly
like Mom that's just not true
yeah after three generations the vast
majority of the population has genetics
only from Mom but that doesn't mean that
those plants are going to breed true in
any way
yeah great thank you so much for
clearing that up that does make a lot of
sense and I I suggest the listeners if
you if you got lost at any point feel
free to go back and listen to it a few
more times but hopefully you will be
able to get there
uh I just wanted to mention we're
obviously so lucky to to have you on the
show and I wanted to chat about some of
your personal breedings that you'd done
before we jump into maybe some of the
sort of intellectual property and patent
work you've been involved in which is
very very interesting to a lot of our
listeners but I first just wanted to
give you a quick Kudos my buddy green
and gold Farms when I was at his house
on the weekend I told him I was going to
be interviewing you and he pulled out a
jar of some of your Sour Diesel cross to
Sweet skunk that he grew probably about
five years ago I think he said but he's
really good at curing and storing things
and so that's been the inspiration for a
lot of these questions when I was riding
them I was puffing away on that one from
you and I tell you what it's a
phenomenal smoke it's almost like piffy
in a way like very up like more
uplifting than you would have expected
either if the parents to kind of be
yeah that's great well it's probably
kudos to him as well I mean all we can
do is put the jeans together it's the
grower that brings it out oh there's
other plants like sweet skunk
like for example there's one over here
called um
it's a seedsman it's a plant that came
out of the seedsman haze which seedsman
were just seeds that they were buying in
bulk from David ah and and if you grow
the and so they I don't know whether it
was they were this this seed came from
ones that they had bought directly from
David or they had bought from David and
repopulated them and then this seed came
from those but I'll tell you this plant
came to me as a clone and I had them in
the grow room and they would continually
get mixed up one for the other and from
Veg clone flower bud
you had to have a really trained eye to
be able to tell the two of them apart
same with the grapefruit and the Soul
Shine
they both have like their their set of
traits are so similar
that you have to know the plant
intimately and be like oh this one has a
slightly wider leaf and a different curl
to the you know the the serration and
the leaf that one is this one and this
one is the other one
but otherwise you can't tell I mean my
friends used to grow the grapefruit and
the soul shine in greenhouses and they
would mix the bud and you nobody ever
knew that the bud was mixed right
yeah okay there you go so so there's a
so that's what I when I talk about a
flavor class that's an example of that
right where
you know
we're not going to push this in so I'll
use the kind of more crass analogy it's
like you know it's kind of like saying
well all all Asian kids look the same
right
yeah it's not true there's a variation
in them you might find two kids that
almost look identical it's just you know
familiar so you can't say the difference
exactly yeah but within any family
there's groups right so the you know and
that's one of the things we we learned
again when we did these large
populations grow as with all the
chemical analysis that you can identify
these unique types and that it's not
every plant is not while it might be
a unique individual it's not necessarily
a unique chemistry right like the buzz
you couldn't tell apart from between
them so
yeah there you go sweet skunk in the in
the seedsman taser pure are the same and
you know again we can talk about that
later with napro but the again we
learned that these terpene profiles
they're characteristics right it's a
trait that gets inherited and so while
the plant might not be identical to the
parent oftentimes
the terpene profile is
right so you can end up with plants that
smell exactly like the mom or the dad
right and so once when Steve found this
sweet skunk plant or his friend that
found it found it whatever the story is
and who cares
yeah he found a plant that was neat but
he just found a plant that was a subtype
of this terpene profile right it's not
really a unique plant the sweet scar
kind of fits the description of what
you're talking about I mean it really is
a kind of pithy equatorial plant
um that has that really what we would
you know classically use I'm going to
use the word I hate using sativa but
it's it's it's got that profile and it's
got like you said the fox tails and the
the kind of staggered calyxes or the
staggered bracks on the flower structure
it's not a big beefy plant
um which is kind of odd because the
mother was right like sour diesel is not
huge but it does have quite dense modern
looking flowers right highly resinous
very very fewly and uh in in a lot of
individuals from that family they kind
of got stomped on by the the sweet skunk
side which was really was not expected
um
but you know it might have added a
little more intensity to the high
so I I like that hybrid there's some
really great plants in that in that
family
yeah I I look I'm certainly Keen to try
some others based on this experience we
had a viewer ask a question of are you
releasing seeds that they would be able
to purchase and if so like where can
someone pick up some of your work
so breeders retail is really the main
bank that's over in in the UK
um because I'm working in Canada right
now
mainly the work that I'm doing in the
regulated market can only be sold
through the regulated market in Canada
one of the things about the legal
aspects in Canada
is that we've created this legal system
but in order to respect International
Drug law of which we're still beholden
to the EU
um we don't export Recreational Products
we can only export
medical or scientific products so a lot
of the work that I'm actually doing
right now won't actually be able to
leave the Canadian system until we can
start exporting it
um all of the old work is still
available
um I actually pulled everything off the
market a couple of years ago when
there's this big pubco Frenzy
um and we're just reopening breeders
retail which is a site
that will be up soon it's an old friend
in the UK that's going to do it and all
the stock is you know produced over
there in Europe many years ago anyway so
it's uh it can be sold internationally
from there
um
there probably will be a way at some
point in time for some other work to be
done in Europe legally and then those
seeds can be sold onto the international
market through that but it's not a
current thing right now we're kind of
trying to
um get this new iteration of the
business within the Canadian Market to
be able to supply clones and improve
genetics to all the new licensed Growers
that are coming online and we've got
many now in Canada I mean it started
with just a few but we have well over a
couple of hundred licensed Growers and
some new small craft Growers what
they're calling micro licenses
that are allowed to grow you know I
think it's 250 square meters
um
which is good because it's enough for a
family to a family-run business for
people to make enough money to make a
living and probably make a good living
and
um it also allows them to focus on a
smaller footprint
so we have a higher quality product than
what was coming out of these very large
grows
uh that are producing hundreds of
thousands of square feet worth of of
flowers and when you start producing
cannabis on that scale
it's actually quite difficult to
maintain the level of quality that
people have come to express expect from
the high quality cannabis that you can
find on you know any given market around
the world really
um and so yeah so our new our new
project is really bringing in the
genetics we've got the ability to
legally import genetics from other
countries so we've been bringing in a
lot of work that was done in Europe
under license over there bringing it
into Canada and we're going to be
re-screening large populations of all
the old goodies and bringing them to
life and making them available in the
new system
that's really exciting
um I wanted to specifically ask I want
to talk about some of your older strains
in just a second but before we do I've
noticed that some of the more newer ones
and by new you know relative term you
you're working with sweet skunk and
obviously you had involvement with
sweets gunk in the past and Steve so
that might be the simple answer to the
question that it was just like proximity
but were there any specific
characteristics about the sweet skunk
that you really liked which kind of made
you want to work with it a little more
yeah but one of the reasons is it
reverses easily it makes a lot of pollen
so you know when you're doing a seed
crop that's um going to be sold you want
it to produce as many seeds as possible
so that was one of the drivers behind it
as an initial feminized release it's
also a great plant it's a it's a really
hazy piffy type as you were saying
earlier
um
and it's enjoyable it leaves this
beautiful
I want to say in like sweet perfumey
incensey
um nose in the air and it's kind of
bizarre it's one of those things that
I've had with other other types as well
typically if you're lighting the joint
you don't smell it but if you you know
if you like The Joint you smoke a little
bit and then you pass it to somebody and
you leave the room
for a few minutes and then come back in
you're immediately hit by this very
sweet incensey kind of unique exotic
smell and it's hard to just it's hard to
describe again because we don't have a
common set of knowledge or common set of
words to describe it but it's really
quite intriguing and um
so so from that perspective yeah I just
wanted to see how she came together and
interplayed with some of the other
plants that I had in the collection
and it's a part of a breeding program
those are not finished breeding programs
by any means but you know I kind of like
to release release small batches out of
those so that other people have the same
genetics that I'm working with and they
can create parallel lines or or back
cross them to for example I mean that
would be a great candidate for example
to back cross to sour diesel or to Sweet
skunk right you can kind of start
different breeding programs with it
um and that was really one of the
reasons that I did that with the
blueberry lines as well
um you know blueberry is a great
population it's an inch really
interesting plant with the colors and
some of the shapes and and things but it
also has some weaknesses and so
when you're using a population like that
sometimes you wanna we were talking
about back Crossing earlier sometimes
you might want to take one of those
traits from the hybrid plant and use
that to enter grass or incorporate into
the blueberry line
right and so a lot of these these things
are part of projects that are ongoing
that I kind of just share along the way
so that they don't get lost if you know
something happens to me either they end
up in other people's hands I think
that's part of responsible plant
breeding is to share things with people
you know
which is kind of funny given the the
conversation that we're going to have in
the future about uh intellectual
property and cannabis development but
um yeah those are fantastic plants and I
really like those populations they're a
lot of fun
yeah I mean the person the pudding right
and you just touched on my next question
perfectly for me where I was going to
talk about how you had some notable
experience working with some of the
earlier versions of blueberry and
notably in your fighting Buddha cross
you use like an F2 blueberry and I think
the part which struck my curiosity the
most was that this was back in the
generations where people often regarded
blueberries like more blueberry back
then like you often hear comments about
the blueberry muffin or the blueberry
syrup terpenes that the earlier
Generations had which are often said to
not quite be present anymore was that
your experience that there was those
sort of expressions and what's your
thoughts on blueberry now
okay so one little correction I think
the blueberry that we we actually used
was an F4 those were seeds from DJ
um but maybe it hasn't probably been
known but I don't think it's terrible to
say that those seeds they came to Canada
um from someone
arrived them here whatever with DJ or
without him I'm not sure but when I saw
them they all came and they were in a
container or they were in a a one piece
of corrugated plastic and there's all
these different lines in it and my
understanding was that those were seeds
that had come back from Dutch Passion
after DJ's uh experience with them
and these seeds were returned to him and
they were the pure seeds that he had
originally brought over from which Dutch
Passion started their programs and so
they came back and when they came back I
think that they'd been a little bit
mixed up to a certain degree
um but
from from DJ's
um notes and information that we had and
he was there at the time as well
I believe they were actually an F4 plant
that we that we or the plant that we
selected was from the F4 generation
and so that word that was done in Canada
was done at a friend's grow
um and it wasn't a huge grow but it was
you know like 12 or 15 lights or
something like that
enough to grow a bunch of really small
plants and Screen them out and we think
grew like or the grower grew I kind of
went over and helped with the selections
and babysat them a little bit but it
wasn't my grow to be clear
um and the grower there you know grew
all these plants and then our friend red
from Legends and DJ would come up and we
would go through the plants and look for
different candidates and so
I was part of the uh the group that did
that got to do all the selections on
those plants so we looked at you know
100 like a few hundred of each type the
flow
um what was supposed to be the the blue
moonshine
um
the blueberry and and they all got relay
renamed you know F the the F number 13
or flow number 13 became f13
um there was a plant called
oh no it was B-25 it was it was in the
blueberry line and that plant became the
mother of grape crush and it actually
was a plant like you're talking about
like she was in the blueberry muffin
side of the Cross but there's also a lot
of stuff on the other side which is more
of like um
I don't mean spicy and like a hot exotic
way just like kind of a dry
kind of a roasty flavor
um and a with a lot of chocolate
influence to it like a lot of chocolatey
notes to it
um and that is really really prevalent
in both the flow and the blueberry lines
and I think at this point in time
well this was an F4 so it was earlier
than the most Generations that have been
on the market but even they were a bit
blue or a bit more chocolatey than the
blueberry flavor I had previously grown
quite small populations because you know
getting DJ seeds in Canada was pretty
expensive I couldn't afford to grow 500
of them
um but I think we grew you know 150 of
them or something like that now I found
a couple of plants that were quite
in that blueberry syrup sweet character
sweet side of the Cross
um
DJ's plants are they've been like I said
they've been bred for multiple
Generations
um usually using one plant as the parent
of each generation and so they in my
opinion they suffer a little bit from
inbreeding depression which is corrected
when you hybridize them to another plant
but it's something that's present in the
line if you're trying to grow up pure
and there's also the this characteristic
that I call the crinkler the leaf that
some people call it the Twisted leaf
but it's a it's a or variegation it's
not really a form of variegation but
it's a genetic anomaly that the plant
has where the leaf kind of grows like
really weird shaped it doesn't look like
cannabis
like I mean it looks like cannabis but
they're all kind of gnarled and twisted
rather than having these long beautiful
straight lamina like the you know the
fingers of the of the typical cannabis
leaf that everyone knows
um
so from a breeding perspective you can
grow a lot of those and throw them away
DJ like to think that he he had an idea
that
um
maybe those plants were
the more
desirable ones
um
and so I think that he's selected for
that trait a little bit in past
generations and that's why again we see
it reoccurring in in future Generations
like again like begets like I mean if
you you select those plants in past
Generations there's a higher probability
that those plants are going to be seen
in the in the future generations and so
I actually personally I tried to stick
away from those plants because I saw
them as a negative characteristic in the
population I mean from a Grower's point
of view I actually worked in a seed shop
a head shop when I was in in University
and I remember a guy coming in he had
spent 250 bucks on 10. of of the DJ
blueberry and he came back in with the
plant and you know this was back in the
day when it was like if you brought a
plant into a public store you were
pretty much crazy right and so this dude
there's two walks of the store with
these plants and they're all twisted
they've got this really ugly variegated
leaf and they just didn't grow very fast
and they were suffering from inbreeding
depression and he was demanding his
money back because it was you know he
thought he had paid so much money that
he shouldn't be gone and it's like dude
that's what the seeds do I mean you know
we're not making the seeds here you kind
of get what you get but I think we gave
him another pack and sent him on his way
yeah as you do right as you do yeah
that's right so but but so I I really
like DJ's population it's it's for the
most part you know when he was doing all
that work in Oregon
it's that he never crossed it like the
one thing that he did that was so cool
is that he never just crossed it to
to everything else I mean there's kind
of this weird thing in the in the
Cannabis Community where you know the
the way that people breed weed is they
their breed cannabis was the last at
least 20 years it's like you take you
you'd grow out last year's Cannabis Cup
winner and you'd find a new plant and
then somebody would win the Cannabis Cup
the next year and you'd get seeds from
that and you'd cross that to your old
plant
and then the next year somebody
has another plant that wins the Cannabis
Cup and then you just go out across it
again to the next Plant right
and nobody really took the time to start
stabilizing or trying to to
stabilize and make anything uniform it
was always about just crossing it to the
next best thing
um and DJ didn't do that right like he
made his initial crosses and then he
didn't go outside for germ plasma he
only worked within the families that he
had that he had created
and so to me flow and blueberry and you
know f-13 and and grape crush and all
these ones to me I look at those as like
they're really all one family but
they're like cousins right or they're or
they're what we call half siblings or
half-brothers right they they share a
mother or they share a father
um
and so to me it's really all one family
rather than a bunch of different types
and they're yeah there are different
phenotypes and genotypes within the
family like you know the blue moonshine
yes stocky and it's got
it's it's shorter stature it's got wide
leaves and frosty Buds and then the
great the blueberry story is a little
bit taller and the the f-13 has its own
thing and they've all got kind of their
own thing right they're all like a
little bit different
um flower structure scent all that kind
of stuff but they all they also do have
all these characteristics that are quite
shared amongst the DJ family like the
really purple leaf stems and the Really
purple striped leaves or sorry uh stems
right the main stocks or the underside
of the leaves I have that kind of purple
color
um so yeah so he that the fact that he
had all that stuff and and bred it in
line and kind of kept it
isolated from the rest of the drug pool
it really makes it interesting for
actually using as a hybridization tool
to cross back to other parts of the drug
pool right and that's why I think that
we've seen such an incredible
um
spread of those those genes I mean we
see it on all sorts of lines from like
bubbleberry to Blue Dream and that's
like over you know 15 20 years right
there's not many breeders that have had
that kind of influence
um so yeah you gotta you know you gotta
love DJ he's also just a great guy I
mean he's a really really nice guy
um
so yeah yeah I wholeheartedly agree he's
always been very very lovely to me so
big UPS DJ and I guess as a follow-on
question to that what's your favorite DJ
Short Cross or cultivar that you've come
across and I guess there's a little
follow-up do you currently follow his
more recent work because he's actually
digging into some of his really old
stock trying to pull some cool unique
stuff out I thought maybe that might be
interesting to you
yeah we kind of lost touch I mean he was
when when we were working together and
doing all that stuff he was living in
Canada and he was actually trying to
move here during the um where he went
through a period of trying to move here
during the bush years
and it didn't work out in the end and um
he eventually moved back down to to
um
uh to wherever he is in Oregon in
California but when he was in Vancouver
I had just moved to Vancouver you know
very like right before then
and he coincidentally lived like three
blocks from my house
right so we always go over to DJ's house
he and his the lady who was with the
time Carla she was just a super lovely
lady as well and we'd have these epic
parties there there they took over um
an apartment in in that area of town
that another friend of ours used to have
and it was like the place must have been
like a 1970s cocaine Palace like it was
all I had this big big shag carpet and
mirrors all over the place and they were
on the top floor and there was an
elevator that would you'd get in and it
would go up to the top floor and nobody
else could get there they'd have to buzz
you up the elevator would open and
there'd be this big mirror bar like
right in front of you so it was kind of
like a great entrance place to have
these parties a really nice like balcony
overlooking downtown Vancouver
um so during that process that was when
I really got to explore DJ's stuff
because like I said we were growing all
these seed lines for selection of what
became you know true blueberry f13 grape
crush and so on
um
and so I got to see the plants that he
was that he liked I got to see the
flowers that he liked
and I spent probably he was actually at
the time we were doing the grow he was
actually still down in the state so I
spent a fair amount of time in the
garden kind of just looking over it and
learning you know learning about his
lines and watering plants and stuff like
that
um and
that was really I really got to see a
large because I honestly have never
grown large populations of DJ stuff
aside from that like I said we did some
smaller grows but nothing with on any
kind of scale deep delving into the
entire genetic diversity right
so
um
the the things that I didn't like about
those plants were again the curl I
thought that was a really trait that it
was not it was it wasn't a great like it
wasn't a great thing for Growers right
it was it was kind of a pain in the butt
to deal with if you were a grower the
plants with the curl they were very
sensitive to nutrients and you couldn't
push them very much
they didn't yield a ton they kind of
grew a little bit slowly
and so I when we were doing the hybrids
I kind of shied away from those plants
and I really went War towards plants
that were
um that were better Growers so from that
perspective from the better grower
plants my favorite plant from that whole
family was b133 which became the
old-time moonshine
an old-time moonshine is a great plant
it didn't have the curl it grew really
well it had all the rest of the stuff
that you'd expect from a DJ line like
the purple underside of the leaves and
the purple stems and it had a really
nice flowers like a good commercial
dense flower structure and scent it had
that blueberry kind of flavor scent
unfortunately we went to make the seeds
from those crosses they all shared the
same parental plant so really we we you
know we selected the winners cloned them
up and then they went in a room
kind of in a multi-grid section with you
know many copies of the same male plant
that that DJ had selected
and all the plants set an incredible
amount of seed except for the old time
moonshine
and the grower was really choked because
they thought they were you know they
were getting paid based on the seed
and
this one you know section of the room
that was like you know 15 of the room or
whatever it barely set seed like the one
plant
it it may you know one plant would make
Maybe
I don't know 50 seeds at the most
whereas a plant that size would normally
produce well over a thousand seeds right
so it was almost Cincinnati there was
something about
um there's something called
self-incompatibility in plant breeding
and that just means when you you know
when you when you breed plants that are
out crossers too closely together they
don't make seeds and for whatever reason
it whether it was self-incomepatibility
or it was just something to do with this
plant this plant was almost sterile not
quite but almost right and so in a Bud
you might have one seed rather than
you know 30.
um
and a lot of buds that had no seeds and
so from a seed making point of view it
kind of sucked because you had this
great plant that it wanted to make seeds
from
but for whatever reason genetically it
just it didn't make seeds
so those things became really rare on
the market and that was why the old-time
moonshine kind of disappeared more
quickly than any of the other ones
they just didn't make enough seed
um
so I've got a bunch of those in the
library I also took that plant and I
reversed it and had it produced male
pollen and It produced copious
quantities of pollen and so that was one
of the ones that I used when I did my
work with DJI we used the same males
that he was using and I took a few of my
favorite of his female plants and I
reversed those as well and threw them in
the pollen mix probably I don't know I
want to say up to 30 but that's probably
being generous it was probably closer to
like 10 to 15 percent of the plants came
from the female pollen and the rest of
it came from the males
and that's borne out if you look at the
you know the sex ratios and The
Offspring that they are pretty close to
regular seeds you grow 100 you're going
to have only slightly more females than
males
um so I really like that one I like the
f13 for the the nose she's a bit of a
quirky grower again she's got that curl
um
the grape Crush was really interesting
plant it had this kind of neat trait
where it had kind of a rounded top Cola
and all the leaf the sub-tending
leaflets the little leaves that stick
out of the bud rather than being
triangle triangles they were rounded at
the tips
and they had a nice little purple stripe
that kind of ripped that kind of went
around the edge of that subtending
leaflet as well
so you know they were pretty plants like
they were pretty they were pretty nice
looking plants
um some of my favorites were the cross
the Mental Floss cross with that that b
uh 133 plant
they just they really came out quite
well
um and that's yeah those are those are
my favorites I didn't love the bee the
true blue the true blueberry I mean it
was neat enough for the most part
um it was a little bit too leaning
towards the chocolatey side for me not
the blueberry
you know and and having said that I've
met a grower in the last year and a half
here in Canada and he bought those seeds
from you know the group that made them
back in
2005 I guess it was
and I met him a year and a half ago
maybe two years ago and he showed me his
blueberry
and it's everything that you'd want in a
blueberry plant I mean it's it's
completely blueberry muffin smelling
it it grows really well
um and it came from that kind of inbred
mom so you know it it might just be that
those blueberry muffin phenotypes that
you're talking about are still in the
line it's just they're a little more
rare right you have you'll have to grow
a bunch of limited a bunch to find it
this guy actually only grew a 10 pack
and he found this really nice plant so
you know
you can hit it it's just but again like
with any plant breeding thing it's it's
numbers
so if you're growing three seeds you're
gonna have a hard time finding it if
you're growing 10 20 you'll probably
have a better shot
yeah sure so you got that one in a
million that's that's awesome to hear I
wanted to ask you about how you had done
a grapefruit cross to blueberry and this
is a cross which has been done in many
forms it's almost a bit of a Redux of
Sweet Tooth but also you know bcga did
their own version of it I guess my
question is do you feel like there were
components of maybe Sweet Tooth or the
bcga cross that you thought could be
improved and the reason why I ask is
because in a lot of your work there's
like progeny of Sweet Tooth being like
sweet skunk and other things so
obviously you like the line I guess but
did you feel like there were parts of it
that could be improved or did you do
that cross for other reasons no I did
the cross for other reasons and to be
perfectly Frank those were done really
out of a Goodwill gesture to Steve and
spice life when he left Switzerland he
was in a pretty rough shape he had been
busted by the cops and things weren't
really going his way he had moved back
to Canada and was is trying to get into
the weed or the wine business
and we had contracted this room to be
produced for those crosses and I said
you know what they they had made a very
small batch of the Sweet Tooth 1.1 which
is the same cross
it's I label it great for blueberry
because I don't want the drama
um but it's
you know they were produced for Steve
right they were supposed to be sold on
the spices live Seed Catalog and uh
through life circumstances
that
they they stopped being sold deceived he
he kind of just I don't know whatever he
stopped selling seeds for a while let's
just put it that way and um and so
I put them under my catalog and just
called them what they were so that's the
deal behind the grapefruit blueberry
they were never intended for my catalog
yeah okay and did you ever get a chance
to try the bcga version and if so did
you have any thoughts on that one
but it's more or less the same right I
mean the Vic High gave me the grapefruit
clone right the the guy from the bcga
you know rest his soul gave me the the
parent he brought it to me one day I met
him in Montreal for a meeting he had he
had gone down to meet his seed supplier
down there and I was not far down the
road a couple hour drive so I wanted to
go meet him because he was a pretty
smart guy and you know he was a he you
know he was cantankerous like like we
all can be at times
um
but yeah when I showed up he was like I
brought you a gift and he tossed me a
tupperware container and it had that
clone and it had
the AE 77 California Orange clone which
I don't know if you know that one but
that was a big thing back on those old
boards everybody wanted it the funny
thing that nobody realized about it was
when Vic gave it to me he said okay
here's here's the grapefruit you know
because you want that for flavor and
this is the California Orange this plant
is a five on ten on every trade right so
it's like it's a five on potent potency
it's a five on Flavor it had a unique
flavor right it had that orangey
terpiness and that's where really a lot
of the orange stuff came from were
descendants from that one but
you know sub cool used it I used it a
whole bunch of people used it
um for different things Vic used it for
the Orange Crush
um
and but the re the real reason that he
gave it to me is that this one's a five
on ten on everything and now we have a
scale that we can use to compare things
we can compare notes from across the
country because I was living on the East
the the more Eastern end of Canada and
he was on the West Coast
um but it was his way of kind of
calibrating the scale you know what I
mean like it was he was he was saying
this five on ten so now you got
something that's a five on Town and
everything and so when we talk about
stuff
you know if this is a five then you can
now assign whatever values to any other
plant right and that was kind of a nice
thing I had to do because it was it was
just a very genuine gift
um you know at that point in this time
Steve was over in Switzerland and when
he came back
I returned the great fruit to him right
along with the sweet skunk as well
um
so
yeah okay that's that's actually quite
full circle there isn't it what goes
around what goes around comes around
right it's kind of one of those things
with plants and I think it's really poor
form if if you find a plant or select a
plant or a plant comes to you and then
you lose it but you've given it to
somebody else it's kind of lame if they
won't give it back to you in fact it's
completely lame I mean but people do
that kind of stuff with cannabis because
they think that they have something
that's unique and it gives them
a commercial Advantage but the truth is
when it comes to plants especially in a
Prohibition Market the only way to keep
it is to give it away
right because if you get a bad bug or
you know a bad police visitor or someone
you know you can lose things right and
stuff happens plants just die in the
grow room like things go wrong right
um the watering systems fail or your
backup plan or your plant gets like
pythium or something like stuff dies
right and really the only way for it to
really survive is if you pass it around
um and if you pass it around and it
survives in everybody's Garden it's
probably a good plant
right if you pass it around and nobody
keeps it that's probably not a good plan
yeah right it's kind of a good way to
get like external validation on plants
definitely definitely and look this is a
perfect segue because I had a question I
wanted to ask and I was wondering how I
was going to slot it in but in relation
to you mentioned the uh the Cali orange
the AE 77 that's an interesting one
because I remember one time I was at
Bodie's house and he was telling me you
know it's such an old cut it was dotted
and it was the first time I heard that
term dudded and then more recently we've
had the the news come out that like the
virus responsible for that has been
categorized it's the Hop late and hemp
virus I'm sure you've probably heard
about this my question is a what are
your thoughts on that virus and B do you
think we might ever see a virus emerge
which actually has a beneficial effect
kind of in the way that Pinot Noir came
out of pin or Gris sort of thing or do
you think that that's too hard to
predict
so Pinot Gris and Blanc came from Pinot
Noir Pinot Noir was the original
archetype yes and the other ones were
the other ones were somatic mutations of
those I don't know that that was a
virus-induced thing
um you know plants when when cells
divide you can remember it's like it's
like you're you're the the terrible
analogy is like if you're photocopying
DNA right so the DNA copies itself and
it's got a whole
um
set of genes that are simply required
that are simply their their whole
purpose is to to make sure that
when the DNA is copied it's copied
robustly and reliably and accurately but
the truth is is that like every set of
biological machines they make mistakes
and mutations do happen over time so
there's something called a sport and a
sport is a excuse me it's a shoot on a
plant like a new branch that comes out
but it's different like you might have
we can use the the Pinot gris or Pinot
blonde allergy the original grape was
purple or Pinot Noir it's a dark-skinned
grape and and the farther south you grow
it really produces a lot of
um a lot of pigments right especially
like down in California they call Pinot
noirs from down there they call them
fruit bombs because they're they're so
dark and intense if you hold them up to
the light you can barely see through the
the wine glass whereas if you take that
same clone Pinot Noir and you grow up
say in Canada or in France which is at a
higher latitude
that they're they're what we call clarat
or you can actually see through the the
it's not as opaque put it that way it's
more translucent
um and so Pinot one somebody noticed hey
there's a branch on this Pinot Noir
plant but the grapes are more Gray
colored and someone else in another part
of the world found one that they were
white colored and what happened was the
gene that was responsible for the
pigment color accumulated the mutation
and that mutation so what they did is
they cut off the branch
um and they rooted it and they created
it into a whole plant and then they took
a whole bunch of cuttings as a mother
plant and they started planting out
sections of this new grape and you can
actually get
um so that Branch would have been called
it was a sport it was a sport of the
Pinot
um Noir plant but you can take a cutting
of a sport and if it's different
phenotypically from the plant that it
came from as you can tell in this case
we're talking about the skin pigment you
can actually take that plant and go to
the plant breeders rights people and say
hey I found a new variation of Pinot
uh Pinot Noir and I want to get you know
this arose under cultivation in my
Vineyard I want to claim intellectual
property rights for this
and you can actually get
the commercial rights for a new variety
by cloning a sport from an old plant
right because because it's changed it's
not the same plant anymore right when we
describe Pinot Noir part of the thing of
having a cultivar or a variety
registered is you have to do a full
description of the plant
and
when you get protection on that plant it
means that you get the protection on
that whole set of characteristics taken
together well one of the major
characteristics like the fruit color
changes it's a different plant
so you can actually register it as a new
plant
right and so Pinot Gris and Pinot Noir
sorry Pinot Gris and Pinot Blanc are
both
versions of
um you know their their mutant versions
of the Pinot variety
yeah do you have any thoughts on the Hop
latent virus
yeah it sucks
to the Plant World right it's decimating
whole Greenhouse Productions in in
California is getting passed around in
cuttings you know I know people down
there that are good friends of mine that
have totally changed their their
production systems people are getting
way into tissue culture now again for
growing that stuff again you got to
remember like
let's think let's think of it again the
terms of the wine grapes I mean Pinot
Gris is like or Pinot Noir I'm sorry is
hundreds of years old that clone is
hundreds of years old right well
cannabis is an annual right it's
supposed to it grows and makes seed
every year it you can't leave it in the
ground and it'll grow back in the spring
like you got to get new plants and plug
them into the ground
um
so the natural life cycle of that plant
is a year right so when we start having
plants that have been around for many
many more years the longer a plant is
alive in a production system the more
likely it is to be to interact with
other
forms of biata like you know like for
example aphids for example or or thrips
right and um a lot of these bugs I don't
know if you know about Lyme disease but
Lyme disease essentially is a bacteria
that's carried in the mouth of a tick
and if you get bitten by The Tick
the slot the bacteria lives in the
saliva of that plant and so the bacteria
can actually infect you and that's what
causes the disease right so the virus is
much like that with cannabis it's it
might be you know transmitted in the
mouths of uh thrips or or aphids that
are biting the plant and when they bite
the plant they they that virus transfers
over
um
so you know these crops that are
typically grown by clone
a lot of the times the propagation ends
up making it into tissue culture or or
propagation in vitro where they grow
little plants on Petri dishes rather
than on mother plants and there's
challenges to that whole technique
that's a whole show that we could deal
on its own but
um
you know maybe for the people that want
to grow these these plants from clone
um that that may become the standard in
in production systems where you know
you're not mothering plants
you're not taking cuttings from other
plants right because again it's like
when you when you cut a branch off a
plant you're wounding the plant like
that's a it's an open spot where it can
get infected by bacteria and viruses
right and so when you're you're taking
and then you take that same razor blade
and you run around your entire
Greenhouse cutting shoot after shoot
after shoot after shoot
you're spreading the virus right
everybody understands this in a coveted
world right viruses spread that's what
they do right they need to live in
another organism to to be able to to to
replicate themselves and that's all that
they want to do
right is replica cells and that's how
they that's how they they you know
that's how they they live right how the
species lives
um so yeah like Horticultural practices
man are super important keeping bugs
away super important you don't want to
be having bugs you get bugs and they're
potentially bringing in viruses on there
you know in their saliva or on their
feet or whatever however they how are
they they transport it
um so yeah hot virus man terrible stuff
there they found some tissue culture
ways to uh to remove it through tissue
culture processes like I think they're
probably using like a heat treatment and
meristem culture but that takes time and
they charge a big bucks you know they're
asking like 20 to 50 000 a plant to if
you want to give them your own cutting
they'll clean it up for you and return
it to you clean
but you know then there's the
possibility that they keep your cutting
um so you might you know you might not
want to be handing out your genetics to
a competitor in a legal Market it's
um and the long-term solution is plants
that are bred to be stable seed lines so
that you can grow you know when you eat
when we grow corn
we plant thousands of acres of corn and
the plants all come up looking identical
why because they've been bred by plant
breeders that know what they're doing
right and cannabis we're using again
using tools like genomics right and
that's why when you plant corn they all
come up like clones we can get there
with cannabis but it's going to take a
lot of breeding work done by people that
really understand plant breeding you
don't just cross your your OG to next
year's Cup winner that's not going to
get you to a stable seed line
yeah so I mean brilliant segue into the
next question I wanted to ask which
relates to how you were mentioning that
you know some cultivars have been around
for you know 20 plus years and I guess
the longer something's been around the
more chance there is for it to
accumulate these you know what I like to
refer to as plant STDs
but the question I wanted to ask you was
there's a lot of discussion around for
example the chem dog it's a very focal
topic of our show and a lot of the
people who are familiar with it comment
that it has lost Vigor compared to when
it was first around and the debate
exists around is that a sort of genetic
drift is that just a molecular biology
whereby there's some sort of vigor but
not necessarily A change in the genome
what's your thoughts on these sort of
more grandfathered plants which are
older are not as vigorous as they used
to be what do you suspect might be going
on under the hood
well it could be all of those things
um except for genetic drift that's not
what genetic drift means genetic drift
means the change and pop in in the
frequency of alleles in a population
over Generations so that's specifically
the meaning of genetic drift the
Cannabis Community uses that word
totally wrong
um Everybody kind of uses that word
wrong it's funny that people have
learned that that's what that word means
it's likely not genetic also I've got
some friends that have a quite serious
tissue culture companies and you know
phds and in plant in Plants uh
whatever I don't even know what it is
like Plant Pathology I guess but they
work they they do tissue culture and
they have companies that multiply large
amounts of cannabis clones for
um for propagation it's becoming a more
a more
relied upon part of the industry in the
legal cannabis World in Canada and it
probably will be in the states as well
over time
um
it will be in any Market over time to be
truthfully truthful about it but
one of the things that they learned
doing this teacher culture and they were
also trying to find a way to validate
the genetic identity of a given plant so
just like how you can identify a
Criminal by the DNA that they've left at
a crime scene you can do the same thing
for a plant or any person or any
organism they all have unique genetic
fingerprints and so in the in the
process of establishing these genetic
fingerprints they notice that some of
the plants had different DNA markers
they're not different but additional
ones
and we're able to tease it all apart and
figure out that what happened was
there was bacteria that actually had
that had colonized the plant on the
inside and they were living in the in
the cells and in between the cells
of the plant
um
and so you know I mean think about how
that could affect phenotype right you've
got a whole other organism that's that's
living within your system
and again the likelihood that like you
said these are grandfather plants that
have been around for a long time
and the likelihood is that they've been
exposed to some kind of either bacteria
or viral vector
that is compromising either the growth
phenotype and I think that that is
more likely than saying that a mutation
happened that said mutations like we
were talking about the sports you know
just a minute ago mutations do happen
right in plants
um it's really low probability that
they'll happen twice at the same part of
the chromosome but it can happen
right and so
um yeah it's also possible that there
was a genetic change in a gene that led
to
some kind of genetic weakness or
inability to plant to grow as fast as it
was you know just one one of these
General housekeeping genes that kind of
keep the plant healthy maybe it got
mutated in a way that it's not quite as
functional so yeah all of those things
are possible
yeah are they inevitable are they
inevitable that they're going to happen
to Any Given plant like not probably not
you know and you can do things like I
said good cultural practices to minimize
the chance of it happening
if you're really serious about it then
you've got a nursery where it's a
one-way thing you know things only come
out of the nursery nothing goes back in
that way you're not adding bugs or any
kind of disease vectors right you clean
your hands you sterilize your gloves you
use new tools every time you cut the
plant or you get serious and you start
propagating them in tissue culture
right
um and and maybe that is the way but I
think honestly the way the future is
that that the tissue culture will have
its Heyday and then finally when the
plant real plant breeders
get a chance to run free in these big
fields with large breeding opportunities
and we're using genomic techniques that
we're going to be able to make these
plants quite uniform and quite
chemically uniform and then you'll be
able to grow them from seed as if they
were clones
right and they're not going to be clones
but but every plant will look more or
less the same to the point where you can
either use it all for a true to type
extract or you know eventually we'll
have the flower morphology nailed as
well
and you'll be able to grow them from
seed
and they'll look like clowns and then
you won't have to deal with any of the
problems of keeping mothers right you'll
just buy your seed and plant it and
harvest in the next year you'll buy more
soup
it's like they do with corn
[Music]
[Applause]
and there we have it guys part two of
three done two-thirds of the way there
one third left make sure you get back in
to join us for that last part that
informational hitter with chimera
foreign
Bank in the game they got all the best
beans go hit them up buy some lucky dog
seeds that's my pick
likewise go hit up cop it biological
systems Your Number One Stop The
Beneficial predatory mites bugs
microbial Solutions
[Music]
come on keep the bad guys or keep the
bad guys away keep the good guys in
[Music]
all the best beneficial bugs beneficial
mites beneficial Predators all the best
microbial Solutions and feeds keep that
positive Army in Surplus get on top of
your problem before it becomes an issue
corporate biological systems go check
them out guys they'll help you have the
best Harvest you've had today
as always huge shout out to the patreon
gang we appreciate you guys so very very
much thank you for all your support you
guys are truly the Lifeguard of the show
if you're interested in supporting the
show please check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
exclusive episodes Early Access and
priority on asking questions it's all
there and more
[Music]
I'll see you for the next one friends
we'll see you
[Music]
foreign