[Music]
hello
welcome been a while
how you been
i'd like to welcome y'all to season
three
who would have thought we would have
made it the podcast you all know what it
is budding enthusiasts that is you
thanks so much for joining me
it's your boy heavy days
here for the newest episode and on this
episode we are joined by the one and
only trichome jungles thank you so much
as always
number one businesses in the game
seeds here now
you know where they are you know where
to get the fill
whenever you got that craving they got
that scratch to fix the itch
you only see bank that offers guarantee
on satisfaction not just germination hit
them up
and as always the good people at 420
australia and organic gardening
solutions holding it down
in the big land down under
and a special special thank you to our
friends at dragonfly earth medicine
that light that leads the way
on this episode trichome jungle i said
it before you ready for it part two
get that hitter
here we go
alrighty so here we are again my friends
part two with a good friend of mine the
guy who i like to chat with a lot
big thank you and welcome to banana man
from trichome jungle seeds
nice to be back on the show again
um yeah i've been looking forward to
this
hey being my friend
yeah really good really good and
yeah just been uh
spending a lot of time
um
[Music]
yeah on my own a lot lately um
and uh yeah just
being with the plants and
yeah just doing my thing really enjoying
the time by myself
that's awesome dude i see that um you
were on holiday not too long ago what
was that about
yeah we uh we did a little trip to
india me
sonic seeds
a few other guys
um a guy from afghanistan um he's on
instagram
um afghan black honey he came out from
afghanistan and he's got big farm out
there and so that was really good
um maps with some indian guys
we're up to milana
um
yeah just all-round absolutely amazing
experience
got to go to the field
and um
yeah select our own seeds found some
really
special smelling things things ranging
from like
melons and
grapefruit to like berries and that
amazing absolutely amazing
wow so what was the standout smoke of
the trip
um we were smoking a lot of charis
um mainly so we um
a few friends
there was some we got some brought some
gelato with us and things like this and
a few different moroccan hashes to show
the farmers there and that so
um yeah but the the charis
up up in that like altitude and smoking
from the chillin
um yeah it's a
total different height really really
um
enjoyable
like
everybody's sort of like you're smoking
the chilling and everybody's talking
there's like a really nice energy from
the from smoking the hash as well
yeah beautiful
so do you feel like it's it's almost
kind of like more satiri like it kind of
sounds like you're saying like it's kind
of social and energetic
well this is the thing right like
yes okay the more fresher stuff seems to
be like more energetic but anything
that's been cured for a while especially
the previous year's charis that they've
cured
yeah when i was smoking that i i
couldn't help but just fall to sleep
like so one day i think i had two naps
after smoking it so
it was that that stuff was super strong
so i think it depends on the curing
process a lot and even from field to
field and farmer to farmer there was a
difference in in um
the
heirloom varieties that they were
cultivating there
so
yeah there was definitely a different so
um
depending on who you got the hash from
there would be a difference in height
and flavor how it smoked how it burnt
everything so
yeah and were they all growing alien
varieties or did you see like some kind
of random stuff in the mix
no i didn't notice any sort of modern
hybrids um
maybe like in
closer to the cities and stuff like that
maybe you'd see
more things like this speaking to other
people
they seem some stuff like that but
right up where we were going
it was just all stuff that
they've been
farming for yeah generations really
um
the smells really unusual in some fields
um but you have this underlining
um
standard smell
that you found a lot everywhere
but then you had variations from that
and then the odd unique one when you got
to the fields and could really go into
the fields
and what was that standard smell kind of
like
like a spice
um
maybe slight aniseed smell
um and
a slight berry smell they were the main
ones and like in the fields you were
finding
i'd say about 20 were purple
and the purple ones had a slight more
berry smell but even some of them still
had that spicy underlying spicy smell
going on
but the most unique ones
were the one that smelt like watermelon
yeah but watermelon sweets
okay but it was just one plant
just one plant out of the whole field it
was just really really strange and then
i found one that was straight grapefruit
pomelo
and i just kept trying to look for more
of it there was only that one plant i
could find
and we're talking like out of a field of
thousands of thousands so i was just
going around but the
the dominant smell was the spice smell
spice berries i think that's the best
way to describe it like raisins raisins
there you go
like raisins
yeah okay and so
were you looking to collect seeds and
were you successful
yeah
yeah so
i collected like i've labeled them as
like what they smelled like mainly um
um because that's what i was trying to
find
um
the growth and other things i i'd broke
down but the main things for me were
like
there was one that smelt like vic's
vapour rub
um there was one that's more like the
grapefruit
then i did a selection for
purple types
um
purple calyx
purple leaf um
ones for red stems
um
and a few other ones that were like
green varieties
but with that typical sort of spiced
smell that the usual ones um but like
you could see a big difference even even
in the growth of the plants as you were
going up much much higher
like when you're going from
like a thousand
uh
feet
higher up and then you took another 500
and like you were seeing a big
difference in the growth
you know things were getting smaller as
you were getting a higher up
okay so kind of becoming like more squat
not squat as such but smaller in in in
structure in in height and stuff like
that yeah yeah
um but they they weren't
um like anything like an indica even
though they're a hash plan
um
but then
once i've seen the seeds being grown out
back
here they look more indica
okay
so i think
um
the way that they grow the plants so
close together
and when they're in full flower the
leaves tend to go a little bit more
thinner and i see this outdoors anyway
you can grow the same thing indoors and
outdoors and you see the more
true true growth pattern of it outdoors
so if i grow say orange soda inside
it doesn't have super thin leaves but
then when you grow it outside the leaves
always come out
thinner and you can see it's a real
sativa and it looks like a sativa like
that christmas tree type of structure
the growth conditions and how they farm
them and all of this really yeah plays a
big role on how the plant looks as well
what was the highest you went up to
eventually
uh
two and a half thousand i think that's
what we went up to
i'd have to double check on my notes and
stuff like that because where as we were
going up i was you know writing down the
altitude and things like that at certain
points where getting the seeds and stuff
like this
that's that's the good thing about these
um smartphones one of my friends had a
smartphone so we could like just keep
checking everything where we were and
stuff like this it was really good we
can even dot it down on the gps if you
really wanted to you could
got the locations where you exactly
found them yeah yeah just dreams
that's sick
yeah okay so what's the end goal with
these landry seeds obviously probably do
a seed increase but what do you want to
work it into
yeah okay so um
the also while we were there the guy
from afghanistan he brought some afghan
seeds with him
okay
um no i don't know if you've checked his
page have you seen his page this uh
afghan kush black honey yeah boy
yeah okay he's got some amazing amazing
plants there so i've just been growing
some of those seeds out
and
i found a really nice mail and i've
pollinated it with the bubba kush
the cherry cookie the sour neo mandarina
so
that's what i'm going to be doing next
is
sorry
um testing them out
and seeing how they come out
um
and
working that afghan into some maybe some
other lines i'd like to do some
selections from the indian thing and
stuff i've collected
and worked the afghan into some of them
as well
so i think that's going to be
a lot of testing and
it's going to be really interesting yeah
just just learning always
this plant teaches me so much
this is like truly like a teacher plan
um
i've learned so much from it you know
from
electrics and photography and
growing plants nutrition everything you
can possibly imagine i think so many
people forget this
and just see the money nowadays
instead of like
having that real passion
to learn about this plant
yeah right well i mean the adventure you
described there's a lot of passion
involved in that but i just wanted to
quickly ask
like how do you feel having had these
kind of worldly experiences with
cannabis how does it make you perceive
just everyday cannabis now does it just
hammer home that feeling of like the
whole poly hybrid thing or is it just
refreshing
um
i still love poly hybrids but i think
when you're talking about real breeding
um
it's like
look at the scene nowadays it's like
loads of people trying to breed from
mongrel dogs
and
expecting
something
um
like coming out like totally stable and
when i say stable i i mean like coming
out uniform all looking exactly the same
yeah we've got like so much variation in
in our gene pool
um
which is a good thing as well but i
think we really do need to go back
towards these um
land race things and create maybe like a
new skunk number one or something like
this
so i'd like to definitely work with the
indica lines and then maybe one that
they've worked work those lines a little
bit more out into the city but to create
something
that's all totally from land race
um
and that
comes out like
a breeding line should come out but i
still love poly hybrids and i love the
variation and i love using all these
different things even cookies and
some cherry pie and things like this
they're all really nice unique
um terpene profiles so
yeah i think i love them all really to
be honest
yeah i agree but let's talk making the
new skunk i've tried to bring this up in
the past and no one wants to go there
with me we're doing it what genetics
would be involved in quote the new skunk
what do you think it's going to be
well from there was two ways i was
looking at it basically using two sativa
lines and then adding the afghan to it
um but now i'm looking towards more to
hash
line two hash plant lines so like a
milano hash plant and i've got a hash
plant
i'm working that line
and then adding the sativa to it
just to
add that
i don't know about that bigger structure
the the budge structure the uh
um
calyx to leaf ratio and things like this
so it could be interesting but this is
all going to be told like it's all going
to be experimental
at first
because
really don't know what the outcome is
going to be i might cross them together
and then just totally be like i really
don't like it i'm going to have to start
again
so
but it's all going to be really
interesting i think i'd either use
the afghan's got to go in there i think
that's that's a key main key to so many
things from the past
and then maybe some of the sativa i'd
use would be probably something from
south america
yeah like a walking type of thing
uh yeah like
something like a maybe acapulco gold
type of strain
does it exist anymore
does it exist
i think i think things could be found
from the areas and we could things can
be found in them i think it can be it
can be done the one thing i have got
from really old seeds are my malawi
seeds a friend collected from for me
from malawi
so that'd be another interesting one
african sativa
um
yeah again i i just really need a nice
big
greenhouse and
one two years to just grow out the
suitcase of seeds i've got of all the
different things
so that that's going to be the next plan
the next plan maybe caribbean the
caribbean is looking good at the moment
yeah okay cool cool so out of uh the
genetics we haven't spoken about you
know non-land race stuff what's some of
the new stuff you're excited to work
with
um
my some of the new things i'm working
with the sour neo is gonna be something
really special that's gonna be the next
sort of new release but from what i
released from
last year and that is the lil everyone's
really loving that and the cherry spice
um
they're just both absolutely amazing
cherry spice is probably my favorite
after the sour near
and the lil is just so unusual
but the little like people have been
asking a lot like what's in the lilt and
stuff like that
and the the father was a jungle kush
and the mother was a cross of
pineapple and something else
so
that come from sonic and that
and that's something i didn't mention
too much about in the last one actually
like you were asking about some of the
uk clones and stuff like that uk
pineapple was a real special uk clone
but after like so many years it lost
something it was like
um some sort of genetic drift happened
or something i think tissue culture
might have been able to bring that back
though so i've been looking into that a
lot lately
that's interesting have you heard of the
concept of like a plant being dotted
yes this is what sonic told me about no
i was that's where i said to him maybe
the tissue culture can help this out
because then if it's some sort of
illness that someone's got
in their plants
it it can be removed with tissue culture
so
i don't know if the dud-in thing can
happen i think he was telling me bodhi
was talking to him about it
yeah dude but he was the one who told me
about it it's like
it's you can look it up because so the
back story is that
a lab today uh or yesterday i think it
was put up a post saying that um
they've got like this patent-pending
process where it's basically you know
meristem culturing
but they reckon that yeah they can
definitely undo a plant that's dotted
and and what dotting is is like
there's this actual um i think it's a
bacteria might be a virus it's or even a
fungi i don't know i'll just cover all
my bases um it's it's one of them and
and the government like literally was
spraying it over california for a while
and if it gets in your plant it just
gets in the systemic system
and the plants just [ __ ] forever
and like they just won't really flower
they've got no vigor it's like an actual
virus you can look it up
so that's great you said that right
about the government right because there
was one show i can't remember the show
but there was talking about
the government releasing
broad mites or another type of mite up
next to the roads
so they
kill the weeds
and that that way they don't have to
spray pesticides that harm the bees
okay
yeah but they've been releasing these in
places where people grow weed in america
and then now all of a sudden they're
having big problems with broad mics and
stuff like and it just like
just seems like
it's just crazy that they would even
release them like that do you see what i
mean like you said
they definitely did it and what they
would also do is i think i read a little
bit about this and
they would go along every so often and
spray some pesticides on the mites like
to kind of fight them at bay and so they
just bred like the borg themselves
yeah yeah yeah yeah this is it
just resistant you see it you see it
like even in holland and places like
this where the mites
built a resistance to so many different
sprays
um
and yeah this is what what will happen
so
yeah
all right we better pull it back in
before we go to alex jones on this so
the lilt seems to be extremely popular
you know and you mentioned the unique
terpene profile how would you describe
the terpene profile and are you going to
kind of find a mail and work it forward
um
yeah well i'm going to definitely work
the line um but at the moment i'm
getting really high percentages of that
female so i'm i was really happy with
that release
um
and everybody seems to be getting
um from a 10 pack they'll be getting
at least
four of the finos like the mother
and the other things are maybe like a
slight water down virgin tropical thing
some people are finding like a slight
fruity tropical cushy thing
that one was really nice
i
found that one was almost better than
the actual mother because it had this
like cushy
with the tropical taste which was really
really nice
but the main flavor from
the lil is like
if you get a tropical juice which has
got passion flower and pineapple in it
that's the dominant smell that i smell
off the plant and while the plant is
growing
it's by far the smelliest planter that
you'll come across in your room
but in a sweet
gentle sort of not like a strong stinky
way it's such a beautiful smell i just
love going into the room literally just
smelling it it's just so unique
um and then when it comes out as a dried
bud
the smell is
um
less in your face and a little bit more
subtle but when you smoke it you're left
with this like tropical taste on the
tongue like a tropical juice sonic says
it's like tin tropical fruits that's how
he describes it and i describe it like a
tropical juice
interesting and so do you have any kind
of plans in the works with sonics or are
you guys just kind of trading clones
no yeah we're definitely going to be
doing um
more work together in the future um
and he's going to be definitely bringing
out more pineapple crosses
looking at the cali schnapple
um the purse sang so yeah there's going
to be a lot of sonic stuff coming out of
the next year
sweet and so do you plan to continue
working with the mandarina or is that
kind of doing its thing on the back
burner while you do some little and
other things
um yeah um
everything takes so much time and
space and stuff like this so
yeah sometimes you have to just put
something aside for the time being but
the mandarina
will be
the next slot will be a feminized cross
um to bring back like the orange soda
the gingerbread
um
what else was there the mandarina kush
and i think maybe i can imagine a lot of
them being grown out in morocco and
places like this
so because they they loved all the hash
coming from that
um
so yeah they're great for the hash
production and stuff like this
hell yeah
so
the jungle kush hybrids in general
appear to be going pretty well received
what's your overall impression of them
in retrospect like if you could only
kind of recommend one to me which one
would you recommend besides the little
obvious choice
cherry spice that would be the one i
should put a caveat and ruled that out
as well
okay something else um
what am i really liking i've already
said about the sauna i'll go into more
deal about the sauna and a sour neo
that's something really special um
okay so
that was made using
um hortylabs sour power
um
clone and the sour diesel
which was selected by karma from
rezdog's
uh ibl sour diesel oh that's the one
he's done that bx2 with
yes
so
um
at the time when we were working
together that's when those seeds were
made and they were like a little limited
release
um
so i did a selection from those seeds
but they were all coming out very like
sour but then there was one
very unique one
um
which had this like sour twang but it
smells like grapefruit slightly when
it's growing but then when it finishes
off
you can't really smell the grapefruit in
it anymore and it turns into this like
sour antiseptic smell
which is like
it's absolutely amazing that's what i'm
smoking some of the outdoor from last
year of this
and
that's probably my favorite
it's not the prettiest plant to look at
like structure wise
but the flavor
like is amazing
and the extract made from it's amazing
the high is so strong um
like you smoke a few joints of that in
the evening and you're having the best
sleep of your life
like um
yeah all round
uh great plant
um and i've crossed that with my jungle
cush
to make the sour neo
um so
that that's a a real special one the
jungle kush mail as well is
just not very dominant in the crosses
so you get
mainly the phenos from the mother side
of things so when i crossed it with a
passion
uh flower everything comes out like
smelling like that tropical passion
flower sort of smell
the
when i crossed it with the cherry cookie
everything comes out like that cherry
cookie type of thing so it's it's it's
it's a really good mail to use
um
like i i've used it to cross with a few
other things to make like um the
um this was like a so the first line was
rose water cookie that's what rihanna is
that was crossed with the jungle push to
make the hundred hand slap
and then a male from 100 hand slapped
was used to go back to the reaction back
cross
and um
that's that's that's like a new line
that i'm just releasing i've also got a
clone that i selected which is the rhian
clone
and that's been passed around as well so
you should see a lot more of that around
this this coming year
oh yeah and how would you describe the
profile on that
um
like
okay
some people say it's like the mac
but with a bit more terps okay
but
like how i would describe it is like
slight
berry
but with like this cookie thing in the
background
um but you can definitely taste that
there's like there's something like
almost cushion there
it's it's it's a it's a nice
um
nice but it's not dominant in any one
one thing like it's not just pure gas or
it's not just pure cush you can taste
all these different undernotes with it
um so yeah it's it's a great one and i
named that after my mother
because you just when you grow it in the
room it just it just stands out from
everything else the growth pattern on it
is a little bit more unusual
all the branches sort of all come up to
a set sort of
uh place and it stays
um doesn't branch outwards it doesn't
like to grow wide
quite a sort of slender type plant
very interesting and so
the question i always have to ask what
kind of techniques you're using to kind
of identify your breeding males
um
i think
one of the main things with i think
selecting the males especially over time
yeah because you've grown so many
different plants over the years like
i've probably got thousands of different
plants and different smells and
structures and stuff like so you get to
see so much
so i think a lot of it just comes from
past
um experience past knowledge um feeling
um
and then obviously after all of that the
stem rub the structure at the time what
i'm looking for if if i'm looking for a
short structure and i want to make
something with a short structure then
i'm going to select the male with that
more
shorter structure so like little simple
things like this
but i think um
genetically is one of the main things
i that the male has to have come
from
[Music]
um plants that the females are all very
stable and that they're all very similar
so then you know that the male is going
to be very similar to the females if
you're picking a male from a pack of
seeds that has got
so many different
variations and phenos um
then
it's going to be harder to select
especially a terpene profile from that
male
so i think a terpene profile is one of
my main things with my last lots of
breeding that i've been doing
so
i'm trying to get if it something is is
like little then i want them all to be
like little and smelling tropical if i
want uh
the cherry spice i want them all with
that cherry spiced gas sort of smell
so
that's the lines i sort of go down
yeah okay so how many seeds do you like
to pop when you're looking to find your
new mail
it varies um
so i i can select a male from
one one packet of seeds because i'm
usually picking a male from something
that i've created myself
so
i already know both parents that have
been grown out from
many generate like
yeah many years
and
um
i know those plants like like the back
of my hand i know how they've worked
previously so
um
when when
i'm using stuff it's normally stuff that
i've already made myself
so i think that that's that's a big
thing
so
what about if you're going to use
someone else's stock how many packs
would you want to
grab well at least a couple of packets
but then if i'm not finding really good
um females from one packet
do i really want to use a male from that
packet to see what i'm saying
but obviously as if you're gonna do a
nice selection i'd be like 30 plants
to do a nice selection
okay and then as like a bit of a
follow-up to that how many seeds of each
strain if you had to guess would you say
generally get pop before you would say
australian is ready for market
okay yeah once once
i've i've grown it out and two or three
friends have said they really like it
then
that's that's like
ready to go
um
like the
last ones all them were really just
tested by me and one friend
um
the previous ones they were done by a
lot more people
um but i'm finding when i do actually
ask people to test things some people
can be quite slow so i'm literally just
quicker to test things myself
um
so as long as i'm getting
i test a couple of packets and i'm
getting really nice things from a couple
of packets
um
i'm happy with that but then
when i want to start writing down
percentages of phenotypes and stuff like
that that's only going to come with
more time
um
i'm really limited by space to be honest
um otherwise i would like to be
starting a lot more seeds yeah
you raise a really interesting point
there because
a lot of breeders seem to be doing
pretty much exclusively in-house testing
much to the same reason you gave that
testers are kind of inconsistent these
days
how do you feel about the idea that you
know a lot of packs that get sent out to
be tested just end up being added to
someone's seed bank
yeah um
i'm not going to say how much how much
i've sent out of like test seats and
free seats but we're talking like a lot
a lot a lot and a small fraction of the
percentage actually get grown out and
stuff it's it's quite sad
um i find
spanish guys are really good they'll get
a packet of seeds and they'll grow them
out yeah um in the uk if they get
something for free you know
that goes in their sea draw but if they
paid 500 for that packet that's getting
popped straight away
so
um
i'm definitely going to be doing
a different way of testing when i do
to the public i'm going to be using
breed bay in the future a lot more which
is a forum that we used to use
um i think i think it's now is the sort
of time to maybe
push that a little bit more and start
spending a bit more time on there i
think people are trying to grow from
instagram
and places like this where there's not
enough knowledge and
like
they need a place where people are
happy to share knowledge um
not going to
like
be horrible to the person if they ask a
silly question because
we were all young we were all learning
at one point
so you know um
i think a place like that's needed right
now so
for expert growers and new growers so
everybody can learn from each other and
a place where i can offer like
little limited releases to people to
test out
um
new um
lines
that i'm about to release and i want
them to just grow them out even if i've
tested them already it's good for other
people to see it and see what they think
so i think
breed bay is going to be the place where
a lot more of this is going to be done
and it'll be good to see people grow
them out and do little grow logs that's
what we used to do a lot more
um years ago you'd see people grow them
out they'd be talking about what ph
their um
their feeding amount how many
milliliters of this nutrient how many
meals of that nutrient exactly their
temperatures and they show it every week
they'd update and i think that's needed
now
um especially for anybody that's serious
about growing
serious about
um even breeding in the future once
they've collected a really nice library
and tested all their stuff out
um
and and to share knowledge like
there's so many things i've learned over
the years and
yeah i'm i'm happy to share all of this
with people
so i think breed bay is going to be the
new place for this
yeah i don't know i feel like it's hard
to get people back on forums because
it's like the idea's been thrown around
a lot but
it seems like you need more than just
the forum to get people on there do you
think there'll be like
other breeders kind of getting on there
which would incentivize it well okay
body's already on there he's got his own
little uh page a lot of people don't
even know this and professor p from
dynasty
he's beyond there he he's still got his
own section so all these guys will be
posting a lot more on there i'm gonna be
going back there sonic's gonna be there
um
so i think it's gonna be
um yeah an interesting little place a
little community let's see if it can
get it going like it used to be i think
there's enough new growers and people
that are serious about growing
that would like to join and
yeah
yeah and it's got a little chat even got
a little chat room on there so every day
people come in
have a chat in the little room any
questions they can see who's online they
can ask a little question and get get
the answer without anybody else coming
on and
being horrible or
missing the post because you post a post
on instagram but
nobody really looks past a couple of
posts and things like people just
flicking nowadays whereas people want to
be able to go back somewhere look at it
and learn something i think this is
missing i think people need to be
learning more reading more
yeah
so i think
it's time we we shall see
yeah okay
sounds g
kind of on that topic do you have any
plans to try to get your genetics out
kind of more into the international
distribution streams
yeah um well benson elvis which is like
a big farm in america
and they already grow
the orange soda mandarina kush um
they're doing the lilt now they're gonna
be doing more of the jungle juice
and they're popping the cherry spice and
things like that next
and they've been getting
um their product it made into extract
and yeah they're all loving over there i
think just more people need to try it i
think once more people try it
then we're gonna see this um
um
burst of uh trichome jungle tips
there's there's been a lot more people
growing out the lilt lately so there's
been some nice uh
batch of batches of it available in some
of the social clubs in barcelona and
stuff like that so that's been really
good to see
um i've even seen mandarina cush on
their menu in amsterdam
and they said that luke will be there
soon so that's really nice as well yeah
these are the little things that make me
smile
like when people um
uh
enjoy
the love and work i put into everything
so
yeah
oh yeah so
kind of
in that same vein this is one i've been
pondering a bit myself lately do you
believe like a breeder's responsibility
over their genetics extends past the
wholesaler like for example if someone
has an issue with your seeds is it kind
of your job or the whole settler's job
to fix that one
no i always tell
the wholesaler to tell them to
send me a message direct on instagram or
my email
um
because
um that way like i i i try to answer
every single message that i get because
um
i know what it was like when i was a
much younger and stuff like if i was
able to speak to breeder i think that it
would have been an amazing thing
so someone's growing
out my seeds and they've paid money to
to buy those seeds and support me
i think it's a little bit part of my job
to try my best to answer as many
questions as i can
but if someone is going to write me a
question i prefer to actually if they
write me a question
not just like hi how are you
like
it's hard to go through so many messages
but if there's a question there that i
can look read it through
a couple days later okay that's it
answer that question
that that's much easier for me
um but yeah um i enjoy doing it as well
especially if i have the extra time yeah
i don't mind doing it at all
yeah okay so how do you handle
complaints by customers like if someone
were to contact you and said they'd
grown your gear out and they'd have some
sort of issue maybe let's say it's like
hermed out or whatever
is your first response to kind of like
you know see if maybe something's up
with the garden
um
okay um
yeah i don't really
get too many but let's see somebody
might message me saying about
germination okay i get this a lot
germination now
all my seeds are fully
tested i test them like on a regular
basis as well
and
they they there's no problem with
germination now i will ask the person
like you know try and figure out what
their problem was i see in winter time
we we get a lot more problems with
germination so
it just shows that it is environment
stuff but i will try to send them a
couple of extra seeds to try and make up
for that just so
they're happy i want everybody to be
happy
um if someone said to me something
hermed and they sent me some pictures
and all of this um
i might be inclined to send them a
packet so they are happy at the end but
um i think a lot of things comes down to
environment
um
we grow out so many
uh different varieties ourselves you
must come across this yourself even in
packs that have been you've grown out
grown out and then maybe you might find
one that hurts or puts out some bananas
it does happen especially if you're
using things like
sour diesel
um
cherry pie things like that which have a
tendency to do it
so
um
yeah it happens
and if i can send him a packet of c to
make him happy then i i will do this
yeah
yep cheers grandma but uh anyway um what
type of lighting are you using at the
moment
um good eaters
um
just because um i got them a couple of
years ago um i'm just still using them
at the moment
um
when i get my new place that will
they'll be changed um i've been looking
into some leds at the moment as well
and
because i'm seeing some quite good
results for them i'd like to just try
them out myself just just as a little
test
um i think that could be something good
for the future with the energy
consumption and stuff like this
but um
outdoors is um
is the way using the sun
yeah
so how are things in spain at the moment
is the laws evolving to kind of cater
more to breeders or is it still a case
of like you know out of sight out of
mind type of thing
yeah like that basically um i've had a
few little run-ins and yeah not the best
of luck to be honest um
but uh
yeah they're still far from being legal
out here so far from it but it's like
amsterdam isn't it like
they have all that in the coffee shops
but how it's produced is all the gray
area isn't it so hmm so
what country would you recommend
aspiring breeders to look to if they
were going to relocate because people
often talk about spain
um
spain is it is definitely going to be uh
the future i i can see it
but
for
at the moment
yeah i think there's still a long way to
go
but then you look to america and they've
gone legal there and everyone's like oh
no they've gone legal now so it
i think
how spain's got it with
the
clubs i think they just need to be
accepted
if they can be
um accepted by a
court of law
and
uh the production for the clubs can be
accepted
some papers can be brought in
so it's almost like
decriminalizing it to some extent
um i think that could really work
yeah okay
so with that being said do you see a
viable future for a person from like a
currently illegal country
to move to spain try to set themselves
up create themselves a job in the
industry over there or do you just think
it's too prohibitive to just do that
um
i think anybody should come out to spain
first
and then check it out and see
how they feel about it spend a few weeks
here
um
see
the clubs speak to the people and i
think you you can
most people would be able to judge it
themselves and how they feel about the
situation
so do you approach it with the view of
like
a producer or a breeder because in my
mind it seems like you could just kind
of be off in the background doing your
own thing and hopefully no one bothers
you right
yeah that's what i try to do but then
um
i live really out in the country so it's
a tiny little place
and
i stand out a little bit
um
yeah
i've drawn attention to myself and the
police have asked questions and stuff
like this and
so i had to pack things down and move
them and it's been a lot of hassle for
me
but
it's it's worked out good in the end
but yeah it's a lot of
a lot of work
um how it's portrayed on the internet
like spain's is totally legal place and
you can grow weed here and stuff that
was uh
was how it was portrayed to me when i
first moved here
and i found out very quickly that it
wasn't like that
yeah okay so i want to play devil's
advocate for a moment here if for some
reason you had to leave spain and move
to another country which one would you
move to
canada
you say that like you're ready to do it
right now
um
i don't know like i think canada
sort of does appeal to me i can't see
myself going there to live though to be
honest
um i like the sunshine in spain i like
the weather
the people are really nice
um
yeah so i can't see myself moving moving
to canada
but i think if anybody is free to do
what they they want and they're looking
at moving to a country
i think canada there could be a lot of
opportunities in canada coming up
so i mean given you are a breeder in
spain a little bit unrelated but kind of
is there the same explosion of breeders
over there in the same sense that we see
in america and the rest of the world
um
yeah there has been a little bit um but
i'm seeing
some people they're
getting like as many sort of clones as
they come together
um
or even just plants that other people
have selected
and then
um
pollinate them
with a male
and
or reversing a plant and pollinating
them and then selling the seeds
not tested
never growing out any of the parents and
i'm just like it's just for real so yeah
like it's there's a lot of
people making seeds now
um
and
[Music]
putting any
any names and
yeah it's all gone a bit crazy to be
honest
um
is that what you sort of mean like lots
of slight seed companies popping up with
no tech real testing and stuff like this
yeah i mean that's definitely one part
of it but i was also curious
sometimes you hear about like big seed
producers over there like i think
dynafem does something over there or
something like that like do you know
anything about that
yeah no i don't know too much about that
but i i can imagine yeah there's a lot
of people over here producing seeds for
their companies and stuff like this so
yeah
yeah interesting there's the horror
stories always relate back to spain
somehow
yeah yeah no there's a lot of um
people use spanish guys uh to make their
seeds
um
yeah many many of the big companies yeah
that's it
so while we're on the topic of
going through seeds making parents how
many plants do you tend to cull before
you find like a keep a female and when
you find your kind of clone onlys
does it happen often from a 10 pack or
given you're at like you know the higher
breeder level do you do these larger
scale searches
now you can do all your selection from a
10 pack
um
it all depends on what you're using it
so
like i said before if you're not finding
really great things from a tent pack
like
yeah you want to be finding some real
nice stuff
um obviously if you start and then
from
uh you find something special and you
really want to look
down that line more
starting
another 500 seeds of that one type is
worth doing to find something really
special again and work that line
um i'm going to be doing a lot more work
with the
a lil mail soon so there'll be a lot of
little hybrids i've just done
the little with the
jungle kush but then
this is more like a little bit of like a
back cross so it's more watered down you
get like this fruity crush thing coming
out so i definitely want to add
the lil with a few different things i've
got planned
and then
from them do some selection and work the
lines the same as i'm going to do with
the
afghan hybrids
we'll see how they come out in the first
generation but each line is going to
really need to be worked
to find something um to get something
that you can release
i forgot to ask what were the females of
the afghan lion like
okay um
okay the male smelt much better than
females
the male had this like uh grapefruit
smell going on but the females were more
on
like how i said about the indian spiced
aniseed smell
it had this thing i could smell it in
the afghans as well
so it's like this
it just reminds me of like a lot of old
school stuff i've had before
even my nap that i had in the past which
made the mantis
that had that aniseed
like hindu kush type smell going on
so
um
yeah it's definitely definitely along
those lines
and do you have any information about
what area the afghans came from
yeah they're from bulk province
and
near mazar sharif
but we've got
like
i've got some here but then between all
of us now he sent a lot more so we've
literally got seeds from
every province and place in afghanistan
and which one excites you the most the
ones i've got at the moment to be honest
but then
i'm going to be getting a few different
uh
different ones so we'll see like some
people are getting ones that are like a
lot more cabbage looking like the leaves
like really really fat so and those ones
were the
you know i'd have to go and look because
i can't remember right now
but there's somebody else that was
growing them that i seen on instagram
but from the same
farmer that he collected from another
farm
in another uh area
so
yeah
i think this year's gonna be the year of
the afghan there's gonna be a lot of
afghan seeds being grown out from
different areas so it's gonna be really
interesting to see i'm already seeing so
many different variations from the
different people growing them
so
have you ever thought of like rounding
up a whole bunch of afghan clones kind
of doing like what bodhi did with like
the deep line alchemy and like just
hitting all these afghans with like this
cool afghan male
yeah i think there could be a a lot of
different things going on and people
sharing a little bit pollen so they can
hit this one and things like this yeah
this is this will be happening
cool cool and so what type of satives do
you want to hit with the afghan
eventually
um
yeah the malawi seeds i'm definitely
going to pop them
and
some of the south american stuff we'll
see how they come out
but i think malawi's i don't know
there's just something about that pack
of malawi that's just
crying to me to pop them so
we'll see what happens with them
and i don't think ever asked what would
you use as the final sativa component
for your skunk
um
i don't
i don't know that may maybe something
south american again
or a thai it all depends it all depends
um
but we've got so many different things
to go through
um
like on on the trip to india there was
like
not just me sonic there was a guy hit
from himalayan connection some other
guys
um
so they've also got some real nice stuff
in their collection things like this so
the
we we've got so many different things to
pick from we've got like some real nice
sativas even from india and stuff like
that so
yeah
um
the library is uh
is very vague at the moment between all
of us
okay so just to kind of play devil's
advocate then again
what type of genetics would you like to
see come back into kind of the community
that kind of aren't really around at the
moment
um
[Music]
some more nice really fruity things
just uh things with
uh
something a little bit more unusual
turkey and profile
um i don't think there's any like
particular
line i'd like to bring back i'd like to
see a lot more
uh maybe some of sonic's
pineapple hybrids
he had one called pine queen which was
absolutely amazing if he brings that
back it'll blow people's minds it was
such a beautiful plant
so um
yeah i'd like to see some of them
from the old school i'd like to see some
hash plants coming back that's why i'd
like to
work with the
afghans and their
uh milana plants
so we can uh
make a nice
hush plant
yeah definitely and so do you feel like
it's inherently a part of those plants
that you get kind of that more cbn more
sedative type of high or not necessarily
yeah no that's what i'm looking for in
in this hash pan type thing something
that literally you you get halfway down
that spliff and it just
knocks you out you want to go to sleep
that's what i'm looking for
and that's why i think it's going to be
interesting with the bubba kush because
the bubba kush
has got that
more
medicinal
sedative type of height to it especially
if you just flow it out that extra week
like
it's such a beautiful smoke and i've
crossed that with the afghan so
um span abysses is is next week so um
a week after so
um
i might take a few of those seeds with
me to give out to a couple of people to
test out
um
gonna do like uh
release of the little again there
because they just sold out so fast
everybody went crazy for them
so doing another release of them
and then um
i'll probably be working the line a lot
more then and doing some nice little
hybrids
are you gonna have your own booth at
spanish
no no i'm not gonna be doing a booth
most of the booths have been already
like taken or that so
i'm just doing like i did them the
previous year where i'll do an evening
event in
a club each night so friday night in one
club saturday night in another club
and the final night in uh
another club and just do little
um
seed release there and it's good
actually it's a little bit more personal
people are coming there to like sort of
see you and that so it's nice to talk to
the people sit down
show them some of the different
um
flower and stuff like this um yeah it's
it was a really good evening so i'm
doing in three different clubs this year
but i'll still be at the expert in the
daytime
sounds like you're gonna have to swing
by my buddy lucky dog seeds get some kem
dog
yeah okay is he there is he oh
yeah skunk va
okay do you know what number buffy that
you have to send me a message after if
you find out yeah dude go get some of
them hybrids my friend sent me a bud
shout out burke um
a while back and i only just finished
smoking it today it was so strong it
just lasted me forever
okay nice nice yeah i love to check them
out
is there anyone else you want to check
out there
um
do you know what i i just it's i got
time to go just to meet up with her
old friends and um
some new friends and stuff like that so
um there's never ever enough time to see
everybody there's always somebody that i
miss and stuff like that
so i'll try and see as many people as
possible there's a few clubs that have
got some lilt and stuff like that in
there so they told me to come by have a
look at it
so
yeah it'll be interesting it'll be nice
to
um
see what people have produced from the
seeds from last year and stuff like this
yeah
are there people like
like selling clones there and stuff like
in the states or not really
no nothing like this
so just like flower and concentrate
yeah you go go to
just one of the social clubs you could
be a member of the clubs and then you
can
get access to that
but most people sort of like bring their
own little bit of smoke and
smoking everyone's smoking quite openly
and quite a relaxed environment
but i've heard high times have just
brought it out
so span a base now he's been bought by
high times
so from this year on is going to be
or span of this high times whatever i
don't know what they'll call it
but yeah i can see it probably changing
a little bit after this year
and so how do you feel about high time
zoning and you think like whatever or
not
good
whatever but i can't see it being um
[Applause]
well previous things it's just it all
changes isn't it and then it all
everybody is just all about whoever
pays the most gets gets the cup and all
of this sort of stuff it's just all
changes
so
um for 2020 spanner this time and a few
people i know are gonna put a nice
little
cup upon at the same sort of time so
that's going to be a nice like
um
more transparent cup anyway you'll get
to see all the votes and everything so
that'll be quite good
um and during spamabis anyway there's
always other little cups on like they've
got the
masters of rosin
and
uh
what's that um legends of hash
that bubble man and them always put on
so there's always little other events
going on so
should be good for
this year next year
do you ever
get sick of any of the egos
yeah there's always egos and it's
getting worse but yeah i just laugh
it's good makes me smile and laughing's
good for your body
so
if people make me laugh yeah it's
beneficial to me
yeah i can imagine you'd have a blast at
one of those events
i'm always smiling
um
so
how important do you think it is to
produce kind of medically potent strains
you know i'm not just talking about cbd
i mean kind of like the example that's
been weighing in my mind is um my good
buddy stray fox he pointed out that
although the pre-98 bubba is arguably a
better smoke you know probably no one
will distribute that
the katsu cut it's far more medicinal
you know so with that in mind do you
think it's important that we like try to
breed with these types of things like
for the medicinal value or do you think
it's just of kind of inconsequential
because the markets just mostly wreck
um
yeah i think because like i go down more
the flavor and stuff like that because
it's the
like that's what i like about it so much
but the high really does come into it
and the bubba is
such a medicinal strain that whenever i
um
crossed it into things in the past i'd
always sort of
um
put that in the description because
every time you added bubba into things
the height of the the the offspring
would always come out with that
beautiful bubba type high added to it
and it was it was definitely felt in the
legs
like such a relaxing type of smoke and
people with back pain and things like
this yeah enjoy it so much
so
i think so many people do use it
medicinally but don't realize it we say
recreational but if it makes you feel
happy and your well-being
is good
that's medicinal if it helps your stiff
joints or you've got a little bit of
pain in the neck or it helps you to
relax your body after work
this is all medicinal
so i think
so many people do actually use it in a
medicinal way but don't actually realize
it
yeah okay and so do you think there
should be any distinction or do you
think just greater education
greater education yeah um i think that's
the main thing because we even know even
with
you're growing something from seed it's
it's not always going to be exactly
how you imagine it you get different
variations in the seeds
um so i think educating people about
um
all these different
compounds
genetics
the terpenes i think that's that's
that's uh
a big thing yeah
and so what field of research would you
like to see cannabis expand more into
then
um
testing
like it like just testing for
terpenes
and
uh all the other chemicals
in the plants
um
and like there's just so many things
that we come to conclusions but we can
never really
um fully back them up unless we test
so i think seeing a lot more
testing and
tissue culture i'd like to see
how things go with the tissue culture
and like we were talking about
getting rid of
genetic diseases or getting rid of
just normal diseases you know with the
tissue culture you're producing
a totally clean
um
clump
of of the mother
so i think that's one good thing i see
so many people passing clones and that's
how you pass disease so
one thing i do not take in his clones
yeah so
do you just
everything's from seed more or less
everything's from cd so i could actually
i like all everything that i i use
now the only clone that i have in my
library right now
is the bubba kush
um
everything else is clones i've selected
myself
from seed originally
or
new things i've selected from seeds
and yeah so i only do things i've
selected from seeds
from now on
it's the best way yeah you know you're
you're you're clean from any other
external influences
so how long will it take you on average
before you find a new keeper like for
example if you're doing a crop every you
know let's just say three months to be
on easy number side you finally won each
cycle you're finding two you're finding
one every two cycles what's your numbers
like
all depends on on what i'm starting um
so
from if i'm starting
10 different varieties okay
um
i'll find three or four nice keepers but
then
the other things are still nice i'm
finding because then i'll i'll pass them
out to people
and
they'll be like i can't believe you're
getting rid of this and i'm like well
yeah just it's not something i'm going
to use
so
um
yeah
there's so many keepers like i'm finding
the more different breeders that you pop
things from as well you find so much
different flavors and smells
um
so
yeah
um
so
so which breeders work are you most
excited to look into
um
would you know what i had got some stuff
from mad farmer he sent me some nice
seeds over and i haven't had the chance
because they literally came at the time
when i had all the
um problems just after that where to
move everything
and then
after that i was about to pop them but i
had to just give them a back seat for a
little bit um
because i was i had to just pop all my
own stuff because things just needed
testing but
really um i would have liked to pop some
of his seats so they're next on the list
but i've got um a few things that i've
picked out for the next room
and
i didn't i did uh
they were picked out with some other
things for a run but yeah i just
had to test all the other stuff all the
things i've been making
yeah definitely okay not a bad selection
so
um
i've noticed on your ig that you've been
playing around with some kind of cell
culturing yourself some along those
lines what you've been doing
yeah it's i classic more like micro
cloning really okay
but um
yeah you're basically taking
um a small amount of the plant tissue
and then you grow it in a
sugar solution
so the plants
making instead of it doing the
photosynthesis and the
getting the sugar from the light you
it's getting the sugar from the solution
as long as you've got no bacteria in
there
then the bacteria can't grow on the
sugar and eat the sugar so everything
has to be super sterile
that's the main thing with it um
and then i'll grow it to
tissue stage where it starts to grow
leaf tissue
and
the
the root will calyx up
but then i'll transfer to another
solution which will be then for the root
growth
um
but the reason i got into the tissue
culture was because i had to move
everything
so when i moved everything i thought
okay if i'm going to do this i'm going
to get a tissue culture
kit and
i'm going to
do this as an extra backup
so
there i did two extra backups of tissue
culture and
moved my mothers to a safe location
so um
yeah so it all worked out and i i
learned something new and i've been
experimenting with that a little bit
um
there's a couple of guys that i'm
speaking to on instagram and one of them
so knowledgeable in this field
and he's bringing out a kit
very soon
and um
i think that's going to be something
that
um a lot of people will really enjoy um
using an experiment in
um same again like
people looking
beyond
just the money and want to learn more
about the plant or plants in general the
science behind them
and um i think these kits are going to
be amazing for them and he's got he's
done them so they're in like a little
bag
and the bag is like a sterile
environment which is going to really
help
people at the beginning stage of doing
tissue culture
so um i'll be doing a post on my
instagram page about that and um
i'm sure he'll be have putting some
links up about the the kits and stuff
like that so
um
maybe you can get him to send you one so
you can try it out if you've never tried
it out yourself
what's the success rate on it like well
okay
well i've been getting pretty much
hundred percent yeah okay
um the only time i haven't is where i've
done little tests so
i've got one out and i've breathed into
the pot okay
and closed the lid just simple things
like this are going to contaminate it so
you've got to wear a mask and stuff like
this so
so the first batch
10 got contaminated
okay the second second time
maybe five percent and then after that
really i don't have any problems
but i've seen even seen in labs where
they've got total sterile environment
they still have five percent sometimes
losses and stuff like this
yeah no
so it happens in the cleanness of
environments
so um
yeah but
as long as you're you're doing
everything super clean and that's why
these kits are going to be really good
with the bag
so you've got a sterile environment
inside the bag i think that's going to
be really good
yeah that sounds cool sounds like you're
kind of getting down to the point where
you're almost doing the meristem
culturing yourself do you ever plan to
do that type of thing or go to labs for
it well no this is what this other guy
is um he's like been experimenting with
all of this stuff so
and he's even so doing like talking
about literally
cells um
just floating in the solution and even
to the point where maybe even um
breeding in uh
in um
test tubes so
we
will see where it all leads in the
future
breeding in a test tube geez ibf seeds
it's more and for me it's more just
educating myself and learning these
things
um
same again like this plant's just
teaching me so much now we're going down
the lines of like a total new line of
genetics
so
yeah
all um
very interesting stuff
learning something new every day
that's another thing i've been really
getting into my a little bit more
creative side
so
you know spending a little bit more time
doing that
um
and i don't know if you've seen in the
new mahakala just like a little limited
thing i've done for spannabis so like a
little limited seed packet all like
little handmade so
they were quite good doing them
oh yeah yeah i've seen you've been
getting your little micro carpentry on
yeah that's it yeah yeah keeping busy
being creative keeping the mind busy so
it's good with the plants and stuff like
that but sometimes we need to
express ourselves in other ways and
learn
learning i think it's good to learn
something new every day
that's it
yeah i did i love it man i love learning
so
i got some weird questions but i want to
bang them out so first one when will we
see a cbd project from you i'm
interested it's due
um
maybe when things change in spain and
i can
yeah i find a location to start doing a
lot more growing and breeding like the
cbd you can actually do out here and
stuff like that and i had some friends
that uh grow legal cbd
and
so
it might be something in the future that
i could work with them but
thc and
is one of my main things it's the high
that these plants produce and
that that thc and the terpenes is just
so special for me
um
the cbd i think there's other people in
other fields
that um
make good cbd i can continue with that
i'll stick with my
terpene rich thc plants
so i mean in a similar idea how do you
think we as a community can cater to the
casual smokers and i mean like
this is kind of stemming from the fact
how i was saying you know like i've cut
my consumption down and god just like
i can't even have more than one hit and
i'm just gone like i need that
i'm like i feel like that old person
who's like weeds too strong these days
so like i'm trying to figure out like
how can you make kind of like more tangy
type of strains where it like tastes
good but doesn't destroy yeah
well you you'd like the little yeah the
looks like this so there are some
females that you smoke and they just
like knock you out but i'd say the
majority of the tropical ones
um have this like beautiful euphoric
higher people will be smoking and people
will be giggling and that
i just i think i think this is going to
be the
the perfect strain for summer and how
we've got spring coming soon
and somewhere just around the corner i
think it's going to be a
perfect strain for those
sunny days and
summer activities yeah i think this is
what's needed
yeah okay
so a bit of a weird one but i wanted to
ask your opinion because i think we've
spoken about this in kind of the dms but
there was like a scientific paper which
came out the other day and it's like
actually detailing how you can use
cannabis to help people wean off harder
drugs like meth and opioids
is that any surprise to you at all
no no because i've seen so many people
that have been in the cannabis community
and
ended up growing
and this plant again teaching them so
much and they changed their way of life
here and
the cannabis has given them something
else to keep their mind occupied
to give them a feeling that they can
relax
and stuff like this so i i see i've seen
it a lot where people have had previous
uh
drug addictions and they turn to
cannabis and it's helped them through
even just growing the plant never mind
taking a plant
the plant taking the plant has helped
them amazingly but growing it the whole
thing the therapeutic
use and the therapeutic property you get
from just gardening
yeah changing the lifestyle
yeah okay
so
what type of growth style have you been
using lately
um okay so
with the
um
last batch these are all bio tabs with
the seeds i'm doing
and
the ones before that were all on coco
because i was running some tests with ph
and stuff like this
um
the afghan is definitely like the a much
higher ph
so
um
this is a handy thing with instagram
both the guy from milan village is on
instagram
the farmer and the guy from afghanistan
so i could actually like message him or
get my other mate to message the other
guy in
because he can speak to him
in his language
and get some answers and that and stuff
like this so that's been quite
interesting
but it's not something that they really
check is the ph and stuff like that but
from a little bit more discussion i
found that is much higher ph there and i
found that with growing them here they
just really reacted better with a much
higher ph
yeah okay cool and what other little
interesting nicks or quirks have you
found about them which you kind of
helped cater to like they like a higher
soil temperature or like medium i should
say
okay another thing that i would do with
them i started some of the seeds
okay
left in low low level light above the to
below the canopy
okay just to see how they react
and
plucked a few out
of the soil stripped the roots down and
replanted them and they still grew it
okay
so it just shows how hardy these plants
are you can pull a plant out of the soil
break all the small tiny roots off where
you're just leaving the main tape room
replant it and the plant
carries on growing
okay so this is just little tests to
show how i see how hardly some of these
genetics are that are grown
in these places at these altitudes and i
think adding them into some of my
genetics and growing them outdoors
i think this is where i'm going to see i
didn't see one bit of powdery mildew in
all of their fields i've seen powdery
mildew on other plants around them
but not on the cannabis not one spot
anywhere which was absolutely crazy i
thought
whereas when people go to morocco it's
everywhere there
so
um
[Music]
these hybrids that people grow
in places have problems whereas the
natural
um
varieties from from that area don't have
the problems
so i think this is going to be something
to look into resistance range for the
future
yeah definitely something of huge
interest to a lot of people i want to
pull you back to something you said
there the moroccan valley two questions
one do you think a lot of the hash that
comes out of there
has become from plants with pm and like
you know i guess we should be worried
and the other thing is
have you seen that photo from the dna
guys how they got like
that valley and the roof full of like
kosher tangy or something like how do
you feel about that
yeah see well they had a load of
mandarina things uh gingerbread out
there at one point and mandarina kush
and stuff like this
it's been happening for so long it was
amnesia not long ago before that it was
some pakistani strains that they were
growing and mexican strains and people
were also saying
cheese they were growing loads of cheese
out there so things have been grown out
there for a long time um
so i think
that's just how it is after the whole
hashish thing in in morocco isn't
like it goes back generation after
generation
it is it's a
it's a new thing that was started from
people bringing seeds back from other
hash producing countries and stuff like
this so
um
yeah it's just a
progression i think and that's what's
going to happen they want to produce
more hash and these hybrids do it
so
yeah it's happening you go to jamaica
it's all hybrids in jamaica
um
so
yeah this happens
how accountable do you hold dutch
genetics and the dutch breeders for
these issues
well the the dutch seed market was a big
part of the market and at one time it
was only dutch seeds there wasn't really
any american companies or anybody else
around to buy seeds from
so you could say dna are they american
or are they dutch
yeah they're american but their company
was in holland so
yeah
um
yeah they bought seeds where they could
buy seeds
it doesn't matter if they're from dutch
or from spanish people or
they'll buy the seeds i think to grow
that
and what i've even heard that they grow
the seeds out one year
and the second year they grow the seeds
from those seeds but the third year they
don't do it
so
yeah
and that's getting promised by anything
so
um
yeah it's all about it it's just hash
production isn't it absolutely that's
that's another thing i suppose when you
start going legal
we move away from that sort of thing
yeah it's a bit crazy so
unrelated
oh no kind of related i don't know
do you plan to make a variety of other
feminized seeds or just kind of the the
one-off clone here and there that really
proves itself yeah no i want to make
some more feminized seeds um because
people want those um orange turps sort
of mandarine turps and feminized seeds
and like i said before
i can probably see them grow being grown
out in morocco and things like this
like
um
like you said tanji there's something
tanji over there and stuff like this
so
another little indoor type of question
what's your prediction for the future of
the lighting technology
um i can see a lot more people going
over towards uh
leds
i think um
just for power consumption and stuff
like this
um
but
yeah
like i said before though i've been
using gavitas but i'll probably change
um
soon i'm looking into a few different
ones myself at the moment
uh lumitec things like that so we'll see
see what i go for in the end
okay so a bit of a hot topic at the
moment in the community but how do you
feel about the idea of patenting
genetics and strains within the industry
and
how do you kind of think this would work
in regards to your own work
i think
patenting anything
in this day and age
is all [ __ ] to be honest
but
that's just my opinion
yeah it's a plan at the end of the day
so
if someone buy
buy the seeds off you
um
or if we're talking clones and it all
depends what you're talking but yeah i
think it's going to be a very hard thing
what you're going to have a court case
over it
it's just yes
just more
i needed stress i think
yeah i just wanted to ask you one other
question about when you're in india did
you at any point kind of think of any
modern hybrids or you thought this would
do well here
yeah but i think if we
yeah i wouldn't want to take anything
there
and then
you know that they would start growing
here and you know they would save the
seeds from here so
i think
taking anything there would sort of
destroy their genetics i think keeping
it as it is is the best way
um and not to take anything there
um but i think a lot of things would do
well then yeah
oh yeah i meant more like theoretically
like is there any clones in your library
that you like just could off the top of
your head be like yeah that'll do well
there
person hates the person hayes from sonic
i think
um
i worked with that line a bit and
it's a field full of that update would
be absolutely amazing
yeah wow
[Music]
so what do you feel about the idea of
kind of these genetically modified
strains to have like specific
cannabinoid and terpene profiles
um
in what way genetically modified like
proper genetically modified you're
talking about yeah
um i don't know i don't think there's
any need for it i think
we could we can do it all with selection
time and space
yeah
it's already happening
yeah yeah it's not something that i i i
would uh agree with it
yeah
yeah binting to see how it all plays out
um
so i did want to ask one question about
the cup i should have asked that earlier
you know how we kind of implied like
some cubs
it's kind of pay to play or pay to win
how would you feel if at one of those
cups that you really thought was kind of
like you know you got to pay to get
somewhere
like you just won like would it restore
your faith in the competition we'd be
like i guess it's not rigged yeah it
would probably change my opinion what i
tend to see is like
third place tends to be the real sort of
like the winner and the first two are
the people that have like paid the most
for
um sponsorship or whatever
but yeah if if that happened
yeah i'd be uh
i thought i would have to look a little
bit differently
something i wanted to ask you what's the
weirdest plant mutation you've ever seen
um
i think one that i see a lot is like um
you know the flat stem thing
yeah yeah plant fasciation yeah that's
it yeah um
that way you get like the almost like
the mohawk style bud at the top or like
four stems where there should be two and
stuff like this
but i've seen a lot of like where you
get the bud growing from the middle of
the leaf
yeah um
the i've seen one recently i think it
was dna genetics put it up
and it was like a leaf with like
actually on the actual leaves not in the
center of the leaf on the leaves itself
there was little buddlers coming out
so little calyx is growing from that so
um
i've i have recently had a male with a
male parts grown from the center of the
leaf
and
there was some guys in
uh
one line i can't remember a freak show
okay it was called freak show i don't
know if you've seen this one
yeah yeah i seen that one yeah that one
was absolutely crazy but i've never come
across anything like that myself
um i've had things come out similar to
like the duck spot
where they have that like webbing almost
on the leaves
um
and yeah i think they're the sort of
main mutations that i've come across
yeah definitely just in case anyone
wasn't aware of that freak show thing
you can go look it up but what i found
most interesting was it actually that
plant and i think there was a male or
two that also had similar traits it
actually came from a pack of coastal
seeds shout out bob
and the crew over there and it was like
a
uh what was it big sir
hybrid so i was like oh that's
interesting because big sur is like a
weird one already like some people think
it's kind of auto flowering even though
it's like a photo period one so maybe we
need to push some of these weird
genetics a bit harder
yeah um i spoke to those guys with the
freak show but they're working that line
themselves um doing some stuff so it'd
be interesting to pop some of those
seeds
um i think definitely people need to
when they find that maybe work it a
little bit more so they
so it actually becomes a little bit of a
unusual line
i think that's just more for like
just
the fun and educational side of things i
would like to do that
maybe it can have a place where it could
be grown where people don't want the
typical leaves to be seen i think maybe
that's the only i think
uh purpose that
it could be used for really
yeah like a better version of australian
bastard cannabis the abc because i'm
pretty confident this uh freak show
one's probably got a better high
yeah they were saying it's got some nice
terps to it as well so but i can see a
lot of people wanting to buy that still
you know just to grow out
yeah it's something something that uh
inspector from csi has taught me is that
as little commercial value as some of
these mutations may have they're still
very interesting and worth preserving
and trying to progress because who knows
what's locked inside and which may be of
use later on
yeah yeah exactly exactly
anybody that collects seeds i'm sure
they'd want to buy a packet maybe to put
in their library or something like this
yeah or as we're talking it last time
they uh
collect a packed test and it ends up in
the library
yeah yeah exactly
oh gosh okay so do you feel like viruses
specific to cannabis are going to
increase given you know the large-scale
commercialization that's going to occur
throughout the world in the coming years
yes that will happen
um
i think
breeding maybe more resistant strains
and stuff like that one thing i've been
even looking into is like
breeding a line
that's uh
uh can produce
the same amount
and same growth rates on less water and
less nutrients
so like almost like an eco weed i think
that'll be maybe something for the
future
yeah right it was almost like trying to
get that uh trait out of hemp and put it
back into the medicinal cultivar
yeah that's it yeah that's it
yeah so there's always like i think um
like you said the commercial thing is
always going to bring more uh
problems and those problems will become
resistant to things that people use
and yeah stronger so harder to get rid
of in the end
which is a which will be a big problem i
can see
so with that being said if you were
given the opportunity to grow a field of
say lil or mandarina
in the moroccan roof valley would you
capitalize on it or would it be a hard
pass
i think people are gonna buy the seeds
anyway
um
so
uh
whether
they buy them from morocco or spain the
seeds get sold um
i've yeah they've already done some
mandarina cush out there and
what else was it orange soda and
uh i'm trying to think what else uh
gingerbread so
there's been a few things growing out
there and people send me photos and
stuff like this so yeah
interesting and how would you predict
that it would change the uh the overall
effect of those plants because earlier
on you mentioned that
um you know when you got some seeds from
the uh the mountains and grew them back
here they're much more kind of squat and
indica like compared to when they're in
the mountains so in the reverse
situation how do you think your plants
would come out when grown there do you
think they'd be more sativa or yeah give
us your ideas
yeah a little bit but they they
the gingerbread's a little bit more
indica in structure anyway the other
ones are a bit more sativa
but the
terpenes um
yeah they retain terpenes so well with
the conditions that they grow them and
dry them and all of this sort of stuff
so
it uh puts up with those conditions and
makes some of the best hash that's come
out of that like
yeah
i think one of the guys got the first
place in the monsters cup in the span
abyss last year
so
yeah amazing hatch amazing hunch gets
produced from there
so what strain so far that you've been
able to experience makes the best hash
the gingerbread and the orange soda the
orange soda from the colada
they it was some amazing hash amazing
hush i really enjoyed
that yeah wow and then so what are kind
of some of the old school strains of
yesteryear that you'd like to see come
back
the afghanis they're coming back already
i'm seeing so many people growing them
so um we're going to see a lot more
old-school hash plants i've been coming
back
these coming years
um
and i even can see some of the old
sativas coming back just because of the
high that they produce
because uh
yeah something special in them so i can
see
the sativas coming back some maybe like
old african stuff
do you think that it's arguably
inevitable that we do move towards a
more sativa orientated customer base
within the community given that of
course depressants in general alcohol
opioids there's a huge market for them
but when i look at things globally seems
like overall more people worldwide are
kind of into stimulants than
antidepressants yeah i think a lot of
people that i know
like the more indicas just because they
use it to relax
and they use it to chill out
um
maybe
get into like artwork and stuff like
that it puts you into like a mum sort of
meditative sort of state
um but i really like the sativas as well
like i just enjoy them for the daytime
and i find that i can like really get
into anything that i'm doing whether it
be in the garden or in the house
creating something or
cooking or anything i'll just really get
fully into it with this with the sativas
so what's your favorite sativa
from from my lines at the moment like i
like the the high from the lil it's such
a sort of
beautiful
up high um really sort of gets mind
mind-blowing creative
um
yeah but from the past
um i i like sonic's per sang haze that
for me sort of just
was such a
beautiful smoker
enjoyable
um
such like
uh pie again
sort of gets
the mind thinking
yeah
really really nice one
yeah cool so i wanted to talk to you
about hazes like what like the term haze
is used as a general term because
obviously not every haze has the
original haze or even necessarily a
derivative haze in it do you just feel
like haze is kind of a term for like a
few land race sativas kind of doing
their thing together
um
yeah i think haze now is
seems to be
any sativa that smells a certain way
with this like hazy spicy sort of smell
that
people sort of associated with
um
but yeah i find
like
a lot of things have that similar sort
of spice but they're more on that dry
side and so
yeah
they vary
yeah that that terpene profile is so
common isn't it that haze one and i
remember being able to smoke some of uh
what was it the c5 haze with bodhi and
the first thing that came to mind when i
exhaled i was like who would have
thought you know c5 haze tastes like
haze
yeah this is a it's um what was the one
i was smoking a bit of uh c4 i think it
was
is there a c4
i'm not sure it could could well be but
yeah there's quite a few different ones
but like they all have that
underlining
yeah haze terpene it's almost like a
spiced thing that's how i would describe
it
yeah yeah more more spice than just a
pure mango thing but when you smell it
you immediately kind of go yeah this is
where it all delineates from right
yeah
you see that smelling there's so many
like different land races as well
yeah
um
i've come across that in in so many
different lines
uh from like caribbean and colombian a
lot of colombian stuff over that way and
south american stuff i've smelled it
from
yeah okay south american that's one that
hasn't really been too delved into is
that something you're looking to explore
at all
what a little trip to south america yeah
if it needs to happen it gotta happen
right yeah
we'll be talking about our trip to
afghanistan
so
um
afghan black honey black yeah he's he's
saying come out there alex want is well
up for it from landry's legacy
so
yeah there might be a little
afghanistan mission going on
yeah true that's right because like when
when we're at the emerald cup and i was
talking to a few different people along
with alex from land race legacies um
it was interesting because they were i
think it was actually cagey who was
saying to me oh you know this guy's got
a british passport he can go to
afghanistan he kind of made the point
you know it's a lot harder for us guys
to go there so maybe we need to get our
butts over there and make it happen
yeah and
i think i'll stand out quite a bit over
there this is my only worry um
and uh speaking to my daddy his first uh
reaction was uh no no no no no
[Laughter]
yeah for anyone who's not aware banana
man's got a pretty comprehensive amount
of tattoos
okay
so what's the kind of one of the more
old school breeders whose work you
really admire
i like the work that um
dj shorts has done with the all of his
like stuff
um i like the fact that like
all the sort of like the flow the
blueberry stuff like this they were all
really good lines
and his breathing
style i think
was was quite um
interesting to read about especially a
younger age
did you ever read any of the articles
where he spoke about
selecting males while on psychedelics
no i haven't actually that no that one
that would be quite interesting because
i think this is a big thing for me like
on on mushrooms and
even on like
um small amounts of
dmt and but repeatedly smoking and going
in like yeah
they
it's almost like the plants speak to you
yeah and these uh
substances guide you
so
yeah it's going to be interesting to
have a read on them you'll have to send
me some links
yeah man i'll dig it up for you but i
guess a pertinent question to ask is our
friend um afghan black honey kush he's
come up a few times do you know if he
plans to do seed increases or is more of
just like an awesome contact
no i can imagine they're going to be
some seed releases going on and i can
imagine um himalayan connection
um
he's going to be
probably doing some
nice seed releases i think he's got one
going on right at the moment which
a lot of
some of the afghan seeds and
stuff like this
so
yeah
they're going on now at the moment
yeah awesome and how do you feel that'll
affect the community having access to
these pure land races
um i think it's gonna really help the
community i think it's gonna be a really
good educational tool for for people
um
and
yeah uh
it's just like a dream almost so like if
i had
access to some
real
afghan genetics when i was younger
direct from the farmer from afghanistan
like that's pretty an amazing thing so
yeah
i feel ya so you mentioned bubba kush
already as you know one of kind of the
old school clones you're a fan of what
other old-school clones struck a chord
with you whether you have them or not
the sfv
i really enjoyed that one
crowberry that's something that we used
to have
it was just some seeds that came over it
was on the forum
uh days
and a guy called monkey had done a
selection
and
that was a real special plant the
crowberry
um
what else do i have
some real nice things
the lemon larry lemon lario g that was a
real nice special one
and the east coast sour diesel
always always such an amazing plant and
flavor yeah
so i think
lozenge from
from uh
back in the day of the clones on the
forum times
yeah crowberry i've never heard of that
what's what's inside that one
genetically
okay it's um
a grand daddy purple crossed with
blackberry
i'm sure i'd have to double check that
but
um
i ended up using it see look memory it
goes as you get older and i used it for
the smurfberry cross
and
yeah just such an amazing plan to grow
like it would taste absolutely amazing
down to the roach
with this like sort of
berry smell
with that
typical purple sort of
um taste in the background like purple
weed has a certain sort of
serpent almost
so it was like with that with this more
berry tone going on
but yeah so many people drew that album
it was such a good plan
so what do you think will be
basically the next major flavor profile
to take a hold on the scene
i think people fruity stuff
um people seem to really be liking the
lil at the moment
and i'm seeing more people bringing out
pineappley sort of things so i can see
maybe that the pineapple turp coming up
coming back
um
yeah i think that might be a new one to
come back round i see everything coming
back around in circles it seems
it's like fashion right like i remember
it seems like gas strains have like kind
of snuck back in but also kind of
sneaking out and i'm waiting for the
fruity stuff to come back i love that
i've got to agree with gooey breeder on
that one that's where i think it's at
yeah yeah freebie definitely that's
where i'm at as well i think the fruity
stuff's coming back
um i think like everybody that's growing
this lil at the moment
like i was so surprised with the smell
myself when i found that that that fino
like i was literally just dancing in the
room i was just like wow this is amazing
and i just kept going back smelling it
and like
it's so nice to get those messages off
people they're just like wow i've never
smelled anything like this or
this is like just pure tropical juice
papaya people are saying one person was
saying he smells like cream
and strawberries with pineapple and i'm
just like wow this is yeah
this is that's this is this is the tip
that people are loving
yeah definitely okay
so
what do you think about the rise of the
vape pens you know we've seen that
glorious south park episode calling it
the [ __ ] sticks um
how do you feel it seems to me like it's
the bridge between the everyday joe
who's not really a consumer and our
community so to speak do you feel like
it's a good or a bad thing
yeah i think um there's a it's
a lot of people are going to use them
just because it's just so easy to use um
for the normal everyday person
um yes but
i think a lot of
shitty materials being used
for them
um
because i'm seeing if anything's really
nice in flower form it's being sold as
flower or
maybe make it into extract or the really
nice extract they're using really nice
flour and then the lower grade extract
they're using not so good flour and then
it just goes down
down and down and then
it seems to be like the shittier stuff
is being used for edibles
and
these are carts and stuff like that and
i'm seeing so many of the carts just not
passing tests in america
so
yeah education again education
so i think a lot of the issues stemming
from those carts relates to people
buying the actual uh housing units the
plastic and the um the little cartridges
themselves from china and there's you
know a plethora of associated issues
with that do you think that essentially
this is inevitable given that people
selling these carts are looking to make
money their game is profits despite the
fact they may try to claim it's all
about the patience how do you think you
deal with this conundrum
um
yeah um
i think
more testing and stuff like that um like
you're saying then if they're buying the
carts from china and they're releasing
all those toxins into the stuff
yeah
like
yeah people just it's more education
more research into these things
and maybe some more guidelines that
people need to be like sticking to when
they are making these products
for a legal market
how do you feel people can ascertain
whether the person they're buying off
really has their best interests in mind
do you think it's just like you have to
know someone for a while
yeah this is where like it goes back to
the whole thing of um
going to a farmer's market or go into a
shop
um
like
big companies are only interested in
profit
uh most of these carts are being made
just for pure profit
so
i think
there you go
it says it there basically so most of
these companies are more interested in
profit than the people themselves
um
so yeah talking about it more i think
with
other people this is where like forums
come into thing
again
it's a place that we can discuss these
topics
openly with lots of people maybe get
somewhere from that
yeah okay
so
kind of an extension of that idea of the
vape pens and whatnot how do you feel
about the introduction of non-cannabis
derived terpenes to cannabis or even the
reintroduction do you feel like this
idea of removing and then adding back is
deleterious to the overall effect
yeah it's not something that um i've
really looked into at all
um but
yeah i don't think it's something that
we should be doing i don't think there's
any need for using
non-cannabis derived terpenes
um or if you are
what is the reason is it just for the
flavor or is it because those terpenes
have a medicinal use as well
so
like i think a lot more research needs
to be done in this area
um
especially about terpenes i think that's
going to be something for the future
like um
i think they play a massive role
in
healing
um
many other forms the high it creates so
yeah more testing needs to be done
definitely
yeah i mean something which kind of
opened my eyes a little bit is that
everyone always knows that terpenes play
some sort of modulatory role with
cannabis you know because a weed with
terpenes gets you really high that same
weed that's been in a cupboard for
months and it's lost all the terpenes
it's just not the same and you know the
implication is that you know the
terpenes are the thing which is causing
the main change and then you realize
that
thc itself is actually a terpene by
definition and to me that really linked
it all together a whole lot more you
know and i don't think many people are
aware of that
yeah
um
no this is it like
education on this subject
and sharing all this knowledge needs to
be done on a more sort of like regular
basis
and because there's so much to learn
about this plan and it's only the start
because
we're only now being able to do the
things that
we want to do
um
i'm still struggling where i am um but
still there are places that we can have
things tested
um
but
america uh
they're gonna be able to
do so many different things now
now that it's opened up how it has
yeah of course of course
so
do you think that with the
commercialization of things we've been
talking about that there's going to be
this increasing tendency to kind of
intellectualize breathing and that the
idea of using a lab to do it will just
become the common and people using first
principles to select a male is just
going to go out the window
um
yeah um
i think
a lot of the maybe some of the other
companies will maybe go down this line
or like
i don't know if it was you on one of the
europa interviews was talking about uh a
computer
generated breeding program
yep
yeah yeah i can see it going down those
lines and stuff but
we'll see how how how they do
um
and what they make
from doing it that way
um i think it's all going to be very
interesting
but um
yeah
i don't know if they can i think his
breathing's a little bit of art as well
as science
you know with that being said about the
old ways of breeding you know using your
nose and not so much relying on the uh
the labs
how long would you be willing to work a
line before you call it quits let's just
say you made lil and there was something
about it you weren't happy with and
you're like all right i'll just i'll
just work it for a generation or two
i'll fix that up and it kind of doesn't
come you know at least not in one or two
generations at what point would you be
like look this has just been too much of
a time sink
um
yeah if it's not doing what i wanted to
after a couple of generations
then i'd probably scrap that line
if
um
if it was like
a
certain taste say i was looking for
and i was only getting a certain
percentage
i could maybe still release it but
explain that you're only going to get 50
percent of this type of fino
um and this one and you might get this
one or maybe we used to do this on on on
breed bay anyway like we'd fill out a
little form and explain like how many
phenos of this type and stuff like that
so maybe like a little bit more of that
should be done anyway
yeah no i i understand so
um
do you feel like this plays into the
idea of why people have this tendency to
release f1s like it seems like not many
people are working lines further and
there's obviously a commercial reason
for that because
it takes time and money and you're not
exactly evenly compensated like a strain
that goes through
several generations of work doesn't go
necessarily for
like three or four times the cost of an
f1 how do you think we combat that
because there seems to be a like a want
for people to like you know the
consumers want breeders to work the
lines to stabilize them more but at the
same time if the financial compensation
isn't there how do we encourage it
yeah
um
yeah this is a hard one like um
for me yeah it's it's time so i've been
making a lot more f ones and releasing
them
um
but during that i will work
some other lines and yeah takes the time
to do it
but i i'm not i don't get any more
uh price on the seeds if anything
my more work lines are cheaper than my
f1 lines
so
yeah
yeah okay so do you feel like maybe the
introduction of a standardized
seed pricing model would be a benefit to
the community and that you know everyone
sells f1s for around this price everyone
sells f2s for around this price and it
enforces like both a floor and a ceiling
to the pricing
yeah it'd be interesting but um
i think
the seed market the pricing is so varied
at the moment
um
i've increased some prices like the
cherry spice because
the amount of the seeds that it produces
is just like so little compared to other
other things i pollinate
so
um
like
i think that i've done it like this so
i've tried to work out which lines sort
of cost me more to make or have done and
i've tried to do it like this but
um
yeah it varies so much then you've got
other people just charging
600 for a packet that's just built on
hype
so
a pricing would be interesting to see
what people
um come up with
yeah right let's let's delve into this
let's get a little bit feisty so cookie
fam with that candy rain they still
haven't fixed anyone up for those issues
they had and i'm sure you're well aware
of this given the uk is pretty well in
the grips of the hype market how do you
feel about that sich
yeah okay so you may have to explain a
little bit to me as well who made the
candy rain exactly was that [ __ ]
yeah see i don't know i heard rumors
that it was colorado
right okay okay
okay
at least he got dragged into it when
people were asking for refunds
right okay
yeah
yeah i'm not too sure but that's all
just crazy again isn't it it's all built
on hype
and they've totally released something
without testing it
and
yeah people have been
left a bit very disappointed i suppose
yeah okay so do you feel there's an onus
on 500 f1 packs to replace seats if they
don't germinate
yeah i think i think um things have
happened in the past when we were online
i think it was a ic mag this was on
or maybe one of the other forums
um
but somebody had made a line i won't go
into like who it was and stuff like but
somebody made line and they were auto
flowering for some reason because when
they were testing them they they tested
them as seeds and just put them into
flour without vegging them too much
so
um
and that guy replaced people's seeds and
made the effort to do that so i think
i think yeah it's
you need to stick by your product
so if if you made a mistake try to um
give something back to the people that
put money in your pocket
yeah for sure so i mean i feel like i've
already dug this hole so i may as well
keep digging would you ever buy some
cookie farm seeds
no
i could never pay for that price
if they gave me a pack for free i might
pop them just see what they were like
and so how do you feel about the idea of
these crews who can't even necessarily
prove the uh the clear lineation of them
creating the seeds having parental stock
etc
releasing seeds because from my
perspective you know and and i'll caveat
this by saying any anyone from cookie
family wants to come on the show hit me
up dude but um but with that being said
you know there's no clear evidence to me
that like this wasn't a mistake so the
idea that they're now releasing seeds
under the guise of like oh well we made
this it's like did you really and the
seeds you're releasing are they going to
be any good even
yeah
um i think
it's just
some i i know
people personally that bought a packet
and stuff like this
like
um
it was it's just unbelievable and it's
just all
built on that
that hype again
and
people get sucked into it we see it with
so many other things
um
with other products that you buy that
you it's not a superior product but
you're buying it because of the name on
it
if you know what i mean yeah no i feel
you
so
just to kind of uh get ourselves out of
this hole quickly
but equally kind of controversial how
would you react and how would you feel
if someone you know kind of put a post
up on instagram and it was like oh i've
got s-ones for sale soon of mandarina of
lilt of her saying hey you know all of
these strains like how would that make
you react
um
yeah like an s one um
yeah it's a little i think that would be
a little bit too much but to be totally
honest
i don't even think it'd bother me i i i
don't like too much bother me nowadays
um
so
um but i can understand like
if someone's saying my mandarina
someone's s wand it
um i'm sure they did that in morocco to
be honest you know and grew up the seeds
and grew out the seeds and grew up the
seeds
so
and someone asked me the other day could
they um
feminize and make an orange soda
for somebody that wants the seeds and
i'm just like well to be honest with you
it's probably something i'm gonna remake
myself for some time
i've had a few people make things that
i might was thinking of sort of making
and they've done the cross from seeds
that they bought and stuff like that
but it's not going to be like how i
would make it anyway because of my
selections
like you can give someone the same
ingredients but will they sort of cook
the same meal
like
yeah so it doesn't really matter too
much but then i like to see that as well
i like to see people use my genetics and
maybe make something
of their own from them by crossing
something together
so
um
yeah i've seen a lot of two people have
been using the cherry spice a few people
have started using the lil with some
crosses
so
yeah um
it's it's nice to see them being used
and that they they think they're good
enough to use compared to everything
else that they've been growing which is
really good but they've grown them out
it's like i see people just crossing
stuff wanting to cross stuff together
before they've even grown them out
which just doesn't even make sense to me
so at least they're doing some selection
yeah it's weird people not doing that
selection but just to link back to your
other point our our mutual body
organically enhanced he he made some
crosses with his cherry spice keeper he
found i think he even used some mac
pollen which
definitely going to create an
interesting cross but perfect segue to
my next question thanks for bringing it
up save me a bunch of effort how do you
feel about other companies using your
work in their crosses like do you feel
overall it's a positive or sometimes it
can be detrimental
yeah it's not it's never really been a
problem for me
um
like saying now somebody uses the
mandarina in the cross
and someone does grow that out and they
like that terp
then they'll want to grow out the real
mandarina because you find so many
different phenos in the mandarina like
that but some better some some like more
sweet some more sour so
like i think people are always gonna go
to the original once they find something
that they like from the crosses
um
so yeah it's never really been a problem
for me
um
but
yeah it all depends if you're if you're
worried about them taking business from
you
yeah i think that's gonna happen anyway
people are gonna buy seeds from
elsewhere that tastes like orange
yeah
but if it's got mandarina in it or it
hasn't got mandarina in it
so
yeah
yeah okay
so
what is the end goal of trichome jungle
seeds i know it's a bit of a broad
question but i mean do you kind of plan
to do like a bit of a body and start
another seed company for kind of
alternative releases that wouldn't maybe
otherwise fit under the banner of
trichome jungles or is it just to kind
of stick to what you've already got and
you just kind of do whatever you want
within that context there might be
another company working with some other
people um
which will be um maybe based in the
caribbean
um
but
myself i'll do like different lines like
the cherry spice and little part of the
finest selections
um
i've got a few other new things coming
up
um so like i'll definitely make
new like my standard lines would be i
would say
um mandarina jungle push mantis things
like this
and then i had a bunch of lines that
were like a feminized line
and then i stopped making them then i
did the rose water cookie line
i stopped making them
i'll work the rose water cookie by
itself now which is the which is the
realm
um
and then i did define the selection line
um i've
dropped one of them i might drop a
couple more we'll see
the cherry spice and a little are just
becoming very popular so i probably will
continue to make them
um and then i'll look for something else
i just there's so many things i need to
work through and so many different
flavors and things like
uh
it's just time again i need a big big
space
and a couple of years
and yeah
um
be blowing some minds with
the flavors and things
yeah okay
so
i've got a random question i wanted to
ask
so what's your favorite food
food
um
okay
uh
i'll eat a lot of avocados
um
papaya papayas i love
papaya um
but like here where i am you you can get
lots of papaya that's grown here lots of
avocados
um
yeah so it's absolutely amazing for that
um but my diet is a vegan-based sort of
diet yeah
or plants
um
so yeah
so another little random question what's
your favorite music and i hope you have
a soft spot for uk grime
yeah i i do i i do like there's a few
uk um
artists that i like from sort of like
the hip hop type scene and stuff like
this i i like loki but he's a little bit
more political and stuff like that but
my music is so buried like prodigy i
love prodigy and he he passed away the
other day
yes
so yeah um but like i'll listen to
anything from psytrance to
uh
mantras and
buddhist chants and
i don't know rock music to hip-hop there
you go that's that's that's how varied
my music is
oh dude i'm gonna have to send you a
link to the the dj mix boat he gave me
it's [ __ ] great
okay yeah definitely definitely
i'll be well up for listening to that
hell yeah so get us back on topic for a
minute um do you have any plans to do
any kind of specific feminized releases
so like a range of f1 feminized seeds or
not overly
yes there will be some more feminized
seeds being released at some point um
i'm going to try and make a feminized
little
and a few other lines
just so they can people other people can
try them
so many people want them in ics and i'd
love them to be able to try this like
the little and the tropical
so
yeah definitely a few more feminized
lines in the works
yeah cool and do you feel like when you
feminize things you want to kind of
reserve it for the things that really
prove themselves or would you be willing
to do like an initial cross and release
as a feminized line or do you as i said
do you feel like it's reserved for stuff
that's proven itself
yeah it all depends in how it comes out
in the testing
um
and um
like
i couldn't i couldn't release the
feminized mandarina that i made um
so
they were just producing
um
hermaphrodites and stuff like this so i
wasn't happy with them
um
but that was an s1
so
i think if i use the two mandarinas i
have instead of just using the one on
one on itself
um
that would have worked out better
but yeah i think um
some things just don't work and just
yeah other things
uh
we see how it works and
yeah okay so how would you feel if you
had a project you really wanted to
release it you're getting some awesome
results from the seeds but like let's
just say one in every 30 or maybe one in
every 40 seeds was like just a horrific
hermaphrodite is that is that at the
point where you'd be like nah i got a
you know 86 this or do you feel like
it's the type of thing where you would
just kind of want to be upfront with
that information and be like it's still
worth it but you know just keeping it
keep an eye out for that
yeah i think if if you're gonna get like
one hermaphrodite
um
in 100
seeds
i don't see that as a major thing
um
especially if you're using certain
things like
we'll say
cherry
pie
for
instance um i see a lot with crosses of
um
cherry pie
uh strains
um but i find like they'll pre it's not
even like a proper hermaphrodite
sometimes it'll be just like a male bit
that you pick off and you don't see any
more after that
so
um
[Music]
i think it's going to be something that
you see i think things with sour diesel
in it is another thing
that you'll spring up
um
so
but the cherry pie has been an
interesting one i'm seeing like almost
like bubba kush like laffy type traits
coming out from a lot of these like
cherry pie crosses
and stuff like this
yeah okay and so i mean cherry pie is a
great example because it's one of those
ones where even when people are growing
it just for the bud
um people will comment you know you get
a few little nanas on the lower branches
maybe they're not getting enough light
maybe there's something else at play do
you feel like these clones are still
worth while breeding with or kind of
that issue i mentioned is a bit
problematic in the grand scheme of
things
um it can be problematic in the grand
scheme of things um it can mess up
someone's whole growl really
um
[Music]
but i think if people are
aware that these genetics sort of there
is that chance of them doing it
um yeah
i don't know see some of them are just
like what i tend to do is try and find a
cherry
pie cross
and select from ma which don't have the
hermaphrodite tendencies and then work
from there so i do a lot of my stuff
from seeds and not the original clones
so i'll make sure that
like cherry pie and girl scout cookies
is the the parents
and then from the selection find a plant
that doesn't show any of those traits
that you don't want
and work from that
so that's where i would go down the line
of doing try and find the terpene that
you want without the other traits
for sure okay so we're on to our last
little quickfire question so
hopefully we're not doubling up too much
but maybe some things have changed since
we last talked but first off what is the
best smoke you've had recently that
comes to
mind um
sour neo and
cherry spice which i'm really enjoying
at the moment yeah
do you try many stuff outside of your
own or not often
um
yes out of some of the new stuff so uh
the skittles i've got to try all the new
like american elite stuff
and the skittles the gelato
um
runts um few other different ones lemon
tree all of these
so yeah um i've got to troll them and
really enjoyed the skittles
um that was a real nice
um
flavor to it so i'd like to work that
line maybe into some of my things that
would be quite interesting i think
okay
and
i'm sure you probably copped a wind of
it you know a few months back just
before december we had a big kind of
kerfuffle in the industry about how the
big al
mac 100.8 were selling and people
weren't too happy about that how do you
feel about that and the emergence of
this premium cannabis market
yeah well it's the same in in barcelona
to be honest like i think that's what
skittles and stuff like that sells for
like basically
um it's like 100 euros and
for three grams or something like this
[ __ ] even more than america
yeah yeah it's coming from
probably places like that so
there you go
so um
yeah crazy prices absolutely crazy
prices
okay
so i've even seen in amsterdam you go to
amsterdam and they've got it on the menu
there for like 40 euros a gram and stuff
and how do you feel about the culture of
import cali you know do you feel like
it's destructive to the local producers
so to speak no i think if if something's
coming at that higher price selling flat
higher price then maybe
local growers get a little bit better
price i think it's when um people start
coming in and selling like really like
[ __ ] extract because there's so much
extract in america now made from like
just crap and
stuff like this
that's going for so cheap
like then that comes over to
places like spain and that brings the
prices right down i think that can
affect things maybe
yeah okay and then just to kind of wrap
up our little hype section what's the
most over-hyped strain that gets sold
for lots of money
the most overhyped strain
like i've heard i haven't had it myself
so i'll give that caveat but i've heard
like runts and grunts and all that
stuff's like not that great um
runts itself the one that i tried was
was quite nice
um but then i suppose it's batch
dependent the purple punch that i tried
was was very lacking
yeah purple punch
um not all that some of the gelatos some
of them weren't even that that nice old
but then it all depends you know
who who's grown it and stuff like this
but i think anything that's that sort of
price is overpriced uh i tried some mac
that was that was nice but then i had
another one that wasn't that good so it
all depends again who grows it or if
it's from the seed or if it's a clone
yeah definitely right i remember the
emerald cup cappulator gave me some mac
phenomenal probably standout weed of
that emerald cup
and then yeah i had some grown by a good
grower admittedly it was outdoors but um
looked amazing organic sungrown just
ticked all the boxes but then when i
tried it it just wasn't anywhere near as
good at all so maybe it comes down to
like the grower i mean obviously cap's
gonna grow some pretty darn good mac
yeah i think that that's going to play a
big role um
like you said then i i wasn't impressed
with it but then i've spoke to other
people and they're like nice
it's absolutely amazing
so
um
yeah i must must depend
yeah okay
so outside of the hype strains what's
one of the you know
most lackluster samples you've tried in
recent memory
something i've joined enjoyed in spain
oh something you haven't enjoyed like
for example what's kind of the worst
yeah what's what's the worst strain
you've ever had
okay okay okay sorry um
worst one
it's recently
i'm gonna say that purple punch was
really lacking because i expected it to
be much nicer with the hype
yeah
there's lots of things like that i've
been lacking from a lot of the like
spanish seed companies i've seen
but yeah
yeah okay
so
one of my favorite ones desert island
question you can take three strains with
you and you've got an infinite supply of
you don't have to worry about growing
them or anything like that so which
three strains you're taking with you
um lilt
sour neo
and
the cherry spice
bows free from mine so i've got
something sour
something gassy
something fruity and i'd probably miss
the mandarina
oh poor mandarina it's still got a spot
in our hearts yeah it's cause i've
smoked too much of it now i think but
i'd miss after a few weeks
almost a little bit of tangy syndrome
yeah that's it
alrighty so
final question for the interview
what is your next strain coming out that
you're most excited about
um salinia there you go i've mentioned
it quite a few times now
um yeah really enjoying that one
and um
looking forward to see what comes from
the afghan crosses i've just done
yeah actually now let's slide an extra
question in for good measure now that
you've got your afghan land race seeds i
believe last time we spoke i asked you
you know if you could go anywhere
collect some landry seeds what would you
do and i think you said afghan so now
that you've got them what's next on the
list of stuff that you don't have that
you'd love to get
yeah um
it's crazy how that happened actually
how you asked that question and then
we were going to india and mate called
me and he's like there's a guy from
afghanistan he's coming and he's
bringing some real afghan seeds with him
it was just so crazy how it happened
so let me see let's see if i can put it
out there and get the next one
and
some iranian seeds
some oh some persian seeds iranian
persian
that would be nice
oh god yes i've had the pleasure of
trying um australian bodies
iraqi which is you know they say it's
probably persian and god it's like a
bakery it's just it's amazing you smoke
this plant and you could be fooled into
being told that it's like just a cookie
cut like it's incredible
yeah that's it that sounds like sounds
that sounds like my cup of tea that yeah
hell yeah well i think that just about
brings us to the end of it did you have
any shout outs or comments you wanted to
make
um
yeah i'd like to shout out everybody
that i went to
india with uh
land race legacy
and indian land race exchange
sonic
sonic seeds uh himalayan connection
um
afghan crush black honey
yeah um and
uh
equity
labs all those guys yeah amazing guys
awesome well thank you so much again
banana man for taking the time to join
us and for sharing all the knowledge
with us
no thank you it's always enjoyable
talking with you guys thank you
so what do y'all think
[Music]
pretty good wasn't it
i thought so
thanks for hanging around if you made it
this far
big thank you to our patreon fans as
always if you want to hear more get on
that patreon
[Music]
there's a few extra little things for
you
[Music]
as always seeds here now best in the
business organic gardening solutions 420
australia we love them
oh yeah that dragonfly don't forget
[Music]
big love for everyone
see you next time
[Music]
see you
so
[Music]
you