foreign
[Music]
budding enthusiasts it's your boy Happy
Days coming at you from the upside down
library and in this episode we're doing
a meet the sponsors
we work with some incredible sponsors
who are very proud to be affiliated with
and we want you guys to hear a little
more about them
seeds here now James Bean you've heard
from him before and you're here again
but on this episode we're going to hear
a little bit from Matt from Premier Tech
to talk a little bit about pro-mix
connect your number one mycorrhizal
products as well as countless other
products you're probably familiar with
and might already used such as their
mediums
likewise we're gonna hear from Kevin of
covert biological systems
an IPM expert in the field and a huge
source of knowledge for any IPM
questions I'm really excited for you
guys to hear this one
I had a lot of fun talking to everyone
and I hope you guys enjoy this as much
as I did
so up first we have Matt from Premier
Tech talking all things chromos connect
we're gonna jump straight into this one
[Music]
let's get into it
the thing which I find really
interesting about Premier Tech and Pro
mix in general is that for years the
company has been really well known in
the Cannabis Community for providing
really high quality mediums and when I
think pro-mix I think a lot of the the
media you guys produce most notably that
for a long time came inoculated with
mycorizer what was it that stimulated
you guys to sort of start looking into
mycorrhizer and wanting to pursue that
pathway a little further
well like you said we're really well
known in the industry by the growing
media you know uh pro-mix HP I wasn't
really developed for cannabis but it
ended up being like an amazing green
media to grow the plan uh but we wanted
to address the market more specifically
so we're looking at our technology which
is available you know uh and looking at
the plan and the growth cycle and
everything uh how we can contribute you
know and seeing all the product out
there we felt like we're able to bring a
pro ion product on the market uh that
will have a Gore grow great cannabis you
know
yeah a really good answer I'm it sort of
stimulates me to start thinking all
about mycorrhiza myself and maybe the
best way to sort of discuss this to
start at the beginning which is how do
you guys grow mycorrhiza like what what
is the process behind doing that
well we have a like a really unique
process at Premiere first it's all done
in-house with our Technologies but in
the mycorizing industry there's
basically two ways of producing uh
mycorrhizal fungi
there's the first one I would say the
most common and I would say the easiest
in the market uh is in Vivo technique so
the mycorrhizal fungi is basically grown
on a full plant that is usually grown
into an inner medium it could be clay or
sand for example
uh and then you are risk all that inner
medium the root system of a plan and the
fungi itself and that's constitute the
base
of the mycorized product
but there are certainly a couple of
flaws with that technique uh yes it's
the less expensive but at the same time
it's it's harder to ensure no presence
of pathogen control the the type of
genetics of mycorrhizae you end up with
the product uh and it's harder to
control also the concentration and the
quality because you know you're growing
it out out there on a full full plan at
the beginning like 30 years ago that's
how permitic was doing it uh but with a
lot of years in research we've developed
a technique which is uh in vitro
technique it's kind of grown on the
artificial root system of a plan in kind
of a microarizal micro reactor if I can
call it that way honestly I don't even
know the process at all because it's a
well-guarded secret in the industry
it requires special type of equipment
you know it's done in the laboratory
with aseptic condition with the special
type of expertise so yes it's more
expensive but you're able to produce
massive amount of mycorrhizae enormous
concentration you know and a very high
quality product at the end yeah okay
that that makes sense I think I had read
a long time ago that
um some types of plants and root systems
will produce mycorrhizae naturally but
but it sort of like takes you years does
that sound correct
uh a plan in itself can I can I grow
mycoresi by its own the week can grow
mycoresis because I would have like a
viable spores or a microsal structure in
the soil and when the symbiosis happen
with the root system well the
mycorrhizal fungi are going to develop
itself you know and at some point you
can arrest the mycorrhizae on directly
on the root system of the plant okay
interesting yeah because I guess my
follow-up question was I was always
wondering
well if you went somewhere that had like
really old established mature growth
like say like the Redwood forests in
Humboldt or like you know somewhere with
really established growth could you try
to harvest mycorrhizae from that soil or
not really yeah definitely honestly for
example Premier Tech didn't invent
mycoresia or anything my crazy was found
in the Woods by digging out some some
Roots so when you have very old uh you
know growth operation outdoor
or even in the forest or stuff like that
you can definitely find mycoresis in the
soil for sure
okay sure but I mean I guess obviously
it's it's it's pretty variable in terms
of the mycorizer product you guys create
I'm assuming that consistency is
probably some like one of the benefits
you can sort of Bank on when buying a
high quality microizer product like
pro-mix connect sort of thing
yeah definitely consistency is a big
thing uh especially for cannabis grower
you know you're growing a high valuable
plants so you want to be able to have
consistency in each of the batch of the
mycorrhizae that you purchase and we've
just just talked about uh about the
method that we're using to produce that
mycorrhizae and that ensure a very high
quality product each and every time but
not only that you know we're we test
each and every batch uh each time and
for pro-mix connect especially it's a
very small batch so we validate the
number of Iowa spores for each batch uh
the the content of heavy metal as well
and also the presence of microbial for
example so each batch of product that
you can buy out there is really really
high quality
yeah that's great to hear I mean I was
sort of wondering in terms of like the
the viability of a mycorrhizal product
is there such a thing as like a shelf
life or it's sort of indefinitely stable
uh there's definitely a shelf life
because you know mycorrhizae at the end
of the day is a live microorganism you
know so you have to keep it viable and
alive uh in order to have the benefit
out of it uh we we have like a two years
shelf life and assuming like escaping at
the right temperature you know indoor
temperatures and not too hot not too uh
too cold you know uh but yeah I would
say we have a two years uh shelf life
yeah
wow that's really quite good I mean
especially compared to some of the the
other microbial products you get sort of
more bacterially based ones that you
know the Shelf life's quite limited
comparatively
a question I was hoping you may be able
to answer for me is I had read in the
past other mycorrhizal products there
can be quite a bit of variation in terms
of what the spores are mixed with or I
think I remember reading one time that
mycorrhizal product I was using was it
had like azomite with the spores or
something or zeolite or something like
that and I guess I was wondering is that
common process and does that affect the
quality of the product the substrate
it's sort of mixed or bound with
uh if I understand the question
correctly you're talking about kind of
the formulation of the product because
the thing is like mycorrhizae it's a
it's a fungi and you can put it in
different type of carrier depending on
how you want to bring the the fungi to
the plant so it could be like in the
case of Pro mix connect it's a wettable
powder uh but you can it could be
granular form uh zeolite is another
example of carrier that can be used and
there's a lot of different type of
carrier it could be into into water but
it's a bit more complicated since you
have to keep in low temperature to keep
the viable G but you know you can
formulate the product in different ways
and that's definitely something that
Premier Tech has become expert at
because it's one thing to produce good
mycorrhizae but you have to keep it
viable until the grower is actually
using your product and formulation so
keeping the micro crazy alive on the
carrier that you're choosing is a big
part of it
yeah that that is definitely something I
was hoping we could touch on a bit
because something I had noticed and the
reason why I stepped away from that
mycorrhizae product I referenced in the
past was as you mentioned you you
understood perfectly what I was trying
to ask so apologies for forgetting the
word carrier and whatnot but you were
right it was a granule sort of base
mycorizer and I found it really hard to
apply it to like the root ball when I
was transplanting for example like it
was it would just fall off like little
grains of rock sort of thing would you
sort of guess that the way pro-mix has
made in the sense that it's that
wettable powder and you can really get a
nice coating on the root ball for
example would you sort of guess that
that's probably a better way of applying
it than say the granules I gave up on in
the past
yeah definitely uh you know in granular
forming can work as well the key here in
cannabis and mycorrhizae is to have
proximity between the spores and The
Roots You know that's how the symbiosis
is gonna uh gonna happen uh and that's
why we developed promise connect as a
wearable pattern it's uh like you just
said uh you have the most proximity with
the route you're able to create like a
coating so like all the spores are
really at the surface of the roots so
that's how you get I would say the
fastest establishment and I uh with that
you get the the best benefits out of it
yeah okay that makes sense that's good
so in the past I had sometimes added
mycorrhizae to just my water and then
watered it in do you think that that's
gonna lead to sort of meaningful levels
of the spores getting to the roots or
you really sort of want to do what you
mentioned and have it like proximally
just really applied to the root itself
if possible
uh I would say closest to the root is
the best uh you you can you could have
an impact by mixing it with water but
clearly it's not efficient enough for
you know first mycorrhizae isn't soluble
so you have to keep like agitation in
your water in order for the microwaves
to stay mixed into your water so so
that's that's first but even that the
spores gonna have to attach itself to
the roots to have really an impact but
probably a lot of them going to be
washed away when you're applying your
water you know so yes it could have an
impact but definitely not as much if you
are applying it directly to your roots
okay sure and is there anything people
can do that you're aware of that would
increase the ability for the the sport
to successfully connect with the route
like maybe like soil temperatures or
like the degree of how wet the medium is
at the time is there anything you're
aware of that could help them get better
benefit I would say uh mostly two things
uh the Water not being too too hot or
too cold you know tap water is just fine
uh when mixing the powder for example
and the second thing would be to maybe
slow down on phosphorus for you know two
weeks after application and it's kind of
renowned out there the phosphorus is not
going to kill the fungi at all it's just
that if you have a lot a big amount of
phosphorus it's going to kind of
intubate the establishment of that
symbiosis you know so you want to give
it a chance to those through those two
first two weeks
so I mean this is just sort of a
question that's come to mind but if
someone was to use mycorrhizae in a like
a more of like a hydroponic setting
where they're using salt-based nutrients
and they're laid in bloom and they're
applying lots of phosphorus and
potassium and stuff
I guess by virtue of what you just said
like you're probably not going to get
that much effect out of applying
mycorrhiza Laden flour in that sort of
situation or it's still beneficial do
you think
well the key anyways not to apply the
product latent flower you know to have
the best benefit out of the mycoresis to
apply it as soon as possible so the goal
we recommend to apply you know when your
clone is rooted that's when you when you
do your first transplant that's one you
want to apply it because you know uh the
establishment of the mycorrhizian the
symbiosis take some times so the sooner
you do the application the better the
benefits you know you're gonna have at
the end so I don't see the point of
doing it at the end like lay flour when
you're gonna are nervous you know a
month from from that point
yeah sure that makes a lot of sense so I
mean you touched on earlier how this is
a a high commodity crop it's a lot of
value for people and that's something
I'm always trying to emphasize to people
especially when people talk about the
economics of products and stuff I'm I
sort of frequently try to remind them
that you know this is such a high value
crop that's sometimes paying for premium
inputs you're going to get a much better
output and I guess in the case of
mycorrhizae there's no discussion in the
community about whether it works just
empirically you can see it works when
you use it it just it's so so night and
day difference but I guess I'm sort of
wondering have you guys ever looked into
or sort of tried to quantify at all the
benefit of using mycorrhizae because I
thought if I had to Hazard a guess I'd
say it probably going to get twice as
much growth or something like very
dramatic increase have you guys ever
looked into that sort of thing
yeah yeah of course uh one of our first
single that we bring to the market is
the return on investment you know and
the way we recommend to apply the
product you know you you're going to
kind of put an investment between one or
three dollar a plan it depends on how
much powder or how you mix a product you
know uh but you know one or two three
dollar a plan it's not much when for
example let's just say not not even a
high uh a high yield increase let's just
say it's five percent you know five
percent on a big plan it could end up to
be 20 gram you know 20 gram at five ten
dollar a gram your written investment is
pretty pretty easy but not only that
we've was really really important for us
to yes the yield yes yield is always
important but in cannabis quality is
everything craft cannabis you know I
feel it's a really growing industry and
you know you get top dollars for top
flowers and uh by bringing yes the yield
but also the quality you know increase
their opinion increase cannabinoids
you're able to produce consistently
higher quality flowers and that you're
able to get much more out of a crop even
for example if you don't have any yield
increase you're gonna get better results
as well
yeah okay I mean that opens the door to
sort of discussing when might be the
best time to use things in terms of
getting the best return on investment a
lot of people use mycorrhiza as sort of
a root stimulating agent instead of your
traditional cloning gels or powders
things like that
how would you use mycorrhizae would you
say for example use it once when
stimulating the roots and then again
when transplanting what how would you
tell if your friend came up to and said
when should I be using mycorizer give me
the road map
well I would just tell you how I
personally use it myself uh you know
most of the Growers are there anyway are
now probably doing only one transplant
that's kind of the trend right now and
anyway the most important application is
the first one
and in my mind the best one is when you
have a rooted clone that is ready to be
transplanted into a bigger pot because
you know you have all those root exposed
and you have to have the contact like I
said before the roots and the spores in
order to get the symbiosis going so I
would say that's really really the key
key moment to apply the product
yeah okay great and I mean this one is
kind of a hard one to answer and that's
why I'm asking you because I wasn't able
to find an answer but I've always been
curious as to how mycorrhiza facilitated
that root stimulating process because
it's very clear based on people's
evidence of just trialing it themselves
that mycorrhizer is a reasonably it's a
pretty down good effective rooting agent
but I could never really like figure out
like what was how is it mediating this
process do you have any idea about that
or is that just something we probably
need to research a bit more to figure
out
well mycoresce Microsoft fungi basically
need the plant to live that's how it
works you know by having that sense we
also is going with the root system of a
plan and that's how the mycorrhizal
fungi is able to thrive and develop
itself you know create the if Network
that bring the benefit the renowned
benefit of the My Verizon which is
picking up water picking up nutrients
you know uh and in return it's going to
help the plant to thrive because if the
plant Thrive the fungi is going to
thrive as well so if you have more water
more nutrient you're gonna be able to
develop bigger root a bigger structure
bigger flower you know and higher
quality it's all linked together so if
if the fungi is doing well well the plan
is going to do well as as well so
okay yeah that's that's a really sort of
nice explanation like so you're sort of
thinking that maybe there's like a
chemotaxic sort of process where the
fungi are stimulating the roots to
ensure their own Survival sort of thing
well there's a whole process behind of
it you know I can go deep into each and
every step uh you know the spores when
you get into contact with the rules like
physically is going to detect where the
roots is in the soil and it's going to
germinate towards it and at some point
it's gonna have a contact between the IV
and The Roots the route in itself it's
going to penetrate the root cells and
create structure inside the roots of the
plant and when those structure like
Arbor school and physical are created
inside the root and they are able to
exchange energy and that's how the IP
network then is going to be created and
you know that relationship yes going to
bring more water and more nutrient but
you know you're impacting also the
immune system of a plant you're
basically stimulating the immune system
of the plant so that's kind of also
where dnns of quality can have been
within European compounds like that came
from
yeah wow okay that's that's really good
information to know so with that in mind
how there's more sort of nutrient
availability with the presence of
mycorrhizae would you sort of try to
angle that effect as you could get away
with using less nutrients because it's
more available to the plant or would you
sort of try to pile up on it and be like
well let's actually add more nutrients
and try to facilitate even greater
uptake
often I try to stay away from that topic
because you know cannabis Gore are
really like personal in terms of using
nutrients you know but for sure you can
slow down on nutrients because you're
going to pick up more but at the end of
the day you can keep the same schedule
and you're going to achieve better
result as well because it's it's gonna
maybe help you achieve better like
become like picking up more nutrient
like I said but also like avoid salt
buildup and stuff like that because
you're having that much nutrient
presenting to the soul you know so so I
mean the majority of our listeners as
far as I'm aware Are soil based Growers
but you know we like to show some love
to our soilless Growers from time to
time
um so I guess my question is
as far as you're aware does mycorrhizal
work equally as effective in sort of
both styles of growing yeah you know um
or am I crazy probably yeah of course
it's probably making it it's worked well
with our growing media but it's
compatible with other type of media you
know uh as long as you have a physical
support for the roots and the fungi it
is going to work you know rock wall or
coco where it's just fine directly into
Seoul as well of course uh the only
issue I would say is pure Hydroponic and
to be more precise aeropanic because you
don't have a physical support to develop
the root and the fungi so I'm not sure
how it would work but in most cases
mycorreza is compatible with kind of
every style of growing fantastic and
from what I had read it sort of was
saying that
ectomycorrhiza didn't really provide any
benefit to cannabis does that sound
right to you
yeah no effect at all because it's kind
of just a filler because at the end of
the day uh the mycorrhizal fungi is not
going to be able to connect with the
root system because it's just not
compatible so we won't have any effect
at all
sure and I mean in the past I'd seen
mycorrhizal products which had sort of
boasted being a blend of you know six 12
different mycorrhizal strains things
like that what's your thoughts on that
does it provide diversity or is it
filler uh you know that's something that
is really popular in the marketing the
most the better uh but unfortunately for
my crisis it's not the case you know
we've did a lot of research at finding
the best strain of the of the best you
know genetic of mycoresis out there
which is gloomless and tried radices in
the pro-mix connect you know by putting
any other uh mycorrhiza in there you're
just introducing competition with the
mycorrhizae which doesn't help the
strain to thrive you know uh and to put
other microlysis in there you have to
dilute the amount of mycoresis that you
put in of your best strain so you know
you just count you know it doesn't work
that way yeah brilliant I'm glad to hear
that from you because that had been my
suspicion for a while I think yeah I had
read that yeah the glomerular
subspecies was the sort of doing the
bulk of the work so that's when I
started to wonder you know the the rest
just sort of filler so I mean do you
suspect that going forward in maybe say
more the long term you'll see companies
all switched to just sort of providing
the one strain that's doing the bulk of
the work or do you think there's still
just always going to be a bit of
marketing at Play
uh there's definitely always going to be
some marketing but you we have to keep
in mind that some people are just aren't
able to produce a perfectly pure product
you know like I've talked earlier when
you're using like uh nvivo technique of
growing digital on the planet it's hard
to keep control of what is actually
growing on the root system of the plant
so you have probably multiple species of
mycorrhizae in there so I feel like
there's always going to be some product
like that out there and people that are
actually able to produce eye
concentration of a specific species
specific species is going to go that
route eventually
so with that in mind are you aware of
any other microbes which may sort of
synergize well or just work well in
conjunction with mycorrhizae that you're
personally fond of
yeah uh honestly most bacteria work
really really well with mycorrhizae
that's why for example our pro-mix plus
line there's mycorrhizae and uh bacillus
inside or green media because they work
really really well together and for
example if you're already using a
standalone product based back which is
some bacteria is going to help
definitely because bacteria work well
when you have organic Surfers available
because they grow on the root you know
and if you have the IV Network that is
well developed well it's more surface
for your bacteria to grow so there's
definitely a good Synergy with most
bacteria and mycorrhizae yeah okay good
to hear and I mean a bit earlier you
mentioned how mycorrhiza sort of
directly can affect the plant's immune
system through the way it connects with
the roots something I always try to talk
to people or listeners is about how when
you affect the plant's immune system
beneficially you're essentially just
increasing its ability to fight off
pests to fight off pathogens things like
that would you say that essentially
mycorrhiza is doing that as well
yeah definitely uh you know it's a big
resistant to stress uh you know if
you're using mycorized the outdoor uh
the death rate of your crop is going to
be way lower than without it because you
know it's a bigger resistant to stress
and you just you just set it uh if
you're able to defend yourself against
pests and stuff like that uh well that
translates into higher terpenes I higher
carabinoids because you know those
compounding cannabis wasn't meant for
for human to get high uh it's a it's a
defense mechanism from the plan so if
you're able to defend yourself more
easily you know produce more terpene and
more cannabinoids you know
yeah I I wholeheartedly agree and I love
I love that you bring that up you know
like as um as much as we'd like to think
we're Masters of the Universe this uh
this plant that's near and dear to our
heart is essentially just trying to
fight off some bugs at its core
exactly exactly
that's good I don't know who told me
that but uh basically cannabis is a
sexually frustrated plant it's just
trying to reproduce itself and we're not
letting it it like reproduce itself we
don't want to have any seeds so she's
just keeping on putting flowers and
hoping that some pollen is going to come
his way oh my God that's hilarious
exactly there you go okay cool well I
mean something I've done in the past and
I'm happy to throw myself under the bus
here a little bit with this is I sort of
just wanted to experiment a bit and make
some weird and wonderful microbial
mixtures so I'd sort of just mix a few
different microbial powders together and
then make a little slurry and apply it
to the roots and just sort of see how it
goes have you heard anything about that
working good working bad is there any
mixtures you might recommend avoiding
like I guess maybe one I was thinking
about initially was do you want to avoid
mixing different fungal spores together
or not a real problem with that what's
your take
like I said before I I don't really
concern myself to be like a grower per
se so I don't have a lot of knowledge on
that subject but you know uh I know
Growers that are using uh you know live
bed to grow cannabis you know mixing a
lot of different kind of different
different compost a different type of
microorganism you know creating like an
alive soil and I definitely see people
having a lot of success with that uh but
if you're asking my personal opinion I I
just I just find that it's maybe a bit
more trouble because you're having the
locks and that you provide you have like
an external containers you know so you
are able to control what you're
providing to your plan so why putting
like so much into it and not able to
manage like specifically when you you
want to create you know
okay sure
and another one I'd sort of always
wondered about which I think you might
be able to answer for me is sometimes
when I'd seen people making compost like
mixing a bunch of amendments like you
know maybe Alfalfa and kelp and a big
pile and then cooking it up before they
eventually grow with it I had seen them
adding mycorizer at that step and just
when they mix their compost pile and
then let it sit for a while and I
thought did the spores just sit there
stagnant waiting or what what do you
think happens there
uh you know we haven't made any story on
that I don't think so but uh personally
I think that maybe there could be some
effect at some point because maybe some
of the spores gonna stay dormant into
the compost but at the same time there's
so much hate into it
probably most of it's gonna die uh but
depending on how you proceed maybe some
of the the My Crazy gonna stay alive and
at some point if you're having there's
proximity with the root that is growing
into the compost or the mix that you
created there's going to be some effect
at some point
yeah I guess that's what I sort of
figured that like you're sort of trying
to Prime the medium to be ready for the
roots but yeah I guess that that hot
composting process might might take its
toll on some of the spores okay well I
mean on the other end of the spectrum
another thing I'd sort of wondered in a
similar fashion was when people were
Brewing teas or making nutrients for
their plants and they might you know
bubble it with an air stone for a few
days before they use it and they were
throwing mycorrhizae powder into that
mixture and letting it bubble for a few
days do you have any thoughts on that
side of process
uh like I I said earlier it's kind of uh
tricky to put mycoresis sometime into
water because uh water makes like
chemical compound more available for the
mycorrhizae so sometimes you know oh my
crazy preserve is that the spores are
dormant you know and when you put it in
contact with water they can they can
come across some chemicals that gonna
you know trigger them to to germinate
and when they germinate at some point
they're not going to have any energy
left to create that symbiosis so like
putting it into water it's kind of a
risky move right from the get-go uh but
like you just mentioned there's so much
technique out there that definitely stop
at some point in some kind of effect but
definitely not as much as the classic
way that we recommend like directly on
the root system you know
okay
I think I had read somewhere in the past
that
mycorrhizae can die after as little as
say 24 hours after being put into water
if it doesn't attach to a root does that
sound like there's any truth in that or
maybe it's not quite correct
well the first thing there's a lot of
mycorrhizae product uh water-based on
the market and if you see a mycorrhizae
product that is water-based and that is
on a shelf and not like a lower like say
let's say four degrees temperature
that is what basically won't work uh you
know in water form it's way like I said
earlier are there to keep this viable
spores dormant so if they get activated
they like I said they're eventually
gonna die because they won't be able to
connect with any type of roots so it's a
bit more tricky when having a
formulation water-based formulation
yeah okay sure and I guess it probably
just varies from Brand to Brand as to
how long the spores would be viable in
that situation yeah definitely and it
also depends on the application you know
uh if you're having a powder form that
you're mixing with water right away and
you are playing seriously on the roots
it won't have time to die you know
because you're using the product right
away I'm all talking into like a shelf
life uh situation
okay yeah no that that makes sense for
sure so a lot of the people listening to
the show utilize a style of growing
chord no-till where the idea is you're
trying not to disturb the soil as much
as possible and just sort of taking out
the stump of the old Route putting a new
one in
does that sort of environment lead to
any benefits with the mycorrhizae
because the soil sort of they're long
term or because the roots are in this
cycle of like being healthy and then
dying off and then new Roots is it sort
of like you're just starting fresh in a
sense each time
uh if I'm interesting correctly you
meaning you're like reusing the same
salt yeah canvas right okay okay well if
you're using mycoresia already and
you're keeping the roots in there
there's still going to be some
mycorrhizian sport left because you know
when mycoresis grow on Roots it creates
pores or physical and stuff that is able
to reconnect eventually with an alive
root system but at the same time uh
reusing your soil is always a tricky
business because you know for example
you're purchasing pro-mix for the
porosity you know the structure of the
solar light is provided and you know the
stability of the ph and stuff like that
but that's something that over time
you're You're Gonna Lose because there's
compaction you know the fiber of the
peas gonna get degraded all of those
stuff that's going to come into play as
well
okay sure yeah so I guess it sort of
would be a bit of a challenging
undertaking for someone to try to like
reuse the same pot just again and again
again just to try to like get their own
mycorrhizer right
yes and no like I mean I I may be more
talking into like a commercial business
type of thing but if you're like trying
some stuff at home like craft cannabis
and trying new things there's you know
you can try whatever you want and see
see how it goes I I seen people doing so
much different thing and I've ex having
success you know it's not because
personally me I'm not doing it that is
not good but I I I see it maybe
difficult to do it like in a commercial
scales but you know if you're going for
fun at home definitely you can try it
something I had always wondered was you
often hear about foods for microbes
bacterial or fungal is there any food
you can give to help make your
mycorrhiza more happy so to speak
naturally yeah it's because you know
basilius and bacteria are able to like
get their food or their nutrients in the
soil you know so that would be like for
for bacteria like yeah you could you can
apply some stuff that will help their
development but you know to develop
itself mycores you just need to plant
that's they they get their nutrient
their energy from the plant so even if
you are adding any type of you know
sugar or stuff into your your media uh
if it benefit the mycorrises because
it's going to benefit the plant and not
directly the mycorrhizae yeah okay that
I mean that's sort of in line with the
principle organic Growers use anyway
feeding the soil not the plant so I
guess it's the same with the micro so
yeah exactly as far as you're aware are
there any factors which can improve the
efficiency of the mycorrhiza once it's
been applied to the plant
uh
uh well we touched point on that earlier
but I definitely like the uh the amount
of phosphorus that you're applying right
after it I I would say like to low down
below 20 PPM would be like a
recommendation to ensure that the
symbiosis get going uh more easily and
faster yeah okay so I guess I'm sort of
thinking like
demycorrhized a favor any particular
medium composition over others or it's
all pretty much effective of similar
proportion no matter what Medium you're
in uh to be totally honest would you I I
feel like is going to work well in any
type of environment because you know
mycoresis also be known to help the
structure of the soil it's such a small
structure that pretty much any type of
soil that it's in is going to thrive and
develop itself really easily you know
compaction is not really an obstacle for
mycorrhizae so I would say it's going to
thrive in pretty much all those
environment okay sure I've been doing a
lot of reading about the pro-mix connect
product and I guess I'm sort of
wondering are there any specifics about
it or the production methods which you
feel helped set it apart from others
well uh we've talked all over the
premier Tech you know using uh in uh in
Virtual technique which is a big part of
our success you know we're in hours
producing Irma crazy having full control
of all the process from A to Z you know
a lot of brand out there are co-packing
that are actually producing my crazy and
just putting in a bag so of course you
don't have the same control as we have
uh you know we've been doing that for so
long now that we're really expert into
not only producing macarizoni but
formulating mycorrezae and not only that
but promise connect has been developed
exclusively with cannabis in mind
and you know
um
when you deal with microbes in the live
microorganism the first thing is it
needs to be viable they need to be alive
and that's something that we guarantee
we have 6 000 viables pores inside our
product so there's nothing nothing dead
in there so you know what you're paying
for and after that we guarantee the
concentration six thousand thousand
valuable spores is by far the most
concentrated product out there there's
not even someone that is coming close so
having a higher concentration you know
you you have a better chance to get the
symbiosis established quickly so better
benefit at the end as well
and the last thing we've developed it as
a weightable pattern because cannabis is
such a short crop you know you want the
symbiosis to get going fast so you have
a concentrated product that it's a alive
and close to the root system as a
wettable powder
yeah okay I think in the past I had read
some sort of different units used in I
think it might have been like BTU or
something like that and they're talking
in the billions or the thousands are
there different sort of units used to
sort of measure the activity of the
product or it's all standardized in like
the Spore count
uh I would like it to be standardized
but it really isn't most mycorizing
products out there are listed as
propagal uh which isn't necessarily a
bad thing propagos is a real term you
know but probably propagals stand for
any part of the fungi that may connect
with the root system eventually
but at the same time that could be a
knife feed it could be a root fragment
with some physical you know it could be
an unviable spores and all of that is
counted into the concentration of the
product but at the end of the day none
of those structure is going to have an
impact on on the plan only viable spores
are able to efficiently colonize the
roots so that's why we don't even count
those in promise connect it's strictly 6
000 viable spores and you can often see
product out there let's say for example
500 purples per gram but at the end of
the day you end up having like 50 10
viable spores in inside the program so
you know we would like to get more
education out there about mycorrhizino
viable spores versus propagals because
definitely it make a big difference
between two products
yeah I guess if someone had used
mycorrhizer in the past and they hadn't
felt like they got particularly good
benefit from it maybe they just need to
try again with something with a bit more
guaranteed activity in the Box do you
think
yeah definitely uh you know there's a
lot of product out there and I don't
want to do any name drop or or anything
but you know uh the viability of the the
product is just isn't there each and
every year permitech we test every
product on the market and you know uh
the viability of the product is just
everywhere all over the place it's it's
it's really rare that a product uh came
up with the same claim as uh as it says
on the packaging so I would definitely
say to try you know a product that
guaranteed a viability of their spores
yeah okay good stuff good stuff so I
mean I guess I'm wondering if you were
trying to sort of describe to someone
Mike Horizon who you know not so
familiar with the ins and outs of it and
they're just sort of looking for the
major points how would you describe the
major benefits of using it
you know it it's all linked together of
course because you know you're having
you pick up nutrients and more water
more easily but all the benefits we're
basically putting them in four
categories uh it would say it would be
like healthier in an inch root system
first uh you know because having that
iPhone network helping the root system
you're able to have like a bigger root
mass you know a bigger nicest
establishment of your root system uh and
then you go at faster growth and yet you
know it make only sense since you've
picked up nutrient and water uh easier
you're going to be able to put more mass
quickly and that's it's kind of a big
deal because being able to put more mass
quickly you're able sometimes to shove a
couple of days of badge which in a
commercial standpoint is a really really
useful useful thing
um after that I would say it of course
the increased crop yield you're able to
have a bigger structure and be most more
energy every available you're able to
produce you know a bigger flower at the
end
and the last thing in my mind the most
important is is higher quality
consistently we've tested higher
terpenes content and and um and
cannabinoids
yeah some really strong selling points
there though I think a lot of people who
listen to this show are probably already
quite Avid fans of mycorrhizae so it's
now just time to get onto the pro-mix
train and see what benefits it has in
store
something I was wondering given you guys
are now doing the pro-mix connect is
what is the the future of Premier Tech
are there any sort of fields you guys
are thinking about expanding into or is
there a a further step with the
mycorrhizal products you want to go in
where do you see yourself you where do
you see the company going in the future
well you know I would like to elaborate
on that but of course I cannot you know
tell too much about it but I you know
protect has always been a company about
Innovation and research so I can
definitely tell you that we're always
working on something and I can tell you
that we're specifically working on
something on cannabis we have a lot of
Technologies available that uh
eventually were be able to maybe bring
to the market so we're definitely
working on some stuff I'm I'm hoping to
uh to bring them to the market as soon
as possible you know
exciting we'll have to keep our eyes
open for that one I mean probably not
going to be too hard for people but
where can people find pro-mix connect if
they're looking to give it a try
uh I can probably provide you with uh
with the link we have a landing page
about the connect uh it listed all the
address or that is available and when
we're also online uh with uh indoor
growing Canada which is available all
across Canada as well and it
probably in the US in the next couple of
couple of weeks so yeah pretty much
available all across North America
ah fantastic and I mean long term do you
expect that people will probably be able
to find it in you know their sort of
local grow store or their best bet is
just to go online get it shipped
directly to them
uh depend on your habits we're
definitely not taking the hydro store
out where we want to gather the hydro
store space because we still believe
that it's it's a strong space to be in
uh but of course with everything that
happened in the last the last year
um you know e-commerce has come a long
way so you know we're gonna try to be
available on that space as well
so and I mean for the people who like to
go to the face-to-face events when they
resume back up do you guys have stalls
there can people come and ask you
questions things like that
uh you know we're gonna start to get
more and more out there uh you know the
world is kind of starting it again so
we're at a lot of uh show throughout the
years we're gonna you know be be out
there interacting with people so yes uh
I cannot in the top of Maya top of my
head tell you all the shows that we're
gonna be in but definitely we're gonna
be out there
yeah now that's good to hear hopefully
people can catch you at some of the
shows and one of the final questions I
have for you is some of our listeners
operate bigger size facilities and sort
of you know have those more serious
operations do you guys provide different
sizing are there sort of bigger bundles
available to people if they're looking
to get like you know a sort of
substantially bigger size
uh the biggest size that we have
available is 2.5 kilogram uh which three
is around 700 plan uh depending on how
you use it so that's that's our biggest
packaging uh but of course
um it's easier to go into like a bigger
bigger format for like let's say a big
big big customer so we're open to maybe
having having something bigger
eventually
so sort of in line with that topic we
were talking about earlier where you
know some products advertise in
different units and they're different
sizes and different prices and it it can
become quite complex quite quickly do
you feel that there's an easy way to
sort of Judge what is bringing value in
terms of a mycorrhizal product
uh yeah of course that you know there's
a lot of product out there so it's come
confusing like very quickly but the
thing that you need to look at basically
is the number of valuable spores you
know because a lot of people out there
are shopping a price for a weight but at
the end of the day you're not paying for
a carrier you don't want to pay for clay
you're paying for mycoresi and what
brings value to my crazy is the number
of variable spores so yes some product
like Pro mix connect we know it we're
high-end product of course but at six
thousand viable spores when you take it
into account we're kind of the most
affordable crazy product out there based
on the concentration
yeah that makes total sense and I think
that's just about everything I had to
ask you Matt thanks so much for coming
on the show were there any comments
shout outs anything you wanted to say
uh you know we're we're trying to get
more and more involved with the
community on uh our Instagram to come
and interact with us on promix cannabis
and also myself on pro-mix Matt you know
uh you you are welcome to it me on my
DMs anytime so uh yeah that's pretty
much it
amazing you know and thank you so much
to both yourself and everyone at promix
who's on board with helping support the
show you know we really appreciate you
guys being able to help us make the
shows happen and it was fantastic to
have you on and get a rundown about all
the ins and outs of Pro mix connect
well I had a blast on you on your show
and thank you for having me yeah maybe
that I'm gonna come back at some point
what do you think guys some awesome
knowledge there from Matt at Premier
Tech thanks so much again Matt up next
we have Kevin of Copic biological
systems
very grateful to have him on the show
let's jump straight into it gang
alrighty so huge shout out and welcome
to one of the IPM Specialists from
copper biological systems thank you so
much Kevin for taking the time to join
me today and to talk all things IPM
oh thanks for having me man not a
problem at all how you doing today
I'm doing good
that's good to hear that's good to hear
so to start out I was hoping you might
be able to give me a little bit of
background on yourself and how you ended
up coming to work with coppet
um I've always actually couldn't grow I
grew up in the greenhouse industry like
in the commercial originates from the
commercial ornamental industry I worked
for since I was like 15 and that's all
I've ever did is what I went to school
for and then I used to be a grower at a
big commercial greenhouse and then I
moved into some other aspects of it and
then I ended up at corporate about 15
years ago and they were kind of always
around in the industry they're you know
back in the day they weren't quite as
prevalent style controls one is uh
commonly used but uh yeah when it
started to take off and it was always
something that interests me so I
switched over to uh to working here
wow that's a that's a cool little Story
I mean it must have been an interesting
journey to sort of transition from you
know like a non-cannabis related
Horticultural field to sort of being
more in the in the active scene of the
the Cannabis related field have you
enjoyed that so far
yeah like just to be clear I kind of
grew up around both things I was always
kind of involved in the Cannabis
industry at the same time
um back in the as kind of involved in
the early days in the medical scene in
Canada and I used to work actually it
used to be the cultivation writer for uh
cannabis Culture magazine but this is
back in like the 90s and then that kind
of had an equal footing both in the
commercial Greenhouse part and uh
and the Cannabis part as well
yeah awesome okay yeah so quite a quite
a depth of experience you've already got
under your belt so one of the things I
wanted to sort of start out chatting
with or the place I wanted to start our
discussion was sort of the utility and
the benefits of predator mites it's been
something which for example in Australia
has only recently sort of come to light
whereas I'm sure in places like Canada
and America where the technology has
been established there a bit longer
probably more aware of it and whatnot
but I guess something I'd love to talk
about starting out is how would you
describe predator mites and what would
be sort of a sales pitch for someone
who's a bit on the fern so not quite
sure how to use them or what they're
used for
yeah I think the first thing is that I
think maybe what people don't realize is
how long they've actually been used for
so
um everyone a lot of the people in the
canvas industry they kind of seem to
think that it's like this new thing when
cannabis started it's really been going
on like since the 80s at least in uh
commercial uh
vegetables it wasn't in ornamentals uh
up until somewhat more recent but
um it was always just not an organic
vegetable position like conventional
vegetables it's always been a standard
um
and in the last like I said I've been
here 15 years and probably most of the
time I've been here it was also
ornamentals this became a standard
um so canvas is kind of the last thing
so it's a very well proven strategy
um and most of the most of our customers
like a lot of people think that bio
controls is something that it's like a
cosmetic type of thing or makes you feel
good that you're doing it but most of
our customers are actually like
conventional AG that they're not organic
or anything they just use it because
it's actually a really good cost
effective solution but they use it in
combination with you know pesticides or
or other other strategies
that's a really brilliant point the
utility of predators across multiple
different systems I guess a lot of
people who follow the organic principles
of growing are generally sort of
interested in this sort of holistic
style of management and whatnot how best
should people apply Predator mine so
I've always sort of advocated to people
that you know if you imagine you're a
city and your city's under attack you
kind of want to have the Army already
there ready to go to help defend you
rather than having to master it up once
you're under attack and you know
everything's on fire and it's a bit of
an issue do you agree with that do you
think people should sort of
prophylactically be using predator mites
to help mitigate any potential issues or
do you more Advocate to use them when
required
uh definitely proactively but you can
also use them like curatively so I'd say
the real answer is it's a combination
you want to have them in the crop but
you usually need to kind of switch gears
into different predator mites when you
get a situation so for instance like
kind of a standard in cannabis is
um generally people are picking kind of
a generalist Predator is kind of like
their base so that would be it's
typically swersky or cucamaris and it's
a predator might that it's a generous
where it can eat a lot of different
stuff but it's primarily Focus like it's
preferences thrips which is generally on
cannabis kind of the main test
um so you're kind of working from that
and then you stack other stuff on top if
you have the issues so sorry they would
Source or cucamaris would kind of be the
base and then if you're in a garden that
you know consistently has like spider
mite problems that you're expecting then
we would put in uh spycal which is the
tree name but it's California and that's
kind of for spider mites it's like a
preventative level but then for instance
if you get Spiderman's kind of raging a
little bit you need to move over to
spitex which is persimuless so they've
all got kind of their own little niche
so a lot of it's about starting off
preventatively and stacking them
accordingly
yeah that's a that's a great point you
make there and it sort of segues into
the next question I had for you which
was that if you look on the website
there's really nice information about
the different Predators what they can be
used to combat a whole bunch of
interesting and wonderful extra bits of
information and something I noticed
which you sort of just touched on is
that they can be a bit of overlap you
know you read different predators and
maybe a commonality between a few
different ones you read about is that
they're all good for affids for example
so my question would be how would you go
about selecting the product to use if
you're seeing a few of them that all uh
covering aphids for example are you safe
with any of them is there a way in which
you might figure out one maybe out edges
the other's a little better for your
situation how would you go about
choosing that
so when you get into aphids in
particular that's
probably for sure the most tricky one
when it comes to anything especially
cannabis because that's one that their
the controls are very like the Predators
are very specific to the type of acids
so the absolute
first thing you need to do is actually
ID what type of aphid you're dealing
with most of the time and I'll say
there's a couple of caveats it's a it's
a big box that Aphid control thing so if
you're using parasitoids which is kind
of our usually our standard approach on
most crops so a parasitoid
um it's like a wasp not like a wasp
sting she was just a parasitic wash like
kind of maybe as big as a mosquito or
something and what it does is it's
really good at searching the crop so
it'll fly the crop and it's smelling out
aphids and when it finds an aphid it
lays its egg in the aphid and makes
what's called a mummy
um
so and then instead of the aphid so the
aphid slowly dies the parasite takes
over and at the end another parasite
hatches out of the eight so that's
usually our standard because it's a
really nice thing to keep going in your
crop because you only just it just you
know for every one if it you know for
one bio control you put out there I'm
just making up a number I don't know how
many years but let's say it's 48 bits
that it parasitizes so for every one
aphid you put in you're actually getting
40 back you know the first two weeks
later and then all of those go and lay
eggs of salads so it really Builds an
Army in the crop so for that those
parasitoids are very
um specific so for instance if you're
dealing with like cannabis aphid
um the one this kind of three main
parasitoids and we found one of them
works a lot better on
for RV works as well fairly well and
then
um Coleman he doesn't work Coleman he's
another parasitic boss doesn't work
hardly at all
um so you really have to be very
specific because if you go at it with
the wrong Paris to it it'll literally do
nothing
so we kind of go at it from a couple of
approaches so that's the parasitic wasp
is kind of the more traditional approach
and then you've got like a completely
different approach which would be more
like a predator bug so that's what when
people think about ladybugs that's what
a ladybug is just like actually eating
the the aphid we don't use ladybugs too
much but we use a lot of lace Wings in
cannabis
um
so the you know the advantage on
cannabis I guess in some situations is
that the lacewings are eating
indiscriminate so you don't have to ID
the aphid anymore it's just going to eat
whatever it sees and it also doesn't
leave aphids in the crop which sometimes
parasitoids because they're leaving that
little you know little zombie mummy is
still there you can get some crop
contamination potentially so the lace
Wing is just eating it completely you
don't have to worry about iding it but
the downside is in order for a lace Wing
to reproduce where a parasitic wasp only
needs one egg lay swing needs again I'm
making them I'm not kind of all these
numbers memorized but let's say it needs
to eat 20 aphids to get enough protein
to reproduce
so a lot of the time it's not getting 20
aphids so it's it's not really
reproducing so you just kind of putting
it in almost like a pesticide you put it
out it crawls around eats a bunch of
aphids and then it dies so
I still think no matter what you're
always really the most important thing
if Aphid control is ID in the aphid and
a lot of times from that you really need
to talk to an expert like a bio control
company or somebody like that that can
an entomologist that can actually say no
that's cannabis aphid or whatever that's
always like the first step in most pest
control make sure you actually know what
you're dealing with
yeah brilliant answer and you you sort
of raise two really good Avenues I'd
love to pursue a little more I mean just
on the end there you mentioned the
Cannabis aphid which some people
probably be aware of but yeah over the
past few years we've seen the emergence
of this new sort of aphid which seems
specific for cannabis I guess the
question is do you think that it's
inevitable as a cannabis community so to
speak that it's going to sort of
inadvertently cause the development of
new and resistant bugs over time
yeah I mean that's an interesting one
because like I said I've been around
like canvas Institute for like 30 years
and that really appeared in Canada
exactly when we legalized and the
difference was there I'm sure it was
around but I mean it's really just
spread almost 100 just by trading with
cuttings and I think there just wasn't
that kind of trade in the old black
market days of vegetative material like
it was traded amongst like Crews and
stuff like that you know like groups but
they wasn't traded like wide scale and
that's what we saw as soon as you know
that LP Market got established in Canada
it just both cannabis aphid and rude if
it just blew up
um and almost I would I honestly never
even heard of it before probably kind of
whatever that happened seven years ago
or something and now it's probably one
of the biggest pests in in Canada so I
think the opening of markets really uh
can be a big Vector for that because a
lot of these are you've seen the same
thing with it hopsulating virus where
um you know it's really just everywhere
now it's another one that probably
barely existed before because there
wasn't that much trading of clones back
in the old days
yeah that certainly makes sense I mean
just to take it one more step maybe
towards sort of the more you know quote
conspiracy theory stuff I remember in
the past I used to read people talking
about how they used to think that the US
government was releasing mites on the
side of the road and stuff to to combat
sort of vegetative growth and I always
thought that sounded a bit far-fetched
and then I found a document one day
which said like maybe they're actually
doing that and that's contributed to
like these mites getting then on
cannabis plants and things like that
have you ever heard or read anything
like that
I have and it I would say it's probably
not as crazy as it sounds because having
grown up in like the 1980s I remember
like I've never seen anything to say
that was the case and I personally
lean away from that being the case but I
mean if you were around back in the 80s
or I think it was early 90s I mean the
DEA 100 was releasing fusarium into
cannabis crops in other countries I
think there's a fair bit of evidence
they've probably released it into
Humboldt like in the you know
concentrated cannabis areas so I mean
it's not unheard of like that that for
sure using you know introducing Pastor
diseases
to control cannabis is a real thing like
that's a hundred percent verifiable the
DEA did do that if you look both for
cannabis and cocaine you can look if you
Google if anyone wants to Google that I
mean there's a ton of evidence that that
happened down in Colombia and elsewhere
um
the Russian so I mean could they do
something like that I personally doubt
it because I mean
at the time it wasn't really something
like a rusted might wasn't really
something that was likely to spread like
that especially back in the black market
days because I said people just weren't
the only way you're gonna really spread
that around is by trading cuttings and
uh so I personally doubt it I think it's
probably like most crops crop pests
where if I had to look into rust it
might it seems like it kind of emerged
probably out of California I know
there's a lot of that similar type of
Might on
you know and when we're talking about
how for us it might that's for sure a
real thing whether that's the majority
of what we're seeing nobody knows
because that's that type of Might is
called a tersona midnight and it's like
a cyclamenite abroad might they're all
in that type of class with these tiny
little mic nobody knows that much about
them so for sure Empress it might is a
real thing whether that is a hundred
percent of all that type of mites we see
on cannabis or one percent I don't think
anybody really knows so if it was time
for us it might I would assume it must
have had to come from hemp at some point
I don't know the details but if it's
some of those other ones it could have
come from like for instance grapes where
they get a lot of that or fruit crops
where they get a lot of that type of
personamic mice you know and what
happens is that ignosis from where I
live is there's a lot of it's a really
intensive agriculture so you'll get like
let's say corn growing right beside a
greenhouse that's full of tomatoes and
there'll be one pest on the corn that
never and even though the corn is only
you know 10 feet away from the Tomatoes
they've got they don't the thrips that's
on the corn isn't on the tomatoes but
eventually sometimes that jumps so what
will happen is you know one strips will
just be a little bit more genetically
adapted to tomatoes you know when you're
you know there's a bazillion thrips
landing on those tomatoes from the corn
every year sooner or later you get a
couple that are more genetically adapted
to that crop they start reproducing and
bang all of a sudden I've seen that
we've got a tomato thrips in my town
um so I think it's more likely something
like that where you know some guy was
you know growing OG beside a Vineyard
and and got some
mites in from there but I mean who knows
never underestimate for the DEA
no that's that's some good Insight I
like that explanation it's probably yeah
some sort of blend of the two just to
jump back to something you mentioned
earlier when I first heard about
Predators I remember in every
conversation I had people were just like
ladybugs ladybugs ladybugs and I guess
as time's gone by I've sort of heard
less and less about them I also remember
that uh praying mantises were like also
you know in that uh top tier Echelon of
predators with ladybugs my question is
in reality do these Predators provide
you know really effective cover that
people talk about because I think when
you look up online you know the little
tables which show you you know what bugs
get eaten by what ladybugs and praying
mantises are often toted as you know
they'll eat everything they're just like
the cure-all do you think that's maybe
not quite the reality of the situation
um yeah so praying mantises I would just
you can fly and say they're really not a
tool they're a cool thing if you just
want to see a praying mantis wandering
around in your garden and it will eat
some pests other than that I would say
as far as I would be aware it has
absolutely no place in your garden
um the reason for praying mantis is
pretty simple so it's
a lot of what goes on with bio control
is how what the numeric response is to
the pest so how quickly that biocontrol
repurpose a lot of the control isn't
coming necessarily from your releasing
it's coming from what you release
building up in the crop like reproducing
so something like for instance let's say
let's say spider mites so if you were to
use persimulus which is kind of the main
thing that people use for spider mite I
think the life cycle reproduction is
like seven days or something like that
so every seven days you're getting a
whole new round of the stimulus in your
crop well praying mantis I believe it's
like once a year maybe it's twice a year
I don't know I I don't know so really
what you're getting is just that one
praying mantis you put in so that's kind
of one of the things that people really
miss when it comes to that stuff and
then ladybugs is a little bit more
complicated where I think ladybugs is
unfortunate the first thing people think
of when they think about bio control and
it is really one of the least like
outside of the Cannabis industry leave
us basically aren't even talked about
they're almost a non-issue
um and that's kind of for a different
reason so again we go back to people are
saying oh they're great they're
generalists that's a lot of the time
don't really want what you need is like
something that's just focused on eating
your pests that you have otherwise you
can get
um weird stuff like I've actually seen
this for instance on some other
um
things I've seen it once with one of the
predatory mics that was a kind of a
generalist as soon as they've got tray
preferences so we for instance put
something in for Crips and there was
also white fly and it just really liked
eating white fly and the strips went
from almost no thrips to taking down the
crop while this Predator was eating
Wi-Fi it doesn't happen all the time but
that's kind of like when you're talking
about ladybugs you never know really
what they're gonna do but mostly
ladybugs they're they're they are a
Genus but mostly they're focused on
aphids so
where that
um where they're typically used again
again none of this is really new right
we've been using bio control on
vegetable crops for a long long time at
the standard so it's very dialed in like
which bios have which place in the
program so where ladybugs are
traditionally used like their strength
is they're really good at like cleaning
up a nasty hot spot so we would for
instance have use them a lot in Peppers
or not a lot but sometimes
um
so Peppers you would use parasitic wasps
generally to control your Apes that's
kind of like your first plan
um because like I said before because
they're late you know I only need one
aphid to reproduce so they're really
good for cycling themselves in the crop
so they don't have to keep introducing
them so we kind of use that then we used
something called aphidend which is like
a gold Midge so that kind of is more for
working more on hot spots so how a gall
Midge works is it will
instead of laying its eggs in the
in the past like a parasitic wash will
it lays its eggs underneath it so what
it'll do is find a real nasty hot spot
lay a bunch of eggs in the hot spot and
then it's the larval stage that eats the
aphids so it's kind of a bit better in
hot spots so it's kind of our backbone
of the program is the parasitic wasp so
if you're talking cannabis it would
probably be
a-fibar M so matricaria and then in some
situations we might use
um the fidelities and then if you had a
hot spot you would use something like we
usually use lace wings but you could
also use ladybugs just to clean up that
hot spot which would be a very small
amount because the where where ladybugs
outshine some of the other bio controls
is for instance aphids they
hoop out like a honeydew so when they're
eating all the plants they they're
constantly excreting this kind of sticky
substance
um which is just their excrement and
that kind of if you ever see like a
nasty aphid spot the whole plant will
kind of glistening it's this honeydew
that they're secreting well that
honeydew a lot of the bio controls don't
like because they've got to like they
get it on them and they get to spend all
their time cleaning the Honeydew off
instead of actually cleaning up your
pests but ladybugs and others and
lacewings they like it like they just
get right in there so other bio controls
don't really get into those really nasty
hot spots but ladybugs or lacewings do
so that's kind of your place but for the
average like honestly if I was a
commercial cannabis place I honestly
wouldn't even use that like not that's
that's little how little I think they
actually have a place
no what a brilliant explanation you've
helped me to sort of piece together many
of the little thoughts I've had about
ladybugs over the years so that that's
great thank you so much and sort of
another topic which I often hear raised
in the discussion of IPM is that it's
often only regularly discussed by the
people I talk to who are sort of indoor
but now that there's a much bigger
growing Market of people who are able to
venture into the outdoor because of
changing legalities in their local areas
things like that I guess it sort of
raises the question of how do you make
selections between the use of predators
in indoor versus outdoor and I guess the
primary aspect I'm interested in is that
whenever I talk to people about using it
in Outdoors there's sort of this
perception that the bugs will just
disappear into the local environment
whereas indoor you know like it's in a
tent and they're gonna stay there so to
speak do you think that's a bit of a
misconception are you able to
effectively use Predators Outdoors
um it's not a misconception it's not
entirely true so the so basically it
depends on which Predator you're using
so if any of the Predator might you can
definitely use them Outdoors um they've
been used
um like I said one of our some of our
largest you know business through our
time has been
um in outdoor strawberries like in
California and Florida that's been
standard for decades using predator
mites Outdoors for
um broad might and Spiderman control so
predator mites they can't fly right so
they're stuck wherever you put them so
you might have a predator Mite that
doesn't like the environment and doesn't
do very well in it but generally if you
put a predator mic that does well in
that environment
um they do fine they're not going
anywhere you don't need to worry about
that so that's definitely not true when
it comes to Predator events you can use
them exactly how you're going to use
them indoors and if the environment is
correct for them they're fine when you
get into some of the flying
um Predators then that's a very
different story which I would say nobody
anyone that tells you they know exactly
what the answer is to that I would say
they're probably full of it
um so there's a there's a lot of stuff
going on out there so how a lot of
predators
um
like parasite wash and stuff work is
they actually smell
um when pet when plants are under attack
they actually kind of let off like a
pheromone type of thing so there's like
a scent plume coming from
um
let's say you got a haze plant that's
got whatever aphids or spider mites it's
letting off a plume of this like alarm
set
um which is there to attract
um the Predators and some predators are
very tuned to that so they will you know
follow that plume which can travel for
really a long way and that's how they
find the best that they need to feed on
so the problem is when you're going
outside let's say you know you've got an
aphid you're releasing something for
aphids well are they attracted to you
know they might get distracted by you
know the scent plume coming from a tree
in the nearby field or maybe not like if
it's so nobody really knows like I've
definitely seen outdoors in in cannabis
and other crops where that type of stuff
did work I think it's just it's kind of
hit or miss you really don't know so you
could release something that's going to
fly into an aphid spot and then they're
you know just spreading around your crop
or they might like some other aphid
species it's just a really they might
like some other aphid species on a
different crop better it's just a really
complex subject that I don't think
anybody really knows so the other thing
with Outdoors is the pest Dynamic is
very different at least in Canada so we
really don't have any of the pests that
we're dealing with like thrips really
haven't proven to be an issue outdoors I
haven't really seen spider mites be an
issue outdoors I think they could be in
some environments when it's drier maybe
I've seen a little bit of rust it might
but basically a lot of the pest and
images is completely different than what
like there's not necessarily a
biocontrol solution so the main thing
that we've been doing on outdoor
cannabis is actually lace Wings because
the other thing you get into Outdoors
it's a lot lower value crop in
especially in Canada most of it's just
going into the extract market so first
of all they've got a higher tolerance
for pest levels because they're just
turning into isolate or something and
um and you also get natural predators
are coming in too right so
out there the kind of strategy that
we've seen is like the biggest issue
that we've seen that we actually have a
solution for is cannabis aphid and
usually that's a self-induced condition
where people have had cannabis aphid on
their clones that they put in that they
had inside and then they put them
outside and expression now you've got
cannabis safe and outside so what we've
kind of been doing is seeding with
lace-wing eggs so lacing eggs are kind
of an inexpensive version of lace wings
and we kind of see the whole crop a
couple of times with lace Wing eggs with
the idea that even though lacewings are
probably going to show up naturally
outdoors they might not show up until
like August where we can put them in
June 1st and then they start cycling in
the crop earlier and that seems to be I
mean it makes sense from a science level
and it seems to have worked but a lot of
the outdoor stuff on cannabis is really
it's Uncharted Territory
yeah fantastic response and yeah it
seems like a good way to sort of
um you know control aphid problems
outside
it makes me think you know there's so
many different types of predators and
there's many different formulation types
be it you know sometimes it's you know
maybe Predators spread amongst
vermiculite I've had Predators arrive
that are sort of on actively on the
leaves of another product and ready to
jump on to your crop things like that
you get sachets how do you know what's
the best one for you in any given
situation
um
that's when and for most situations is
usually sachets so the sachets are kind
of like the evolution I think a lot of
people don't cry this like the evolution
of Bio controls it all kind of started
off on bean leaves for instance that
that person for instance persimilus so
persimmona started off by being reared
on bean leaves and people would sell you
know you get a bean leaf with some
persimulus on it it's also usually got
some spider mites on it because by
default you got to have spider nights
there and you and sometimes some other
pests so then from there that evolved
into
um having whole greenhouses where they
would rear
a crop it's usually done on bean plants
um and then they would
have infested with spider mites then
they would infest that with persimulus
and then there's a special extraction
technique where you can basically vacuum
off the just the persimmas and leave the
spider mites behind
so and then the latest technology which
which we've just developed this year is
um rearing it on a fictitious host so
something other than fictitious host
just means something other than its
natural prey source so we just figured
out um that this year's how to do that
so then you don't have any risk of
introducing spider mites
um you it's a lot more standardized
production and you can actually get
better results because you can ship them
with food so they've got a higher for
gun to do which means they can lay more
eggs in the crop so anytime when you're
buying stuff on bean leaves you're like
going back a couple of decades so kind
of the evolution was being leaves with
on the in the case of persimulus or
other stuff would have been
for other types of mice like for
instance cucamaris or swarovsky they're
californicus they're reared on
a fictitious host so it's usually a
brand might which is kind of like a it's
just a Mite that feeds on brand and
basically they're reared in climate
rooms
with bran
than the brand might it's eating the
brand and then the Swarovski or the
Cucumbers is eating the feeder knife so
kind of the first you know wave of Bio
control was just selling that loose so
you'd buy the brand with the feeder Mite
and the
um square feet on it
um the vermiculate they're talking was
actually evolved from that so
vermiculate is a way to get rid of the
feeder mites so some crops are really
sensitive to those feeder mites they can
damage certain crops
um so they would filter the feeder mites
out and put them on vermiculite so there
was no food source for the feeder right
so that's really the only reason to use
something on vermiculate
for predator mics it's different with
other uh with other bios would be if you
get a crop that's sensitive to feeder
mites which cannabis isn't and we don't
even use that type of feeder right that
causes damage anymore or
for ornamentals where you don't want the
carrier like let's say you're growing
poinsettias or cannabis would be the
same let's say you're putting a loose
application of bran on your cannabis and
then maybe you're doing a foliar spray
well that sticks that brand Like Glue to
your leaf or your butt or whatever and
then a lot of times it molds and it's
like a contamination issue so it was
traditionally ornamental Growers would
use that vermiculite product so it
didn't stick to the plant
so then the final evolution was these
sachets so what a sachet is it's
basically taking that breeding system
the brand the brand mites and the feeder
and the actual Predator might you want
and putting it into basically a little
envelope just kind of keeps the humidity
up in it so it keeps like a breeding
system going so
um or rather than if you put loose
material in your crop you're just
getting whatever was in that bottle and
then whatever reproduces in the crop
with sachets it's releasing like for
instance the regular sachets that we
would use in canvas they usually last
about four weeks so they're constantly
releasing predator mites into the crop
so that's for sure always the vast
majority of cases sachets are hands down
the better way to go you don't get
contamination of material into your crop
because it's contained in the sachet
it's far cheaper because it's breeding
itself and you're just getting a
continued release another reason is what
specifically on cannabis why the sachets
are really a good idea is because in
order for predator mites to reproduce
they lay their eggs on specialized plant
hair so kind of like a trichome
um and people with cannabis probably
aren't you know exactly what I'm talking
about because canvas doesn't really have
the type of trichome that they like so
imagine you know a cannabis it's got
like the glandular stocked trichome and
then I think they're called capitate
sessile ones which is just like kind of
like a little hair so they like to lay
their eggs on something similar to like
a cavity specile trichoma just like a
thin plant hair and canvas doesn't
really have a lot of them it's like
they're very specific about the size and
everything so I wouldn't say you don't
get any reproduction on cannabis but you
get really low compared to a lot of
plants like a swarce will reproduce way
better on like a cucumber plant or a
pepper plant than it will on cannabis so
because it's not really reproducing that
well you really want to be having a
constant source of them releasing into
your crop so that's where the sachets
really are to me a hands down because
did you you hang in your crop once
they're giving you continual release
into the crop for four weeks
wow yeah really comprehensive answer and
you touched on a few things I'd love to
segue into so that that's perfect and
you know it sort of using the the sachet
Innovation as a springboard something
else I noticed that you guys are doing
really well which I haven't really seen
many other places in terms of innovation
is the the feeding sachets
and I had a few questions around them I
guess most notably uh you know sort of
at the Forefront of my mind is are these
feeding sachets sort of something to
help you bridge the current Predator
armor you've got to say you know a few
weeks ahead or are they able to be used
sort of indefinitely and if someone had
purchased you know a reasonable size
amount of predators they might be able
to sustain a pretty good percentage of
that population over the long term with
regular feed sachet use
and we do have one type for prisimless
which is just a release sachet which is
just it's literally just to stop the
carrier from getting in the crop if
you're in flour all the other ones are
breeding sachets so they've got the food
and everything in there
um so they're that that's what's
happening is it's for all the food is in
that sachet and it's like a it's a life
just it's a life cycle in there so the
prey mites it's cycling in there and
constantly coming out so there's no such
thing as like a feeder sachet there is
like some
um sometimes we'll put in it's not a big
part of the industry but there's two
things you can do on top of that which
maybe I think you're maybe thinking of
is where you're actually putting some
food in the crop for the predator mites
to
it boosts the numbers so you can put we
generally use again those feeder mites
we'll just sell bottles of just those
feeder mites and put them in the crop
and that works because it's uh so this
feeder mites there's pollen and there's
some other stuff like like our team our
team in which is kind of like a brine
shrimp different feeding sources I'm
generally not a big believer in them on
especially on cannabis because they I
don't find they're needed a ton on that
crop and they also are a big source of
contaminants so to me I'm like when
you're putting brine shrimp on something
like that at the end of the day like
somebody smelling might have a shellfish
allergy I don't know but it's a source
of potential contamination and the same
with pollen so all that pollen that
people
will use on it first of all it can feed
thrips so you're also feeding
um the pest where so that's not a good
thing
um okay it's a complicated issue there's
some situations where I'd say that is a
good idea most of the time I'd say no
when why we prefer just using the
um the feeder mice is because it doesn't
feed the pests so as first gear or
cucamaris it nutritionally is a lot
better for it to eat protein than a like
it's going to make it reproduce better
and then you don't have to worry about a
thrift thrips is an AEP beater might
um
so I think that's maybe what you're
thinking but there's also some other for
some other bios there's like cards and
stuff that can hang in the crop I'm I
said I personally am not a big believer
on with it on cannabis for a bunch of
reasons the other thing you gotta
remember with pollen is all that pollen
mostly comes from China and wherever it
comes from so it's cocktail pollen and
the pesticide residue not that they're
spraying it but like most stuff has
pesticide residue like maybe it's close
to an agricultural crop or whatever it
goes through the water table
um so you never know what you're
actually introducing into your crop like
when you're getting residue testing if
you're putting pollen out there you know
and pollen quite often can have
pesticide residue in it in some level so
I think that's probably what you're
mistaken but
um yeah sachets is just generally a
sachet is a breeding sachet and that's a
system on its own
yeah no thank you for the clarification
I think I had read about Brian shrimp
when you were talking about but yeah
that you answered the question
nevertheless so thank you very much and
I mean while we're on the topic of crop
contamination something I had heard from
primarily soilless Growers actually
whenever the topic of predators were
raised was that it sort of always came
across as this sort of contrarian thing
to say in my opinion but they would say
oh you know yeah predator mites but
don't they just eat the bad predators
and then they still poo on the plan and
then that's contamination blah blah blah
I had never really heard of this being a
meaningful issue or something that had
sort of been considered a realistic
detract and from using predators and
then it also negates the point that
you've gotten rid of the infestation
which is you know sort of the number one
goal what's your view on that sort of
opinion that even Predators will put
excrement on the plant is it something
you think there's any real Merit to
worrying about it's more of a
superficial concern to a meaningful
solution to an actual bug infestation
I think that would be another one the
answer would be both um it can be a
issue I would say it's not generally
issue it's like anything you have to use
stuff correctly if it's used correctly
it's a non-issue so I would first of all
caveat like Canada for anyone like
that's not familiar with it's probably
the most regulated cannabis Market in
the world because it's always been
regulated not always but since it's been
legal it's been regulated on a federal
level by the government so it's it's on
kind of ridiculous how regulated the
market is so everything is like as far
as contaminants
I would say we 100 have the most
regulated market that comes from that
and it is essentially never come up the
only time I've ever seen it come up
which was issues when it was both the
past there was pest in the crop that was
contaminating it and yes there was bios
in the crop also that was eating the
pest so I'd say well does it really make
a difference whether you've got spider
mites and for stimulus in your
contamination or just Spider-Mans it's
the same thing so where I would so I'd
say mostly it's a non-issue but I do
think it is a potential issue so I'd say
if you've got pests in the crop anyways
I don't think it really makes any
difference but a lot of the cases like
we're trying not to have pests in there
so that's when you really have to have a
strategy when you go about it so the the
issue with those sachets that you need
to be aware about so most stuff it's not
going to reproducing the crop unless
it's got it passed for instance like if
you put for stimulus in a spider mite
crop or in a spider-made infested crop
where stimulus will keep reproducing in
the crop as long as there's spider mites
there within about a week of there being
no spider mites they disappear it
cannibalizes itself and it's gone so
that's really a non-issue but when you
get breeding sachets it can be an issue
because then it's giving a source of
food so that sachet basically you hang
that in your crop it's releasing feeder
mites and predator mites in your crop
for about four weeks so when with our
program we always front load something
so for instance in cannabis for like
swersky or californicus we would only
ever put sachets in like right when your
crops going into flowering that's kind
of like you do once the start of veg
basically like let's say you're vegging
for three weeks you're gonna put sachets
in then to cover your veg area you put
them into flour you put another round of
sachets in because the first ones would
have expired and then that's going to
kind of protect you up until your buds
start to stack you know for three or
four weeks what you don't and I do see
people do this sometimes what you really
don't want to do is be hanging them like
in week four and then you've got sachets
that are releasing right until week
eight well 100 you are going to get not
just fecal matter contamination but
actual might contamination is it a big
issue not really I don't think most of
the time you'll even see it but I
personally wouldn't do it to me like you
really want to finish that you know the
last
half of your crop with nothing in it
like there should be no pest there there
should be no bio controls you know so so
it's like one of the things it's people
blow it up the way people talk about it
I'd say that's really not an issue yes
the Predator might poop absolutely still
to pass like so it's it's one of those
things you just need to time the
applications properly and it's and it's
a non-issue yeah a great answer there I
guess as you mentioned in an Ideal World
the second half of the the fruiting the
flowering phase there's sort of ideal
conditions but in a sort of more
realistic world one of the questions
which time and time again comes up is
how do I fight off an infestation that
I've only just realized is there like
week four week five you know so you're
on that second half you know it's a
tough question I understand but I guess
I'm always interested how would you
personally go about tackling say a mind
infestation that really only been picked
up around week four week five of flower
yeah there's not a great answer for that
because there it's one of those things
that this can Will bios do
help you there
yes can they turn again if we're talking
about Spider-Man specifically you're
really that's getting to the point where
it's the point of no return so what
happens with Predator mice is because
they're you know they live on the
underside of the leaf primarily there's
walking around the leaves like that's
how they hunt
um
and they'll walk like if you put a
predator might on you know one leaf
it'll walk up the whole plant walk to
the next Plant if the leaves are
touching like they get around but like
the you know trichomes that's what
they're there for is to protect the
plants against bugs right so predator
mites they'll get stuck in the trichomes
like it's toxic to them they get stuck
physically get stuck to it
um you know the terpenes probably in
some varieties are anti you know they're
probably mitochondyl
um
and also just a buzz just from a
physical like when you get you know a
dense butt a predator might can't
literally walk through it so let's say
you have spider mites I see this is a
pretty common problem where somebody
doesn't
they don't pay attention
all sudden they're like holy cow I got
spider mites and it's weak sticks or
something like that and then they want
to put stuff on well like you basically
have to put the persimilates on every
leaf you want it because it can't walk
through the buzz so there's some tricks
that you can kind of like you can do it
but like so on a home Garden it's
doable on a commercial Garden it's
pretty much impossible because you just
like that's bio control you're relying
on the bio control to do the work for
you of walking through the crop and
finding the pests and they just can't do
it anymore
um so there's stuff you can do but a lot
of that time you're really getting into
physical controls like you're getting
into you know wiping the leaves with
moist cloths or you know in commercial
really your only option is you know you
could spray them a bit with water to
break them up and the main option is
physical removal just going through
deleting this stuff and hoping for the
best there's really people want to hear
there's a great solution the great
solution is pay attention to your crop
earlier on because you didn't just get
spider mites in week four this doesn't
happen
yeah 100 100 and I guess that's one of
the reasons why you know we sort of
advocate you know spend time with your
plants you'll pick up on these things I
guess one of the options people would
maybe consider as you sort of referenced
it that uh week four week five
infestation stages they might think oh
I've got to spray with something uh
what's your what's your thoughts on neem
oil I I think something which I've heard
of a little bit is there's maybe a
little bit of a misconception like
people get predators and then they spray
neem oil and I'm like oh I think you're
killing the Predators there
um it doesn't really seem to be clear
consensus in some people's minds what's
your thoughts on neem oil and would you
ever use it in the presence of already
released predators
um I think neem oil probably has a place
I've definitely I've used it long long
ago we run into it a fair bit I
generally steer away from it and in
Canada in Canada neem oil for reasons
Beyond me is really highly regulated so
it doesn't actually come up like you're
not allowed to use it you're only
allowed to sell it so I have had a fair
bit of experience with people using it
so I'd rather than focus on neem I would
say just generally any type of Botanical
is a good idea to stay away from with
bio control so I I let's say two things
one I've never seen anybody actually
control pests properly with them people
all swear by it but they still all have
spider mites or thrips and neem is
definitely a powerful tool I mean we
both know that in certain situations
um in specifically in using it with bio
control
most and again most of our business is
in conventional agriculture so we've got
a lot of experience with side effects
like the side effects of pesticides of
all kinds on beneficial insects
every time not every time that most a
lot of our problems when you come into
side effects on beneficials come from
Botanicals that Botanicals have a just
like they're having an effect on your
mice of some level they're also having
an effect on your Predator lights so I
generally steer clear of them completely
um not just mean to rule it out I my
personal view is I'm big on like if I
want to spray I'm going to eat like
soaps work great if you use them well
soap is just like the second it's dry
you can put predators in there's no
residual like they're good to go same
with some of the
um the fungus like the Bavaria and stuff
like that uh entomopathogenic fungi
those are generally useful I personally
like after like I said I've kind of
grown up around all of it I've grown up
around the Canada scene I've grown up
around big commercial greenhouses where
they spray a lot of peptides and I've
grown up around Culper where we use a
lot of Bio control I personally on
cannabis would almost never spray like
that's one of the things that
people I really in the majority of
situations I would never sorry for a
past and I'm not just saying that
because I sell bio control I honestly
think you'll get better control with bio
control than you will with sprays most
of the time
um
it's one of the big myths I find in BIO
control is people really underestimate
how strong bio control and they is and
they overestimate how strong some magic
potion is
yeah a brilliant answer I you sort of
touched on just the topic just in your
answer you know sort of Bio control
myths I'd be interested to hear are
there any other sort of common bio
control myths that you find yourself
dealing with
um probably I mean that's a big one is
just that people really underestimate
they really don't
get how powerful it is like a lot of
people
um like I said I would like to use my
example of when I came from copper came
to covert initially I had this I had the
same perception where I thought it was
kind of like this you know it's it's
good you're not you're not affecting the
environment it probably don't work that
well but you know you know what it's
environmentally sound blah blah blah and
the first literally my first day at work
at COBRA they took me to this greenhouse
that was just the highest
um test pressure I've ever seen in my
life and they had literally
switch to buy up to almost entirely bio
controls because the pesticides just
didn't work so not that pesticides
didn't work they needed to use them so
frequently that the past had just become
resistant to them all so it was like in
a normal situation yeah that pesticide
worked great if you use it once or twice
a year not if you're using it you know
50 times a year and so that was really
eye-opening to me that when you got into
a situation like that and you're like
wow like they're not even this is the
highest pest pressure
I've ever seen in my life and they're
not even using Apex that they're
literally just battling it with bio
control and it's winning so that's one
of the big things I think people just
need to wrap their head around it's
really a strong tool
um one of the other ones that comes up
all the time is the climate so
definitely people like there's
definitely differences with
um different bio controls have different
climate preferences but people really
over complicate this so like first of
all like most crop plants grow in the
same rough you know temperature and
relative humidity situations
um so like you never have so people are
like oh I don't want to use persimmon's
because I've got this special climate
conditions I have like I said I've
worked here for 15 years I've basically
never seen anyone with a special climate
condition
um that you couldn't use bio control
with one caveat if you're growing some
crops nothing to do with cannabis that's
really cold then that's a situation on
cannabis it always works fine
um
do they work as well as they would in an
optimized climate like for instance one
of the big things is relative humidity
so a lot of Predator might be really
like a higher relative humidity
um so you know and you know when we're
finishing you know especially Indica
stranger going really way down like 40
45 relative humidity that's definitely
not ideal for a predator mic
but
one of the uh one of the Agricultural
research stations near where I live
actually did a big uh like a
peer-reviewed journal article years ago
on this and they actually measured the
climate conditions on the Philo plane
which is the you know the immediate Leaf
surface you know the underside of the
leaf and what they found is that phyllo
plane which is that's specifically where
the Predator might is living it huge
buffer against the environment so even
though we're going down and again I'm
making these numbers up so hold me
verbatim to them but like let's say
you're cranking your relative humidity
down for late flowering at like you know
40 or 45. that phyloplane
um climate it's probably still like 70
or something like that like it's very
hard to deviate to make that
microclimate change because they are
because of the stomata so the first of
all like the leaf is kind of shielding
it from the light the stomata is one of
the big things it's you know it's
letting it water vapor underneath the
leaf so in the you know we're just
talking about you know a quarter of a
millimeter or something like that it's
still humid there so they it's not as
big of a deal as they think about it
it's honestly something that unless your
temperature is under like 20 or 20
degrees Celsius all the time you don't
really need to worry about it
um they there are people be like oh he
doesn't know what he's talking about
there's
um their eggs dehydrated at a low
relative humidity that can sometimes be
true for sure but you can still use bio
control yes maybe it just doesn't
reproduce as well
um we've like I said bio control has
been absolutely standard in Canada for
cannabis production since the start of a
legalization so I know how many years
that is quite a few
um it's a Well proven thing
um less so in the U.S just because of a
couple other reasons just because they
have more pesticides and it was less
regulated but for sure in Canada
everybody's been using cannabis
um or bio control on cannabis since the
start everyone has very similar climates
it works fine
yeah brilliant explanation there and
given your experience in the Canadian
Market a question which a lot of the
American listeners are often sort of
interested in is what do you think will
be some of the biggest pest issues
facing the Cannabis market for example
in the US as it continues to expand and
get bigger and more people get involved
yeah well is this two things the biggest
pest issue I think is probably always is
going to be grips and spider mates but
they're also ones that there's good
tools for they're fairly easy to control
um might be a little bit different when
you get into down in this more Southern
parts of the US so one of the things you
get is like for instance if we look at
thrips that's for sure like one of the
big issues
um but we've got a lot of good tools
like all the bio controls work really
well on trips but 99 of all the trips we
deal with in Canada and Northern us is
Western Flower thrifts or onion trips
and we know bio control works really
well on that but there's thousands of
different types of trips so when you get
down into like you know Southern Florida
probably Southern California any of
those Southern areas there's a lot of
different types of thrips the biocontrol
doesn't work for so if that could emerge
as an issue or there's just not any
great tools like not the traditional
tools don't work that's to be seen right
now I would say the bigger issue is most
likely aphids
um because and maybe hempressive maybe
aggressively for two reasons or for one
the same reason is there's not a lot of
great solutions for it so aphids control
is
really challenging there are some great
solutions for it but the thing with
aphids is they live birth so when it
when you get one aphid in your garden
um they're already like they don't need
to sexually reproduce so they've already
got all their babies inside them ready
to go and I believe some entomology is
probably correct me I'm pretty sure
those babies are literally like the
second they come out they've already got
babies ready to go so they reproduce
at a scary rate like I've seen multiple
times where someone's literally got like
one cannabis they fit in their garden
and you come back three weeks later and
like the whole garden is ready to come
down so we have predators that work
really really well on them
it's really hard to get rid of all of
the aphids though so like the thing when
something's like I do literally have to
get when it reproduces that fast you
need to get rid of every single aphid to
control the problem and that doesn't
really happen very often either with
spraying or
um bio control it does happen if you've
got like a real you know heavy synthetic
systemic spray you can get rid of it's
one treatment but I don't think that's
likely to be an option
but I think that's going to be a real
challenge just because
bio control
for aphids as all we kind of know what
all the tools are when it comes to bio
controls and we know they it's it's
challenging to get rid of aphids 100
it's pretty easy to control them 80 but
you don't necessarily especially with
cannabis even it is really for anyone
that doesn't have them don't get them
they are absolute nightmares
um it's basically it's essentially
impossible to get rid of them once you
get them so just don't get them everyone
brings them in on clones like it's very
preventable it's preventable pest
but it's not a particularly controllable
Pest and then rust it might or whatever
any of those parsonoman mice they
haven't really emerged too much as a
pest so far in Canada I know that it was
more of an issue down in California and
Colorado
but it does have the potential
just because
um they kind of have a niche where
Predator might generally are pretty good
at controlling stuff like Russ at night
but again they're hard to control them
100 so a rough it might or broaden my
they're really tight so they're a lot
smaller than a
um Predator might so that's kind of
their evolutionary Niche is they can get
into spots where the where their
predators can't get so for instance if
you've got a plant in flowering it can
go way deep into a trichome stand where
a Swarovski even though it can eat it or
californicus can eat it it can't get in
that in that uh
stand and you get same thing you can go
again growing tips and stuff so
generally what we've seen again I'm
looking not just at canvas with other
crops usually when people use bio
control as a main standard
those paths like rusted might or
Broadway aren't much of an issue because
preventatively they do a really good job
of stopping them from Ever Getting
established and it's kind of why I think
maybe you saw that emergence in the
early days out of California and
um Colorado
nobody was really using predators that
much back then so and you don't hear
about it as much and we've definitely
had a couple of outbreaks in Canada at
LPS but it's been very very low but I
could be like the potential and they're
ones that's very easily spread through
cutting material and that's the one
thing I've seen in the legalized
industry is there's really a just an
unprecedented amount of spreading of
clones between facilities and that's
something that could easily get going
but if I have to pick one it would be
cannabis aphid second would probably be
root aphid yeah I mean there's certainly
two pests I've seen cause havoc in a
variety of different grow environments
something I was hoping to get your
opinion on is I'd noticed I'd been to a
few bigger facilities when I'd been over
in the states and it sort of seemed to
me like when a facility got to a certain
size it just sort of reached this
critical mass and pest infestation was
almost inevitable from what I had seen
and admittedly limited number of sites
I'd been to you've probably been to many
more larger facilities than I have would
you agree that you've seen that sort of
thing happen regularly or is my
experiences maybe a little skewed and
that's not what normally happens
no it's definitely true we've also seen
it on other crops it is a general rule
as as the facility gets bigger the fast
issues get bigger also
um I think it's for a bunch of reasons I
think more of it though is like I've
definitely seen because I've kind of
seen this evolving you get
um you know even you'll get guys that
when they've got small scenes you're
kind of on top of like for instance
bricks is one of the things like I've
seen and same with spider Mike I've seen
guys that have literally they've been
growing for like 10 years on you know
they maybe got a 40 lighter they've
never had
thrips
and all of a sudden they get them and
they can never get rid of them how are
the thrifts under control they're like
yes like they're using bio control it
controls them but I think it's like one
of those things like once you get thrips
in your crop that's like that's just one
of the big things that I think people
don't understand properly when it comes
to path is the difference between like
a thrifts or any past and a thrips
that's adapted to the crop that you're
in so when you get a thrips that you
know let's say you get a thrift
infestation by default you know you've
got
a kazillion thrips in there some of them
really like
cannabis right and those tend to be the
ones that reproduce so then you get in
really
um
adapted to your environment and they're
really hard to get rid of because like
again all you need is you know one or
two thrips I guess two thrips and so you
you know maybe you don't have them for
it looks like you don't have trips for
two months and then they come back well
it's just because you didn't it's almost
impossible to get rid of every single
strips out of your versatility so I
think when those guys were smaller it
wasn't they could go a long time without
Ever Getting strips but now they're
bigger eventually it comes in from
somewhere and once you get them you've
gotten for good like trips just if you
look at any other crops which is just
like a standard like anyone thinks
they're never gonna have thrips is
dreaming like they're just they're
everywhere right they're outside in the
grass they're coming in on your workers
they're coming in on pegs in your plant
material like there's too many avenues
for them to come here so
um
yeah I think that would be my answer for
that one
yeah okay I mean you've got me sort of
thinking now what might be some of the
sort of specific challenges the cannabis
plant presents in a bio control program
or like for example even just the
environment you know are there any sort
of room conditions which might make bio
control more challenging or more easy in
fact
yeah the biggest I mean the biggest room
condition it generally hasn't been much
of an issue the one thing I've had now
that people have kind of dialed in their
systems that don't see it as much but
back when those first facilities started
getting built you know large scale I saw
a bunch of times where people had um
their horizontal airflow fans just
mounted too low and there seemed to be a
pressure all right some guys that really
liked it you'd probably see them like
you go under their crop and you're like
man it's like a tropical storm in here
you know the plants are bending over
they've just got so much fans going on
them and that's the only thing that I've
really seen in cannabis production
that's caused a big issue so for
instance we had a facility that had a
big they had a thrifts problem but the
thrift's problem was only around the
perimeter of the room and what it was
was in the perimeter of the room those
fans were creating like a micro climate
they were just basically drying out the
leaf so much that the Predator might
just could just couldn't live on there
so the predator mites were working fine
in the middle of the room but when it
got close to the fans they the thrips
were taking over because the thrips were
able to uh you know tolerate that high
wind so that's really been the main
thing that I think we've seen and it's
not that common it's kind of now that
people's relation plants don't really
like to be grown in a tropical storm
condition people have moved away from
that the plant itself definitely
presents some challenges and one of the
biggest so there's two the two main
challenges is one that a lot of
uh predator mites don't reproduce on it
the way they reproduce on other crops
um
so like I said if I kind of got into
this before where they really need that
specialized plant hair to lay their eggs
on and I think you get some like I
definitely seen some reproduction but if
I compare it to like a pepper crop or a
cucumber crab it's nothing compared to
those crops like they really those are
ones you could literally put in a little
bit of loose stuff in one corner and you
come back you know two months later and
there's predator mites like over your
whole crop with cannabis you really need
to put the constant Supply in there to
keep the numbers up high enough so
that's one thing that people they try
and extrapolate what's gone on in other
crops and you can't really do it from
Peppers to cannabis it's different crops
so you really want to make sure you've
got
again not drink during Peak flour but
you want to have a continuous source of
Predator mice which usually means
sachets
um and then the other thing that people
you really need to front load it so like
for instance like a pepper crop or a lot
of other crops
um you've got like a Long window to
control your pest in like a pepper crab
that's like a year in a greenhouse
[Music]
um
with cannabis I mean I don't know what
the average should to look at I mean
probably average guys vegging for like
two weeks and then they've got another
two or three weeks in flowering before
the buds are too stacked up to control
them properly so you've got at best a
four or five week window to work with so
you can't use conventional rates so for
instance on a vegetable crop you might
put 10 per meter per stimulus again
because it's got you know months to
control of spider mates in cannabis
you've maybe got four or five weeks so I
mean instead of ten you're putting in
like 100 or something like that so
that's something you really need to
compensate you really need to
go hard like front load everything you
want to be treating your it really
starts at your mom's you want to make
sure you really want to just start from
the from the start of the whole thing
and then you're ramping off as you get
into flowering not what a lot of people
do is go holy cow I got a big problem
and then they start ramping up as you go
into bio into flowering you really want
a strong preventative approach and to be
on those things before your buds stack
up once you're in like you know
depending on the strain once first I
find most strains it's like the first
third of flowering is the stretch period
like the veg period so you really want
to have all your pests controlled done
within that first one third
yeah a brilliant sentiment hopefully
people can start implementing that one
so they don't find themselves in the uh
the dreaded week four week five surprise
of finding the the russet mites are
actually everywhere sort of got me
thinking about the future of IPM
strategies and Pest Management and
something I was hoping you might have
some insight into is anecdotally said
that various strains have different
susceptibility to pests yet sort of long
anecdotally been said that plants with
the strong blueberry lineage are like
almost like magnets for tests at least
that's been some of my experience do you
think these sort of anecdotes are true
that like certain phenotypes or certain
strains are just inherently far more
susceptible to pest infestation and as a
follow-up do you think that breeding for
pest resistance might become a more
focal part of Pest management in general
in the future
yeah it's 100 True like there's no doubt
about that we've seen it so many times
um
with I've seen it in LPS I've seen it
like it's a standing joke in the
Canadian cannabis Community there was
this clone going around called uh people
call it the perps or Vancouver Island uh
purple indica and it is the every person
I've known has had this thing it is the
most pest prone thing you've ever got
like if you've got an aphid in the
garden it's on this clone it just and
partly I think it's really old clone so
when plants get older they become more
attractive to pests but it's definitely
like this clone is I've passed magnet we
actually do at Cooper we are actually
doing research on on uh on cannabis
Aphid control we specifically actually
used that clone because we knew the
camera see if it just loved it and I've
seen it a lot I don't think anyone can
like think we're like definitely was
seen for instance sativa like really
sativa ones
um they tend to get thrips really early
but again it comes down to the terpenes
and I think there's it's so it's so very
able I've definitely seen a lot of hazes
really get drips
um bad
um
I'd say terpene is one of the bigger
issues and where I think people
overthink it so is this can breeding be
done probably I personally think it's
more of a disease thing than the past
thing I think stuff like that purple
Indigo clone will just naturally get
called out of the population because
zubac wants to deal with with that
um I think disease resistance is very
much and uh something that needs to be
done and will be done in breeding
specifically for powdery mildew and
botrytus
um past one I'm not I'm not sure I do
I've definitely seen some people steer
themselves wrong where they're like no
no I'm not going to grow any Haze
because I know I heard that Haze gets
whatever thrips or something else and I
mean you know you know yourself like
it's not so it's not like any of the
strains there are so
um
stable like every different phenotype is
slightly different so I think you got
people that are like I'm not growing OG
Kush because it's this and I was like
well why don't you if you grow a pack
you're probably gonna get one that
really gets thrips and another one that
strips won't even go close to it so
it's not so black and white and I've
definitely seen some LPS getting into
that where they're like I'm not growing
that because it's this strain and
they're like dude like all hazes aren't
the same
um it's not you can't make those blanket
statements but definitely from clone to
clone that is not a urban legend that is
for sure real that some stuff is far
more susceptible to different tests than
others
yeah okay that's really interesting to
hear and good to know it's uh it's not
all in my head another question I was
interested in is that I've noticed there
can be sort of a variability in activity
levels of some of the mites I've gotten
are there any recommendations you have
that can help ensure once I do have the
predator and I'm releasing it in the
garden that I'm sort of getting the most
out of them you know are there any sort
of factors which I may unawaringly
hindering them or you know accidentally
killing them off after releasing them
um not too much usually if there's an
issue with like the only two real issues
is that spraying is one
um excess airflow is another of just
like like Direct on the plant but the
one thing I would I would caveat that
statement with is that it definitely
like Predator might like there's a lot
to them so you there's definitely
suppliers on the market that probably
sell some pretty crappy Predator
termites
um but what I would caveat is I would
say
um like I run you know part of my job is
I kind of oversee a lot of the the sales
complaints and stuff that come in and I
would say the vast majority of
complaints that we get
um for especially for predator right
they're just perceived complaints
they're not there's not actually nothing
wrong with the product so like they're
hard to see like especially if you don't
know what your look like if you're not
really trained for what you're looking
for and a lot of people they're looking
at it with a bare eye well I've been
doing this for like half my life and I
can't tell you without a microscope so
there's a couple of things to keep in
mind so one Predator makes because
they're so tiny like they're really hard
to count so what you can definitely get
is a real thing like let's say you buy a
bottle of persimulus let's say it's
supposed to be 10 000 in it most of the
time there's more like 15 or 17 000 in
there because they over pack everything
and I'm sure we're not the only company
that does that because you need to
guarantee there's ten thousand you can't
have somebody sitting there it's very
difficult to calculate exactly how much
is in there so people overshoot it so
let's say we're and don't hold any of
these numbers but it's definitely like
this like it's okay you're way over the
spec and then
maybe there's uh like first of all those
populations fluctuate a little bit so
the same amount of material one week
might have
whatever ten thousand mites the next
week might have 17 000 mice so it
fluctuates and you've got people but
people don't get so we're guaranteeing a
minimum and quite often they're getting
way more than that and then what happens
is yeah there's some weeks that you're
actually getting what we say you're
getting and but you get used to seeing
something and it's it's not accurate you
know what I mean you're getting used to
seeing way more than you were actually
paying for that's definitely a big
a a big issue and the thing also with
pressure which people don't guess like
there's a there's not like there's some
bios that are difficult to ship predator
mites are one of the easiest things to
ship because they've got to because
you're not shipping them dormant like
there's a food source in there so
they're just alive and at room
temperature most of the time so there's
not really a whole lot to go wrong in
transport so does it happen sure
sometimes absolutely but it's a very
small percentage of the time
that that's great that answers what I
was wondering almost perfectly
so up next we actually had a question
submitted from one of our patreon
listeners and they basically said look
you know I love that I'm just going to
read a word for it because I love the
way they've worded it they say thrips
are the devil they naturally occur
outdoors in my area and it's impossible
to grow a plant without getting them
I've knocked them down before but they
always come back if the plant stays
healthy and they don't take them over
it's just a constant fight without
pesticides beneficials help but they
don't seem to ever reproduce enough to
keep up have you got any suggestions
yeah so I think and you do get some air
like the out the outdoor kind of ambient
level of thrips can vary a lot between
different places like I always remember
I had a greenhouse
um like I said I grew where I live is
like there's literally 3 000 Acres of
greenhouses within 20 minutes I've seen
like a lot of past pressures like I've
seen a lot of crops but I also do all
over I work all over Canada and I
remember being out in the Prairies once
and which is a drier grassy kind of
habitat and we could never control
strips of this one facility and
I remember trying to put my finger on
like what was going on and I was like
you know what I'm just gonna hang some
sticky cards outside to see like what
the outside pressure of scripts was and
this was like a 10 acre greenhouse or
something and I hung a yellow sticky
card outside one end of the greenhouse
and then I drove to the end which maybe
took you know two minutes or something
like that and hung hung another one and
just on a fluke on the way back I was
like I'll just check that first card and
see if it caught anything yet and that
first card had like you know 10 000
trips on it or something where where I
live it would have like one if that
um so it's really can be different so
you definitely can get some areas where
you're just getting a crazy amount of
strips coming inside so I don't know
whether he's Outdoors or or in a
greenhouse or indoors indoors there's
definitely a lot of buffer between you
so I'd say if you're getting a big
problem in a small indoor place you're
probably making the problem yourself
even though you don't want to admit it
um so
basically where I think most people go
wrong it when serps control is they or
not most people but when there's a
problem it's generally to the to do with
this issue is
predator mites they're only they are
your best
your kind of Baseline attack but
Predator might doesn't matter what kind
they're only used they're only eating
the first n star of thrift so that's
frips will lay its egg on the planet and
then that egg hatches out into the first
larval stage which is kind of like a
little worm that that has no wings they
can just crawl around in feeds so thrips
or a Swarovski or cucamaras they only
eat that one stage
so once it gets past that stage if
you're just using predator mites there's
all these strips in your crop that
you're not controlling at all and then
an adult thrips in some in some
temperatures it'll last like a month two
months even longer so that can be like
your whole crop where you've got this
big strips problem and you're putting in
swersky thinking you did something but
you've got all these adult herbs flying
around
you know causing chaos that nothing is
controlling so you really have to go a
multi same with any pass you need to go
with a multi-pronged approach so for
there you're going to put your Predator
mic as your kind of base level control
but then you need to put something else
in to get those other stages out of the
equation and the best especially on
cannabis because it really likes the
canvas point is the product or trading
is Thrift or but it's uh Aureus and
that's like a predatory bug so it can
fly around and they're like thrips
Killers like they're generous but they
really like killing thrips and you put
like they will literally turn get rid of
all the thrips in like a week usually
the problem with like and they go after
all the different stages the problem is
if you were to not put the Predator
might and just put in the trip or or the
Aureus is they'll eat all your thrips
and then they die off because there's no
food and then there's a whole bunch of
trips eggs in the leaf which two weeks
later hatch out and then there's no
predator for them and bang you got a
purpose problem again so that's why you
always want that overlapping you know
the predator mites are controlling any
new stuff coming up and then the Fripp
or is killing any of the larger stages
another when it doesn't work quite as
well but it's a it's a viable strategy
is to use a lot of sticky cards so
sticky cards will uh attach the adult
trips that are attracted to it so you
can also use that combination where
you're using the Predator mic to go
after those young stages the sticky
cards to go after the to catch the
adults so I most of the time when I see
people have issues with drips it's
because they're ignoring those other
life cycle stages
I guess it's sort of segues into
the future of products you know a lot of
uh recent and interesting new
technologies are emerging in the
predator and IPM industry and one that
we've been talking about a little bit at
the start of our episodes is some of the
new technology you guys have been
working on particularly the one that
caught my eye was the spidex revital
that proof of predation technology was
really interesting from my perspective
because it gives you that real-time
feedback on the activity levels of the
mites with that um you know changing
color sort of Technology do you think
that that'll become a new industry
standard having these sort of built-in
features around predators and do you
have any other cool things on the
horizon you might be able to let us know
about
um so I don't know that so that's an
interesting one because the the so what
happens is when you buy the Predator mic
it's translucent so you can see through
it so and then when it eats spider mice
it turns bright red so that was kind of
a side effect of something else so that
spider mites was that one like if it was
the last remaining Predator mic that
nobody could figure out how to rear on
something other than its natural prey
source so it's a it's a consequence of
eating spider mites that makes it bread
so in the old up until this year we used
to rear them on Spider-Man so they'd be
red when you bought them
um now we've figured out how to rear
them on a different food source
um so they're actually not red and it's
a really cool thing because you put them
into the crop and they're clear and they
instantly so there's no doubt about
whether they're working you're like well
are they red okay well then it's eating
spider mites like it's that clear
because that's the only thing that can
make them red but it wasn't there as an
indicator it's just something that was
kind of a cool thing that
um
that you know was an added benefit
um so that was kind of the last one for
like all the other predator mites were
always like that so I don't know whether
that will
be uh where the future I actually don't
know where the future a lot of it will
probably some new Predator might is
really the Forefront of the of Bio
control it's you know not for some past
like aphids and white fly or white fly a
little bit but
um just because they're really they're
cost effective because they're quite
inexpensive to rear and
um versus like if you're using some of
the other you know macro type of BIOS
like a parasitic watch and stuff
generally they've got to uh be reared on
a pest and that's cost prohibitive
because you've got a greenhouse with a
crop in it then you gotta pass it so I'm
gonna guess that probably more along
those lines of rearing stuff on
fictitious hosts
um is going to be the future and
possibly some new you know new
Biologicals that
um you know maybe there's a new a
different parasitic wasp it doesn't
exist it isn't commercialized right now
that's really good on you know better on
cannabis aphid or a different Predator
might that's really good on hemp for us
it might always stuff like that in the
future but that yeah I just sell them
they tell me that when everyone is ready
to sell I don't get too much of the
privy on the on the behind the scenes
the r d and sorry what was the other
part of your question
for that one I I guess the other
question was do you think these sort of
features like for example the proof of
predation and things like that will sort
of start to become integrated as sort of
Mainstays in predators to or do you
think that's just a one-off sort of
situation
yeah I think that's just a one-off I
mean that proof of prediction is there
it's just left noticeable I think it's
more that people are gonna like we're
really at an infant level especially in
the Cannabis industry in understanding
bio control like Kansas people think
they're so Innovative but honestly like
most of the other crops are years ahead
of them when it comes to understanding
biocontrol because they've just been
using it for a long time so for instance
that same proof of predation I mean you
can see with swersky May that it changes
color depending on which past
um it has like I can look in a crop and
look at the color of your swirsky and
tell you whether you get a pest problem
or not because of the shade of Amber it
is but you know there's lots of stuff
like that
um
so I think that just the general
understanding has a lot of room to to
come up I think most people are not at
it it's really it's changed rapidly in
cannabis you know in those years because
that's the first time where I said a lot
of the industry I'd say is a little bit
maybe a head is the wrong word but the
Cannabis industry has definitely evolved
way faster because it's the only
industry where they literally got like
some dude with a PhD in BIO control
that's running their bio control thing
but it's just it's a newer crop right so
it wasn't that common before
legalization to use bio control time
yeah okay yeah that's that makes sense
for sure it's it's definitely a new crop
where not everything is the same as
prior one of the sort of final questions
I wanted to ask you that was of personal
interest to me because I am
unapologetically biased towards organic
growth styles do you think that organic
growth Styles sort of have a innate
better chance to fight off pests than
coco or do you think it's relatively an
even Battlefield
oh man you're trying to make an internet
uh give me some internet heaters views
expressed a minor loan and not yours so
this is going to get a whole lot of hate
but I would say unanimously and Cobra's
like a big company so like we're all
over the world and there's like
literally some of the top best control
people in the world work for us
I would say pretty much unanimously
everyone that I work with in Copper and
in commercial green henders thinks
that's largely a bunch of hokey
um
I have not seen that I think it's
probably like most things there's a bit
of
both things I've honestly seen the most
pest infested crops as a general rule
are the organic ones not a conventional
ones and I'm an organic guy I really
believe in organic agriculture I'm just
telling you the truth and I think what
agriculture people miss about organic
stuff is like one of the missing links
is like the nutrition levels like so you
get a plant it's very hard to dial in
the nutrition especially in the
greenhouse or indoors where it's like a
really intensive you know lighting
regime and stuff like that to get a
properly dialed in
um plant for nutrients in my opinion is
way easier with synthetic and best with
synthetic fertilizers and you'll see
even if you've ever read Steve Solomon's
book who's one of the you know gurus of
organic it's one of the things that he
discovers once you start looking into
like the nutritional value of organic
food yeah it doesn't have pesticide
residues and it's probably got a lot of
attributes for like you know maybe it's
got higher antioxidants and stuff but
when you start looking at like okay well
how much calcium does it have in it or
how much phosphorus does it have in it
a lot of times the organic stuff is
really low compared to synthetic not
that it's not possible but that's just
the reality so I think that's part of
the time I get healthy like I said I
think a healthy plant is more resistant
to diseases but I think or pests and
diseases but I also think it's it's
definitely over inflated I'm not
claiming to be an expert all right
you know
the the word but like I've seen I there
might be something to it but when you
see like I've Just Seen thousands and
thousands and thousands of Acres of
crops
and a lot of times pastas show up
willy-nilly they're not necessarily
going for the weakest plant that does
happen sometimes but a lot of times it's
just like they just show up randomly so
let's say it's not as true as everybody
thinks and I think a lot of it comes
down it's not to do with whether it's
organic or conventional it's to do with
what the nutrition level is in the plant
that actually makes sense I want I want
to believe man I literally have come
from that like I I literally was in
Amsterdam in like 95 when uh positronics
used to do like T they were like the
original Proprietors of of no-till I was
there like I learned from those guys and
I actually
I'm a no-till non-believer I'll just
I'll just say it not a non-believer but
I've been there and I've left and I will
never go back I just I think there's a
lot of I'm not convinced that that's the
best plan on multiple levels and I know
that's a
heavily highly unpopular opinion but
that's my No that's good and you know it
also it makes me start thinking that you
know there's sort of a lot of variables
in the equation because as you said it
actually totally makes sense to me that
the worst Gardens you see with
infestations are organic because if
they're utilizing the things we've
touched on earlier like neem and things
like that in an attempt to stay organic
but uh you know maybe somewhat
ineffective whereas maybe you know the
soilless guys are a little more ready to
use some of the more bang for your buck
type principles be a pesticides things
like that but that's interesting to know
and it's good to hear because it's sort
of for a long time I've been wondering
why the biggest producers are all
soilless so that's probably a pretty
good reason why right like it's just it
plays into it I think well I think
there's a bunch of reasons I personally
like where if my general beliefs in just
agriculture which like I said I've been
in it for like probably around 30 years
or more and it's kind of evolved every
time I've been a pure organic guy in
some cases and pure synthetic and
honestly when it comes to whether it's
Plant Nutrition
um
human nutrition or Pest Control pests
and Disease Control I'm really a really
and I think and covert also is we're
really firm Believers in integrated
where I don't think that pure organic is
the solution and I don't think that pure
conventional is their synthetic
Association I think the real answer is a
combination of the two I think there's
some really good things that Organics
brings to the table and I think there's
some really good things that just
putting chemical salts can bring to the
table in in some situations and it's
really the same with bio control like a
lot of people think that Cobra's like
where oh the corporate guy or the bio
control guy he's always going to push
bios we don't really believe in pure bio
control there's basically nobody in our
company that believes in that we really
believe in integrated
um like there's a ton there's certain
paths there is just probably never going
to be a great bio control solution
you're going to need to whatever use a
physical means or or a spray or
something like that and I think that's
that's kind of my view on agriculture
it's really everything's integrated and
whenever somebody gets too far into
their that's their belief system
integrated their ideas too much it's
it's not necessarily the best thing and
I'd also say part of the reason why some
of those organic places that I've seen
like I've seen some really filthy
organic places filthy synthetic places
too but
I'd say part of the factor in those
organic things is the magic factor is
they want to believe that everything's
magically taking care of itself and they
just don't even look and then you go
like I always remember I won't mention
any names or there's one other guys in
Canada it was literally one of the most
famous organic people here he was one of
the pioneers and I was friends with him
from before I was in Copper and he said
he invited us out to the greenhouse just
because we're friends and he's like I'll
go take a look he says I'll tell you up
front there's nothing to see there
because you know the magic Factor you
know we've been organic for so long and
everything self-regulates and it's all
in balance and it was the filthiest crop
I've ever seen and this was a place that
literally that was the highest the most
expensive produce in the time in Canada
and it was absolutely filthy and it was
because he he believed that he was clean
and chefs probably believe that it was
Queen because he keeps telling him how
magic everything was so
I'm kind of a I don't know become more
of a practical practical sword for over
over the years
yeah no I I'm on board I'm on board I'm
inherent biases make fools of us all
right that's really interesting to hear
that that's how it sort of played out
for you I will have to keep that in mind
but um with that being said I think that
pretty much brings us to the end of what
I was hoping to chat about did you have
any comments or shout outs you wanted to
make
um no no no real comments uh shout outs
to all the people that like bringing us
new bio controls and new technologies
because I think those are the people
that they get underrated a lot of
everyone doesn't I don't think most
people realize how much work goes into
bringing new products
um to Market those are kind of the under
pressure people so shout out to all the
r d people they're locked away in a lab
somewhere coming up with Solutions
yeah a huge shout out to those guys and
you know likewise a shout out to
yourself and everyone at culpit for you
know being on board with helping support
the show and helping to sponsor us we
really appreciate it and your your
support does not go unnoticed so you
know thanks so much Kev for coming by
and having a chat with us today we
really appreciate it yeah I appreciate
having you on and if we don't really
like we don't really sponsor a whole lot
of stuff we just like I think you have
bringing some really good content there
and that's partly why we uh we chose to
offer your support but thanks very much
for having me on amazing
killer information there from Kevin
Copart thanks so much again for coming
by my friend really grateful who had you
on
foreign
there you have it friends what'd you
think
however I'm really grateful to have had
all the guests on the episode today Matt
of Premier Tech talking about promix
connects and Kevin of Coco biological
systems thank you so much everyone for
coming on we appreciate your support it
was great to hear from you and as always
without you guys the show couldn't
happen if you guys are after any of the
products you heard today Google them
online you'll be able to find them all
the best products we only work with
companies we get behind thank you so
much everyone for listening
don't forget to check out the patreon if
you're interested in supporting the show
and getting early access to content
www.patreon.com podcast I appreciate
everyone on the patreon you guys are the
lifeblood of the show I hope you enjoy
hearing this one early
much love to all the listeners though
and I'll see you for the next one
we'll see you
business