[Music]
all right all right all right gang
welcome back as always you're joined by
your boy heavy days here from the upside
down library and on this one we want to
give a massive shout out to our
incredible sponsors who helped make the
show happen as always C in now your
number one seed bank in the industry a
guarantee not just on germination on
satisfaction meaning at the end of the
growth if you're not happy hit them up
they'll send you something to make it
right the reason why they offer this is
because they only stock the highest
quality breeders in the game that's how
they know you're going to be stoked at
the end of a grow don't just worry about
wasting your money worry about wasting
your time a guarantee on satisfaction
means you don't need to be worried about
this a massive shout out to copit
biological these guys are the world
leaders in Sustainable biocontrol
Solutions to crop Pest and diseases if
you're battling spidermites check out
cop's new spidex vital plus sachet these
are new personis breeding sachet that
release predom mites into your crop
continually over a period of several
weeks providing sustained spidermite
control now you don't have to spread
carrier material into your garden just
just to introduce some Predator mice
just hang the sachet in the crop let the
personis walk out and do the work for
you trust me guys you don't want to have
to go up against a spidermite
infestation without spyx vital plus
these are truly the best Predators on
the market the best in the game I
promise you try it once you'll see the
quality pulse sensors you know them you
love them you probably already got a
pulse unit in your garden why cuz it
helps you track all of the Hidden
variables that you may not be
consciously thinking about on the
day-to-day level and through fine-tuning
these parameters you can get a bigger
yield more turs more flavor more resin
more potency God what can it do whether
you're thinking of running a single tent
a single room a multi-state operation
it's time to get serious guys get
yourself a pulse sensor it's a
no-brainer and given theyve just
recently introduced the pulse hub no
better time to get on board to be able
to fully integrate all of your units
into one Central localized Hub massive
shout out to pulse sensors we love and
appreciate you guys thank you so
much massive shout out to our friends at
Organics alive helping the homies grow
the highest quality product worldwide if
you want a powdered simple organic
fertilizer option organic alive is the
one for you people have been sweeping
competitions all around America using
organic salive cuz their products are
superior if you want an easy to use
all-in-one versatile option that has a
range of different products to help any
situation including Bloom veg transition
micronutrients microbes Organics alive
has everything you need they're going to
help you take your next crop to the next
level check them out guys quick release
because they're fine powders all organic
what more could you ask for huge shout
out to our friends at Organics alive we
really appreciate you guys getting on
board please everyone go check them
out and a massive shout out to our
newest sponsors dap I'm sure you guys
have heard me talking about dap they are
an incredible Vape company based out of
USA producing some of the most coolest
Engineering in Vape technology you've
seen for a while these guys honestly
helped me get off bongs and transition
to vaping I cannot speak highly enough
about dap's products huge shout out guys
go check him
[Music]
out and on this episode today we have
the hanol hero the head honcho of
pirates of the Emerald Triangle The
Strain historian and breeder
extraordinaire a massive welcome and
thank you to Caleb CSI
Humbolt here to talk all things
breeding his recent work with the F1
Durban upcoming
[Music]
projects how he's able to make all the
incredible lines he
does and so so much
more without further
delay let's get into
it all righty gang you know what time it
is Big shout out for joining us today
and we have a special one an old friend
a man whose work output is simply
unbelievable both in terms of volume and
quality and massive shout out to the
mesino pirate himself Caleb of CSI
thanks for joining us or the hble pirate
either
or the real Jack
Sparrow how you been since we last spoke
oh just staying busy as always I don't
think anyone can deny that what have you
been working on
recently um I mean I've been doing a lot
of uh reproducing of of uh
all the original lines I reproduced you
know seven eight nine 10 years ago um as
far as the the regular pirate stuff and
then just keeping busy uh trying to make
you know a whole catalog of you know
s1's for preservation and you know some
hybrids for fun you yeah a bit of
everything I love that a man of all
tastes so let's let's touch on both the
most recent regular line you've done if
I'm not mistaken is that the DC hybrid
or or do you consider that still in
progress um oh I uh reproduced the DC uh
reproduced the pinear Kush or not the
pinear the Christmas pintar is actually
coming up soon um and then uh the
Burmese uh I think the Burmese
is one I I don't know it's it's
one one of the most uh um difficult ones
you know because sativas are not easy um
pure
sativas um and then uh then I U I have
Panama on Deck so you know wow you
starting to tap into your sativa side of
things oh yeah well I've always had it
it's just and they're a
pain you know any any of these uh you
know pure pure sativas that take 20 24
weeks they don't even start flowering
for six weeks you know I mean come on
you don't have a seed set until eight
weeks deep yeah I was about to say I saw
the photos of the I think it was the
burmes you posted up and could have been
week two in my garden but I think you
said it was week six or seven or eight
maybe yeah oh it was probably close to
eight yeah yeah wow what's that burmes
like and where did it come from
so the burmes uh I rep I reproduced that
oh I don't know maybe eight or nine
years ago something like that I forget
um but uh um the the seeds my buddy had
been given were from the late 90s and
they had sat in his fridge forever and
he passed them to me there was like 70
seeds or something um and he had gotten
them um from you know through the grap
Vine from this dude uh who went by the
handle preservation dude or colonel
colonel Cosmic I think um but this dude
was you know really well known around
like you know Central California the Bay
Area um and you know he preserved a lot
of stuff and so I don't know exactly how
far back they date before him but
they're at least you know mid 90s if not
you know he probably had him for quite a
while you know but he he passed on o
probably damn near 20 years ago maybe 15
but you know it's been a while yeah wow
and you mentioned it's like one of those
like really really long flowering
sativas what what do you think you could
compare it to like is it is the effect
and the smell like not dissimilar to
other plants that go that long or is
like how would you describe it for
someone I guess it's definitely like a
tie plant
you know wow it's a it's an old school
tie type of
plant damn and and does it have that
same sort of effect like real
uplifting oh yeah yeah yeah yeah it's
it's it's right in line with all that
kind of stuff for sure oh that's
beautiful we actually had a fan submit a
question and they said they were
thinking about pulling the trigger on
the Burmese and they wanted to ask you
how many packs do you think they should
run through to find like what you would
consider one of the better
plans I
mean you know I'm not going to go all
Tom Hill and say you need a
hundred but I I I'd say you know um just
my personal recommendation just just do
one and then you know give it a try and
because they're they're not easy to grow
uh just by themselves you know I mean as
especially if you haven't grown sativas
before I mean you you can flower out a
little 6inch sativa and end up with an 8
foot tall plant you
know before it even starts putting
flowers on you know totally totally
maybe just yeah maybe just get over the
initial hurdle before we go to Tom Hill
on it that makes sense for sure yeah you
know I guess as a followup I'd be
interested in general when you offer
your preservation lines I love how you
do like 21 seeds or more in a pack is
that because you are trying to encourage
people to like do a little digging or is
it just because you get more seeds or
something like that so you know I was I
was a member of you know plenty of these
like preservation groups you know land
race groups you know online for years
and you always would see people
sprouting four seeds or 10 seeds and I'm
like no no no no no I mean hell honestly
i' I'd like to you know just do 100
packs you know minimum 100 packs but the
reality is not everybody has the space
or the time to do 100 at a time so I do
21 because I'm like well at least make
your selection from you know a bigger
amount or if you're going to open
pollinate you know do it from a bigger
amount you know and I know I know a
hundred's not perfect you know a
thousand's better but you know I
mean you know we're just trying to pre
preserve as many of the genes as
possible for future Generations
essentially you know yeah hugely hugely
and I I can definitely get on board with
the sentiment of you know you see people
doing three or four seed open poles and
you're like oh
no I mean you
know uh that'll that'll definitely
narrow it down to what you want or don't
want that's it that's it right okay I
mean while you mentioned the Burmese you
know it's like a tie type plan and we
just quickly touched on Tom I'd love to
ask would you have any interest in
running Tom's
Hayes um I mean I think Tom's doing a
pretty damn good job with with that you
know I'd really like to you know see him
after he gets his open pollination his
most recent open pollination done I'd
like to see him actually get in there
and you know directionally go somewhere
with it and get that ratio of one and
100 you know maybe a little little lower
one in 10 that'd be nice I would be
appreciative I'm looking for that
mythical Haze clone and I just sadly
don't have enough
space yeah yeah yeah but uh I I listened
to your interview with him and I really
liked it and I I I relate it a lot
because uh it seems you know Tom and I
we we've always tended to preserve but
we've we've never done a whole lot on
like directionally just narrowing it
down and you know making something
that's just you know you know really
high quality out of the things we've
preserved you know we're always on to
the next thing you know so you
know I'm I'm trying to take
notes oh you're too kind thanks for for
listening to that one and and look you
know what I I feel like you touched on a
really focal feeling that a lot of
Growers have which I try to relate to
people and I say sometimes as you're
getting towards the end of a project or
like a Harvest or whatever you're almost
like checked out of those plants and
you're more invested in like what's
about to you're like I'm about to flip
these other things they're going to be
bomb Oh especially if it's 24 weeks
later oh where' the year
go wow so yeah that's cool that's cool
okay I mean and you know we're talking
about Tom you did you did the Deep chunk
project any any interesting takeaways or
observations you made while doing that
one
um I definitely found some some uh some
plants I didn't really um you know I
hadn't noticed before in previous
reproductions um I think I just you know
in my old age I'm paying more attention
moving a little slower you know and
there there was some there were some uh
some sniffs that I wasn't expecting just
you know a little little skunky to them
and I was like hm you know I don't
know it could blend well with some
things that's exciting to hear I I would
love to ask you specifically I know
you've been posting some really
impressive looking photos of some deep
chunk males you've been playing around
with I think you've narrowed them down a
little bit were there any specific
traits or things you were looking for
with that selection or how did you
Whittle them down I was looking for
stinky ones and you know of course
Frosty ones you know I mean I I asked
Tom you know what do you go for in those
males and he's like I like the frosty
ones so you
know you know I was I was you know
making sure I got those ones beautiful
beautiful beautiful and do you think
that like people are are Keen for the
Deep chunk or do you think that it's
sort of a bit difficult for a lot of
people to
grow oh yeah I mean in its own it's own
regard it's it's just as difficult as
like you know the sativas you know it's
a short Stumpy super slow growing you
know inbred inbred Indica you know and I
mean anytime you get anything inbred you
know whether it's indica or
sativa you know it's not they're not the
easiest to grow you know so certainly
and and how would you like compare and
contrast it to say the maah line cuz
I've been eyeing that one off and I'm
like oo I kind of think I want to run
the Mazar how are they different how are
they the
same um the Mazar it tends to like grow
a little little little faster or a bit
faster really have have more distance
between the nodes and more be like a a
traditional type of just
um kind of like a Hindu Kush type of
thing um definitely uh you know not the
monster you know fan leaves of the Deep
chunk and the super stoutness and all
that you know it's it's more of a
regular indicia type versus deep deep
chunks yeah
super super Inda I don't know yeah no I
definitely get yeah I can understand
that um I can't remember who it was but
someone was on the show and they were
saying that like The Afghani sort of
archetypal structure and flavors and
effects that people in say America and
and all over the world think of is sort
of a Mazar type plan would you say you
agree with that in general yeah I think
so I think so uh it it's definitely you
know more of the norm type you know
Afghan indicia type plant um there were
there was even a a couple of them in
there when I reproduced them last um
that uh were a little bit reminiscent of
say like a a Kush
you know you know not not Bubba for sure
you know but definitely you know and you
see that a lot with you know some of the
you know Hindu Kush you know um Afghani
indicas and all that you know you know
that that look of a plant
so yeah nice and and I mean like if
we're talking about say the ma or the
Deep chunk or really any of the lines
we've touched on so far have you found
any like really standout Keepers or are
you more just looking to open pollinate
and you're not looking to find a keeper
per se oh there's definitely been been
ones that you know if I had more time
more space more help I'd definitely you
know be keeping some of these I'm
terrible at keeping stuff like I'll keep
them for I don't know two months six
months and then it's just like you know
my my mother rooms are already
overflowing I I got to make decisions
and if I have SE you know I tend to let
let a lot of these Keepers go so yeah no
it makes sense and you sort of touched
on a question I wanted to ask you which
is that I can't count how many breeders
have just like offhandedly made the
comment being like godamn the amount of
work Caleb does is insane I I wanted to
ask how do you do it with just on your
own because I know you don't have a ton
of help like how many sites you got how
do you how do you like get
sleep
I do have a very small crew of dedicated
helpers um you know I've I've got I'd
say three three helpers that you know
put in some serious time and uh you know
uh I
run five right now I I downscaled it a
couple years ago but I run
five um breeding rooms um two rags and
three
fam um and uh you know I try to stay up
on it I do pretty good most of the
time yeah truly it it it really is
honestly inspiring to see how much work
you put out and you know cuz I feel like
sometimes it's easy to drag your feet on
projects and to like you know just dick
around and there have been times in my
life where I've been more productive
than maybe I am currently and then I I
look at you and I'm like damn that's
that's honestly the
goal right right uh would be nice if you
know I only had one or two projects that
that kind of sounds good to me lately we
need a crowd fund some help so you can
go on a
holiday I I Really Wanna I I really want
to head to Australia one of these days
oh look I would love to have you here
and let me tell you there's a lot of
really nice CS Cuts floating around
Australia like the one that jumps to
mind immediately is I know that there's
a really nice lemon tree headband cut
that my buddy found and oh my God
beautiful all day everyday
smoke oh I bet I bet yeah I'm I'm I'm a
big fan of that lemon tree yes and the
headband well before we get there I want
to quickly ask because we've sort of
been talking about some of the older
projects you've been doing can you give
me any insights on the uz Becky stand
line so that um that came from Charlie
Garcia um
and um that was from the original seeds
he reproduced before he outcrossed it to
the Northern Lights
um and
um I got those uh or or we got those um
I think through
bod um so Charlie had given them to um
this this one cat who had then given
them to Bodie and then I ended up
getting them from bod and reproducing
them gave a bunch to Bodie gave a bunch
to Charlie you know um but it's just a
it's another old school you know indicia
um kind of a leggier indicia plant but
just super super Frosty hash plant style
like like when when you hear people talk
about hash plant and then you get these
hash plant clones that have no Frost
it's like why are you calling a hash
plant but the US Becky you could call it
a hash plant because it's a frosty hash
plant so you
know but yeah that that's awesome it's
definitely one of the more rarer ones I
think and so it definitely has a bit of
Allure to it it almost like touches on
that same interesting Vibe when people
see bod's ancient OG and they're like oo
Iranian that sounds intriguing it's like
from a part of the world that you just
never hear from you know right right
right right yeah yeah there you go well
the last sort of mutant one I was hoping
to quickly touch on because I know you
got a bit of experience with it is over
the past few years you've um done SL
collabed on some cool um Australian
bastard cannabis stuff what what's that
experience been like has that changed
your outlook on things at
all you you know
uh I I I did a lot of work with it for a
few years there and
um it actually it taught me a lot it
taught me more about breeding than
anything um in the fact that um
basically anything ABC is going to be a
recessive genetic and you can breed you
know these recessives on ev Everything
You know you you grow out 100 you know
F1 F2 F3 them and you can breed those
recessives but the end of the day uh
most of those recessives aren't aren't
the best uh plants you know and ABC is a
tough one I mean the only the only one
I've ever seen that you know really
looks like a halfway decent plant is you
know um you know homeboy over in your
neck of the woods you know who I'm
talking about I was going to give him a
shout out bin chicken shout out
doua yeah yeah I mean he has a he has a
Navy see that looks like a damn normal
plant you know yeah and there's a lot of
like interesting genetics in there as
well right it's a hybrid of a hybrid of
a hybrid yeah so okay and like I mean as
a followup you made like a bunch of cool
hybrids I remember there was like a TK
hybrid there was a cheese hybrid there
was there was a number of them I don't
want to do a disservice by forgetting
one or two so we'll just cap it there
but did any of them end up doing what
you hoped where like you got a lot of
influence from that regular mother on
the ABC type plant or it was more harder
than just doing the
cross I mean so I I honestly think I
chose wrong uh at least with the ones I
did um I took a TK um you know times ABC
to F4 and I found in the F2 Generation I
found uh you know a a plant that um um
was an OG Kush ABC plant right um but
then when I BR it to the
F3 you you C you couldn't even find any
of that OG
cush you know as far as TPS go you could
find the look sure but you couldn't
there there I didn't get any of the TPS
you know
so um and there's a few ways you know I
could Backtrack on that um one of them
would be uh to uh make a feminized you
know with an OG Kush you know type and
then breed into the the problem with ABC
is it's always been Tor pentalene Dom
like many many many sativas and you know
even indicas but it's hard breeding
terpinolene
out yeah I've often wondered why that is
like it it is such a dominant gene isn't
it I wonder if it's just
maybe it was like one of the first Tes
to ever be expressed by cannabis and
it's just so deep seeded in the genome
or
something right I mean back in back in
the day Hy hyp told me good luck
breeding the tarpening out of
ABC and he worked with it for 20 years
so you know that that's that's
experience right
there wow that that's really cool to
hear it taught you so much I I I
wouldn't have guessed but then when you
said it out loud I was like oh I guess
that that makes sense actually right I
mean don't get me wrong though I do like
tentene um I'm just not the hugest fan
of smoking terpinolene like I like the
sniff but I
mean the smoke just never hits I don't
know well I mean before I forget what is
your favorite sort of tpine profile oh I
I love uh limonin uh pinin um you know
even like Limon Lun uh
aamin uh any any of those just I I think
though the the the the loning and pining
are probably pretty close to my
favorites yeah beautiful I mean I guess
you must love like the lemon lime OG's
oh yeah yeah yeah yeah and the the lemon
tree turps even Skittles
o that I mean you know that's a whole
another topic well going to get there
don't worry I I wanted to I wanted to
ask you so we've spoken about some of
the regular projects you've been doing
recently let's now talk about the fem I
know that the community is absolutely
bursting at the seams to get their hands
on these F1 Durban hybrids you've been
making right tell us a little bit about
this one how did this project come about
I mean uh you know I've always kind of
wanted to test
theories and you know see if certain
claims are you know what they what they
are um I mean you know most folks know
that you know [ __ ] you know claimed
that you know uh What uh cherry pie was
F1 derb times granddaddy purple and then
Girl Scouts
was um uh Flo flowa OG times F1 derb now
you know you got other folks like Kenny
Powers being like nah uhuh and then you
got you know other cats like s flux
capacitor being like yeah no so you know
you got a lot of these folks in the
cookie fam you know who actually were
more into the breeding side of things or
accident side of things I don't
know saying we don't think so but you
know uh it doesn't hurt to try out the
F1 derb uh itself grows like Girl Scout
cookies but it doesn't smell like Girl
Scout
cookies so that's very interesting what
what does it smell like had of
curiosity h a stem rub um I I was
hitting old uh Noto dog up and being
like the stem rub smells like a Mendo
purple
hybrid and S flux
capacitor he he was alluding I think
don't quote me but he was alluding to
you know that F1 dur being a Mendo
purple hybrid of
sorts you know I don't I don't know but
that seub it was just like because
anybody who smelled meno purple on the
stem rub it is one of the most pungent
just o wee plants you've ever smelled in
your life and that F1 derb has that same
thing but then it it it produces kind of
a a cookie is kind of nugget you know a
flower um and and then that Sim up
doesn't really translate so much to the
flower which you know it
happens yeah wow that's that's so so
interesting and I mean out of curiosity
does the F1 derb does it smoke just like
a regular durb what what's it like on
its own okay um I'm mostly familiar with
uh the uh this cut that goes around
Colorado Oregon California yeah as
Durban Poison and it's just a a super
strong it it tests it like five% or
4.5% uh pure
terpinolene and so the F1 derb I I don't
smell any t pentalene in it you know
so but then uh you know there might be a
aspects of like uh black licorice Anis
to it which you know uh most people
associate that with Durban Poison you
know the original old school Urban
Poison um but Mendo purple like
especially in the s1s there's all kinds
of black licorish and Anis in that stuff
so I associate it more with the meno
purple whereas other people might
associate with you know an old school
Durban
Poison yes okay okay this is all very
interesting cuz it all it definitely
checks out in your head cuz the meno per
structure is also probably not too
different to a cookie structure in a
sense it's a it's a lanky indicia type
yeah yeah I was going to say you
mentioned earlier that there's long been
these speculations uh from uh from
Powers up jiger you know Cherry Pie has
F1 derb in it in GDP do you have any
thoughts on that do you think that's
more likely or less likely than the
cookies climb ah man I
mean I I I could go either way um you
know on that um you know maybe yes maybe
no you
know I I don't want to over speculate
quite yet what it makes me think is if
it was true he like jiger would have had
to have somehow been connected to like
either their crew made GDP cherry pies
cookie made it all and that's how he
knows or he was somehow tied into all of
the crews that did it and they're all
like oh yeah we all use this same clone
like it does just even from a logistics
point of view it's sort of a bit
doubtful right I think a lot of it is
just you know they had this plant this
plant and this plant in the room these
plants Herm you know and you know they
got seeds out of it and then when they
grow them out it's usually if you know
your plants you can you you can kind of
tell you know what might have pollinated
what you know etc etc I mean that that's
what got me into feminized breeding you
know 25 years ago you know a little Herm
in a room finding a seed in your sensey
crop and being like o growing that seed
out that seed don't harm grows something
fantastic like a little bit of this a
little bit of that it's like oh shoot
you know these femin seeds can't be as
bad as some people say they is you know
truly
truly so I mean I know you've done
extensive work with the kle have you had
any change of mind do you think kle
might still be in cookies or are you
more now leaning to the Mendo perss as
you've alluded
to I mean if there's GDP in there at any
step you know that's that's going to be
you know Ural right there
um I still think it has to have it there
because there's the whole OG Kush breath
thing and anytime you double up on a a
cookie type genetic like if you cross uh
cookies with fritters or cookies with
wedding cake or wedding cake with
fritters you get these
ogkb the OG Kush breath uh you know Girl
Scout cookie uh types and that's always
a doubling up on the genetic it's the
recessive trait coming back through in
any form of an
F2 and so it it's got to have that that
urle trait in there from from some way
somewhere you know I mean because I
haven't seen that that that phenotype or
genotype or whatever of plant you know
on anything but you know URL and Girl
Scouts going forward you
know yeah definitely I tend to agree
that I mean I guess the question then is
do you think we'll ever Truly find out
the lineage or do you think the best
we'll get is what you're doing just
making similar sorts of things and just
seeing what the seeds
produce I mean if the hybrids are
similar the same I mean uh you know I
think I think we can find out but you
know
um yeah yeah I don't
know it's trying yeah I mean well I was
gonna ask have you found that like the
most popular line from the F1 hybrids
you did with sorry the F1 Durban hybrid
you did is the flow r at F1 der like
people wanting to test it yeah I think
that's that's the one that definitely
holds the most
potential yeah H la la and have you have
you popped any of those yourself so far
is it just two early days oh no no um uh
they're they're they're in the ground
now I should have
known that's brilliant cool cool okay
well I mean I mean while we're on the
topic of the K I wanted to ask you know
have you got any urle projects in the
future because I know that like I mean k
work in general is pretty interesting to
me cuz I really like the plant I like
the effects the the flavors the smells
but you've also done a Twist in that
you've done like S2s and I think that
work is really quite novel among a lot
of breeders do you plan to take it to
S3s what what's your thoughts on the S2s
where are you at with the urle project
overall um so that that ties into you
know the whole ABC kind of recessive
inbred blah blah blah um so when when
when you grow the URL s1's out um you
get like 10% mutant which is that ogkb
type of plant and then you get like I
don't know 40 or
50%
crap and then then you get you know 20%
that you know are are pretty nice decent
representations and then you get maybe
10% that's just like o wee you know
these are high quality you know Urkle
type plants now when I took uh and you
know made uh Sister Sister S2s where I
took one sister and pollinated another
sister with it I grew a bunch of
different ones of those out and they
were all phenomenal they were like
90% uh just excellent plants you got rid
of all that nastiness that was in the
URL
s1s
Unfortunately they grow half as half as
slow or half as fast they grow twice as
slow as URL there we go and anybody
who's grown urel is like Urkel is slow
as [ __ ] and these things grow even more
slower well R of Snow's pce at that
point yeah but their their quality is
through the roof you know and so it's
just like as as a standalone they're
there you can't give this to any you
know it can't be grown
commercially you know so it's just like
well the quality is super high but the
economics of it is super low so it it
would be great as an
outcross um to something but not as just
a a a standalone type of
plan that's perfect cuz I wanted to ask
you know you've you've done a few
remakes of lines you've done using the
update like you know the KL S1 that
you've selected over the original when
you do these revised crosses do you find
that you get significantly different
results or it's just minorly different
but maybe a little better in certain
ways they're they're definitely
different um so uh like the 103 times
Urkel I've done it both ways I've done
uh Urkel times 103 and then 103 times
Urkel um those plants don't have the
they're like twice as big you know twice
as fast growing as the sister sister so
you know it's because it has all the
Urkle genetics and then you know um you
know the the S1 where the S1 S1 you know
it it doesn't have all that wide so
those those plants grew way better than
you know than the S1
s1s but their quality was way more
variable as
well you know they were higher C quality
than an S1 just by itself an URL
S1 but you know um they weren't as high
a quality as just the Sister Sister s
ones wow do you you think that that sort
of thing is what you're going to do
going forward like looking to hunt
through some s1's and then do those
pairings yeah no that that's that's
that's my favorite part that that's why
I make s1's you know I mean you know and
and eventually you know like you know
breed them into S2s and then and then
hybridize you know this F S2 population
with this S2 population you know and th
those plants those plants can really be
phenomenal if you make the right
selections that's really exciting to
hear I'm I'm Keen to see where it goes
you you've touched on a deeper sort of
point that I was hoping to ask you which
was that I was wondering have you made
any observations about the way traits
are passed on when you f one plant
versus the other like as you said you
reverse the 103 onto the original and
you reverse the original onto the 103 do
you find that the act of reversing a
plant and making it the pollen donor
changes the way it passes on genes or
it's Lely the
same it seems like it's different um so
um the main one I have uh example of
that is I grew up um let me make sure I
got this right I grew up I think a
hundred of um meno purple times
Urkel and the meno purple itself in s1's
is extremely variable you know um flower
wise smell wise I mean the plants you
know all look almost the same but once
they flower it it's all over the map um
now in the Mendo purple times Urkel it
was like all kinds of different uh meno
purle type
variations um but then I grew 20 24 25
out of the uh Urkel times meno purple
and every single plant was an URL type
plant you know um so it's almost like
you know they depending on if they are
used as a male or female they push
different things
forward you know I don't know I still
have a lot more experimentation to go on
all that but it definitely seems like
you know you you create different things
um depending on which one you reverse ah
you know and I remember in the past I I
can't remember if it was subcool or
someone used to say you know whatever's
the pollen donor is going to impart like
structure and potency do you think it's
as clearcut as that or do you think it's
like it's more variable and it just it
might vary I think it's real variable
especially I think it really depends on
you know you know what your pollen donor
is and how much you know stuff is in
that um you know I I uh had phos run up
a bunch of stuff you know over the years
you know for better or worse and um a
lot of their data
is yeah not factual um but my main thing
for doing doing that um having things
tested is I really want to know what the
you know um what the stability is what
the um you know I'm having a brain fart
on the words I ain't a scientist
um you know whenever you get into an S1
S2 population you know everything
becomes more and more stable and so it
really depends on what you're using as
your
male um how how it passes forward I
think you know on on that topic I mean
it was one of the fan submitted
questions people were wondering you know
obviously the phos the way it all played
out and the Fallout from it left a lot
of people quite skeptical of genomic
companies and data collection companies
the like M do you think there's any
companies that are currently around that
you would trust with it or you're just
not really engaging in that sort of
thing at the
moment I haven't uh entertained it too
much just because um you know uh F's
kind of left a sour taste in my mouth
and I don't I don't know
if any of these other um you know
companies can do what we want them to do
or if it's just going to be more of the
same filos type of blah blah blah you
know yeah I think that's a pretty
understandable approach a few questions
ago you when you were talking about The
KES being really slow growing and like
not not good commercial picks at all I
did want to ask you out of the seeds you
offer
what are your top three recommendations
for someone who maybe has a facility or
a bigger space they're working with and
they're like I want to run your stuff
but you know it does need to lend itself
a little bit towards the things that a
commercial operation would need you know
maybe a little better yielding and maybe
some good TPS what are maybe some things
you might recommend for those folk oh
usually anything in the like uh
T1000 uh you know catalog th those you
know were really good when you know I
ran them um you know I I like the KMD
hybrids you know they make really high
quality you know plants and big yielders
you know stuff that you know people can
you know get potency and yield because
that's that's another thing too uh when
when you're doing commercial you need
you know yields and you need High tests
because everybody's obsessed with you
know something that has got to be 30 35%
testing you know none of the
dispensaries you know are going to pay
money for something that don't test
High yeah it's a sad truth right I feel
like you know the real hardcore cannabis
Community the the sort of the space that
we exist in so to speak like generally
speaking I just say anyone who's
listening to this show you're probably
like in the top 0.1% of passionate about
CU like who else would sit here and
listen for hours about this stuff and um
feel like our community is starting to
accept very much that like you know the
chem 91 you know maybe it tests like 18
19% but it's it's good smoke you know do
you think we'd ever get there
commercially where we get more of a
general education among the public or do
you think the numbers will still
dominate they it needs to get to a point
where the numbers don't mean you know uh
anything because real realistically if
you think about it the numbers are an
equation you know
every plant or most plants have like a
ceiling right and you know if you take
one puff you know two puff three puff
you know you keep going up well some
plants might have a ceiling of two two
Puffs whereas another 10 another 100 you
know and so you know something with 18%
10 pffs Deep you're like whoa I
shouldn't have taken those last three
you know where has you know something
with a ceiling of like you know three or
four Puffs uh you can't get higher so
it's just like you know that 30% you
know a ain't really doing you much much
favors when you can't get higher than
that three or four Puffs so you
know have you got any thoughts on what
it is that actually contributes to the
ceiling effect I think I I Rel listened
to the DJ Short episode not long ago and
he said oh I think maybe there's like a
tiny bit of CBD in the background or
something it just sort of like limits
how high you can get I'd be interested
to hear do you have any thoughts on what
might be that ceiling we talk
about oh I don't know if I think that
deep good Smoke's good
smoke yeah yeah I'm I'm a pretty simple
fell you know if it sniffs good you know
and does the trick you know I'm okay
that works for me as well I mean on that
topic have you got any plants or crosses
that you would recommend to people if
they are looking for something that has
a higher ceiling cuz I actually get a
lot of messages from people who are
probably only used to the more modern
stuff and they're like I don't really
get what people mean by this ceiling
thing right right I mean I swear the the
the cams uh you know the whole chem
family you know tends to do really well
and like you mentioned about that chem
91 um you know it generally does only
test around like 18 19% you know every
time we have it tested and yet it will
in hybrids it will almost double a lot
of you know if you cross it with
something weak it almost doubles the you
know the numbers with whatever you cross
it to so you know I mean chem 91's not
even remotely my favorite as a
standalone but just what it can do you
know in hybrids and everything you know
there's no arguing it's it's an
excellent plant ideally you know more so
for
breeding let's let's go down this path
because I got a few questions about the
chem I'd love to ask you and and the
first one is what is your personal
favorite of the chem 91 hybrids you've
done um I've had a few I've had a few uh
I I definitely smoked all of uh all of
this uh slacked plant of uh uh Sour
Diesel times chem 91 that thing was
amazing um and then there was there was
just a regular old chem 91 times Girl
Scouts that I smoked all that one too
was really good um so um I don't I don't
know how many I've grown in in the last
year or two oh uh no no there I I grew a
few but they were like triple hybrids I
think they were uh Kim 91 times Girl
Scouts crossed with you know like
ruthless runts and uh you know some of
these other things
um and you know th those all came out
really nice as well
so that's interesting I I was talking to
Noto dog recently and he he mentioned
that you and him were talking about it
and you'd said you know the chem it just
really passes on potency quite
consistently when I heard that I started
thinking do you view it in that sense as
essentially a breeding tool more than
like its own unique thing or how do you
use it in breeding projects
oh definitely definitely I mean you know
it it's definitely a tool to to increase
potency and you know all that um yeah
and and most recently you've done the
really interesting and novel chem 91
hybrids I think a lot of people super
interested in them um for the chem1 how
would you describe it to people what's
its effect like what's it like as a
plant so one um it it it tests you know
on par with you know a lot of the other
chems uh roughly usually around
20% um but uh it uh it hased like 5%
Tarpin and um the bulk of that is all
mirene it's like one of the highest just
you know pure miren plants that you know
have in the catalog um it's like a oh I
don't know know 11 or 12 week type of
plant and she's pretty ugly you know by
you know today's standards you know I
mean everybody wants that pretty pretty
looking you know flower but she she's an
ugly girl and she kind of tends to pass
that ugly on oh no you know but you know
I
mean that's a tough one as especially
today everybody loves Girl Scout cookies
and all the poly hybrids you know with
that they like them CU they're pretty
but you know half the time if you like
smoke and cardboard they're all right
too you know that is a common tur
profile we've seen a lot of hype strains
the old cardboard
T I mean while we're talking about the
chem1 I think as time's gone by I've
been able to appreciate more that it cuz
to me I always thought the chem1 it was
just out in the field on its own and
then the more I look at photos of say
the chem 4 I'm like actually I can see a
lot of relation here the question is do
you think it's from the same seed stock
as the chmd and the chem 91 or do you
think it just has to be
different okay so you know you you you
might you know uh get different
information from different people's you
interviews but uh I I still uh stand
strong on the fact that I think chem 91
you was the only you know seed that was
really kept from I mean there was the
original chem sister from 91 and I think
she was kept for a while too um but for
the most part it was the 91 that was
kept and I think the D is a hybrid with
the 91 and then I think the one through
four are all the same hybrid or not the
same hybrid as the chmd but all you know
um a hybrid of 91 cuz you know I got
those those uh I got clones of those
from Joe bran seed plants you know of
the one through four and they they were
almost identical sisters you know but
then their flowers you know segregate
out and they they look a lot you know
different you know to each other the
number three was like the 91 but bigger
chunkier better better plant um but it
was like you know a match on the the you
know the the look and the smell and all
that um the four was like amazing
compared to all of them except for the
fact that you know it was It was kind of
terrible you know three or four weeks
after you harvested it because it just
went
Brown yeah I I've heard that a bit I
mean I'd be curious to ask you know I'm
sure we're going to do a lot of
questions about this but like the chem 1
and the chem 4 visually at least have
always struck me as looking like like
there's like an nl5 Haze in the mix what
do you suspect the pollen donor onto the
chem 91 might have been to make
those I I think somewhere in that realm
you know it definitely something
something sensey and you know
the the the the question I've always had
is you know um it for for for Greg you
know Kim dog Greg um is uh what was he
growing in the rooms because I know he
only had chem 91 in for maybe four or
five years at best before he lost it
right and
so what was in his rooms you know during
those years where something might have
harmed and you know that's where he
would have gotten those seeds he swears
they came from that same Original Seed
bat but it's highly unlikely
you know I don't I don't believe it you
know but you know that better question
is what was in his rooms at those times
and he's posted what you know over the
years what was but you know uh I think
some of the posts uh from like Planet
ganja and IC mag aren't aren't there
anymore you know Planet ganja's gone and
IC mag you know he deleted his account
I'm sure and so a lot of his posts that
weren't like you know you know copied
and you know
um blah blah blah are gone you know and
it's hard for most people to find out
who said what you know because it's just
going to say guest you know and uh you
know somebody like me who was there is
like I know who that guest
was you
know okay so I mean the followup you
sort of alluded to it but I just wanted
to nail down on it you know there's a
lot of focal discussion recently when
Matt put up a post saying that you know
he's suspects the chem D is the 91 by
Super Skunk is that the lineage you
think is what's behind the
D it could be it could be um or uh I
mean uh I've I've always almost thought
uh you know it could be like maybe a
Shiva
skunk because I swear I swear I swear
Greg was growing some Shiva skunk back
then but you
know it could have been any of those
types you know yeah Shiva almost see
feels right you
know yeah now that you say I I do get
what you mean a bit of that skunk
influence in there as well like the not
the uh Virginia Super Skunk but just the
sensey
skunk right right right
yeah yeah no that that certainly makes
sense and then so look we as I did when
I was chatting to Noto we've spoken
about the one and the four the D the
question has to be asked
any ideas on the 91's lineage then I
mean for one I think the just by you
know breeding with it s1's predominantly
because you know I've grown out the
better part of a couple hundred you know
s1's with me and you know the homies and
it it it's so stable I swear you know
the s1's I've made I I think the chem 91
itself is an S1 and so you know
technically I think you know what I made
are probably S2s you know and then
um I think uh whatever plant the chem 91
came from
um yeah there's there's a little bit of
debate on it but uh I I don't I don't
think some people are too wrong with the
the whole tie in with hash
plant yeah well that was what I was
going to ask where do you feel Skelly
fits in the picture cuz I I really
believe that the smell and the effect
are very similar but I will happily
acknowledge that the structures are so
different I'm happy to entertain the
debate that maybe they're not related
but it is it is a very uncanny
resemblance in smell and effect I've
always
thought so you know I have I have Skelly
um I also have
hp13 they both have a similar look
between each other you know not not any
where close to you know like identical
but you know there's a lot of
similarities between those two and then
those two kind of got me thinking well I
grew hash plant one back in the day um
from the devil's Harvest crew and that
plant has some very strong uh
similarities to not only the uh hp13 and
the and the Skelly but it almost almost
looks more like the chem 91 you know
because it has those dark dark leaves it
has a similar Leaf shape and it actually
grows like a a bigger uh chem 91
Outdoors um than you know chem 91
itself so I don't know I don't know
there there there could be something to
the whole hash plant you know
theories yeah totally I mean you touched
on the hash plant 13 I think it's one
where people hear about it but it's hard
to get a lot of info about it what's
your thoughts on it is it is it cuz I I
mean I've only seen the plant in veg one
time at Bob hemp Hill's house and I was
like oh this is a very thin leaf plant
and he was like yeah um what what's your
take on
it um I think it's a hash plant hybrid
you
know definitely retains a lot of you
know the hash plant to it which you know
anytime you have an indicia sativa
hybrid a lot of times those indicas can
be dominant in the structure it seems
you know um I've got a ton of experience
going right now where I'm trying to go
both ways you know Indica sativa and
then sativa times Indica I I I just want
to see how all those pan out with the
you know using the different different
ones for male and female but uh um the
hp13 um you know it uh
yeah yeah
um I don't know I don't want to even
speculate on that one well I mean I was
going to say you know I think uh JJ has
put up some posts talking about how he
thinks there's like some burmes and some
stuff in there given your experience
with the Burmese have any thoughts on
that speculation because just based off
what I'm hearing it sounds like the
Burmese is like maybe way too long
flowering right but you know the the
right Inda you know it'll it'll shorten
that flower time down pretty good and uh
I don't think the hp13 is a a really
quick flow I mean you know maybe a 10
weer so yeah um you know yeah I don't
know I don't
know some of those tur profiles do kind
of match up you know with that that
sweetness of of the Burmese it's
definitely not Doesn't Remind me of like
the Indica type of tur
yeah interesting interesting okay and
then a nice little segue into the NL
work you did was for the longest time
people have speculated that like sort of
the backbone of chem dog may have some
NL in it now that you've done your NL
work do you see that at
all
um if if there is any NL in it um I
don't think it's going to be the five
and the only you know one I've I've run
out
was is the five um there were some
similarities uh on you know uh at least
one plant specifically when I first ran
them out to the old norn lights I got
from my dad back in
94 um but overall it it was more of a a
a different type of you know Norm light
that you see in a lot of hybrids you
know out there um I don't think you know
I had the nl5 you know back in the day
we just had it as Northern Lights so you
know I'm not entirely sure you know what
we had one two 10 I don't
know and and like what what's your
takeaway been from the project you've
done with Matt and you know the seeds
from Greg mallister have you had any
cool insights into that all and and tell
us a little bit about what the NL seed
line is like in
general um I mean it it's like a you
know know uh the nl5 of course is you
know essentially supposed to be a pure
indicia crossed with a Hawaiian
sativa um so um it's definitely hash
plant esque you know um you know super
Frosty you know um some some of the
plants lean towards that um you know
that Hawaiian type um you know but you
know most of them most of them are just
kind of like that that Amsterdam thing
you know that was wild and crazy all the
way through the early mid 90s you know
and uh you know def definitely a
throwback that's for sure you know to
those that era and do you think it
stands up to what a lot of people
remember or do you think there is an
element of like rose shade
glasses
uh I mean as as much as I'm you know I I
love preservation and you know I mean
you you you take all the you know the
land races land races are not you know
they're they're they're not great for a
whole lot of things you know you can't
grow in commercial you
know oftentimes they're they don't
they're not great for Standalone plants
like you know head stash you know
they're like building blocks and it kind
of feels like the NLS you know might be
great for building blocks but they they
really don't stand up to you know the
the designer weed of
today yeah certainly I can understand
that I mean as a follow on having had
that experience with the
nl5 is there a part of you that would be
Keen to grow out the purest Inda if you
had like good
source um I mean uh Matt uh Matt rot uh
he's he's got some of those seeds and he
um he tried to give them to me a few
months back and um I think I got too lit
and forgot
him I'll shoot him a message and bump
him I like do it oh no no no it's not on
him at all shoot all I have to do is say
yes and yeah we'll gets to Kraken I
don't I don't know uh you know the the
the Pierce is a is an interesting one um
it could be you know probably closer to
the the northern lights that you know I
grew back in the the mid 90s um but uh I
mean I'd like to grow it I got so many
things though on the plate it's like
damn it I'm not trying to overload you
so I mean look if you had to guess what
do you think the NL you were growing
back in the 90s was do you think it was
maybe more like a one or something
that's my guess that's always been you
know kind of my hunch um yeah because I
I never from everything I've seen of the
five it definitely you know didn't seem
like that was that was the hybrid um but
uh yeah yeah yeah that's cool and I mean
you know to tie it on up you you also
did the work with the Hawaiian lights
which was really cool you know how did
that differ to the nl5 and and what sort
of the general description you give for
that one they were extremely similar to
the nl5 but there was just a ton of that
super you know sweet pineapple just
fruity you know just Hawaiian turps on a
lot of those ones you know um there
there was like hints of that stuff in
the uh in in the nl5 but it was it was
almost prominent and dominant on on a
lot of the ones in the Hawaiian
lights yeah wow wow and I know that you
had selected keepers of the ANL and the
Hawaiian do you plan to breed with them
going
forward oh well you know
uh the mother room got a little full
again and uh I had to make some harsh
decisions so I I I have I think I have
two two keepers held of the nl5 and then
everything else um oh maybe I I might
have kept one Hawaiian Life my my mother
room is ridiculous
so sometimes I don't even know what's in
there do I dare ask how many plantss do
you have in your mother
room uh well let's not talk about that
on
TV too hot for TV I love
it okay well look we we did have a fan
submitted question and they were
wondering uh they sort of reading into
where we were going with this discussion
they were saying you know I can only
imagine that maintaining a mother room
the size you have is almost a full-time
job in itself do you have any tips or
tricks for maintaining a big big library
and as a further followup do you have
any IPM tips cuz I can only imagine
that's something you're having to keep
on top of right right um I
mean I'll admit right now um I I uh um
try to do as minimal as I can just to
keep everything alive I try to grow
things I underfur things a lot not so
can vouch for this I underfur things a
lot just to slow down so they don't grow
fast I I give very very limited nitrogen
you know because otherwise you know
they're always up in the lights if I
don't you know slow them down as for IPM
uh my favorites are pyganic spinoid and
uh liquid sulfur you know that tends to
you know keep most of the bugs you know
that could potentially come through you
know down and out
we we always have uh the thrips flying
in through the through the open doors
and you know that kind of good stuff
definitely there's always powdery mildew
growing on everything outdoors so yeah I
can only imagine up your neck of the
woods cuz I think like a lot of people
who have never been to mesino or you
know Northern California in general
probably can't appreciate how what the
climate is like there cuz it's only
recently I've really like you're like it
is really foggy in the mornings and most
of the day like it's hard to
appreciate yeah and I'm I'm pretty much
entire mostly most entirely Coastal
based with all all my stuff uh I I still
grow my you know six California you know
personal legal plants uh you know out
out out in my place in the Hills but you
know that's a totally different
environment out there you know it's 100
115 degrees you know all summer long out
there um and you
know total total opposite of the coast
wow I mean on that point what sort of
plants would you run for yourself both
from like things that you like but also
that would do well in those conditions
because it sounds pretty
hot yeah um I mean uh one of my old
school favorites out there um that
always really did well was old Betsy you
know and that's something that you know
90% of people are just like what but you
know people around this general area are
like yeah old bets's what's up you know
so she she was always a good one um my
uh my uh bomb threat Bubba um my bubba
S1 selection she she actually does
really well out there you know um for
for whatever reason I've got one of her
growing this year and uh Irene Irene
tended to do pretty okay um when I grew
her so I've got a on Irene this year um
kimd did good and uh um you know she's a
late one but you know really good
quality so I broke down put a KMD out
this year just for just for fun so and a
few few others I'm just trying out this
year that's a a beautiful mixture I
would be feeling very pleasured to smoke
any of those strains so I guess the
question is are we going to see you do
hybrids with some of those ones like a
project maybe with like cuz I know
you've pollinated old Betsy and some of
the other ones you mentioned would you
ever in the Irene would you consider
doing a project like reversing Irene or
reversing
Betsy so uh I reversed Irene
and um I think I had a half half a bed
half a light of Irene to pollinate and I
got 20 seeds oh no yeah uh Irene was um
like what I call a one percenter like
she like I got so few seeds on my IR
like a four light Irene reversal that I
grew a bunch of them out immediately
just to make sure it wasn't like pollen
contamination or like something else
hmed in the room and they were all Irene
plants so I was like yeah yeah okay but
the the yeah it was the pollen was not
very viable um and there wasn't much of
it to begin with um and then Betsy uh
she produced zero pollen I I reversed
her and nothing so I'm a yeah I'm a
little sketched to do Betsy again I
don't know um but yeah yeah yeah that's
beautiful segue for me it's my favorite
saying beautiful segue because we had a
question about like failed reversals
like one of the listeners is currently
trying to reverse a chem dog D S1 they
got from you they found like a nice one
they really like and they're like for
the life of me I I he's I've seen the
photos he's reversed it two or three
times he'll get the nanas but there's no
pollen in them ever you got any tips or
tricks for stubborn
reversals I I kind of wish I did but it
it's it's tough and you know uh it gets
tougher in each gener
um like you know s1's you're going to
have less plants that will actually you
know give you viable pollen um when you
hit S2s it's even fewer um I've heard
Sam the skunkman say that once you hit
S5 it's terminal you you don't you don't
go past
S5 you know but just seeing how plants
do you know from the S1 to the S2 you
know I'm like I don't know if I don't
even want to deal with it S4 or five
plant little shrubby little
mutants wow but I I honestly I I don't
have any tips for that because
uh
um the the the few times I've made a
bunch of selections um with s1s and I I
I've gone through and I've sprayed all
of these uh different s1s um you know
I'll have some that produce lots of
pollen some that produce a little bit of
pollen and then a lot that produced no
pollen so you know it's not easy it's
not easy sure sure we had another
question that was was very similar just
talking about you know you you change
dilutions do you apply the spray more
frequently if it if I'm interpreting
this correctly it sounds like you've
just got to reverse a lot of plants and
and maybe one of them will work is that
right uh yeah it it can be like that too
um that that's the thing too uh um i'
I've experimented a lot with you know
different
dilutions uh multiple you know frequency
you know Springs uh you know this that
other um and so i' I've mentioned this
before um generally when I just reverse
you know a a plant I'll I'll take uh
like eight plants is my usual and you
know they'll be in like five gallon pots
and they'll be you know nice two to
three foot you know plants you know
round and tall and uh often times with
uh some of these you know even moderate
you know reversal plants I'll only get
out of eight I'll only get like two that
produce decent pollen and then I'll have
a couple put on you know midy pollen and
then I'll have a bunch of them put on no
pollen so if you have somebody reversing
just one plant or two plants I mean that
you know you're you're going to have you
can imagine you know there's there's
going to be like you know three four
five fails and then you might get one to
kind of hit and then another time you'll
get one to really hit you know and
that's off just the same exact plant
same dilution same spraying you know so
I mean i' I've definitely done this a
lot but I you know I I still can't you
know tell you oh this is what works you
know because it's so variable and why I
mean my question is why can you spray
eight plants with the same exact
dilution same time same everything and
yet you know two are great pollen two
are midy and four don't even give you
pollen I I'm like uh I got questions
too
look yeah I have to acknowledge the
first time I ever did a reversal I think
I got one of the midy ones and and I
thought that was like the Baseline and
uh I'll acknowledge I've been caught out
the next time I did it I got no pollen
and I was like what the [ __ ] is going on
right
right happens to everyone it's so
variable uhuh it's like uh it's like the
chem dog it's up to the
Stars yeah yeah yeah so I wanted to ask
you you know you have been doing these
Wicked grows in these Planters I think
everyone should go look at your
Instagram you do like you know these
really cool feno hunts in the beds um
really gorgeous looking plants can you
give us a quick rundown of your style
when you're doing that because I got to
give you a shout out I remember first
time I came to the emerald cup I came
and saw you at the booth and uh you you
were mentioning that um the Girl Scout
reversal you were trying to do it didn't
work so you ended up with all this
sensey crop and um the cookies and the
patient zero bud you gave me was so
memorable and you were like yeah I grew
it in like the the Planters and um oh my
God so Superior really memorable stuff
how do you do it what's the run
down uh pretty basic I just use like a a
a cocoa Pete blend uh you know um around
here it's called Black Gold but you know
um there's tons of different types and
then uh I just uh put in a bunch of uh
bunch of amendments um I think my base
is mostly fish frass insect frass and uh
um you know trace minerals
and yeah i' I've got like 20 different
organic ingredients I kind of I try to
give the plants a buffet of quick
release uh medium release and slow
release stuff and then I try to just
give them plain water for the duration
that they're in in those beds just super
simple you know um yeah beautiful stuff
beautiful stuff I'd love to ask you
normally we we start with this one but
uh we've been a bit sidetracked having
fun what have you been smoking on
recently um I've still been smoking on a
ton of like the um uh the Family Feud
Family Feud times uh um or wait yeah
Family Feud times like ruthless runs um
Family Feud
times uh the punch one was okay
um uh the triangle cush uh arle 103 s1's
um those were really nice um bunch of Z
s1's A bunch of sherbet s ones um
basically uh uh I I I did a a feno hunt
a handful of months back and so I've had
like 500 plants
hanging we we go up and like just you
know pull pull you know three or four
you know samples every every night or
two then we'll smoke through you know
the the different ones um but uh yeah
pretty much uh you know just been
smoking on that last 500 seed run
so yeah just a bunch of bunch of stuff
it's it's a tough job but someone's got
to do it that's right that sounds
amazing I mean a lot of questions to
jump into there I I think the first one
is do you feel like when you're testing
that many
phenotypes it it can almost become a bit
more difficult to discern the clear
winners cuz I'm sure at the end of a 500
seed feno hunt you've got like 10 plants
of the same variety and they're all
really good like how do you how do you
Whittle them down or do you just end up
with a few cap is it starts like that
like it starts you know initially like
it's it's difficult it seems and it
probably you know is the whole time but
um eventually you you start you know
Finding ones that really stand out right
and then you know you go back to those
and you go back to those and then you
get sad when there's no more of that
plant left uh we had a a a skittles 85
S1
and uh that one stood out and we kept
trying to smoke all these other Skittles
ass ones and it was just like H eh and
then we just chiefed through the whole
z85 plant and now we have no more z85 we
don't even want to smoke the
others you know you become
spoiled yeah yeah yeah but um I actually
am uh trying uh I've I've got a reversal
going with that z85 right now and uh I'm
not crossing my fingers too too too much
because Z is a hard one you know to
reverse yeah interesting what's what is
the 85 phenotype
like uh well it it has like all the
turps of of Z and it's
potent wow because Z itself ain't ain't
the strongest smoke in the shop um when
when uh when I uh um had a
um had uh the ABCs
tested um they came in pretty low and Z
came in 2%
higher so B bastard cannabis is almost
as strong as Z wow I never would I never
would have thought that there you
go so you know so so when you've done
this massive Skittles feno hunt what
what sort of insights have you gotten
from that have you got any more ideas
about what might be the lineage of it oh
I I think well for one I think it's
probably an S1 uh Z is an S1 to start
with um and then um I'm pretty sure it's
just some some type of like a Girl Scout
cookie hybrid um Girl Scout cookie OG
type you
know something along those lines it
doesn't even have to be an OG type it it
could just be a Girl Scout cookie hybrid
type and the OG is you know you know
from the Girl
Scouts so yeah wow okay so and then you
know you you sort of touched on it
Loosely you did the sherb S1 project did
that help solidify any thoughts about
the possible relationship I mean there
was definitely some Z types in there for
sure um or Z leaners let me put this way
but um I only ran 70 of them out I think
it was 70 only and yeah that's like more
than anyone
does but I I I didn't find a plant that
was like that right there is z you know
so um I did find one plant that was
freaking amazing and it was the best
smelling plant out of 500 plants
freaking off of that seed run um and on
the sherbet s1s it was just absolutely
amazing and it was just one of those
sure best ones but it was amazing and of
course you know I went to the Clone room
and yep that was the one that was dead
oh hot
breaking yeah so I kind of want to dip
into the sure best ones again and run
out at least a 100 or maybe even 200 see
if I can't find Z and that one so
interesting interesting and I mean from
like sort of a commercial point of view
what do you think we'll be able to
Dethrone the Skittles turps because it
feels like for something to be really
popular these days it's got to be like
gassy Skittles purple that's sort of the
general combo do you think anything is
going to help us Break Free of that
mold
uh maybe maybe a a new flavor but just
as just as
pungent yeah yeah so just some yeah I
guess it's almost ushered in this wave
of like it has to be insanely loud or
it's just it just can't stand up yeah
yeah cuz there's there's tons of just
average out there you know it it just
has to be something just really really
pungent and
strong yeah wow okay I mean in that same
Lane of thought indicas are just
absolutely dominating the market and I
know that there's a small but growing
movement of people who are like you know
we really need to show The General
public that sativas have a lot to offer
and it doesn't need to be like a pure
tie but you know super silver Hayes did
really well for a reason right like it
was sort of that middle ground do you
think that we'll ever get more traction
with sativas and the general public or
do you think that inder is just too
prevalent and when most people think of
weed they think of like getting a bit
zoned out in your chair at the end of
the day as opposed to like an uplifting
energetic thing right right I
mean it's should it should become more
prevalent um you you'd think more people
would would be entertaining it you
know during the day and stuff I don't
know uh it it's just uh I don't know
even the sativas that are available
they're just kind of so hybridized out
you know I don't even know if you're
you're really getting that sativa sativa
experience from you know
uh a lot of the sativa offerings you
know that's true would you ever want to
focus on doing like a sativa line or
it's just not really your passion oh no
no I I definitely would they're just I
mean indicas are way easier than they
are that's I'm sure yeah the time
constraints makes it hard doesn't it
yeah I'm I'm definitely trying to cross
kind of uh going back um you asked about
Tom's Hayes and um I'm I'm entertaining
some uh you know uh some of the kind of
how they built Hayes right um you know
hybridizing you know different sativas
Al together you know so I mean you know
cross the Burmese with you know a
Colombian with a you know a Mexican with
a you know so on and so on I mean if if
you start making you know good
selections of each one and then you know
you know combining them and then you
know I can even you know combine those
uh you using feminized techniques which
you would really speed things along and
you know kind of you know get to finish
product a lot sooner than if you're just
doing rag braiding once a year type of
thing yeah we we got uh a good um fan
submit a question which was they were
saying are there any Mexican varieties
that uh stand out to you that you would
consider to be some of the better ones
cuz I think there is a growing movement
of people who are realizing that
Colombians Mexicans maybe some of these
were the real unsung heroes of like the
land race sativas because you just
mostly hear about Thai and Southeast
Asia but Colombians go to big
following yeah I mean any of the older
ones you know I I wouldn't I personally
wouldn't trust anything you know uh
that's that's come up in the last 20 20
plus years but you know the older W
Hawkins Mitchell K you know all that
kind of stuff um anybody who's preserved
you know uh lines that came came out
because anything that's really I'm I'm
talking maybe 25 30 years anything
that's come from Mexico since then has a
good good chance of being you know
contaminated with you know modern
Amsterdam genetics whatever whatever you
know I mean and that's the same to be
said anywhere where land races come from
I mean I don't think you could go to
Afghanistan or praan or anything without
running across a bunch of DNA genetic
contamination of course I like the pun
as well DNA genetic contamination that's
good that's
good shout out Arian it wasn't a
purposeful
pun yeah um I mean you know
while we're on the topic I would love to
ask you know how do you go about
sourcing this material like if someone
messages you and says hey I got this
killer old stuff like do you have to
sort of approach that with an element of
Suspicion or do you have like a set way
you go about vouching stuff what's your
process I mean most of the stuff I've
you know worked with is you know all
either older stuff or you know you can
kind of uh you can kind of vet where it
came from you know follow the trail back
um you know if somebody's like I just
got it from my cousin you know last year
you know blah blah blah I'm like yeah
well you know might not be the best
source yeah but uh you know in in in the
land race Community you
know a lot of them a lot of folks in it
you know tend to you know Trace Trace
things back you know pretty well so and
then bottom line is is you know uh I
always grow you know grow these things
out
beforehand and if I like them I'll use
them but if it's there there's been
plenty like I grew out a a purple yaron
line uh years ago and it was absolutely
horrible and tons of people are talking
it up but man uhuh I didn't even make
one seat of that no thank
you yeah so you know
wow that I mean just to quickly you know
wrap up that school of thought with the
land Racers do you think where quickly
slash have already got to a point where
land races essentially will only exist
in people's seed cataloges and like
they're not really indigenous to places
anymore oh yeah I mean there there might
be little tiny Pockets here in
there but I mean uh land races generally
stem from areas where a decent amount of
people were you know growing you know
for some kind of commercial you know
right reasons and that's you know why
they have seeds that's why you know
seeds became available one way or
another so but now you know there's
either not that happening or you know I
I I don't see a whole lot of people you
know keeping things going
you know outside of little tiny Niche
Pockets you
know yeah look it makes sense and it's
certainly a bit concerning I I have to
sort of hope that in the next 20 so
years like people realize what's going
on and especially when you see Thailand
opening the floodgates to cookies it's
like I don't think they're going to be
growing Thailand
races no they're
not uh uh uh uh
well yeah well okay while we're on the
topic of old school stuff that's been
preserved I know you've got the Kush 4
cutting which is one that you really
don't hear mentioned very much what can
you tell us about it or you could say I
had the fish for
cutting that one fell through the crack
uh it was a it was a cool plant it was a
cool Plant
um I don't know if I can't remember how
if I'm supposed to talk about that or
not um I I I got that through
bod maybe maybe I'll hit bod up and be
like can I talk about that you can
censor it but uh got I got that through
bod and he got it directly from Jim
Ortega right
and um one one of the stories was uh the
Hindu Kush um you know that was
available back in the day was kush 4
crossed with norn lights 2 right which
was the cushiest of the norn lights um
so I mean you know it it's a nice plant
um you know has a nice insy turp um it
smells very Bubba
esque on a different structured uh style
of a plant um but you know um
past past you know it coming from Jim
Ortega
um I don't know a whole lot about
it yeah that look that's that's the
story I'd heard from bod that it was
like one of the parents sents he used
and it meant to be really good so that
that all kind of checks out I know you
did some hybrids with it with like the
T1000 have you had a chance to see how
any of those have turned out or you just
got your plate full already no no I I I
ran a I ran a couple of the Kush hybrids
out um definitely the
t1000s and uh they they were good
um they they weren't as turpy as you
know I mean Ju Just like we've talked
you know there's one two three different
things that everybody wants and you know
everything else you know people are like
eh and so it kind of falls into that
category it made some beautiful flowers
they smelled good blah blah blah but
yeah they weren't that overthe toop
turpy so
you know kind of to the
Wayside yeah that that is interesting
how you talk about it you know like
there's things we want there's things
other people want if you if you were
just left to your own devices and could
pursue just purely passion projects you
know you you win the lotto and so now
you're just breeding for just shits and
giggles it's what you want to do what
sort of stuff would you be focusing
on
h Huh maybe I should start thinking
about that all the time
um I always um I think I'm kind of
already doing that um but uh I don't
know uh that's a good
question I love the answer man that you
you're living the dream already you're
pursuing the passion it's a good answer
right because I tell people a lot of
people have this sort of dire straight
view of the modern breeding landscape
and they say you know how am I meant to
establish myself everything's the same
and I sort of allude to what you just
said it's like pursue what you're
interested in if you're interested in it
people will probably be interested in it
right right I mean uh honestly you know
uh stuff that was just purely uh passion
was you know plan around with the ABCs I
mean uh surprisingly enough there wasn't
barely a single Dollar in in the ABCs so
uh yes uh I I had a lot of fun with
those and I'd like like to revisit them
too you know um but yeah it it it
definitely has to be just all passion um
I like those weirdo plants and I'd love
to be able to make one of those weirdos
actually you know a decent quality as
well yeah um definitely that that's cool
and we'll have to touch Bas next time we
chat how it's going for
you so there you have it friends what do
you think another
cracker as usual a massive massive shout
out to Caleb for taking the time to come
join us
today we're incredibly grateful to both
him and for everyone who's made it this
far into the episode please go check out
his incredible work you will not be
disappointed all of the CSI crosses are
fire as always we want to give a massive
shout out to our sponsors who you will
equally not be be disappointed with seed
here now number one seed bank in the
industry a guarantee on satisfaction not
just germination check them out guys you
will not be disappointed all the coolest
breeders the hottest drops everything
you could want and more Under One Roof
seats here now we appreciate you so so
much likewise prop biological we love
your Pest and predation technology
please guys don't wait until you have an
active infection to release some
beneficials into your garden do it now
stay on top have peace of mine knowing
that your garden is happy healthy
pumping on all cylinders huge shout out
to cop biological
systems likewise a huge shout out to
pulse sensors if you're looking to keep
your room dialed in you need to go no
further from VPD to ppf to all the other
measurements Under the Sun they got you
covered and with the introduction of the
latest pulse Hub you know you can
integrate all of your information into
one centralized unit whether you got a
single tent a single room a single
building a multi-state oper operation
it's time to get serious guys increase
resin yield flavor
potency get serious get a
pulse huge shout out to Organics alive
you want to be giving your plants the
best nutrition available and you know me
I'm an organic guy so it's no surprise
that I am stoked to have Organics alive
on board products ranging from Veg to
transition to flower any problem you're
in they've got a product specifically
designed to help you out don't just take
my word for it check them out online
guys they've been sweeping cups all
around the country from hom Growers like
yourself winning incredible cups there's
never been a better time to get on board
Organics guys check out Organics alive
massive shout out we appreciate you as
always and a massive thank you to our
newest sponsor Dino back if you're
looking to get off combustion and give
vaping a go I highly recommend you check
out dap they have small discret units
easily accessible both in price and
convenience with hits that replicate
bongs and Joints I cannot emphasize this
enough guys if you're thinking that you
want to get off combustion please
consider dinat I truly believe in this
company they produce phenomenal products
that will give you a hit unlike any Vape
you've ever tried before massive shout
out and thank you to dyat we appreciate
you
greatly that's about it for this one my
friends
looking forward to seeing you for part
two I'll see
[Music]
you