[Music]
[Applause]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts
this episode as always was brought to
you by our amazing sponsors seeds here
now guarantee not just on germination
also on satisfaction hit em up best in
the game best breeders we love em you'll
love em
go check it out
likewise go check out our friends at
radio ridge nursery
for all the best cuts in the game
exclusive breeder cuts you can't get
anywhere else
why waste your time pheno hunting just
kidding you should do fino hunting but
if you can't go check out their cuts
big big shout out to our friends at
organic gardening solutions top shelf
seed bank
and of course
dragonfly earth medicine
[Music]
as always guys if you want to help
support the show go check out the
patreon lots of additional content on
there for you to check out
episode we are extremely grateful to
have norcal i see mac here to lay down
the history
talk about some modern strains and what
he's up to
let's get into it
alrighty so a big thank you and welcome
to
the one and only the forum legend
himself norcal i see mag thanks so much
for joining us today
thanks for having me doug
as always i want to know what are you
smoking on my friend
uh like uh pretty much right now that
the newest thing is gonna be the og kbx2
and then i'm waiting on these uh
these new apple fritter crosses to come
out um but i mean they're they're still
a little ways away but uh the og kbx2 is
is basically uh
the og kb cross to a blueberry headband
and so uh like it's i mean it's
i definitely like it it has a lot more
vigor and it's uh it's it's it's not as
stony as the og kb the original one but
it's uh it's it's you know it's
definitely like more of a like a
a plant that you
you know you'd rather grow than the og
because og keep is kind of a pain in the
ass
for sure i mean just on a personal note
i'm curious what's the flavor on that
one like because i hear a lot about it
but i've never been able to try it
myself
yeah i mean i literally just finished
flowering it out which is when i saw you
i think of the emerald cup um that was
the first batch i had i mean there's
still some dialing in to be done
um but i mean it's a very like blueberry
dominant and so i kind of want to
further like work the line but it's just
um it's just a matter of getting the
time to do it but uh me and compound
genetics are actually uh i gave him the
cut so he's gonna be crossing it i want
to say it says like jet fuel gelato or
uh like some of his mails that he has
and so you know that's going to be very
interesting to see as far as like you
know that's uh like as far as what comes
about from that
yeah for sure i've seen some really nice
stuff come from that jet fuel gelato no
questions but just to divert back you
mentioned some apple fritter crosses i'm
always keen to hear about apple fritter
what can you tell me about it
i mean it was just a cut that i got from
my homies in la um i mean it's
definitely like you know i it's it's
it's uh apple fritters it's a very nice
cut i like it a lot you know i just
happened across it because i hit it with
like some palm that i got from my homie
um like always be flowering genetics and
uh like also my like uh i had some
purple pollen as well
um from
like csi like humble basically he
he i had some males from one of the
breedings that he did and um and you
know like i i utilized that pollen uh so
it's kind of like it was like an open
pollination and so um it's it's gonna be
interesting to see what comes out of
that right now i'm like i'm sexing all
those seeds like right now so
that's cool and are you looking to
preserve the apple flavor because i
often hear people debate about whether
the apple flavor really even is apple
like it's kind of a roundabout but it's
not super on do you want to keep that or
refine it or what's your plan
i mean i'd like to cross it i have some
blueberry f7s from dj short that i like
once i get a chance to have like a
little bit of time to uh to you know
fully like focus myself on that on that
work um i'll you know i'll crack them
and germinate them and and then utilize
those for to cross to that and see where
we get you know so it's um you know uh
besides that also i want to hit it back
to the og kb as well
uh you know so we'll see where it all
where it all ends up at but for the
meantime they're all just kind of in the
vault as far as this uh holding on to
them the the no seeds
and that's cool i'm definitely keen to
see what pans out with that and i've got
to ask the question
do you have any kind of fond memories of
any of the older dj short work like you
know everyone like has one thing where
like you know i used to get this really
good flow or i used to get this really
good blueberry do you have one of those
stories
uh i mean
it's the the only time that i would have
ever had access to like uh dj shorts
genetics uh uh like i never bought any
like uh you know like um from overseas
when
when we were buying stuff on on like
seed bay or breed bay or whatever
um but uh like it would it would have
been in amsterdam i was in amsterdam in
like 2006. they had like a couple
different phenotypes of like it's
blueberry there was a i think it's a lsd
uh
i i can't think about the strains off
the top of my head to be honest like if
i actually have his book was it
skywalker
no no it wasn't like skywalker came way
after after all of that like it's there
was an lsd i want to say it was one of
the strains he had uh the original
blueberry is one thing um i think there
there was a there's a few other ones
that he was pretty well known for um
like i said i have his book
here but um i mean we'll actually know
so
somebody actually took the goddamn book
so i don't have to be but the the
straight names would be in there but i
remember going to like barney's and uh
and and i think that the bulldog
in uh in amsterdam and they had a bunch
of stuff but this is in 2006. so a lot
of those lines have probably been
reworked or um or just are not even like
a like around anymore so
yeah yeah and i know that
he kind of stopped formally working with
them and then at that point i think they
started popping seeds to find new
parents and stuff like that
yeah yeah i mean now with like tissue
culture uh like being more prevalent i
it's definitely a lot easier to preserve
like genetics for like a longer period
of time but i mean it's really hard to
keep a plan alive for you know like i
said
like 15-20 years so
yeah okay well i love to ask people this
question what's the oldest clone that
you're aware of
man honestly like to me like me still
having the og kb is pretty like uh it's
pretty impressive
just because like that plant is
like when i got those when i got that
strain it was it was
it was butchered um it was in very bad
condition so it's it's uh it's it's very
interesting to see how like you know
like how it does now like it's pretty
healthy but i've actually had it tissue
cultured by my homie um at dsg labs and
um and like you know like he's pretty
much trying to figure out like what the
issues that it actually had because i
mean we went through like sorium and all
sorts of stuff so the fact that it's
still even um
like has as any vigor uh it's it's you
know
kind of impressive in a sense but beyond
that um
it's
man like i i like it's it's hard to put
a you know
to
to to basically tell you a strain that's
been around for so long i mean there's
like most most stuff has been lost and
you know and um unless they they backed
everything up by seed or whatever but
other than that like most times like
back in the days they didn't do it like
you know any of that so i mean even like
if people tell you that they have a
certain strain nowadays like if
somewhere to be like like they have uh
like train wreck or something i mean
more than likely i would i would
probably
um
i wouldn't say i wouldn't believe them
but it's just more of i think it's just
more of that terpene profile and um and
you know like that's
you know that's more of like where they
would classify it as far as like uh in a
train wreck profile
uh but you know i'm it's
i'm yeah it's it's at this at this at
this point and um
you know that like down the road it's uh
keeping a plant alive for that long like
train wreck was from like you know i
mean i remember hearing about that in
the 90s uh it's it's it's it's going to
be pretty impressive to find someone
that actually has like access as a
genetic still
yeah of course shout out to the people
who have that one i i've met a few who i
think do but i get what you mean where
like that profile became representative
of the strain in a way didn't it but
let's jump back on track for just a
second i know everyone's keen to hear us
talk about the og kb because you just
brought it up but let's put that to the
side for just a minute what was your
first experience with cannabis
i mean it was like uh
i mean i didn't i didn't smoke weed
until like basically i got out of uh out
of high school i graduated whatnot and i
was just i pretty much took like the
semester off and i didn't go to college
or anything and so i was just i was
hanging out at my homies house and um
and you know uh we we pretty much we
used to like literally just throw down
on like a dub every day and a 40 and uh
go to his house and just chill and his
parents were cool as [ __ ] uh
unfortunately like my homies not with us
anymore but um you know it was like we
had like a tight little crew
and uh like that was like our daily
ritual and that's when i started smoking
weed and then
pretty much i got into selling weed as a
result of all that because i figured it
would be
cheaper to just you know grab you know
grab a grab more like you know like a
larger amount like grab more quantity
and and it was because we were paying
like back then we were paying 20 bucks
for a [ __ ] for a dub which is like
it's kind of like unheard of nowadays
yeah okay and so do you remember any of
like the notable name strains of that
time
uh i mean back then
people i mean people were just throwing
names on whatever there was like juicy
fruit i know there was m39 um
uh okay i mean a lot a lot of the stuff
was coming from from you know from
british columbia from from uh from from
you know from canada so it um like i
said like like juicy fruit m39
um critical mass i want to say uh
like you know like just very
commercialized strains at this point
that people normally like if you had it
to this like this day uh you probably
would not be able to get much money for
it
and did you have a soft spot for any of
those looking back like kind of guilty
soft spot
i mean i mean not necessarily it's like
like uh
it's
i mean a lot of that stuff is was really
it was just like chemed out you know um
phospholoated you know like uh like
product that was just coming from like
like i said bc you know more than likely
uh like uh the
the only stuff that was like actually
was more notable would be probably the
outdoor that was coming out of like
mendocino and humble but
um you know like back then a lot of the
stuff that was in the streets was was
all going to be like canada like bc
stuff so
and it's um you know like they were kind
of like a lot of the times like they
were like what was coming in was stuff
that was kind of bland in the uh in
in the the sense of like like a nose as
far as like like the smell
and it all kind of has to do with as far
as like uh they didn't like when you're
shipping large quantities of of
anything you're not gonna want it to
smell too bad and you know so that all
the skunky varieties were pretty much
coming out of like mendo and humble at
the time
um
but back then there was like i can't i
can't say there was anything that that
was that uh memorable
no understandable understandable so
i guess my question is did you have a
eureka or like a light bulb moment with
cannabis where it all kind of clicked
for you and you realize this was
something you wanted to dedicate
yourself to so to speak oh yeah i know
when i started growing it was uh it was
like it was very like a eye opening in a
sense where
it just gave me a whole another respect
for the actual
plant and you know it's it's like
medical properties and how it can help
people out and and you know like when i
went to amsterdam it was uh in 2006 i
went with like eddie left and
and uh we went there and i met like
ariane from greenhouse seeds and
and like that's kind of when i was able
to actually because we didn't like the
clubs here were very like minimalist i
want to say it was medical at the time
and um
and it just there wasn't that as much of
a variety like everything was coming
from amsterdam actually and there was a
transitionary period where actually a
lot of the stuff started coming from
here like from northern california and
we started becoming a staple as far as
like uh being known
as the
the uh
like basically like the the
the
sorry my dog is tripping um like uh like
they basically like like like the that's
a staple for like a lot of the good
strains here and also like the like the
the granddaddy when it came out the or
the urkel actually um that was one of
the bigger like you know game changers
and whatnot then after that i would say
it was like the og and then
and then uh and then cookies you know so
yeah of course it definitely fits with
the general consensus that there was
that paradigm shift and kind of
a changing of the world's superpowers in
regards to weed from yeah the europeans
to americans so
i guess was there anything notable about
that trip would you would you make
avarian when you met
him mean it's pretty much well
i mean he was he was nice he was cool
like but uh but i it gave me a big um
like a big understanding as far as as uh
as far as like the game and how
everything works like as far as seed
companies because it at like back then
it was like if you were going to grow
you couldn't go on craigslist and get
clones i mean like i at s at some point
um like darkheart nursery they started
like off on like on craigslist but
back then you know you'd want to grow
like the fire and
what you would consider the fire would
be the cannabis cup winners and so you'd
open up like a like a high times
and um and there would be low old
greenhouse
seeds and they you know they they would
tout how many like cannabis cups they
won
and whatever and
like when i actually went to amsterdam i
realized like like a lot of the dutch
genetics were
inferior to what we have here in uh and
actually like in california or in you
know yeah in california basically
because i was there and i was like i'm
paying the euro was definitely um
you know the dollar was was definitely
weaker than the euro and so to pay you
know like whatever 18 20 euros for a
gram
and like to realize that it was actually
not like it wasn't that good of weed it
was very eye-opening to me you know
yeah and that's a really pertinent issue
we should talk about like people buying
cups or rigging cups or however it is
you know
do you think that was something which
was kind of limited to the european
scene or do you think that that's
happened and like what might be some
examples of it elsewhere
well i mean i like i i couldn't tell you
to what extent it still exists but i i
mean i definitely know that
um
like i like
back in the days it definitely came off
as uh like you know ariane um
he you know he
he he would basically i mean they have
so many cannabis cups and like like i
said the other day when people are
looking for you know they want to start
growing they're they they're gonna
they're gonna trust like high times as
judgment and they're gonna you know
think that whatever one that the latest
cannabis cup is gonna be you know the
like the hot stuff and so um i mean even
like like eddie left told me he's like
every time that he wins like a cup it
equates to literally like over a million
dollars in seed sales and back then that
was you know like
you know quite a bit amount of money and
um and so you know just a matter of
buying advertising space and high times
there's no definitive evidence about all
this but it's kind of like you can
i mean you can put two and two together
and you know realize that that's kind of
what was going on so
um you know like uh
i mean i was there myself when i was
kind of like oh damn like i want to when
i started growing i wanted to grow
the like we didn't have access to clones
so i wanted to grow
you know like the best weed ever and i
assumed that it was pretty much whatever
had won the cannabis cup that year and
um and like that when i went to
amsterdam it was kind of eye opening as
far as like uh that wasn't true
of course of course
so yeah
tell us do you remember about your first
grow what were you growing what was it
like
uh the the i want to say the strains
that like what i was growing the
the first ones that i did i was actually
i was growing up my mom's in the closet
of my mom's house and um and it was uh
og kush i actually had gotten like some
legit og like sfvog and uh back then
like those pounds were going for like
over six thousand dollars it's crazy
like and i happened to meet one of my
homies homies and he had these clones
and uh i mean it was legit og cushion so
that's the first first train i grew and
that was like you know one of the game
changers as far as uh where people were
like like i guess transitioning more
from like the fruity stuff to more the
gassy stuff and um and you know like uh
like like yeah i grew that in my mom's
closet
and uh
and it i mean it was it was definitely
uh it was it was it was pretty you know
it was nice to have your my own smoke
and whatnot it was definitely better
than most [ __ ] that i was getting on the
streets
wow and did you realize kind of what a
baseline you had because i often talk to
growers and you realize very quickly
that everything's so relative it's like
what what's your best could be [ __ ] for
me did you realize at the time you just
had the kill
i mean i i mean no i actually i did not
like i was i like thinking about it this
like uh to this day like it's actually
i'm very um surprised that
you know like my homie he was kind of
known he was more like a connoisseur or
whatnot but back then they were like
connoisseurs were definitely like the
minority within the you know the uh the
industry and whatnot and uh like for to
even be giving those clones it's uh like
i'm very i'm still surprised at this day
that i actually got those cuts it's kind
of like you know i like to get like
legit og clones back then was uh you
normally you would get some [ __ ] like
you know
somebody would just throw the og name on
it just to sell it to you know so i was
very uh you know i was very grateful for
that but i yeah i was it was legit it
was like i said vog and then we got the
larry after that
and um and you know like you know even
to this day like it's
they're hard to come by so
yeah larry is like a personal favorite
of mine but it's also one i find hard to
talk about because there's like that
lemon larry and it's like most people
don't know which one they're getting and
whatnot have you tried both and which
one do you prefer
i mean the original one was um
it was very like lime greenish and and
uh like i i i would say like
yeah lemony but at this point like
nowadays it's
i mean it's it's really hard to find
those same exact genetics like i mean
it's uh like i have not come across them
um ever like since
you know so it's kind of like even like
uh like the urkel like like most i mean
that it's a pretty hard
hard strain to come across nowadays you
mean like uh especially once it got
watered down with the granddaddy and you
know people were trying to get more of
like a yield out of it
so um but yeah i mean i like yeah i you
know like i i the og was there was a
reason why it was it was a game changer
and at the time like everything seemed
to be like fruity and kind of blandish
and og was just like like uh like gassy
so people you know people definitely
took you know took to that
for sure
so
what was it like when you were then you
know starting to progress in kind of
your skills you'd had a few harvests
you're getting more clones how did you
kind of develop
i mean i like like i i pretty much i
kept my closet at my mom's house rocking
for
for a little while uh like probably like
at least like a year year and a half um
i mean at that point too i like
the reality is like you didn't have to
really grow that good of weed um so you
know there was like a more of like there
was a higher margin for like for error
um you know if i mean i had [ __ ] that
when i was starting to do seeds that had
literally gotten seeded up and i i was
still getting rid of the pounds for like
four thousand dollars just because there
was so much shitty weed on on the market
um you know so back then it was you know
like i definitely made a little bit you
know a nice little chunk of change off
off of that two there was like two six
hundreds in the closet
and um and and yeah like it's like it it
was uh
it was nice because everything else like
i said was coming from more than likely
canada and and it's it it was not it
wasn't comparable to like what i was
even growing when i was just starting
off so it was fr and from then like i
got
other spots and you know like save my
money up and whatever and
pretty much
you know moved on like growing
more and more uh like basically like you
know get getting more lights going and
all that you know all that [ __ ] getting
a warehouse
here in the city and then um you know
like i kind of regressed a little bit
just because like the whole tech boom
that came in into play
um like the prices for for the rent on
like the like the warehouses went like
through the roof and whatnot so we went
back to residential stuff and you know
like that's
um you know like that's pretty much
where we're at now in a sense you know
like that's uh like okay i mean getting
into the market here in california is
pretty pretty expensive you know so
that's kind of why i choose to
do like more of my consulting and like
like uh dabble in like other states
because it's just it's it's cheaper and
easier to get into yeah it's cutthroat
in california i want to jump back though
just for a second to
how you talked about getting an
industrial space i feel like this is a
topic we don't really delve into a lot
on the show so
i'm just wondering when you first did
get your bigger space no matter what
like the context was
were you quite anxious about it or you
just overwhelmingly excited and what
were kind of the factors that played
into mine when you were selecting say
strains for it were you just thinking
well i've got to get a good return so
that's kind of the priority here or was
it like you were able to kind of just
grow whatever you wanted that wasn't a
consideration
yeah i mean i mean back then it's i mean
it's crazy because the market's
completely completely changed um i mean
back then i wouldn't i mean i was just
buying like uh you know strains from
from like seeds from from
you know dutch genetics and whatnot on
like breed bay and and uh like scene
band what not and i just i just
literally remember being up at like two
three in the morning to like get in on
these auctions um you know for like
certain like strains i like like
reservoirs stuff and um
you know back then like honestly like it
um
it's it like the the market the way it
was it allowed me actually to have a lot
of my mistakes as far as like like like
messing [ __ ] up like i said as far as
like missing males in in the room and
then like when you're like you know uh
when you're sorting through seeds and
whatnot
and um and like having us like a seated
crop and still like being able to sell
it like nowadays you wouldn't be able to
to do that so it was uh but back then it
was that there was no
there was no um i mean og kush was
definitely like the probably like the
the you know the top strain at the
moment i just was never into like mono
cropping and that kind of i mean that's
that's actually like my own
like no i don't say issue but in a sense
i just always was looking for something
else and so i ran some of that i ran
some of you know whatever whatever else
is available but um you know like back
then you could pretty much grow
whatever and most of the time if you
were growing like decently you would be
doing better than whatever's coming was
coming through like on the streets yeah
for sure
so
correct me if i'm wrong but it sounds
like probably the next big thing that
really caught your eye after you're
running the og was probably the first
cookies right
i i mean yeah like um i mean og kind of
like i mean it's it's still pretty
pivotal as far as like like uh you know
like within the market there's a huge
market still for it people love like you
know the gassiness of it um but yeah
cookies you know there's a reason why
cookies was a was a game changer as far
as you know what like why it is so
prominent at like as it is today um and
like yeah i mean it's
like i said it's just a matter of like
with your market and what you have and
you know um
but like coming to see how like like
like you know like the first time i ever
saw cookies and came across it it was
like there i mean people were passing
off bubbas as cookies so i was like a
lot of people were showing me stuff and
i was like this just smells like bubba
you know and um and when i finally
actually got a hold of the real deal
cookies i was like oh this is what
everyone's talking about but like i said
people were you know trying to pass off
[ __ ] left and right as far as you know
being cookies like like especially
bubbas um and like you know it wasn't
you know to me i was like it just smells
like bubba so
when i finally got
a hold of like the actual you know real
deal cookies it was i was like this is i
understand why you know why it's a game
changer at that point you know yeah so
what was the first sample you got to try
was it like forum was it like thin min
do you have any idea
actually i i couldn't tell you what it
was i know that um like the like the the
first packs were coming through
from from
like burner to like oh like basically og
kush bread which is my homie um
and like that was like even like like
frost boss uh like he like i remember
like you know i was selling them packs
like they they like they had [ __ ] up a
bunch of those batches like there was a
bunch of seated packs that came through
and we were still [ __ ] selling them
like like nothing and this is
in i want to say like uh like probably
like 2010-ish 2009 which actually was
like the
the crash of the weed market in a sense
where everyone kind of went balls of the
wall and grew a bunch of weed
and um the prices like plummeted like
went through the floor
and so like you know like back then to
be able to get rid of like seated
products and you know like people were
like lining up to buy cookies but it was
also more of the fact that that uh it
was only coming out of like the cookie
fam little like they're the circle and
so there there's only so much to go
around and um i mean luckily i i knew
like like oh gee kush breath was kind of
tied in with all them so he was like
showing me you know those packs and i
remember going to his house and i was
like yeah like actually this is like
pretty fire you know and then when he
told me the tickets i was like like i
don't know if i can get rid of this sort
of you know this stuff for this kind of
a ticket but you know there's a certain
market that definitely wanted it and uh
like said like frost boss and my other
abf and um like unknown profit they kind
of had that uh that market where people
were actually like willing to pay for it
it was you know pretty crazy so
yeah wow
so though when you said those first
couple ones came through with seeds
you mean that the first batches coming
out of cookie fam when they were grown
it was seeded with like s1's or whatever
yeah i mean well no that i mean there
was a like a bunch of batches that came
through that were fine but then there
were some that
that definitely were seated and so uh
you know it was just kind of like
like beggars can't be choosers if you
want cookies then you're you know you're
gonna have to [ __ ] buy it so
uh and i like i'd probably like
attribute that to actually all the
different phenotypes that we see um
today just because like there were so
many seeds and if you were smart at the
time you would have uh you would have
planted the seeds because uh because you
know the strain was in high demand so
yeah okay
and do you remember how long it was
between then and when you first tried
ogkb
uh i mean the the og kb just kind of
like like uh pretty much fell into my
lap as far as like um
they're like we were already testing the
the animal in the forum because we
already had access to those
and then uh like i said like the og we
kind of just fell into my lap as a
result of
like uh like unfortunate incident in a
sense where i you know i pretty much
i grabbed the clones and like those uh
like like out of og kush red spot and
and um you know like i we we only knew
the animal in the forum and at that
point um you know when i got the actual
i mean oh the og kb clone was not even
it wasn't even named that it was just
more of
i named it after og kush bread because
that's my homie who gave it to me and
that's pretty much it but i you know
like it's uh like it it's like a mutant
cookies that actually is like [ __ ]
like you know like really good obviously
yeah of course so a lot of people are
really curious as to how you actually
got your hands on the og kb would you be
able to tell us the backstory behind
that one
yeah yeah so i'm so basically um i mean
like og kb was like like i've known him
for for a long a long time at this point
it's you know close to like almost 20
years and um he's
like
he actually like brought me in the game
and whatnot and um and he's all he's
always taking care of me but at that
time we only knew of the animal in the
forum and there was a instance that
basically like one of his um his spots
had gotten robbed like like they it was
like a home invasion and so he was in i
think he was in vegas and he called me
it was like like three like three or
four like four in the morning and um
he just he was like yo he's like can you
go clear this spot out for me because
uh like you know pretty much they was it
got robbed
and so i was alright cool so i i hopped
in in my girlfriend's car and like i was
saying like at the time i didn't have
like a license i grabbed my pistol and
just you know pretty much took off and i
had to make a bunch of trips back and
forth it was pretty pretty [ __ ]
pretty wild really like to think about
it and um
and you know whatever it is what it is i
got i cleared the place out there was a
bunch of plants that were literally in
like
five gallon pots that i had to put in
contractor bags and and like luckily
there was people there um but like they
you know
well once they were like some of them
were all tied up and whatever so i once
i you know got them you know loose and
whatnot they were able to help me out
but i was like driving back and forth
uh with with these huge plants that were
literally like five six weeks in a
flower and um in like five gallon pots
and in my car
or and um
you know like basically what was there
was the og cabbie is what we know is the
og kv now and so it was uh it was it was
pretty wild like so i got you know i got
it taking care of it one night but like
like you know back then it's
it was at different times as far as uh
the legality of as as far as what we're
doing and stuff
so um you know like it's that was you
know the cops could have came in at any
given moment i had no i had no idea what
the hell was going on but i just want to
get everything out of there and whatever
and then when i brought that like all
the stuff back to my house
um i asked them what like you know this
mutant ass plant like what like what it
was and he said it was cookies and i was
i was like that's weird because we've
already like been documenting the
cookies um
as you know as far as like what we know
and he's like nah so it was like a whole
other phenotype of the cookies and once
i finished everything up
it was definitely like a you know a very
a very good cookies cut
and um
it wasn't that desirable to actually
like grow because of the fact that like
a veg so damn slow
but like that's pretty much what came to
be known as the og kb and i mean it
wasn't even named that at the time it
was pretty much
i named it after my homie like pretty
much after him and that was pretty much
it just to like differentiate the clones
that we had already
wow what an amazing story i'm giving you
a virtual clap for being a solid homie
on that one so i guess the first
question is
how does og kb himself
feel
about how the strains gone on to become
so popular because he really doesn't
seem to be involved in the scene too
much you don't really get to hear his
perspective much
yeah i mean i mean at the end of the day
uh i mean that's the reason why uh why
it was named after him at the new day
like the the
the recognition will kind of always go
back to him so
whatever but it's it is kind of crazy
how everything has kind of like
you know uh snowballed into like what it
actually is and how it's actually very
very you know it's it's a basis of a lot
of like fit you know one of the some of
the most famous strains i guess
to date now you know
um it's uh yeah it's a very unique plant
and whatnot but i mean he's not really
concerned with a lot of that stuff to be
honest you like i don't think he is he
it's just more of it's just
crazy how it all kind of likes like i
said like you know just everything kind
of came into this whole situation and i
mean it's a good plant it's it's it
produces [ __ ] you know fire
uh the offspring is definitely like a
lot of it's very promising
um and you know like yeah there's
there's a
it's you know
i like it's doesn't you it's hard it was
a finicky plant to get basically dialed
in and whatnot but like you know
whatever like i said like at the end of
the day
to see where it's at now as far as like
if you saw like the healthy plants that
i have
of the og kb and that that i even have
it's still alive it's pretty
pretty crazy considering the the uh the
shape that it came to be in
yeah of course it's a great little
turnaround story i definitely want to
chat about the offspring of the og kb
but just as a quick little side track
do you
know much about or have you tried the og
kb 2.0 the one that came from the bag
seed
uh i i have not is that like uh dark
horse or
i'm not sure who it is but like someone
bought some og kb from a dispensary and
they found like some s-ones and they
popped it and it was like really good
and they called it og kb 2.0 and now
there's even a few breeders who agreed
with it like most notably in-house has
done across and he calls it og kb 2.1
yeah i mean at that point i i don't know
like man i'm honestly like people hit me
up all day and they want to uh
like they want me to vouch for their for
whatever their their clone or whatever
it is um
i i just like like like i said at the
end of the day i just tell people like
yo if you're happy with what you got
like you know and it's fire then you
know like um you know that's that's
great just be happy with that like i
can't i can't
you know specifically vouch for her
for for your clones like i have no idea
like you know what
what what the wheat is people are very
quick to attach a name to something that
pretty much sell it so the end of the
day like uh like you know it's it's kind
of hard to tell but if it like i said at
the end of the day if it's good then you
know this is what it is like you know
like you got to give props to that but i
i have not tried any of those um you
know like the the og kb 2.0 and whatnot
i don't i mean for me it's just more of
like i have the original like like why
the hell would i
what
you know like experiment with like
trying something else and and whatnot
yeah understandable
so when you started growing it out did
you notice any similarities with the
ogkb and any other plants and the reason
why i asked this is because
we've heard um
csi in the past say that some of the
urkel s1s
come out with that exact same morphology
that mutant kind of look that the og-kbb
has have you ever grown the og kb and
just kind of thought oh man i see a bit
of this plant in it
i mean uh i mean yeah the urkel is very
uh i mean it's a short stocky plant that
was and which is pretty similar to the
og kv and i mean he definitely could
have be on on to something um
besides that the only other one that i
actually noticed like the leaf structure
was that at the time back then was uh
was the cherry pie that was going around
and it was actually like a the cherry
pie tended to have
uh tendencies and uh and
and uh back then it actually was it was
pretty similar in in structure and
whatnot and um it had to kind of like
that
the leaf structure and it was kind of
short and squat and it also tended to
make uh like like um like like you know
pollen sacks but they were they were
non-viable so um like but that's the
thing is like it was kind of like uh the
cherry pie came first and then cookies
started coming around after that
and uh and you know like like it was i
mean even i i wish i still had that
cherry pie i was definitely that cherry
pie was was you know was was nice it was
just not very uh very stable
yeah of course
so
you got the og kbb
when did you first start to do some
collaborations with it
uh i mean like back then i i i
met fletcher from archive c bank through
uh through the forums and um and it was
just kind of like a thing where i was
like yo like you know uh he was working
with the face off oh g mail at the time
um on and uh and so that was kind of
like like the basis of a lot of his uh
his seeds
and um his his seed company was kind of
more like the infancy stages as far as
like it was kind of like just taking off
but not quite and so i was like yo man
like if you want to you know hit like
people were asking me left and right for
the og kb because we had uh the form and
the animal already but like the og kb
once it became known as like uh like a
like a very like legit cookie strain
people you know people people were you
know they everyone was interested in it
so
i hit him up and was like you know if
you want to pollinate it you know just
you know we'll split the seeds and
pretty much that's about it and that's
what became the dositos basically and um
and you know like
and from there it just uh
it's kind of progressed into like
everything else that it is nowadays too
so
yeah okay so the seeds were made did you
pop them immediately were you really
excited for it or you kind of didn't
really suspect it would go on to become
what it's become
yeah i mean well like a lot of the seeds
were like um like they like the og kb
tends to produce very like white pale
seeds that are typically non like
non-viable like they don't it's really
hard to get them to germinate so i mean
i had like a jar full of seeds and uh
and you know i kind of actually held on
to like some of them and i i gave them
to i think was np cali actually my my
friend uh my friend ryan and decali and
he got actually the last of the of the
dositos original dosito seeds um and
they they were it was really hard to
germinate them and whatnot uh like but
you know that's that's pretty much where
the dositos came from i you know i got
the jar i started like doing the
selections and then pretty much like
that like fletcher named it the dositos
and like you know that's that's pretty
much like where it's at now you know the
mendo bread is another story as far as
uh that was done with gage green and um
and you know like it's it it was
like like you know out of like a tray of
seeds i'd probably get like
like less than a quarter like 25 of them
to like actually germinate they're you
know they're they're they're definitely
uh they require a little bit of work
how did the mendo breath collab come
about
oh that was um like
like i had i had a friend that was like
that that was trimming for me it was
like a friend of a friend and he
actually mentioned to me that uh he had
some neighbors that i guess had the seed
company and like like back then same
thing gageman was kind of in their
infancy stages and in a sense that they
weren't um you know they weren't that
big but they were definitely doing like
breeding work and so i was like yeah you
know whatever like i was i'm always like
you know about like you know if
if you know i'm always about working
with people and whatnot and so i was
like oh that's cool you know this and
that and then he had talked to them and
then they were like oh yeah i know i
know who you're talking about like as
far as like you know me having the og
kush breath and whatever and being on
the forums and um
and so like i like we you know we made
an agreement and i gave him the clone
and then they pollinated it and there
was
uh the mendo breath and the grateful
breath and then you know there was
you know that was those were probably
the two most prominent strains that they
actually like produced and whatnot so
um like you know but it like they uh
they you know it
they
like you know like
what like a lot of the stuff that comes
from the og kb it tends to be pretty you
know pretty pretty uh impressive
without question so how do you feel that
the majority of their work now is just
really stemming off the ogb and then
even further you know gromer's now made
his whole thing off their whole thing
like you've almost given birth to a
brand that's given birth to a brand if
you get what i mean
yeah i know it's like the the basis of
uh the infrastructure for
other people's [ __ ] companies um
i don't know i mean it's in a sense it's
kind of flattering but i'm not ever
really
one to be uh like a hater in a sense you
mean like like at the end of the day i
like i like the the way that this this
industry is like i'm i'm not gonna try
to go and like
shake people down for you know whatever
it's like i'm just happy for people that
they're being successful with it and at
the end of the day if you really know
what's up you'll know that like the work
came from me you know i mean so there's
always you know um you know there
there's always that sort of recognition
in a sense but at the end of the day
like you know someone's you know doing
well like i'm i'm happy for them you
know like as long as they're not a you
know a punk [ __ ] like [ __ ] to me
i don't anchor you know like like even
like with gromer
um i literally hit him up and i was like
yo like i wanted to run i think some
like the peanut butter red so i asked
him for like a pack of the seeds and he
sent me like
25 packs of seeds of like all the [ __ ]
you know like i respect that you name um
and i'm sure he's made plenty of more
money than whatever those are worth but
at the end of the day like it's you know
it's uh i respect the fact that that uh
you know he kind of paid it forward you
know
so
yeah of course that's always good karma
stuff so a lot of people would know you
because through name because the fact
that the predominantly widespread cut of
both the docido and the mendo breath are
the ones you found when you were doing
those pheno hunts did you realize that
these were going to be really good like
i remember we just spoke about when they
were in seats but when you're actually
flowering them out and you could smell
them and get excited were you really
excited or you just thought oh this is a
nice cut i'll give it to some friends
no i mean i could tell they were they
were game changers um
it's like as far as like like how you
know how it's you know they've taken off
or whatever um
i mean there i mean nowadays there's
there's definitely a lot of like like
really good strains out but at the time
they were definitely like you know game
changers you know there was definitely
very special as far as whatever i
already had on deck and um it kind of
blew everything else out of the water
which is why i was like if you look at
my instagram or whatever you realize
like i i wasn't i didn't never intended
to hype them up i'm not like uh like
like i call like a like like a used car
salesman where it's it's kind of like
i'm not gonna put my name on something
that's not gonna be that good um and you
know
pretty much now like you know one like
to nowadays
if there's a reason why people utilize
those strains for you know for for the
the basis of their breeding products too
you know
of course
so at this time i think it was kind of
about the same time like look cookies
was just going through the roof you know
like you had like rappers starting to
name drop it and the really the cultural
side of weed started to really generate
a lot of interest in cookies as well did
you ever think to yourself
i could try to like you know jump on
docido or mendo breath and try to launch
it or did you just feel like that was
just kind of not in your lane
i mean it's
it was i i think like a lot of the the
hype that came along with it was very
organically uh
fabricated um you know i mean like a lot
of people like would hear about it and
uh they like
it's one thing to hear about something
that's another thing to like you know
actually
have it and you know uh like smell it
and you know just like you know smoke it
whatever
um you know like i but at the time it
was you know it wasn't
it wasn't about like capitalizing on
that all that hype really like i'm
actually very surprised as far as like
how far uh even like you know like
cookies itself has like come along you
know so it's uh but but it was at the
time it was definitely like i can't deny
that it was not i mean that it was a
game changer you know like it was just
definitely
um like like like i said back then
people were passing around bubba as
cookies and i'd be like this ain't that
fire you know whatever and then when i
actually got a hold of the actual like
real cookies i was like oh this is what
people are talking about this is
actually yeah like game changer [ __ ] you
know
yeah okay
so if we try to put personal attachments
and whatnot to the side if you consider
the fact that you conceded you know it's
not not a great breeding plant the ogb
and it's a bit slower overall do you
still think that it's worthy of the
title of like it's a good plant or do
you think that it's just like worth the
hassle but overall it's probably not
really a great plant so to speak
no i mean when it when i mean the
flowers are are i mean that like
whenever i have any of it
i mean there's plenty of people that
like if they want to run it into ice you
know like ice wax or uh like you know as
far as like making it into hash or even
you know just
it's i mean it's sold always it's just
not necessarily the most lucrative plan
to to run when you're when you're when
you're running
you know when you're growing um
but uh but i mean i always love having
it around it's it's definitely
very much
a really good a good plant but i feel
like the offspring
in itself too is actually
it you know that it holds a lot of
weight as far as uh again against it as
well you know so i kind of prefer to
work with the offspring as far as like
you know just like the dositos or even
the ogb blueberry headband that like you
know that i just did all those plants
are going to be like definitively a lot
more like have more vigor and just be
more like easier to work with you know
so
yeah fantastic um so i guess before we
jump into the
ogb blueberry headband stuff a little
more i do have one last question do you
have any other plants which kind of fit
that category where you know it is a
little bit finicky and most people don't
put in the effort but you still keep it
around because it's the killer
i mean
i not really like honestly like that's
the one plant that
i will always make space for in my veg
in my bedroom um i know that there's
like a i hear like the mac one is like
very similar and like it's a like uh
characteristics as far as like
vegetative growth i've not i don't have
that plan i've never grown it so i i
couldn't say anything you know about
that um
but as far as just the og kb just it's
uh
like
i mean it's clearly it's it's it's a
it's a plant worth keeping around
considering it's notoriety at this point
so
wow you've never grown the mac one i
guess you're one of the few people to
resist the overwhelming hype
i mean i i mean i i i know cap like if
i'm sure if i wanted to go grab a cut i
could go down you know see him and and
you know grab it i i run
uh like like some of his seeds and
all that stuff it's just more of i'm not
really one like the type of person to go
out and like uh like seek certain things
um
i mean i've seen flowers of the mack one
but yeah it's just i don't know man i'm
like i kind of just work with what i
work with because i'm already sifting
through so much stuff as it is
uh and it's um it's kind of like
uh it's i mean it's a good thing and a
bad thing but because like there's a lot
of a lot of [ __ ] that you have to
sit through but uh you know like i like
i have
so many seeds and things that i like
crosses that i've already made that i'm
kind of like i kind of try to focus on
that
yeah for sure
but i gotta ask
did you end up getting into like gg4 or
skittles or any of the other commonly
hyped ones of recent
um i mean i literally just got a
skittles clone um
probably like like a month ago but like
like like i said for me um
i'm you know like gorilla glue 4 was
like i i want to say it was that that's
josie's
uh like clone and whatnot and i've ran
it but before i i like it it just um it
wasn't it didn't it tended to get over
like overproduced to the sense where
like it actually like the market got
kind of saturated with like a lot of
gorilla glue as a result of that because
it was a huge yielder and it was it
wasn't that tough to grow
so um but skittles i mean i like it
wrong but like i said i kind of tend to
focus on a lot of stuff like that i'm
already doing myself as far as like you
know my own work
of course so let's jump back into the og
kb x2 which is the blueberry headband
cross
what do you hope to pair with that like
do you plan to find a male from that and
then pair that with stuff or use that as
the mothers
i mean with that one i mean at like
it basically was a cross that i made uh
an outdoor cross and so like i i still
have some seeds left of it i can which i
can sort through like i said a lot of
those seeds from the original og kb are
typically not like non-viable i think i
like i said i
i i planted like 72 in a tray and i
probably got like
like you know 14 or something like out
of that um and so
like you know for me i still have
i probably still got another like 20 or
30 seeds left that i can sort through
and whatnot but that og kb blu-ray
headband was definitely um like you know
as far as like what i wanted out of the
og kb it was it definitely like brought
more vigor into it and i also like it
has more like the blueberry nose on it
so it's um and like and like i said
right now like compounds going to be
working with it so i'm like i'm really
more excited about that whole situation
um you know and like see where that that
like that all goes that's cool and so
you plan to
get a few females together and then
he'll provide the mail or do you know
how you plan to do the co-lab exactly
i mean i i pretty much i made this
election and then i gave him the uh like
he saw the flowers and was like oh damn
like i like he liked it a lot so he was
like you know whatever like we should do
like you know i guess collaboration and
so
um you know that's pretty much like
where we're at now so he's i was like
yeah if you want to take it and like
work with it go like you know go ahead
dude you can do whatever you want with
it and so that's uh like i said i don't
know exactly we haven't really discussed
exactly what he's gonna do with it as
far as like what males he's gonna use to
uh to pollinate it but i mean i'm just
excited that like you know that that
work is getting you know like it's
progressing and and whatnot because i
don't um i don't i can't always be
pollinating things um you know
considering like
you know my like you know like my the
spaces that i have and whatnot
so
do you think that you'll ever open your
own seed company or do you prefer to do
this sort of collab type of creation
no i mean honestly like it's i mean like
like you said i i really would i like
i'd rather work with people and you know
like i i like the idea of it um you know
like i think like collaborative minds um
when they come together they like a lot
of like good stuff can come from that so
i mean i'm not trying to be a jack of
all trades uh and you know like i just
like i like i appreciate the fact that
certain people are even willing to work
with me and things like that but i'm
like you know as far as like
establishing a seed company i mean i'd
rather
i'd rather work with somebody that i
already know and you know let them do
their thing and then we can figure it
out from there you know but i'm not i'm
not uh i just i don't really have the
time for that at the moment and i don't
really see myself having the time for
that
yeah okay so i mean with that being said
what do you perceive as your future
within the cannabis industry where do
you see it going and what do you think
your role will be
i mean for me like i like i i'm pretty
tied up with like a lot of my consulting
work as far as um you know designing
like certain facilities and and uh
things like that we you know right now
we just submitted our application to uh
in illinois
and so once that goes through and if
everything is you know good with that
then i'll definitely be busy with that
but i mean i just i i just like growing
leaning like it's um it's like i've
always liked
that you know
like the plants and you know as far as
like working with them and
just just uh being around them really
it's very like it's therapeutic in a
sense you know and then also the fact
that like certain you know like i i
would like to do more research as far as
going into strains that are like more
medically uh like you know they have
more like like medicinal benefits and
you know things like that as as far as
like word you know where they tend to
help people out with like certain
ailments they have and you know uh like
things like that like that's kind of
what kind of drives me in a sense
that's really cool in terms of the
medicinal stuff you just mentioned do
you think that that will take you into
the kind of cbd realm or are you talking
more of like
just a regular thc dominant strain but
it just also happens to help with x or y
uh i mean
like
uh there's i mean the the i feel like
the sky is kind of the limit it sounds
kind of like weird but like there's so
much stuff we don't know about the like
the cannabis plant at this point um like
certain compounds that we're just like
discovering and seeing how they uh like
like you know medicinally like how they
affect people and stuff like that so
it's it's like like i said uh at the end
of the day i'm just happy to to provide
like a
a
a service for people if like if they
feel like the you know these you know
these certain strains um you know
medicinally benefit them
and are there any conditions that are
maybe like
close to heart which you'd like to be
able to work on or anything which
catches your eye you just it's just a
general topic of interest
i mean
like i feel like like uh like cannabis
is so subjective that
it's you know when you when you smoke
like someone could smoke a sativa and
tell you it's a sativa
um
and then someone else could be like oh
that you know that same strain like kind
of put me to sleep or like they feel
like it's more indica dominant it's i
just feel like it's very subjective but
at the end of the day if you know that
like like like i said if any of my work
or whatever can help anybody out as far
as um you know like like you know
therapeutically or like medically i mean
that's just very uh
it's it's very um
you know like it's
it's it you know it makes you know makes
you feel good in a sense you know
yeah definitely definitely
so you mentioned that you submitted an
application illinois soon
i mean given we're dealing with kind of
this current corona uncertainty thing
going on how do you perceive that's
going to affect your work in general do
you think everything will come to a
grinding hold or do you think the
cannabis industry will kind of keep
doing its thing
i mean i mean i it's it's really hard to
say like i know that the
the application deadline was extended by
two weeks in illinois because of the
whole corona virus thing um so
that's one thing um and then um
it's uh
i mean yeah well they may extend it even
further and also like as far as on the
application process they were requiring
people to submit the application itself
in person to like the office i guess it
was
in springfield um and uh and now they
they don't even want you to do that so
like um i like i couldn't tell you to
the extent that it actually is gonna
affect everything but it actually it has
affected you know somewhat already like
they don't they don't want to take any
applications from anybody in person
anymore you have to mail them in and
things like that as far as like moving
you know down the road
um i mean
who knows man with this uh with this
whole situation i i wouldn't
i wouldn't have uh
a forecast that i would even get to this
point as far as like where we're at now
or literally like we can't you know
can't leave our houses you know
yeah
well we've heard a general sentiment
from a lot of notable instagram figures
saying
you know now is a great time to just
spend some time with your plants do you
feel like that's a good idea
yeah i mean i got nothing better to do
really you know
so it's like uh like like literally like
hang out with my dog and and you know
yeah just basically like yeah like just
put some more work in the garden there's
nothing else to do um
you know typically there's
other stuff to uh
to uh like i guess attend to or whatnot
but at this point
we're not supposed to leave our house so
yeah definitely so
just to kind of jump back for a little
bit
was there any certain point when you
were on the forums where you felt like
you started to have like some kind of
notoriety so to speak or do you feel
like that all came after that
i mean i i i mean i
i still wouldn't tell you that i have
any notoriety man i'm just blessed to
like be able to work with the people
that that i that i have and that um you
know like that we have mutual respect
and
some things don't always necessarily
work out with the
you know there's like you know with with
the people that you you deal with but
you live and you learn but um you know
like like i couldn't i couldn't say so i
just know that we were doing a bunch of
like documenting as far as the uh you
know as far as the cuts that we had and
you know just everything just kind of
like i say like snowballed into
where it's at now you mean like i like
uh but i wouldn't
i don't i mean i wouldn't
i wouldn't like to uh
to you know to to uh to you know
to basically accept the fact that like
you're you know like that there's
notoriety that comes along with like the
territory that you know i'm in i guess
yeah ever humble that's always nice so
what was your favorite forums or did you
have like a favorite for a moment in
general
i mean like i see mag was good at one
point i think it's very convoluted like
watered down at this point um just
because you have so many like new newbie
growers uh but it was like it was you
know icy mag uh overgrow
um thc farmer uh like you know it was it
it was just a huge
uh
like
like uh
like a the you know huge like a library
to basically learn like about growing at
the time and so we were you know like i
said like like me and like ivan from the
jungle boys like lump status frost boss
like uh unknown prophet
um like like abf now
like you know that uh you know to have
met those people and and be able to have
shared the knowledge that we had like
it's kind of you can't really
you like that's not gonna like i i don't
foresee that coming about like again
like back then we were like just super
underground you know just basically
starting out and you know just sharing a
bunch of information and um and you know
like like i said i i kind of stuck to i
see mag and that was about it but it was
never about like gaining any notoriety
or anything like that like really when i
jumped onto like uh instagram was when i
noticed that like a instagram was a huge
marketing tool um and you know it was i
was very surprised at how like
everything from there to kind of took
off
um you know and so it was like when i
when i said i'm like my instagram handle
people were like recognizing me for the
forums and i was like how like how do
you know about about that
and uh and you know people had basically
had been following my work and so
they were you know they were like kind
of like like are you that person from
you know whatever i see mag and uh and
yes it was that's kind of what surprised
me a little bit and whatnot
yeah okay well i mean you mentioned the
marketing of instagram
do you look at cookie fam now and feel
like they've done a pretty good job
marketing and if you were to say that
who do you put the uh like the kudos to
who out of the cookie fans the marketer
i mean i don't think cookie fam did
anything really they like realistically
like burner is the one that actually uh
hyped the strain like um
at the end of the day like the strain
actually kind of held its own weight
because it was like i said cookies was
definitely a game changer but
um like i don't i don't you know i don't
i don't see how they did anything to
like uh fuel that whole situation uh
burner definitely
definitely did um but at the end of the
day like it's i mean it's kind of ironic
like a lot of people
uh assume like burner's like a like a
weed grower i'm like he i mean he might
have grown weed back in the day or
whatever but he's more of a hustler in a
sense which i mean i totally respect but
uh but like you know like he
he uh he was the one that fueled the
whole cookies hype it's it's uh
it's you know that's that's i i would
say that's really who's responsible for
it if not like uh scherbinski like but
he's he kind of branched off and did his
own thing
um but he also had like the the
you know the um
the the momentum from like the whole
cookies thing as well
you read my mind that was going to be
the next question it was about shibinsky
and how he branched off so what i want
to know is he's been name-dropped a lot
in a lot of pop culture like even in a
calvin harris song which is pretty good
for him um do you feel like he's done a
better job and furthermore what do you
think will happen to the cookies brand
if they continue to be passive as you
said
uh i mean there's only so much that that
they that that i mean they can actually
do i think uh scherbinski's definitely a
lot more of a
like a marketing type of person and like
you know um that's [ __ ] great for him
i like said i'll never hate on anybody
you know i mean but um even like when he
branched off from the actual
cookie fam and all that other [ __ ] like
like initially i was like i like you
know i didn't i couldn't foresee how it
was actually going to work out for him
and whatnot but i've i've met him he's
cool as dude um i mean you know like he
like you know i'm i'm very happy for
anybody that's [ __ ] making anything
happen at this you know in this industry
and whatnot um but he's i mean you know
he's he's definitely more of a of a
marketing type of person you know in in
the mix as far as
uh you know like branding and things
like that which is actually um like it's
it's very surprising how everything's
come together nowadays as far as
branding within like the industry and
all that it's like a lot like
it goes a long ways you know i i would
have never thought that it would have
came with this
do you feel like it would be wrong to
say that
cookies in a sense was the root of where
all this bloody branded mylar bag comes
from if you like kind of really think
about it
i mean i mean not not at all like i mean
it's uh cookies is the basis for pretty
much i mean even the
like uh the dos like dositos like what
like whatever it all it all kind of
stems from from there um i mean we're
just like uh
burner base i mean he has a platform to
basically promote this like that strain
and he has a huge following and uh and
as a result it kind of uh it's like a
trickle-down effect so where you know
anything associated with it can actually
you know be very you know worthy of
recognition in a sense um so like you
know like sure like i said like you know
sherbinsky um
as far as like him branching off and
doing his own thing like he does have
you know very prominent strains that are
like pretty well known in the industry
uh like under under his belt and whatnot
um but
it's uh yeah i think
it's you know like i like you can't deny
the fact that like cookies literally is
the basis for a lot of the stuff that's
going on now in the industry that's the
bottom line
of course yeah i think that you can
reduce it all down to like cookies and
tk
yeah i mean
i mean a lot i mean a lot i i feel like
the tk is more of a connoisseur um
like
market most people would not know what
like what what the tk is you mean so
yeah but i mean like all the hybrids are
like have those two components in them
mostly
yeah i mean it's it's uh
yeah i mean it's i'd like yeah i would
not i would not uh argue with that for
that way
but um at that like at the end of the
day like like like i said uh
cookies is i mean there's a reason why
it was a game changer in a sense it was
definitely like when i first saw the
actual real deal cookies i was like oh
this [ __ ] is actually fire like and the
only other strain that i could attribute
that to would be
like uh the og kush like the like the
original sfv or the larry that that was
around and then uh and also like the
urkel um like back then like nobody had
like purple strings it was kind of crazy
to to
to see so
um
what did you make of the sherbets and
the gelatos when they first came out did
they impress you at all
i mean honestly like i didn't i didn't
uh i'm not i'm not the person to like go
go and seek out these strains and if it
comes across me like like then i you
know i'll check it out and usually like
the people that i deal with they they're
uh they're
they they're
you know they they hold some weight in
the industry in a sense where like i
would trust that whatever they had was
legit um because like at some point
everyone wants to kind of pass whatever
they have off as the sherbet or like
gelato but
i mean it's you know that they're
they're good strains they're wrong like
but
like you know like i was i didn't even
have any idea that the
the the gelato like there was the
different um different types are
basically just different phenotypes of
the same you know i guess like seeds
uh and so i was like yeah i had no i you
know the sahih and um
the uh
like whatever other like you know
phenotypes there are they're all kind of
all based off the same seeds
but um you know like that i mean they're
they're good
i can't i can't deny that for sure
yeah for sure i'm a fan of the old 41
but
have you seen what the uh cookie fam are
doing now with their like their collab
with jbz and the mints thing
i mean i i have seen that like in there
i mean
like there's definitely like a lot of
good strains coming out of that uh out
of that camp in a sense um
like you know like i said then today
like i wish i'm not nothing but the best
um i'm in the same boat where i'm always
looking for something better i just hope
that everything works out uh
you know like for them and you know
there's uh there's when money comes into
play a lot of bridges get burned
sometimes it ain't so
yeah that's you know like that's uh but
i mean they're they're doing good work
so i hope everybody's getting
compensated and everyone's getting paid
and making money and you know be able to
take care of their family
of course
so a sentiment we've heard echoed by
many different people over the past few
years is that
everyone's so hyped over like these new
school things but people don't really
give enough credit to how some of the
old-school strains were really awesome
do you kind of feel like you're into
that mentality or are you not really
subscribing to that
i mean i i i'm
like i i love old school strains man
like the problem is they're just not
like necessarily available anymore so
and like a lot of the new stuff is
definitely
um like very you know like there's a lot
of not like nice stuff that's out like
nowadays
but um you know like to be able to have
like a like you know some land race
genetics that are you know you know from
back in the days it's just not really uh
it's it's
it's very few and far between like to
actually come across them especially
like the legit ones um you know there's
there's a
yeah i mean there's
like there's certain like there was a
like that the pepper uh pheno of romulan
that i like is very like for me like
very nostalgic um
like
probably a couple others i can't even
think about them right now off the top
of my head but but uh like things like
that you're not probably not not going
to come across them again
yeah wow pepper fino of romeo and i've
only really heard of a berry one
yeah there was a grape one but there was
also a pepper one um i mean i actually
brought it back from amsterdam when i
when i came back um
you know from the cannabis cup and like
i think it was like 2006
and um and yeah like i brought back the
seeds and and there there was i know i
know the grape pheno was that was one of
the uh one of the more prominent ones as
far as like that that was one around but
there was also the pepper fino that was
very like kind of like spicy and it was
like yeah like like i said in the day
like if i had it today um
there's
you're probably not you're going to get
more money for things that are a lot
more hyped up like like jbz stuff or you
know gelatos or you know sherbets and
all that stuff you know all that stuff
so
it's uh it's more of a personal
preference to run them and you know keep
them in the stable
so when you pop new seeds do you like to
delve into some old some new or you find
it's fairly much the new
um i mean
like as far as like uh like
as far as what i'm looking for or yeah
like if you're gonna do like a fino hunt
just kind of you know look through some
new stuff
yeah i mean it's it's uh
for me like it's it's i mean there's a
lot of stuff that gets uh
that ends up you know you have to sit
through a lot of the [ __ ] to get to
the good stuff and so that's that's just
kind of like the reality of it um you
know but like when i'm selecting like
males or you know and like crossing them
to certain females
it you know it's all like a matter of
selection and um you never know exactly
what what's going to come about but for
the most part if you put your best foot
forward you usually will get something
you know like you know something worthy
of keeping around but at the end of the
day too everyone gets tired of [ __ ] like
after
you know you you run the same strain for
like a year year and a half people are
gonna get tired of it no matter what
do you think that popping new seeds is
really kind of a vital thing to the
scene
i mean yeah it is it's honestly like as
far as like uh
like uh like i mean the longer you keep
a plant alive the the more of an
instance it has to actually
become you know a diseased or like have
like a like like some sort of a like
pest and infection i you know i guess if
that's what you want to call it um
and so like seeds are are you know
definitely
you know like if you constantly are
are uh popping seeds and looking through
stuff which like i said in the day you
have like you have to sit through a lot
of [ __ ] to get to some good stuff
sometimes depending on the stability of
like like a lot of the the genetics
um
like you know like you're gonna always
have like new stuff i i love that the
idea of always having something new to
like look forward to even though like
it's not always gonna be like not
everything's a winner you know
yeah okay i definitely feel like we've
all had our fair share of junk seeds but
in that kind of same vein of thought
when you are popping seeds do you
subscribe to this idea of like maybe
popping a certain amount like for
example if i gave you five seats would
you be like man it's not really enough
to do a good hunt or do you just
whatever's there is there
well i mean
i mean if someone give me five seeds i'd
just plant the five seeds like uh it's
uh you know beggars can't be choosers in
a sense uh
but
like yeah i mean it's definitely nice to
have like more of a
like like a broader
you know spectrum to like select from
and whatnot but you know like you can
also you know you can find some some
winners within five seeds um like like i
said it's definitely nicer to have uh
like like you know
a lot more to choose from but
you know at the end of the day it you
know it is what it is like it's uh you
know like i'm at the end of the day i'm
probably going to narrow it down to
probably like a few phenotypes and
that's it and then toss everything else
like it's it's it's easy to get like
attached to wanting to keep certain
things around but at the end of the day
it's just like you have to realize like
like there's always going to be
something better you just got to keep
looking you know
definitely so when you do a pheno hunt
do you like to
run the keeper so to speak as a clone a
few times before you rule at the keeper
or do you feel like you've got a good
idea from the first run because i find
people different opinions on this
i mean yeah i mean you have to like like
like uh i mean
it takes a little while to dial the
strains in because they all have like
different you know um like
nutritional requirements in a sense as
far as like uh like
like you know nutrients and whatnot um
and like so your first round may not be
like you're not going to hit it out you
know out the park
but uh like you know you'll get a decent
idea of what you know what it can
produce and what you know what not if
you get a pheno that's
super you know larpy and uh and like has
like a like you know like like a bland
smell you're probably i mean i probably
are not going to run it again but like
there's you can definitely see the
potential in certain strains as like you
know like when you grow them but at the
end of the day um you know most of the
time like i can tell within like the
first round like what's going to be
worthy of like keeping around and and
running it again and trying to dial it
in better as opposed to just like
wasting my time on keeping the mothers
for you know certain genetics that are
not going to be you know that
like you know worthy of keeping around
in a sense
yeah okay so
a bit of a hard question to answer i
understand but
what to you makes you want to keep a
plant like do you have like a certain
baseline and you think if it doesn't
meet the standard maybe like a a common
plant you just refer everything to and
you're like if it's not better than that
i'm just not keeping it like how do you
try to define what's going to stay and
what's going to go is it just a hunch
well realistically i mean it comes down
to a matter of space and um after like
most of stuff that i'm gonna select is
gonna be stuff that i kind of like i'd
like to keep but then as i'm sorting
through new stuff then things have to go
and that's just the bottom line you know
um and so like you know like there's if
i have unlimited space and things like
that it's one thing but at the end of
the day too it's like it's always nice
to start from new seed stock and have
like new genetics and like you know
everything gets old no matter what
that's the bottom line it's uh like it's
ironic how like now um
certain strains like are literally like
vintage strains in a sense if you call
like you know things they're like
um like like the the trends are cyclical
in a sense even with the weed it's crazy
and so it's it's uh it's you know like
like i said
some people like nowadays they'd want
they're like oh man i wish i had like
this train wreck or something and it's
just kind of like that was you know
around a long time ago and it's really
hard to come by nowadays um but you know
like i said it's it's just it's ironic
how things are very like i said like the
trends are very cyclical even within
like the cannabis market and whatnot
of course it is very cyclical like with
a lot of things i haven't asked you yet
what's your thoughts on femme seeds
would you ever make them
uh i mean i like i i personally wouldn't
i'm actually running some for the first
time
uh right now um
and and i got like that's that's gonna
basically be the basis for for my
opinion on on that i typically wouldn't
i know that like back in the days
uh like like there was a lot of
hermaphroditic like tendencies that
could come about from like the feminized
scenes but i like from what i know now
like i'm running uh some of like um like
like like from abf genetics some of his
are like feminized and you know like i
trust his judgment so that's why i'm
running them and like uh like i probably
wouldn't
um keep mothers for longer than maybe
like like a few rounds as far as taking
clones off of them but that's just me
you know erring on the side of caution
as far as uh traditionally
like back in the days
hearing that like they they tend they
tend to have her hermaphroditic
tendencies uh after a while um so i mean
i i could be completely wrong though so
okay sorry so just to clarify you're
saying if you found one you'd like you'd
run it a few times but you'd probably
give it up after a while because it'd
probably start to hurt
well that i mean i i can't say that
that's that's what would happen but more
than likely like in my experience back
like back in the days before things were
like a little more dialed in that's
that's kind of what was the consensus at
the time things i mean they people i
mean even like autoflower genetics and
like feminize autoflower like like uh
like everything's gotten you know people
have definitely dialed in things a
little bit better and so
um you know like it's i like i couldn't
i don't know in my experience i've
always like uh like back in the days
there was always kind of her
hermaphroditic tendencies as far as like
back then people would typically run
feminized seeds and
uh for like one round and then you know
move on to the the next round of like
like new seeds but um you know like i
said like this is literally like the
first time i'm running feminized seeds
and
you know we'll see how it all goes but i
trust like i said my like my homie
brian's judgment and um you know if he
tells me
there shouldn't be a problem then then
that's you know that's why i'm running
them
yeah that's exciting to hear i'll keep
my eyes on your instagram to see the
updates just as a quick follow-up are
there any other
packs of seeds or breeders that you're
kind of excited to run
uh i mean
i mean there's there's tons of stuff out
like um you know
like on the market right now like i mean
i i like i'm very fortunate to know like
a lot of you know like you know very
like good readers and and
when i see them they they'll throw me
down seeds and they you know things like
that and i'm always very like very
grateful for that and um and like i mean
i already know like they do really like
really good work so um you know like um
there is you know there's a lot of
prominent breeders like cannerado um
uh swamp boys uh
uh like seed junkie
um
you know like like obs um i mean i'm
gonna forget certain people at this
point so i don't wanna like offend
nobody but you know there's there's you
know i'm very fortunate to like you know
not like no uh you know know a good
amount of these people and and uh and
you know like like i said be able to run
some of their gear like it's uh you know
they all do good work some really big
heavy hitters in the list there another
heavy hitter you mentioned early on was
mp carly
i think i can guess what type of gross
style you use and my question is do you
use mp carly pro nutrient mix
uh no actually i i do not at the moment
um
i like i
i i use perfect grower and um like i
like you know they're they take care of
me like they
they you know like the nutrients are are
dope like you know we have very good
success with them um uh you know but
like you know ryan is is is my homie and
so like i i wouldn't you know like
i would not shy away from utilizing his
stuff but it's also more of at this
point i'm kind of like uh we you know we
were already used to running the the
perfect grower stuff and um and like
like ryan's he's a brilliant person like
he's i'm his product i'm sure is like
really well so like me like you know
maybe like further down the line
unfortunately at the time when i was uh
making the transition from like my like
my old form formula like which is based
off i think it was like a
uh cutting edge um
like he he hadn't he hadn't gotten his
nutrients like like you know on deck yet
so um so yeah that's why i went with the
perfect grower and you know like
everything as far as for me it's just
more of like if it it's not broke don't
fix it and we have really good success
with that so but you know i got nothing
but respect for ryan like he's he's a
really good friend of mine yeah yeah of
course i didn't didn't mean that in uh
you know kind of throw you under the bus
way at all that's awesome to hear that
there's some other good brands out there
and i guess kind of on that topic are
there any other products which you think
are really solid products just lifted
your game happy to kind of throw a shout
out to him
oh i mean like like everyone that that
like pretty much messes with us like as
far as like uh like from the lighting as
as far as like luxe lighting like you
know from my homie ivan like you know
jungle boys
um like the dli lights as well we we
utilize both of those
um
you know the floor flex they like aaron
at floraflex you know they
he he definitely takes care of us uh at
a troll master uh
you know um
like miami mango like you know that's
like you know that's they like i i just
appreciate everybody you know coming
together and um you know uh like the
camaraderie that comes along with like
uh like you know like as far as people
taking care of each other and whatnot
they all they all definitively you know
they uh like i'm very fortunate to
to be in the position to where like i
have their phone numbers and all that
stuff so there's any issues i can always
call them but yeah like i mean it's you
know they they're all like you know i'm
i'm very grateful for all of that
yeah wow a lot of big hitting names just
mentioned there i definitely want to get
into some of the nit gritty of that so
first of all
people are going to be super interested
in this what's like tell us about your
relationship with ivan of the jungle
boys
uh i mean we we just we came up from the
from the forums and whatnot like you
know like he was one of the pioneers as
far as uh like like i mean he he taught
me how to literally like set up a pump
start relay and irrigation controller uh
like for over a drip system and like you
know when we didn't have access i need
this information um you know and so it's
uh it's it's just crazy to see how
everything's kind of progressed as far
as
to where we're at now and you know and
whatnot but he's he's definitely like a
pioneer within this industry and he's uh
he's he's a smart guy he's not [ __ ]
he's uh you know he's he's definitely
he's definitely not not i mean i don't
say not stupid but like i'm saying like
he's a [ __ ] smart guy i respect the
[ __ ] out of him but it was more of just
like a like a relationship within the
forums that we had and uh and like
that's you know that's kind of where we
all came up from like um as far as like
i said like abf uh
frost boss which was actually yes for
prop 215 on ic mag i don't profit like
you know i got like all of our homies
like it's it's crazy to see how we've
all kind of came up and and we're at
like where we're at now you know
yeah definitely it definitely seems that
when you talk to all the kind of more
notable names in the scene there is a
common thread especially in the early
days which is nice to see that
you know the people who associated
together in the early days putting in
the work it's kind of translated on
yeah i mean it's it's a it's like i said
it's really crazy to realize like how
everything's uh fabricated
as far as like our success and um and
you know whatever like it's kind of like
like we all kind of took up a trade that
was
um you know we're very underground
at the time and then uh that's like it's
like a trade that literally is in very
high demand and we uh are like you know
we're getting paid for our experience as
far as like how many [ __ ] ups we had
so
so you also mentioned the troll
automated system do you feel that that's
going to be the future of growing with
these really tightly regulated automated
censoring which helps keep things in
control
i mean i i like the idea of it but like
you also always like eat like um like
like i remember when um
like there's there's a thread i want to
say it's on i think it's on thc farmer
and it's like it's weird how i actually
even remember this because it's so long
ago but ivan um from jungle boys he had
mentioned that like he had uh it was
like one of the threads as far as i
think he was sitting like an irrigation
controller up
and he was like you can automate this
but like i still like to go there
and push the buttons and literally like
make sure everything's getting watered
appropriately um so it i mean it's good
but it's also uh you know you have to be
there there's certain things like
mechanically that
like that can def definitely like fail
on you and if they do like uh depending
on how big of your of a of a setup you
have like it could be catastrophic as
far as um you know like
like you know things don't get watered
or there's certain clogs in like certain
irrigation lines you know you always
want to be there uh but automation is
definitely nice it's nice to have the
like uh the ability to
to uh to like you know to have access to
these products because back then
we didn't like we had to
pretty much kind of like uh come up with
ways to to do what we needed to do with
what you know in in our industry because
the products weren't readily available
they had to like you had to incorporate
other products from other industries to
actually uh you know like like get what
we wanted to get done
so with that in mind what do you see as
the future of more large-scale
cultivation
i mean it just it really depends on like
what what you're going for i feel like
there's a
you're going to have like your
budweisers where you know um you know
that like
people still buy budweiser but there's
always also a uh
a market for like craft beer and uh like
the same thing with like with weed like
i think x for me i'm very much into like
exclusivity and having that like uh like
you know not
not you know not necessarily having
whatever whatever everybody else has
access to or has but at the end of the
day too i mean i like you know people
love to clown on uh purple punch or blue
dream or green crack but um i do know
that i got homies that have dispensaries
and they like people love to to buy
those strengths you know so
it's uh it's it's you know it's it's
just a matter of like what what people
want um you know like
what like what the market dictates
yeah so kind of something i've been
thinking about for a long time is the
budweiser analogy it's a good one
because i think people understand it
would you
on a personal level be a little bit
bummed out about if we use that same
analogy you know budweiser makes a lot
more money than a lot of say craft
breweries that are making a really high
quality product
if that same analogy holds true in
cannabis is it a bit disheartening or is
it just a whatever thing to you
i mean at the end of the day um
i mean i like like like uh
it's i mean it's it's commercial growing
versus like i guess more like craft
growing but at the end of the day like
once you commercialize something um like
especially agriculture and whatnot it
usually always is gonna lead to like a
degradation of quality and so i mean
there but most people are like like i
always say that there's like the
consumer market and the connoisseur
market and um
most of them it's it's a very thin line
as far as like discerning like whether
or not this weed was grown you know
commercially or or like you know like or
someone grew it like uh you know ten
lights or versus like a hundred likes so
i mean it's it's uh like i said it's
it's pretty subjective and most of the
time like the majority of the market is
going to be uh like
consumers not necessarily connoisseurs
like a lot of people it's crazy to me
that they
will literally like
buy stuff without even looking at it or
like you know like uh like i just i
can't i can't
i can't buy something like that
yeah certainly
yeah as far as like going to a store and
um you know like like
not being able to look at the product
like that's why like even like delivery
services i'm like i like i don't you
know
it never really like uh like you know um
like struck me as far as like a
lucrative
um
business in a sense because i'm like who
the [ __ ] would want to buy something
that they can't necessarily
like see or smell or whatever but i mean
it's i mean i clearly i was wrong
so
so let's get down to some of the neat
greedies of growing itself what type of
medium do you like to grow in and what's
your how would you describe your general
style
uh i mean i i just try to keep things as
sterile as possible um i like i like
using uh i mean rockwool is just kind of
like a generic term in a sense because
there's so many other like brands it's
uh
but like you know i i like to just keep
it simple i've i've done pretty much
everything up like that you know i've
ran every single medium you possibly
could deep water culture
i've done uh like
water cooled lights at one point uh
which was a disaster
uh which is not a medium but i'm just
saying like you know i've i
i tried everything on it like you know
everything that is pretty much
like like
is it's tribal and uh
and i i kind of settled on the rockwell
because i had my most consistent yields
and um and you know like product to come
from that and it's it's it's it's uh
it's
it's it's sterile and you know like like
i've like said i've done cocoa i've done
beds
um i think you know like the other day
like rockwool was just kind of like what
i did best with
great and so
um is there any little tips or tricks
you might have for our growers in
regards to
how they can produce a better quality
and bud just general ideas or product
recommendations
it's like there's a very negative
connotation that comes along with
rockwool especially rockwool with
salt-based nutrients
people will always you know the soil
growers it's like a never-ending
argument where they're gonna they're
gonna you know tell you that like uh
it's
it's gonna taste this way or whatever
but at the day i feel like a lot of that
is somewhat subjective um you know and
uh and i mean it's it's definitively
subjective but like you know at the end
of the day i i i've
i've smoked organic you know soil which
i like i definitely like but on a
commercial scale it's not necessarily uh
like feasible i mean it is somewhat but
it's it's like when you're talking about
like minimizing your not necessarily
like just your cost but as far as like
like a labor intensity and things like
that uh you know like rockwell's like if
you you know
it can be it's a lot easier to work with
than and it's it's sterile so like every
time you buy it it's going to be sterile
there's no pots you have to sterilize
like after every round and
um you know dirt all that stuff can
become very like you know labor intense
um it's not about being lazy either it's
just more of
uh like i you know i i like the idea of
having everything kind of uh
you know like like just like streamlined
and you know that's it like it's uh yeah
it's it's i like i like i said i've done
cocoa i've done dirt um it's and
and i like the product but at the end of
the day like i could there's very few
times that i've actually been able to
discern the difference between you know
like something that was grown in
rockwool with salts that's flushed
properly as opposed to uh like you know
like soil that's you know organic soil
so you mentioned earlier that you like
luxe lighting are they the
ceramic metal halides
uh the ones that we have are actually we
use the the cmhs for our our mother room
in uh in oklahoma like like everything
else is like dueling in like hps's so uh
like but you know we're
basically we run dli and we also run uh
run lux so like they're they're both you
know they're both good brands they both
take care of us like you know i
appreciate the [ __ ] out of all like you
know both those companies so
and so what type of temperatures and
humidities do you like to run your
flower rooms at
oh the fl i mean the flower room is
typically like i i like to keep right
around like 80 maybe like the low 80s as
far as when we're running like like uh
co2 there's a lot of people they're
gonna like
they want to follow like the vpd charts
which they i mean it's not a not a bad
idea but uh like those charts uh they're
not necessarily tailored for like
cannabis growing um they're like they're
kind of a generalization for for like uh
like i like agricultural crops but
cannabis like you can't
run that high of a humidity like
according to the vpd charts uh like that
later in a flower and uh and so like you
know it's kind of like you kind of take
it with you know
you know take what you want from it and
whatnot but i usually run everything at
like 80 and like the humidity is always
going to be like between 50 and 60 and
that's that's it
cool and what's your kind of basic
outlier for your dry and cure process
because i find this is an area people
are always kind of looking to learn more
about
uh like honestly it's uh
it's not it's really not that not that
difficult in the sense where we pretty
much uh we we cut we we cut at the like
the base of the stock hang it on on a
hanger um and have it in a climate
controlled room uh like a drying room
that's like gonna be about 60 degrees uh
you know you want to keep a little bit
colder just because
you like the cold tends to uh to inhibit
the growth of like mold and whatnot and
um and uh and like the humidity just
like right around like you know 50 you
know basically like 50 percent like 60
degrees and just let it do its thing for
you know two weeks and then uh from
there everything gets trimmed up and
then from there like we like i designed
this the this uh we call like a can of
seller and uh and for our place in
oklahoma with uh where we have like the
cure tubes so from you know we're not
throwing them in like turkey bags
directly after we like uh like after
everything gets trimmed we're literally
we're throwing them in the the tubes and
from there they can kind of cure like a
you know as long as we want until the
product actually gets uh gets gets
gets uh get gets bought by the by the
distributors
and do you feel that'll be the future
for a lot of brands getting out of the
old turkey bags
i mean i i don't like the idea of um of
uh like you know just
trimming your you know your your buds
and just throwing them in a turkey bag
like it's like
you're gonna
i mean you could literally see the
trichomes
getting you know like uh like sticking
to the actual turkey bag if you if
you've opened open up a turkey bag like
you know
i like after everything's been trimmed
and you know like thrown thrown in the
bag um so you know i just i just like
the idea that you know you're gonna
smash trichomes and things like that i
mean it's
at the end of the day it's just you know
like it's just a matter of doing things
like as as best as we can so
um you know like i like i love the idea
of having that uh
that that can of seller and you know
like pretty much taking everything from
being trimmed and not throwing in a
bunch of turkey bags and you know
throwing them into the cure tubes and
letting them cure in there from there
you know
yeah definitely
so just to kind of jump to a different
topic i forgot to ask you earlier
between the dosey doe and the mendo
breath which one do you like more
uh honestly like i like them both they
they
it's uh i would say the dosa does is
probably like a little more indica
dominant but uh the mendo breath is like
you know like if you're gonna run it out
the words like the dositos is very i
feel like um
like it's very reminiscent of uh
of like more of an og the mendo bread
though just like stacks like if you i
mean i have homies that they'll pull
down like 10 12 pounds off of like one
single plant uh outdoors um and with the
dositos it's going to be
pretty tough to do that uh i mean it's
like
it's probably doable but like it's it
takes less effort to deal with the metal
breath and uh and like i mean yeah i
like
they they both have their own like you
know place
in uh as far as like what what i you
know what i like them for or what not
but i think um you know the mendo bread
definitely will yield a lot more for you
i just think that the if you're looking
more for indica effect your uh the
doseos is probably going to be your best
bet
yeah okay
so
often when we talk about ogs and chem
dogs and things breeding i often talk to
guests about
what pairs well generally speaking
in your mind do you feel as though
there's something which generally
speaking pairs well with cookies
there's there's nothing that i like
necessarily prefer there's certain like
cookies crosses that i definitely
have like been impressed by and whatnot
but i mean i like you know when you take
two things it's i mean for me it's just
very interesting to like pretty much see
what comes about from you know from the
cookies like i mean the dositos is
basically like a remade cookies um which
is you know like uh
you know like as far as that when it's
the dositos crossed the skittles i
forget what the actual name um
of the uh of the strain was that i want
to say fletcher
yeah yeah exactly that's
uh so yeah like it's it's it's
definitely um i mean you know like
when you take two like really good
things you usually will come out with
something pretty damn good so
uh but they're like you know like i like
i'm i'm still like experimenting with
that as far as like the you know
breeding like uh things with the og kami
especially and like stuff like that i
have like certain projects that i i'm
looking forward to like down the line
but it's going to be a little while
before we before i get there
oh okay well yeah let's talk a little
more collaborative stuff
what's your affiliation with cult
classics they seem to use a lot of your
stuff
i mean like
i mean marcus is basically like someone
that was introduced to me and
um you know like we like
i like say it's kind of the same thing
as far as like everything else that like
that i've done i gave him the cut
and uh and you know like he he bred it
so like it's like you know um a bunch of
like whatever like males that he had and
whatnot i just kind of let him do his
thing and uh it's you know like whatever
like he like uh
i unfortunately like i don't i don't
really hear too much about his company
at this point but uh but you know like
uh like there was certain things that
came out of like those breeding projects
that were like pretty like very like
very promising so
yeah i remember that ultra violence
thing he did was pretty popular
yeah that the cement shoes
um you know like there was definitely a
lot of promising stuff that came out of
out of those breeding projects and you
know like i was like for me at the end
of the day it's just it's it's very uh
like it's exciting to see what comes out
of these crosses and these these
pollinations and whatnot
definitely so someone we've spoken about
a few times already always be flowering
you mentioned he's a good friend i guess
the question is do you have any
collaborations in mind or do you think
that it'll happen in the future
oh well yeah with um i mean i'm always
like uh like
eager to work with him regardless like i
respect the [ __ ] um
uh like i mean yeah he has og kb i gave
him the the cut uh
he you know he's free to pretty much
work with it like however he wants so
like i like said that today like i trust
his judgment as far as what he's gonna
do with it and uh i'm same thing like
i'm excited to see what what would come
about from from that whole you know that
whole situation so
if someone wanted to get their hands on
some of your work what would be the way
to do it even if it's in the future you
know what do you think will be the best
way for him to get it through a seed
bank or maybe through a clone bank
i mean like i i like i said that's why i
kind of let other people handle that
that whole situation um like i couldn't
tell you i honestly i've had multiple
offers for like all sorts of stuff where
people are you know they they they want
to carry like uh you know like whatever
like the you know the crosses i make and
whatever but i at the day that's not
really like i would say it's not my
specialty but it's just more of like
i'd rather leave that up to like
somebody else and have them take care of
that you know just like you know work
with somebody else and you know do like
the collaborations and have them uh you
know take care of all that
you know as far as like uh facilitate
like you know the liquidation of all
of like the seeds and all that other
stuff
what i'm sensing here is that you're
actually giving a message to all the
pollen chuckers out there being like
guys making the seeds isn't the hard
part it's the other bit i don't want to
be involved with
yeah it's i mean it's it's uh i mean
it's i mean selection goes a long ways
that's what takes the longest time you
know but uh but like yeah for me it's
just more of like i like working with
people and um and like uh like you know
like seeing what like like i said it's
exciting at the day to see what can come
about from from the work and the
collaborations that can be done that's
really like uh like you know a lot of
people are very
they want to keep everything in house
and and uh not work with other people
like this industry industry's very ego
driven and um and i i think that's kind
of what will hold some people back at
the end of the day and so
like i said i'm like you know like i
decided at the end of the day like i
think just kind of everybody eats so
whatever if we can all help each other
out let's make it happen you know
certainly so you mentioned
people contacting you about stocking
your things and even earlier in this
episode you you mentioned darkheart
nursery they're a notable um nursery
that definitely sells a lot of the mendo
breath clones do you feel like honored
by that do you like how do you feel when
there's places stocking kind of your
work directly or indirectly
oh i mean at the end of the day like
like i said if you know uh you know like
not especially like the lineage of like
of the genetics but like you know a lot
of the times all that stuff is kind of
associated with me anyways so
i'm in a sense yeah like kind of honored
but at the end of the day too like they
like i said when i released the uh the
the the clones the documentary
um they were some of the first people to
literally line up to like grab them they
paid for them they can do whatever they
want with it at that point you know i'm
not it's uh like you know i can't hate
on on on them at the end of the day like
it's it's uh like all the
all the you know the the notoriety that
comes along with those strings kind of
if you know where they came from they're
it's gonna come back to me anyway so at
the end of the day like i said before
like i'm more than happy for
them doing their thing they actually
just
uh
identified like the hop uh i think it
was like the hot blatant viroid
um
issue with like plants and whatnot like
you know like they uh
yeah exactly like when we yeah years ago
when we were uh when we were growing it
was that that's pretty much what we
called it was dying but they actually
were able to lock it down and you know
like uh identify it so you know i
respect that that's cool as [ __ ] because
it probably didn't cost them it probably
cost them a lot a lot of money to uh to
retain the people to actually you know
do the work to figure that out so
whatever
yeah that's cool so i'd love to get your
opinion on this situation then how do
you feel when people
like
i guess kind of do what groma did you
know grab someone's strains and like
just f to it and sell it or just run
with it does that fit into your same
philosophy where like you know you're
not really gonna hate just whatever or
do you feel like at a certain point you
draw a line
i mean there's nothing you can do so
like why well like why lose sleep over
here like it's uh at the end of the day
it's like if uh
if uh
if i can i in a sense i feel like i
helped somebody out you know and um if
you want to utilize like my work to like
further yourself [ __ ] that's great uh
when when people want to uh
to like you know like if i mean if
someone wants to mouth off and and uh
and like you know like like uh you know
like i said like with him i literally
hit him up and i was like yo i wanted to
get a pack of like peanut butter bread
and he sent me like 25 packs of scenes
like i i respect that you know he
doesn't owe me [ __ ] um so at the end of
the day like i respect his work he's
done good work based off of
my stuff but that's kind of just like
that's kind of what you know par for the
course as far as what comes with the
territory and you can't you can't
control that so
um you know like at the end of the day
uh i mean if he was a dick and was like
you know like
like you know
like wanted to like you know like talk
[ __ ] to me about you know whatever when
i asked him for some seeds then that's a
different story but he was cool he
[ __ ] you know i i
i respect that so
great so i just really
yeah i just realized i hadn't actually
asked you what was the story with gage
green how did that end
well it was just so i mean it was just
more of a like like that was like i said
me like me and fletcher like people want
to think that like uh they're you know
think like i got rich off of
uh the whole docidos like situation or
whatever but like our original agreement
was basically to make the cross and
split the seeds and that that was it
like so you know i respect the [ __ ] out
of fletcher um
and you know like he's a good friend of
mine um and i'm very like uh you know
i'm very happy for him and like his like
success as far as like like the you know
the the the the sea lions that he's
running like now we're not based off the
docidos like all that [ __ ]
um with them i we actually had a
contract where there was like uh like
you know like i was supposed to get
compensated for you know the scenes that
were sold and things just got kind of
like convoluted and uh didn't
necessarily work out the way they were
supposed to um i mean i i like i
i know uh i guess like key play and uh
and mike and
and uh like you know like we're cool i'm
not like there's no bad blood it's just
more of like they
you know like they i mean they they
definitively like defaulted on our
agreement put it that way so but at the
end of the day there's not much you know
else you know you can do this it's not
an industry where like i can have my
lawyer contact you and uh and
sue you for you know whatever so
yeah okay and do you think that more
contract based collaborative project
will be the way going forward or do you
hope not
oh yeah i mean not like like everything
i do like even like with with compound
like uh like you know our agreement was
like i wanna say like 30 pages or
something you know like my lawyer put it
all together um and you know that's i
mean at the end of the day it's it's uh
i mean
it's it's
it's uh like it's it's just it's just
tough the industry is very it's not very
like uh mature in the sense where you
can actually like uh exercise these
rights but at the end of the day too
it's like i just i'm i just feel like it
like i'm over the whole like handshake
[ __ ] and you know like uh like those
sort of agreements like if everything's
written down on paper and at the end of
the day uh like someone defaults on it
um you know then it's like you know like
it's like it's it's it's clear as day as
far as like it's it's you know it's all
written down there this is what we
agreed on and that's pretty much it so
yeah okay so you mentioned earlier that
um we bumped into each other at the
emerald cup what's your feelings on the
emerald cup and on the cups in general
how do you feel the general vibe of them
is going
uh i mean what's ironic is actually like
a lot of people they they
they consider the emerald cup as as like
being like a very like i guess like like
a a custy
um uh
expo or whatever and and like this year
was actually the first year where people
were actually kind of more uh they
responded to to like going to the
emerald cup and uh because like
everything else actually like high times
all those all those other
shows are just like you know they're
they're they're garbage you know so um i
mean you know i like i like it i don't
like the idea that it's only uh for
outdoor growers
and uh like you know things like that
but whatever i mean like i i have fun
you know attending those things uh
seeing meeting people like you and you
know like conversing with people that uh
that you know like that are like very
prominent within the industry you know
so it's um
it's uh it's yeah it's like i just at
the end of the day i like having like
even like mj biz bizcon like i don't go
there
for the like actual conference it's like
i go there to have you know see every
like all of our homies under one roof
and literally just you know like
converse with them you know it's nice to
have everybody under one roof and
uh be able to to you know converse with
them and you know talk business
yeah of course
and uh i was also lucky enough to bump
into it at the counter illuminati party
the thing to me which stands out about
the counter illuminati party and also
things like the ego clash is that we're
seeing the rise of these kind of more
smaller boutique events because some
people are losing a bit of faith in the
bigger ones do you like that or what do
you how do you feel about the smaller
more boutique ones
oh i mean
at the end of the day like it's uh i
mean if there's i always i always uh
i like i always like to see like what
people have to offer at these sort of
events and whatnot you know like there's
a you know so
like the the i mean the bigger ones are
you know
i would say they're definitely a little
bit more uh like watered down and so
it's nice to have like see the up and
coming people that are like you know
literally like trying to like make moves
in the industry and that are like you
know doing like really good work because
that's really where you're going to see
it at most the time you know um as far
as like the up-and-comers like you know
at the
i like the bigger events you're going to
see the people that are probably a
little bit more established which is is
dope as well but you know it's like you
know there's always like i said
something new coming up and like you
know like it's it's always interesting
to see what other people have to offer
you know especially the underdogs
so one of the last things i wanted to
ask you about before we get into the
quickfire questions is
the concentrate takeover we haven't
heard so much news about it recently but
for the longest time you know
the rise of the vape pens the issues
with them the way it's you know kind of
taking over the market the casual
consumer just totally just having an
insatiable appetite for it where do you
sit on the concentrates taking over the
market debate
uh i mean it's it's uh like
like i i i don't mind like a like a like
a nice like uh like dab especially if
it's like you know like if it's ice wax
or you know like uh like sauce or rosin
you know if it's a good product like you
know uh i'd like i definitely like enjoy
it and whatnot but you know as far as
like the pens and all that stuff it's i
just feel like it's it's more of a
matter of um
accessibility and like uh like uh being
very like like inconspicuous as far as
you know that's why they're it's it's a
lot of it's very popular in like other
other states that may not be so uh
so privy to like you know like
legalization and like things like that
so
it's uh but at the end of the day like
it does suck that there was a whole
issue with
the the vape cartridges that you know
were all tainted and um
and you know like people were getting
sick from them and things like that so
it's uh like you know but i like i good
concentrates are like you know they're
good like another day like really like
it's
it's uh it's i think it's a lot more
healthier uh you know than actually like
smoking uh like like flowers or whatnot
because uh you're smoking you know at
least you're smoking you know thc like
the majority it's gonna be thc as a for
as opposed like a bunch of foliage that
you know like you roll up and you smoke
but i still like smoking like weed you
know that that's that i'm just kind of
old school like that
yeah 100
so let's jump into our last quickfire
questions
so first one indica sativa which one for
you oh i mean it's uh it's
like it like everything has its place i
feel like it's uh like i can't i can't
necessarily tell you i prefer one over
the other there's certain teams that are
gonna be like panic attack inducing and
uh
there's also like uh like you know
certain indicators are good if you're
gonna try to go to sleep but
but uh like you know especially at this
point too like nowadays i mean
everything's been hybridized so
it's uh it's kind of you know tough to
say exactly like what uh what i would
prefer in a sense but everything has
it's that you know it's time in its
place
as far as if i wake up
uh i'm not gonna want to take a dab or
uh
or uh or you know smoke a joint of like
some heavy indica uh you know obviously
like a sativa would probably be better
to get my day going um but at the like
at the end of the day if i'm trying to
go to sleep or something yeah like an
indica is probably gonna be your you
know your you know your best bet
but at the end of the day like i could
say too it's uh a lot of it's very just
very subjective you know it's all like
everything has a time and a place and
you just gotta you know figure out what
works for you
yeah i agree
so
flower or concentrate
i honestly like i i like flowers like i
feel like the concentrate game is uh
is so new that like we don't
we don't know the negative repercussions
of uh
of like like even with the whole thing
with the cartridges as far as like
smoking concentrates and stuff there are
certain uh there's certain ones that are
definitely more pure than others but
but uh like yeah i mean i'm just i'm
super old school in a sense that i like
i like smoking flower you know
i've i've had a conversation with a few
people before where it's like i said
it's it's just everything like certain
things are just so new that we don't
know what's gonna you know like we won't
know exactly how it affects people and
as far as their health until probably
like 20 or 30 years down the road you
know so if you're smoking cartridges
like all day and um
and you know like like you know people
are still gonna weed you know flowers
for
forever at this point but uh like we'll
know more or less you know the
the consequences of
smoking you know other other things like
it's like you know butane extracted uh
concentrates uh cartridges all that
stuff
it's like i said we won't know until you
know like i said it's gonna be years
before we figure out like what exactly
what um like how like how it affects
people and like their immune systems and
whatnot
yeah for sure so
out of the following three strains you
have to pick one to smoke which one is
it mac gmo or skittles
uh i mean i mean you can't really go
wrong with either of those i mean i
would
i would probably say uh uh the skittles
really like the mac to me to be honest
like reminds me a lot like of like kind
of like a bubba um but it's it's it's
it's a very good straight wrong um and i
i tend to like more of the fruity stuff
to be honest
um so like yeah like skittles is
definitely you know
probably uh the gmo is good it's it's
definitely super gassy
i think i just have like uh some sort of
affinity as far as like
not wanting to smoke it just because
really like it takes so long to finish
because it's a longer like flowering
strain
yeah definitely
that's just a personal thing you know
but uh like yeah like skittles i like i
like yeah i'm i'm like yeah i definitely
like i was definitely impressed with the
skittles when i when i saw it for the
first time
when you saw it or when you tasted it
i mean both but i'm saying as far as
like when it like literally
when i actually saw the real deal you
know so yeah okay cool so out of all the
way you've smoked ever what's been the
most memorable
uh i mean like like i said there's that
that pepper fino of the romulan and then
there's um uh
uh
the like like the blueberry headband
that i like that i crossed the og kb um
like there's like a certain actually
like i saw like a
what was it like i think it was like a
blue diesel when i was actually in
illinois
um and i was actually pretty impressed
with it like the it was like super
frosty
and i i didn't get to smoke at those but
as far as like you know looks wise and
like uh like you know like the like
terpenes and all that it was definitely
uh it was i was pretty impressed with it
so
but uh but for me like it like the one
of the most memorable memorable strains
realistically is gonna be
like so there's like the dj like i i'm
just very
very like uh like
very uh i like a lot of the blueberry
strengths but that way now so like like
the dj short blueberry that i had in
like amsterdam
like was it's very nostalgic to me um uh
like the blueberry headband that i've
had like i've only had like a few times
it was
very like yeah like it was
it was uh it definitely stood out so
so on the other hand what was a strain
which really kind of took off with other
people but you were just like man i
don't get it this is trash
like i said like everything kind of has
its uh
its place as far as like uh like for
smoking there's people that you're gonna
talk [ __ ] about like said blue dream
verbal punch
um you know green crack um like i i at
the end of the day i'm actually like
pretty grateful to have the selection we
have nowadays because what
you know what i smoked
uh you know 15 years ago or whatever was
you know a lot of this stuff was just
garbage so
it's uh like you know like there's
i mean that like yeah i've definitely i
guess i mean i've
i've i've smoked out a [ __ ]
out of like uh aluminum cans and stuff
like that where it's got
it's kind of like uh
you know like a
taste is kind of irrelevant at that
point but uh like you know like like
i've definitely had my fair share of
smoking of like a lot you know a lot of
[ __ ] really like that's that's you
know most people that used to smoke back
in the days like you know they
they uh like yeah
there was definitely a lot of stuff that
was going around that was you know just
uh like not not like what we have the
selection of today
yeah thank god we are where we're at now
so lucky last question if you could go
back in time any place anywhere in
history presumably to grab seeds or
maybe a clone where would you want to go
and what would you grab
huh i mean there's uh i mean it's always
nice to have land raised genetics um
it's i mean but at the end of the day
it just depends on which what you want
like i know that like you know like
like like uh
to go to africa and get like some like
you know some german poison scenes um
you know like any of those land races
like that like the hindu kush
uh
like things like that that are you know
like you don't you don't see that
anymore but um like to be able to go
like go and like acquire those genetics
would be pretty dope um i like you know
at the end of the day though we actually
have a really good selection here in
california just not uh like it's
like obviously not everything's gonna be
like a land race genetics
coming from like you know like south
america or like africa or you know um
like the middle east and whatnot so
it's uh
it's it's hard to say actually like what
i would actually want to uh like what's
on my on my uh my hit list as far as
like what i want to like what i want to
acquire
yeah there's certainly a lot of choices
in there well with that being said do
you have any shout outs or comments
you'd like to make
i mean i mean not really man just you
know [ __ ] uh i'm grateful for like
everybody that you know like uh
that you know has worked with me like i
got a lot of like you gotta read through
the [ __ ] to get to the the real
people sometimes and you know very
grateful to have access to like you know
like uh knowing a lot of people that are
very prominent with the industry
and uh and that like i respect a lot
like you know i have my my crew out in
like oklahoma city that they they you
know they stay crushing it um
uh you know like i said like like ivan
from jungle boys lump status my boy
frost boss brian
uh unknown prophet
uh my homie uh
like garrus that helps me out over here
he's miami he's he's he holds it down
when i'm when i'm gone all the goddamn
time he watches my dog and stuff for me
you know
um and uh you know like it's you know
just i'm just very grateful and blessed
to be able to
uh be associated with like a lot of
these people and uh and be able to like
absorb their knowledge and you know
share like
share what we've learned within the
industry within over the course of the
last like 15 20 years yeah what a lovely
sentiment so you know thank you so much
norcal i see mag for coming on the show
setting the record straight and laying
down all the cookie knowledge we're
really excited to see your future
projects
yeah i mean
i'm excited for you know you guys uh you
know like see uh like you know all the
unfortunately the last sentence got cut
off there guys sorry about that
[Applause]
so there you have it
[Music]
there's a good episode some really
really really good knowledge about some
strains i love in that one
as always big shout out to our sponsors
seeds here now
radio ridge
organic gardening solutions
top shelf seed bank
and of course the patreon gang we love
you the lifeblood of the show thank you
so much guys please go check out the
patreon if you want to help support the
show and get some additional content and
access to early episodes
[Music]
as always my friends
i will see you in the next one
[Music]
thanks for stopping by
we'll see you
[Music]
so
you