oh
[Applause]
[Music]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts
this episode we are joined by the
fantastic chimera of chimera genetics
hope you guys ready for that three out
of three hitter
wrap up this epic six hour chat with a
bang
as always a big thank you to our
fantastic sponsors seeds here now best
sea bank in the game guarantee on
satisfaction not just germination why
would you go anywhere else they've got
all the biggest breeders in the game
fire from swamp boys skunk va mean gin
you name it they got it likewise check
out coppet biological systems your
number one stop to get all the goodies
to keep your garden happy and healthy be
it beneficial predator bugs beneficial
microbial powders or even feeds to keep
that beneficial army alive happy and
healthy and make your next harvest the
best today
likewise a huge shout out to the patreon
gang you guys are the lifeblood of the
show and truly helped keep episodes
happening if you would like to support
the show and continue to ensure that
more episodes come out as well as get
access to additional content unreleased
interviews and some other bonus goodies
go check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
[Music]
i hope you guys are excited for that
final three out of three part hitter
from chimera
let's get into it
[Music]
a lot of people over the years have
expressed concern to me around the idea
of the development of such a strain
whereby you know it's it's approximately
the same height structure profile
terpenes it's got all these traits on
lockdown such that you know like a big
combined harvester can just harvest a
field of it perfectly and it just goes
through to production that sort of idea
and the the fear that gets expressed
with this sort of end outcome is that we
could lose genetic diversity if these
populations were to hermaphrodite or to
put pollen out that sort of thing
do you think that that is a legitimate
concern or do you think that it's more
akin to the way there's corn and then
there's heirloom corn you know they both
still exist
genetic diversity for me is a concern
for every species on the planet
and so cannabis being
one that i've chosen to be a custodian
of
hell yeah genetic diversity is a hugely
important thing
and i think that everybody needs to
practice good
prac you know we need to be
doing open popping like whenever
whenever i do a population like for
example when we do the blueberry stuff
with dj we grew all the stuff and we
just let it open pollinate we didn't
make we didn't do a lot of seed from it
but we let it all get a little bit of
seed and all that seed got bulked
together
right and it's like now you've got
everything
right
and that goes in the freezer somewhere
um or a fridge somewhere whatever into
your long-term germplasm storage and
then you start working from the clones
of the individuals and creating sub
families but the first step is the open
pollination the first step is the
preservation of the genes in the pool
right because it doesn't stop you from
doing any other type of breeding
down line you know you might want to
open pollinate the whole thing and
collect all the seeds from all the
plants and then you've got it all again
right and you don't have to do that for
another 25 years right and then you can
take the one clone and make seeds from
that one plant right so now you've got
an inbred version of your population and
the the breadth of the genetic diversity
in another population in the fridge
right um
and i think that's a crucial part of if
you're serious about germplasm
preservation or genetic preservation of
a crop that's what you do
right you
you preserve it and then you improve it
and you put the preserved stuff in the
freezer and then you can
improve the line and then if you want
you can go back to the original
population or cross the new line to the
old line or whatever your options are
limitless
but if you didn't do the preservation
you can't go back
right
um
so yeah
hugely important for all plant breeders
and and definitely people need to be
starting thinking about it
um
is
making uniform seed going to compromise
the genetic diversity of the species i
don't think so because again
you might be able to make that new new
line
where all the plants look the same with
a small subset of your population
but as long as you've got that genetic
diversity that you've preserved in the
first place you're not really losing
anything right
sure
sure sure
so just to jump back one question
you raise a brilliant point and one i've
actually kind of struggled to navigate
the minefield of myself in that a lot of
people in the community use like the
incorrect sort of nomenclature around
certain topics and my suspicion is that
it arises from the fact that a lot of
growers are genuinely very inquisitive
and curious
and so they try to look into things and
often
you know words get used in the wrong
context because maybe there was never
like a formal education around what it's
used and and often it leads to just
people like myself using the wrong terms
just so that people can kind of
understand what we're talking about the
question becomes do you think there ever
will become a sort of formalized
nomenclature around cannabis and like an
effort to set it straight and the reason
why i specifically reference this is
because we're seeing a shift with
seeds instead of being called s ones
people calling them r ones and whether
that's correct or not it makes me
realize that people are starting to
think about this sort of thing what's
your thoughts what's r1 reversal
yeah
well that's silly because yeah that's
silly because it's a it's a s1 means
self
right so
yeah yeah after
you have to reverse one plant but that
plant that you reverse doesn't make the
seeds i think that's a weird thing to
call it s1s
and it's actually kind of funny i think
it's actually a good way to make this
point
the cannabis world kind of likes to be
on its own you know you asked the
question that you asked was will we ever
get to a standard point in time
where everybody uses a strict set of
terminology that's correct
i mean
there is a whole strict set of
terminology that's correct and the rest
of the plant world uses it but for some
reason stoners don't
right um
and it's it's no fault of our own like
when
listen when somebody teaches you
something the wrong way
and you we all learn it and we all think
that it's right and then all of a sudden
one person learns that hey we all
learned it wrong it's pretty hard for
the rest of the people to come back and
turn around
right so words like strain sativa indica
like all those words are used wrong
right like i even used it earlier i used
the word
um calex k there's no calyxes the
cannabis doesn't have calyxes cannabis
has braggs
right but again when and i'm not blaming
rob but rob in in marijuana botany he
misused some of these words
and
you know he learned them the wrong way
as well he was taught them the wrong way
it's i'm not trying to put any blame on
rob for this
um
so let's dive into the sativa indica
thing for a second here
sativa so
let's start with indica indica means
from india
right like there's there's other plants
that are from india
and they're like you know medicago
indica for example right like
indica means from india well if you look
at plants from india the cannabis plants
from india what are they like they're
equatorial they've got long thin leaves
right
but we call those plants sativas
well sativas
sativa means useful or cultivated it's
latin for
it's kind of got a bi meaning it's like
useful or or cultivated
um
peas are piss
sativum right and again that sativum is
the same
root word which means useful right so
somebody had taken
a plant out of that collection and found
a a use for it really is what it was
what it is and they they cultivated it
in out of the wild it's kind of like the
process of taking it out of the wild and
and putting it into into your own
domestic cultivation is
is what the word sativa means well the
plants that we mean to be that the
plants that were first described by
linneas
to as cannabis sativa
were hemp it wasn't drug cannabis it was
hemp
right and hemp plants have narrow leaves
and really tall stems
okay
so what are the so what are the wide
plants then with the wide the really
short stocky plants with the super wide
leaves that we call indica they're
actually afghan so they're afghanica
so
what we call af what we call indica is
really afghanica
what we call sativa is really indica
and sativa is really meant for hemp
right well that might sound all
interesting and everything but like how
the hell are we gonna get everybody to
get on board and understand that that's
what it is
right like i mean even yourself you're
like a highly informed person in the
space
and we still use these terms right and i
i'm not trying to
you know make you feel bad or dumb about
that it's like i run into this like
every day with people right it's like
everybody i interact with it's like oh
this is a diva this is a strain you know
the word strain
the plant people that do the name the
the naming of plants in the world they
kind of oversee there's like another
organization
um
that kind of ha that develops the
taxonomy and the names for plants they
don't use the word strain
right strain is simply reserved for
bacteria and
viruses right so you can have like
covid19 is a strain
right and it's this the reason it's
called the sort of the coronavirus
that we call covid the reason is that is
that
it it has that name is that that
all all
individuals within that family that came
from a common ancestor since it's spread
all over the world it's undergone all
these mutations in its genes so it's
actually no longer one individual
genetic type reproducing itself it's
become like a hairball of all these
different genetic types that are
reproducing themselves the reason that
we all call them
um
you know the covid strain of coronavirus
or whatever
is
that they all induce the same phenotype
in humans
right which is the coronavirus disease
or covid
so
really people that are using the word
strain should stop if you know if it
would be my recommendation
what you're calling what you refer to as
a strain like for example blue dream
is a specific clonal type that has been
selected from a population
and every plant that subsequently comes
from that clone or from other mother
plants of that clone
that should be called a cultivar okay
cultivars don't necessarily breed true
um but as long as you propagate them
through clones
the traits that we refer to that you
know the traits that we named we have or
somebody has named blue dream
all of those traits are consistently
re they consistently come from the
plants
as long as you're taking cuttings of it
okay
yeah
if you then cross that plant to itself
or one member of its family and all the
plants came out
again identical to blue dream that would
be called a variety so a variety is a
seed family that reproduces a type when
you
inbreed it
through sexual
recombination
a cultivar is a plant that maintains it
type its type when you reproduce it
through clone okay and so i think
cultivar is the word that people mean
when they say strain
and there's probably not enough
true cannabis varieties yet for that to
really be too too relevant to most
people
um
pinot noir for example it's a clonally
propagated plant that's a cultivar it's
not a strain like you'll never hear i
mean
you hear it occasionally but
the plant people would never call it a
strain
right
yeah um
and so that's kind of why i lean away
from words like indica and sativa and i
try to tell people or i try to i try to
use the words all i can do is set an
example by using my you know these words
myself and i kind of try to use the word
equatorial for
what you've been referring to
colloquially as sativa
right um
and then afghanica i think is the best
word for
indica
again
linnaeus the guy that did this work was
you know whatever over 100 years ago
well over 100 years ago
and then when the drug cannabis growers
started getting into cannabis and call
it the late 50s or maybe 60s and 70s
that's really when the words sativa and
indica
appeared in our pop culture vernacular
or even our cannabis culture vernacular
and
it's pretty understandable that
they went and read the scientific
literature and and decided oh look this
plant is tall and it has thin leaves
it's probably sativa without realizing
that linnaeus was describing a hemp
plant not a drug cannabis plant
right and and same with the indica right
so really
it becomes hard when
everybody is using the words to mean
different things it's again it's like
we're talking with terps and we don't
have a
a consistent um
agreed upon definition right everybody's
got their own definition of what the
word these words mean right so someone
says oh i got a strain of cannabis and
it's like oh yeah well what what what's
a strain
ask them what a strain is and it's like
watch them try to figure out what it is
right because a strain
a strain when it reproduces it should
always reproduce the type but if you
breed a cannabis to a cannabis plant to
itself
and it's a cultivar it's a hybrid
cultivar when you breed it to itself it
falls apart the kids no longer look like
the mother right and that's the real
problem in the seed market because
some dude gets the cutting again we'll
stick with blue dream some dude gets a
cutting of blue dream and he's like i'm
gonna make a bunch of money or he or she
thinks they're gonna make a bunch of
money making seeds from blue dreams so
they take one copy of the clone and they
reverse it with their sts and
take that pollen and put it on their
their other plant
and then they put they harvest all the
seeds and they put them in a bag and
they label it blue dream
right and those seeds go off to the seed
vendor and he puts them on his website
and puts them in a package it says blue
dream and when you grow the seeds out
they look nothing like the parent
right so the word blue dream becomes
meaningless
right because again it doesn't you know
then that goes out onto the market
and some guys let he finds a plant
that's totally different from blue dream
and he's selling into his market as blue
dream
and now the public has no idea what blue
dream even means
right like if you go into a grocery
store and you buy a macintosh apple and
you're in vermont or australia or like
london uk or amsterdam it's the same
apple
right because it's
it's been registered as a plant variety
right and they get that when you when
that process happens that's when you get
to put the name on the plant and you get
the commercial rights to the plant and
the name
right some other dude can't come along
and start like
selling an apple in his backyard is
macintosh
right because eventually everybody gets
to know the flavor of the macintosh and
they realize yeah that's macintosh
that's granny smith that's honeydew
right and people learn these things and
unfortunately we don't have that kind of
standardization in cannabis
and you actually have to be
of a certain level in the business with
access to lab testing and you know a bit
of a
snob like a somalia kind of snob person
to
to really understand the differences and
be able to pick up a plan and say that's
this this is the other thing you know
and and sort them by chemical type
and i'm you know
i like to complain about these things
but i mean really the only reason i
complain about it is because it needs to
become a talking point before people are
going to do anything about it
um
and you have to have some you know that
was one of the things that i did when we
were working down in california the
company that i was working for gave us a
really quite significant budget to go
and buy all the weed that we could find
in the state and run it through our lab
and through the process we were able to
start seeing
okay all everybody agrees that this is
sour diesel except for these people
they've got something else they're
calling sour diesel
or the entire market agrees that this is
blue dream except for these people
they've got something else this blue
dream and you can start
making a you can start linking a
chemical profile that that is
discoverable by a lab assay
that means the type
right
and you know a good way to think about
it is like if tom cruise has kids we
don't call them tom cruise and start
telling everybody that the kid is in top
gun right
i mean it's like it's just that
we all agree that the the words tom
cruise or whatever word you want to use
is a symbol for a type
right and that symbol and that type
should remain constant from group to
group
right for it to be a real thing
otherwise what people are doing is
they're just trying to slap a popular
name
on a different variety to sell it and
fool the market but really what that
does
is it just confuses the market in the
long term and then nobody knows what
every anything is and
it's one of the shortfalls of cannabis
right it's like i maybe i'm a
way nerding out on about it too much but
i i think it would be really great if
everybody understood
that this certain smell profile is sour
diesel this certain smell profile is
what we call blue dream
right
yeah hundred percent and uh some really
good food for thought and a little
something i'm gonna have to keep in mind
going forward trying to use the right
terminology because i'm definitely a
huge advocate of that's how things get
very muddy you know i've i've certainly
told a lot of people when they make some
s1s you know make sure to say that it's
an s1 you know like otherwise you have
that same problem you mentioned but just
to jump back to something we were
talking about earlier with the the ae77
cali orange i just wanted to ask there
is this prevalent idea that exists
broadly around i guess all orange
strains but maybe it stems from the
calio because it is so widely used and
it's like you know a common ancestor for
a lot of the popular ones at the moment
you've worked with it and you've made
the colors are and the c plus in your
experience do you think that there is a
link between that orange profile and a
lack of potency because a lot of people
speak as though you just can't get like
a an orange flavored strain that hits
you in the way an og does what's your
thoughts
um
no well no
yes and no probably i think the long
answer is no
um
and the reason is is that like like i
kind of mentioned to you off cam or off
recording
scent or smell is a hair heritable
characteristic okay
and so it's a trait like every like
anything else and it's probably a series
of traits that all appear as one
and usually when you have traits like
that on a given chromosome
they kind of get stacked in one part of
the chromosome and so chromosomes during
copying they break apart and they can
switch people we were talking about the
blue and the red chromosomes before for
mom and dad
when that
when that child from you know from mom
and dad has it goes through it's making
sperm or eggs or pollen
those pieces of chromosomes can actually
change little pieces of information so
you might get like a
majorly
blue chromosome with a little tip of red
and correspondingly a majorly red
chromosome with a little tip of blue
and so
they do exchange little pieces of
information the probability of
those
genes that are inherited on that same
little chunk
getting separated like the closer two
genes are on a chromosome the more
likely it is that they'll be inherited
together okay because there's less
chance of a crossover happening
um at that part of the chromosome
between those two genes
but it can happen okay
um it's just really low probability
and so
when you say
is thc and orange
you know are they linked to be that
there is no thc there's no higher
potency orange stuff that's really not
true but it takes a lot of breeding to
get to that point you have to it's and
that's a phenomenon called
gene linkage and so people can look up
on google gene linkage or even on
youtube i'm sure there's videos gene
linkage and gene linkage maps
and there's ways that you can
um
if you if you score traits over many
generations and you very diligently
record the traits and the occurrence the
number of times those traits appear on a
set of plants on the population you can
actually start to figure out how close
together
sets of genes are on
the chromosome okay and if you're using
genomics or molecular t techniques you
can actually do it a lot more quickly
but the idea is that you want to so it
might be
that the orange flavored genes are very
close on
the same chromosome to a version of the
thc gene that doesn't work very well
right and so what we need to do is we
need to take that
piece of the the gene for the orange
sorry the piece of gene for the
mediocre thc production and
switch that out
for a gene
that is that makes thc but it's very
effective at doing its job
and that's called breaking the linkage
right
and the closer two genes are on a
chromosome the harder it is to break the
linkage between those two alleles
um
so again these are all things that can
be solved with plant breeding but it
really takes doing like a
across within you you want to cross
probably you want to cross something
like um
you know an orange plant to a high thc
plant like cookies or og
and then you grow the f1 and you let
them all breed together and in the next
generation you want to grow like say 50
000 plants
right and when you grow that many of the
next generation
you have a higher
likelihood of finding
the plant that has all the orange flavor
but also
the high thc production of the high
cannabinoid production
um and that's just plant breeding in
numbers right like luther burbank used
to grow hundreds of thousands of plants
looking for i think he you know i think
he selected
the russet potato out of like a hundred
thousand plants
right i think that he kept two plants
from a hundred thousand so
it's
impressive yeah and it's a chore and
it's serious but it's like man you want
to make those improved plants
that's what you do and now when you've
done the work now you've got an orange
plant that is um
high in thc
and uh that's that's pretty cool and it
but it takes a lot of work to get there
and you certainly can't do it in the
closet
um
now that we have genomic tools you know
they can definitely aid in the breeding
to do that but they also have a cost
right you're still
paying
however many dollars per sample to have
every plant genotyped
um
so yeah
the good news is that the new ones like
you know some of the sherb and the new
things they're they're orange and
they're a lot more potent than the ae 77
is
yeah certainly certainly so we actually
had a question from one of our viewers
submitted about like what are your
thoughts on the occurrence of like the
supposed like one in a thousand phenos
and specifically
they kind of reference this idea of
every now and again
for the most part you'll see most plants
having just
lots of characteristics of the parents
some blended some leaning more towards
one or the other but every now and again
maybe you call it a one in a thousand
fino so to speak you get a plant that's
almost unlike either of the parents in
any regard
do you feel like this is a real sort of
phenomenon that occurs or do you maybe
it's pollen contamination and do you
think these one in a thousand phenoes
will be more sought after given we've
kind of discussed them a bit and how
there can be advantages to finding these
special occurring plants
they they can be better than the others
but they're not necessarily better i
think when people are talking about the
one in a thousand it's really most often
about
you know it's like you said you get
traits from mom and traits from dad
but like did you get all the right
traits for mom and all the right traits
from dad right that's one of the
thousand kind of material
um
the other thing that you might see i
think what you're hinting at is there
are these very rare
genetic combinations that lead to an
alter phenotype of some type
and the reason that they're rare is that
again it's really
it with with breeding it's again like i
said it's statistics and math it all
comes down to just having the right
genes and if you have all the right
combinations of genes
then you can get an aberrant or a
stranger a new
phenotype that was unseen in either of
the parents
but that all is based on probability
right um
and it's really just rolling the dice
over and over and over and over and over
again until you get the right
combination
of genes together
sure and i mean
it seems like a good point to segue into
some of the more advanced science and ip
stuff we're going to chat about
the first question i have in regards to
genes and the way they line up
do you to the best of your knowledge
know if crispr or any kind of molecular
editing
has been used to create altered cannabis
varieties i don't believe so it might
have been done somewhere in some lab but
crispr is not as easy as everybody
thinks it is
um you don't just dip a plant in crisper
juice for example and the whole thing
comes out changed right like these
genetic changes they happen on a single
single
cell right and then that single cell has
to have integrated the new trait
and
that single cell needs to become a new
plant and so when that single cell
divides and divides you have what are
called when you get a clump of cells you
get what are called sectors in the in
the cell
and those sectors might actually like
you might lose
the crispr
mutation or whatever the crispr change
has caused and so now you've got a plant
that is growing as a chimera like it's
actually a plant with multiple genetic
types within the plant
but what you need to have is a plant
that is all one genotype
that all incorporates the
you know the new crispr mutant
version of your your altered gene
um
and so
when you grow
how do i explain this when you when you
grow cannabis plants
it's not like the shoot that comes off
of a plant it's not a single cell it's
an organ
right it's not one single diff
undifferentiated cell
it's like all the cell types are already
organized in a way that they know what
they're doing right so the the
equivalent to people can think about in
humans
if you've got you know the cells in your
heart are are heart cells they're heart
tissue cells the cells in your lungs or
lung tissue cells the
the
the nerve cells in the back of your eye
are eye tissue cells they're all highly
specialized and differentiated okay
now any cell type can revert to what we
call stem cells and plants have
equivalents of stem cells
um which is you know more or less
callous it's it's really like a
a d differentiated cell it's a cell that
started as an organized group of tissues
and it went back to the cellular level
well if you do that and you get it down
to the one cell now you can make your
crispr changes on that one cell
but you have to grow it back out into a
full plant that is re-differentiated
into the proper types
okay and that doesn't just happen
spontaneously like you have to
there's protocols with different
chemical and hormonal applications that
you have to get that you have to go
through
to
redifferentiate a stem cell it's like
you know it's like if you want to take a
stem cell from someone
you take skeleton cells out of their
skin
you you put them through a genetic
program and it makes them back into a
stem cell now it's like
the progenitor cell that can can become
heart tissue or eye tissue or lung
tissue and so depending on what you want
that cell to do in the end you have to
coax it along that genetic pathway so
your little baby stem cell grows up to
be a heart cell
right and then you can take those heart
cells and
coat them on some kind of like matrix so
that they grow into a piece of tissue
that you can actually transplant into a
heart for example
you don't want to put lung cells into a
heart
right and so there's a whole science
that nobody has figured out to my
understanding that nobody's figured out
in cannabis
to really go through that process of
single cells to
differentiated tissue secondly when they
go through that process of
redifferentiation there's something
called soma clonal variation
and again you can look that up it's
somaclonal
soma and then the word clonal variation
and that's
genetic variation or epigenetic
variation
that stands upon the genotype
um
and that can actually che through
something called dna methylation that
can
either silence genes or
over expressed genes
and the result of those things may be
that the plant that actually comes out
of that form of tissue culture is not
the same as the one that went in
regardless of the genetic change that
you made
right so
i think that for now
listen it's going to happen at some
point in time
somebody will make
you know crisper cannabis it hasn't i
don't believe it's happened yet um
typically you make those kinds of
alterations in in
species that that are already id are
mostly ideal but you just want to fix
one trait
and
there isn't the natural genetic
diversity that is present in the species
for you to be able to go back and select
those traits through breeding
um
it's a it's a it's a shortcut it's a
really cool technique it's super neat
that we can that we're at the point in
time that we can do that now but i don't
think that anybody has to worry that
that's happening with cannabis at the
moment
right it will come one day but i don't
think that we're there yet
yeah what a really comprehensive answer
so if we jump to the other end of the
spectrum you know as a as opposed to
maybe the
the quote experts using genetic
modification let's talk about the novice
for a second
what would be your advice to someone
just starting out on the right way to
breed what would be any tips or sort of
principles you would recommend they
adhere to
genetics for dummies and get yourself a
genetics for dummies textbook
understand a basic plant breeding
textbook or even a basic biology
textbook that
teaches meiosis
um meiosis is the dance of life that
goes on
like i said earlier in the forming of
the cells that become sperm pollen eggs
and
you know um ovules and plants
that genetic dance
is more important to the breeding
process than anything else because if
you understand how it happens then you
understand what's possible and what's
not possible
once you have that knowledge you can add
on cannabis knowledge on top of it and
you only become
more informed
but
the vast majority of books
on cannabis don't do an adequate job of
talking about it
um
rob clark's book is not bad for it it's
it's a pretty good start you have to
remember the context and i say it's not
bad it's an epic book but i say it's not
bad today because it's 2020 and that
book was written 39 years ago it was
published in in 1981.
um
so
the amount of things that we've learned
about science since then is pretty fast
and a lot of those things are kind of
left out of the book
um so i don't you know i don't talk bad
about rob's book because it's it fails
because it's it's not a good book it's a
great book it's just it's got a lot of
science from you know that time period
and our perspective on breeding from
that time period
um
so yeah start off with basic plant
breeding do yourself a favor just read
you know the first 10 chapters of a
plant breeding book
then go and start really digging into
cannabis and i guarantee you that it
will make your cannabis breeding that
much better because you'll understand
how you can do things what you can do
and what you can't do
and those are important things to know i
mean you have to know
you know
plant breeding is about getting from
point a to point b
you have to understand where you are at
point a
and know where you're going to point b
you don't just get in the car and start
slamming the gas down right and and
close your eyes and hope that you're
going to get to your destination and
that's kind of the way that we've been
breeding cannabis
um if that if you can
take that as an algae
sure a really good answer as well i
think probably do everyone even myself
good to brush up on that sort of thing
so the next question is we commonly hear
people discuss this idea about how
breeders of years gone by maybe people
working in the 90s or even earlier
it was it's commonly discussed that like
they just had such good stock to work
with but then on the counter end of that
argument you hear that well maybe they
were just better breeders so to speak
but part of me thinks that's well there
wasn't as many breeders back then so it
would be weird that like there was such
a high number of breeders that
historically have been considered to
have done some pretty good work what's
your thoughts do you think that the
stock was better or that there was some
interplay of skill involved
no i don't think either of those things
i mean there's good plant breeders then
there's good plant breeders now
i think the stock that people were
working with back then was probably less
refined
not better
there was probably more dogs in any
family any seed population that you
you'd grow there's probably more subpar
plants than there are today
because again the people that are
breeding today they get to benefit from
all the good
choices that people made in the past
and in the past i mean it depends on how
far back you go but i mean we're talking
like 70s
you know
at that point in time people were really
using
um
what i would call like more close to
land race or indigenous or region of
origin populations
and like i said before
those types of
of genetic material that type of genetic
material is usually quite it's a lot
less refined
and so you have a lot of of
a lot more less desirable traits in
those populations so things like
intersex you were talking about you know
for example thai ever a lot of people
know that tai has got
intersex plants and you know david i
spoke a lot with david about tai because
he's probably done more thai breeding
than anyone i know he used to go there
and collect seeds and then bring them
back and do a lot of work and
you know
he said that like that 95 of them were
just trash
right tall weak potency intersex
and you know so if you're growing like a
few thousand thai plants
and you're only going to find
you know less than 100 that are even
potential candidates that's not that's a
lot of work for
um not a lot of reward also thai doesn't
yield anything like it's a tiny little
sparse plant so if you grew 2000 plants
and you're not yielding very much that's
also not a very good
use of your resources right so there's a
reason that we don't grow those plants
anymore and i know that there's
specialists that like to go back and
haul small home growers
and i think that that's fantastic like i
think it's great that people are growing
those things and still playing with
those plants because
even if you're just crossing and
stumbling around like the chances are
you might you might stump there's a
possibility at least that you might
stumble into something good
um
but i think from seriously going to work
a line like that really
you know it's nice because thailand's
just about to legalize medical cannabis
and it's like you really want to go back
to thailand and grow
200 300 000 plants looking for the one
right um
and and so when i talk about cannabis
you know and genetic resources it's like
we have some painful
steps that we have to do through those
processes but
that you know that would be a terrible
thing to have to do grow like 20 acres
of plants just to find the one
because they're not going to yield
anything so from a commercial
perspective it's kind of like how do you
convince your investors that's a good
idea
but if somebody does it and they do find
the one plant that is
just epic for whatever reason for
whatever set of trades
then yeah like at that point in time
we move forward from that new starting
point and then things get better
right and corn apparently i have some
corn breeder friends too and they they
tell me that corn kind of went through
the same thing like there was a lot of
times where there was a lot of crosses
with all these different
corn varieties
and again the vast majority of them were
dogs they were just terrible populations
they were they didn't taste good they
didn't yield well they didn't have good
mold resistance or you know
crop protection traits all that kind of
stuff
but once you once you go through the
hard part of purging all those negative
traits out of the population
you're actually you you end up at a
starting place that's much better than
where we are
and once we get there we'll be able to
turn cannabis into that type of crop
like we were talking about with corn
where you can plant seeds and they all
come up looking
you know i call them bulletproof plants
they come up
they're perfect they got the perfect
chemistry they got the great yield
they've got all the proper resistances
they're all uniform you know everything
that a a true crop producer could want
right like i think that's really
what a plant breeder's goal should be
aside from the discovery and right now
you know we sell
breeders
typically in the cannabis market sell
the variation as a
um
a feature not a flaw
do you know what i mean like it's not
really like if you're growing crops
and you're a you're a farmer you want to
plant all the seeds and they come up
looking the same if you plant
a thousand seeds and all the plants are
different you're not gonna be very happy
right because then you got to go and do
all that phenotypic selection and you're
you don't you lose all the uniformity in
your crop which is a pain in the ass for
many many reasons from harvesting to
marketing to everything
um
and so we got to get to that point in
time where we've actually bred the
plants to be
reliable
seeds so that you can plant a crop and
and the farmer can know that what is on
advertising the description is going to
come up in the field
yeah
really valid point there and some kind
of often under considered um kind of
points you raised there
it's it's a shame but it's just part of
this evolution and you know
like everybody wants to be a breeder
it's like a lot of people think that
like
okay i'm i've been growing five years so
now i'm a breeder and it's like no
you're not it's a totally different set
of skills yeah you got to be a grower to
be able to to appreciate the minutia of
the characteristics of the plant and
look and understand what you're seeing
but really if you want to be a breeder
go learn how to be a breeder it's not
hard
right it just takes time and and it's a
set of heuristics that you have to
understand and methodologies that you
have to understand it's not difficult
stuff to grasp it's not like
you have to be some super special crazy
person to do it you don't
but you do have to put in the time you
know just like you don't pick up a
guitar and then like start touring with
metallica
right
yeah very good analogy and i mean on the
point of being a good breeder a question
i always like to ask the guests
what are some if any attributes you look
for in a male that you think are a sign
of quality or will help with the project
well i'm going to flip it back right to
the same thing i said before about males
i think males are a detriment to
breeding drug cannabis because they
don't match the morphology and the
chemistry
um that the female plants use so
you know i am really doing a lot more
work these days on i'll do preservation
run if i have a population and i do a
preservation i'll open pollinate it
using the males
and then i select my females from once
i've open pollinated the males i know
that i've got all the genes from the
plants right from the entire population
you cross all the males to all the
females you that's that's what's called
an open pollination
and all the genetic diversity is then
preserved that goes in the freezer or
the fridge
then you take your females and you start
selecting
like i said for
traits of interest on any given size of
the cross so
you know you ask me what are important
traits i'm going to put it back to you
and say what are important traits for
you right
you know
flavor yield potency
or i'm not going to say potency but can
have my profiles because you might be
selecting for
you know thcv and against thc it's not
all about the drug
or at least the thc the recreational
drug
there's all these other compounds
that are really have important potential
medical uses and so
if you identify that compound in two
female plants you cross them together
and now you've got a population that's
more likely to have that trait in it
and then you can start adding in
you know stature or morphology or plant
architecture or
flavor or color or you know cannabinoid
profile or whatever it is
resistance to powdery mildew resistance
to molds resistance to pests like
all of those types of traits especially
the last three
they're impossible to breed for in
closets you just can't do it
you have to be grown on a field with
disease pressure and selecting plants in
the environment that you're going to be
growing them and i think that those
kinds of traits like the things that are
really important to growers
have kind of been left out of
um
the agendas of plant breeders because
let's face it everybody's been chasing
flavor and potency
right really above everything else and i
think even you look at the basic
architecture of of some of these the
plant the plant architecture i call it
or the stature or the or the structural
morphology of the plant you look at some
of these new hybrids coming out of
california and their statures are
terrible right like these plants you
have to support them you got to stake
them you got to grow them in nets
because they can't support themselves
with the weight of the flower the stems
are all tiny little thin
things that you you put them in a room
with any kind of powdery mildew issue or
greenhouse and they're they're turning
the powdery mildew and mold
so all those traits that have been
ignored like we really need to start
breeding for those things because
again from an industry there's two sides
and i call them
i look at them as competing interests
but it's i call them growers plants and
smokers plants
right the plant the plants that the
grower wants to grow are typically not
the plants that the smokers want to
smoke
right because the they've kind of got
competing in
interest the grower wants the big one
that's bulletproof you know it's it's
mold resistant it's powdery mildew
resistant it can
it doesn't matter if mites bite it like
it just keeps going it's got these big
thick leaves or whatever the traits are
to keep the mites at bay and the same
with like root aphids or anything i mean
we could be talking about any part of
the plant here
but
that's really what as a breeder you need
to deliver a plant because they're your
customer the customer is not your
customer is not the smoker your customer
is a seed
purveyor is the grower right and so you
need to be serving his agenda
but
also his agenda is to have a marketable
product that he can sell on the market
if you give him a bulletproof plant that
sucks to smoke you're not really also
not doing any flavors right
so
it's really about
balancing the wishes the goals and the
growers versus the goals of the smokers
and ideally you can create a plant that
caters to both that's a lot of work and
i don't think that there's
any plant breeders on the planet really
with cannabis that are at that point yet
where we've got
plants that do both
you know um
again prohibition has kicked us in the
teeth of the last 40 years 50 years we
haven't been able to make any any
progress 60 years right we haven't
really if you look at the genetic
progress that
crops like wheat and corn have undergone
in the past 60 years
their lights they're light years ahead
of where we are
because we just haven't had we've been
kept out of the system they wouldn't let
us play in the game right
every time he tried to set up a row the
cops would show up so
in the un's un's in the united states
are running around the world paying
people to cut down the other weed it's
it's been a pretty hard time for
cannabis for the last 60 years
yeah undeniably so
i think the next question admittedly is
one of those ones where it's like a kind
of like a how long is a bit of string
question but a lot of growers and
breeders often ask the question
what is sort of the minimum number of
seeds you'd want to run through to feel
like you had a reasonably good idea of
what was in the gene pool so to speak
and so i'd love to hear your thoughts on
that
well it depends on the number of cheats
that traits that you're tr you're
chasing
we would when we would do a cross down
in california the minimum we had these
uh nursery trays that are called 72 cell
nursery trays it fits in a 10 inch by 20
inch standard nursery tray and it has
72 cells
and we would start those and that's
enough to get a good
excuse me a good initial look at the
population
and depending on what you see in that
you might find an incredible plant you
might even find a plant that's a breeder
you might realize that the population
sucks or you might decide let's grow
another
10 times what we grew or another five
times what we grew
right but i i kind of feel like
you know i'd like to do more but just
because of
this is like a good size for starting
you know it was like it was an easy
thing to put in our inner production
system
um so it's not ideal but it's it's a
pretty good idea to get a good idea you
got to remember also
most people are breeding from like three
five or 10 seeds not 100 or 72 or you
know 500
so 72 is a lot better than we've done in
the past that does doesn't mean it's
close to ideal but it's it's all about
being able to
move your project forward
and balancing with
you know the resources that you have
available right it costs money to grow
plants
right it takes time there's an
opportunity cost to growing plants
because you could be growing other
plants
right and truthfully i got so many
populations of seeds it's like i'm never
going to get through them all
right so
um
it's about prioritizing them and
sometimes you make a cross and you're
like well that was that was great and
but now i need to grow the next
generation of those plants and the stuff
that's in your vault waiting to get
sprouted you know you don't even have a
chance to go back to it because
every time you grow a new line you might
add a new population or a new project to
your goal
your set of breeding goals so
yeah
72 was what we were doing it was a good
start like i said
yeah that seems like a pretty pretty
nice number to start with for sure it's
it's far dude it's far less less than is
ideal like i'll tell you that off right
off the bat i mean i'd want to grow a
thousand if i could but
a thousand plants sent to the lab at 50
bucks a pop that's a thousand dollar
bill
right
so
it's probably worth more than the crops
worth right so
you know it's all about balancing
your resources your space available and
and your priorities and there's no magic
numbers
yeah yeah i understand
so we've been alluding to it all episode
but time to get into it some people may
or may not be aware but you're involved
in the first case of cannabis having a
patent on it i'd love to hear how you
got involved in this initially yeah well
the first so
the first they weren't the first
patents involving cannabis they were the
first utility patents involving plants
and truthfully i had nothing to do with
the patent side of it i worked for a
research company and i did the plant
breeding and the
ip development and the patents
came from
more or less the lawyers of the group
um there's certain things that i can
talk about that i that's public this has
been publicly disclosed and there's
unfortunately stuff that i can't because
i'm i was under contract with these
folks and i signed a non-disclosure
agreement but yeah there was patents
done on work
that i did on these plants and
my name is not affiliated affiliated
with those patents at all
again
people get really freaked out when you
start talking about
patenting plants
these weren't
patents on a specific plant they were
patents on the use of a specific plant
it might seem like a like splitting
hairs but it actually has a big
difference
plants plant patents per se like
specific
plant patents
are only really valid in a couple of
countries one being yours and the other
one being the united states so australia
and the united states are i think
two of the only global
um
justice systems that are legal systems
that actually recognize patents on
plants
in canada they don't recognize
patents on higher organisms
although you can patent the cell of a
plant which is kind of bizarre so if
somebody has a plant with that cell in
it
i guess you can in some way try to
enforce intellectual property rights on
them it's pretty difficult
um
everybody's heard the story about
monsanto going after this poor organic
farmer that grew seeds
and his seeds were contaminated by
monsanto the story that most people
don't understand which is the truth
was that this farmer
planted his soybeans right beside
monsanto's crop that was next door
and he went and actively collected all
the seeds from the plants
right along the border
and then grew those plants
and subjected to them those those plants
had a gene in them that caused a
resistance to a chemical an agricultural
chemical called
glyphosate or roundup
and roundup is a a herbicide it
essentially kills plants that don't have
this specific gene in them the gene came
from a bacteria
and then they put it into this plant and
then once the plants had the gene they
became resistant to this
thing so percy schmeiser who was the
farmer
somehow the media really painted him as
a bit of a hero this poor organic farmer
against big old bad monsanto and don't
get me wrong i have no love for monsanto
but the truth of the matter was is that
this guy actively went after
using their genetic technology
and he wasn't growing organically he
exposed those all those seeds to this
agrochemical
and then in the process he essentially
stole their ip he took the gene
um and he went to court and he lost
so
but somehow in the media that became oh
this poor organic farmer he's being
bullied by the big guy and i think that
that's probably a bit of a
a narrative that was created because
there's a certain segment of the
population that's
against genetic modifications and you
know
the way that we do genetic modifications
now
compared to the way that we did them
20 30 years ago is really different
we've become you know back then it was
probably closer to like
you know doing surgery with a with a a
japanese sword rather than you know a
scalpel
um and nowadays we're very very skilled
we have all these new technologies that
allow us to
go in and create specific changes to
dna like like you're talking about
heavenly with crispr
and those things kind of are just by the
way side
so
anyway i think just to clear it up i
think you know there's a lot of people
running around online saying that i was
patenting all the world and i was trying
to steal the whole world strains truth
is i had nothing to do with it other
than breeding the plants
i don't my name's not on the patents i
don't get any intellectual property
rights from them i don't get any
royalties from it i really have
absolutely nothing to do with it and i
don't work with that group anymore and i
haven't for a number of years
um
so so yeah it's kind of a it's just kind
of a funny thing
i was really you know i started working
with the group because
they were quite patient focused and i
had an opportunity to
have someone build us our dream lab to
really start screening uh large
populations of cannabis in a way
with like height what we call brute
force
um
chemical breeding i mean it's it's like
i said it's expensive to grow a lot of
plants and then send every single one of
them to the laboratory
and have full
you know
full terpene
and cannabinoid and we also looked at
other chemicals as well that influence
smell and flavor
and
it was a learning experience for me and
i really enjoyed it like i really
there were some good folks in the group
and we created some really cool plants
that had unique chemistry cbdv thcv
you know cbd type 2 plants with altered
cannabinoid ratios and really
interesting terpene profiles
and all that stuff was able to go to a
series of dispensaries and companies
that were growing it
and it was really really a lot of fun
and it was really gratifying to be able
to create these
you know these plants that we'd always
talked about
and deliver them to patients
um
there was a few people in the community
that were pretty upset about the idea of
cannabis patents being granted
and they did a lot of effort to
create a narrative where people thought
that you know
that we were trying to steal the world
and nothing could be more further from
the truth
you know the only things that were
patented were
new unique combinations of cannabinoids
that and terpenes that had that didn't
exist before like they were new plants
right they really were
new
inventions right
um and when we did that i think that's
the lawyers for the group we're like oh
we need to protect these things and
well i think that that's also a thing
that you know people kind of want to say
ah it's unfair that you can patent a
plant or a life and that's like you're
an organism that occurred in nature well
dude these things didn't occur in nature
right like these plants are not you're
not going to go into any population and
find a plant with this set of chemistry
they just don't exist they're new
and you don't spend
many hundreds of thousands of dollars or
more
doing research into any kind of
technology or plant or
breeding program or you know you're
designing a new computer or whatever it
is it's like you don't design you don't
spend money in research and development
if
the people that are paying for the
research and development can't get a
return on their investment right that's
just the way it is
um
and patents aren't the only way that you
like we said that you can get
intellectual property rights on plants
there's these
things called pbrs or plant breeder
rights registrations through upof which
is the
union for the protection of plant
varieties which is a global organization
like i said before it kind of oversees
the intellectual property matters of
plants right like if you if you spent 15
years to make a new apple variety and
it's let's just call it again granny
smith or whatever
you know you ha you should have the
rights to reap the commercial rewards
for a period of time
and part of that system
exists
that yeah you get the commercial rights
but you have to make the plant variety
available to any other breeder in the
world
and they can take that variety and use
your work to make something better
right and
and that better plant even though you
have your commercial rights for 20 years
or 15 years or whatever it is depending
on the jurisdiction
it might be in five years somebody's
created a better variety of yours anyway
than yours anyway
uh using your work right and the reason
it's set up like that is so that
humanity benefits from
you know it's a communal
development where the whole world gets
to benefit from a new technology yeah
you might come up with new technology
and you get some rights to a few years
to use it but everybody else in the in
the in the industry also gets to take it
and then start using it in their own
breeding programs and so it's kind of a
trade-off um
anyway it's it's a funny thing because
you know i've had i've had death threats
online about it
right
and it's just bizarre right because it's
like
it's like read the patent my name's not
even on it like i really have nothing to
do it i don't i don't get a penny from
it and you're threatening my life
because
of some perceived
notion that somebody took something from
you which couldn't even be further from
the truth it's like
you know anyway it's just it's just
weird it's just what it is but hey man
that's uh
you know part of the thing that's going
on from
this transition from the old world to
the new world you know i've been doing
this for a long time
um
i've been growing cannabis for 30 years
and so
you know i've worked with people all
over the world and all these different
really you know like like i said
we've all the people that we've talked
about
these people are all colleagues and
friends of mine right
and so
when when you get new people in the
industry that come in and they've been
around for two years and they're
accusing you of stealing from the
community
it's kind of like go [__] yourself
you know it's like you're johnny come
lately
i've dedicated my life to this kind of
work and you're telling me that i'm
stealing from you like give me a break
it's ridiculous
um and truthfully the reason that we did
the work is so that we we could provide
these new types of medicine to patients
so
i don't i don't feel bad about it you
know
um
i don't know if i would seek patents
myself on plants but again it doesn't
apply in my market because because in
canada
that's not how you seek intellectual
property protection
it is one way you can do it in the
states and you can do it in australia
but um
it's not something that interests me
so
yeah no what a what a comprehensive
answer to a question i think a lot of
people have been interested in hearing
the backstory behind another
similar question you hear discussed in
that same vein which
i've always been interested in but quite
skeptical of the truth behind it is you
hear people discuss this idea that if
someone were to be able to say obtain a
pattern right or some sort of patent
over
a very primordial sort of cannabis
genetics which i don't even know if
that's possible that they could then
like pull the plug on anyone growing a
distant descendant of that so to give it
some context like if somehow i got a
pattern for the original northern lights
the fear is that like i could claim
infringement on anyone who's growing
anything with like northern lights in
the genetics do you think that's that's
that's not true anybody that says that
doesn't understand how patents work and
patent and intellectual property rights
work
um
when you get a plant patent in the
states or australia
you get
the rights to that one clone that one
specific genotype and it has to be very
described and usually they've done a dna
fingerprint profile if somebody else
takes that plant and cross it to
something else
it's it's gone it's out in the open
right you still can't grow their one
plant that's registered but you can make
a hybrid of it and grow that
so
it's kind of a like this idea that
somebody's patenting primary the other
thing about patenting
varieties if you want to call them that
it's actually a great little term
is that you can't patent anything like
one of the key criteria for for getting
a patent granted is that your patent
your invention this is what a patent is
as a protection on an invention your
invention has to be novel and that just
means new
right so you actually have to have
something that's new
you can't come along and like
take something from the market and
patent it that doesn't work right they
would never they'd never grant the
patent and even if they did grant the
patent
right the pate
patent is just really a piece of paper
that says i own this thing right i got i
got this patent now on this thing well
someone can say i'm going to challenge
your patent so they can take you to
court
right and then there's a court case and
the whole process that goes on about
deciding who actually owns the patent
and so if if you're granted a patent
on a plant
and somebody else says
oh hey i've got the same plant or
whatever
you you have to sue the person that's
violating your rights right so it's
actually a defensive strategy like if
you own the patent you're not the one
getting sued you're the one that's doing
the suing but when you start suing
somebody
it could be ruled that your patents
invalid
right so it has to be worth your while
to go after someone right it really has
to be affecting your bottom line
right because you always open up
yourself to the chance that the court
rules in the other person's favor and
you lose your patent rights
right so
a patent is not like an impenetrable
bulletproof vest
it's a stake in the ground
like you know when people stake mining
sites right it's like you're planting a
flag in the ground and saying this space
is mine
right and really
whether that space is yours
is really can be a matter for the courts
right it doesn't necessarily mean that
your claim is true
it just means that you got it by the guy
that says yeah that seems like a legit
claim
right so
take that for what it's worth
yeah i had a sneaking suspicion that
that might be the case so that that's
good to hear your input on that one i
think we've got some kind of more less
technical questions as we're kind of on
the tail end of things so i'm interested
to hear the answers to some of these but
one that's
came up a few times from our guest when
i put the call out if anyone had any
questions how did you get the name
chimera
i just chose it i mean it was i was
studying dna at the time in genetics and
a chimera it's actually a funny question
because years after i kind of chose the
name i actually became a
chimera through surgery a chimera is a
it means different things in greek
mythology it was a mythical beast that
was a lion
with the tail of the lion was a serpent
and there was a like a goat head or two
goat heads growing out of the back of
the animal and so really it was this
scary
mythical beast that was composed of
three different monsters really is what
it was supposed to be
um but in in dna in the dna world a
chimera is
something that has
dna from two different organisms okay so
any different tissue like if for example
if someone had a heart
transplant they got a heart from
somebody else they'd become a chimera
because now they had
an organ of a different type of dna
growing within their body right which
satisfy the condition of what a chimera
is
for me the word i kind of felt like the
word was like
a um
it was
it it to me what it meant was a
combination a fusion of science and
cannabis which back then at the time was
completely unheard of right like i
didn't know anybody in my cannabis
community that was into science they
just didn't care
and i was so interested in nerding out
about the plant and chemical analysis
and the genetics of it um that to me it
was more of a symbol for the fusion of
understanding of science and
understanding of chemistry
and i didn't ever intend for it to be
a name that stuck it was just a name
that i chose to register on an internet
web board at one point in time right
um
and so it's stuck and i never you know i
i never changed my name on the internet
i didn't
i always was the type of person that
kind of i would just say what i wanted
to and if you didn't like what i was
saying well too bad but i'm not gonna
say something and then change my
identity so that i don't have to have
the consequences of what i said right
um
to me my word means something and so i
always just kept the same name over like
it's been you know a long time now or 25
years at least on the internet
which is bizarre to even consider that's
true but um
yeah so that's what it meant to me and
then later on i had i developed a
condition called keratoconus and i had
to have two uh cornea transplants
and so i've got
corneas from two different people so i
actually see the world through
the eyes of two people that have left
this world
um
becoming a chimera funnily enough
yeah wow what a real life sort of twist
to the name
yeah it was bizarre
i didn't even realize it until it
happened and then i was like hey i guess
i'm a chimera now
there you go so
the next question we had was
how do you store your seeds what's your
what's your method for long-term
germination viability
uh mostly just the fridge four degrees
celsius and a very expensive scientific
incubator that i bought at an auction
for a song
um
and that suits me very very well um
again taking cues from i actually came
up with my i decided to put them at four
degrees celsius because
there was all this discussion on whether
freezing cycles damage the seed
and i you know
i i figured getting the closest possible
to freezing without actually freezing
was probably best for these things
water's densest point is at four degrees
celsius
and so to me that seemed like
the optimum point to be storing seeds
and and later when i you know
started spending a lot more time with
david and we kind of you know we
once we became good friends we kind of
just opened the doors to each other's
not knowledge like it's like i taught
him everything i know and he taught me
everything he knew
and we just kind of had this open
exchange of ideas and and sharing
techniques and stuff and he's been
actually storing seeds and under the
exact same conditions
for
over 25 years
and when we were cataloging this massive
collection a couple years ago
we we actually pulled some out and did
some germination tests on these you know
25 year old seeds and we were pulling
out 25 year old seeds that were
germinating at like 80 90 percent
right so that's perfectly sufficient for
i think the time scale of the rest of my
life
um i think seed fridges are fine you can
now do
i've got a friend in that was working in
spain name he's a sicilian guy named
salvatore cassano and he started doing
some cryopreservation on seeds and that
worked out pretty well
um like a deep freeze in liquid nitrogen
or sorry you you actually don't put the
seeds in the liquid nitrogen you store
them in the gas above the liquid so it's
not quite as cold
um
and i thought that was really cool and
so
i started looking into whether we could
freeze tissue cultures and
you can like there's all these different
protocols online for hops and other
plants on how to
actually freeze shoot tips
and there's a real trick to it
there's a few tricks to it and it's
quite difficult but it's actually
possible
again it's an expense
right it costs money to do it and
maintain the tissue cultures at that
temperature for
extended periods of time but it's
totally possible
so yeah you can freeze it you can use
crop preservation to freeze material
you can use cryo preservation to freeze
seeds and you can keep seeds in the
fridge for
a long time and as long as they're
properly dried
you can do things like flushing them
with oxygen or not oxygen i'm sorry you
eliminate the oxygen from the
environment where the seeds are stored
um like you know specific little vials
or something or nitrogen container
nitrogen containers where you've pushed
out the
the oxygen gas you essentially flood it
with with nitrogen and then you seal it
um and those can extend the seed life
even further
so i don't think you know this a lot of
people get all bent out of shape it's
like oh you're selling these seeds and
they're 12 years old it's like just put
them in the dirt and see you know don't
worry about how old they are if they
germinate
then they're germinating and if they
don't i'll send you more right
that's kind of the way i feel about it
like i'm not you know i don't obviously
i don't retail seeds myself we sell them
through legal channels and in europe but
i always tell my retailers
if you have problems and people calling
and complaining just give them more i'll
replace them right like it's not
i kind of i said at one point in time
online it's like i'm not just giving you
seeds with a germination guarantee it's
like if you don't like the plants tell
me
right come back to me tell me what's
wrong i'll send you more i'm gonna send
you seeds until you're happy
right that's what it's that's that's why
we do it right i want people to grow the
things that we find interesting and
enjoy them
and if they if they some reason grow
them and they feel like that we've let
them down and they they have they've had
a subpar experience
dude i'll make sure that the retailers
send them the seeds until they're
they're happy
right because that's what i want from
our customers that's why that's why i do
the work that's why i love working with
cannabis is because it makes me happy
and i want
other people to experience that same joy
through our seeds
yeah really really beautiful sentiment
around the plant for sure
so the next question i had was what
style of growing do you like to do or
maybe you could phrase it as what style
of growing do you like to advocate for
like cocoa soilless soil where do you
stand
it's you know
to me it's six to one half a dozen the
other i think all growers are gonna find
they're all or they're all gonna find
their own unique thing
i think if i had my druthers
live
organic soil
um
respectful of the plant respectful of
the environment respectful of your
resources around you you know i don't
like the idea of people growing with
tons of salts and that running off into
groundwater or
you know people flushing nutrients down
the toilet i mean that's all [__] to
me like it's really not okay to be doing
that to the planet we don't need to be
damaging the planet just because we're
growing some cannabis
it should be able to be grown in line
with nature
but
you know if you have to grow in a
there's reasons why you would want to
grow in a sterile hydroponic system
for you know if you're in a certain
commercial greenhouse or whatever
there's lots of there's lots of ways to
grow cannabis and i'm not really against
or for any of them i think if people can
be sustainable about it and healthy
about it and you're not spraying like
aggro chemicals on the plants like
pesticides and fungicides and all that
kind of stuff i think that that's really
to me that those are the important
things
um
we did a bunch of work on different
cultivation varieties with our because
again we had this lab in the
standardized cultivation environment
both greenhouse and indoor
we could run the same cultivars over and
over and over again
in different iterate like so we'd have a
you know it was it was large had a
couple hundred lights so and we had like
20 light rooms for example so
every week you'd be harvesting a
different room so rather than putting
making one room emoji cushion one room
train wreck and run
room blue dream we would run a single
four by eight table of each cultivar in
every room and harvest it every week
and then those samples would all go to
the laboratory
we would do random sampling from the
crops or represent representative
sampling from the crops and each crop
would get a lab test and so what it
allowed us to do is go back and look at
the environmental data
and see oh look there's a you know there
was a
humidity spike or a temperature spike at
this week and look how it changed the
terpene profile we would vary the diets
on the plant we would feed them you know
chemical fertilizers we would feed them
organic fertilizers we'd feed them
chemical fertilizers with a biostimulant
or organic fertilizer or the
biostimulant and you'd see like oh look
when you use
when you use organic
when you use organics to organic methods
with biostimulants
the
uh the terpenes would go up and the
cannabinoids would drop down a little
bit
when you were growing them more or less
hydroponically with chemical salts very
little organic inputs the the
cannabinoids would spike and the th or
the the terpene contents would crash a
little bit
right so
there's all there they're just tool to
me it's just they're just tools in the
toolbox
it's really about what you're trying to
do if you're making really beautiful
extracts
and flavors important i'd be growing
organically with biostimulants right
if you're looking to make thc diamonds
right these you've probably seen those
and that kind of product
yeah
then
use chemical salts as long as you can do
it in a way that's not damaging the
planet
right
yeah good answer good answer
so this was more of a personal question
i was wondering
do you feel like there's
a compromise between big yields fast
flower times and inherent quality i
guess what i'm wondering is
in a world filled with these ultra small
yielding exotic plants so to speak and
exotic is like you know a poor code word
for like cookies and things like that
sure i feel like there does still exist
a plant that's like big yielding fast
flowering high quality or
at some point you have to kind of
compromise on some of those traits
we have to compromise today because
those combinations of traits don't exist
together but i firmly believe that
through proper breeding strategies and
especially with the aid of genomics and
the laboratory chemical analysis that we
can get the best of both worlds
right that's the joy and the goal of the
breeding
is that
it's all about what we can produce for
the future right
um
and really those things are just
combinations of traits and there's no
reasons that we can't just shuffle the
deck and put all those combinations of
traits together in a specific way yeah
right now the ogs and the things like
that the cookies they're small
right but you can
you can embig in them maybe is the good
word
through uh through selection and
breeding right you can improve their
yield you can improve their
uh their stature you can improve their
resistance and that's that stuff is it's
gonna take time right like these aren't
this does not make a couple of crosses
and boom next year we got a huge cookies
right this these will be like five ten
year projects
where you learn to understand
oh these are the genes that are
important for bigness in cannabis and
then you reshuffle those genes reach off
of the deck and screen
and look for plants that are that have
the the genes for bigness
and the genes for
whatever quality metrics we
we ascribe to the plants together right
it's the combination of those things
and like i said because of linkage that
might be a little bit difficult but
with the right
with you know with being able to scree
it's really about plants it's about
having to be able to screen the plant
numbers having access to the lab data
and being able to afford to do it that's
really those are the barriers
right so it's not impossible but
it's also not easy
yeah right so
i was just gonna say a bit of a random
one we got submitted by the guests but
they they noticed that um somehow you
ended up on one of the george cevante
dvds about how to grow marijuana and
they were wondering what was the
backstory behind that was it just like
coincidental timing you were there or
how'd that go down no george found me
online i guess he was writing a new book
and he was trying to get contributions
from all these people
and he said
oh everybody that he asked about
breeding they said come and talk to
chimera and so he found me
and i he just you know he he sent me an
email one day
and i was like no [__] it's jorge i
didn't know you know i just knew him as
the guy through the books right
the books and the dvds so when he caught
me contacted me i was like right on yeah
i'll uh i'll chat with you and he's like
i want to do this breeding chapter and
i'm thinking you know you're the guy to
do it and so i agreed to
to do the breeding chapter for the book
and he came to
vancouver about six six months later
um
funnily enough it was the the week
before mark emery was busted by the dea
on the charges that got him extradited
to the united states
and so that week before we built a grow
room in the bank across the street from
mark emery's shop
and just for the purpose of the vid i
mean we didn't grow in it but we built
it for the purposes of showing people
how to build a grow room for the video
and i kind of took him around the city
and introduced him to a bunch of people
and he he said to me one day he's like
you got to be in this video and i was
like george i don't want to be in your
video i'm not interested in putting my
face
on the video and he said we'll get you a
mask
and so that was it that was how i ended
up on that video in a weird lions mask
good good backstory and maybe you can
fill us in likewise on this next one
are you able to tell us a little bit
about the [__] morocco you selected from
the moroccan line
yeah she's a bear she's just i don't
know i don't know how moroccan she was
you got to understand it's like you were
saying before
things kind of get modernized because
people bring in
um new genetics right so
what
moroccan originally was i think it came
from turkish hemp because it's just it's
so similar
um
and the cannabinoid contents were really
low for traditional moroccan hash now
obviously over the last 30 years they've
been bringing dutch seeds down there all
the time it's not very far and as you
know i mean moroccan hash is one of the
main major one of the major export
centers for moroccan hash is amsterdam
so there's definitely a lot of back and
forth that people are doing between
business between those two places and i
think as the guys would come up to to
sell their hash
they'd buy some seeds and bring those
back down and those things would get
crossed into
uh the natural populations and over time
they become more modernized so this one
plant that we got there that i pulled
out of the population
it was fat i mean it was like six and a
half weeks seven weeks and it was like
pretty much done but it had this really
strange well it wasn't this
unheard of trait but it used so it put
on so much weight in like week three and
week four like it was bulking up before
other plants were even putting little
cotton balls on the tips of their their
shoes
um
and it used it used so much nitrogen
that if you if you if you stopped
feeding it vegetative food
and then switched to to flowering food
right at 12 12 or when you induced it
into flour by the time you were like the
end of week three or beginning week four
the plant was really yellowing out
significantly
um
and it was doing that because it was
using so much nitrogen to build that
really early floral mass
and
uh
that was a pretty neat trait if you
could you know as soon as i learned that
about the timing of the trade it it
caught me off guard for a couple of
grows
and then finally i was like i'm gonna
hit this thing with with way more
nitrogen than the rest of the plants
early in flower and it managed to stay
green all the way through and the thing
just bulked like crazy
um
really good like we were talking about
growers plants before this one was a
grower's plant
but it had a really nice kind of
raspberry nose to it
um
fruity but like really in that kind of
raspberry flavor class
and she just became something i was like
this thing is actually worth
keeping and worth breeding with so we
did we made a bunch of crosses with it
and she's still around but it's um yeah
that's that's what we're using
there you go a great little explanation
on that one on to the next strain of
yours i'm interested in and we've had a
few people inquire about you even
mentioned it yourself the mental floss
will you ever remake it and what do you
think it was about that lime which made
it so memorable in so many people's
minds
probably the name
it was a great commercial plant it was
for me it was a great commercial plant
um i could i could pull two pounds off
of light no problem and it and the thing
that i really loved about it is it made
these this really really high quality
bubble hash like water hash and even dry
sift was it was incredible but it really
held on to its flavor through the water
process and it made a hash that was just
fantastic i remember bringing it to
amsterdam the first time i met david and
david is an insane hash head
and
our you know our mutual friend bubble
man he was there and he said david you
really got to try this hashish
and pulled it in and there's something i
call the tell or the bubble towel when
when the hatch is of such a high quality
and you put it in the pipe for someone
and they can see the ball when they're
br when they're burning it their eyes
open up and their eyebrows essentially
hit the roof
right because they're so surprised at
the the way that it melts and and the
flavor that comes off of it
and uh you know i put it in dave's bowl
and
he was uh
he definitely gave the bubble tell it
was like you know it was
it was hard for him to not you know to
to be like i can't you know it was hard
for him to not give me respect at that
point in time because not only did he
think i knew what i was talking about i
might have been a lot younger
but um
you know
i had the good quality hash and that's
kind of like the
the secret handshake to get into the
club right if you show up with the great
hash that you've made
yourself um
it's kind of like you're welcome to sit
at the table right
yeah of course
so that's one of the reasons why she's
also got a beautiful color i mean you
can probably see that picture on my
twitter and you might have seen them
online she does this great
lovely rainbow thing when it goes at the
end of flowering the leaves go from
purple to yellow
shades of purple and yellow
all on the same leaf and it's just a
beautiful plant with a beautiful smell
great yield super dense nugs
and so yeah so i've got it'll come back
in in some form i've got tons of
different hybrids of it but i'm really
working on the right combination of
plants for the next release of it
there's still tons of the original i
mean i've got to have there's
there's
you know at least 10 20 000 seeds left
over the first one so
if anybody wants it you can still hop on
board
that's exciting to hear
the next one i wanted to ask about was
in your sassafras cross you use what you
refer to as the superior afghan skunk
would you be able to tell us a little
bit more about that and what made it so
memorable and just superior to the
others in your mind
well it was superior to the others i
think going honestly going back
i probably wouldn't use that plant again
um it was superior than the other afghan
skulls that i had seen because it had a
great growing characteristic and stature
and a nice flower
it was it was old school
weed it wasn't
new school weed right it wasn't it
didn't have that banging
scent profile that a lot of the newer
stuff has
it was great that you could grow it
surreptitiously you know like i could
hand it to commercial growers and they
could put up big growers of it and
not worry about scent that kind of stuff
but i've really moved away from those
plants
um
i tried to move away from those plants
because i think that we've
graduated out of that phase of having to
grow
low set
plants
right i went into this hydrostar once
and when i first moved to vancouver i
went into this hider store and you know
some of my girlfriends
brought me in to meet this plant
pathologist girl that was working there
and they introduced me and she said oh
you grew you invented the free you bred
the frostbite didn't you and i said yeah
i did actually and she was like that
plant almost got me [__] busted you
know she was so limited about how much
that plant stank right
and and it was like you know i was like
yeah that's kind of what
we select for now right like that's
that's what we want
um
get some carbon filters so
but yeah
yeah
sorry sorry please go on no just she
relayed the story about her landlord
standing outside and she was trying to
get rid of them it was
you know grower problems right
that's it right thankfully carbon
filters are pretty good these days
yeah yeah
so the next one
the c4 strain this had always caught my
eye because obviously the name it's very
close to the c5 which is a notable clone
a northern lights haze however the
genetics couldn't be more different on
paper a cotton candy crossed by shishka
berry was this an intentional play on
words because you saw some similarities
or purely coincidental no the c4 for me
meant fast and explosive there was a
kind of porsche porsche carrera 4 and
that was really what was named after
that and the
idea that it was so fun i mean it hit
this thing also hit like week six and
seven and just exploded
um and i i really thought that it was i
still do feel like it was a big
improvement on either of the two parent
plants like when they came together
you know one plus one definitely equaled
three
um it had the best of both really rock
hard flowers i remember i had this one
one grower i think he went by the name
reggie the roddy and he used to grow the
stuff
and just turn the the entire crop into
hash
and he had this the hash was white like
it was beautiful it was the most
light-colored hash i've ever seen
and you'd put a flame to it and it would
just turn to a liquid right away
um
and so yeah i'll i'll probably do
something with that in the f when i want
to get some space to actually grow into
we've actually got an opportunity now
um with two different 20 plus acre legal
farms that are within an hour of where i
live now
and they've both offered me as much
space as i want to kind of play over
there
and just screen for things and we're
gonna start you know try to improve the
auto lines that we're working with and
really try to make
true to type
um
auto plants you know a lot of times
you'll buy like these days you'll buy
auto plant that's like auto cookies or
auto whatever the name is
and they don't actually smell anything
like the named plant right because autos
are a little bit of a
a tricky thing to work with breeding
wise that you have to breed them in a
slightly different way you can't keep
backup clones
or most people can't keep backup clones
um so because they're just difficult to
keep alive in that in the clonal state
unless you're using a specific tissue
culture
regimen
so we're going to try to use genomics
and
you know classical breeding techniques
to actually make auto versions of
all the plants that you you know that
you'd want to have on the market because
that kind of thing in canada would be
really ideal for
the new um
the new industry where people are
growing purely for
you know for example rosin extracts
right you want to have like
a few acres or more
ideally
of plants that are going to fall that
are going to flower fast
uh we have a relatively short season
here in in canada compared to say
california we can't grow you know you
got to pretty much be done and out of
the ground by
mid to
late september in most parts of the
country
and even going that long you might be
well into the wet season so you're
risking
you know molds and all the bad things
that come with rain
um and flowering cannabis together
outside
so the idea is to like really try to
breed those things um
and screen a lot of the old stuff i mean
you just can't i've got so many seeds
like
you can't grow them
you know all indoors are in the
greenhouses we just don't have that much
room so
a couple of 20 acre plots is pretty
attractive to
uh to look at for screening right the
question is will everything finish in
time but you just you don't know until
you do it so
yeah sure sure
so maybe a bit of a hard one to answer
but out of all the various lines you've
worked thus far
which are you most proud of or most
pleased with the results
it's kind of like asking a father what
kid child is their favorite
um honestly the most proud
one
of the last couple years has been
this beta-caryophyllene cbd plant that i
bred for the group down in california
that was subsequently patented
um
cbdv is a chemical everybody knows about
thc thcv but cbdv is
um
a chemical that's even more effective
for epilepsy than cbd
and so we created a variety when i found
the the propyl plants and started
breeding them into the cbd background
we ended up finding plants that were
like roughly 50 50 percent of the
cannabinoid fraction was cbd and the
other 50 was cbdv with like very little
thc in it
so it had zero recreational or fun
potential it was not that kind of
program
um but the idea hidden came to me at one
point in time actually i was at the icrs
listening some speakers talk there about
beta carryoff lean
and
they mentioned that beta carotene was a
um
it had anti-spasmodic properties
and i was like damn that's perfect i
need to breed a beta-caryophyllene
terpene profile into the cbdv line
um
and then i started looking at what other
terpenoids could also have
anti-spasmodic defect and linole which
is from lavender
also has some anti um
convulsive properties
and so i was like you know what i'm just
gonna try and find a plant that i can
stack with cbd cbdv and if i can make it
have a terpene profile that's like
beta-carotene and little rich
then that's probably going to be a good
plant for
kids with epilepsy or right that was
kind of the the genesis is like how do
you take a medicine like cbd that all
these children are using for
you know
what is it lennox gusto syndrome or
whatever it's called
um these epileptive disorders for
children and they're really massive
these these these kids have epilepsy so
bad that it leads to these massive
developmental problems i don't know if
you know the story of
charlotte figgy but i mean
you know she she passed this year and
she was just a kid like she was a baby
really
um
and it's just horrible watching these
kids go through this stuff and if you
can make a medicine that actually works
for them
that's pretty awesome and so i'm not in
the medical testing space like that's
really i don't consider that my job
i kind of see my job as
let's make the plants and then let the
doctors figure out what's going to work
for the kids
but
when when we cross the cbd v plant that
i'd made into
the plants for the desired
terpene profile
we had to flip through a couple of
generations but after a couple of
generations this one plant popped out
and boom it had the right cannabinoids
and it had the right terpenoids
and it was really like the in my opinion
and maybe i'm biased in saying this but
i think that in my opinion it was really
one of the first
plants that was made
so that you had the cannabinoids that
were effective for
are potentially effective for this one
condition
and then you surrounded it with an
entourage effect of molecules
that that had the you know that also
had
been shown in the scientific literature
to do that same kind of thing right
and uh it just to me it was like it kind
of epitomized that new kind of potential
that what we could do with cannabis
where you're creating a plant with the
idea that it's actually optimized for a
specific condition right a specific
ailment
um
and so when it popped out and it worked
it was you know it started off as a
breeding goal like can we do this it was
a breeding experiment
and when we found the plant it was like
man it was just a really good feeling
you know
um
so yeah i hope i hope that plant ended
up making it into the hands of people
of children that could use it
yeah what a powerful and fulfilling
feeling that must have been at the end
of it all
yeah well i mean you know we've always
been breeding for how plants make you
feel and there's nothing wrong with that
it's just a totally different it's a
different type of cannabis it's like
okay i'm gonna make some cannabis that's
not for the stoners
right and
to be able to create a plant with
potential therapeutic benefit that's
gonna help children that are really
suffering is like
jesus dude it's so rewarding like i
can't even tell you how good it made you
feel when it pat when it popped up
right it's like yeah let's let's let's
figure out how to make more plants like
this
that have no
fun potential right
you know because it's great i like
making the fun plants too i mean i'm all
about it right
but um
it's just another it's just another
thing to help a different group of
people right
yeah so so
getting towards the tail end of things
just so you know i
don't want to keep you too late um
are there any bc varieties that you feel
don't really get the mention they
deserve ones that kind of fly under the
radar and the add-on to that would be
are there any maybe older school
breeders who similarly don't really get
the recognition you think they deserve
yeah there's probably tons of them i
mean i think most people i try to be
pretty good about propping the guys that
i
like i mean i really like jaime from
residence deeds there's a few other
people over working with otto's in spain
i've got a good friend named roberto
who's who has a seat company i think
he's actually folded the company but
they were doing grass-o-matic
and they were they're kind of neat
little hybrids
um
i think anybody that's working you know
jaime from resin seeds has worked with
catatonic
my friend salvatore cassano that is not
a drug he's a he works more with like
hemp and cbg varieties and he's an
incredible agronomist and
you know there's a there's a lot of
people out there
that are doing things just quietly and
you know i just met another guy
yesterday and he lives just on an island
just off the coast here
and um
he's doing a whole bunch of interesting
work and i'd never even met him i didn't
even know he existed so
you know just i'd like to reach out to
all those people and meet them and then
you know see how we can support them and
how we can help make their work better
um
in terms of the vancouver island stuff
our industry out here got really went
through a a
not a great phase with all the purple
cushions i mean everybody liked it you
know the market certainly loves it
but
the genetic diversity amongst the
growers is like everybody started
growing the purple and the paint kush
and baba kush and you know at least we
have these plants here people call like
death bubba and all these different
variations on the kushes they're really
all the same flavor
class they're
they're they're different variations of
high limonene uh high mir mircine and
high beta karyophiline plants
um
so kind of in that og master kush family
of plants
but um yeah we've got the market here
has really gone through a period where
it's like no i it's like if you want to
grow and sell weed everybody was growing
and selling kush
and it wiped out a lot of the genetic
diversity
and that was all happening right around
the time that i kind of left for
california and so
when i went to california we did this
like i said this massively deep dive and
analyzing all these different types of
cannabis from all over the market
and in the process learned a lot about
the different types of chemistry's
terpene profiles that can exist
and so that's kind of really one of my
things right now is that i'm trying to
bring all those things back
and
re-diversify the market here
right so that it's more than just that
one
flavor profile and you know like we were
talking about before we're trying to
bring back some of these
milder varieties of cannabis right which
again sounds counterintuitive to people
but
it's all about
providing the the breadth and diversity
of the cannabis species
so that anybody that wants to use
cannabis can have something that they
enjoy
right and i don't have to like you know
like if i want to give something to my
mom like if i gave her a toke of an og
dude she'd be on the couch for a week
you know
so
having these lighter
lighter
kind of more
social varieties
for certain population groups like you
know a gift to grandmas and stuff that
don't want us that don't want to get
blasted and they just want to have their
pain taken away i think that those
things are really important out on the
market too
and it's uh we're facing a little bit of
a challenge with growers and with
distributors who don't you know they
think that they know better
and maybe they do but i i don't think
that the the distribution people know
better you know
they just know that the only thing that
sells is high thc stuff so they only
want high thc stuff well it's kind of
like having a liquor store that only
sells whiskey
right you can't get a beer or a bottle
of wine
and it's not really a diverse market
yeah
it's it's sad but true
um
what are your thoughts and experiences
on hawaiian strains and the mexican
strains in general i know you've got a
good sort of um experience base with
them but the thing which interests me is
that you commonly hear about thais and
southeast asian lines being all the rage
these days no one ever really mentions
mexican do you think they'll ever make a
comeback
[Music]
i think when
i mean mexico is developing an industry
they're about to uh
like they've got some version of
legalization essentially with they're
allowing home growers or not home
growers but people to grow
a little bit of their own and i think
that they're trying to work out how the
system what it's going to look like
um so i'd like to take a lot of those
things back there
and replant them
um
again the way cannabis was grown there
it was all grow there was nobody was
growing from clone back then everything
was grown from seed so there's probably
a lot of dogs but i think that if you
took them
back down there and grew them in the
right environment or even in very
southern california
um
that you'd be able to find a lot of
traits of really you know related to
resistance and
i'd really like to see these equatorials
i mean it would be hard to sell them in
the canadian marketplace because just
you know the market wants big fat buds
it's kind of a weird thing i mean it's
just what it is what it is
but um you know i'd like to put on like
the the the hot the guerrero and that
highland mexican cross with the
blueberry because it's it just makes
these weird knuckly
long fox taily spirals just collections
of bracts right
and
again that's i think that would be a
sign of a healthy market when they there
is that diversity
in choice for consumers
right a legal market of just kush isn't
very exciting to me
yeah sure i think everyone's a bit burnt
out on that right now
it's got its time in its place but it's
like not they want to smoke it first
thing in the morning
yeah exactly exactly
so
what are your thoughts on males found in
s1's like i think the most notable case
of this is can a biogen release like the
peyote purple line which supposedly was
the result of like a male they found in
some bubba kush s ones do you think this
is a like a a case of pollen
contamination or they do occur and if so
would you be hesitant to use one
well again i'm trying to move away from
mail so i probably wouldn't use it
unless it had some special set of
characteristics
um
if it is like you got to remember we can
confirm all these things now using
lab data or genomics right and so if you
have a plant that is free from
markers associated with the male sex and
you self that plant
and then you find
that plant you know you find a plant
that comes up as
we'll call it in quotes male
you can send that lab that plant to the
lab the dna lab and see if it has male
markers if it does
well it's a pollen contamination
right and if not and it's a plant that's
just producing male flowers
for some other reason you know one of
these weird genetic anomalies that we
were talking about before
then to me those are also interesting
from a research point of view it's like
well let's figure out why
um but i don't think that i'd be more
likely to use them
because i just don't i don't know what
benefit that it would add right but i'd
probably self the plant i'd probably try
to solve the plan and see if i could you
know
would that trait pass on right
i was telling a story the other day too
when rob and i were in morocco we were
walking through these fields with
thousands of plants and we found this
one plant
that was
it was a female
um
but it looked for all intents and
purposes like a male but rather than
having
male flowers they were female flowers
but the morphology of the flower and the
way the growth habit and the stretch and
everything
it was a you know it was a it was a male
it was a just a bizarre one of those
weird off types like those really rare
you know
one in 10 000 kind of genetic anomalies
or it looked like
and uh
you know
it was it was just it was it was neat to
see because it's not something that you
see all the time
um if i ran into something like that
yeah i'd probably try to breed it out
just for the
anomaly of it right just to see
is this can this trait be passed on
or is it something in the plant that's
just reacting to the environment
yeah
understandable it's it yeah it could be
could be one of many things right
yeah it could be anything and until you
start doing the experiment your
experiment and and analyzing it with the
tools that we have available to us
you can't actually figure it out right
it's like everybody can hypothesize
you know
doobie is a great you know louis dewey
the breeder for uh for ace he really
knows what he's talking about he's also
another super nice guy in the industry
just a really good person
and
he knows what he's doing
but
there's you know i have another friend
in spain
he lives there he's actually jorge
cervantes and he goes to these like
neighborhood meetings
he went to one meeting and some guy
showed up with a male cannabis plant in
like
in august and he ranted and raved at
everybody in the neighborhood meeting it
was like
this is a male cannabis plant you have
to destroy it right because
you guys are all pollinating my stuff
right
and that's kind of an inevitable thing
with cannabis pollen like it does travel
on the wind and and depending on what's
going around your neighborhood and how
you know how serious the year about your
filter in takes on your grow rooms right
pollen can get in and
cross you can get cross-contamination
and especially if you're doing other
types of breeding around i mean
it can happen right so
before i would really believe that a
male plant came from an s1 seedling i'd
want some actual data to be like okay
let's actually just confirm your
hypothesis and say yeah let's look at it
and say are there genetic markers you
know or is does it look like there's a
genetic contribution from an outside
plant and we can figure all that stuff
out now because we have all these tools
at our disposal
so again i think that the
growing and breeding community really
needs to embrace these kinds of
technologies rather than being afraid of
them
yeah definitely i mean it makes sense
just to utilize the new in the in the
current
so
i think that brings us to our final five
questions i love these questions i we
ask them to every guest always get great
answers out of them so the first one is
what's your absolute most memorable
strain or bud or hash you've ever smoked
the one that stands out more than any
other
i think again it's probably nostalgia
but there's a friend brought me
something that he had he worked at a
a back country cabin up in the mountains
of british columbia one summer and he
came back to the town that i lived in
and he had this this flower and it was
grown from an island out here on on in
the vancouver island strait or the
strait in between vancouver island in
the mainland
a little a hippie island called leskidi
and this plant was called leskidi
sweetie is what they called it
and it was some kind of haze variant and
it was so
ripping strong
at least to my memory it was like really
strong and i don't know if it was that
everything else that i was smoking back
at the time keep in mind this is i was
in high school this is a long time ago
um but it was it was so much stronger i
don't know if it was just so much
stronger than what i'd been smoking or
it really was this anomaly planned but
yeah that one really i remember it
really whacking me more than anything i
had ever said and i've never
of course never been able to track it
down again to be able to duplicate the
experience
but that was a memorable one there's so
many i mean
you know
when i came back from morocco with rob
um
i got we we both had the same meal the
last night in morocco
but i had
mayo on on the fries some there was like
a garlic mayonnaise that they had put on
my fries
which i shouldn't have should have known
not to eat in like a country like
morocco but of course i did
and i got the worst case of food
poisoning i've ever had like salmonella
and i felt like i was on my deathbed uh
coming back
from morocco to amsterdam
and like i mean there was people on the
plane that were trying to kick me off
the plane they thought i was spreading
ebola to europe and stuff like that
i really didn't look good um
and so we had to back we ended up back
on you know i was i'm sleeping on the
floor in rob's apartment for a few days
because
my host in amsterdam
david's wife she's had the surgery and
she's immunocompromised so i can't just
show up
you know
puking bugs all over the place right so
i wouldn't stay on this little
cushion on rob's floor
and um
simon had he had met with simon when we
got back and simon had brought a little
jar of
uh cali mist and so i remember
lying on the floor
trying to like keep my bodily fluids in
check smoking a joint of simon's cali
mist grown in amsterdam by simon it was
a pretty cool thing
you know it was a little
not everybody gets to have that
experience
well yeah that must have been very very
memorable i guess on the opposite end of
the spectrum was there ever a strain
that just got hyped up phenomenally and
you were really excited to try and then
when you finally got it you were just a
bit unimpressed yeah tons there's so
many of them
there's you know vancouver unfortunately
was full of the kind of stuff we we kind
of classified them all into this
category we called bimbo bud
and they were like you know it was what
the the
the brokers that were always running
around vancouver trying to buy all the
weed to send down to the states that i
kind of kept away from those guys
because i always thought they were just
a heat score
but that was the kind of stuff that they
were looking at and it was um
bimbo bud was just lime green
really bright
kind of white
and all kind of just smelled generic and
you know everything just kind of fit
into that thing and there were so many
of those that were just disappointing
you know sugar shack that was one of
them there's a whole bunch of them jbud
there's a ton of them
they were all really just biker grown
hash plants that were stuffed full of
hydroponic nutrients and really really
frosty but not very not very much punch
to the
you know to their appearance
yeah yeah sure
so the next one is if you had to be
dropped off on a sort of deserted island
left to your lonesome you can only take
three strains with you what strains are
you gonna take just kill me man
yeah i'd probably take a a high
trapenoline variety i'd take something
in that hazy kind of sweet skunk family
and
hmm it's tough call
yeah
yeah i'd probably it's a tough call i
mean it's it's it's that's my nightmare
right to be limited to three how unfair
would that world be
i used to only give people two
i don't know cookies og something for
the bitter carry off in class i mean as
much as i rage on the cushes there there
is a beauty to them you know
yeah definitely i've i've got a very
sweet spot for cookies myself even
though
people like to call me a fanboy so
this one uh
is is the opposite end of the last
question let's say instead of you being
marooned on the island someone you're
not the biggest fan of is getting
marooned on an island and you get to
pick the three strains they get left
with what are you gonna leave him with
oh man
what can i say do on to others as you
would have others do unto you
there you go would you give them the
same as what you'd take yeah why not
i love that very diplomatic we've you're
the second guest to have shown that they
uh have a bit of humanitarian in them so
i do appreciate that right
so
final question for the interview and one
of the fan favorites if you could go
back to any point in history anywhere
around the globe and presumably collect
seeds or a cutting where would you go
and when
well i would take the seeds
and it would have to be
in the heyday you know before
you know i was born in the 70s so
i'd probably want to go back into the
60s
and uh late 60s and go to all those hot
spots you'd go to columbia and thailand
and you know india it was southern india
like karaya area kerala
um
pakistan afghanistan back when it was
friendly to do so as a as a caucasian
person um
you know
really i want to go all those places and
that's one of the reasons that you know
one of the things i really respect and
love about david is that he went and did
all that stuff
um
and i get to learn
as we do all we all do when we respect
and appreciate our elders we get to
learn from them
you know
and and learn those experiences through
him he had some incredible experiences
traveling around the world
and um
yeah it's a shame that we don't we can't
do that today
but
we can do things today that they
couldn't do back then too so it's kind
of a trade-off right
yeah certainly
so i think that just about brings us to
the end of things was there any shout
outs or comments you wanted to make
before we wrap up yeah just much love to
anybody grow on the plant
keep it clean keep it safe don't spray
chemicals
and you know much love to our elders you
know the folks that led the way for us
the
mel franks and rob clarks and david
watsons and all those people even
neville i mean you got to give respect
you know
again david says his thing and it's true
we all stand on the shoulders of giants
right
we wouldn't be where we are today
without the efforts of so many people
that have contributed to the community
and contributed to the plant
and um
let's just keep moving it forward and
and
you know it would be great if we can
like i said we get legalization and
you get to experience you know a legal
regulated system down under and
you know all these different places in
the world that need it europe right
let's make it happen
it's about time
here here i think that's a sentiment we
can all get a hundred percent behind so
thank you so much for you know the
extensive knowledge drop the in-depth
explanation and information thank you dr
ryan lee for all of your contributions
pleasure and i'm not a doctor but
pleasure seeing you guys and they're
chatting with you man and i had a really
good time a great interview
and there you have it friends
what an epic conclusion to our episode
50 huge huge shout out to chimera thank
you so much for taking the time to join
us and to share all of this incredible
breeding scientific and historical
knowledge we are incredibly grateful to
have had the chance to listen
likewise a huge thank you to our amazing
sponsors ct now best sea bank in the
game go hit em up get all those fire
seeds you need for your next crop also
swing on bike cop it biological systems
you're gonna need some beneficial bugs
and microbes to keep the bad ones at bay
i promise you you won't regret it guys
these two killer combinations couldn't
recommend it any more highly finally a
huge huge heartfelt thank you to the
patreon gang i really appreciate you
guys you help to ensure that more
episodes happen if you enjoy the show
and would like to get early access to
episodes unreleased content and a few
extra bonus goodies including giveaways
t-shirts and more go check out
www.patreon.com
forward slash the podcast
or google the podcast patreon it's there
oh and if anyone wants to grab some of
my seeds feel free to slide on into the
dms on instagram guys i got you back
[Music]
that does it for this epic three-part
hitter guys i'll have to see you for the
next one
as always
it's your boy heavy days signing out
from the upside down library
i'll see you for that next one
we'll see
[Music]
you