[Music]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast cannabis podcast for buddy
enthusiasts as always this episode was
brought to us by 420 Australia organic
gardening solutions and Bodhi seeds this
one's gonna be a big one folks we're
gonna do a two-parter so without further
wait alrighty so a big welcome and thank
you to possibly the most prolific
breeder in the industry being held in
more high regard than probably any other
breeder I know you know it love to
welcome Bodhi thanks for coming on the
show well thank you and it's beautiful
to be here I'm really happy to have a
nice conversation with you awesome so
the first question I like to start off
every interview with is what was your
first experience with cannabis you know
how did you get introduced to it huh I
mean that's a good question you know
when I was a teenager people were
smoking and I think you know that was
like the mid late 80s and there was a
lot of good strains around but I never
really connected with cannabis I was
really into I was really into like
ancestral shamanic herbalism and so I
kind of thought cannabis was just kind
of ho-hum and petty and that's what
everybody else did and I you know I was
really into getting that of the jungle
catalogs and the church of Tree of Life
and ordering all these strange and
unique plants and try those and I was
you know I really enjoyed mushrooms was
a big one and cactus and I really never
got the full download from cannabis
early on I smoked it once or twice and
didn't really do anything and I really
didn't find that deep connection until
on one of my journeys with one of my
friends and we were in Belize and the I
think it was right around the 90s you
know it was kind of it was a little bit
rough and tumble I think were the only
white people there and you were just you
know Aaron I think I was 20 and we were
just we just cruise around
bumble around you know and out of care
in the world no no clue that it's pretty
dangerous it's like the height of the
crack era and that's when I was like
let's get some you know let's get some
pot before we go to the you know the
Mayan ruins and I'm like okay and so we
bumbled around and so we found this
Rasta guy and you let us through all
these places and I'm sure it was so
sketchy and eventually we got this
little foil-wrapped ganja and we you
know we paid the guy who scurried off
and we kept it with us
and my friend actually when we finally
made it to I believe us to call he's
like hey you want to try this this is
funny and I'm like you know yeah the
students and that's when I got it like I
it was when I finally realized that
cannabis is like nature's Wi-Fi it's
like it is the plant that allows us to
connect with all of creation on a really
subtle deep human and plant-based level
it's just I really understood that this
is like the link that keeps us bound to
the our garden planet it's like it is
it's almost like our plant ally supreme
it's almost like you know I explained I
just I got it and you know cannabis was
good I would smoke it here and there and
then I really really got the download
from it when I was in the Himalayas and
they called cultures with the Baba's in
the hash and they're rubbing and when I
smoked in the Himalayas like I was
hooked and I knew that this was my one
of my fasten and it also kind of links
back to when I was doing a lot i wass
car and I had these visions in the you
know and the plant fire WASC it was like
you know you're meant to work with
plants but it's not ayahuasca it's
another plant and that means are all
stories with those stories they call if
you linked up but it's just through a
series of deeper evidence for nature and
plants and people I it awakened in me
this connection with cannabis and I
don't know I I guess that's the first
time would be maybe at those temples so
do you think for people who maybe have
more of that mainstream connection to
cannabis and maybe haven't found their
spiritual connection with it do you
think that maybe trying to
I paid in you know such an activity
would be a good way to try to you know
reestablish that link within yourself
yeah I almost think it's for people that
are kind of lost that link or can't find
that link and I think any working with
cannabis in any way could be totally
Monday and it could be spiritually could
be just commercial I mean I always like
the thing now it's like is all the guys
all the bros now that grow cannabis and
basically they're caring for this female
plant and they're creating this
relationship it's like almost nourishing
their feminine it's getting them in the
garden and when everybody says oh it's a
gateway drug and I'm like yeah it's a
gateway drug to gardening you know maybe
the front the fridge had a few other
things but I think any way you interact
with it and I always wonder you know
maybe back in the 20s if it wasn't
demonized and it wasn't scheduled and it
wasn't run out what the world would be
like today if we had cannabis for like
the last whatever it was a hundred
eighty years it would be a totally
different world I think you know I think
there would be a lot more compassion
there would be a lot more art there
would be a lot more connection to nature
and each other I think it's just this
it's this amazing force that's kind of
coming back to reclaim who we really are
as stewards of this amazing place okay
and so I mean you mentioned mushrooms
and on your Instagram I've seen things
like tobacco and poppies where these
other kind of ethno botanical plants sit
in regards to cannabis phew you know do
they all kind of sit on the same shelf
or do you use them for different
purposes I think you know they're they
they're all tapping into it like a
similar place but on a different kind of
wavelength and you know I I don't really
like real poppies once in a while more
for the beauty I'm not a it's not really
my thing and tobacco I enjoy to certain
my like prayers after the creation
matrix maybe once or twice a month and
mostly I grow it for the beauty and it
really is a protector plant so I love to
plant it all around the house all around
the gardens and I think it has a really
deep connection in India a lot of times
I know a lot of people like to smoke
cannabis and tobacco together and I see
where you know maybe eight weeks out the
flavor and dadada but there is a
beautiful kind of connection whereas too
a very male plant and cannabis is a very
female so you put those together and you
have like a coated kind of combination
and a lot of the Baba's and Saudis in
India and the Himalayas they mix those
two along with other herbs
interesting analogy around the you know
the kind of unification of the male and
the female plant do you find that mixing
tobacco and cannabis is kind of overall
a better few or it's just better for a
certain purpose I think if that's your
you know I I think whatever works for
people whatever gets them to the place
that need to be to find those
realizations is great and beautiful for
them personally for me I don't usually
mix them unless I'm in a place you know
if I'm in the Himalayas a lot of time
everybody's mixing so I just go with it
and I'm usually addicted to nicotine by
the end of the trek but you know the
their plants there's also a lot of other
plants that people mix in there's like a
calamus it's called vodka and it cools
the smoke there's a Himalayan shamanic
recipe where they use a mugwort and
night blooming jasmine flowers with the
hash like there's a lot of alchemical
blending of herbs that can really push
the cannabis experience into a more
focused kind of beam that makes sense
I'm try not to be too esoteric but
there's a lot of herbs that can
helpfully they say like Bridal kind of
like you would put a saddle on a horse
it allows you to write it better it
allows you to go someplace longer
without fatigue I mean I think it's a
unique thing and I don't think people of
so got into it there's a lot of
artisanal hash making and a lot of
really neat things but you don't see too
many blending philosophies except maybe
in pens where people are putting in
straight terpenes and such but it's all
alchemor I mean really alchemical when
it's nature but I kind of just like it
straight straight up as buds in my pipe
okay and so are there any kind of
additives that are commonly available
you might recommend people could give a
try if they're interested
there's genrih ways um what is the name
of that one or if there's one herb
that's really unique it's an I think
it's actually an Australian herb and use
a powder I think it's kind of uh not not
a cactus and not a plant what's its that
was kind of like a succulent yeah what's
it called Oh Cana you can take Cana
powder and put it on cannabis and it
will erase the the feelings of like
paranoia and you know people that get
edgy on cannabis and they just can't
handle it it'll really take the edge off
and in India they use bachi which is
calamus and that bridles the plant and
cools it for smoking and it also keeps
it from getting too out there it kind of
keeps it kind of focused and what else
there's a lot of shamanic recipes I know
the one in I really I tried to make my
own version of the night blooming
jasmine mugwort and hash but I couldn't
get it really right so I think that's
gonna be in the future I'll try that one
again but you know there's a lot of
Native American herbs that are really
good like that all help out lobelia and
Moline lots of things to cool the smoke
and nourish the lungs I think it's a
whole realm that people really need to
explore because they're you know there's
so much to it you know without and so do
you find that you're able to treat a lot
of the things that are bothering you
with this more kind of natural approach
or do you still use some kind of Western
medicines so to speak I use like a
Western allopathic medicine as an
emergency medicine
I don't think it has it really treats
the problem and not the root cause of
things and so I don't I really enjoy a
lot of the ancestral herbalism and like
traditional Chinese medicine are even
aid any kind of thing that's working
with meridians energy plants minerals
things that are really taking the body
as a whole and also taking into
consideration things like mental states
you know even environment geography I
think everything plays into healing but
I think cannabis is our primary healing
plant it's kind of like the dog version
of a plant it's like the thing that that
is right there for us you know on every
level from medical recreational
spiritual you know it covers all the
bases okay so with that being said the
first strain you ever bred was that
trying to create something medical
something that's going to help you to
better tap in to these kind of you know
streams of consciousness if you want to
give it that term or was it more of a
happy accident so to speak I think the
first time it kind of really it was a
happy accident I think I got some seeds
from Marc Emery we went up and got some
seeds one time a long time ago up in
Canada and which was but hermaphrodite
'add I think it was a feminized one and
I got seeds and I was like oh this is
amazing so this is so easy I could do
this and I'm like you know and I I kind
of played around and crew those out and
and said wow this is really unique it's
like it's because before that I was
really into DJing and making music and
blending things on that level in the
realm of therapy so I was like wow I can
take different could totally unique and
different plants and bring them together
to make some in this kind of Union or
love to make brand new things and I
thought that was the most ultimate
beautiful thing and then that kind of
started my seed addiction and then I
just went from there so who were the
first breeders you were buying when you
develop your seed addiction I mean the
reason I ask that is because I'm sure a
lot of people listening who buy your
seeds it probably themselves consider
that they have a seed addiction so it's
always interesting to know you know who
is the breeders breeder I don't know you
know what I used to kind of pour over
those old catalogs you know and I always
looked and I would like go over them and
like finding it I get my little magic
marker and circle all the ones I get and
of course I you know I didn't I didn't
have a lot of money so I can only get
one or two but I would kind of go
looking at descriptions in
kind of look for ones that kind of I
felt jive with me and it was funny it
was a some of the flying old flying
dutchman men like the suma con Dios and
DJ shorts ones always intrigued me
because especially the f13 is like it's
a real bell ringer I'm like a cool bell
ringer that sounds right up my alley and
anything kind of weird and unique and
special I always look for a kind of like
a extreme possibilities I always look
kind of fruit for me I enjoy like the
ruling fringe cannabis like the really
unique odd weird maybe doesn't look that
great maybe doesn't grow that great but
it has a you know unique effects and
even its own unique kind of spirit okay
so I mean the first question that comes
to mind with that is is you mentioned
you had the seed bank catalog so that's
interesting I I know that you've
actually got quite an impressive
collection of seed bank catalogs from
years gone by was that like an
intentional hobby or due to just kind of
workout that you happen to accumulate
them you know I've always been like a
treasure hunter and treasure gatherer
and so anything that I'm passionate
about I really love like you know I
collect records too so if I you know you
saw always in books like books are my
first passion and then from there in
winter records and then when I wanted
seeds I started selling my books and
records to get seeds so you know it's
kind of morphs you know isolate crystals
but not so much anymore because I kind
of feel bad for the planet but I don't
you know I just love to gather and
collect things that I'm passionate about
and some other all those catalogs are so
unique and so fun and I don't know it
brings me a lot of joy so I can just eat
out you know you'd be the perfect person
to ask this question to I've long since
held the view that that photo of Neville
in the hash then holding the the Brix of
hash you know I think that's the most
like chronic photo in cannabis culture
so to speak but you've probably got a
far better having seen you know more
magazines and I have do you agree with
that always there are another photo
which kind of stands out a bit more for
you I don't know you know I I love all
those photos I especially you know I
always loved the Saudis like smoking the
Chilam those always got me they always
look so like regal and and like divine
and devout and just the plumes of smoke
but I totally agree with that that
picture of Neville and the crazy
thing is through synchronicity I met the
guy who took that picture really was he
an Afghan guy no no actually never this
is like this is a story in itself
Neville took along a photographer when
he went on and he's and kind of like a
sidekick like a Batman Robin situation
on his famous trip that went through
Pakistan or India and Nepal and and his
name was Steve and Steve took that
picture and that's where I kind of got
that first eighty five seed bank catalog
from him because he still had a bunch
left and he would tell me some wild
stories and yeah he actually took that
picture and actually all the pictures in
that catalog Wow
just as a bit of a Australian pride
question where do you where do you sit
Neville in the hierarchy of breeders
throughout history so to speak knowing
some of the deeper human stories of him
I mean I I try not to put anybody on a
pedestal he definitely was a primordial
like archetype for gathering and
dispensing and creating like I don't
know kind of like all he was almost like
Isis eating out of him himself and he
kind of bloomed in in the Dutch scene
and really through passion and drive he
collected seeds from America from all
over from Southeast Asia Central Asia
and really kind of jump-started that
whole movement I mean along with sensi
and some of the older guys I mean you
know I mean you can say good about him
you can say bad I think he was an
amazing guy and I would love to see him
kind of come back out and and really
shine again because you know I really
believe in respecting and nourishing our
elders and the people that come before
us because there's a lot of knowledge
and there's a lot of information and
there's a lot of there's just a lot of I
don't know good mojo in that and so I
think novels a pretty cool guy and I
mean maybe he's a bit of a two-parter
I've heard some rumors that he is
considering maybe doing more things
within the scene if he were to come back
would you would he be the type of person
he would want to work with and then as I
follow up which breeders would you want
to
work within like a collaborative sense
you know are there any who you really
kind of did what they're doing and you
think together you could do some cool
stuff maybe you know I I kind of thought
about this I kind of work here and there
with friends or do stuff I four
commercially I don't really work with I
never really thought of it the only
thing I thought it was kind of like I
had a secret seed company that I was
starting called synergy and it was gonna
be working with all the breeders that I
kind of respected as one offs and all
the money would go to charity so each so
it's kind of like how you know that
collab with glass they come up with
these one collapse of glass and it's
like two famous glass artists and they
make this thing and that's it and it's
this beautiful piece so I thought if we
could if I could like find some of the
breeders that I really respect and we
can share Paul and our share of plants
and create maybe like two strains each
and each person gets to choose the
charity I thought that would be a really
unique way to to work with people and
make it for a good cause and then for
people I'd want to work with you know I
don't know because I don't want to like
say people and then not say enough
people and leave people out but anyone
that has a niche and it's passionate
about their work and really you know is
so I don't know there's so many so many
people and so many respect and it's like
I almost don't want to start naming off
names does not want to leave anybody out
but I would say anyone that's passionate
has there has their skill set down has
the way that they worked down and is it
has a niche like has a an avenue that
they like to explore I would be more
than honored it's just I can barely keep
up with things here on my own since it's
just me and my wife I don't have time to
even brush my hair or brush my teeth tie
my shoes I swear every day just was IPPs
by and I get to come out at the Emerald
cup but I don't know I mean maybe later
maybe I'll come up with some names in
different context but I don't really
name up names I don't want to leave
anybody I don't want to hurt any
feelings but if there's a lot of amazing
breeders and there's a lot of passionate
breeders with good hearts and those the
people I'd like to work with yeah
fantastic inside a quest
we've got from a lot of people was are
you able to kind of explain the
differences between your seed companies
a lot of people are aware there's a few
of them now something I personally was
interested in is what is the distinction
you know is do you look at a project and
you think oh this is a super natural
selections project or you know it is
there kind of rules and then that you
know dictates what each project falls
into or is it a bit more loose than that
kind of it's almost like a like a artist
that has a couple bands you know and
they're like free to do whatever they
want within the context and bands I
don't get tides you know like you don't
want to do this on this band you're
gonna do that so I would say so
bori seeds is kind of the original and
that's kind of like I can do it's all
about doing whatever I want I can I can
mash up hybrids I can do Italy crosses I
can weave things and this it's kind of
like just really freedom it's but it's
also the one that pays the bills and
it's the one where I kind of have to
cater to the flavor of the weeks and
kind of add my own twist to some of the
modern elite hybrids or make unique cool
things and it's just kind of like it's
this the basic creative model and then
Marika is kind enough that's more the
preservation angle and that's would be
like working with heirloom and landrace
and sometimes mostly those may be
vintage but not so much but mostly just
heirloom landrace preservation and that
kind of anything I collect when I travel
anything I get from other people with
good graces I also all that money that
is generated from Eureka goes to
scholarships and to funds to keep on
going and keep on collecting so it's
kind of just a preservation seed company
and you know there's a couple releases
each year and what I think is kind of
fun or fun to work out and what I think
people would enjoy working away hour
just having their bank or their
collection and that's kind of that and
then supernatural selections is new and
that's kind of like that's really what
I'm really excited about because it's
it's going back to the roots of things
it's all there's no modern hybrids I
mean it's using no modern lines so it's
all landrace vintage or heirloom and so
I get in there all f1 hybrids using
these old things so I get to go back and
I can create so many
unique things I'm not stuck in that kind
of the stagnant hyperbole gene pool that
we have right now where everything's
kind of mashed up kind of like fasting
around 31 flavors style which is awesome
there's so much unique stuff to pop out
of that but this really gives me a
chance to kind of blaze my own Trail and
go back to the countries that I've
always loved and the places and you know
because all these seed lines especially
the vintage in the land race they all
have their own special spirit and soul
and effect in flavors and by combining
these it's like it's it's pretty amazing
like you kick your Congolese and then
and like a Kashmiri like so you're
taking these beautiful Himalayan
planting and merging them with these you
know deep humid tropical jungle strains
and you're getting these extreme
possibilities and from there you can
really go all over the place and I think
it's I don't know it just for me it
feels like instead of kind of like
deejaying it feels like producing music
arts I don't know and then hope I'm not
around with too much and then the final
one was you sooner and sooner Gina's
just me wanting to have fun connecting
with people in a way also give back to
the community but I'm so busy it's
really hard to kind of get that started
and I have you know I have a few people
I've been talking to and and I think
it'll happen eventually it's just I'm
just so so busy doing my own stuff I
kind of wish you know it's almost I kind
of want to scale down and be able to
enjoy life a little more I feel like I'm
just never-ending Lee grinding away but
it's I mean that's my service so I feel
good about it it's my way that I can
kind of nourish the community is by
creating and by doing that so it feels
good now you never consider kind of
expanding the team Boddie so to speak
such that maybe you did have more
freedom to you know for example go
pursue landrace seeds or things like
that or are you is is part of it being a
small kind of mom-and-pop business part
of the central theme of it all I mean it
is I know I don't think I'm like a
control freak but I really like to make
sure that my hands are in every single
process and I think that's how we keep I
don't know if that's how we keep the
prices down or I mean that doesn't make
sense but um
it allows me to stay connected to
whatever I produce and you know I would
love at some point maybe when the laws
are more solidified and things change it
would be nice if some someone could take
care of my mom room I can keep it a lot
healthier than I can or so I can travel
and I can do it and there's a lot of a
lot of my friends or getting in reading
and they're doing amazing jobs I would
love to kind of branch out but yeah at
this point I'm just I'm kind of so in my
flow that I almost don't want to kind of
move out in any way so it's more to see
what the futures gonna bring if it
brings us you know this brave new world
of cannabis I would love to kind of free
it up I would even love to do like an
Anthony Bourdain travel cannabis show
kind of like strain hunters but Cheech
and Chong meets kind of Austin Powers
style okay
so that's actually one of the questions
I had was um would you ever consider
documenting your landrace adventures
because I mean the viewership is there
and you know I'm sure everyone would
argue that you could do a better job
than what strain hunters did in almost
every respect um you know the funny
thing is if on breed Bay and I think I
see Megan if you dig there are you stay
when I had more time I used to do these
big elaborate kind of travel logs with
all the pictures and I write about all
the things so they're out there if you
search for him I think there's like five
or six listening on breed Bay but
they're on some other ones and I would
love you there's so many countries that
I kind of flail and I haven't done yet
but I just don't have time to like at
the end of the day I'm kind of burnt or
I don't want to just want to listen to
music or smoke and just meditate or
think or you know I don't that's writing
it was hard and I loved it but yeah I
would love to I would love to go out and
do that I mean I I don't think I would
be as daring as going into the Congo and
places like that but I would definitely
like to go to places like you know I
would go to the Ewok village if I could
if I was spaceship I know they're
smoking something ordinary I would love
to go to the places where people are you
know kind of the same places I've been
like mountain people people that have
that deep connection with nature and to
the heart and do more shows and kind of
I don't know there's this one guy that
this show called going tribal
I think that's what it's called but it
is the most unique show cuz he was an
anthropologist and he would they would
send him to all these really cool tribes
out in the middle of nowhere and they
would just show him
connecting with them and and like
laughing and caring and sharing food and
that's kind of what I like to do but ya
what throw in the cannabis - that would
be amazing so but so get to down the
rabbit hole of Landry's hunting cos got
a whole whole bunch of questions on that
I just wanted to bring it back to a kind
of an idea you mentioned earlier in that
in regards to supernatural selections do
you feel that doing these kind of raw f1
landrace hybrids is gonna potentially
lead to the next skunk or the next
Northern Lights and that could
potentially be what kind of injects that
invigorated energy into the community or
do you think maybe a won't pan out like
that because that was more a consequence
of the time you know the lack of
genetics and that was maybe why those
strands got so big I don't know those
kind of particular strains were really
strains that were braided over seasons
you know each year they would add in and
new since it was pre kind of clone grow
I grew out the plants they found in the
bag seed from Mexico Thailand Colombia
pick your favorites keep the seeds next
year braided into the next favorite one
and these were these elaborate kind of
breeding programs through time and I
think those produce some of those really
amazing ones like skunks and haze but my
goal with Supernatural selections is to
really allow people to I don't know to
see the extreme possibilities of
cannabis has to offer to really see
where we can take it where we can go and
how things combine and then the
beautiful part about it is you can f/2
that thing and it opens up an amazing
treasure chest of those two lines and if
those lines are vintage lines they're
like little time machines and it takes
you back to those simpler times when
that plant and even its geography all
the information held in that and it's
like I always say that right now I'm
drawing planes but I think it's just my
way of getting to like mine kind of
graduating getting to the next level of
being even more creative at the plant
yes
if to myself of saying okay you've got
to a certain point where you have a
basic understanding of cannabis and
plants and breeding or what there's
stuff like that and now this is
something that you can embark on now
that's even more of a challenge but
offers so much more treasure okay so
that brings up this kind of idea which
is quite prevalent at the moment the
idea of as I say the concept of getting
permission to breed with other people's
genetics or just in general breeding
with other people's genetics a lot of
people are having kinda you know the
debate is is buying someone seeds enough
for you to then breed with them or do
you think it's you know kind of good
practice to first go ask the breeder if
it's alright to do so first where do you
sit on this issue well you know I
understand it coming from all different
angles I'm pretty open I feel really
honored when people breed with my stuff
and I don't have an issue
I understand people but you know I don't
put a lot of time and work into some of
their line working and stuff and they
want to keep it proprietary but what I
think really the basis of it is is
communication I think I think if you're
gonna breed with someone else's work
what an amazing time to be able to
connect with that person like to send
them an email go hey I really enjoy this
I really want to breed with it you know
and make that connection maybe it's a
friendship maybe you know I think with
just the basic respect in communication
it opens up like a whole new world and I
think it can really heal the whole
cannabis breeding community because
there's so much bickering and fighting
and weird everybody doing kooky stuff
then I think if people just communicate
it and even if someone says no you don't
have I mean it's really up to you I'm
sure you can still make the cross maybe
you it'll be kind of taboo but I think
most people are human and you ask them
and and you explain what you want to do
I think it should be fine I mean I don't
think it's cool to 2f2 people's work and
then sell it unless you ask your more if
it's a deadline maybe it's no longer
being produced or the breeders no longer
around that's fine but really I think
it's an opportunity for communication
that we don't really have you know so
it's interesting that you mentioned the
idea and I feel it's true there's a
sentiment within the community right now
that
the level of camaraderie and friendship
is kind of declining compared to in
previous generations do you kind of
agree with that and more so how do you
think we deal with that if that is the
case you know I definitely see that it's
kind of you know and it's also - its
kind of in flux there's a lot of people
that are being attracted to this because
it is so it's such a magnificent thing
and you know know it's kind of hard to
weigh in on for me I think a lot of
problems now as with social media I
think before in the early times there
was a lot less people so there's a lot
more communication there's a lot more
camaraderie it wasn't as commercial
people weren't producing seeds and there
wasn't so many elite clones the forum's
were about information and people
connecting and they went over time you
know like Instagram is an amazing thing
it's very visual it's mr. oral it's all
it's good for a TD people but it doesn't
really foster community because it's
just basically for promotion it seems
you post up a picture people get to
write a couple things and then it's on
to the next thing it's not like a thread
in a forum where people over the years
or adding to it and you know what I mean
it's so quick and and so glossy and
in-your-face and neon that you don't
there's not a way to really make that
enduring in a way and I think it causes
a lot of problems because people can be
very short very quick very disrespectful
very I think it just it really doesn't
bring out
I mean sure they're people that do
amazing things on it but it doesn't seem
to be the best angle for fostering a
community do you think that the best way
for maybe a newly emerging breeder or
someone with maybe not quite as big of a
reputation as they deserve do you think
the best way for them to get known is to
not kind of partake in that marketing
game so to speak the invention but kind
of let their work speak for itself or do
you feel that maybe we're in an age
where you almost can't be off Instagram
you know that you need that
getting a SPECT otherwise he's never
gonna take off yeah I mean four new
breeders I think Instagram is pretty
crucial in a way because it's kind of
like the roster it's like you sign up
like hey this is me this is what I'm
doing it's a tough one I think for what
I four new breeders you know I say make
a good cross and give away a bazillion
seeds just give away seeds and make
friends and communicate and let your
seeds be talked for you after people you
know where the mouth is the ultimate
thing that's why I don't I don't ever
I'd never advertise I never promote
myself because I believe that I'm
promoting myself through my work and if
people like to work they're gonna tell
their friends they're gonna do more it's
like I think just if you're into it do
it do it for the plants sake do it for
your community make them awesome hybrid
give out all the seeds and see where
that takes you yeah that sounds like
some great advice so if we go back to
kind of the breeding side of things when
you are thinking about doing a new
project maybe a line or just a certain
cross do you approach it in a very
conceptualized manner like do you think
I want to pair this male with this
female and I think that'll work out
quite well or is it more so just a
general process where you're thinking oh
let's see what happens you know like
this could be interesting yeah well for
me I kind of have a lot of different
approaches
sometimes I'll breed like I'm
emotionally where I just kind of feel
like this plant and this plant need to
be together like they just kind of feel
like they have similarities and
dissimilarities that would work perfect
together and I just kind of want to you
know it's almost like you're the
matchmaker or it's like the dating game
or something and you know especially
when you know your plants and you've
been around them and you have a nice mom
room you can kind of there's the plants
have their own interactions you can kind
of say like hey this plant kind of seems
like it kind of likes this plant you
know and bring them together or you know
it's always fun to put twists on some of
the new elite hybrids or add some
special thing to the chem line I mean
you know additive and subtractive you
know goals are great if you have a goal
like you want to make but some plant
that has a specific terpene signature
you can really you know you want all
your your goal orange I believe to
it's all kind of like for me I try and
kind of just keep myself open to the
extreme possibilities and just kind of
feel out what's going on and for
breeding if I'm you know for my
commercial breeding where I'm kind of
generating enough money to keep my
family and I said is I usually develop
males you know special males and then I
will pollinate basically my whole harem
and then slowly test those over time and
see where those go and and continually
each year you know finding more unique
males and kind of seeing how they do and
I'll use like a target female that I
know how she expresses so when I took a
new male it's usually hit to her first
so I can see kind of what she does with
this new male and then I you know for me
I guess for basically for Bodi seeds
it's all about developing special males
and then using them on kind of my own
special plants and then the flavors of
the week so I mean that's kind of the
gist I mean there's different breeding
styles we could get into that of tricks
and stuff but really it's just kind of
following your bliss being passionate
about it and you know okay okay and so
if you decided you wanted to take a
certain strain to the next generation or
you want to you know look for a special
male to work with how many seeds do
ideally like to pop to kind of get a
good representation of the strain to you
know be able to see what's locked within
it from my seeds I'll usually just pop
one pack and if I don't find something
in a pack then I call it a bummer thing
I think you should be able to find an
excellent plant in every pack that's
what most a year should be should be
aiming for at least yeah vegans get
multiple packs research and you know
these days it's not hard to make a good
hybrid our gene pool has been so refined
over time you know it's not like going
back to the 70s and 80s where you're
bringing these land races together it's
like we have a highly refined gene pool
and it's almost impossible to make a bad
cross with some of the stuff we have
today unless you know except you know it
may be from a frenetic tendencies and
stuff that kind of have been slowly
creeping in it's not it's not rocket
scientist and if you're passionate it's
pretty easy just to put things together
and get good things out but if you have
a vision you're really gonna want to do
some goal or into a reading where you're
really kind of focusing on an outcome
and doing everything you can to
fill that okay and so do you find that's
the case with most of your projects like
I think the the analogy that jumps to
mind is I think sub cool said that in
his mind when he's breeding to create a
certain flavor it's kind of like cooking
you know you're kind of thinking what
two flavors would add together to make
that strain is that kind of similar to
how you think when you're thinking about
those crosses yeah I mean if I'm being
specifically for terpenes and flavor
usually that'll be my primary thing as
all is I'll find two plants in the theme
you know that I know have either
complementary or similar smells that I
think could either bolster them or
increase it and you know for aroma based
breeding it's probably one of the
besides color based breeding it's
probably the easiest reading you know
you can basically take your males flower
them super long until they put out
visible resin and you can smell the
resin and then you basically can choose
which one is the one that smells closest
to what you want with the best structure
and if you can't wait you can use ethyl
on what is that stuff called um there's
a nano name for it but basically it
turns your males to females yeah you can
and you can you know smelled a lot
quicker but I don't really think that's
a great way because then you can't find
resinous males and I'm really into
resinous males I know some people aren't
but I think resinous males for me is
really what I kind of aim for what I'm
looking for
aroma based breeding okay what do you
think is the most well known bode
strains so to speak what what strain
embodies bode seeds the best in your
opinion I don't know you know the two
ones that people always say my like
flagships are go gog and sunshine
daydream kind of using those two males
if I used a lot there now kind of
retired those I guess would be my my
current legacy in a way I was I was
gonna mention those two but I thought if
I if I suggested them it might bait you
into picking them so the tranquil if an
tiser is a line that's always been of
interest to me I mean I've personally
played around breeding with it myself
but the the aspect which I find most
interest
it is how many times it's been you know
remixed and reworked what was it about
that cross which made you go back to it
so many times it was just kind of like a
fun and fascinating thing to kind of
play with it you know I'm really in with
I'm really into music I'm really into
like DOM and the remix and the E and
taking things and you know moving him
back and forth and I love flipping
parents and it just seemed it was a
unique line and I had you know some
really fun things and so each time I
would kind of tinker with the parent
lines I'd be like okay so I'm you know
moving it forward a generation or
backwards or using male/female reversals
like let's see what this does you know
this is like another kind of facet of
the tranquil elephant Iser so for me it
was just having fun and kind of
exploring bouncing back and forth and
and you know and even I don't know I
mean it was mostly just for the
experience of just exploring that way of
working with the plants you did it with
the mother's milk as well did you find
the results were as good or young and
you know as a result of that is it
something you would consider doing again
in the future or is it more of a
case-by-case basis well I I can't make
this anymore I mean I can line breed
them but I retired both of those males
so I mean in the future I love you know
I might I'm thinking about kind of doing
fun things with the goji now that it you
know that it's gone maybe line reading
it or taking my favorite fee knows and
kind of playing off those or even you
know making remixes in a way but for me
I'm always trying to move forward I
don't like to stay static I don't like
to be stuck in in in lines I like to
kind of always be exploring and moving
forward and kind of following my passion
and if I get stuck in things like you
know
static lines it's like in the UK they
always get mad because they say oh you
know you never restock your whole mind
you're always creating new ones and I'm
like yeah I don't want to just be
creating those same old lines over and
over I'm sure they're great and you know
it also gives people the ability you
know goji's no longer sunshine dude you
have to go longer so people can F to
those they can play with them they can
do their own twist on them I think it
you know it's beautiful to pass the
torch and allow people to bring their
own special artistry to it too so I you
know I think moving forward is a is a
really good thing and I think remix
seeing and playing around and moving
things back and forth and males and
females moving their positions I think
is a really unique way to kind of really
see the deeper side of a string and so
the ancient OG that's another one which
has a bit of a cult following my feeling
is probably due to the Iranian genetics
in it I've seen a quote on mine it was
on a form I think it might even been
from your post and it said something
along the lines of the Iranian might not
be an Iranian landrace but just
something along those lines this brings
up the idea for me of how do you know
what's real especially someone in your
position who must be offered a lot of
things and most of the time you're
probably unable to verify it for sure
maybe using the Iranian as an example
you know like how do you go about trying
to verify or what's your process in that
regard well I mean these days I try and
I think basics popping your own seeds
you know exactly where it came from I
think that's the best way to to make
sure something is verified
I tried pretty pretty good I used to be
even more better at really make tracing
the pathway of a clone who I got it from
who they got it from and really making
sure I know the origin stories and stuff
and a few times I get myself into
trouble you know like I think in the kim
91 a long long time ago there was only
one kim 91 clone and it and and it was a
verified by kim dog and this and that
and it came from jo brands kind of camp
and then later it came out that really
wasn't the kim 91 it was like a
divergent line or an alternate line and
you know the the real community was the
stunt VA and when I got that I was like
okay now I see so I had the kim 91 jb
and kim know anyone's don't be a and
they're both amazing plants but by you
know talking to people and and really
you know I respect a lot of people who
do a lot of the strain research and
really listening to them I'm like okay
yeah we're right so I had to make a
disclaimer and all that and then with
Iranian you know that was a unique
situation I got a couple clone
from a friend who had a really unique
connection offline connection it was an
old Persian man and he had some really
cool old kind of like la stuff like he
had the LA pure curse she had the LA
Street Gani which it was like a plant
that was back before the og that was
pretty popular what else he had he had
that Iranian and then something else and
so he had so many unique and rare lines
I kind of bought into that yeah this may
be this is the progeny of maybe you know
Persian strains could be the og crush
maybe this Israel does have a lot of
similarities but you know I don't know
if it was a missed mark or something I
almost think it could have been like
maybe like one of the more primordial oh
geez
just the way it was it was so close to
energy it was a little bit more wild but
it sure does make good crosses and it
makes great outdoor crosses I can almost
see it having the vigor and the kind of
stability of a Landry so I know that's a
tricky one that died kind of adds the
mystique and I kind of like that people
are really loving that line because it
does so well outdoors and I really like
that people are doing f2s and are really
kind of they're kind of taking the ball
and running and I mean try an F to it or
f3 and kind of explore - but I'm just
stoked to watch other people but it's
such a cool line and so you know it's
that's one of my anomalies there's only
a few but that's definitely one of them
and all I can really say about it is
it's Bruce Lee but it's amazing line I
don't I can't verify that particular one
because I wouldn't no longer in contact
with that person yeah okay that raises
an interesting question what do you
think are the origins of the og I mean
we've heard a lot of people who I
personally have heard a lot of people
say that it's TK and then possibly cross
211 tie or possibly just s ones you know
like and then the oh geez so to speak
went from there what's your opinion on
this I mean that's a good question
there's so many different people saying
that you know I've heard everything from
it's an old Kauai strain it's a or there
was you know what Kahlua cater Missy's
name he was singing you know was an
old-world Pakistani lemon tie and then
there's the whatever is the soup or not
in Florida and you know all these people
tracing it back and I think that's all
great Oh Reese tracing it back but for
me I don't really even care where it
came from I want to know what it's made
of I want to know go back before that
like what is it what is its actual
genetics is it some old Dutch stock that
somebody found our old super sativa Club
or was it a combination of something
special like a Pakistani Mexican or
maybe even a Thai Mexican or some kind
of all right you know a lot of more
Central Asian strains when people say
cush
you know the whole cush moniker it's
basically that kind of spicy powdery
coffee baby powder kind of smell that
people associate with a lot of the
California and LA strains I've never
experienced a plant from the Hindu Kush
region that smells anything or looks
anything like that maybe looks like if I
never smell like it but you know where
those plants that smell like that come
from is Iran Iraq all of Central Asia
has those very perfumey spicy with those
same kind of things I really think that
it must have been a Central Asian and
then some kind of very terpene rich
lemony-lemon Leone maybe a Mexican old
Mexican maybe it's high but you know
that could that could play into why it's
very hermaphroditic in certain ways you
know I don't think anybody will ever
know I would love to see that
I remember that the Adam Dunn show where
they were doing that whole genome
testing and I love to see FiOS maybe go
deeper and see kind of where you know
through genetics where it might be it's
it's a unique strain and it's so amazing
so beautiful but no one seems to know
the exact origins yeah in regards to
that Jay became 91 you at you answered
about three of my questions so I'm gonna
I'm gonna try to amalgamate that's left
as I'm into one so in regards to the JB
you know chem 91 what what about it
makes it worth breeding with because you
do still breed with it you just label it
you know the JB chem 91 so you know like
what's what's different because in my
mind I thought we'll is it different
enough such that it's worth breeding
with or is it kind of just like a bit of
an imitation that's not quite as good as
the original you know I think it's
pretty cool it's definitely not
so if you know the skunk VA is kind of
almost a genius and it's kind of like a
dark Afghani OG like it rich and oily
and and spicy and then the chem 91 JB is
this really unique it has a really
unique look it's got that really kind of
old-school kind of almost like hash
planting nodules but it has a very kind
of like diesel e and then kind of earthy
and almost skunky it's a lot more kind
of decently earthy skunky than the stunt
VA which is kind of that more dark deep
Oh G thing so I definitely think it
hasn't it kind of has like it reminds me
of kind of like when people when I was
in high school when people come up like
with the super tank bud you know the
skunk it kind of reminds me of that it's
just knobby and I think it's great plant
I mean sometimes it's not the most
stable in crosses but I think it has its
place and who knows what it is it'd be
unique to get Joe brand to kind of talk
about some of these kind of cuts that
kind of slipped out of his Arsenal and
what they really were and no one seems
to really know and now there's all kinds
of you know there's still a lot of cumin
anyone's out there there's like the big
worm and there's a lot of different ones
and who knows really where and what
these are coming from and if they're
just swans or if they're hybrids or
maybe they yeah it's the whole string
strain is inspector strain thing is
pretty amazing when you get into it I
mean the Kemper sign has got a lot of
mystery surrounding in my opinion I love
following the history on it what was
that whole process like of you
discovering that it wasn't the real chem
91 like how did that happen did someone
come to you and say this is the real
chem 91 and then it was just kind of
obvious or was it more of like a
discovery thing yourself or how did that
go down it was a combination of things
it was you know a few people that really
communicating with a few people that I
really respect their knowledge about
strains like I think my favorite people
to ask about about California and like
ma you know Oregon West Coast strains
would be like inspector I think he has
one of the most vast and underrated like
strain mines on the planet like he is
he's like a strain computer and he was
you know we're friends and
he showed me some of his pictures and he
told me about his experiences and even
at one point we traded and I got the cut
I grew up side by side and then I saw
what was it what does Louis country
isn't he was a big dog I mean when he
would never when he first came on line
and I see Meg dog he posted these
pictures and I'm like it looks similar
but it's not the same and then you know
really growing up side by side and then
seeing and then I mean the whole thing
was funny as it threw me off is you know
I did everything in her power to verify
it you know someone even got enough to
Kim dog himself and he verified it as
the Kim 91 so I was like oh that's
probably as good as I can get and that's
why it's got it so I kind of loved
eating crow like going back on my words
I think you know I think it it's good to
kind of come before the community and go
hey I messed up and it shows people that
they can do that too and and so I don't
know the Kim line has so many unique
like it's almost like this planet
shooting islands like satellites of
different things so we normally they're
all cool plants yeah sure and money pay
buddy wanted to know do you still have
the chem one or the chem - by any chance
I've never had the - I have the one
seems like a little it's a little dotted
with me I'm trying to bring it back but
that yeah that's an amazing plant I
don't think that many people have
experienced it and it it's kind of a it
would be like the sativa of the bunch it
goes a couple weeks longer it has more
kind of cerebral kind of high it's not
as you know kind of like Kim dog is very
like up it kind of muscles you it's like
putting on with those inflatable samurai
suits when you go out to our Halloween
party they kind of like you know it
takes you down and it kind of it's like
a big bear hug in it you know also it's
very heavy whereas the the Kim one it
has that same color it has the Kemp
smell it's a little bit different but it
definitely has more of a sativa in a
really kind of sativa here I like
because it has that still warm hug but
it has it's it's got kind of that heavy
indica thing where your mind just goes
off into amazing realms so I think it's
a plan it's not I don't think it's
commercially viable so much and it does
take a while
but it's a really unique kind of lens on
the whole Kim family
so do you find the refer more indica or
more sativa strains for example or you
kind of up for anything because I just
remember I was reading an article in
Skunk magazine and I believe you wrote
it and it was basically saying that the
white snow Lotus might mistake the snow
Lotus was some of your favorite personal
smoke and it veered a bit towards the
sativa side from memory you know is that
kind of how you find things in general
or is that just the snow Lotus you know
I always have liked sativas a lot
because I like psychedelics and I like
kind of that meditative opening up space
and I really like I think sativas have a
really unique spirit to them like they
all kind of have their own unique
personality some are very pushy some are
you know it's a more a roller coaster
ride some are super creepers there's I
mean I'm sure indica stew but they they
have these unique properties and each
one kind of opens up like kind of like a
little higher center in your mind so I
would say that but you know now as I'm
maturing and I'm getting older I kind of
I've been really enjoying like heady
indicas like you know should be saying
broadleafs but really unique maybe
heirloom or landrace broadleafs that are
deeply relaxing on the body and healing
but at the same time like opens your
mind almost like a dreamlike state so
I'm really loving kind of like heady and
because but I like extreme possibilities
I've always looked for plants you know
that it just body like absolutely no
mind I was like I gotta find that like
how nice would that be just to go out
dancing or say like you're saying or
about if you're going to meet people are
more social and then I also like
completely mind like absolutely no body
like some of the Indian lines that I
have are or almost nobody at all and I
even have some ones that you smoked
Vietnamese when you smoke and you don't
really know if you're higher or not
everything is just kind of slightly
weird and everything's a little brighter
and it is kind of it just feels like
you're on another planet but you don't
really feel high you're almost like did
I get stoned or what what's going on but
it puts you in a completely different
state I don't know if that's a an
interaction of multiple cannabinoids or
just this way terpenes interact
you know it's such a we're still kind of
in the early stages I'm really figuring
out why cannabis does what it does to
our physiology do you think that there's
a market now for weed which maybe
doesn't get you just you know completely
stoned so to speak but more what you
said maybe makes things feel a bit
different I mean the example I often
hear is people say oh I breed for turps
and to me that is kind of saying you're
doing what I said you know you're
breeding cannabis that's maybe not as
potent but maybe got an overall
different effect maybe more up someone's
alley who's up for a more sedate of type
of thing do you think that's a market
worth looking into or do you think maybe
it's just someone trying to make up for
poor potency within their crosses I mean
maybe both I mean I think as the
emerging kind of recreational market
sweeps over Canada and America and now
we have medical in Mexico and all these
places are tuning and I think for people
that aren't smokers that have never done
cannabis I think it's kind of nice to
have training wheels to have something
that's tasty and visceral and and and
great to the senses that is very low THC
that can kind of ease you in if you want
to keep on going you know if your
grandma you want to smoke something or
you don't want to get too high they want
something special and I know now there's
branded things like sex pot there's that
pot that's supposed to make you feel
sensual and horny and and you know
there's also then the CBD style stuff
where the CBD THC things those are kind
of more you know those are a different
feeling themselves they seem to be a lot
more freeing up of the bodies and so
much the mind I think there's I really
think there's a market for any
expression it's just finding that niche
and going there and then also finding
the place that you're going to be able
to then that or you know it's it's
almost like you have to have a passion
for that specific thing you're going for
else you're never gonna prevail so one
of the more interesting things I
remember talking to about at the Emerald
cup was how you said you only really
smoke once a day or so and it's more of
like a meditative slash ritual type
thing as opposed to just a recreational
one would you mind going a little more
into detail about that and kind of how
you do it are you combining say meditate
with smoking or is it more just smoking
and trying to undergo it as a type of
meditation I mean really when I say kind
of meditation like more it's just like
me time I usually smoke whatever I want
to sleep here I have three kids and I
I'm hypersensitive to cannabis and all
kind of plants so I don't need just I
like to take bong hits and if I take a
bong hit during the day it's like I'm
just gonna be staring at plants and not
be able to be working and not being
really able to interact with my family
so it's kind of like after I'm done with
everything I have all these plants that
I test and so I have hundreds of
different strains hanging and I'll be
like okay what are we gonna try tonight
and I'll you know usually the city
hasn't usually keeps me up all night but
for me it smoking once a day allows me
to not only not bludgeon my
endocannabinoid system but keep me like
sensitive enough that I can really
perceive the individual differences in
plants especially if I'm going through
new lines or different she knows it
really allows me to stay crisp and an
honorable to the plant like everyone has
their own special relationship to the
plant I don't I don't going to judge I
think people that need to smoke it a
hundred times a day
is beautiful if you don't need to smoke
it once a year that's amazing it's
really how we interact with it and I you
know I hear some people get kind of like
fooled on or making fun of that they
don't smoke that much or they're light
weight I think light weight should be
celebrated I think being sensitive to
the plant and knowing how to be
respectful to the plant in in take a
engage it in a way that they you know
it's a special meeting I think that's
good and I think that more people should
do that I think sometimes when you smoke
way too much you don't really get to
experience as the nuances you know I
understand for medical reasons people do
you need to do that and even for
self-medicate you know things I think
it's great but I think to keep yourself
really sensitive and clean to if you're
breathing and really diving deep into
different strains I think it's kind of
good to create a special time that you
interact with it and for me it's just
it's late at night and sometimes I
meditate sometimes I'll listen to music
some
you notice than that if I do yoga and
the day our ride mountain bike I'll do
it I don't it's not like I only do it at
night but usually trying to smoke once a
day and that kind of in that what's what
work basically works for me unless I'm
trekking then I'm gonna smoke all day
long as I Trek because that's what I
like to do that's awesome so it's given
you know you're relatively small amount
of consumption compared to say other
breeders do you find it hard to
personally sample all the plants you
grow out or I mean my assumption would
be that you must kind of have a group of
trusted friends who are kind of act as
your power in a certain regard or do you
still manage to kind of work your way
through a mall you know I do my best to
work through all only of 365 days a year
I do it anyway any friends come over I'm
always like hey you wanna try this want
to try this and like you know I make
bags cuz I learned that my whole garage
is like it it's just hundreds of strains
and I don't know what to do if I well
usually just they get too old I was
through them over the hill um you know
cuz it's just it's a wonderland but I'm
always like hey try this try this try
this true this what I need I wish there
was some dedicated like super stoners
that would I could just give like a bag
once a week and be like hey try this and
right I used to have people a long time
ago they're like hey try all these write
down what you think about each one and
give that kind of bag to a couple
different people so I could get more
kind of insight but these days you know
I'll give a bag to whoever comes over
but really it's kind of just me and you
know I get one one chance each night and
it usually works pretty good I can do
you know week I can do fee knows you
pretty much seven fee notes from a new
line in a week and take all my notes and
kind of know where I'm going from there
what what kind of percentage of your day
do you spend hacking through uncharted
uncharted territories looking for new
land races yeah that's rare I mean I
it's kind of sad I feel kind of like a
dork I used to really be able to get out
there more and I really like my heart
just soars like my spirit is so happy
when I'm out in the field like that's
where I feel at home like just you know
no expectations there's totally out of
your element every every moment is
something new I just mind Spiritist
bobbles
but now with three kids and the business
and all that I'm kind of like stuck and
it drives me crazy I mean now things are
starting to pick up again I just did a
collection strip with a couple friends
we bought them all about six months ago
and kind of contemplating a quick one in
Oaxaca in about a month or two I got
some good ideas for a special spot but
date-time it's really you know I do a
lot of trading and I do a lot of seed
popping and I just kind of try and
explore what I have and you know maybe a
day is I wake up late because I go to
red light I usually do kid stuff pick up
kids do this do that and maybe in the
afternoon I get to do some outdoor then
it's time more kids stuff
dinners with the kids a bit then I go
out and I do indoor stuff and then and
then when everything's done anything
I'll go down to kind of live in a dome
down on lower proper the property and
I'll just pick something that from
hanging from the ceiling and take a big
bong rip and usually listen to meditate
listen to music
take notes read just kind of get in my
own space and kind of like kind of
realign with the force I guess and
what's happened to key into my sleep you
know I pretty much like any kind of
music except maybe I'm not so into
contemporary country-western like that
for me and a lot of like you know any of
the new whatever whatever is on the
radio I'm not so thrilled about like all
the new puffy stuff but I primarily
listen to maybe like I guess people
called bass music a lot of electronic
music that's heavy on the low frequency
I also like a lot of older stuff like
about Hendrix and Zeppelin a lot of
sixties Punk and I even you know some
some right but mostly I would have to
say it would be classic electronic music
and then newer really psychedelic bass
music and they're like ambient I like
world music you know I like I'm pretty
open but it like wash your hands a lot I
like kirtan
you know I like even listen to podcast I
you know I was like listen to my own
ears but really I think if I had to pick
one thing it would be if I faced music
and I know that sounds strange but
that's me nice so although I was kind of
you know joking a bit of tongue-in-cheek
with the whole hacking through uncharted
territories it kind of is a fairly
accurate statement in many ways at least
compared to other breeders so how does
that whole process go down you know I
remember when you're on the Adam Dunn
show you said generally you have a
contact organizing when you go into a
different country would you mind filling
us in a little more on the details of
you know how the average trip goes down
yeah usually you know usually I'll do
some research and I'll pick a place that
I've always wanted to go to that also
has a history of cannabis and you know
I'll do a lot of looking in books and
I'll do a lot of research online and
I'll try and find specific places or
specific strains or try and get clues
and then hopefully I made a friend there
maybe I have a contact it all depends
and then you know the real thing I try
and do and sometimes it backfires when I
haven't done it for a while is
synchronicity go to a country go to the
places that you research be the coolest
person you can be you know be who you
really are open your heart laugh make
connections with people and usually I
travel alone recently I've been taking
French which is really fun but I used to
travel alone so I'd meet a lot of people
and you just kind of develop
relationships and I swear
synchronicities happen like people you
know from point A to point B just follow
the clues and they'll usually take you
to where you need to be you know and I
usually play I love to choose places
where I can track like kind of get up
into the mountains and mountain people
are so friendly and you just have to be
really respectful you know I try and I
never bring in my own seeds I always
bring in like heirloom vegetable seeds
I'll spring in like antibiotics I love
to bring in pencils chocolate I like to
like really give them myself and I
always bring these fake teeth and crazy
glasses cuz I like to make people crack
up and smile and make the kids laugh and
the key to you know I think anyone that
loves cannabis and anyone who loves
traveling I think it's our birthright
and it's our duty to get out there and
save those strains you know and even if
you can't go and you say you're a big
commercial person you have trimmers
where do trimmers go after they trim all
summer they go to Thailand they go to
Guatemala you talk to your trimmers go
hey bring you back some seeds or even
better talk to your dad's old hippie
friend see if he's got any I mean you
got to follow every single Avenue but I
really think people should Trek if they
like to travel they like cannabis get
out there and really show the world like
how cool we are and make those lasting
connections and you know help people out
and let them help you out and I think
that's one way that we can really make
this a better planet yeah really
so you kind of touched on the topic
without trying to throw anyone under the
bus how do you feel about you know the
idea of trading more hybridized seeds
for landrace seeds to you know the
farmers in these countries is that just
a personal choice you decide not to do
or do you think as a kind of modern
society we have a an obligation to not
do that even these people may not fully
understand the implications of you know
cross pollination yeah I think it's a
it's a hard one I think it's a really
ethnocentric for you to bring in
anything that we think is like super
awesome and try and replace it was
someone that they already have that they
have a history of it that their
ancestors grew it that it's part of
their collective consciousness that it's
weave through their toil and their sweat
you know it's like these plants that
have been grown in these areas except
now with you know rapid
commercialization and also even with
drug cartels and and people bringing in
stuff to try and pump out a lot of stuff
for foreign markets it's like these
strains are special they're magic
they're timeless they weave through
cultures they weave through people's
lives and it holds a lot of information
and I think the that it's it's criminal
to take in especially feminized genetics
into these cannabis hot spots I think
it's really short-sighted I think it's
it's it's not a smart thing at all and I
mean it's one thing you know I've opened
up a little bit because I've met some
really cool cannabis breeders in other
countries and I mean you know considered
sending stuff and I'm like you know if
you're growing way out in some mountain
valley where there's not a lot of
cultivation and you're just doing your
thing as a modern cannabis guy sure you
know that'll be fun to trade seeds and
do this but if you're in an area that
has like it you know the eons old
traditions of working with certain
strains and certain areas that have
developed over time and are you know
that are made for those areas to bring
in something else it's just so so wrong
and it's so sad and it really it sets up
for a global homogenization that's you
know we're just we're gonna basically
we're just gonna braid ourselves right
into a hole and so I definitely think we
shouldn't be thinking for genetics into
cannabis hot spots you know but there
are exceptions but that's my feeling and
I think yeah I mean she reaches on now
I'm not gonna pass judgment but I really
think it's a bad idea so I read a post
recently from your buddy sonic seeds and
he said that he's working with some
landrace Jamaican seeds he got from her
body but he's in kind of analysis of it
all was that they weren't in fact
landrace Jamaican seeds but more just
kind of acclimatized watered down super
Silver Haze hybrids from kind of all the
imported genetics of years gone by that
had polluted the pool so to speak have
you ever felt a similar thing happened
with any seeds you've brought back only
to kind of find because this is the kind
of follow up question is most of the
time when you're getting the seeds it's
probably you know you probably don't
have a really amazing representation of
flower side by side for a do so you
probably have got to kind of wait till
you get back home and grow it out before
you really know what's inside there or
is that not the case what depends if
you're doing if you're doing collections
doing bag seed testing and sampling or
if you're actually seeing the plants and
collecting seeds directly from the
plants I think then you really get to
see what's going on and you can kind of
tell whether you know things are modern
hybrids are or have that or if you're
more in the tropics if they're like true
equatorial but I mean it's kind of a
unique question because the big
our trip to Guatemala was all about
trying to reclaim the strain that I had
long ago that was one of the best
strains I've ever smoked in my life and
so in Guatemala there's a sister Lake to
Lake Tahoe it's a caldera Lake it's a
lake that he was a volcano that's been
filled with water and it has its own
microclimates it's called a lager Lake
atitln it's this amazing beautiful Lake
but the classic thing is ever since the
80s I don't know if you know how many
dead shows everyone's been to but you
know the 80s and 90s everybody wore like
Guatemalan shirts and Guatemalan shirts
and it's kind of like the style and
you'd sell them on straight down street
so a lot of those vendors when tour
wasn't going on they would go down to
the lake and be buying up the clothes
and they'd also bring down their lot see
it's like you know they're basically
their dead family seeds and they would
grow them and those seeds
I think hybridized and pollinated some
of the local sativa varieties and you
were getting these really unique plants
that were kind of like dead lot meats
sativas and then they were you know
bringing over cycles over seasons and
they were climate izing and becoming
heirlooms and you had these amazing
amazing combos of basically ancestral
sativas and deadlock seeds and so that
was kind of my goal was to kind of go
down there and see really if those were
still available because I'd had sampled
it before in the past and and when I got
down there I realized that you know what
there's so much people bringing in so
many genetics from a lot of trimmers are
going down there especially the San
Pedro and setting up shop there's a lot
of growers diminutive to America and
buying from seed bags that the lake is
pretty polluted you know it's it's the
gene pools pretty fluid it's unique and
it's special they're getting to try new
things before really stoked but those
deep older lines from like the 90s and
early 2000s even are seem to be gone or
maybe I just didn't get a chance to look
deep enough but you know there's still
that there's a plant down there called
what's it called Manjeet oh that's kind
of like there
their blue dream down there like the
Guatemalan attrition of my dream I guess
you know it's grown all over Guatemala I
think it's like a throwback from like an
earlier time and it has some really
unique effects people don't seem to
really like it that much I thought I was
kind of cool cuz it makes you absolutely
stupid it's like one of the strains
where you just like stare and laugh like
I think that's kind of neat and you know
we brought that back but that's being
hybridized with the law and there's some
really cool people there's a lot of cool
Ottomans there's a lot of new breeding
going down there but you know that
finding land races is difficult there
now and then you know there's you can go
to the jungle the patina is cultivated
but a lot of the organized cartels of
moving in there and they're pumping
stuff out so it's like it's happening
everywhere in Mexico you know Jamaica is
a good is a really good way to see it's
like Jamaica had so much early Dutch
stuff brought in that it it basically is
a lot of the island is these Dutch
Jamaican hybrids and now they've kind of
turned into heirlooms and sure there's
Rastas that sob the Lambs breath and
stuff but really must the island is a
unique kind of like Dutch Jamaican
hybrid that's turned into an heirloom so
I mean in a way that's kind of cool
because you're kidding you're I still
love hybrids and I still love when
things come together for the first time
and kind of make this unique love but at
the same time the world's being
homogenized very quickly very fastly I
don't think it's gonna slow down at all
I think it's only gonna gonna get faster
and faster and faster until we're all
basically everything is going to look
and smell pretty much the same so on
that idea of land races which one kind
of interests you the most in terms of
moving forward with it we often hear
people talk about very reminiscently you
know Thai do you feel that maybe Thai
hogs the spotlight a bit and there's
another land race that deserves a bit of
a mention that if it did come back into
the mainstream conscious you know it
really rocked people's world so to speak
yeah I mean a good time in it Thai it
comes down to being people being able to
like grow it correctly and and you know
really find a way to see what I think
really for maybe I think as cannabis
becomes globally legal and we start to
see these like trade deals where
we're actually gonna get stuff you know
shipped over from Thailand Colombia all
these places we used to kind of get it I
think then maybe because it's you know
from my experience smoking like
landraces at the point of origin and
then coming home and growing them and
smoking it it's like completely
different well it's kind of like one's
like a light version like because the
plants developed its you know in a
specific environment Tharoor also you
know there's a lot of things going to
cultural heritage there's so much
information in epigenetics that that
that we've through these plants in the
places that they've been for so long
that they've really developed their
vital essence and you know ice local
hock and in Oaxaca that just blew my
mind and I'll bring it back here and it
was kind of where and it's you know if
maybe after a couple seasons of getting
used to the new environment and you know
keep cleaning a couple secessions of
seeds they can adapt and bring out some
of its qualities I don't think we're
really gonna get rocked by these land
races until we can really start
importing them from their points of
origin I mean you know there's people
that really do you excel at drawing and
sativas indoors and really finding the
niche I have a couple friends that do
great jobs and you know I think that
there are lines that have been in Kalama
ties especially older lines you know
back from the eighties and stuff that
have been around forever that wear a tie
that we kind of got climatized to our
mountains you can still get those
effects but really I don't know I mean
and even stuff like tie you know tie
gene pools been pretty polluted I think
the only way to really find some of
these Southeast Asians that are really
noteworthy is to go deep kind of like
that Lau Asian strain I brought back
that was kind of right on the border of
China and Burma and it was way up up in
kind of the high high Highland for us so
it was it wasn't the lowland kind of
like humid tropical was like I got
Jurassic Park style thinking it was
pretty untouched and it really had its
own unique essence I think people are
gonna really really want to find unique
and rare stuff we're gonna have to
really get back up in there
or dig into older stuff I think you know
I heard Rob Clark I think it's real
Clark say that you know the best land
races are going to be found in your you
know your dad's friends collection or
thing it's like I think old seeds are
kind of these special treasure chests
that hold a lot of the magic you can
even though there are still hotspots
that contain amazing genetics I think
it's really about recovering a lot of
stuff we have here especially in
California and all across the states
were you know it's been grown it's in
prohibition I think you know talking to
old people like connecting reaching out
I mean and now's the time to sprout
those things I mean get them out get
them going you know get that germ plasm
out and about because it's it's only
getting older and I think maybe it's
that's the kind of safer bridge there's
is getting deep into the bush and then
also getting deep into people's
collections so what the oldest seeds
you've ever been having to germinate oh
that's a good question I mean our shrine
is for old ones I can get them to pop
but they never come up you know I use
seed bombs and all kinds of weird
popping strategies and I have friends
that can do pretty good getting really
old ones I'm trying to think what's my
oldest I don't even know I mean most
likely probably 80s I have a lot of
seeds from the 70s that I can't seem to
get to go I guess would be either you
know a lot of times some of these old
old ones are there being refreshed every
like nine years or you know they came
from somebody's dad who had them and
then their uncle made more nine years
later and then someone else made you
know they kind of they're being
refreshed and that's one way that I keep
getting a thing I don't know you know
there was a really kind gentleman that
came on Instagram from Alaska that like
buried a bunch of seeds and he has a lot
of cool stuff from these and he's
getting great germination and so I mean
it it's all about storage really and
it's about people that have kept that
vibe alive and are now kind of as the
laws are lifting and people are being
more comfortable they're like people are
coming out with their treasures and I
think that's a it's really it's a kind
of a gift to the community is that as we
legalize things they're kind of coming
to the surface that we never really
thought with the wood so do you think
that if people do you know
how should we say metaphorically find
the seeds in the dad's friends little
stash case do you think that people
should you know try their best efforts
if possible to try to do a bit of a Tom
hill in this situation and you know do
the open pollination and try to you know
generate that large a stock cool to work
with without bottlenecking it such that
we can then work further yeah I think if
something's really special I think you
should always open pollinate it you know
and I and there's there's ways to get
there's kind of like fun tips and ways
to get it to have fun with it and still
over pollinate you can do like a
targeted open pollination where you do a
bunch of seeds and you kind of you pull
out you know the ones that are are
really not gonna be good for the gene
pool but who's to say what that but you
can kind of narrow it down I prefer like
a total open pollination and then from
there I'll I'll pick my favorites a
couple favorites from that open
pollination and I'll save those backs
with clones and kind of work with those
but every time I get like a unique seed
line like I have an old-timer friend
that once in a while sends me some more
really special cool stuff and the first
thing I always do is I do an open
pollination make a bunch send him back
some keep those and then I'll kind of
work from those from the ones that I
selected from the initial open
pollination that I really kind of
connected with but yeah I think it's
important to keep that gene pool and
that kind of open and contained for the
future even if you can go back and you
know it's great to have that you know
what if your grow room dies or there's a
storm comes by or you know the power's
out it's easy to lose clones it but it's
it's hard to lose seeds yeah plant the
tree so just kind of living back to a
previous question have you found any
land races that seemed to be
particularly compatible with modern
strains you know most likely you would
have probably found this through
supernatural selections and then the
flip side of that the opposite you know
have you found any modern strains you
know maybe an elite clone so to speak
that seems to work quite well with land
races that's a good one the funny thing
is a lot of the elite clones they work
good with land races were kind of like
all
clones there were originally landraces
kind of are ones that have been kind of
inbred quite a bit because I mean Nikita
- you know - f1 hybrids is really
getting inbred lines so if you're taking
two inbred lines and you're putting
together they're very distinct they
don't have a lot in common you bring
them together you get that true f1
hybrid vigor where you're getting this
like explosion of life force and you're
getting this this really unique
combination of genes and they display
pretty pretty stable and pretty similar
in that first cross and they just blow
everything away with vigor and they have
amazing root systems and they really
shine and then from there I mean you can
have tuned stuff but I really think the
best things to mix with land races our
other highly inbred elite clones are
highly inbred clones have been kept out
for a while and I think that's where you
get the best results you know and then
it's always fun to play like I think oh
geez are fun to cross anything into an
OG because OG such a cool plant and then
across an a crazy land race it's like
then you get these really kind of weird
unique accents or really freaky you get
freaky buds with an OG smell but a
completely different structure it's kind
of fun to take your favorite things and
just kind of hit them with the magic
stick and see what crazy stuff comes out
you know what's your favorite OG to work
with and then secondly have you ever
found when you you know did hit stuff
with the magic stick so to speak I like
that expression by the way if you ever
found that just something just
completely you know the most unique
exotic smell you know maybe never even
encountered it before in cannabis you
know have you ever had that happened to
you yeah definitely I think especially
with with a really unique and special
and very like super especially with like
the super super heavy Terp plants when
you put two really unique to your plants
together sometimes you get the weirdest
wildest smell you would have never
thought and then sometimes they cancel
each other out which is always weird
like you get the two smelliest plants
and like oh this is gonna be the
ultimate and you throw them together and
then like somehow they cancel there
smells out and then sometimes you'll get
crazy stuff like you put an OG and a
blueberry
you get onions out or you know it's like
it it's the way the genes combined is
just so amazing and magical and it might
be you know sometimes it could be
recessive genetic she could be backing
something that came from you know an
earlier earlier generation and yeah I
think it's just it's fun that's why I
always say find like a targeted female
like a female that you know and you've
always used in your breeding that you
can put your new pollen on and really
see what it does so you can see what
that kind of brings to a cross and then
I think my favorite Oh G to work with it
was that Nepali Oh G but you know I no
longer have it but out of all the oh
geez I ever worked with that one would
always consistently make the best
hybrids and I mean besides the ancient
Oh G besides the Iranian did really good
too and I think that they you know if it
wasn't Oh G I think did it
it would it was probably closer to that
kind of Grass Valley Tahoe kind of
emanation of oh gee that was there for a
while okay there's kind of like a point
of contention within the communities but
two schools of thought one is that we've
made the land races more potent and
maybe arguably more flavorful however we
have potentially lost certain
characteristics the other the other
argument is that the new the new strains
while definitively being may be more
flavorful or having certain savers that
weren't accessible in the land race
roots are not as potent do you think
that the land races were more potent and
we've watered it down or that we've
refined it for the better
um I think both things I think human
selecting plants to their you know each
each season smoking the stuff finding
their favorite things and just going
with that each year and each year is
like that's the amazing thing as humans
we can do is I was thinking of like you
know gene pools is energy and then where
the awareness that we bring to it so in
a way I think you know of course you if
you've really been deep in the bush
there's a lot of jungly cannabis and
it's pretty junky like I wouldn't a lot
of stuff in the Himalayas a lot of stuff
that's scaped into the wild
even earlier than escaping the well they
kind of revert back to their their own
kind of vibe and it's pretty you know
it's pretty jungly it's pretty rough I
mean from a roughing perspective it can
be some of the best hash ever because
it's you know these plants are just
they're horrible to look at but the
resin that come to office is truly
amazing
but I think it's kind of like our duty
to kind of push it in the ways that we
want to as artists working with the you
know the plant spirit and the cannabis
realm and then at the same time I think
we do lose certain things like I was
talking to rob Clark about this like
what makes all the old strains so
different and he's like oh they were
more mono turfy like Mexican had this
effect because it had just one kind of
terpene signature I like one
you know like lemon or something where
and it would take you this way where
another one from this like Colombia it
was kind of a monitor but had just the
smell and this so people remember like
he's Colombian raised with a certain
smell or Panama with a certain smell and
and so they had these they weren't so
mashed up the whole global cannabis gene
pool wasn't mashed together in all these
ways creating all these different genes
expressing themselves with all these new
smells and combination smells it was
like there was these very distinct
varietals they had distinct morphology
they had distinct look they had distinct
smell taste and the effect too because
they were very specific to their you
know single or just a few terpenes and
that's why it held their very held their
uniqueness and as we grew as a cannabis
culture and community and started
blending all these things together you
really started to blend together a lot
of the effects kind of almost sometimes
getting me things sometimes muddling but
I thought I found that really really
unique and really kind of really
expanding my mind like wow yeah I guess
so if it came from a specific place in
this a specific environment in the
environment forced the plan to do
certain thing and release certain
terpenes in it you got it in a brick in
the 70s or 80s from this place of course
it's going to have this unique effect
and I think that we're kind of losing
that these unique effects
I think we're get gaining in the smells
and flavors and aromas and even
structure than yields but we're really
losing on the the kind of subtle spirit
subtle effects that cannabis has to
offer that we that we no longer kind of
experience in our modern gene pool
that's really interesting because I've
always wondered and I posed the question
to mr. solo I said what is it on the
molecular basis do you think that causes
a strain to quote not have a ceiling
because people often talk about maybe
Thai for example or haze not having a
ceiling you know you just keep getting
higher and higher the more you smoke and
so my first thought is well there's got
to be some you know molecular basis for
the ceiling and I guess if we kind of
think about what Rob said if it was a
similar kind of thing happening with the
terpenes that would almost suggest that
some terpenes inhibitory you know if
maybe monoterpenes led to a high that
didn't have a ceiling maybe multiple
terpenes somehow brings in a ceiling do
you think do you have your own little
kind of hypothesis to what's going on
here yeah you know I've always kind of
wondered and I always like you know what
is going on like even when I would get
like and say like a broadleaf Jamaica
and and it would I have one you know I'd
be like okay this push more smells kind
of like a haze so why does it have an
effect you know kind of like a down
relaxing thing in this haze that smells
the same why does it have enough and I'm
like what is going on you know because I
you know terpenes are usually they kind
of lead the experience they're you know
they're either bolstering or are
cancelling out or making things go
through the blood-brain barrier faster
or you know or yeah so I was wondering
that too and I don't know if it's a
combination of like octillery Kent
cannabinoids mixed with terpenes you
know for awhile people thought maybe a
lot of the high elevation and a lot of
jungly like equatorial they had THC v
like something that would kind of lead
the cannabinoids into you know a more
effective deeper synchrony with your
brain I don't know I would love to it's
that's like one of the things that
fascinates me and I think that people as
we get more into genetics and terpenes
and and auxilary cannabinoids that will
kind of
see but yeah the ceiling thing is wild
like and even or even legs yeah like
what makes some strains last for so long
like I have some strains that look super
ugly I smoked it and I literally can
feel like I drank a coffee and I'll be
up all night long but and I smoke maybe
even a different fee no and it won't do
the same thing like where are these
ceilings sighs and these like
long-legged highs it must be the
chemistry uh yeah it's it's really
amazing and I would love to know because
yeah I'm that so it's a fascinating
subject yeah and it would certainly be
interesting if we could figure out the
answer because presumably we could then
work towards incorporating that ceiling
this ceiling lessness it's probably not
the best way to phrase it into more
strains but what about oops sorry gone
oh yeah I was just gonna say like what
about so you know everybody's really
into these pens and I know now the kind
of thing is like a rock and I'm annoyed
compound and then they're putting these
fake terpenes like trademark og
combinations you know they're running up
through the grass chromatography and
finding which terpenes or however they
do it in each strain and then they can
kind of mimic that so why I love you
know there's people that make amazing
pens and I like pens for certain things
like traveling and stuff but why does it
seem like pens they just don't have the
spirit there they're kind of like this
muddled kind of basic Highness like I
don't get a lot of different effects
from a pen it seems to be all very
similar and then why if if if the
highest chirping driven why why why
can't I mean it's you'd think that
people could put in these diverse food
based terpenes and get similar effects
to the strains like there's got to be
something else
I don't maybe it's something
metaphysical I don't even know it's you
know it kind of boggles my mind it's
like why can't we recreate okay there's
obviously something magic going on we
haven't figured out yeah if a me I mean
it raises a kind of a parallel issue
where that is will we ever be able to or
maybe another way of putting it is are
we wasting our time trying to
artificially replicate the plant when we
know that it just doesn't seem to really
compare you know like do you think that
we'd ever get to the stage where you
could get you know a capsule or a pen
for example that would completely mimic
say you know like ingestion of the whole
plant product by a combustion maybe or
something like that or do you think it's
just still you know the technology is
not there and we don't understand it I
don't know I mean it's the same thing
kind of with you know modern herbalism
there's a whole school of pulling out
the specific Fido chemical and
standardizing that and then sailing that
as a natural medicine versus a whole
plant extract versus eating you know the
herb and it's like you know sometimes
people do spa Jarek like an alchemical
extract there's co2 there's alcohol
there's all these ways that people try
and capture the essence of the plant and
I think maybe spirit is probably the
best because it's a more of a
metaphysical thing but you really can't
capture the true you know it's like
anything you can't capture the true
nature it's even like the live music
versus recorded music and I think really
the whole terpene pen thing I think
that's just more of a commercial thing
it's a cost-effective and I think in the
future sadly what we're going to see is
massive massive massive cannabis farms
where they're just basically harvesting
all the tops making raw THC and they're
adding it into these propylene glycol
with their proprietary mixture of
terpenes and you get them it's MLM
together I don't think flowers are gonna
have a place in the future except in the
people that really love and enjoyment
I think legalization we're gonna see
just this mass light kind of blah kind
of exposure to just both cannabinoids
and flavors I don't think yeah I don't
really see except you know maybe 5% is
gonna be these really deep heads that
are love their concentrates and they
love their flowers that are you know
we're really utilizing these these
labor-intensive practices to produce
this it's kind of like a labor of love
versus commercialization it's going to
sad
that is is an interesting argument in my
mind I saw a I think it was in the
states a farm that was producing some
horrible looking plants but their
defense was well this is all just
getting to get converted into extracts
and so it doesn't actually really matter
but it wasn't just the case that these
plants would like you know visually not
very nice like it was the case that they
were clearly not very well looked after
and that's why they didn't look very
good do you feel that that is a
disservice or the fact that they are
producing some product for someone who
probably needs it and is better off with
that then nothing is is a good way to go
and I guess the deeper philosophy of
this question ties into the Australian
scene you know I'm of the opinion that
the the medical system that's being
prepared to be rolled out in Australia
is actually kind of a farce and so it's
like should you accept the sub quality
product and in exchange for having
accessibility to it or should you deny
that and you know only accept the
highest quality of you know the proper
sort I mean it's conundrum I think
people generally like need something
like basically as a medical thing if
they need it for their health and it's
imperative by any means necessary but
it's the same thing it's like you know
if they have these scraggly cows that
are called diseased and they're all
caged up and like oh it's okay we're
just making hamburger you know it's like
that's another thing people need the
protein I mean I don't eat meat so it's
a weird analogy he just kind of popped
into my weird stoner brain but it's like
I think the fee I really think craft
cannabis has been part of our heritage
and it's I think that we need to do
everything we can to preserve that but
you know it's a big world and there's a
huge way of coming and it's scary and
that's why another reason why I think
people should stop bickering and start
communicating it's like people should be
fighting getting all weird with each
other it's like there's a huge force
it's like something wicked this way
comes it's gonna engulf everybody and I
think now is the time to create these
guilds and create these friendships in
these communities and really everybody
come together because we're gonna be up
against a serious wall that sees cash
over anything and I think we have a
little bit of a window and it's time to
kind of get with the picture but you
know for medicine well if I'm any means
necessary
but I think we owe it our fellow humans
to make a compassionate product that
that has our heart and soul because half
the healing you know even is is what you
put into it there's a there's a vital
essence there's an energy to it and you
know the body works in mysterious ways
it's you know like even psychosomatic
wounds and you know placebos and they
work why because we we believe in it
with their heart so it's like I don't
know it's it's a tough one yeah so how
do you think the organic versus
non-organic argument relates to the
quality of the product are you of the
opinion that organic will always kind of
be a better product at least
holistically as opposed to synthetic or
do you think that there it's you know
kind of just down to the skill of the
grower and you've had non-organic
product which was quite medicinal or you
know where do you sit on that I mean
it's it's it depends I guess if you're a
master of your craft if you hmm I I
personally just smoked organic and I
love that it has a connection to the
earth and to the you know the biological
web of the earth and energy into the
dirt into the yes and there's a lot of
forces at play but at the same time you
know it's also a science it's like
people have you know I've seen like
online like the jungle boys they they
looks like they've I haven't sampled it
but looks like they have it pretty wired
and they produce some pretty amazing
stuff I haven't seen how it burned or
how it tastes or what it does but you
know there is a sign science is also an
another tool that people wield and very
effective and amazing ways and if you
can create a quality product that people
enjoy it's mostly a market thing if
people want to smoke synthetically grown
cannabis that's grown well that's their
prerogative and if I mean you know it's
more I think a personal preference I
think that cannabis as a plant enjoys
being in the soil where it's always been
but I mean I'm not gonna pass any
judgment and people do amazing jobs
growing you know and if they're
passionate about it and if they don't
use a lot of garbage and they use pure
salts they don't use any crazy chemical
additives or pesticides fungicides I
think it's probably okay and so do you
find the
being organic yourself that makes the
maintenance of your mother garden or
just your general garden for example
more easier because this is something
I'm constantly telling people is that
it's really easy to look after mother
plants in organics you know do you agree
with that yeah I mean yeah I mean if
you're not like pulling clones off of
them
relentlessly I think yeah I think it's
super easy put it in dirt you use PETA
you can even just like I'm pretty like
MacGyver like ghetto style organic
gardener like I don't have time to be
brewing seed teas and doing ferments and
all these amazing things that people are
just going for which I find fascinating
I think I love all these people doing
these crazy things but I don't have the
time I would love to be sprout and see
teas and so I pretty much just throw it
in in some good rich potting soil and
top dress with organic amendments may
make some teas here and there use a few
different things but I go for ease
because I don't have a lot of time I'm
just trying to keep everything alive I
have you know hundreds of different
strain mother plants that you know that
I kind of it's like my crayon box and do
my hardest to keep them alive but you
know if a kid gets sick or I leave on an
adventure and someone doesn't water like
you lose stuff and that's it's sad and
definitely soils probably I think it's
the most friendly I mean I know people
have systems dialed in where they can
look on their cell phone and change
things and they get there's a camera and
you know our friends are like oh I could
leave for two weeks of my hydro system
and go to Hawaii and it's I mean maybe
there's if you're like Brainiac and
you're in your super good at I mean if
conceivably the stint route could be
better but for ease and just throwing it
right in there and just giving it what
it wants its I think dirt is the best or
you know even cocoa is so hard to deal
with because it dries out so fast and I
think God made dirt and dirt don't hurt
I like that I mean kind of expanding on
that point your library I imagine that
it must contain the biggest differential
of growth between plants in anyone's
library you know you must have some
plants that grow three or four times as
quickly as others you know probably
sativa type ones do you find that you're
constantly having to kind of wrangle
these land races
compared to you know your other strains
which may be a bit more tamed yeah I
mean a lot of my it's funny Nick
the strange thing is a lot of my time I
actually goes to cloning I make every
week I'm climbing cuz I don't want to
lose something or things get too tall
anytime I cut tops off things I'm always
cloning cuz you know something can
happen or I don't have backups or you
know and you know in my mom and dad
rooms I have a couple and you know I'm
pretty loose I have the males and the
females and the team isn't in because I
try and kind of put the indicas on the
front row the sativa is in the back but
things do get crazy and they go in there
you know and they all need you know I
haven't pretty dialed where everybody
gets along and I don't feed too heavy so
everything kind of stays the way it
should but it's hard to keep a library
like it Encyclopedia Brittanica of
strains you know it's super easy to lose
things and if you're not on it you can
get bugs and things are always growing
too fast and you have to repot like it's
it's hard to I mean I I wonder how those
Botanical Gardens keep everything
together I guess they have a whole team
but it's not easy to keep a library yeah
I can relate and I'm sure mine's nothing
compared to the size of yours yes my
question was on top of having a big
library you also seem to be at least
from what I can see the breeder who
releases the most of their personal
cards was this something you
intentionally wanted to do or just
something which kind of happened through
you know just kind of generosity I guess
I mean I always like to give them to
friends and stuff but you know recently
it was weird because I you know I have
some people saying oh you should keep
your really special ones maybe you could
you know trademark rmr sell them to uh
in the future to a place you know - like
when Starbucks has their cannabis
division their special strain and you
know like but for me it's like the way
things are going like I love to see
whatever he's doing in there everybody
seems to be kind of focusing on the you
know cookie Kim sour gas thing there's a
lot of amazing things that are coming
out with that but I wanted people to
kind of experience other other plants
and a lot of people go from clones and I
thought you know what's the what better
way to not only
you know help get people understanding
chemists from a completely different
thing is to give out some special stuff
that maybe is different from other
things and that people can riff off of
our experience are like oh wow I didn't
know I could do this or wow this is that
or oh here's a stiva that's has a great
high but maybe it's quicker and for me I
was I saw everybody hoarding and I was
like you know I think I'm just gonna do
the opposite of or I'm just gonna start
giving all the way all the cool stuff
because you know you can always make new
stuff you especially if you know a good
seed collection you can always create
new stuff and that's the funny thing
about elites it's like they are all came
from seeds
it's funny how every chases these elites
but really you could find all these
things they're everywhere and this is if
you just have the time and you and
you're in the kenai and the passion you
can pretty much pull anything out of
your head and it's I think it's fun to
let to share and let people check out
new things and experience stuff so I
think I'm just trying to foster like
kind of an environment of giving and
caring and exploration and kind of like
sharing our buddy strife Fox had a
question relating to that is radio nurse
are you gonna be your main spot to kind
of release your cuts in the future well
you know it's funny he's like I've
always liked you know a few times I've
kind of taken my trays down and tried to
give them out but I don't have time to
make trays and my mom room really isn't
the cleanest place you know I'm always
battling some foreign invader that's
slipping in from our organic garden so I
[__] her like a dork trying to bring in
trays because you know you know
sometimes like at p.m. sometimes have
bugs I don't want to do that so I never
found I always wanted to give it to like
a local stream place and no one ever you
know ever everything kind of fell
through and then I met the radio rich
people and they have really good hearts
and I really like I mean it's a
male/female combo and they do a really
amazing job and I'm like yeah I would
this is a great outlet so yeah um they
have a bunch of my stuff and they're the
mostly putting it out in this area I'd
love to see people grab those clones and
take them other places and get them out
I love to see him go all over the world
and pretty soon there'll be some
supernatural selections cuts going out
and then just some more stuff and some
of you know landrace maybe some landrace
but you know people don't
really jive with it so much I kind of
just leave that to friends but a lot of
the new super natural selection stuff is
indoor friendly and it's definitely
sativa indica hybrids but they you know
they have a nominal flowering time and
they still keep their unique character
and they're usually friendly inside so I
just want people that it's really get
get exposed to new things and really get
passionate about the total spectrum yes
I mean with that kind of point in mind
would you be able to tell us some more
stuff about the Dredd bread and the oMG
that goes into that one because I've got
a friend who's grown out some hybrids of
that and we couldn't find a ton of
information on it but we could see that
it was of landrace origins so we got
excited at that but again yeah it'd be
cool to know more about that one thing
as it is popping up a lot in the tester
lines at the moment oh yeah yeah and
that was just kind of like a male and I
was like I found a good male that kind
of matched my favorite female as like
I'll just try it on some of my outdoor
stuff we gathered up from some seeds
from home some of my land rights outside
but the drug bread is kind of like the
first release of super national
selections and it's your basic f1 hybrid
between an Afghani and a Colombian so
it's mango BJ and this was like seeds
that I got from a friend who's in
Ecuador Colombia I mean mango be
Chicanos like the Blue Dream of South
America in a way it seems like everybody
grows it everybody loves it it does well
in their environment and it yeah so who
knows if it's really an heirloom or
landrace it's been around long enough
that you would it seems to be some kind
of land race or land race hybrid that's
turned into an heirloom and it does
really well and it for most of South
America so I got some seeds and grew out
the mega BJ and I found one one that was
really really turf rich and really
special and really easy to grow and it
was pretty quick for a mango VJ so I
kept that and then I have this old
Afghani line that I got seeds from a
long time ago and it was just they were
just it was just called old Afghani or
vintage Afghani then I popped those many
years ago and I got this really
beautiful Afghani expression kind of
like it almost seems like it it
be a land racer even maybe one of the
really early Dutch afghani scuzz it it's
so resonance and nice and it has this
kind of like floral all citrus thing -
it's kind of like through a while there
was these Afghan ease that came out that
we're kind of more on the citrus and you
know it seemed like true time different
varieties of Afghani have popped up from
the acrid to the like more very smelling
- like the bready to the even to the
roadkill II there's all these different
expressions and this seemed to be one I
would kind of have to pick it like in
the maybe that ease or something where
it's this highly resonance beautiful
quick very full resinous males just as
perfect breeding Afghani for like a
modern kind of mindset so taking that
mango Beach a-gonna sativa trippy rich
thing and putting it with that really
nice chubby rich Afghani I got this
really cool it's really cool hybrid and
so it kind of kind of started that as
saying like okay this is gonna be the
first super natural selections and the
funny thing is I just got we're just
starting to pack up the seeds of the new
run of the us dread bread so people
should be able to get those in a couple
weeks like then it might give away a
bunch too so people can kind of really
experience and get them excited about
these new kind of unique iPhones and get
him excited about people using them in
their programs and FM and finding stuff
and just try and just try and like
really open up that mandala of smells
and effects and things just get I don't
know I just want people to get
passionate and exposed to to the full
extreme possibilities that cannabis has
to offer and from there people to really
find what they like and really get into
their niche like that's what I find hard
with today's breeding kind of modality
is there's a few people that are really
finding their niche and enjoy driving
with it and those are the people that I
really like like you know I did I never
really had a thing for autos I was like
oh they make good house plants that are
you know great for Grandma and then you
know there's people these days that it's
fine like mefisto
like he found his niche like I'm not
gonna ottoman I've seen what he's doing
I'm like wow you with your fashion
and you're really going deep you're
making amazing things and I think people
are you know there's some some of my
friends that are doing that too you know
like Doc tea and stray Fox and snow high
and coastal seeds and Sam and all these
people they're finding their niche and
whether it's the land races or some
people just like even if you're in super
no G psyche take that thing and run with
it
or people doing it selfing s ones in
instead of just bashing up s1 hybrids
really go deep start doing s 2 s 3 s
like do some weird stuff just get into
it and really explore and find what you
like and just move forward with it and I
think that's that's kind of my whole
thing right now is to really it's kind
of like the antidote for what the tidal
wave of homogeny that's like coming and
I'm hoping that if we can just light up
on the left minds and hearts and palates
that we can kind of like reverse this
tide of like oh cool it's almost like a
global warming of cannabis you know it's
it's coming and if we can turn things
around we we can really create something
special well some answer because I love
misto as well and I actually had a
question for you anyways have you ever
come across any really cool land race
orders you know that's funny because I I
kind of have and I've heard of some
stuff too you know there's things like
Mighty Mite which is supposedly an old
nepali indica I've never seen indicas in
default so I find it a little hard but
it's one of those ones it wasn't you
know maybe I had one or a list or
something or me is about Auto but it was
one of those plants that was kind of
like semi-auto and you know in Morocco a
lot of their plants are kind of auto in
a way and I've have you know bred I've
worked with some Moroccan plants that
I've collected and I'm like oh wow I
could probably slip this in and I could
really kind of kick things into gear and
but you know I realize it's not it's not
really my thing and I'm like there's
people that are way more passionate
about it in our way more knowledgeable
about it and I respect and I'm just
letting them go for it I mean so yeah I
don't have any plans to really do autos
or really do it but there are you know
besides rules there's some Afghani
like there's that Auto Afghani there are
some plants just due to their geography
and due to their selection over time
have created some of these these
tendencies where they grow when they hit
a certain size or they grow it when they
hit a certain duration I mean it's out
there and but I think that the auto
spectrum has been pretty dialed you know
especially over in Spain there so Auto
it out and all the auto feminized now
that they've kind of got it wired
they've got these genes kind of locked
in for what they want to do especially
now in America with some of the a lot of
people here I think it's kind of a done
deal almost you know what I mean sure
and so just to loop back on another
point you made earlier about s ones or
feminized seeds how do you feel about
them you know you've never done them
yourself is that because you're not
interested or you don't feel they're as
good as regulars um you know I long time
ago I tried I got my STS and I did all
that and it was just I just made a mess
out of everything else horrible I
couldn't gonna have to work on stomach
it was just kind of more my whole thing
on it was like I wanted to unlock the
gene pool if I could s1 or s2 you can
really crack open a strain before we had
like the whole genetic testing and we
you know you could really kind of see
what was in there you could see maybe
it's parents it's grandparents you could
kind of you know that's the unique thing
about selfing stuff is you could you can
kind of see what's in there and some you
know some of my friends that do a lot as
s-1 work is they'll get you know forty
plants that look exactly alike and then
they'll get five that are like
completely different so it was this like
kind of something that was back in its
history and it's a really unique tool
but for me you know it's I know it does
happen in nature but for me I just I
don't know maybe it's just I like just
basic sexual breeding you know I just
like to bring males and females together
and that's my jam that's my niche and
that's kind of what I do you know I for
a while I was kind of down on autos I
mean I thought oh sorry boys fams
you know I didn't really understand it
as much until I met people that really
just truly had away with it you know
like inspector
he does amazing autos are Illuminati you
know incognito he does crazy I get
autist Matt riot does amazing out of
some people have then they just have the
they have a gift and they have they know
what they're doing and they push it in
different directions I'm not a big fan
of the taking like basically you're kind
of flavor of the week taking an elite
Cologne and feminizing and spraying it
on everything sure there's gonna be
unique things in that but it's kind of I
mean that's just really kind of a kind
of a short-sighted shortcut it's easy I
mean it is I guess I can't really pass
Church but it does it is cool but it's
kind of I call that kind of like your
that's kind of like the kindergarten
level of breeding because you get
because you you know not and it not an
interrogatory sense I mean like as a kid
like you're so excited you want to have
fun you want it fast you want to see
what this does what happens if you know
I put this Lego on this like it's great
it served its purpose but I think it's I
think some of the deep magic comes from
the real work that people put into stuff
so I think something is you know I used
to not think it was that great now
people have changed my mind people
change my mind every day that's what I
love about this community is people when
they're passionate and they find their
niche they truly can create magic that
hasn't happened before so I give them
props to everyone that does that yeah
it's interesting you can almost reminds
me of like a spray-and-pray
type of approach interesting you brought
up Matt you know we had Matt on the show
a little while ago I think what's most
interesting about your friendship with
him and what people seem to be
interested in at least is how kind of
polar opposite you guys are as people
you know like how did you meet Matt and
do you find in general you're drawn
towards people who are quite different
to personality-wise or do you find your
more kind of likely to hang with someone
who's more similar to you you know for
friends it's I think more similar I've
definitely met people online and
in-person that you know that we're much
differently probably wouldn't be friends
if we didn't have can cannabis their
lives to geek out on but really you know
if people are if people are cool to me
I'm called amide
try and create an attitude I try and
meet people at a basic human level you
know people don't rub me on the wrong
way or they you know arrogant or this
and that but if someone is is really
themselves they have a personality
they're even a character like I'll give
them the space to be who they are and
format like you know I met back in kind
of the older forum days when it was more
of a small community and he was doing
something really cool he was working you
know he was he was trying to create a
medical Garden for patients and I think
this is where he got a lot of the bad
rap is he was started to ask a lot of
readers for seeds cuz he wanted to do a
lot of different stuff for this this
medical garden that he was part of and
it you know was very altruistic and I
was like sure and a lot of people said
sure and I guess it all fell through and
and it didn't happen and he still had
the seeds but that's okay people give
seeds altruistically and I think they
may later on maybe he was you know there
was an auction and maybe one or two of
those seed packs came up and that's like
watching your people see it's like who
cares what they do with them and I think
people got uptight and they you know and
then all these rumors started and then
as people come on later in life they
don't really go back and look at the
actual information they just hear the
rumors and take him for a Point Blank
and I know that he rubs people the wrong
way but he that's his service I think in
Arkansas community where there's many
characters and there's many people that
have vital positions and his service is
to call people out and not taking EBS
and to be a bunker and [__] [__] and I
you know I I think if we have a place
for everybody and I know people some
people hate him some people love he's a
great guy we share a lot of stuff on
music and he's got a kind heart but he
doesn't take any BS and I kind of like
him for that and I like him for that he
he doesn't take a lot of flack and he
almost you know I he's almost like a
punching bag a lot it I think a lot of
people are spared because he takes a lot
of the hits and I think that he's vital
in a way to keeping everything fresh and
fluid I think everybody plays a pardon
if everybody comes you know if
everybody's communicating from their
mind in their heart
there's room for everybody and I like
that I think he's a cool guy and I would
get along great and there's a there's a
lot of characters like that in the can
in this world that are kind of where our
personalities are kind of a lot
different but we share a passion for
things and I think that's in any
community so yeah I cherish those kind
of characters and people in our
community they're a lot different that
are kind of pushing things just add to
that we also love Matt and ease take no
[__] attitude so just on a bit of a
different topic when is a project done
for you you know I use someone who sets
deadlines on things do you think well if
it's not working by this point I'm gonna
move on or do you kind of go by feel and
you think now I'm gonna stick with it
till it feels like it's done you know
for me I have lots of projects like I do
a lot of grid work and then for my kind
of personal projects where I'm doing you
know people don't think I really line
read that much but I have a lot of
different things I've lined bread I just
kind of keep them more for myself as my
own breeding tools or to make them more
inbred so they can use them with other
inbred things I don't really release so
much library stuff because I really it's
my personal work that I make kind of for
myself or for my toolbox and you know
recently I kind of got some flack online
and I realized okay so you know I hear
what people saying and and I get it and
and so now I'm kind of like oh I'm gonna
start you I'm gonna start letting out
some of my line work you know I have a
my purple unicorn lion is like it f4 and
I think my dragon's blood is it the five
or six and I have you know have some
Lucky Charms I have a lot of my strains
I'm bred out and I think you know
especially as things go extinct
I might start releasing some of my line
bred stuff my whole theory was that I
like to people to buy f1 hybrids to get
something special and then if they want
to go deeper in spawn they can do f2 s
and they can find things that look like
just like the parents and they can
really pick out what they like not what
I like like I'm not trying to tell you
what school I'm trying to give you a
maximum gene pool to work with so you
can really find what you like and that
was my whole thing but now I'm finding
that people kind of do want to know what
kind of iLike and what I'm pushing
things too so I'm gonna release some of
my kind of like my more worked lines and
out there so that makes people having a
hope that they can use them in their own
programs so with that in mind do you
have a preferred type of project like do
you find that f ones bring you the most
kind of happiness or do you like to lime
breed but you know you just don't see it
as necessarily fit for public release
like what how would you rank things in
terms of you know F ones live readings
I guess family be at the bottom by
definition you know I personally like F
ones it goes it there's something magic
about two things meeting for the first
time there's this you know and even even
nature congratulate a true f1 in hybrid
vigor like in people to if you have like
you know when the French colonized
Vietnam you get these combinations like
look at women women are amazing aren't
they the most beautiful lines I like
these they were like these walking
biological flowers and if you take and
say you're Vietnamese man and a French
woman you know in Vietnam they breed
increase these amazing special things
and I love that and that's why I like
and even my you know my philosophical
and my religious beliefs are based in
this kind of combination of energy and
awareness or basically male and female
these polarities and I love when these
things come together and that's kind of
what I like to give out and then you
know all these other projects like I've
had a roadkill skunk project going for
years and years and years I just pit all
the way out in and I you know I do so
much work behind the scenes with all
these different kind of projects I do
have a lot of weird projects purple
projects and landrace projects and I do
a lot of I do a lot of line bringing
primarily it's just really for myself
and really for making my mic toolkit a
lot easier to deal with you know I'm a
really big proponent of making your own
tools and making your own things to work
with you know I think that's is as we
get more proficient in cannabis breeding
and combining we can really do things
that people never really even matter
you can do so for me I'd like to keep a
lot of personal projects always open
they could take years even short-term
little fun things but a majority of my
stuff does tend to be and then it's just
in those f1 hybrids and that's kind of
what the market wants like if I just did
we finally did Marika I would be leaving
out a cardboard box like you know I mean
what sells is the is these is the
mashups like the special mail and elite
mashups everybody wants the new best
thing they want the chirp every new
flavours and you know and I try and
develop my my special mails as I you
know I try and think of ahead a little
bit and see where the markets going and
see what people are into and I kind of
face my new mails on that and then I
release things and you know people say I
release a lot of stuff and I do because
I made our hell of a lot of students
I've been doing this for a long time and
I make big runs of seeds and I keep them
in the fridge i vacuum seal them and I
test them and sometimes I mean you know
things I made six years ago are just now
seeing the face of they maybe they
didn't get tested right or someone
disappeared or I never got around to
them and so when things good things come
about as when I usually release them and
it seems to work and it gives the
illusion of this massive workflow when
really it's just this dance through time
and and selection that was my cat yeah
yeah so if we just jump into the idea of
lion breeding a little further I've had
a few questions from people regarding
the sunshine daydream if it'll ever be
done as a line as opposed to our crosses
because obviously there's some hybrids
of it floating around at the moment we
ever consider F doing at f3 in it yeah
yeah you know I think I do I'm big
searching through lines in the summer
when I can have them outside and then
sometimes I'll bring them inside you do
like i'll utilize our outdoor season buy
into like threes on plant stuff early
and when it gets mature I'll throw it in
my flower room and I'll kind of do that
three times so I can really move through
a lot of stuff and you know maybe next
year you know each year I pick I pick a
couple of my lines and I really kind of
look deep to see what's going on and
this year
was a I did a big dirty hippie seed pop
which is basically you know I mean dirty
hippie f2 and then I also did a big
tiger melon so those are kind of the two
right now that I'm kind of going through
and seeing if I want to take it further
and couldn't see what it opens up in the
f2 so yeah I think any line that that is
really special
I can always revisit it and I really do
and that's definitely sunshine daydream
it is one that I really love and I would
love to just do it just so I can get
another cup cut back because through
time and space I've lost both of my
favorite females so I'm kind of I don't
even have any sunshine JJ man it is a
really special plan in how it works with
the body and how it eases like the
neurological pain that people have and a
lot of it seemed it seems to be like one
of my more medical orientated strains
even more so than like the good medicine
or the barefoot doctor and some of those
CBD rich ones like it is a really
special strand that's kind of why I
retired that male I didn't go for it
because it's like it's a strain where
it's like I don't think anything's
absolutely perfect but it's one of the
strains that kind of stands on its own
and it doesn't really need to be made to
be messed with and I kind of only hold
that sunshine day gmail back out again
because through a mishap I lost the mail
that I was going to use on a pollination
and I was like well you know I have this
really old sunshine day tree mail that I
use a long time for the go for the
sunshine for and stuff I'm just gonna
throw it in there you know it's a great
plant it should make some really fun
stuff and that's how this kind of came
about and then I decided to kind of kill
that mail so that those will be some
really special and people can kind of go
through them and that also too that it
makes me want to go through more and
really dig deeper into lines and I think
that's really nice kind of like going
it's kind of like you know visiting an
old lover in a way you know it's like
there's a cherish then and you get to
come back and you know there's a
familiarity you kind of know what you're
looking for by the same time you're
excited and it feels so good and so do
you still have the Barbra Jean I don't
know you know that's sad that's when I
lost and I lost the proper shine now and
the funny thing is the story about the
Appalachia Mail would have never been
used if I wouldn't have lost
buhbuh shine mail at the last second the
bombs shine was gonna be the big
pollinator that of all those hybrids
that were the Appalachia so I just lost
the female to Dedinje which is a strange
thing that really drives me nuts that's
kind of affecting a lot of people that
no one seems to really know what it is
but I have made it quite a bit of
hybrids with it and I actually have a
new male I'm kind of looking into right
now I'm playing around with it's a
bubble shine Instant Karma cross so
that's kind of my current bubble shine
kind of play around with kind of thing
I'm doing okay you mentioned your CBD
projects when if CBD kind of sit for you
in the scheme of breeding you know I
know that the CBD lines you have
released in the past were mostly
freebies and there's some information
around them that you released you know
just kind of saying oh you know I had
these laying around I just wanted to get
him out to people do you plan to restock
those or potentially work them further
and the reason why I ask is is because I
had a friend who had good medicine and
he thought it was just like the best
plan he'd ever had just even in you know
a recreational sense sorry and um and he
was really bummed out he lost and I was
like damn it'd be good to get some more
of those yeah I mean I go get you some
ice I still have kind of all I think I
made like I think I liked a dozen CBD
maybe more maybe like 15 different CBD
hybrids you know originally it was more
two six exploring that medical side I
was but when I first made the good
medicines it was back before everybody
was in-situ CBD there was only really
harlequin and then I don't know if ac/dc
was in the state so much then and I was
like you know I want to explore this I
want it you know I my emphasis on really
for me is like I love recreational I
love medical but really my thing is I
want to create spirit nourishing strains
like strains that awakened something
inside you that that's kind of either
dormant or your that you're cultivating
but for CBD I was so interested and that
was right around the time that SC labs
opened in our and our in Santa Cruz kind
of where I live and I was like you know
what this is cool I'm gonna try this out
I you know I took in my samples I took
in my early leaf
samples for my mails he was like six
years ago
five years ago found that and played
around and I was really excited to see
Wow like it was just another one this
thing's like what is gonna happen and
with the good medicine you know I found
a CBD rich male and I took it to the f2
and then I released those and then with
that I I started pollinating a lot of
stuff with a good medicine a lot of the
other CBD clones are coming out like the
aam Rita and the ac/dc and then even
things like heroin and think special
things I made a CBD og one that people
liked and then the the logical
conclusion for like I really I was like
okay sunshine daydreams by like one of
my favorite pain relieving strains what
if I made a CBD rich sunshine a dream
and that's what kind of barefoot doctor
is and that's kind of the one I think I
will push forward if I do but you know I
give I think I've given away over
yeah thousands of paksy seeds for free
because I don't really I think it's
funny when people charge a lot of money
for the CBD rich strains like I know
that's our Trojan horse to get get
cannabis into like basically all of
America that have been like totally
brainwashed if there's a plant that can
heal their kids that can heal their
grandparents we get give those seeds out
like you know I think somebody should
just devote a whole warehouse and just
pump out a million CB seeds get those
things everywhere like it's truly our
Trojan horse to get into the hearts and
minds of people that have no clue and so
my whole thing is I don't spend as much
time on the CVD work is because I just
give it all away free and I usually
always try and make each pollination run
a couple CBD strains like I'll usually
throw in an ac/dc or Harlequin into
anything I'm making but for my specific
CBD projects I think the good medicine
and the perfect doctor were like the
ones that I really put enough the most
time into and I love it when I see
people make more of those or use those
in their own project like I think the
medical aspect is amazing and it's
beautiful and I really think that's one
of the ways that we're really gonna see
cannabis basically become our main plant
oil and earth like it's always been
since you know the the dawn of time and
so which kind of a nursery which CBD
strain do you like to work with the most
I guess in in all regards
I mean I've personally have had ac/dc
and I thought that was fantastic and
then on the other hand I've heard
breeders say that Charlotte's Web for
example while being a great strain
doesn't particularly work very well for
breeding or at least I heard that in the
sense that it's not very true breeding
like not a lot of the resulting seeds
will carry those really high CBD traits
so at least I'm told that with that in
mind which kind of CBD cuts to shine
more - or do you find work better for
your projects well I think I mean I
think white Charlotte's Web doesn't
totally work out is because it wasn't
like a finished product it I think those
guys kind of heisted it from another
breeder that was working on CBD rich
plants and I don't think he'd fully it
was just a one-off of one of the stuff
and I think he's perfected I think it's
from a man in Colorado who that we all
know and love and in his name has a
numeric number in it um but I don't want
to ruffle any feathers so I think that's
probably why you see Charlotte's Web
doesn't work is I think it wasn't a
fully realized line I think it was
something that is kind of grabbing
around with high personal II like
Harlequin myself because it does seem to
be true being it's not it's not coming
from Spain and that whole z7 like that
whole you know CBD crew and they tend to
be kind of territorial and about their
stuff and they tend to be a little you
know a little bit snooty so I try and
stay away from any kind of drama and
Harlequin was brought to America by uh I
think it's a seed fund by Wayne weight
laughter and it's an old I think it's a
Dutch or Swiss or some kind of old
combination that they had there that
just Express that and it's kind of the
first one we had in California and I
think even in the States and I've always
kind of just connected more with that
and it you know and it's a beautiful
plan and it has it's very resinous and
you know ACDC is awesome it really pumps
the CBD and it's very true reading it
really crushes it on that but it it's
kind of like a wily kind of almost
sativa like plant you know it's a pretty
kind of just a giant bush and I mean
I've made some crosses with it that it
come out great and I've kind of tame the
beast but I think if I had to choose a
CBD rich cultivar it would probably be
the Harlequin although you know coastal
seeds he's finding that some of their
Panama red work is coming up rich in CBD
which is really amazing and you know
that kind of goes back to the whole
adage of people like oh yeah Panama red
that's awful Nakia that was like the
tequila bud like it you know even back
in the day Panama red was kind of known
as kind of like this knock you on your
ass stuff and that makes sense that it
maybe was a sativa that had some level
of kind of us CBD in it yeah if we just
take step back and look at just breeding
in general not necessarily CBD how do
you find the location of where you breed
affects things do you find that when you
I mean obviously there's going to be
physical differences I've read that I
believe it was the China un strain on
one of your Instagram posts said it
doesn't particularly perform well
indoors so we put that bit aside instead
let's look at the breeding aspect if you
were to try to read that plant indoor do
you think that would have you know kind
of epigenetic effects on the seeds
resulting it's like so do you think that
landrace lines should be ideally bred
outside if possible because it's gonna
you know maybe be more synergistic with
their genetics or what's your feeling on
this I mean you know back like ten years
ago I would say that they probably I
mean that's a tough line so I don't know
I think that you can with if you put
your will to anything I think you can
work with the plant and basically get it
to perform anywhere and I think that
before during prohibition most people
were growing inside so it was important
to to try and push that gene pool into
more harmonious expressions inside like
you wanted to try you need definitely
landraces freaked out like especially
ones that you you know like I have a lot
of problems when I bring then races from
like the Himalayas and I plant them
straight out here at sea level like they
go cuckoo they don't know what's going
on there like they're used to being up
in these high elevations in this certain
environment and all the sudden now
they're in the fog line not the beach
like they really tweak out so I think
you can create
a more harmonious environment for them
indoors if you're really catering to
them but I think it's important though
to if you are going to make landrace
hybrids that they are stable indoors
like that's the whole that's why super
natural selection has been so hard it's
taking so long to release all these
things that's because it's not easy to
to mate landraces and expect them to do
well inside like they do crazy stuff
they do weird stuff there
they're very hermaphroditic indoors they
you know and that's the whole thing with
my road kill
stunt project I can make sure I make
plants that smell like roadkill and get
you super high and then I mean they hit
all the you know they've got all the
eyes and they check all the boxes but
they they don't like to be indoors like
for some reason the one I'm working on
it's just it's about finding the
specific out cost they don't things a
lot of things just don't like being in
an artificial environment and they
express that so I think there is some
magic in really working a line indoors
to remove that from athletes traits but
also outdoors if you can you can create
some amazing heirlooms if you say say
you went to Thailand and you were in
Chiang Rai or something and you got a
sack of pot and you got some seeds and
you loved it and you brought it home and
you've grown it outside in your garden
it may tweak out it may hurt him out the
first time you grow it but and you find
your favorites you breed those and get
the seeds you grow it again after three
or four times of it experiencing a new
environment it's gonna reprogram itself
and it's gonna adapt to the new
environment and it's going to slowly
become your kind of a personal heirloom
so it's all about I mean it's about
doing the work really on those things
it's you know it's not just taking these
these hyper chirpy amazing plants that
are all been bred indoors that are you
know in slap them together that's it's
easy but trying to get things that are
from completely different environments
and bringing him together and anew and
thing is really difficult it's like that
it was like that Eddie Murphy movie
wasn't he was like an African king and
they dropped him off in New York
King of Queens or something like that
yeah it's like the same thing you get a
plant and then you drop it off here yeah
I do some work on that thing you can't
you know it's yes
strange things happen and that's the
beauty that's why I really tell people
it's like explore the gene pool you know
click seeds collect as many seats you
can't trade seeds like get a good seat
collection find crazy cultivators travel
like really give yourself all the
colours you can to create your your art
you know and also don't let anybody ever
tell you that you're breathing the wrong
way like that's one thing I you know I
have deep respect for all the
horticultural science people and I have
a background kind of in that that I but
really you know no one can tell you how
to breed the proof is in the pudding if
you can create something good with your
skills and either way you do it then
that's all that matters and it's like
you don't need a Mendel square you need
like you need good senses you need an
open heart open mind you need to create
awareness with the plant and you can do
anything you never let anyone and all
these people like oh you know I went to
horticultural science that's beautiful
you know you can learn all about a
paintbrush you can learn all about paint
you can learn all about canvas but that
doesn't make you a good artist so I say
people just followed a passion grab you
know really get into this and really
make it something that nourishes you and
your community and don't let anyone tell
you what to do and also don't tell
anybody what they can't do everybody
needs to get along and really and really
do this I think we have a great
community and a great future ahead of us
if we can just keep our eyes on the
prize so I think you already answered it
a little bit with that last answer but
what would be your advice for a new
breed oh and by this I mean someone
who's maybe thinking about getting into
breeding not someone who's just started
I would say you know for new breeders is
a start growing planets grow a lot of
different plants find what you enjoy
find what you like and then kind of
stick to that like if there's a plant
that speaks to you or a certain strain
then yeah take that work with that maybe
mix it with something else you like
filled up your seed collection trade
trade clones you know really get into
that form of community make friends like
I think that's the best thing and you
know what as you as a beginner give away
seeds make cool stuff give away your
seeds get the hype
it's like and you know I also too is
like for me I don't call myself a
breeder I call myself kinda like a
artist or I kind of just work with the
plant maybe I'm just a plant helper I
really think that using your senses and
you've been using your sixth sense like
my the whole thing I think is like a
heart race breeding it's like you know
there you have your five senses but you
also have a sixth sense that sense of
kind of this knowing and that's
basically your heart you know your heart
has an electromagnetic force five
thousand times bigger than your mind it
radiates out like five feet and I think
that's where people you know they get a
where you can kind of feel things out
and if you can tune into that that's
where you can connect with nature that's
also where people get their sixth sense
or that was funny feeling about
something and they connect with
something that's like the hearts
electromagnetic field interacting with
other things and I think cultivating
that and cultivating our awareness of
yourself and the plant just being a good
person and being friendly and being
humble I think that's the best way to
start out breeding and just if you have
passion and you have your senses intact
then you're here all the way there
pretty much you just gotta move forward
[Music]
[Applause]
stay tuned far2
[Music]
[Applause]
you