foreign
[Music]
gang we're back as always you're joined
by your boy heavy days here from the
upside down library and on this episode
we've got our massive fourth installment
with the Mendocino Master old school
legend not so dog massive shout out to
not so dog for joining us today
and as usual we want to give a massive
shout out to our incredible sponsors who
helped make the episodes happen seeds
here now you know them you love them
they got all the hottest breeders all
the latest drops if you're looking to
get some quality genetics look no
further with a guarantee on satisfaction
and not just germination why would you
go anywhere else if you buy seeds from
them you do a grow and you're not happy
with the results at the end hit them up
they'll Square you up I heard you can
get some heavy days packs a few of them
even sold out so get in there quick
seeds here now your number one seed bank
likewise check out our good buddies at
cope at biological systems if you're
looking to produce a Next Level Harvest
you simply have to keep your garden Pest
and pathogen free it makes sense to
periodically release beneficial
Predators if you're worried about spider
mites check out the spidex vital if
you've got aphids check out the RP param
these products are second to none copit
are the world leaders in Pest and
predation technology huge shout out to
our friends at Copper biological systems
we appreciate you so much thanks for
helping to keep both ours and
everybody's Gardens running on all
cylinders pests and pathogen free
likewise a massive shout out to our
buddies at Pulse sensors these guys have
the latest sensor technology to ensure
your Garden's parameters are in check
from VPD to ppsd all the variables you
can't measure with a simple thermometer
or your eyes will help you to fine-tune
your next crops to be superior if you're
looking for increased yield resin
cannabinoids terpenes trust me guys
you've got to get yourself a pulse
sensor and they've recently released the
pulse Hub you're gonna have to pre-order
that one guys integrating all of the
units together to make sure that whether
you've got a single tent a single room
or a multi-state operation your crop is
going to be the best today get serious
get a pulse
you've heard me talk about it guys shout
out to the newest sponsor Organics a lot
truly incredible organic powdered
fertilizer if you're looking for an easy
solution while growing in soil they have
it it is not hard to see why they are at
the top of their game I highly recommend
it for all the organic Growers out there
give it a try you will not be
disappointed your plants will be next
level
and a massive shout out to our newest
sponsors Dino vast they are an
incredible Vape company based out of USA
producing some of the most coolest
engineering and bait technology you've
seen for a while I cannot speak highly
enough about dynavat's products if
you've ever had a vape and wished it was
able to replicate the head of a joint or
a bong check out Dinobot they're second
to none for good reason we're really
stoked to be working with dying about
huge shout out guys and last but not
least a massive shout out to the patreon
gang we love you so much truly the
lifeblood to show if you're looking to
get early access to upcoming episodes if
you want to hear exclusive patreon only
content with guests the like of Mr Bob
Bodie meme Gene trichome jungle 707 seed
bank it goes on and on we've also
started giving away genetics on the
Discord every fortnight come check out
the patreon guys
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast we really appreciate it much
love to the patreon Gang
huge shout out to not so dog for giving
us so much of his time we're very
grateful here to talk all things history
reading politics
and so so much more so without further
delay
one thing I found really interesting
about what you just said there was you
know you said that the chem 4 you think
it might have like some nl5 Haze in it
and you've said that the D is probably
the 91 crossed to the super skunk
so then my question becomes what do you
think the 91 is like you know we
discussed in our first part that it may
or may not be the park but I'd love to
hear just even generally like Afghani
and uh what sort of Vibes do you think
it'll be
well it's a great mystery but what I
will say
is that
um
CSI and I have this Theory
that
possibly
the chem 91 itself is an S1 already
because when we he when it when it got
S1
those seeds are so uniform
right like there's there's you know
there's some variance and potency and
there's a little bit of variance in
flavors and stuff like that but the look
and the growth pattern and all that it's
like very narrow
yeah right
um and so and that's you know that's
obviously observation
it's weird in the sense that
uh I'll bring up his name again or
whatever but uh because he's just so
prolific but he's told me that basically
there's almost nothing in his collection
that passes on potency
as consistently as the chem 91.
yeah you know that it you know it
doesn't look that great and a lot of
times it's it's dark it's not that
Frosty you know it has these weird
leaves that likes to eat itself
sometimes and you know like the leaves
yellow and look all funky and start
dying on you and stuff but the actual
weed itself
um you know it really is potent it
affects most humans pretty strongly
right and so
I you know I don't actually believe it's
related to the puck at all
um I've seen I've grown the puck I've
grown hybrids of the puck
um I know there's a rumor that it's like
you know and some people strongly
believe that it's from Oregon and that
like there was this dog Bud that got
crossed to the puck and that's what they
got
um again that would be the type of thing
that the puck lives
right and so does the chem 91 and so if
we ever get genetic testing that's that
specific one would hope they'd be able
to tell mother and child
but I don't see very many growth
similarities or Buzz similarities in it
um
you know at the at the first uh you you
actually visited us the the
um at one of our uh can Illuminati
parties that happened after Emerald cup
um at the the second year but that for
the year before that that you weren't at
uh you know I had all these kinds of
theories about it and CSI was like
what if it's just an S1 what if it's
just an NL leaning S1 of nl5 haze
[Music]
and I was like [ __ ] you know I didn't
want to believe it but
um it's that's the funny thing about it
is there's so little known you can
almost insert your pet Theory into it
and uh
you know because we don't know the
grower
the as far back as we can trace the chem
um are the middlemen
at best
so there's nothing verifiable on what it
was really uh we we do know that it came
that it was weed in 1991
and so you can look at you know uh
strains or around back then and you can
try to think of this or that or whatever
I wouldn't Hazard to guess
um but to me I've always kind of
considered it as some kind of throwback
ancient Afghan
some kind of like weird Kush
you know
um
just because it was you know
it's its effect is so Indica it is a
little taller than a lot of afghans
you know it has some stretch to it
um which is unusual but I wouldn't
Hazard to guess because you know I was
just barely starting to smoke weed back
then and I don't think we uh you know I
think our best hope is for genetics to
prove the relationships between these
things but that won't necessarily tell
us where it came from
that'll just tell us what came after
sure yeah I can agree and just to
quickly clarify because you sort of
alluded to it but I'd love to just get
it firmly because I remember I asked
skunk bi the same thing
do you think that the chemdog does have
some amount of sativa component in its
lineage
I could buy that yes
I could
yeah very interesting it's Paul you know
in in a sense
um it's kind of it's kind of lanky uh
you know uh it's it's certainly not some
like squat Afghan thing like the puck or
like
um like purple Urkle or you know
something that like grows super slow and
super tight inner nodes has a certain
amount of stretch to it
um I take it 10 weeks
so it goes you know
um 70 I know there's debate on when to
take it I take it upper 60s you know 70
days that's when I find to be the
potency to be the best for me
you know there's been people that have
started taking it earlier because it
tests higher earlier
in terms of like THC percentage
um but I don't care about THC percentage
I care about my preferences
you know so
um and it seems like when you take it 70
days
um it likes to fall in that like 18 to
22 percent range
but if you take it in at 55 days it
tests at like 29 percent
but I think it's worse wheat yeah
interesting I mean you're a good person
to ask this one to what sort of genetics
in general do you think pair really well
with the chem dog style genetics do you
think like so for example do you think
sort of pairing it with other cushy
similar sorts of plants do you think
really radically different crosses tend
to do pretty well from your experience
what do you think are good pairs usually
reading in general radically different
is all is usually better than very
similar
as a general rule
um you know
I've gone on record saying this a whole
bunch uh I think uh chem skunk
is unbelievable hybrid
you know
um because chem brings you know skunk
tends to not be that potent really
um chem brings the potency and the skunk
brings Aromas and it brings Frost and it
brings you know some stretch and stuff
like that so uh I am a big proponent of
crossing radically different things and
seeing what comes out uh I don't think
that sometimes when you cross things
that are too similar to one another you
don't actually get that much interesting
progeny
you know and I think that's kind of
happened with cookies
uh where they crossed way too many of
the similar things together for too long
and they lost certain aspects of of
quality in there and then they can't
find them again
so I think the best thing for chem dog
to cross to is something that you think
is like got really good growth traits
and is really terpy but maybe lacks
potency
and you want some added heft to the bud
and you want to add some potency
um adding potency would be the number
one reason I would cross chem dog to
something yeah you mentioned skunk in
there is a nice counterpart you've got a
decent amount of experience with the
super skunk and I'd love to ask you you
know how how would you describe the
super skunk what was it like was it like
rks to you was it something different do
you think it came from
uh the sssc skunk stock that skunk VA
talks about when he says that the story
he was told from his mentor is that it
was like an F2 of some skunk stock what
do you think it is genetically and what
was it like from your memory
uh well the
certainly the um what it's like from the
memory I'll chat about and that can just
be my personal thing
um you know I've I can I've communicated
a bit with uh I guess we'll call them
skunk va's Mentor you know uh
but he
he's kind of like a
uh older tour rainbow hippie and like a
lot of the guys that you interview or
talk to that bred in the 80s they didn't
really keep very good notes
and they kind of hodgepodged things
together
um
my understanding of it which does not
negate what he said whatever is that
you know
um dude had stuff from Neville and stuff
from SSC that was skunk
right which makes sense because in the
80s those are the really the only two
major seed banks that existed and he
crossed
um he crossed these various different
things together
okay over a number of years and he used
to call it the skunky skunk
okay and then I I believe in 1990 the
super skunk as a strain came out from
Neville
and I think that he took his skunky
skunk and crossed it to the super skunk
okay and I believe when some people call
it the skunk six or whatever that was
this the number six Fino of that cross
now could it have been he made that
cross to the super skunk and then made
f2s and then it popped out of there too
sure you know
um he's light on detail when it comes to
that and I do believe that you know uh
skunk VA you know he told a different
story a long time ago and I don't think
it has anything to do with lying or
anything like that I just think it's
like different pieces of information
come to you at different times
right
um and on top of that the guy that made
it got into some trouble uh with some uh
you know some Grateful Dead types things
and went on the run for a while
so it wasn't like dude was around okay
um when it comes to my own experiences
I'll just I'll say this
um it was lime green
uh it was fast I would say it was done
about eight weeks
okay
um if you took it longer it had a
tendency to harm
uh the Herms had live pollen
right and it sometimes would Herm early
so but that makes sense right because it
takes four or five you've made seeds it
takes four or five weeks after
pollination for a full seed to form
so if you pull down some chem dog or you
pull down some super skunk and there's
tiger striped viable seed in there at 60
days
that pollination had to happen
much earlier right so
um the super skunk wasn't the end-all
be-all that everybody makes it out to be
um it wasn't
it was moderate potency
right
um it grew fast it was very lime green
it was very frosty it it was it was
light and what I mean by that is like
you could put a really big bud on a
scale and you would be surprised at how
little it weighed
like it was it was I don't want to say
dense it was like well-formed
but not particularly dense
right you know uh and You Know It uh it
didn't smell like skunk at all in veg
but as it grew I would say probably two
three weeks before you harvested so
maybe like week six on
it was a real problem how bad it smelled
I mean people talk about like that lost
skunk terp I remember pulling up in my
driveway
with my windows down and getting out of
my car and being like Oh no
it was kind of like in the era before
carbon filters a lot of people actually
stopped growing it because it was a bust
it was really really hard to contain the
aroma in humans typically have a really
sensitive nose to that kind of that kind
of like
Funk that kind of skunk you know
um and so I could not you know people
talk about carbon filter Killers you
know this was before carbon filters but
I could not contain the smell
I couldn't it the last couple weeks a
harvest it was like before Harvest it
was like oh man you know uh I would pump
it into my attic I would put it through
like
um you know UV generators and then have
like a 30-foot run and tubing to let the
UV try to kill it I would blow it in my
garage I would do all these different
things because it was kind of the era
before carbon filters became popular it
still reeked to high heaven
it rigged like crazy
um and what was interesting about that
is I didn't know I didn't nobody in my
circle ever talked about terpenes or
anything like that but today I would say
that the thing that made it skunky was
pretty volatile
in the sense that
the two weeks before Harvest it wreaked
during Harvest it reeked and for that
first three or four weeks after you cut
it it really stank but the older it got
the more generic green weed it became
right
um and you know it was best fresh
like as soon as you could get it to burn
that was when it was the best in fact
Staten Island and I we used to grow it
you know um
we used to grow rooms of it together and
we would like the the dog often because
it was denser it often took three or
four weeks of like drying and curing
before it got like its best self
yeah
so we would often smoke Super Skunk
incessantly
for two or three weeks
until
the chem dog kind of came into its own
because we learned if we smoked the chem
dog too fresh it just wasn't as good of
an experience as if we waited
and if you waited too long for the Super
Skunk it got worse so if I used to if I
made hash from the skunk it would
actually keep in the jar it would keep
the skunk Aroma for a while but I can
remember smoking a bunch of like six
seven eight week old super skunk
and like the flavor was mostly gone and
it would almost go to like generic green
weed
so whatever the terpenes or whatever the
theols or whatever the components that
made that aroma
they were somewhat volatile and maybe
they oxidized and they were they only
lasted for a period of time
in fact when I was talking to you about
um
uh you know what would I breed chem dog
to the whole idea of breeding chemdog
and skunk together was to get the frost
and the stretch and the lime green and
the flavor of the skunk
onto something more potent
because it wasn't that potent I bet if
you I bet if we had it today and you
were testing it it would probably come
out in the mid teens
and I don't think I don't think it would
be nearly as potent as like death star
or TK or sour diesel or you know I mean
to me Sour Diesel is chem skunk
at its at its core that to me was was
the Super Skunk the super skunk was not
a perfect strain it harmed
um it's uh and then obviously sometimes
too it's like when it Herms it's like
back then it wasn't such a big deal but
even still if you had little white seeds
or little immature anything in the weed
people were gonna complain
um a lot of people got rid of it because
of how it smelled and a lot of people
got rid of it because they got tired of
occasionally it herming out and throwing
a bunch of live pollen on their plants
and creating
immature to mature seeds like obviously
when you're trying to grow uh seedless
getting seeds is a pain in the ass
and um it's one of those things about
preservation where now for the last 10
15 years people have been falling all
over each other to try to find that terp
when there was a lot of people that had
that terp back in the day
and chose to go in a different direction
with weed than that
in fact when I got in trouble and I lost
it
um I couldn't get anybody to help me
back it up
to be fair
people wouldn't help me back it up there
you go there you go and look you
mentioned the sour diesel being skunk
Cam and something I certainly noted
myself was that when I look at those
early Polaroid skunk VA took of the
super skunk that structure undeniably
looks like the sour d but I've also
heard you and many other people talk
about how sour d supposedly comes from
the diesel II so I'd love to hear how
does that all play together do you think
it's like just skunk onto chem or do you
think how do you think that plays into
diesel too
well again
um is one of those things that genetic
testing is the only real way to solve
the debate but if I had to make an
educated guess not being there I would
say that uh we'll call them weasel I
would say that the weed that weasel had
um was from Greg
and Greg was growing according to his
conversations with Staten Island he was
growing hybrids of skunk
Cam that he loved
and that skunk tended to throw Herms
into its progeny right and according to
you know uh swell and vondo they were
buying sacks of this weed and they were
collecting you know they found some
seeds 12 or 15 seeds over the course of
x amount of of purchases over time right
and that's what they popped that became
diesel one and Diesel 2.
right and then apparently
it harmed and they found seeds in diesel
too that lead to
sour
so I'm not going to sit here and and
claim you know uh that I know all the
steps and again it was young Partiers
and there was some different things
going on and it's a multi-stage accident
none of it was intentional
right
um but you know when I look at Sour
Diesel or the diesel family I can see
both parents
I can see skunk and I can see cam in it
does that mean it's the only thing in it
I can't say that for sure
but you know I've grown
um I've grown
you know uh M now for
I don't know 20 plus years right easily
and uh I grew the skunk for quite some
time
um the sour the original Sour Diesel
cutting I have even does the same weird
Leaf rust eating itself thing that
chem91 does
and then sometimes you crack a jar or
Sour Diesel and just reeks like skunk
you know and you see that like you said
you see that structure
there's an undeniable similarity right
like if you've seen Sour Diesel Spears
and you look at some of those old
Polaroids from skunk VA
it's not a big stretch to say that man
that spear really kind of looks like a
diesel spear
yeah so I'm not saying I know the
complete recipe to Sour Diesel but I
would say that the basis of it or a
large percentage of its genetics are
chem skunk
I would bet money I would bet money yeah
certainly certainly and then so I guess
the next question is what do you think
the differences are between some of the
more popular Sour Diesel Cuts you know
so you hear about Sour Diesel you hear
about East Coast Sour Diesel the
charcoals cut all these other ones do
you think they're most likely just s1s
of each other or do you think some of
them are just like hybrids but very much
leaning and then as a final follow-up do
you think the very original Sour Diesel
is still with us or what we have
circulating nowadays is all sort of
offspring
um
okay well I'll take that in chunks I
would say that this I can say for a fact
is that when Sour Diesel Sour Diesel was
probably the most popular strain in
America
for at least 10 years
okay in Mendocino County and Humboldt
out here
like there's a lot of strains now where
there's sort of like the the demand
might be high but it's also shallow
right
where in the sense with Sour Diesel and
it's heyday
if you had good Sour Diesel it was
basically endless the amount that you
could move
and nobody cared about lineage the I've
had I got a sour diesel cut on 2000 and
it came helpfully labeled sourdie
I don't know anything about its history
before that but what I can say is that
in that era it basically if it had the
nose and it had the look
like you know it's like a broker would
come by and they would open up the the
contractor bag of turkey bags and they
would stick their nose in it and they
would look up and they would be like
this is gonna work
like they'd still look at it but like
they it's like if the nose hit them that
strongly it's like they knew it was
going to work so
in the first wave of Sour Diesel nobody
cared about names it was like there was
one Sour Diesel cut and then like if
your broker liked it that was the cut
forums came into play like much like
you know the dog gets called the skunk
uh VA cut
because he was the first person on the
Forum sort of hyping it up
in a way right and like forums add names
to things
right
um like the choco cut
was the cut of Sour Diesel that came
from choco
the Amish cut was the cut of Sour Diesel
that came from
from shroomy
the res cut
you see what I'm saying
so it's like it's almost like a tie to
like well you know who spread it out or
who'd you get it from
and what happened is is that
no one really cared back in the day what
the lineage was
then Sour Diesel sort of got supplanted
a bit by cookies and Skittles and all
that and now it's sort of had another
wave in the sun in the last three or
four years and everyone's gotten
incredibly interested in the oldest
realest best diesel cut out there
but the problem is there's not like 15
or 20 cuts that have sour diesel
attached to them
I did in 2017 or something like that I
did this sour experiment where I was
like all right I'm gonna see I think my
headband is a renamed sour or something
like that maybe I got my Sour Diesel I'm
going to gather up all these sours and
I'm going to grow them side by side
indoor and in my greenhouses and I'm
going to figure out which ones mine are
and which ones are which ones are just
the same but different names
so I gather up eight or nine of them and
I grow them all side by side and they're
all [ __ ] different
and none of them are mine and I'm like
well
man you know and so there's East Coast
Sour Diesel there's New York City Diesel
there's choco there's Amish there's
um res cut there's you know there you
can go through the list now the last
four or five years there's been Albany
you know Manny this that whatever else
and from what I understand from what
Vando and swell and Manny and these
other guys say
I don't think there was just one cut
even in the beginning
right like there was diesel one and two
and then you know he found Sour Diesel
in a bag of diesel too
but there was a few seeds
right and then Vando took according to
vondo he took some of those same seeds
and when he moved West he popped some of
them in LA
resdog did this thing which annoys the
crap out of me
which is you take a famous cut and you
make seeds with it and you name your
seed line the cut
so when RES dog is selling Sour Diesel
seeds how many of those seeds do you
think got named Sour Diesel
every one of them
right
and then when you've got a strain that's
that popular
that literally it's the most popular
strain going for probably a decade how
many bag seeds on a strain that
sometimes Harms
get found
and named
and so now it's like in the last three
or four years we've been trying to like
piece together what's what
and it's like a big family with
obviously like a lot of different cuts
involved and people have been putting on
their like Sherlock Holmes hat and
trying to sort it all out
and the deeper you go the more confusing
it gets
so far at least
and part of the problem like one of the
good things about like the chem dog
story is that Greg gave the chem dog to
Staten Island
he took it West
he ended up giving it to skunk the A and
he gave it to and you know I see
Collective got it and then I got it
right and so there's like really good
provenance of this person to this person
to this person and it ties back all the
way to the beginning
we don't really have that with sour
diesel very well
so so it's a big family with at least a
dozen to 15 cuts
that all have the d The Sour Diesel
moniker
and 25 years later we're trying to
figure it out
and everyone's convinced that they have
the oldest realist bestest
the right one the real one
ain't that the truth and you actually
must be a bit of a psychic on the
download because you predicted how I was
strategically lining these questions up
to ultimately get us to this one which
is I want to talk about res I want to
talk about splitting the art from the
artist you know I think he's a great
little uh piece to analyze for that
because I think undeniably he has to be
the person who's the most polarizing yet
equally has you know some work that is
really regarded by many to be quite
stand out and even more impressively is
that evidence has come out you know
about how he was just breeding in a few
tents and like you know like it all
seems very unimpressive which makes you
think like maybe there was some
legitimate skill involved there what's
your thoughts on the res situation in
terms of separating the art from the
artist do you have any soft spots for
his work
well you kind of have to
separate the art from the artist
because I'll tell you that in
researching
um
we have this like running joke amongst
my small group of friends when we start
battling about like the 80s or 90s or
something like that which is like which
untrustworthy [ __ ] do you put in your
corner that you're gonna go to bat for
because they all have warts
right
um and you know you look at I could pick
apart Sam Skunk Man
you could throw darts at Neville Shanti
you know you can you can I mean there's
uh you know uh Jim Ortega you know all
these different things and I'm not
throwing it out there to like knock any
of those people I'm just saying that
like humans are complicated
right and just because you do something
cool in weed
doesn't mean you're not an [ __ ]
you could be a narc you could be a wife
beater you could be a drug addict you
could be in general like not the
greatest person
and still produce cool beans that make
an impact
right
and so
um res is an interesting case in the
sense that even like my buddy high and
Lonesome will say like even long go on
the forums before all the the things
happened
he was kind of a jackass
you know he wasn't the nicest Homie by
any means right
and then you know he got supposedly you
know one of the more famous people in
weed in trouble
and he might be there's a big debate in
the community I didn't talk about this
um when we talked about the legal scene
but there's a big debate in the
community about what's knocking what's
ratting
doxing what what ethics are acceptable
right and there's a lot of people that
do things that I consider to be ratting
these days
that are perfectly that suffer no
consequences
right res is probably the person in the
community as far as like publicly being
shamed he's like the think of another
person that got publicly shamed for
ratting
he's not the only person that did it
there's a list
you know yeah just to your last question
like who else is being shame that much
like no one really no one you know
um you know so should should he be
excluded uh you know do I think he
deserves like some kind of extra special
you know you're a scumbag no
but I I think there should be more
people in the room with him
because because to me
like when it comes down to it if you
want to do something illegal
and you get caught
and you shut your mouth
right
and you just be quiet and you you accept
that what you did had some risk to it
and you go down
and not everyone does that
right and there can be all kinds of
nuance to it and you can say oh they
already knew so much about all these
different people
I was just filling in some blanks you
don't know what it'd been like to go
away for that long or whatever but when
it comes down to it it's like you're
throwing someone else under the bus
to get
a better situation for yourself
and people can have whatever views they
want on that
I don't approve and I generally speaking
don't engage with people that are
willing to do that some of that is just
self-preservation because I'm like well
if they did it once
why would ever why would I ever talk to
him about you know
I mean imagine like you hook up with
someone right and and you find out that
like she murdered her last husband
you might be like man
I'm gonna reevaluate things
oh that was an extenuating circumstances
you know but it would be red and and so
separating the artists from from the art
you really have to do with cannabis
because there's a lot of
people that you could pick apart on a
personal level that have done cool
things in wheat yeah certainly right
um and you know he got ostracized for a
long time
and then he sort of came back and I
think he came back because the scene has
expanded enough and enough time has
passed that like he couldn't have ever
come back in the Forum era because it
was too small of a group of people and
he would have been hella ostracized but
even when he came back on IG he had to
turn comments off on his posts
because it would just devolve into a
open Warfare in the in that comment
section underneath his IG posts
um
and uh you know there's there's
Defenders of him out there
um you know I don't know him personally
um but you know it does seem like the
one of the better ways to become a good
breeder is to have excellent starting
stock
so res working with Sour Diesel and
chemd and chems in general
you know I love those strains so the
likelihood that he's going to make
something decent out of them is pretty
high
you know I mean I'd even say that about
Neville like half of a good half of
Neville's success
was he got to be the first person to
cross Haze to Northern Lights
he got to be the first guy to cross the
Northern Lights to skunk he got to
collect the best of a lot of these
American breeders who didn't know each
other
and then blend those things
that's a really big component like I I
mean I'll I'll I'm a Neville backer and
you know and so I think he definitely
had the eye and he was really good at
seeing
quality and knowing what to go for but
it's undoubtable that like he got skunk
one he got Haze he got G13 he got
Northern Lights he got these different
things and he got to blend them first
yeah that matters
because he started with really good
genetics
and so I think res dog has really good
and that helps
and
um you know I I can understand why
I mean he it's funny in the sense that I
know people that know him and he's not
even sure what the res dog cut of Sour
Diesel is or who named it that or where
it came from
and he's got his name on it
he's not even sure how that occurred
you know
yeah that's a that's a very interesting
perspective and I think for me the sort
of the thing that to me gave me I sort
of thought was like the beautiful end
outcome of it all was that when I spoke
to Gypsy who did do jail time because of
res he had actually he says that he made
his peace with it he said I don't I
don't hold the guy accountable he said
you know like he basically says I blame
the laws in America the insane penalties
that were being imposed on people he
said why why would you throw your life
away it makes sense to me that you would
do that but regardless I understand your
point of view but I thought that's
that's beautiful at least he doesn't
hold him still to this day accountable
you know
I could I could I could say something
about that I won't get too specific but
let's just say that like obviously like
when you're involved with hippies on
dead tour
you know there was a lot of ways that
weren't exactly legal that they
we people did in order to stay traveling
around the country without a job
you know
and sometimes people got in trouble and
sometimes people went to prison over the
things that they were doing
and it was really interesting there was
times that there was people that I
thought were total scumbags
okay
bad people
and they got busted
and they kept their mouth shut and they
went away for a long time
and there was people that I loved and I
thought were good people and I
personally cared for a bunch and when
they got in trouble
they did whatever they had to do to get
out of that trouble
and so I think it's one of those things
to speak to gypsy's point it's very very
difficult to say what you would do
if you're facing significant prison time
right
like without actually facing it
everyone of course would like to say I
would never
but then they're like you know you can
talk to us and you can give us this and
this and this and we already know so
much about these different people and
you're not even all that important we
actually want these other folks and we
already know so much about them and if
you can just fill in a few little blanks
here and there we're going to massively
reduce
you'll spend a year not 10.
right and they're scumbags about it in
the sense that they'll be like if you
have kids if you have a lady if you have
this or that or whatever they're going
to use whatever strings they can pull on
to get what they want from you which is
information
and not everyone is going to hold up in
that environment
there's not
you know and so you can judge people but
like I said there was people that I was
like man if that person ever got in
trouble
everybody would be doomed
and they kept their mouth shut
so it's really hard to tell
until you're faced with it yourself
that's my experience at least you know
it's very difficult
um and uh you know that doesn't that's
not me making excuses
because I do feel strongly like I just
personally I don't you know like if
I don't think other people should suffer
for actions you're taking
so it's like if you don't want to go to
jail or you don't want to go to prison
for something then don't
do it
yeah I mean there's there's a thing I'll
tell you honestly like I'm from the mid
I'm from Chicago originally
when I moved out to California there was
a lot of money to be made if I wanted to
ship a bunch of California weed back to
Chicago
and I wouldn't do it because I was like
I would rather just grow weed in
California and have it stay in
California
right
I don't want to be involved in some
smuggling thing where I get in trouble
and then I have to go back and do a
prison sentence or whatever in Illinois
and then beyond probation
if somebody else wants to take that risk
that's fine it's that's not what I'm I
don't want to do that
right and so sometimes people take risks
because they're trying to make a lot of
money or they're trying to do this or
that or whatever and it ends up you know
if you're gonna smuggle
which is kind of like when they brought
down Gypsy and all that different types
of stuff if you're gonna break
International borders and you're going
to do all that kind of stuff they're
probably going to come down on you
pretty hard
certainly I mean historically at that
time right it um the the penalties would
not LAX at all there were not lacks at
all so I I don't it's not like I you
know
it's like there's a thing where I can
still judge you and forgive you hmm
interesting does that make sense yeah no
I get it it's always interesting to hear
the range of opinions because as we said
at the start it's such an interesting
case analysis but earlier on before we
started talking about Reds and we were
talking about Cam and skunk you
mentioned the clear chain of provenance
in the way the cutting had moved about
and I wanted to quickly ask you the
provenance of the TK because obviously
you know TK Origins Marty has come out
and you know I haven't had a chance to
speak to him yet so I'm not really sure
what this hitch is but I'd love to hear
do you think that's sort of the story
you're going on as to where the TK came
from and you know as a loose follow-up
do you think that the TK is sort of the
quote mother of all ogs
uh no and no
and the the reason why the reason why I
say that is that see this this is the
hard part too with like telling history
and stuff like that is that uh you get
people's feathers ruffled
um but really simple I wasn't there so
again it makes it hard for me to make
definitive statements but what I can say
is that
TK Origins has told
three different stories about the
origins of TK
and he's written them all out
you know he told a certain version on
icmag
and then he told a certain version to us
on like our server and now he's got a
certain version that he tells on
Instagram
right and they don't match up
like he wrote all the words
so what do you do in a situation where
the person's story from him typed out by
him does not match up
are we talking about like big or small
discrepancies I guess
pretty big so just in a nutshell I mean
I could I could after the show I could
send you because I have them saved I
could send you the things but on the
when he first wrote about it on icmag he
he talked about
um he was he was young and he got hired
by the guys that he was working for
um in 1994
to go to Amsterdam and mule back seats
and they he went they bought five or six
different strains he listed them all out
you know I can't remember off the top of
my head but it was like Hawaiian indica
and AK-47 and and uh nl5 Haze a few
different ones on there they they came
back they had this cut called Emerald
Triangle that the only thing they knew
about it was it came from the Emerald
Triangle they were growing that they had
this 12 light room that was very
difficult to move around in once you had
it all set up he was being paid to be
the house sitter Waterboy run run the
grow for these older cats
they put in five or six of these new
strains
they grew a bunch of the Emerald
Triangle and at the end of that
um they found some seats
that's the first version
so that's 1994 right
um then he came out when he talked to us
on the server
um he told us that he went there in 1991
and he bought Hindu Kush directly from
Neville
okay
um and then now on Instagram he talks
about how he went in 1989
and he and the guys that he was with
bought Hindu Kush directly from Neville
right the problem that I have with that
is that Neville didn't sell Hindu Kush
in 1989.
you can go look at his catalogs in 89
and 90. there's no Hindu Kush in there
the other thing he told me is that he
turned 18 in 1990.
which means that if his bosses hired him
in 1989 to go mule seeds they were
hiring a 17 year old kid to do so
I somehow doubt that they hired a minor
right to smuggle seeds for them
so if I'm going to believe any of his so
it's basically like
his first story was 1994.
his second story was 1991. his current
and most modern story is 1989.
he went from We Bought five or six
different seeds I don't know what harmed
or what or what through pollen but it
ended up seeding the Emerald Triangle to
I know specifically it was Hindu Kush
even though Hindu Kush isn't even listed
on the six strains on his first story
right so how do how do you parse that is
it 1994 is it 1991 is it 1989 is it the
first five or six strains that he listed
when he first wrote the story
is it Hindu Kush how did he get Hindu
Kush from Neville in 1989 when Neville
didn't sell anything in his catalog in
89 or 90 that was labeled Hindu Kush
and he'll say I was there you weren't
there bye
but
he wrote out all those stories and
posted them himself
so if I'm going to believe anything I
would believe the first story he told
which is that he was 22 years old or
something you know 23 he got hired by
these guys to run a room they brought
him out to Amsterdam to mule some seeds
he got they got five or six strains they
grew them all up it was mostly a room of
Emerald Triangle they don't know what
hit the Emerald Triangle
they ended up lightly seeding the weed
but it was still valuable and it got
sold and that's where the that's where
this that's where it got found
that I think is probably the most
believable
if it's true now
if you want to extrapolate from that
he estimates that there was 25 or 30
pounds of lightly seeded weed that they
sold
I don't think that the TK and the cut
that
um Matt Bubba and Josh D brought to La
are the exact same one
I have a tendency to believe that there
was a few phenos that got found in this
lightly seeded weed that ended up in
Florida
I think how many I can't say at least
two maybe three or four
okay
and out of those three or four strains
comes the
um this is a joke but the 34 different
phenos of OG Kush that we have today
right
you know
um
I think it's one of those things that
like you know as people get famous they
need to come up with more detail than
they had
you know um and like some people might
say I'm calling him a liar or something
like that
I just don't know how you take three
different stories that he all typed out
and posted
that are from three different years
and have fairly different details
and it's like okay so if he's telling
the truth which version do you believe
was he lying on the first story is he
lying on the second story is he lying on
the current story is it a mishmash
how do you know
it'd be one thing if it was all
consistent
what if what if he had turned just to
play deva's Advocate before we move on
what if he made a mistake and he didn't
turn 18 in 91 but he turned 18 in 89.
that that could theoretically reconcile
the difference between story two and
three but not one and then the others I
guess not not the first story that he
posted that as the real tri-tip or
whatever on icmag where he says 1994 and
not the list of strains that he gave
that doesn't include Hindu Kush sure
another problem is that he says he got
it from Neville
and I mean I can you can I'm sure you
have them but if you don't like there is
nothing in Neville's catalog in 1989 or
1990 that says Hindu Kush
I guess you know that's that's really
interesting to hear that perspective and
that's good because I'd heard there were
discrepancies but I never knew what they
were specifically but my follow-up
question is do you think that it was in
fact Hindu Kush to whatever this Emerald
Mountain strain is or do you think the
lineage might be something because I
think somewhere someone said oh Emerald
Triangle that was a sort of hinduy cushy
type plant I mean he said he said that
they called it
Kush because of the
you know they you know the Emerald
Triangle so it might not have been a
Kush at all you know Emerald Triangle
could you know but I don't know I wasn't
there that I can't
all I know is that he wrote multiple
stories that don't seem to add up we
know that from we know that the TK came
from Florida
we know that the cut that Josh D and
Matt Bubba brought out from Florida to
LA in 1996 or whatever came from Florida
we have pictures of that weed yeah uh
and
it obviously likes Sour Diesel Kush
became extremely valuable and extremely
sought after and it went from one or two
or three cuts to several dozen
yeah sure
and people had an intention to you know
muddy the waters a little bit right
um and you know a lot of times like I'm
not throwing it out there or whatever
but I mean I think that for a while
people thought in California Swamp Boy
seeds you know uh Ricky and chrome and
those guys were the guys that like they
were the TK guys hmm like they were the
people that sprouted it they were
responsible for it
yeah I've had that and then it kind of
came out that they just got it early
certainly look it sounds like it's one
of those ones where we'll have to wait
and see and as you've said a few times
to a few questions you know I'm sure at
one point genetic testing will help
yield some answers but you're you're
also asking a bunch of questions about
uh a bunch of weed strains that
originate in the early to mid 90s
at a time when prohibition was high and
information and the internet didn't
exist
and a lot of this information is
percolated out very slowly
yeah long after the the initial
events occurred
yeah
I mean that that [ __ ] uh that dude
from Hawaii I don't even like saying his
name but that dude from Hawaii will tell
you that it all originates from crippy
that that you know that the the surfer
is brought it out and it's actually
Hawaiian originated from Neville but
Hawaiian and then it went to Florida
and then the guy Alec I mean it's one of
those things where you start pulling on
it and it's like there's unknowns and
how do you resolve those unknowns
true well look let's you know we've been
gone for basically three hours now let's
do some more fleshed out light and fun
ones before we wrap up and I've I've
written some special ones that sure I
think I think we'll still be able to
have a good little chat about them but
there's some interesting ones and so the
first one I want to throw by you is did
you ever get to try the Francine strain
from Staten Island that skunk VA spoke
about or was that gone by the time you
met him
it was gone
I didn't try it but that that is the
reason why Statin got
um got the skunk at least
um
and uh Statin got rid of it because it
had horrific mold
okay
it had really really bad mold problems
um and you know obviously like I don't
know if you've ever had this happen to
you but if you've ever had a crop you
harvest the crop and you realize that
it's riddled with mold it's very
depressing
um and so he dropped it in favor of uh
other strains he did have
a very nice glass piece by
um
by Bob that he uh uh only had smoked the
Francine out of huh and he never ever
smoked any weed again out of it so it
was just kind of like this like museum
piece or whatever but unfortunately it
you know there was a huge fire in the 17
fires his house burned down and uh he
lost all that glass then
but
um yeah I was you know I don't I don't
really I don't really like to tell this
part of it so I won't but I will just
say that skunk VA and Staten Island were
best friends
um they had a falling out and then I
ended up sort of being for that next
that Next Period sort of like statins
best friend
um so uh skunk VA and him were friends
before I knew him
um and that's when he grew the Francine
by the time that I met him he had
replaced it with the skunk and the chem
and it wasn't he wasn't growing it
anymore so I never saw it or smoked it
yeah no it's interesting okay and then
similarly would you have any interest in
growing out either say the purest Indica
because I know that that you know that
seems pretty interesting or on the other
hand once Tom's finished any of Tom's
Hayes either of those strike you as
interesting uh Toms Hayes certainly
yeah I Haze is uh I I love Haze very
much
it's uh it's very difficult to find a
good one uh part of the part of the
problem with Haze is that it takes
forever and that only about
um five or ten percent of them are
really super nice
so you have to go through a lot of mids
and a lot of garbage to find the
exceptional ones but
I would definitely lean much more
towards that because I do think the
provenance of him getting it I believe
him that he went there in 1994 from
positronics and got it I believe that
he's like reprode open pollinated at a
few different times
um I went to I went to his I went to his
house not that long ago and uh saw the
little project he had going on so I
would be I would be definitely
interested in in that the purest Indica
I don't know how I feel about that one
really
um for a variety of reasons but uh I I
think
um in general I think that we have if
you want to talk about chems and cushes
and the I think we have a lot of really
really exceptional afghanis to choose
from
and I think we have less sativas to
choose from than afghanis
so if I had to choose which one at this
point in my life I'm more interested in
it would be sativas
simply because we already have such a
big blessing of indicas
that are available and out there
yeah true that's a really nice answer I
like that so we've been talking about
you know nl5 Hayes and Neville I now
want to ask you if you could ask Neville
any two questions what two questions
would you want to ask Neville
oh man
huh all right it is a good one
um
I've been blessed in that I get to talk
to some of Neville's old friends still
that helped him with a lot of projects
so in recent years I've been able to get
a lot more in depth with a lot of the
questions that I had as best as could be
answered I met Neville several times in
in Holland but I was young and and
Starstruck and I I would love to say
that I had some like deep penetrating
conversation with him
but I did not you know I did not have
any kind of deep or or involved combo
with them and the few times that I was
in the same room with him
um he's significantly older than me you
know and I was a dumb kid
um but
I uh if I had to ask him
I would probably ask him and I kind of
know this already but I would kind of
ask him
um
one of the things that he lost did he
still think were most current like
were the things that he regretted the
most
and
you know and why
you know because you know for instance
if you read a bunch of his posts out of
all the seeds he got from Sam Skunk Man
um he only got about seven or eight of
those hazes to pop
and by 1991 he only had one left because
they were long flowering and a huge pain
in the ass and he didn't realize there
was anything special about them
until he'd made a few mistakes
so he never actually got like almost I
think all of the commercially available
seed stock was all from Haze C
you know but
um there was one year that he released
Haze B but he never really got a chance
once he knew what he had to play around
with them so I guess my second question
would be if you had all seven hazes that
you popped
what directions which ones would you
cross and why and where would you want
to go with them
brilliant I love that pondering thoughts
for a soul I definitely would be
interested to hear what his answers are
and now I want to remix it same question
you get to ask two questions to Sam the
skunk man what are you gonna ask Sam
would he would would he be would he have
to be honest with me
he he has to be honest with you uh what
Afghan did he use in Skunk one
and when he was making skunk one is the
Mexican Colombian part of it Pollyanna
from Rob Clark
aha that's beautiful thoughts there
that's what I would ask him if he had to
be honest
do you believe that the Colombian that
was used in Skunk is the same one that
was used in Hayes as the internet
stories say
you know I don't know
um part of the problem with the haze
story is that until it gets to Europe
there's only really one guy telling it
you know supposedly there's a Hayes
brother or two that's alive but they've
never decided to come out there and talk
publicly
so you only have Sam and I can tell you
from The Forum days he has been
defending everything he says is the
absolute truth for 25 plus years
vigorously
uh on cannabis world he used to go by
the handle know it all for sure
and he would
fight people like intensely on all this
different stuff and you know
um there's a big debate whether like you
know there's no doubt his impact on
things but like the other part of it is
that the one other guy that was around a
bunch
was Rob Clark
and their best friends
and he won't refute anything that Rob
says or that that Sam says
so it's really hard to get
um you know like if you do if you do a
study and you get a result you hope
somebody else can get the same result
yeah it would be it would be and that's
kind of like the scientific method or
whatever is like can different people do
the same experiment and get similar
results
I would love if there was five or six
different people
that were all talking about the skunk
and the haze and that era
and we're willing to put what they
remember down on paper because what we
basically have is Sam's version
and so how do you battle that
uh I know that that Rob was working with
a bunch of Mexicans and Colombians me
and a few friends have a sneaking
suspicion that the that the um
the the
uh sativa side of skunk one is from
Rob's work
yeah
but it's hard to say I mean I'll tell
you do you remember how you know Matt
and I did those interviews with mag oh
don't go there was this my next question
no go for it yeah of course they're
incredible well I will say that like
when he got all those skunks in 1978 it
was Rob who delivered them all to him
too true and that was you you're such a
mind reader because I was about to say
you know having done those incredible
episodes with mad Jag how has your
perspective changed on Rob Clark
I have always had a high opinion of Rob
Clark
one of the first three books I bought to
teach myself how to how to anything
about weed was marijuana botany
um it's a little bit simple these days
but for some for
in an era where there was almost no
verifiable information about how the
cannabis plant worked to have Rob come
out with a very simple primer laying out
how to breed and how it worked and what
it did
um he was invaluable to me in teaching
a lot of Basics about cannabis
you know uh and it seems like you know
he did a lot of work it's he's kind of
quiet about it I think if I had to guess
I would say he lets
Sam shine with some of his work
and doesn't care about it that much in
terms of like who gets the credit
but that would be for him to say
um I do think it's interesting like
speaking of magic or whatever that Sam
always insists that his seed company was
him and only him and nobody else was
involved but him
but then when mad Jag bought like a
ridiculous amount of seeds in 1978 it
was Rob who flew them out and gave them
all to him you know
do you not think that it's interesting
because what I took away from that
moment when I heard that was these guys
must have felt like they were still
small fry for Rob to have delivered that
order in person for what was what was
like three or five grand or something it
was five grand in 1978 it was the
biggest purchase of seeds that they had
ever done at that point
right and but it's still still small fry
in the scheme of things right so I
thought to myself they must have been
really giddy like wow there's a big sale
for us considering they'd hand delivered
it yeah and and Magic still has the
original packaging they came in
um
he does so that's pretty crazy and he's
got you know real experience and like
what they were like back then and all
that and you know he said Rob had just
incredible collection of killer weed
um when he when he when he got hand
delivered the seeds or whatever
um you know I I think
this is indisputable although Sam won't
like it but I think when Sam went to
Holland
he gathered up a bunch of seeds from
people he knew
and brought them out there
Hayes skunk he got the Durbin poison and
The Afghani one from Mel Frank
you know
um so it wasn't all just his work I
think some of it was Rob's work some of
it was Mel Frank's work some of it was
his work some of it was the haze
people's work because even he admits
that it's like you know
um he didn't do the haze it was like he
got seeds of it
you know
and uh you know but there's
inconsistencies in his story too he'll
swear that he was never busted and then
I've watched videos of Mel Franks saying
oh well he went to Holland after his
second bust
foreign
you know so some of these things are
like Old-Timers covering for each other
you know but you got to realize the era
that they were into
uh and most of it I will say for anybody
that is listening to me
um my experience with seed breeding is
whoever gets famous there's a small
group of friends or Associates around
them that helped at various stages
that don't get the credit
so I do not believe that Sam was like
alone with no helpers with no partners
with nobodies contributing that he was
doing it all himself that every strain
he used was original to him and no one
else ever had it
can I prove it wrong no but
you know I uh
um I also think that from what Neville
said and from what Corel from sssc and
some of these other guys said is that
the skunk that he brought over at first
was much different than after he had
done some open pollinations in his own
line breeding in Amsterdam
and you know he bred it in a way that
they didn't prefer
so but Rob Rob is one of the more
important people in cannabis in his era
he wrote a he wrote some lasting books
um he he got some information out there
I definitely think he did a lot of
underground breeding and I think he's
responsible for more than he wants to
admit
so would I wish that he would just come
out and say it all sure but despite that
he still did it and we still benefit
from it so
huge kudos to rob the the next question
I have for you is that photo of Neville
in the hash Den in Afghanistan I think
it's got to be the most iconic cannabis
photo of all time do you agree or
disagree
it's pretty iconic
um you know I think Neville gets a lot
of credit in the sense because he was
first
he certainly suffered more than most
seed breeders being first
and struggled a lot more
um you know he got bitter in the end
because people you know stole so much
stuff from him
but it's actually kind of interesting in
that regard of I don't know if he's told
this story so it's not like it's secret
and he and he wrote it on Mr nice but
do you know what he had to do to prove
he wasn't a DEA agent didn't you have to
like shoot heroin in front of him or
something
yeah
because they figured no de agent would
do that and it just turns out that he
was a heroin addict
so he could do that without dying but
his photographer Clyde OD'd over there
and almost died
Jesus
um so it was very sketchy I mean he went
over there and dealt with the muhajidin
you know when the Soviets were you know
were right in the middle of their big
Afghanistan war there was a lot of stuff
going on over there you know and um it
is pretty interesting to think that if
you like weren't a heroin addict
you probably would have either had to
refuse and maybe been killed by The
muhaj Deen
or you would have done it and OD'd and
died because you didn't have a tolerance
because you weren't a heroin addict
huh right place right time
it's funny how life works sometimes
interesting stuff I'm sure everyone's
Keen to hear more about that and maybe
at some point we'll hear more I have
this opinion I've held it for a while I
think I might have even said it once or
twice I think sub cool space queen mail
the mail he calls space dude I think
that is maybe the best male we have
access to like it's still around it's
it's empirical evidence it produces nice
crosses I think it may be the best smell
that we have what comes to mind when I
say that and agree slash disagree
uh
uh I will say that uh
with the reversals revolution
males are few and far between
also say that males
um typically get traded much much less
than females so
there really isn't like a collection of
Elites
in terms of males that get passed around
right
um so males are sort of like the the
secret sauce if you were
and
um you know I uh
I would say and I I've been trying to
figure out if it exists for forever to
me the most impactful male in cannabis
is probably the haze female
yeah and I hear rumors that it's alive
and I hear rumors that it's not
you know
but as far as like an impactful it
doesn't mean we can get our hands on it
but as far as an impactful male that's
like made a bunch of hybrids that have
gone on to be like crazy
um you know uh just influential in the
scene
that is probably the Primo mail that's
existed
um but
I don't have any experience with his
space I mean that male really so I can't
really comment on how good it is or not
but I will say
that before all this reversal stuff
existed
um
Matt likes to call it the shotgun method
but really there's there's no way to
test to see if a male actually does what
you want unless you grow out it's
progeny
which is very time consuming obviously
because you have to like make seeds and
then grow them out and then see
and so when people find males back in
the day it used to be that all those
seed companies the males were the
backbone and the most important part of
their breeding process
they were hoarded incredibly
because once you found a male that
passed along desirable traits that you
were looking for it took so much time
and effort to figure that out
that you typically held onto it never
passed it around which means no one else
ever got to experience it
I don't know if I answered your question
or not but that's about as close as I
can come
no that's good and it's it's a very
interesting point that you know with the
Advent of how popular reversals are does
it even is it even really that relevant
anymore which is I can certainly
understand that so on to the second last
question for our part two will people
ever be able to buy your seeds
probably
um
I have uh it's kind of a running joke in
the crew
right where I haven't commercially said
yes yet
because you know I watch what all my
friends go through when they sell seeds
and it just looks so attractive getting
people calling you a hack or a chucker
you know or a Herm breeder or a fake or
this or that and sort of like
um you know it's really hard to accuse
you of being a a money-grubbing scumbag
when you're not making any money off it
you know
so and then the other part of it too is
that all the breeding that I've ever
done has been for me and to try to breed
weed that I liked and to create weed for
my friends that we liked I never
actually and by doing that it's
incredibly freeing
because you literally don't have to care
what the public thinks
so once you're in a commercial seed
situation you kind of have to try to
make things that you think people will
like
yeah if you want to make money off it if
you're fine with just making what you
like and if it bombs it bombs
you know but in the way seeds are now
anytime if I made if I made seeds and I
passed them out there would be a bunch
of people that would there would be not
a bunch but there would be some people
that would be like oh he's been building
this
um you know this group for a while just
to like have a market to sell his seeds
oh we knew this was coming you know or
then people grow them out and they're
not what they want or they Herm are they
this or that and it just goes to show
that I'm like I'm a shitty breeder or
whatever
uh so with all that being said I do
think I'm going to release some seed
um probably before the end of this year
and it is going to be stuff that
interests me
and hopefully people like it and if they
don't they don't
I like that I like that we'll wait and
see what comes I'm sure it'll be very
exciting it could also fail too I mean
it's actually like in it's actually in
progress right now but we'll see it's
gonna I'm gonna try to do
so I'm gonna try to do some reversals
you know and if it works out uh you'll
know about it
and I don't want to reveal too much I'll
I'll leave the finer details for you to
really reveal in due time but I would
love to know what what are you reversing
at least
uh well
I'll say this
um
there are there are a number of projects
that I have going and I kind of balance
them between my own interests
and then things that I don't think are
generally speaking out there in the
public
right because even though I've held chem
91 forever
there's a lot of people doing reasonably
you know doing some pretty good breeding
work with it there's no like shortage
you know of of chem 91 beans out there
right so if you're going to make an
impact or something like that in this in
the seed world you might as well bring
out things that are not very circulated
so at least you're adding some new
wrinkle or some new genetics to the
larger pool that's out there so that in
a sense
um
you know uh is a big driver because if
you're gonna do it you might as well try
to like break some new ground or
whatever
um so there's some things that could be
in the works in terms of like that uh
that headband cut that I call the LA
because I don't think it's very well
circulated and it's one of my favorites
um that that definitely is going to be
something
um my Maui cut that I have
um also not particularly well circulated
so and I have some really cool ideas
with it uh possibly the Flowrider OG cut
that I have which is also not very well
circulated but it's in cookies
um and so it's a combination of
something that's rare that people could
you know maybe take in a different
direction but then also something that
to be fair commercially something that I
think people would be
um interested in
you know I had friends talk me out of
you know it's not like I'm gonna do like
some Bodhi thing right off the bat and
like release like extreme sativas that
are a huge pain in the ass and uh you
know would take forever and would you
know you're trying to you're trying to
like balance what would people be
interested in what would be something
new what would be a different wrinkle
you know and to me it's it's
um it would be a cool way to get
genetics out there that uh aren't that
spread
with the LA it's a little bit cheating
in the sense that I gave it to CSI and
he released
La by TK and la by chemd which got like
very warmly received and a lot of people
found winners in that and so it sparked
some interest so it leads me to believe
that perhaps
um that could be both fun for me and
commercially viable
you know
so uh and then I'll say this and this
might get me into some trouble or
whatever but
uh it turns out that there's a lot more
chemds out there than people think
and um that opens up some room maybe for
I might do some chemd work not only
because I love it and I think it's super
potent
but also because I think there's four or
five cuts out there
um at least that go by the moniker of
chemd and even some ones that people are
absolutely sure is is
the one might not be the one that I have
doesn't mean mine's special or whatever
I'm just saying that like it kind of
fits into that like get something a
little different out there
um and then you know those things if
those things actually work they would
probably get crossed to a bunch of
things that are I hold in my collection
that I think would be interesting
you know some sativas some Afghans some
purples some this some that some
different things it probably would be
very old school grouping of cuts because
that's kind of where my collection leans
I don't have a whole bunch of new ZaZa
so you're not going to see a list of uh
of things that are wildly popular in the
last four or five years it would
probably be blends of classics
you know I mean my whole breeding career
I basically just like made seeds for me
and friends and given them away
so the whole idea of like starting a
seed company is a little odd
um but uh you know I have so many good
friends bugged me about it
um that it might be time
so we'll see
here here that's exciting stuff so
on to the final question for this
interview it's sort of a two-parter but
I'd love to hear it you're going to
theoretically start a company from
scratch you've lost everything you've
got you're starting fresh you can pick
one pack of seeds to presumably find a
male from that and then start the
company with that
here's the two-parter to it one possible
outcome is you're gonna do it and it's
what's available today has to be
something that's currently commercially
available and then the part B is you
could sort of do the time machine thing
where you could pick a pack from it
throughout time you know and choose it
so what would your two options be in
each scenario well
um
boy
so
if we're talking about one pack of seeds
from today
you got to realize that because you said
I would you'd get a male to start it
that eliminates probably 95 percent of
the current market
because we've been doing reversals now
for a good 15 years so the amount of
people that are releasing regular seeds
is
very small
well let's let's Jazz it up you could
you can equally you can get a pack of
CSI you know chemd cross headband and
get a female and reverse it that's also
cool you just it just has to be one pack
one pack
um well I would say if I can if I can
pick all females and reverse it
I'm gonna cheat and I'm gonna say I
would get a pack of lad from CSI simply
because those are two of my all-time
favorite strains that I would have lost
and I would like to hunt through those
both to refined leaners that of the
things that I lost and I also think that
it's just incredibly Fireweed both of
them so the chances that you would have
good things
and then
um
if if we're talking regular seed
right
um this might sound nuts but I would
probably if I can get some [ __ ] from I
would probably try to get some of that
uh op uh Haze that uh Tom is working on
if we're going actual like regular males
and stuff like that you know
um because that that ties back to way
way way back
you know and there's a lot of diversity
in there and you could take that and you
could cross it to a lot of modern
indicas and a lot of different new new
and it's so different
that you could get some cool stuff
perhaps
and then if I go back in time
boy
if I could go back in time
I'll cheat a little bit
and and say something that most people
probably won't think of
um but I would probably go back and try
to get early Pearl
and the reason I say that is because one
of Neville's oldest friends that I chat
with told me that the last five six
years of Neville's life he was crossing
a bunch of Mexicans together
because out of all the stuff that he had
one of the things that he was really
hunting to find he'd done a bunch of
haze work in Australia with the the um
the Outback you know and all that type
of stuff but he was really looking for
this certain sweetness and the certain
Buzz that he got from those Mexicans
that came from the early Pearl
and so I figure
um if he loved it that much that out of
everything he ran through as he aged he
really wanted to refine that
uh maybe going back in time into the
late 80s and getting some early Pearl
when it was still legit before it got
lost would be that would be something
cool
that's beautiful
really cool to hear I wouldn't have
thought of that that's a I'm gonna have
to dig more into the early pill
obviously I tried a little sample of
Pips uh silver Pearl and it was
beautiful so I can only imagine the
early Pearl equally special
I think uh with that being said we're
just about at the end of it for this one
did you have any general comments or
shout outs you'd like to make
um
I meant sure I say this a lot but I'll
say it again
is uh growey that you love
uh if you're breeding try to find two
plants that you like qualities of each
and you hope maybe you can get those
qualities in the progeny itself
so therefore like don't breed for what
you think other people will like breed
for what you think you would personally
like
that's the best way to do breeding is to
look for things that you enjoy
and when it comes to preservation
nobody can preserve everything but if
you can hold on to one or two or three
things during this storm that's going on
right now if you can find some old
things that really speak to you and you
really love
um you can't hold everything but even
holding on to one or two or three old
maybe even currently unpopular things
but really really do it for you
um that can help preserve it for better
times ahead
you know and then
beyond that thanks to all the weed nerds
and everyone else that like listens to
my homies show all the time and I
appreciate uh there being enough
interest for him having me back and
listening to me Babble for hours on end
so that's always good and
um
you know uh we will uh if you know if I
do decide to release seeds to the public
or whatever I'll certainly like pass it
out through him and the various things
and you know a small Core group of
enthusiasts can keep something cool
going
so even though you're out in the middle
of nowhere even though you feel isolated
even though it's something if enough of
us work towards the same goal
um we can kind of keep the fire burning
uh through some tough times
and that's that
a truly beautiful and inspiring
sentiment and I think I speak first of
all when I say we're very excited for
the idea of an upcoming seed release
we'll have to wait with baited Breath
Again a huge thank you for part two the
originator of Mendo pervs one half of
the incredible breeders Syndicate a huge
thank you again not so dog for coming on
the show
yeah thank you for having me dude I
really like chatting so it makes it easy
and there you have it gang a huge shout
out to not so dog for taking the time to
come by not once but twice and share
some of his cannabis law cannabis
knowledge and some cool tidbits from the
past
if you like this episode please go check
out our patreon the only way to get
early access to content
www.patreon.com the podcast our patreon
supporters have had access to this
episode for a while now be sure to check
it out if you want to hear more content
before it goes live for the General
Public
likewise we would love for you to go and
support our sponsors by supporting them
you help them to support us seeds here
now best seed bank in the industry
whatever drop you're looking for they're
gonna have the latest and greatest from
all the best breeders people who I vouch
for as well a guarantee on satisfaction
not just germination please go check
them out seat here now your number one
seed bank just like I want you to go
check out Copa biological systems these
guys have the best predators in the game
I cannot stress this enough if you want
to keep aphids and spider mites out of
your garden please get the happy param
inspired extra Idols a hammer on about
these products because they're so bloody
good thank you so much copit for
supporting the show we are such big fans
of your products and truly grateful to
have you supporting us
likewise a huge thank you to the ongoing
support we get from pulse sensors these
guys have the best units in the game I
run them in my garden there's absolutely
no doubt it's helped improve the quality
of my crops and with the release of the
recent pulse Hub there's no reason not
to get on board get excited and get
yourself a pulse as I say from a single
tent to a single room to a multi-state
operation get serious get a pulse
you've heard me talk about it guys shout
out to the new sponsor Organics a lot
truly incredible organic powdered
fertilizer if you're looking for an easy
solution while growing in soil they have
it it is not hard to see why they are at
the top of their game I highly recommend
it for all the organic Growers out there
give it a try you will not be
disappointed your plants will be next
level massive shout out again
and a massive shout out to our newest
sponsors dinova they are an incredible
Vape company based out of USA producing
some of the most coolest engineering and
vape technology you've seen for a while
I cannot speak highly enough about
dynavat's products if you've ever had a
vape and wished it was able to replicate
the head of a joint or a bong check out
dying about their second to none for
good reason we're really stoked to be
working with Don about huge shout out
guys
and That Just About Does it for this one
my friends
thank you for making it to the end as
always
much love from your boy Happy Days
signing off from the upside down Library
I'll see you for the next one
[Music]