[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
as you're joined by your host heavy days
and this episode as always was brought
to you by our incredible sponsors
seat here now number one seed bank in
the industry guarantee on satisfaction
not just germination go check them out
all the hottest drugs all the best
breeders they've just put up some new
stock to go see if it's what you need to
make your next run fire as hell
likewise in order to get the best run
out of your genetics you need to keep
your garden happy and healthy and for
that we'd like to give a shout out to
our friends at Copper biological systems
these guys have all the best predators
in the game to keep bug infestations
away and to fight off any unwanted
issues you may be experiencing check out
their spidex vitals or their apipa M
both fantastic products for fighting off
spider mites or acids respectively two
pests a lot of Growers struggle with but
they're here to help you get on top of
it
furthermore huge shout out to promix
these guys have been in the industry for
years you know them they make great
media based products using Pete and
mycorizer but guess what now you can get
their fantastic mycorrhizal products on
its own promix connect the number one
mycorizer product in the game helping
you to achieve greater yields better
resins enhanced flavor and perfumes
helping you to make your next harvest
the best to date check out Pro mix
connect for all your mycorrhizal needs
we would like to welcome our newest
sponsor onto the show Charlie's cannabis
these guys are family-owned small batch
craft cannabis out of Oklahoma City
providing you with fantastic flavors and
Incredibly high quality flour for anyone
who's in need of some high quality
medicine growing strains like Star
Pebbles chemical sunsets and so many
more go check out Charlie's cannabis for
all the best craft small batch Oklahoma
grown cannabis they've got all the
flavors and herbs you need to make sure
that you're puffing good last but not
least huge shout out to the patreon gang
you guys know you're the lifeblood of
the show helping to ensure episodes
happen if you would like to help support
the show and ensure future content is
continues to be created please go to
patreon.com forward slash the podcast
and sign up you'll get access to unheard
content additional interviews giveaways
and so much more patreon gang love you
guys so much appreciate you
welcome back my friends for part three
of our epic chat with JJ NYC of Top Dog
genetics if you haven't checked out the
prior two installments of this episode
please go do so it'll get you up to date
and ready to get right into this final
one where we're chatting genetics
history all things related to Top Dog
and so so so much more so without
further ado
let's get into it
I guess it sort of just speaks to that
idea of like how sort of the hazy longer
flowering sativa stuff it seems like
it's really got a home in New York
yeah well you know in New York you know
people have always you know wanted the
best weed so
um and they want stuff that's different
that not everyone else has so you know
look at yourself with a product That's
Unique uh you you're able to do that and
almost build your own customer base off
of that
yeah definitely definitely
you know I was talking to Bob Hemphill
recently yet again and he mentioned how
grateful he was that you had gifted him
an old Scentsy star cutting that you had
and he was saying how much he loved it
and um it made me think you know will we
see any more Sensei star crosses from
you and is it one you like to smoke and
breed with
uh well I had I was given a cut from a
friend of mine uh from Washington
and I think you know he told me it was
one of the old-time Scentsy Star Cuts
and it was the more uh stretchy one
I guess I guess there was a couple
different ones that were around
so um yeah so he gifted me that and I
did a little bit of work with it and
then I lost it unfortunately yeah I gave
it to Bob and
um my friend I think he brought it back
to an F3 or something or F4 F3 I'm not
sure I he I I have some of the some of
his
um seed stock that he made with that
original so I think that he had gotten
that cutting and then got some original
Scentsy store seeds and then I started
to um F1 and F2 you know went back with
for a couple Generations so that's what
he based it off of that cutting and so
yeah I just got to cutting and you know
I crossed it out to uh the star dog and
I think a cam Crow another cam cross I I
can't quite remember but I did a couple
breedings with it and then I lost it and
it was nice it's kind of I mean an old
school Amsterdam
um kind of peppery uh
yeah it was you know it's only it kind
of reminded me of the star dog a little
bit but without the chem you know but it
was kind of peppery and you know back in
the day it definitely was a special cut
um but you know if you put it up to
today's standards I don't think it would
really uh make the cut in most people's
book but you know um if you're in more
of a Nostalgia type of a guy and breeder
like Bob is then you know uh then yeah
that's something that that's going to
interest you and you know I think you
know a lot of the stuff you know
um you know our our past is our future
you know referencing some of these older
cuts and older streams and you know
trying to bring them back uh
revitalizing them and out Crossing them
and you know uh yeah so I think you know
you know that's what I always say is our
past is our future so I'm one of those
guys that kind of like to that that
looks back on on on some of these older
strains as they not might not be
significant to most of the people you
know on in today's world uh it it did
mean something at some point for a
reason so I still think that they're
still you know a lot of uh things that
could could come out good out of those
genetics and especially something that's
different compared to today's designer
genetics
yeah great rundown thanks for giving us
your answer to that one one of our
listeners asked a really interesting
question and they were wondering when
you're in the process of creating
stardog for example and you maybe grew
out the seeds or they were tested via
whatever means did you find like the
quality and the potency to like surprise
you at all because I think a lot of
people would probably agree you know
they've got to be up there with some of
the best and greatest seeds ever
commercially produced did you have any
idea like how big it was going to take
off or was it all a bit of a surprise
no I was a little bit of surprised I
mean I I mean I knew like the genetics
that I was using were you know were
special and so uh
but really they kind of took a life of
of their own like you know I like I said
you know I when I first popped those
seeds you know I don't know how many man
maybe four or six seeds I might have
popped
because you know I you know back then
you know I I was growing 99 plants for
you know uh
production you know and so 50 would be
vegging and 49 would be flowering so
like so if so if I take you know if I
was going to pop you know four or six
seeds that means like four or six
production plants we're gonna be able to
be grown so I wasn't able to you know do
huge you know seed pops for selection so
when I first did that first you know uh
seed pop and found the the Quarry star
dog I was you know pretty impressed on
you know what it was you know and so uh
once I started to uh you know get that
out there uh I think one of the first
few people I gave it to was uh was Joe B
uh because he had given me this chem 4
so I wanted to give you know give him
you know something for giving it back so
I was like here's the Quarry so once the
Quarry got out there and humbled it kind
of took a life of its own you know and
really started to become really popular
out there and
um yeah I mean that's really the only
way I could explain it is it kind of
took a life of its own you know and a
lot of these things happen that way
where I might make something and you
know it takes you know and I can test it
like I just explained and I knew I had
something really good and started
getting you know passing that clone
around and and and until people you know
got the Clone and was able to grow it
and finish it in the people that bought
the seeds and bought the seeds and were
able to grow them and finish them by the
time they get to them and by the time
you get a final product you're talking
like a year later you know by the time I
first made it a year or two later by the
time you know it starts getting into
people's hands starts getting passed
around starts making taking a life of
its own then I mean that's you know so
you know and that's basically like all
my work is always been like that like
it's not like me telling you how great
it is and you going and buying it it's
people buying it and telling everyone
else how great it is so a lot of the
times that takes it takes time for that
to happen and so um you know it's
happened numerous times and so uh that's
the only way that I can really explain
it to where you know you make something
you know you can test it you know your
friends and all but it's really the
general Public's perception of of what
it is
yeah I I guess it you know must have to
have been a little bit surprising but
yeah I guess great to get that feedback
even if it does have a bit of a lag time
before it gets to you
something I was hoping you could answer
for me was that
I think it's undeniable you know Tres
dog as a male has made a number of
killer strains out there but
interestingly enough we really don't see
a lot of Tres dog females out there
clone only there is one which I believe
stray fox has a cut of one which he
really likes and um maybe another one or
two floating around there but do you
have any thoughts on why maybe we don't
see Tres dog as much and how did you
find the females
well the the reason why that is because
we never I never real there was never
really commercially like released there
were there were some small releases but
generally like that was really made for
to be a breeding male
so a lot of the times you know I just
made
it was just one breeding so like I did
the initial Afghan chem d as per se
um I think most of those seeds were sold
on uh seed Bay and not a lot of them you
know uh I still have some of those
original uh Afghan chemd uh seeds so out
of that seed stock I would you know pop
and find another male and then I did the
back cross into the into the KMD again
and made the double dog now the double
dog became a little more
um accessible and um
I uh you know I got I let some of those
seeds some of those seeds did get out
and and I think on seed Bay also and I
think
those those ones were I remember taking
a picture of one of my original packs
and it was just in a small little
plastic
Ziploc baggy with uh a hand printed uh
pen uh on on the
um on the plastic itself there so there
was no label or anything it was just uh
a pen printed on the on the plastic
itself and you know I said double dog
and those were my original that's how
those original packs were sold they were
just unsealed in a little Ziploc baggie
with 10c 10 or 12 seeds in it and it
might have said you know a double dog 12
seeds on it or something like that so
you know then you know obviously I took
a mail out of that and made the Tres dog
so when I made the Tres doll dog
um
that was just one breeding I took a
double dog male and I made like a
certain amount of those seeds which I
still have some of those original stock
of so really at that point I decided
that I was going to uh that would that
was gonna be it that was going to be
this was going to be my my mail stream
the trade dog and uh so there was very
few seeds that that that we released
that I that I let go and because I want
you know because that was gonna be you
know I wanted to get a little bit of
feedback from it I think and then you
know I wanted to be that I wanted that
to be exclusive from that was my
exclusive strain you know so really
that's like one of the reasons why like
no one else really has it because we
know I never really worked it really Pat
past that you know uh I had given you
know we've um you know I've passed some
seeds off to money he has made some uh
chemd back cross threes and I think some
fours uh but we've never released them
or we've never worked any of those seats
he he you know we have them for a future
for future use but
um yeah it was never the trade dog was
never intended to be a production uh
seed strain it was really supposed to be
my exclusive uh male that you know no
one else was going to be able to have
yeah interesting like that's a brilliant
answer as to why we don't see much tray
dog females out there and really you
know and really if you look at it like
you know the people now that are copying
me and ripping me off you know uh you
know they could only use the seeds made
from that where they can't get that
Original Seed stock yeah so you kind of
segued into the next question we had
which was from one of our listeners but
I'll admit I too was interested in this
one uh sort of along the lines of what
you just mentioned what's the story
behind goo from Green Point seeds using
star dog it seems like I've heard rumors
that it was like your cut exactly or is
it just from your seed stock what's the
backstory there
well you know I'm just going back a
little bit when I had my my legal
troubles and my absence of the internet
during during that and that was right an
Inception of um Instagram I would say so
I think that we were talking like
2014 maybe I think 2014 so you know I
had you know I had like I mentioned I
had gotten to a jammed up a little bit
there and I had to close down so I was
absent from the internet for for a
little bit a while but during that time
like unknown to me during that time my
stuff was blowing up like I had gotten
in trouble and I had kind of dropped out
of the scene a little bit and so uh
during that time every I was just
blowing up you know my seeds were
blowing up like we were getting really
popular but we were nowhere to be found
so uh and that's when uh Green Point uh
they had gotten some of my original uh
star dog stock and so they decided you
know since I wasn't around that you know
they made some kind of a statement
saying that I was retired and that they
were you know going to further on the
genetics and so on and so forth and just
kind of took advantage of the situation
and I was kind of down and out at the
time and you know I you know at the time
I kind of you know I think you know I
rebelled with some posts and stuff like
that there wasn't really much I could do
because I wasn't growing at the time and
so really just really
um
you know uh gave me more incentive to
get my [ __ ] together and to and to
really you know and and really uh widen
my perspective of the possibility of
this really being uh something uh uh
something because you know back back
then you know uh the the only really big
breeders back then were kind of some
Amsterdam you know and so those were
those guys were only the real those guys
were really legitimate and you know they
were you know obviously working under
you know uh easier conditions that we
were
but you know the thing about you know
the difference between uh Dutch breeders
and American breeders is we have so much
more passion uh you know you go over to
Amsterdam and you know these guys are
smoking spliffs with [ __ ] tobacco in
it because the weed is too strong and
[ __ ] whatever and you know we show up
over there and we're smoking bombs of
[ __ ] Street [ __ ] Diesel and
they're looking like that that does like
work [ __ ] crazy you know so you know
the Americans have always had much more
passion for uh for stronger the
strongest weed you know and so uh and
and basically the Dutch is up the Dutch
have everything they got over there
they've got from us originally you know
it's just that they were you know
working you know not under prohibition
like we were so that's really why the
reason why a lot of those genetics wound
up and in Amsterdam because they were
able to work there so I mean you know so
the the Americans always had a strong
passion for the the best of the best you
know so you know you know when when we
you know when I first was coming up and
doing doing what we were doing and doing
what I was doing you know I never you
know you know would you know uh try to
compare myself to a Neville or a Scentsy
seeds or Shanti Bob or or or any of
these guys you know because you know
they were just uh you know such a high
level and you know we were just you know
a bunch of people on the internet just
trying to you know figure things out and
you know make our own way so to speak
not knowing that you know the the
genetic the genetics that we were
working with were you know you know some
of the best in in the whole wide world
you know and you know
it's you know it's it's just really kind
of hard to explain you know the reason
why that is you know in in some of it's
just kind of pure luck because you know
we're only given the stuff that we had
access to you know so we didn't have
access to any of that stuff we never
would have been able to have it
obviously you know so you know a lot of
places are kind of
um
you know uh you know everyone every
place in the world Khan has their own uh
kind of like home strains that were
popular at the time you know and and
that and that's and that's all that they
know because that's what they grew up
around you know so you know like you
know fortunately for us you know uh you
know the chems were around and and you
know not knowing that they would be you
know the strains that they are today you
know you know in going back to you know
some of the uh you know the older stuff
that I had seeing the hash plants the
ties and stuff like that you know back
then you know I didn't really have a
really full full grasp of the whole
genetic uh pool you know like I do today
you know the you know the knowledge and
the experience just wasn't there you
know so you know you see all these
different streams you know that you know
come out of Amsterdam and you know uh
you know and you know and looking back
like you know how how many of them are
still relevant today uh in today's world
you know we're in when back then they
were super popular you know so you know
you know it you know it was never you
know
it's it's hard to believe that you know
we've built up you know a a genetic
diversity in the states here that just
kind of just lead the world you know
it's you know and it's just from
people's passion for the flower itself
and for taking risks and just traveling
and just you know
um you know we we you know stand on the
shoulders of giants you know of people
that you know or initial initially you
know went out and took those risks
hugely hugely agree
so when you were developing the Tres dog
line I'm wondering what how are you
making your selection were you just
selecting a mail that you felt best
looked like the chemd sort of each time
and what would be your general tips for
listeners who are hoping to get better
at selecting males
yeah I mean that's really you know
pretty much you know
um
yeah I mean early on you know it was you
know and I was really I guess the the
concept of back Crossing you know uh was
just really trying to like tighten up
the gene pool you know around uh you
know around the chemd you know I you
know I had I've had you know a little
bit of breeding knowledge just from uh
from dogs uh from pit bulls and stuff
and I used to study the the the the the
breeding lines and how they would you
know do things and how a certain dog
would would become a a a line in itself
and how that was done meaning like a one
male almost almost kind of like you know
a string you know like it's the same
thing with cannabis a strain within the
Stream
so um yeah so I had a little bit of
knowledge of that and a lot of it had to
do with you know
um just going back to the original
um genetics is uh you know and it's
really just a theory of back Crossing
and stuff and and also I had read a
little bit you know on the Mel Frank
stuff and uh the concept of cubing and
back Crossing in Cuban and stuff like
that so uh you know I thought that would
you know be the best way to really just
you know try to tighten up the the gene
pool of the of the cam D so
um you know and so you know initially
you know I would probably say there was
no real selection when I first took my
first you know
um initial mail and I just really you
know just it was just really a donor
mail and you know and just really just
really really that's really the only
thing thing it was really donating was
the male part of it because my my vision
was to just to keep bringing it back you
know until you know a certain point and
then testing you know not really testing
as I went along you know in in the very
beginning and
um
yeah so I mean once you know you know
once I got to uh you know to to the
trade dog and then that's when I
um you know because I I've used a lot of
different males of that and initially
like I would just you know I had I would
do a breeding and then kill the male you
know and so you know so really you know
and at that point it really wasn't
really like
my vision to continuously breed it was
just because I had a certain
um
clone at the time that I wanted to
preserve so I would just you know I
would just pop a new mail and and do it
bam you know I mean then I'd go back to
production you know and then I'd get
another new clone sometime and be like
well I don't have to keep a mail and
I'll just start new new seeds and find a
new mail and you know so that was really
you know uh the way I did it in the very
beginning you know because I you know I
you know I didn't really have a lot of
you know breeding experience and I was
just kind of learning as I go along
you know whereas now you know I do a lot
more
um uh more selections on the mail and
um looking for certain characteristics
and kind of like
one good example would have been like
the trade dog times a sour diesel which
made the sour dog so what so when I did
those when I did that initial cross you
know um you know my thing was all right
you know I want to produce a sour diesel
you know uh Sour Diesel line so
um it was quite easy to pick the mail
for the next batch because the um the
trade dog you know it it grew short you
know so any of those short phenos
obviously would have been more tree dog
leaning
so if I wanted a more shower leaning one
I was looking for a more stretchier uh
sour leaning type of structure you know
so you know that's one way of doing it
is like you get two different opposite
of of the spectrum you got a tall plant
and short plant well you want you want
to breed for the tall plant but you use
a short plant for the male donor and
then so you do that initial cross and
then just select for the tall plants
going there there onward after so you
know um and then you know uh you know
then there's another way of doing it
where you actually grow out your males
and females and then you know you see
the the male or the female that you like
and then you try to pick a male that's
that grows similar to that
so you know so you would be like all
right you know these things both look
same one to male one's a female so you
know you would know that that man would
kind of show the same characteristics as
that female but that's doing a little
bit more work you know and that's really
something that people don't want to do
nowadays you know and this is one of the
things that kind of makes me mad and
it's not that you know I don't get mad
that people use my genetics in in and
outcross them to other things you know
which I don't have no problem is with
you know and I don't get mad that people
are you know they cross you know they
are gonna they want to work with the
chem dog or whatever but if they're
going to work with the chem dog whatever
well why don't you use make your own
mail use your own genetics your own
outcross what they want to do is they
just want to take my stuff that I work
and cross it into a chem and make it
their chem instead of going and getting
their own Afghan their own Hindu Kush or
whatever the outcross that they want to
do make their own mail do all that work
and you know and a lot of that takes a
lot of time you know and and that's what
people do not want to do nowadays they
just want to steal people's work make a
quick Cross put it on Instagram and try
to make a quick buck and you know and so
a lot of people they'll sell their stuff
for half your price or what whatever
fifty dollars a pack and you know I'm
selling my stuff for double or triple
that price because I put that amount of
work in I have years of work in that
cross and someone just takes that now
and F2 is it in you know so that that's
that's the stuff that I don't like if
people want to take my stuff and out
cross it and use it for something
different I mean I'm happy that they do
it but you know the people that just
want to you know kind of pray off of
your work you know and then there's
always the argument well if you don't
like it don't sell regular seeds or once
you sell them then you know so there's
all these different arguments and you
know it just really
um on how you want to you know conduct
yourself and be known as you know if you
want to be one of those people and you
know there's always going to be people
that are going to support them because
you know some people you know they just
want to buy cheap seeds or you know you
know there's a there's a you know just
like you know going back to you know the
res dog thing you know there's always
going to be someone out there that's
going to you know uh that's going to
support
them and it's the same thing with me you
know there's there's people that are
always going to support you and there's
always been the people that are going to
hate you and those that's one thing that
you gotta you come to grips with no
matter who you are you can think of
anything in the world the best singer
the best soccer star whatever you're
always going to be someone that's going
to be like you know I don't like that
person because of this or that or
whatever so that's fine I could live
with that just as long as you have more
people that support you than that don't
that don't like you
yeah some wise words right there
what was interesting about that answer
was how you were mentioning that like
you know each sort of breeding is like
its own unique offering because it's
you're using the mail like one time only
is that still the case or have you been
keeping males more lately
no I keep males now yeah I mean um yeah
you know uh one of our last you know I
kind of learned because one of the the
tree log one of the last ones I used was
was one of the purple we called the
purple Fino and that one you know
everything that that was that meal was
bred to came out kind of purplished we
had the sour dog the uh original New
York City Diesel
um there was a a few other strains too
uh that that that came out like that and
um so after that yeah you know after
that you know I decided that you know
it's it's
it's better for me to try to keep one
male and to to to keep reusing that and
you know since I'm not you know uh
growing for production anymore
um so that you know that whole formula
now is you know is different so
um really it's more about uh the amount
of uh different strains that I have and
uh yeah just in just the overall plant
count overall so you know I'm able to
keep a lot more different type of
funerals I think right now I have I
don't know maybe like four or five
different males that I'm sitting on
nice nice it must be you know sort of
relaxing nowadays that you're able to do
that as opposed to in the past whereas
maybe a bit more harder to do that but
another question we got from one of our
listeners was how would you describe
stardog for someone who's never been
able to try it
uh
yeah I mean it it's got like it's kind
of uh it's kind of piney you know uh
Cami uh uh yeah uh
it's very unique you know in um
yeah it I mean it's kind of it's really
a good blend between the chem 4 and the
cam D you know so you know there's a
little bit of like Piney dirtiness in
there I guess that's really what I'm
looking to looking to looking for a
Piney dirtiness and a cami you know and
and so it's kind of almost a layered a
little bit of a layered palette and
that's really uh one of the things about
the chems because
um you know you can cross a cam into
something that's terpy and still retain
those Terps and get like a a chem a
layered chem flake flavored and so I
think that's really you know what a lot
of people that are really into Terps are
looking for is like you know you get
that layered flavor flavor where you're
getting multiple different uh different
flavors rivers in one hit where you
could taste chem you could taste Pine
you could taste fruit or whatever it is
and so that's what makes a lot of these
uh strains really unique
yeah it sounds delicious doesn't it well
that was a bit of a cheeky segue
question because as I'm sure you're
pretty well aware star dog has really
become a major player in the UK scene
you know it's almost like it's the new
cheese in a sense I guess I'm just sort
of wondering like how does it feel to
have a strain that's become that
critically acclaimed like there are
people who have had popular strains but
you know when you're at that point it's
really to a different magnitude isn't it
it's kind of funny because like uh you
know I don't really you know I've been
to the UK once you know for a brief time
so I haven't really spent a lot of time
there
and so you know it's really uh the the
people of the UK that's kind of blown
that up you know uh some you know
someone you know wound up getting some
seeds and some
um uh The Cutting um I forget what what
is the um the cutting the popular
cutting that was over there it's
someone's name I'm trying to it's it's a
particular type of uh cutting stuff yeah
so you know
um yeah I mean yeah I did I just finding
them it's it's amazing you know I mean
it's just it's just unbelievable you
know because you know it's just
something that just you know took a life
of its own you know like it's it it's
you know who you know
it's just really hard to explain because
you know I I didn't really have anything
personally to do with that you know like
you know I sold the seeds and somehow
they got into the hands of someone over
there and it just took a life of its own
it just you know and I know this has
been going on for quite some time so at
least five or six years now you know
I've been hearing this and uh that you
know the the star dog has just you know
taking over has taken over the cheese as
as the most you know popular commercial
strain
um I get a lot of people you know
telling me how good it is and I have a
lot of people telling me how bad it is
because it's being so commercially grown
so
um and and some of it they don't even
know if it's really the star dog or
someone just putting the name store the
dog on it so
um yeah yeah like I said it's just it's
just amazing because it's nothing that I
that I can I can't take claim to that
because some someone someone else did
that and you know just going back to
when something's that good that it just
takes its life of its own I can't really
say anything else other than that so you
get some Kudos I think but I quickly
Googled the the name of it and I think
it's called Manny's cut
man yeah the man he's cut correct yeah
the man he's caught right so that's one
of the more popular uh I think that's
the most popular one I've heard is the
mayonnaise cut so I'm not familiar with
the man he's cut right I don't know
anything about it but
um yeah it's made a name for itself man
whoever man he is
yeah I mean hopefully if you have a head
back someone will have a bag waiting for
you but um onto another sort of
international based question
a few different fans actually asked me
to try to find out from you what's uh
the can you give us the lowdown on the
top dog Thailand Endeavor you know I
think people have been following it and
are like oh this seems very interesting
like what's the backstory behind all of
that yeah well you know
um yeah I mean we're really interested
I've always been really interested in in
in Thai weed you know I had and I told
you the story of my experience with you
know earlier and so I mean that's always
kind of stuck with me you know so
um you know once we you know I started
seeing that you know they were you know
starting a a medical thing and
um
uh you know they were you know so you
know we we decided you know that we were
you know wanted to you know to try to uh
get more information and they actually
had a um
uh I'm trying to think the name of it
now but they had uh uh a CBD uh show in
in Bangkok
and so you know we decided to to go
there and and check it out you know and
and you know make new contacts and and
and so um
a friend of mine me and a friend of mine
um he's a panther grew lion and he was
the one that actually uh gave me the uh
that Scentsy star cut so um you know we
decided to uh you know take a trip over
there and you know get our feet wet and
see what you know see if we could get
into the market somehow and so we went
over there and we were able to you know
establish some contacts you know start
getting some information and everything
and then my friend stayed over there for
he stayed over there for a few months
actually
and so
um he wound up going up uh into Chiang
Mai and visited a few farms and grows
and stuff and started collecting seed
and so really uh you know we decided
that you know we wanted to you know try
to
um on one end tries to start collecting
Landry seed and try to start exploring
some of the mythical uh Thai stick
strains that have been you know uh
talked about and you know the ones that
I have experienced from personal uh you
know uh
from from myself
um experience personal experience so you
know we want to try to find some of
these strains and you know bring them
you know back to uh you know the
Forefront and because these things were
you know very they have a place in
history and and for a reason and uh so
you know a lot of that you know we're
finding out a lot of different things
about you know the Thai stick a lot of
it had to do with the curing process and
and stuff like that so uh you know as
well as long with the strain so yeah we
want to
um yeah so that was one end of it is we
wanted to you know bring back the lore
of the indigenous you know land race
strains and then on the other hand we
wanted to bring them up to speed with
modern technology
and uh you know from what you know we
experienced uh there seems to be a lot
of the Dutch
seed companies are trying to make
influence over there and
um
we think that we're better we know that
we're better than a Dutch and so we want
to make sure that uh Thailand is going
to be having you know the best strains
available from America and
um and not get bamboozled by the Dutch
because they're being targeted because
they're an upstart
an upstart country they don't know the
difference between uh a lot of this
stuff so we want to educate them and we
and we also you know uh we want to bring
you know
um you know uh modern medical
um standards there and as in testing and
um and and and and all of that you know
because um you know they they want to
um you know have a medical CBD program
over there
um they're they're having problems with
um with strains over there you know a
lot of them a lot of the streams uh
can't grow well over there uh they're
not testing for CBD uh High you know a
lot of them are um got uh THC in them so
you know there's there's you know
there's a a lot of stuff that you know
so um they're really on the ground level
of and so um you know they they need uh
to be shown you know the right way and
hopefully you know we can um help
influence them to uh you know you know
to do things uh in the correct way
because I think uh you know there's you
know
um uh a huge a huge um possible you know
they you know uh
of Asia you know because no one no one
in Asia is really you know taking the
Forefront for medical over there I know
that China has some type of thing going
on but um you know in Asia itself I mean
uh Korea South Korea uh Japan uh you
know that there's uh you know a lot of
neighboring countries and so I you know
I see you know uh the prospect of uh you
know uh of a lot of a good you know uh
economy they have um uh a lot of
tourists over there uh that you know so
you know they're talking about a future
uh letting tourists bike you know
cannabis or you know so
uh you know I see uh you know a lot of
uh future prospects there possibly so we
we want to we want to get in on on the
ground score on some of that stuff
hopefully and have some influence uh
around the world
yeah nice nice that's a good idea I
guess I never really thought about the
Dutch getting into those markets but it
makes sense that there would be in there
nice and early trying to get that jumped
the gun on people well you know the
funny thing was I S uh we sat in on a
um you know they did a discussion and
stuff uh presentation
and they showed like all their target
markets around the world and the funny
thing was
the number one target market
was excluded
which is America
why wouldn't you want to Target America
because you're Irrelevant in the market
as it is now as most
you know Dutch companies are so now I
mean so now they have to go into all
these upstart countries to where they
don't know any better
yeah it's interesting do you think that
it was purely just the change in laws
which led to sort of the decline of
Amsterdam or do you think that it's
maybe just you know more factors than
just that
uh that's part of it but I don't think I
mean they're they're they're breeding
techniques and and knowledge were you
know uh very bad I mean they were
breeding for all the wrong things early
finishers heavy yielders
orange hairs
you know so after years and years of
bottlenecking and crossing the same
things into the same things into the
same things you get what you got today
yeah certainly I think it's um it's a
tough situation if you're growing with
Amsterdam genetics and hoping to get a
good outcome
well at one time they were the best in
the world you know I mean if you go back
to you know the the the the the late
novel days you know and uh and and I say
you know uh the late 80s 88 89 90 uh and
then going into the Scentsy seed and
they were probably good up until about
95. anything uh from Scentsy seeds that
had the original cellophane card pack it
was a cell it was the see-through
cellophane with just a card in it and
then you had your your you used to be
able to get I think it was 15 or 16
seeds that they gave you originally in
that cellophane pack and it just had the
card in it with the northern lights on
it and then you would flip it around and
and so uh and then uh probably the last
the last best thing that they did was
the Jack Herrera the original Jack
Ferrer and uh I think that was what like
94.95 somewhere in the mid 90s and that
was kind of after that that was it uh
they had they changed their packaging
shortly after that and it was the the
product was never the same I had a
friend that went out and got some of the
original Jack Carrera in the cellophane
pack and he brought it back and he he
grew it out and I remember it was like a
77 Day plant but it used to I mean the
top buds were your forearms it was just
a heavy yield or it went a little bit
longer it had a really nice
um hazy tip to it you know but it was
kind of it wasn't super strong or
nothing but it was really nice like the
original Jack Herer cut and um so I mean
these guys uh once they found out it
started to produce and they just started
pumping it out and then I mean they just
started over producing it and I was like
whoa whoa hold on now I'm getting
overburdened with this stuff is not
moving anymore I was like we got to cut
it out eventually you know I told them
we can't do this anymore it's just not
selling so they're like all right no
problem we have we have the rest of the
pack of seeds that we have I was like
all right kill it all right so a few
days a few years down the road I'm like
hey why don't you you know find that
pack of Jack career and get that going
again oh I can't find it I lost it
all right so at that time I was doing
the seed Bay thing and getting getting
the seed credit so I was like I'll get
you another pack of the Jack Herer so I
got him a the new and I got them in the
new packaging I think it was in uh it
was in the bubble in the box and all of
that and so I give them a you know a
packet of Jack Carrera and you know I'm
looking forward to them to finishing it
out you know he finishes it out shows me
the final product and it was just [ __ ]
it was just so disappointing it just was
nothing like the original it was just a
stringy [ __ ] [ __ ] it was just so
disappointing
and just yeah I mean and really I mean
to sum it up that's kind of you know how
I feel about most Dutch genetics you
know there are a few exceptions Karma
and a few other guys that are that are
out there doing the real thing but you
know any of the old original guys are
just pretty much just you know going
through the [ __ ] you know emotions
and just producing [ __ ] that you know
for so for pretty much for souvenir
purposes because they're really not
worth much more than you know the
packaging itself you know so I wouldn't
you know I mean what what see what what
what strains of greenhouse are relevant
in today's uh on Instagram you know you
can go down
the whole list of all of them and you
know what's relevant today and really a
lot of them are offering American
genetics now and branding themselves
such as yeah yeah I think Bonnie's Farm
have just come out with a like gelato
wedding cake and it's like okay yeah
yeah yeah I saw that yeah yeah well
interesting stuff I mean to bring the
focus back to the US
um you know the Cannabis climate around
the sorry the legal climate around
cannabis in the U.S has been a sort of
changing landscape and there's a bit of
a sentiment nowadays that uh both
legally and financially Californians
just starting to push Growers out of the
market and even out of the state what's
your thoughts on the legal climate in
the U.S and how do you feel about some
of the newer places opening up and
becoming the hot spot like say Oklahoma
um well I got kind of mixed feelings on
some of it because a lot of it is just
geared towards money and corporate like
like a California you know um if you're
a small mom and pop operation you know
uh they just make it so difficult uh for
you to operate that it's just not
feasible you know the licensing costs
the process of getting a license uh a
lot of places you have to secure a
location to get a license so that means
you're you're going to be renting out
um a warehouse possibly for a year or
two even before you could even start uh
working there you know so uh the the
court the the startup cost on on on some
of these it's just it's just ridiculous
and they have it set up uh so it favors
uh big money incorporations
um on the other hand you know you have
States like
um Oklahoma and Oregon where anyone with
three thousand dollars can go and set up
shop
unfortunately uh there's not a lot of
money in those States you know so
um what's going to happen in Oklahoma is
you know is the same thing that happened
in Oregon you know once they got up into
full speed full production then licensed
you're gonna have ten thousand
people that are producing and trying to
sell weed all in the same spot and
um how many you know as far as I know
Oregon and
Oklahoma any type of tourist attraction
um the the the
uh household income is probably very low
so you're really stuck in a market where
it's over saturated
there's not a lot of money
and
everyone's fighting over the same nickel
you know so
um
yeah I mean it's kind of [ __ ] up you
know because they you know that you know
uh
the same thing in you know is is
happening in in New Jersey now and in
New York you know the the you know they
say they want to open it up for you know
um
people that you know has been affected
by the drug war and and this and that
you know and then they start making up
all these rules you know you got to be a
resident for three years all your
money's got to be in the bank for three
years uh
you know uh and then you got towns uh
you know uh all right we got a town that
uh we don't want we don't want uh wreck
in our town so we're not you know we're
not gonna allow it or we're gonna allow
four licenses
and you know the people with political
connections and money and who are who or
who knows how that licensing process is
going to be how how that's going to go
down and so
um yeah so a lot of a lot of people uh
get get get shut out and you know even
you know someone like myself
and who some may say has got some type
of reputation or or whatever you may
think in the game it really doesn't mean
[ __ ] to a lot of these people you know
you know what I mean because uh you know
a lot of these people are only
interested in in uh these are corporate
people uh you know in their only the
only thing they had to do is count money
and you know the the the corporate
structure is hey if we made 10 uh 10
million this year and we only make eight
million next year Well we lost 2 million
in in their eyes so you know uh I see it
as more of a commodity you know and so
um yeah it's really gonna be interesting
on how you know
um this all plays out because the way
that I see it is if you can't get in now
you ain't gonna get in later you know
and that's kind of like what's happened
here in Colorado because
um in the early days
of medical uh just anyone could have
just gotten set up anywhere you know and
then
you know they they uh you know they
brought wreck down and you know they
they uh they made a lot of rules and
they forced a lot of people out for
different reasons you know uh and then
they can do it through zoning and
through you know if you have uh a record
and there's just a lot of these
different things you know that that they
do to uh to to make it make it you know
virtually impossible for a small time
operator to to get into it you know so
it's you know really uh
geared towards Big Money a lot of these
states seen and and those are the states
that that have the money you know that
you will be able to make you know some
type of a profit you know I mean but you
know the the the startup costs are in
the millions you know and you know we we
are working class people most of us and
you know if we had millions of dollars
quite frankly we wouldn't be who we are
now you know what I mean so you know
there's a you know there's a big Gap in
between between you know uh reality and
perception and uh you know what people
think the market is is going to be
yeah hugely
so a sentiment I've heard expressed a
little bit more recently is that there's
a sort of growing suspicion that
National legalization may not be too far
off the future do you see that being a
possibility
well you know it's really politics and
you know unfortunately politics in
America is really [ __ ] up right now
and you know it's really uh kind of like
two parties the Democrats and the
Republicans
and you know most of the Republicans
don't favor cannabis legalization
most of the states that aren't legal or
run by Republicans
with that being said our president is a
Democrat
and
at first it seemed like he was signaling
towards legalization
and now it seems like he's signaling
against
Federal legalization
and so you know it's kind of caught in
the middle because originally
the drug war was started by executive
order by Richard Nixon the president
and it could be ended by executive order
by the President Biden if you wanted to
but no one seems and it could have been
done by every other president in between
and so uh
you know I don't see them doing it
unless it's beneficial for them somehow
and uh
for them to just keep things at status
quo kind of you know kind of protects
them and it's kind of like the same kind
of issue of of the immigration issue
that we have here where they just it's
[ __ ] up but they don't want to they
don't want to fix it they just want to
keep it the way that it is
so
um
yeah and then you know go and then the
only other way to change it is by an act
of Congress so if you want to do it by
act of Congress then you need
Republicans to get on board and you know
the
the politics in this country are so
polarizing that it's just you know it's
like living in two different worlds
yeah it feels very tense very polarized
at the moment doesn't it
so I just wanted to ask you a question
I'd love to ask all guests what would be
some advice you would give to someone
who's maybe hoping to start breeding
maybe now maybe down the track what do
you think some good advice you'd give to
someone
um is try to do something original you
know
um
you know you can't really you got to
make your own way and not really ride
off the coattails of other people's
success which you can in in a certain
way you know if you do it the right way
but you want to do it in a way of
creating something new not copying what
something old so you could take
something that's popular and new and
cross it into something that's totally
different and possibly come up with
something uh
so uh yeah I mean that's really you know
really the thing is just to try to be
original you know and you know like I
say your our past is our future and a
lot of people only look at the status
quo of what's popular today you know I'm
the kind of guy that want to go back
into land races go back to the original
start of things and start from there you
know start over again or use that into
some of the stuff that into some of the
new modern stuff you know the key is to
create new and not really try to uh
replicate what is yeah that's some great
advice and I mean you just reference
wanting to dig into some land right
stuff I noticed on your Instagram you'd
post some Afghani seeds recently and it
made me wonder are these some of the
stocks you might be looking to work with
and what sort of land races in general
would you want to work with
yeah well right now there seems to be a
big
um search for uh roadkill skunk you know
so you know in my opinion you know
that's going to be found in some Afghan
strains uh so you know looking back on
the history of it all uh yeah that's
where I think you really gotta start you
know so you know
um really you know just like you know
like I was saying you know about the HP
13 and not land right restrained uh yeah
you have to you have to go out and you
have to uh search for stuff you have to
try new stuff
um you know you gotta you know do stuff
that people aren't doing and that's how
you find stuff that's special and unique
you know you you know you find something
that's different and you know uh you
just you know you you you start you
start from there and start working off
of that it it's a step-by-step process
and you know really
um you know with the amount of land race
stuff that's available today well you
know there's Indian stuff uh Hindu Kush
uh Afghan you know and that's really you
know the base of you know all of the
genetics that we have today you know is
this that people you know they're that
they're too lazy they don't want to put
in the work you know a lot of it takes a
lot of time and a lot of effort a lot of
a lot of time you're you're you you know
you're you're wasting your time a lot of
wasted time you know so you know people
don't want to do that they just want to
do what's easiest for them and just it's
easier to rip off someone else's stuff
and do you know do some some kind of
cross like that and uh so you know
that's really kind of what separates you
know people that lead you know uh
compared to people that follow you know
if you're if you're a leader you're
going to go out there and you're going
to find your own stuff you know one way
or the other you know there's so much
stuff out there you know you just got to
go out there and find it and um and yeah
and just grow it you know I tell people
to pop seeds you know I mean pop keep
pop and seeds you know because that's
where the next best clone is going to be
found obviously you know and where is
that kind of where is that seed gonna
come from well that could become from
anywhere so you know that's that's
that's
the joy and the anticipation that you
get when you pop something new because
you want to see you know what what it is
you know and as in especially if you
made it yourself you know then it you
know then then you have that much more
tried to put into it you know but if
you're just really searching for
something you know you just got to try
to you know come up with a game plan and
just
um you know have an idea on you know
what you want to do and kind of like
what I'm saying about this roadkill
skunk stuff
for me you know I'm searching for it and
you know I'm just gonna have to try
popping different land race afghanis you
know until I can find something that's
similar you know you may find the next
chem something Fury or you don't know
what could come out of some of this
stuff because that you know that's been
the foundation for all this stuff that
we've we've we've had for a long time
now you know there's been a a lot of
um uh
um unstable situations over there so the
um you know I don't know you know
um you know how you know that's affected
you know uh indigenous uh farmer
generational farmers who who
traditionally farm from seed crop the
seed crop the seed crop the seed crop
and produce hash
from those you know from that stuff and
that hash actually is what uh provides
for their family so you know there was
always great family pride in the Pro in
the product in production in a product
that they would bring out because that's
what kept their family alive so it was
something that was always kept in the
family generation after generation so
after you break that cycle you know
where are you then so you know after all
the you know the fighting and and and
all this stuff throughout the the years
you know um you just got to think to
yourself you know how much has that
affected some of those indigenous
strains and and then and and and and has
some of them been lost forever and and a
lot of that can just you know you can
just look back at the seed for I mean
the Hass production and how that is
because that's how that I mean that's
what all of that at the end you know
produces the hash and Afghanistan was
always known as the one of the best
house producing countries in the world
and you know it it became that into
becoming just a commercial grade so you
know there's a lot you know unless
you're you know on on the ground and got
intimate knowledge of the region and you
know and stuff like that you know um
which people do you know there's a lot
of English people that are able to you
know better Afghani and Muslim and
they're able to you know travel back and
forth to the country to the Homeland
where if you and I went there and
they've seen our white asses they would
behead us so uh you know uh for us
traveling into those regions would be
you know uh very dangerous and you know
and something that I wouldn't wouldn't
want to do you know but you know I I
believe that you know those genetics are
uh possibly still out there but you
gotta go out there and get them
yeah comprehensive answer there and
while we're on the topic of you know
advocating for popping seeds which we
always do I'd like to know how many
seeds do you pop when you're looking to
search through a line to try to figure
out what's inside it as many as possible
I mean uh you know it's kind of hard you
know
um
you know when you're just working you
know uh not in a commercial facility
so uh you know you gotta pick and choose
you know kind of
um the direction on what projects you
you want to do
uh space is always a concern uh because
I mean obviously uh
you know you just can't you know this is
not a enough room for all plants but um
like right now
um I'm popping
um some Sour Diesel bx3 f2s and I think
I got about 20 of them going right now
and so I mean ideally I would like to do
a lot more than 20 but that's probably
about the limit that I could do in uh in
in the confines of the space that I'm
working working with now
um you know when we um are doing these
big Fino seed hunts in in the warehouse
you know we're popping 200 a hundred you
know uh we're doing a big
um big seed pops and Fino hunts and you
know like I explained earlier most of
that is for you know for hash and and
for flower production so you know
luckily I'm able to
um
um work with some of those selections
that you know that we're working uh out
of the um Warehouse with
but
um me personally you know uh when I'm
doing the seed thing like I explained
earlier I'm doing about 20 of those uh
so what I'll probably wind up doing is
running them
um selecting uh uh a male or two
possibly and then
um breeding them I would cross them and
then I would
um find the um
the the Fino that I thought best
resembled the sour diesel
and then those would be my next
generation of seeds that I would work
with yeah what a great answer you you
put in many of the blanks I had there a
question we got from one of our
listeners is can you tell us a little
bit about the bubble gum chem that you
used to have and have used in the past
yeah uh the the bubble gum cam uh
originally was a tray dog bubble gum so
um that was the original cross
um
I had gotten the bubble gum cutting
I don't even remember where I originally
got it from but yeah it was definitely
the real deal bubble gum uh fruity uh
really uh crystally
um
yeah it it was it was it was nice I uh I
brought it out here
um a friend of mine motive
um I gave him some seeds and he did some
F2 work with it he gave me some of those
seeds back which I uh which I sold some
of them and yeah
um I haven't really done much other than
other than that with the with the bubble
gum cam
that makes sense because I do remember
seeing some of those f2s on his page as
well okay so it all ties together yeah
and it wasn't really a stream that I
really planned on working you know it
was like one of the things where I'd
explained earlier where I'd gotten the
the the cutting and I just wanted to
make a a a cross with it and I pretty
much that's what I did with it and and
and that's and and so that's what I do a
lot of times whereas
a lot of times I will have a breeding
um direction that I'm going with so to
speak with like the sour diesel like I
explained but if I have a sour diesel
male that I'm using to further that line
and then I have a bunch of Clone onlys
that I have ready to flower I'll throw
the Clone only in with that with that
breeding and do a one-time breeding with
that and so sometimes those breedings
are
um you know they're just one-time deals
kind of like what you're talking about
the OG skunk or or something like that
it was nothing that I really kind of
um was going to further it was kind of a
pollen shock one time deal and a lot of
times the uh some of these things uh
take a life of their own and sometimes
people find find some really special
things on some in some of them and
um yeah you know you know it was just
something that you know I did at the
time and there was nothing that I really
intended to work any further than what
it was uh kind of like what Bodhi does
he does a lot of one time pollen Chucks
and so you know I I I I do some of that
stuff but then on the other hand I do do
a directional uh line breeding in in in
a place where I want to go so it's a
little bit of a combination of the both
that that the way I do that and so would
you ever consider doing any feminized
braiding uh I mean I've kind of thought
about it and
you know and really getting back to the
initial reason why I started breeding
was for
preservation so
you know you can't really have
preservation and
um without a male I mean you can I guess
go from S1 to S you know keep asking all
the way up but for me it's always been
about the
Evolution I guess of of the plant itself
into
breeding that's going to
further the genetic pool uh
in time if you know it kind of like
bettering each you're trying to do
something better each time so in theory
over a period of time you should have
something that's
you know that that that's evolved into
a superior product so to speak you know
and I guess I guess that would really we
we
really be talking genetic genetically
you know where we're over a period of
time that that yeah you would have
something that would be superior
yeah sure so something I forgot to ask
you earlier but I would be really
interested in your perspective on was
what was your first impression of OG
like I'm imagining you were probably
growing cam at the time and then all of
a sudden OG came out you know did that
sort of change the game for you or was
it still business as usual
uh well it was kind of business as usual
for for us because uh it wasn't readily
available I mean it was something I
could definitely appreciated and wanted
but yeah I mean we just didn't we didn't
have access to it you know I think like
the first time I was able to get it I
was able to get like a ounce or
something like that you know it was
really tightly held like anything really
good back in the day and to really get
like full General access to something
like that was just you know kind of
impossible because it was just locked
you know it was just held down and
locked down so so tightly that I just
would wasn't you know wasn't readily
available but you know I I mean as a
connoisseur I thought it was amazing you
know and uh yeah give me give me more of
it give me more of it so
and it makes me sort of wander on that
same sort of vein before you guys had
chem dog what in your opinion was the
best smoke on the East Coast
yeah I mean you you know we're really
kind of you know going back into there
wasn't really a lot of names
strange back then you know like anything
that you would get from Amsterdam would
be considered something super exotic
early pearls the early skunks
uh the silver pearls uh the I forget
there was a couple other ones and
um yeah so I mean back then we thought
that was the [ __ ] is it because we just
you know we just never saw something
like that before so it was really
anything that was kind bud or exotic or
from Amsterdam or yeah cents a million
you know I mean there's a whole bunch of
different things that were around but
not one particular thing that I could be
like you know because you know something
would something great would would come
around and then it would disappear you
know because the thing was there wasn't
a steady
um uh flow of that stuff you know a lot
of stuff got smuggled in and like I made
it through one time and that was it
you know unless it was being locally
produced you know once once we started
locally producing everything then things
became more production like when things
were being smuggled in it was just hit
or miss yeah sure
so what would be your recommendation of
one of the top dog strains for a more
newbie grower and also what's your
personal favorite strain you've ever
made
uh well right now what I have available
like right now the dirty taxi seems to
be really popular and if you're really
looking for a really kind of uh dirty
chem kind of chemd uh kind of a tip uh
that's what I would recommend the the
dirty taxi
um we have a lot of different stuff out
right now uh that's been selling out
the the sour diesel back cross fours
obviously has been really popular really
good representations uh Of The Sour
Diesel uh money has just you know made
some new I-95 uh ixes off of his keeper
mom uh so they've been flying off the
shelf
um the piths the black Pips
um so really it really depends on your
own personal taste and what you're
looking for you know you know I've tried
to You Know cover you know all the bases
of you know a lot of my uh personal
favorites and try to give people some
kind of representation of that you know
so you know a lot of that really comes
down to your own personal stuff you know
we have uh you know been like the I-95
stuff is you know kind of OG stuff and
stuff we've kind of tried to take in a
little bit of the best of everything in
some type of form so
um
so yeah I mean it's you know a lot of it
comes down to personal preference
but I but you know like like I was gonna
uh like the star dog you know you know
you know for a first time or you can't
go with the star dog unfortunately
there's no Siege currently available but
the good thing is is that uh there's
gonna be uh they're gonna be harvested
soon so we just did a remake of the star
dog I did uh yeah the Corey Haim in
Cross uh we did the guava in Cross uh we
did the
um original New York City Diesel and so
that was the three cams which was a one
of uh a really uh popular strain which
you know which was originally kind of a
pollen Chuck which you know uh you know
because we just had the original New
York City Diesel and uh you know cross
to the star dog and not really thinking
you know uh it would be as you know as
popular it was because uh you know
basically you got all three chems in
there you got you got the tree dog which
is chem you know chem 90 uh chem D you
know and then you got that cross to the
chem four and then uh you got Trey dog
uh uh trade dog 91 in there so you have
a good blend of uh
491 in um chemd in there so
um yeah that was you know another good
one the three chems that will be uh
which is being remade
yeah brilliant you brought it up because
I always saw that three cams and thought
that looked particularly nice and you
know Kudos who also brought up I-95
which is an incredible strain in its own
right and you know you see some people
who have got some pretty wickedly
Devotion to it it's uh it's pretty
impressive did you ever anticipate the
I-95 would have become such a success
and what was sort of the background on
its Inception how did it come to be
well you know that was that was a Money
Mike creation
and I you know I believe we we made that
in like
2015. uh we brought some seeds out here
to uh Colorado and we had uh gifted we
originally gifted some to Tara Rojo uh
who who was working and uh working for
mindful at the time and so we I gave him
some and uh
yeah uh and then we we that was the
original uh release of that and uh that
original cross was star dog uh Legend
OG was the male
times uh to the triangle Kush
so
um yeah that I mean
I don't know what that combination did
but it just really opened up uh uh a a
new box of uh
of the way that I mean the the way the
crystals and uh the formation of the
buds and everything it just really you
know uh gave it hybrid Vigor is really
what I'm trying to say really because
um what what really came out of it
really you couldn't find in any of the
in any of the parents sick you know by
themselves so
um yeah I mean it's really got kind of
an OG tip to it and it's got that
stretchiness to it but it's got more of
a cheminess I guess and as a little bit
more body uh and and stuff to it because
of the Indigo of the star dog so it's a
very very unique
um special strain and yes a lot of
people have tried to you know copy it
and try to
um make it as their own because it was
never really put into like uh full
production so
um you know there was you know uh
releases of it but it was never really
uh commercially released across the
board and so you know the the packs that
were released uh you know people were
just fine finding such phenomenal uh
phenos out of it that you know the
string kind of just took a life of its
own uh once again and you know people
just started you know blowing it up
blowing it up and
um it's probably been more copied I'd
say probably than the star dog because
star dog was more readily commercially
available in releases
whereas the I-95 really was it you know
we've had that initial release of it
like I said no it was 2014 2015 and then
you know it you know we wound up blowing
up you know over uh you know the first
few years and you know uh
so yeah uh you know we really didn't
really realize the magnitude of that and
um you know he had a limited amount of
original stock that he released but I'm
sure I'm pretty sure that he still has
you know quite a bit of that original
stock that he's that he's sitting on and
also
um you know he's just recently
um you know done a remake of that you
know from that so uh yes I mean is this
something that you know once again one
of our streams just you know it's what
other people you know did with him and
made them popular because we never
really
kind of push you know we don't really
push any of our strains on people you
know it's like we release them and you
know people buy them and then they
decide how good they are so
um yeah so one of the questions I was
interested in uh asking you is the chem
genetics in general are sort of thought
of as having some degree of sensitivity
to stress and you know somewhat prone to
a little bit of instability if they're
stressed out
when you're breeding with it do you just
have to accept that there will be a
small amount of instability to a degree
or do you believe it's possible to make
chem hybrids that are you know say as
stable as any other strain so to speak
uh no I think you know you know a lot of
that sentence sensitivity you know stays
present
uh you know a lot of it depends on the
the you know the conditions of the grow
and so you know when you have unstable
conditions in a bro then uh yeah that's
gonna you know affect some of the uh
genetics and you know some of the
genetics are really sensitive like the
sour diesel and the 91 and you know and
even some of the cushes you can you
could say that about the same things too
so
um
if you know
it's all about environment and and I
think cannabis adapts to environment and
so you know if if it's in an environment
where it's going to be stress and it
thinks it's going to die you know
obviously it's going to go into self
preservation and start the Herm out and
and I think that's you know um can be
true that's true at any strain so I mean
I think that's a built-in mechanism
that's in cannabis regardless and yes
some streams are going to be a little
more sensitive than other strains but
really in the end what's key is having a
stable environment you know not having
light leaks not having big temperature
swings having your pH right you know
there's a lot of little different things
you can go down a list of things that
happen you know and and what happens is
you know um people have it in unstable
environment they pop a pack of seeds
through life half the pack turn mail and
the other pack hermied on me your
genetics suck you know and so
I get that all the time and you know
and I've argued and I've fought with
these people you know and you know and
now I now I just reached the point where
you know I'll just give you a new pack
of seeds you know and it
so you know it really comes down you
know to breed or air I mean a grower air
a lot of it and they you know they're
quick to point the Fig finger at the
breeder and they'll say well you know I
had a pack of your stuff and a pack of
and other stuff and the other pack
didn't harm but your pack did and you
know so you know um
there's just so many variables that that
are in cannabis itself and then you add
that to the variables of of the
conditions it grows in and you just have
you know you know you just don't know
what it's gonna you know turn into so
you know to me you know it's it it
starts with the grower you know you have
a stable environment you have everything
that's tight and you know you shouldn't
really have too many problems even if
you're using sensitive genetics you know
but you know there's always going to be
you know those cases where you know
something's going to hurt because of the
genetics or whatever but you know you
have to do your homework on the people
that you're you know you're you're going
to be buying seeds from what kind of
what kind of reputation do they have you
know
um how long have they been making seeds
for you know how long have these strains
been around like you know you know you
know after a while you have a track
record you know you gain a reputation
and and it's not what you say about your
product it's what everyone else says
about your products so it kind of speaks
for itself so you know you really gotta
you know go into depth and do a lot of
research and you know and what you're
buying so you know you know and and
usually you you you get what you pay for
you know and if you're going to do
research into someone and you and you
know they're going to have good genetics
and yeah they're probably going to cost
you you know more more than your your
usual uh pack you know hundred and fifty
two hundred dollars three hundred
dollars you know but you you know what
you're getting you know I mean when you
buy a 50 pack of someone that that's
knocked off someone and yeah you might
be able to find some really good stuff
in there and and on on the other hand
yeah you might get [ __ ] and and and it
might get a Hermie bomb so
um yeah it's really you know the way
that I've always looked at it is it's
like I've always tried to buy my seeds
from the source
from the original Source or as close as
you can get it you know so that's why I
went to Scentsy seeds you know I mean
and and I've bought other greenhouse and
you know Mr Nice and you know all these
other name breeders I I buy from the
source you know and you know so you know
what you you should be getting and you
know the reputation behind it and when
you're just buying some random Cross or
you know it's it's a crap shoe and you
know you get what you pay for in the end
so true so true
so we've just got a few final fan
submitted questions before we do our
final five quick ones
one I'm definitely interested to hear
your answer to Is do you know any of the
origins of the Nigerian silk
no I mean I was given the Nigerian
um as a clone only
um from my
from what I remember it came from a
group of people up in New Paltz New York
who were a bunch of skydivers so
actually I think the The Cutting came
from a girl
and from from what I read the story that
I was told that I guess someone had
taken a trip over to Nigeria and brought
back these seeds and they were grown
upstate
now how true that is I I don't know
because I didn't I didn't know the
original people the skydiving people I
didn't know any of them so it was my
friend who I got the cutting from so I
can only go by what I was told in
um yeah that's as far back as I can go
with it you know I know that there's
been uh I know I know that Neville had
released some Nigerian uh seeds at some
point and there might have been a few
other people but uh yeah I mean I
remember first seeing the Nigerian from
uh the weasel he was growing it uh back
in the mid 90s and I remember getting it
once or twice and I remember him saying
how it took too long and it yielded too
little and he cut it out and
uh once I remember you know and then
once once and once I was able to get the
cutting uh yeah I jumped on on that
opportunity and then you know just like
I would with any Elite uh strain that I
got I tried to make some type of uh
representation and Seed so I mean that's
really you know what I did and uh
and that's what I've always been trying
you know I've been doing all along and
just you know had just been kind of
fortunate on the way things have been
working out
yeah very nice so I think that's more
information than I knew on it so that's
great the next one was have you ever
been given any breeding advice that was
particularly memorable or left an impact
on you
no I mean not not particularly from one
person because I've kind of learned you
know everything myself going along I
mean obviously you know I've read you
know Publications from DJ Short Mal
Frank
you know Ed Rosenthal and you know so on
and so forth so I've tried to you know
do as much you know uh
research that I could do
um as possible you know other than you
know really meeting you know
you know Neville or Ashanti or you know
one of these you know uh Skunk Man and
having you know one of these guys you
know telling you something
um
some type of secret other than that but
not no because you never get to you know
you never get the the chance to meet
people like that and and even if you did
I don't think they would tell you their
breeding secrets so you know a lot of
these things you got to kind of just you
know learn as you go along uh try to do
as much research as you can
um there's you know there's a lot of
books out there you know and now with
the internet and everything you can kind
of get you know a lot more information
that that used to be out there that you
can get now
yeah definitely grateful for all the
amount of information that's out there
that's for sure
so the next question was for you
personally what are the most rare seeds
in your collection
um that's kind of a hard question
because I have so many seeds I mean I
have seeds from all around the world I
mean
um and I guess you know
um probably you know more of the land
reach kind of stuff I would say
you know uh because you know a lot of
this stuff you know
um
you know I just made you know I I made
it you know so you know really
um
I I really can't I really don't have an
you know I'm trying to think I really
don't have a specific answer that I can
give you because I would say it's my
whole my whole collection in itself you
know because
um
I can't point to one particular thing
and say like that is
you know the
creme Delhi creme so to speak you know
because everything is is so different
and special in its own right and
deserves its own space
so I mean there's such a in a thing
about cannabis is such a wide spectrum
of different varieties and which give
you different effects and just
everything so
yeah I mean I mean the thing that would
be
most valuable is something that I can't
get you know
so if I can get if if I could have
something that I can't get I would say
that would be the most valuable thing
but because most things you can get you
know I mean and especially you know uh
you know luckily like you know someone
like me
um you know if there's something that I
really want I mean I can make a post
about it and I'm pretty sure like
someone out there you know would offer
me some kind of a trade or or something
like that you know I mean but it doesn't
always work like that you know I mean it
doesn't you know I mean so
um
yeah I mean I guess the thing that you
know people want the most right now is
that roadkill that original roadkill
skunk that mass Super Skunk that
you know rancid you know
skunk so
um
yeah you know I mean so I mean that's
what
that's what everyone's looking for now
so I mean and that's really why you know
I I you know getting back to the land
race stuff and you know so I would have
to say probably some of that land race
stuff because you just don't know
what the potential of something
could be in there whereas a lot of this
stuff I already know what it is you know
so I that's what that would probably be
the answer is kind of like the unknown
because you know if you have something
that you think has potential but you
just don't know what it is until you
actually get into it you know whereas
you might have a bunch of seed stock
that you made and you're already kind of
know what it is and you already have you
know
stuff that you know clones or whatever
so yeah that's yeah that's what I would
say yeah strong words I dig it so on to
our final five quick questions before we
wrap this one up so first one is what is
the best or most memorable single sort
of hit or smoking session you've ever
had what left the biggest impression on
you
uh
well I told that that story earlier
about the tie you know that was that
that was probably one of the you know
most uh memorable smoking sessions that
really uh made an impression on me you
know when I you know broke out this this
Thai weed at it you know in the dead
dead show parking lot you know when
you're you know eight ten people in a
circle and you know and we're smoking
and people are dropping out like flies I
mean that was you know that that told me
that that weed was killer
great answer it sounds amazing so on the
other end of the spectrum was there ever
a time when everyone around you was
really hyped about this new strain and
everyone's talking it up and then you
finally try and you just really weren't
impressed
yeah uh I guess Take the Girl Scout
cookies and
you know stuff like that you know I mean
there's been I mean there's been a lot
of streams like that I mean just you
know being on the internet for so long
and you know you uh you get caught up in
uh the hype that people put out this
kind of like how I explained you know
the lore of certain things and uh yeah I
mean uh you know in kind of like a
perfect perfect example would be kind of
like the Bubba Kush like that was
something I was you know really you know
really excited to get and then when I
finally got to grow it out and smoke it
not that it wasn't that bad but it
wasn't that good and I can kind of see
how it had its time and place in history
at one time but by the time that I got
it I already had other strains that
[ __ ] you know that crushed it you
know what I mean so you know there's a
lot of things out there that you know
you know that you hear about and are
hyped up and so on and so forth and you
know you finally get into them and then
you're just like that's just not all
that and you know that's kind of how I
feel with you know a lot of the designer
strains that you know that are coming
out now and everything and so you know
uh the Skittles you know when I finally
got to try the Skittles
I mean it had a nice you know nice taste
all in all to it but I mean at the end
of the day I mean probably
test it out in the in the low teens in
THC
but once you put that into concentrates
now that becomes a whole different
product
so
yeah on one one hand I could say yeah I
didn't like the flower it kind of sucked
but it you know it had a nice flavor to
it but once you put that into
concentrates now you know now you're
talking about concentrates where you're
concentrating the THC and really at that
point it's only about flavor
you know so you know now you're taking
something that is not really such a
great flower now making it into a a
concentrate product that is exceptional
for some people so uh yeah it's you know
it's you just don't know what what what
you know what will what will become at
what can become out of a stream should I
say yeah a good Insight so let's do a
desert island situation if you could
only take three strains with you onto a
desert island what are you gonna take
uh I'm going to take the chemd
I'm going to take uh
uh probably the black Haze pith
and uh
probably the OG a good OG you know so
that I mean that's you know so really
that would be kind of like you know I
got a really good heavy Indica I got a
really good hay sativa and then the OG
could kind of be like a nice little
hybrid you know so uh yeah I think that
those those three would be my choices
yeah three really nice picks I could I
could get behind those so now to be a
little bit Devil's Advocate all right so
now we're gonna drop someone else off on
the island and you don't like this
person very much but you get to choose
the three strains you leave them with
what are you gonna leave them with
laughs
well if I don't like them very much uh
I'd have to you know I guess you'd have
to give them the Blue Dream just because
you know uh
[Music]
I guess I'd have to give him you know
the Girl Scout cookie
you know I'd have to give him something
to
something just to give you just enough
you just don't get it just doesn't get
you quite there you know you're almost
there but almost not quite there you
know and then I guess
you know I just have to give him a skunk
one you know because uh
what can be more generic and a and a
skunk one nowadays so I guess that those
would be a mystery some really good
answers there so final question for the
interview if you could go back to any
place and time in history where would
you go and what seeds would you collect
while you were there
um it would definitely have to be back
you know in Afghanistan you know
definitely during the Silk Road time you
know there was a time you know and this
is really I believe the the Inception of
uh Landry seeds because
um in England they used to run tours you
know
um and they used to run train and bus
tours to India
and uh it would go as far as Bangkok
and um if you know anything about the
history of the Silk Road and the the
routes that it took
um you were able to
um
basically you know
travel in a lot of these um
Muslim past producing countries you know
where where hash was you know originally
from
and um
yeah I mean you used to be able to uh
just travel freely across Iran Iraq
Afghanistan
uh
you know the Hindu Kush
India
um Nepal
uh Morocco
all of these countries uh were very
friendly to backpacking hippies and
adventurers
and uh most of these countries uh were
legal back then you know we're we're
talking uh early 70s late 60s uh you
know before uh the drug War uh you know
it was really during that time that
Nixon Nixon really forced a lot of those
countries to go illegal because we were
um you know we were funding a lot of
those poor countries and when we just
basically told them either you make it
illegal or we're not giving you any more
money and so you know a lot of those
countries were just forced you know to
um go illegal and you know over you know
uh Generations you know it just a lot of
it has become Taboo in some of these
countries like Thailand for instance you
know uh cannabis is pretty taboo uh with
the general population over there and
um the same could be said in in a lot of
uh Asian countries you know
um
most of the modern Asian countries
should I say you know you can go to uh
Vietnam and Laos and in that in those
places in in you know the cool the
cultural still is is alive you know and
you know and that really dates back to
to uh you know them just using uh uh
cannabis and hemp for General use in in
Men in medicine you know so they've been
using you know this stuff for centuries
and had been until you know the United
States came in and told them they
couldn't do it anymore
so you know hopefully you know
um all that stuff will you know will be
coming back in in the future as you know
we get over the the stigma of uh you
know illegal cannabis and it's harmful
and it's a gateway drug and so on and so
forth yeah what a fantastic sentiment to
end things on so you know thank you so
much JJ for coming by and for sharing
all your knowledge and your experiences
did you have any comments or shout outs
you wanted to make before we wrap things
up
no no I I know I appreciate you have
having me on and
um yeah I just appreciate everyone's
support and you know if it wasn't for
you know everyone that's you know
supported me and helped me over the
years you know I wouldn't be you know
the person that I am now so I just want
you know to thank everyone that's you
know that's ever you know uh ran a pack
of seeds or you know made any type of uh
you know shown any type of support it's
you know it's nothing that I ever really
uh imagined it's blossomed into so
um I just really
um consider myself very lucky and
um you know you know and consider
uh
you know just to be uh in a very special
uh special uh spot you know and um I
just want to thank everyone because if
it wasn't for them it wouldn't be
possible so
no fantastic and you know likewise thank
you for everything you've done and for
coming on the show and sharing all your
knowledge
it's great to talk to you
[Music]
and there you have it gang the end of
part three a fantastic ending to this
monster Trilogy episode that has been JJ
NYC of Top Dog genetics sharing all the
information he has on the New York scene
reading with Top Dog strains so much
more thank you so much JJ for sharing
all of your knowledge we're incredibly
appreciative
[Music]
as always huge shout out to our amazing
sponsors for helping us to make the show
happen CT and the IPC Bank in the game
go hit him up for all the hottest drops
from all the Breeders you know you love
guarantee on satisfaction at the end of
a cycle not just guarantee on
germination why would you go elsewhere
likewise go check out coppet biological
systems with all the most Advanced
Technologies these guys have got you
covered will keep the passive bang check
out the appy param or the spidex vital
both of them incredible products can
help you overcome any infestation you
have or more importantly keep away a
potential infestation nothing better
than being proactive and getting on top
of a problem before it even exists guys
go check out coppet biological systems
incredible sponsors we really appreciate
them and last but not least Pro mix
connect your number one microrizer
product in the game genome Pro mix
you've probably bought their Pete before
guess what they've got a killer Michael
Riser product now and if you check it
out I promise you you plan to will be
better off for it no questions asked
better resin better flavor better yield
you know mycorrhiza is fantastic I don't
need to sell you on it go check it out
promix connect number one microrizer
products in the game
[Music]
furthermore huge shout out to Charlie's
cannabis your number one family owned
small batch craft cannabis producer out
of Oklahoma providing you with
Incredible flavors chemical sunsets star
Pebbles so many more on the horizon
check out their Instagrams to see what
they've been hunting at the moment I'm
really excited to have these guys on
board and I think it's going to be
magical to see what they produce going
forward you need some high quality
smokes you're in Oklahoma go check out
Charlie's cannabis you'll be tough and
good I promise
finally shout out to the patreon gang I
love you I appreciate you you are the
best if you want to get access to
unheard content Early Access to
interviews giveaways so much more go
check it out we recently got a Discord
guys I'm a bit late to the Discord party
but I tell you what I'm loving it some
good chats going on there be sure to
check out patreon if you want to help
support the show and ensure content
continues to be made
that's it for part one guys I'll see you
back for part two and part three
thanks for hanging around
[Music]