[Applause]
thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast providing
enthusiasts
this episode as always was brought to
you by our phenomenal sponsors see it's
here now number one seed bank in the
game guarantee on germination and
satisfaction why would you go elsewhere
they got all the hottest breeders and
the latest drops likewise a big shout
out to pop it biological systems they
got all the beneficial microbes all the
beneficial Predator bugs and the feeds
to keep the good army alive go check
them out to make your next Harvest a
success good afterwards grab the app it
ends good spider mites grab the spider
makes sense
[Music]
also a huge shout out to our family over
at the patreon if you want to be a part
of the lifeblood that helps make this
show happen getting early access to
episodes exclusive unreleased content
and prizes give away so much more go
check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
[Music]
on this episode we are joined by the
meme Master himself the head honcho of
pre-born selections you know him you
love him he's got the lime he's got the
Cherry Mean Gene of Mendocino here to
talk all things breeding history and so
so much more for a two-part Epic
[Music]
so without further ado
let's get into it
alrighty so a big thank you and welcome
back for part two from the breeder
extraordinaire meme Master himself and
the guy who I like to think of is the
Elon Musk of cannabis Mean Gene thanks
so much for joining us today
hey man thanks for having me
not a problem glad to have you back for
a part two our fans have been very
excited for this one to happen so the
first thing I want to ask you what are
you currently smoking on
currently smoking on let's see right in
front of me the latest stuff that I got
which is not really that late I've had
it sitting here for a little bit
um I got a really cool uh LA
Confidential
from uh
from my friend who does uh Tyler Buds
and Roses he gave me some of this uh LA
Confidential he said it was a nice run
and it's kind of cool I'd always
wondered
I heard that they use this thing they
call the AFI
um
to breed that and
it was really interesting to get it
because it's actually probably about the
closest weed I can remember seeing to
what we call Black Affy up here which
makes me wonder if there's any relation
or if it's just that it's that good kind
of uh
darker coffee Afghani type I mean it's
it's pretty common in California Afghani
so that's kind of out of out of the
ordinary because it was a it was a gift
but um pretty stuff really nice
yeah that's an interesting strain
because
a lot of people talk about how that
really special Alfie mother you
mentioned was replaced in subsequent
releases of that of the LA con with
something else I don't suppose you'd
ever tried the subsequent releases that
people weren't so impressed by
um this one I assume just judging by
what it looks like I assume is the
original one although I have really no
ground to stand on on that except for
saying that it really has an old old
Cali Afghani
um look it's very similar to what I have
that was the Hindu cross black Affy
back in the day that I made and um
the black Affy itself was a little less
resonance and then crossed with the
Hindu kind of beefed up the resin
content
and uh this was like pulling out they
could have told me oh I had I I I kept
some of those seeds and I grew this out
and I would have thought it was the same
uh Hindu cross uh black coffee
so that was kind of cool but I don't
remember ever seeing anything from the
later ones all I know is the first time
I saw LA Confidential
was at a point that was two thousand
uh seven
and 2007 yeah that would have been 2007
and I only remember because it was like
the first time I went to the emerald cup
when it was still a little event
and um
it was still at the area 101 there and
my friend who has a company now called
Giving Tree genetics which has really
nice stuff
um he had it and he had just come back
from Amsterdam and he was like yeah I
got all the different stuff over there
and this was one of the nice things and
it's called LA Confidential and we had
never heard of it we had never heard of
DNA we had never we didn't really know
anything about any like Seed Company
stuff other than like old Neville and uh
seed bank
and so he showed it to me and what I
remember about that particular one was
that it was like a really sweet fruity
OG
and I was like wow this is this this is
[ __ ] bomb like it was really really
nice weed and he had grown he had
brought the seeds back and grown it
himself and he's a really good grower
from down the road from here and uh
you know kind of makes everything shine
and so it was like that was my first
experience with it and so I kind of
expected something like that when I saw
this and then to see how much it was
like the black Affy that's why it kind
of made me think like oh so maybe that
La AFI was very similar to
um
to the black Africa you know
so wow that's a that's a cool little
rundown on it all something which has
always piqued my interest especially
when I hear the term lafi and black Affy
in general it makes me wonder if this is
the same sort of Alfie which might have
gone into the creation of Urkel I just
at least whenever I hear Urkel I always
think black Alfie is that sort of what
you think or do you feel like they're
they're kind of bit different actually
well I mean the way genetics work it's
really hard to be able to call that kind
of stuff
um somebody like uh uh inspector at CSI
would have a better idea of what's
inside the gene pool because of um
because of us wanting that because a
selfie uh the Urkel what people I think
don't know there's a there's a
belief that a lot of people hold that if
you take something and you self it you
get a bunch more of the exact same plan
but the reality is when you sell
something it's the most extreme version
of an inbreeding you can do which will
reveal anything recessive that can pop
out
and
um of course show you also those those
those dominant things that are in that
plant so you get a picture of what the
parents were and you even get a picture
of what the grandparents were and the
great grandparents probably you know he
he might have a better idea but I've
kind of seen what he posts from it and
I've grown crosses of it
and uh inbred those and I haven't seen
anything that I would say as anything
like what
um the Affy was that I had the black
coffee
or
what obviously is the AFI that's in this
La conf
um
it uh it has more sweetness and
um Urkel the really really impressive
thing about Urkel to me was it has a
a kind of a rose a rose oil and a lime
peel
and
um things I associate with like fruits
fruit loops Flintstones Vitamins
artificial flavor candy things and a
nice little dose of some skunk on it
which
people don't think of it as but when you
have really nice outdoor Urkle it gets
this little bit of skunk over the top of
it
and uh
you know the AFI that I had was more of
a more of a earth spice licorice incense
um
and that's the same deal with this La
con so
I would say you know that the that the
the Urkel
I wouldn't be surprised if it has
something that's Afghani in it because
it's very short
um and stout and bushy it grows sideways
almost
faster than it wants to grow up
um
and it gets it gets nice big fat buds if
you grow it right like an Afghani
so I wouldn't be surprised if it has
um something like that in it I kind of
you know this is on a tangent but when I
was about nine years old
I went to Leggett to this lady's house
and this was when
this was when the movie Willow was brand
new and I watched the movie Willow there
and
when we were chilling there she pulled
out
some pounds of weed
and this was when I had only seen a
little bit of dried Weed really like and
had any interest in it because you're
just at that age where you're not just a
little little kid
and I looked at it and it was what she
called the purple
and it was more of a red purple than a
blue purple or a black purple
and it was purple from the inside out
and it had this particular sweet smell
and
that was the first time I had ever seen
weed that was purple and so it had this
impact in my head like whoa that's crazy
there's weed that's purple because to me
it was always like oh pot it kind of
smells like hippies burning sage and
it's green and then I saw this and I
went huh it smells like
sweetness and fruit and
it is purple so that was really really
weird to me so I remembered it it's like
probably the first wheat I really
remember anything about as far as
features besides it being some green
[ __ ] in a bag you know
and so in about 94 or 95 a lady who's a
really really close friend of mine who
who I consider like my Aunt who actually
moved up from Santa Cruz when my mom was
pregnant with me
and uh
in uh into 79 early 80.
um she moved up here and she had a place
and when I was uh proud for freshman
year
um
I moved up I lived with my sister for a
while and then my sister moved and when
she moved I still wanted to stay in
school because I didn't want to go back
to Sonoma
um where I had been living for eighth
grade
and so she was cool enough to say hey
you can stay in my cabin
so I stayed in her cabin and she and her
neighbor
were growing this clone
and
she showed me the weed and offered me a
little bit of it
and I said oh
this is crazy purple I go as this is
this thing from so and so and Leggett
and she goes yeah I got it from the
neighbor over here you know if you've
seen it before and I go yeah I remember
it from years ago when I was a little
kid I remember the smell as soon as I
smell it I get this nostalgic smell
so she had it at that point so not only
did I see it when I was really little
but I saw it about five years six years
later and it came from the same lady so
it was like the same thing you know it
was a friend a friend both of them are
friends of my mom and
um
now when I smell Urkle crosses cherry
pie crosses
granddaddy crosses
um things that are in the Cherry Pie
things that are in the gelato there's
this common smell they all have even in
a little bit of the Purple in my Pina
it's that same thing which I call the
smell leg at purple
because that's where I originally saw it
and from this one from this one
particular lady now I'm fairly convinced
that whatever that clone was and I
believe it was probably some kind of a
killer Afghani clone or something
I think that clone was probably the
mother
of everything that people now call like
the perps smell like granddaddy all that
different stuff and the only other stuff
that I ever saw different than that that
had a real name on it that would give
you any idea of origin was that the
purple purple Nepal
and um I don't know that that was
necessarily that was really Nepalese
weed or if somebody just thought that
sounded exotic and slapped a name on it
but long story short I think because of
being having that knee-jerk reaction of
deja vu when I smell these smells and
it's sending me back to when I was young
like that I think that that clone was
probably where all these other purple
things came from because if you look at
that and you go it was already something
in 89 being grown by several people and
by the time 95 came around it was still
being grown
uh you know a little ways down the road
not that far but far enough away from
Leggett to branscome
um
it had to have circulated quite a bit
and I saw 94.95 probably 95
for the last time and Urkel seems to
have surfaced about 96.
in Redway
um so I personally think there's some
connection there and I tried to see if
that clone was still around and the lady
I still see her sometimes in the store
and she runs a she runs a little
business
um down the road A Little Spa business
probably not there anymore unfortunately
she said that she gave it to one person
in Canada years ago and that he might
still have it and I haven't ever really
checked back in on that but I I really
think that that was where all that [ __ ]
came from
um and I couldn't tell you what that was
but it is very different in that the AFI
is more of an acrid sometimes has some
garlickiness to it
it's more deep and licorice sometimes
but not like Jager or something and then
um
it has like a resin where you think it's
not resinous but then you smoke it and
it chokes you it's like it's coated in
resin instead of Frosty whereas this old
perp thing and the Urkle and all that it
has a more visibly you know it's
resinous when you look at it it doesn't
trick you you know so I think that
they're I think those are kind of two
things that are uh parallel and and uh
unconnected just based on
um my experience with both both jingles
wow what a comprehensive sort of
breakdown on The Afghani lineage and
purple strains in general I mean there's
so many Avenues we could go off in the
first question that kind of comes to
mind to me is that sometimes when we
hear these stories what kind of starts
to pan out from them is that rather than
what I used to mistakenly believe in
that we started out with like these
really shitty clones and just through
Miracle you get that one in a million
and it's a bit better and then it gets a
bit better it sounds almost like the
opposite was true in a way in that like
the older stuff was possibly the best
and sometimes it was retained in quality
each generation but sometimes it went
down would you generally agree with that
sort of logic or how do you see it
I think you know if you go to places
um you know it's neat because you get to
kind of follow it a little bit
um with with some of the people now who
share things
uh
like uh
um Deepak uh what is it uh Horizon is
that how you pronounce it yeah yeah it
isn't yep when you follow him around you
look and you you can you can watch
people take these fields of stuff that's
hardly fed hardly Dr hardly um watered
not really dried the way anybody you
know who are our contemporaries would
dry their head stash
what's in the sun you know it's maybe
leaned up in a room it's put in huge
piles it's passed through and if you
know anything about hash and you look at
the resin that they produce in these
piles you go wow that's actually really
good [ __ ] resin
and the the quality of cannabis comes
from the resin it's not about whether or
not you have a
flower that looks a certain way and you
you look at these places that are
traditional
producing countries and um you know it's
it's been said for a long time that they
don't have anything anymore all they
have is a bunch of bastardized European
remakes of other stuff that was given
back to them and their Gene pools
diluted
but I know the old original Afghani
types because when I saw them here they
were only had been bred maybe two or
three times and even if they had been
hybridized with newer stuff those ones
still pop out and I look at stuff that
he posts like right now from Kandahar
and I'm like that is the same [ __ ] we're
growing like that is Cherry Pie that's
cookies that's like the things that
people think are so modern
um they're there and they uh they're not
really grow like you know I've grown
things a lot of different ways and when
you just leave something you can have a
clone
of something that's exceptional and if
you just kind of put it out there and
you barely water it you barely feed it
then it's you're just like yeah it's it
is what it is but it's not it's not
going to look like a crazy Instagram
picture of some [ __ ] quote-unquote
Zaza you know and you you can look at
stuff he's posting from Kandahar right
now and you go dude if you grew that
indoor or in a deck or just really took
care of it and grew it outdoor like you
would be looking at that and going [ __ ]
is that what is that cherry pie or runts
or gelato or all those things that
people are like oh these modern things
are [ __ ] I'm like they honestly just
seem like the old [ __ ] from back in the
day to me you know
um
and then I was just talking to somebody
um today or yesterday
and they were talking about the old
stuff that we had around here
and growing up I always thought that it
was like so so long ago you know because
it's like oh it's 95 and they're talking
about 84 the import from 84 or
81 or whatever and I was like whoa
that's crazy that's the old school stuff
and
now that I'm not 15 years old anymore
I'm like dude that's [ __ ] yesterday
the difference in in breeding if you
import something in 84. and somebody
makes seeds two or three times and then
you see it in the mid 90s like it's
still the same [ __ ] weed you're not
gonna get that far doing enough
breedings just to make it be
um fresh seed because you know in the
back in the day people didn't just make
every make seed every year and try to
improve it it's like they got some
killer Afghani or Pakistani they brought
it here they made seeds they seeded a
whole plant they grew them for a few
years and then they went you know what
we should probably make seed again this
year so by the time you're seeing stuff
it's only been displaced three three or
four breedings at the most from 84 to
95.
so my own opinion of how all that plays
out is that
some people in basically from the 60s to
the 90s really to the to the early 80s
got their hands on things that were
already killer they made more seed they
grew them while they selected the
females a couple times that were a
little better or maybe a lot better than
the average and all of a sudden they
have these really really knockout
strains that today are what we consider
everything that's killer and then at the
same time
through all those years people took
things and they bred them the other way
where they had something that was really
great and then they turned it mediocre
because they thought man this is too
stinky it doesn't look crystally enough
it
um you know it doesn't quite have the
right thing that we're looking for and
they bred away from what actually made
enjoyable killer weed in their pursuit
to try to make what they thought was
what weed should be but they had a weird
idea of it you know and uh so I think
there was two directions I think there
they started with killer stuff they
started with bad stuff some people made
the killer stuff more killer some people
made the killer stuff less killer and
some people took the bad stuff and
thought they made it killer and it just
was like you know going in a weird
Direction because they had these strange
ideas like oh we need it to be stealth
it can't smell or we want it to look
Frosty but they didn't realize the resin
was in the heads and not the [ __ ]
stocks of the of the of the the
trichomes or you know so uh I mean
that's my take on it I don't think that
what we call Modern cannabis is nearly
as far displaced from traditional
cannabis as people think it is I just
think there's a lot of places where they
had stuff and they were happy with what
it was and they kept having it and there
was other places
where they had really crazy killer weed
and they just kept it that way and
different people over the years
um wound up with these different
different things from different places
and some people have the luck to get
something from Kandahar or to car or
like different places where there was
these really good things and then
Missouri you know Mazar or other people
you know got these other things and then
went oh this is you know Colombian and
it's like yeah that's not actually the
good Colombian it's you know and then
the name stick and it leads people on
all these Goose chases for all this
stuff but I think that all the best
stuff
is only a little bit different now than
it was way back I think
if you had the best stuff in 1983 and
you pulled it out now people would be
like oh yeah that's just as good as the
best stuff is right now and then
recombining things so so say you find
something like the black Affy that
doesn't look resinous
but it's Ultra potent and then you cross
it with something that looks very
resinous and is ultra potent and you add
the potency from the one into the one
that actually produces more resin and
now you have more of what was already
Ultra potent I think that's when you get
something like OG and sour and chem
where
you know you had you had the luck of
these combinations and I think that's
what the modern stuff really stepped it
up to was going okay well
you know and I think that's where the
magic of breeding is is going okay we
have this thing imagine if it doesn't
look resinous but it'll knock you on
your ass imagine if you could make that
same resin be produced in larger amounts
and then all of a sudden it's like oh
[ __ ] you know this is this this stuff's
really crazy so there's like a little
level up I think we did but I don't
think it's what people think it was I
think it's I think it's uh overrated a
lot as far as what what modern people
did I think that the Afghani people and
people in Pakistan Thailand Vietnam and
all these other places had already made
stuff that by today's standards would be
really [ __ ] good weed but um
you know people ReDiscover it in these
Gene pools and they think it's different
because they did it now as opposed to
them and that's you know that's my take
on that
yeah what what a bunch of solid info
there I think um looking as we speak at
the uh erasing posts you talk about and
God you're right some of these plants
look almost exactly like Cherry Pie and
cookie sort of things it makes me think
are you excited or interested in
exploring some of this stock that
deepaks found and if you were are there
any of your own lines that you would be
interested in sort of melding together
with some of these
um you know land race afghans
yeah I'm really interested
um I've been looking at the stuff that
he's collecting right now in Kandahar
and to me
it looks like really what I've always
been looking for when I was wondering
like can you still get real Afghani
seeds and people
would always say no everything's gone
every Everything since after the Soviet
invasion is [ __ ] it's all been
brought in and everything's everything's
everything sucks now and I'm looking and
you even look just using critical
thinking you look at these areas and you
look at these people
and you go so you think these these
people really have these thousands of
years of tradition of of holding these
things and then someone showed up with
some [ __ ] and all of a sudden all
their [ __ ] just turned to [ __ ] I just
don't believe it and then you look at
the weed and you go
they didn't have anything to bring from
Russia or Amsterdam that would have been
this not to mention that even if they
did if you're familiar with breeding
with some of these types these things
are Ultra dominant some of these
afghanis like these afghanis could just
stomp on the outside genetics and turn
themselves back into what they were to
start with anyway because they're they
they that that's how they behave in a
gene pool you know
um they're like what I call the bullies
you know they just come in and they just
bully everything you're like okay go
ahead cross something with deep chunk
and see if you get something like what
you crossed with you're gonna have more
deep chunk do that for a few years and
you're just gonna be back to having it
again and um
I but I don't think that's the case I
think I think it's the case that that um
there's a lot of people who were
isolated there and I think that uh a lot
of people who went to try to ReDiscover
the old stuff went to little markets and
they got [ __ ]
um tourist [ __ ] seeds that weren't
really what was the real deal with the
real people and the real people are
probably pretty intimidating if you're
if you're not from there and they're
probably pretty hard to approach and you
have to have people who
um who could really access the right
people in the right areas and and get in
there you know and so uh
I think it's really crazy stuff and I so
I'm really excited to dig back into it
and I have stuff from him and a couple
other people who have collected uh from
over there uh like land race Legacy and
uh Afghan selections and you know I'm
gonna dig in there and see what's there
and I'm also excited about some of the
other stuff that Deepak did
which is like the uh the stuff like the
um
you know there's there's a couple other
ones like the low lab and the uh and the
uh Manipur and
a few other things because I look at
them and I know the background on what I
have a little bit and then I look at
these things and I go oh that seems like
maybe
there is some shared Heritage there and
so you know that's a really cool way to
um reinvigorate things without adding
something that is really completely
outside so I I do have some plans to dig
into those I think this coming year I'm
going to get into a lot of afghanis and
then a few other Oddball things too
and uh see what we can pull out of those
and then try to just get those out
um to a lot of different people
you know so that they can uh
you know so you can keep the gene pool
um
more diverse and and I think when I look
at some of the stuff it's like it has
what people what people want and maybe
if you do big big selections from them
you might be able to go okay well this
is still without hybrida there's a thing
that everybody does they get their hands
on some seeds
and then they feel like they're they're
going to be doing the wrong thing if
they make more seeds pure like they're
stealing and for me it's like and I'll
say this right now just for anybody
listening if anybody gets my seeds and
they like them and they want to make
more seeds don't feel like you're
stealing if you make more seeds that are
the exact same thing you don't always
have to hybridize everything when you
hybridize everything then you lose what
you started with so I try to put out
things that are fairly true breeding so
that if somebody gets their hands on
something they can make more pass them
out they can get you know they can they
can get circulated and you still wind up
having that preserved gene pool that's
that's not crossed with everything else
and I always kind of cross things
together
um with certain goals but it's not just
because I want to make it be different
than what I started with if I get
something and I already really like what
it is I want to make more of that pure
to have and to share and
um you know it it can be considered
unethical to make more of what someone
had and then just sell it because it's
like you're kind of undermining people's
um business that they have
but there's nothing wrong with making
more pure and handing those out and
sharing them and all and all that kind
of stuff and I myself personally don't
care if people make more of my same
seeds peer and just sell those I don't
give a [ __ ] like I tell people to do it
all the time like
um
you know that is how you keep having the
same breed
um around and not have it Go Go funky
because I've seen most of my favorite
things I've seen over the years they
disappeared and somebody will go oh I
have that and I'll be like oh yeah cool
what is they're like well I crossed it
with this and I'm like wow oh
that's cool but it's going to take a lot
of work to get back to where you started
so like for me I want to take those
things make them pure
hand those out and then take them and
maybe work them into what I have at the
same time but I don't want to just
always hybridize like hybridizing to me
is just getting away from
um
from having what you already had that
was good you know so I just want to
throw that out there because I notice
it's what happens people get something
from me and they're like yeah I made a
bunch of seeds and I'm like cool what'd
you do and they're like well I put it on
this I put it on that I put it on that
I'm like did you put it on a couple of
the females of the same thing and
they're like oh no no I didn't want to I
didn't want to be a biter and I'm like
that's cool but if somebody took my
stuff and made more pure I'd almost
rather have their selections back of the
same thing that they made different than
I might have made it but from the same
exact thing than the new hybrids because
as soon as you do that now you're back
to a whole new process again you know so
that's that's my plan with those kind of
land races I want to make more pure and
then I'll do some other stuff on the
side too but I really want to circulate
those things so we preserve them because
you've got to keep
um you've got to keep them around in
their in their original state so that
you you can have them because they're a
huge part of our human Heritage is our
is our plant uh the diversity of our
plant varieties and when you lose those
it's it's [ __ ] up you know
yeah sure and I mean if we go back to
something you mentioned a little earlier
with
the black Affy Hindu hybrid you used in
some of your crosses in the past do you
have access to those genetics still and
would that be some of the stuff you
might want to cross with these afghanis
well so here's what's interesting I have
a lot of seeds of the straight black
Affy
I have a lot of seeds of the Hindu cross
black Affy I have a lot of seeds of the
Hindu cross black athlete cross Hindu
back cross to the Clone which was what
right now I would love to plant some of
those plants had like this uh
almost like a gardenia smell to them but
with like a coffee skunk at the same
time to me like probably the best kind
of stuff that I ever made and that is
really similar to what wound up making
like root beer and jarrow
um
that's was the starting point was the
Hindu cross black Affy but those seeds
are still alive but not viable enough to
Sprout so
I've had a couple good leads on labs to
be able to do real tissue culture and I
talk about it again and again and I'll
keep on talking about it because
that's what we really all need is to get
somebody who can take a couple cells
living out of a seed turn them into
callus grow them into callus
take those just like you do with
mushroom mycelium take one plate of
callus make 100 plates of callus and
then start hitting them with hormones to
get roots and shoot so you can get
plants
to get back these original things and
mine
I know we're good because as soon as
they got to the point where they
wouldn't quite Sprout all the way I
stuck them in the fridge
and I've checked on them
and they're really good as far as being
alive but they don't have enough Vigor
to be able to grow as a normal plant and
some of these things if you do get them
to pop up they pop up but then they
don't have a meristem so they only they
come up and they have their seed leaves
and the seed leaves open and there's
nothing there and sometimes that happens
and you can leave them sitting there for
two or three months and eventually
they'll grow a branch even from under
the seed leaf or from the middle and it
just takes a really really long time and
if they'll do that it's worth doing that
with them but the ones I have will only
get a tail
and then they'll Peter out and I can't
get him to get past that point and so
I'm not going to waste him on that but
um I do have
um I do have like what I call root beer
and what I call jarrow and if you plan A
lot of them then you do get the
Throwbacks that are like I have a clone
right now that's a throwback to the
black Affy Hindu and it's one of my
favorites we smoked some fatties with my
buddies came by the other day not the
other day now at this point it's a
[ __ ] time warp it was probably a
month ago
but um we smoked it and after sitting
there for a while we got about
two-thirds through the joint and
everybody was like whoa this ain't
normal weed like we we got a funny high
right now this is some different [ __ ]
not to mention it's very tasty it's very
hearty just really really killer weed
and um
so like it there is that and so I can
take these killer afghanis and breed
with those throws that are like that but
there's a Trippy thing in my brain where
just because it's the same plant
the difference in in the actual makeup
of the genetics and the provenance and
the story and tracing it back like even
though I know I can pull AFI Hindu out
of jarrow I still want it without the
sour diesel in the in the PK in it and
for me a lot of that is because
um
people assume that things like the root
beer are killer only because they have
the headband in them and the Hollywood
pure kush which are these famously
potent killer plants but what people
don't know is that if you had just
smoked the black Affy crossed with the
Hindu which kind of predates all that
other stuff and goes back to the 80s
when you smoke that that was just as
chokey and you know had the great high
and all that the plants just didn't get
as big and that's what led me to
hybridize them with these stretchier
things that didn't water down the
potency but they didn't necessarily
really add any potency it was already
really really dank at the point just
with the Hindu
um
so I I do still want to get those back
I'd rather work the pure Rafi and the
AFI Hindu
with these land races then pull out the
plants that match the description but in
reality aren't the same thing and that's
more it's more academic it's not going
to be a different product and it's not
even going to be more practical but it's
just a thing of being like oh this is
pure this is the pure [ __ ] it's a funny
uh it's a funny thing in the brain where
it just makes you makes you want that
because of the story and because of what
you know it is and I think a lot of
people kind of share that enthusiasm for
um for like purity of of of lineage and
provenance and and stuff like that it's
a it's a funny thing but I do
want to dig in and do those things but
in the meantime
um I'll definitely be doing some hybrids
with the things that are the later
crosses and I just released something
that was the What I Call special Indica
crossed with uh it was a ghost OG cross
special Indica across with special
indica and I gave out some of those
for people to dig through and find those
old Affy types and what I call Big Blue
and um
you know but it just as soon as you put
OG in things it's like everybody thinks
it's good because it has OG in it and
then there's no way to
there's no way to explain how good the
old stuff was when you've put OG in it
um so like I really want to get back
into the old old one so people can
understand that better because they they
the old stuff really is as good as the
new stuff but
how do you tell people that when the old
stuff doesn't exist it's all across
through the new stuff you know it's a
funny uh a funny thing
yeah certainly I think there's a lot of
Merit to that idea you just referenced
with people on this never-ending quest
for the purest stuff and I mean speaking
of the pure stuff I don't think I've
ever seen as much demand for any one
particular strain is what the public has
for your root beer is there any chance
people might ever see that in pure form
or are you looking to do crosses with it
the thing about the uh the thing about
the root beer is that it's and this is
this gets into a whole other
a whole other thing
so if you look at
growing weed in general for me
When I grow weed
the best way for me to do it is to take
live soil
and put it outside under the sun
and
I can grow you
500 pounds
for probably
two thousand dollars tops
you know what I mean wow now people want
to take
and that's what I'm talking about like
with overhead you know of course I'm not
going to give it to you for that but if
I was going to do it I could do that and
people go to do that indoors and are
already looking at huge power bills
they're throwing away piles of cocoa or
rock wool
in most cases not that people don't grow
soil indoor
a lot of people also throw away their
soil even if they do grow in soil
I'm paying for all these Foods they're
doing all this different stuff
um even when you're in greenhouses the
level of issues you face with pests
humidity you're running dehumidifiers
you're using supplemental Lighting in
some cases a huge amount of stuff all
basically to have something that people
will be able to look at and go oh wow
that's fancy and it's kind of ironic
because you're going to literally light
this [ __ ] on fire and throw it in a
[ __ ] ashtray which is probably about
the dirtiest [ __ ] thing in the world
like if I'm frying on mushrooms or acid
and I look at an ashtray with dirty
roaches in it and [ __ ] I'm like that's
that's the funkiest [ __ ] but you're
taking this thing and you want it to be
the most pristine and shiny and Frosty
and it has to have all these
all these things going on with it
um
and all said and done if you take
something like root beer and you grow it
indoor it doesn't even develop quite the
type of resin and Funk that it does when
you grow it outdoor something like Urkel
even OG I feel like is really good
indoor there's certain things that
really indoor they kind of live up to
their potential whereas outdoor they
might be more potent and chokey and
um have a little bit more of a richness
to the smoke and the flavor but they're
they're different
um and they don't they don't get they
never get this kind of bag appeal where
you open a a pound of indoor Urkel when
it's done well is so special and a pound
of outdoor Urkle while it's really
special if you can appreciate it it
doesn't have the same impact and
interesting uh profile that you get
indoor so
my point I'm getting at is that root
beer is interesting because it's only
really
fit the way I bread it to be outdoor
because I bred it outdoor and I selected
it outdoor and
it was the nastiest best most practical
thing to be a large Plant outdoor and
people when they buy seeds they
generally want to be able to put them
indoor outdoor and adapt whatever it is
and I understand that because that's
what's practical
but root beer is a funny one because
if I back cross to it endlessly and make
it just be
straight root beer it's really unstable
inside and in depth and people have
heard this again and again because I
always [ __ ] say it but
I have this thing where I almost don't
even want to [ __ ] get it ready to be
indoor because I almost feel like if
people are that excited about it I
should just leave it as Outdoors so
maybe people will grow some [ __ ]
outdoor and realize the outdoor is
chronic if you have the genetics that
are really really good outdoor
um
and so I might release it as an outdoor
seed I'm getting all the time I get a
little bit closer
to not really wanting to have anything
that is unreleased or that I keep to
myself
um
but what's interesting is that
it can seem it can seem greedy for
people to look and go okay well you
won't let it out because you just want
to have it but there's a weird thing
that happens with value
where like I've still never made
anything off a root beer for myself
but I've probably been able to bring in
I mean I don't want to put a number on
it but there's been a lot a lot of help
and money that has gone to charity so
far just by being able to leak out a
little oh this is this cross with root
beer this is that cross with root beer
and it's a weird thing because
if I ever release it for myself then
that would undermine that because it
doesn't bring in as much
but it's like it's almost better to
leave it unreleased so that it can leak
here and there as different things that
can be more helpful for people even
though I can't do a charity for myself
really
because I'm not that's not how that
works
but
it's hard to give up that leverage of
knowing that you have something of value
when it can be really helpful
um even if it's not helpful to yourself
because for me like I don't like I look
at it and I go yeah I could just release
it if everybody has it I feel like
pretty soon it won't be that like when
cookies first came out you could sell a
clone for five grand or a tray of clones
for five grand at least
and now people are like ah cookies
whatever maybe if it's the best pack of
work something and you auction it off
maybe you get a few hundred bucks
but it's still the same weed it was when
it was five thousand a flat root beer
has that little bit of hype and
following and all that
um
it has this value and it has this
leverage of people wanting it to where
it makes that amount of money if I
release it for myself nobody's gonna pay
five thousand dollars a pack but if I
release it for charity for other people
people will pay way more than they pay
for anything else I have so it's almost
like if I let it out and I give it to
everybody I lose the ability
to have that leverage with it
for it to have the power it has it's a
weird it's a weird thing like
because I didn't ever think I'd have
anything worth [ __ ] people didn't even
want to grow in my seeds in the 90s you
know what I mean and I gave a lot of
seeds to people in the 90s who grew them
and made a lot of money
but a lot of people then was only four
or five people you know
and
now at this point people are like root
beer root beer and there's root beer
Madness and I'm like well I can release
it but it'll just be another thing
everyone has like cookies
if I don't release it
then it has this thing where it's like
hey if somebody's really [ __ ] and I
can help them by putting out a little
bit of something crossed with root beer
so I'm up in the air dude and I know
it's a weird thing and the way my brain
works is kind of like
[ __ ] up because I overthink everything
and I mean I'm sure you can hear the
wheels turning just as I talk about it
but that that's kind of like how I look
at it is like I want everybody to have
it I just want to release it and that
way I know it's preserved and it's out
there because it's really it's really
good weed like it's very enjoyable it
makes you feel good it grows crazy it's
[ __ ] gorgeous
uh the plants they grow really fast and
and all that so for outdoor I think it's
really good and I have like dude I have
so many of the back cross three seeds
now that I'm like okay this would be a
really cool one to put out
but I just look at it too where it's
like okay if you put everything out then
after a while
um because I do a lot of the charity
stuff
it's like it's almost like well I would
be able to benefit from it hugely but
then I I try to figure out well what do
I have that I could put in for this
charity stuff that would still create
this kind of a buzz and this hype
so it's [ __ ] weird you know
um so I don't I don't know dude that's a
huge run on [ __ ] which I'm totally
probably at this point [ __ ] known for
like [ __ ] Kevin JoJo or something but
um
you know it's my it's my take on it it's
just it's a tricky it's a tricky thing
this whole this whole hoarding hoarding
versus whoring thing you know you don't
really know
um
you don't really know what to do with
stuff when you have something popular I
don't have a million popular things I
have tons of seeds but you see there's
only Interest really in certain things
so I uh I always try to measure it out
and do the right [ __ ] and I don't
[ __ ] know it gets at a certain point
it's tiresome and I just want to be like
dude everybody can have everything do
whatever the [ __ ] you want with it and
then I won't have to even think about it
anymore you know but I also want to be
like I want to use
the energy that's behind something to be
the most helpful and not just to make a
quick Buck you know it certainly does
sound like it's a double-edged sword and
I think the community is seeing a number
of instances where you're trying to you
know walk the line of as you so
poetically said hoarding versus whoring
which is definitely my new catchphrase
it's brilliant I love it so for sort of
the more aspiring breeders we might use
root beer as an example because it's
kind of what I've noticed this with if
someone did have some work that they had
made and they were sort of proud of I
noticed that like with root beer for
example you had a bunch of projects
already finished you know in the bank
ready to go and so you were kind of one
step ahead in that regard and then I
noticed that there was a number of your
sort of closer friends who had the root
beer cut do you feel like that might be
a good sort of duality of like you're
getting it out there enough that people
can hear about it and stimulate it
um some interest in it but at the same
time it's not you don't have to be too
worried about giving it out because
you're kind of a few steps ahead would
you advocate for sort of an aspiring
breeder who's made something and they're
looking to get it a bit more popular or
a bit more notoriety do you think that's
kind of a route in which they could do
that or how would you advise people
so it's an interesting thing I mean I
had that and I smoked it for a long time
and it was pretty unknown and I knew it
was really really really bomb because I
would try to smoke other [ __ ] and I'd
wind up just putting out the joint and
rolling up a lime one or a root beer you
know and so I was like okay I know that
it that it's really really good and
I gave it to a friend of mine
and I said you know
you'd probably really like this what had
happened was he had grown he had grown
some of it crossed him and his brother
had grown some of it crossed with the uh
with the chemdog Special Reserve
and he was like man he goes you know I
had High Hopes but it just it wasn't
that great and I'm like dude you it must
not have been a good cross then
try the Clone you know and if if you
like it keep it for me so in case I lose
it I can get it back you know
so I gave it to him
and he grew it
um him and his brother and they were
like yeah it's it's [ __ ] fire and
he posted it and all of a sudden it was
like everybody was like root beer and I
was like huh I guess it's a really good
name and it's really got a pretty color
to it and it just it just kind of
sparked imagination like you can't
really predict what will be
what everybody really latches on to it's
like people who make songs
you know they make an album and they go
this is the hit and then it turns out
this other song they thought was going
to be
you know it's gonna flop this turns out
to be the one that really really is the
hit and uh
it wasn't that I didn't think it was
that it was really really killer weed it
was just that it was funny because no
one had smoked the weed and they heard
the name and they saw the picture and it
was popular
it was a strangest thing to me because
had they all smoked the weed I would
have understood that yeah you guys
understand
but it only took the name and the
picture
it's such a [ __ ] weird thing so like
um
it definitely is really really important
that if you have something
that you want to popularize you can't be
the only one with it unless you're
already
really really well known
and uh
it was like this guy's account
that was my friend uh Southern humble
terp Farm
he had an account that must have had 60
000 followers or something at the time
or 40 or something like that a lot
and um
it was just like once he posted it and
said it was really good then all of a
sudden it was really good
and I was like wow that's crazy because
I thought to myself had it not been
really good I think people would still
think it's really good
but I also think that most people knew
that if it wasn't good he wouldn't have
said it was good you know it was like
you know him and his brother had killer
[ __ ] uh his brother makes really really
killer
uh live resin was one of the first
people to have really crazy big fat jars
of the of the best live libraries and
figured out kind of the the the tricks
um to get the Terps to separate and
everything that was a little bit ahead
of the curve and um
so
so I think people kind of there was like
a level of trust there and that helped
but I think that you do have to be able
to have things out there there's no way
you could just have it and say it's good
and everybody will believe you of course
some people will believe you and of
course people who know you in person and
they've seen what you think is good now
that's what I like to look at like if I
know somebody and I know they only
really like stuff that I like as well
because it's all up to preference but if
if that's the case then I'm like okay I
gotta see it and then I'll believe it's
killer just because they said it's
really killer because I know we agree on
certain stuff but um
you gotta definitely let stuff out to an
extent but like the root beer
has only been grown by
Southern Humboldt terp Farm in southern
humble concentrates
and skunk Tech
and
me nobody else has ever grown it
and they've only grown it for one run a
piece
and for some [ __ ] reason the name the
pictures it just got this mythology
and it's really funny to me because
coincidentally it really is like my
favorite weed to smoke along with the
lime one but it doesn't make any sense
to me it's a really strange thing so
um
you know like that was only a little bit
of circulation it's really really not it
hasn't been out there and um
you know so I you know I I'll I'll I'll
tell you straight up
you can do whatever you want in life in
general
and you can try as hard as you want and
you can do all the right [ __ ] but if you
don't have good fortune if if Good
Fortune doesn't [ __ ] smile on you
then
it it doesn't [ __ ] matter how hard
you try but you gotta try because if you
don't
then if Good Fortune Smiles on you you
won't have [ __ ] to [ __ ] to [ __ ]
display when the [ __ ] when the
sunshine hits you you know so you got to
do your best but it's really weird
because I don't feel like uh
you know I don't feel like everything
that I did with you know whatever
[ __ ] breed and root beer Yachts
killer it's it's great I mean it is it's
not that it's not but at the same time
it none of it makes sense to me like it
doesn't make sense to me that
um
people think I'm any kind of a person to
listen to about what's good or
that
if I bread it and I think it's the best
like it's you know it [ __ ] means
anything you know it's really trippy I
just I think a lot of what works out for
you has to do with whether or not
you have the luck of it happening where
something gets a little bit of shine
but you do have to
do all the work and you have to just
keep trying try and try and try and
different things different flavors
different crosses different moves
sharing things with different people
[ __ ] just trying your best to be okay
and and you know being all right dude
with some okay [ __ ] and then maybe
something takes off because you can
listen to that right there with the root
beer it's like what how is it popular
like you're like yeah it's it's this
it's one of the most I'm like oh [ __ ]
nobody's even grown it nobody's smoked
it for some reason there's just this
mythology sir that's why I always joke
there's there is no group here it's not
a real thing it is it's real and it and
I have seed that actually you can grow
them and they'll all [ __ ] be root
beer you know but
um
the facts don't really support the
outcome like the the even though
everything even though we know the weed
is the [ __ ] the plant is the [ __ ]
it's like but how do people know that
why did it connect I have no idea dude
it's just like people who make a hit
song and they go I don't know we made it
and everybody latched on and [ __ ]
Jimi Hendrix made foxy lady and for some
[ __ ] reason people thought that was a
[ __ ] he didn't want to even [ __ ] play
it at least the root beer I like it you
know but um yeah but you you gotta you
know you gotta shoot your shot and and
do and do the work and then you know
everything else I think kind of [ __ ]
handles itself it all just pans out to
be what it is it's that's a weird that's
a weird thing that I wanted to dig into
that so people really understand though
it's not
it's not about
it's not all about just
having perfectly executed plans and
um all this it's just about trying
trying trying trying doing your best
doing your best doing your best and then
see what the [ __ ] happens because you
can't there's no recipe other than
um trying your best trying your best is
the is the master key to
[ __ ] anything working a little bit
you know
interesting stuff sounds like there's
some formulation out there and while we
may not know it it certainly seems like
you know hard work good genetics and
luck are certainly a bit of a mix in
there it's interesting if we just jump
back to a question we spoke about a
couple questions back you mentioned how
you know people will see headband or OG
in the mix of the list of genetics and
then all of a sudden it like gets them
interested I was interested in asking
you I've noticed you tend to work a lot
with both ghost doji which I've seen in
some of your more recent crosses as well
as with the Skywalker OG which people
will probably remember is a big part of
the skycard lacush would you say that
these two are your favorite ogs and if
you had to pick one or the other what
would be your absolute favorite OG to
work with within your projects
okay so the original my original
experience with OG which when I first
got it I thought was the original OG
um which is
fully not true it's not even a pure OG
but the Hollywood peer Kush is the one
that is the most present in my work and
that's because I got it before I had
anything else and I think I got it 2004
2005.
um
now that one
is
um neat because you cross it with things
and it doesn't
uh crybaby Organics was talking about
this on a post the other day there's
certain plants that you use
as a mother for seeds where when you
cross to them
it
it adds something without taking
something away
so for me using the pure kush was
interesting because
it doesn't it it it it doesn't it's not
a bully
um you cross with it and whatever male
you hit it with most of your seeds come
out smelling like the male side but
um in the case of all the things that I
used with it which were these squat
indicas which tended to want to get Bud
mold
um they didn't yield a lot in a large
pot I was growing medical Gardens where
you could only have 25 plants you want
them to be as big as they can get
um it made things more rangy and it
didn't dilute their potency and in some
cases it added to their potency
depending on what you were using
and so that was the one that I used that
was
um
that was the prevalent one in my crosses
now something like Sky cuddler Kush I
took uh big red put it on Hindu clone
put it on pure kush then I put it on
Skywalker
but I took that and I put it back on the
pure kush again
and
I really like it
the thing about the pure kush is that
it's a finicky plant
and something like Sky cuddler Kush has
so much PK in it that if you grow it
good and you know how to grow oh geez
just like the pure kush clone the pure
kush clone if you grow it well you get
these huge buds
that are caked in resin that are super
dense that are super loud and when you
smoke them you're like wow there's not
anything else it it's literally the
flower is more potent in your chest than
most
hash which I had never really
seen before that except maybe on the
black line or on the
um Hindu AFI which were both things that
I crossed to it to make what became line
one and what I called OG coffee which
was the father of root beer and what I
call jarrow
and so
um
when you grow these things if you grow
them right they're amazing and you might
not even know why you grew them right
but they come out great you get these
huge plants with huge colas and they're
[ __ ] excellent and then people
[ __ ] them up and they don't know how
they [ __ ] them up and I can't tell
them how they [ __ ] them up other than
maybe
underwatering over watering like really
hard for a few little rounds to where
the metabolism of the plant gets [ __ ]
up and then all of a sudden they have
weed that's either larvae or light or
it's just not quite right and you're
like well I don't really know what to
tell you because when you grow a normal
soil mix
and you don't [ __ ] with anything they
just have these plants that
they just throw down
but if you [ __ ] them up then you see
that PK weirdness where all of a sudden
you're like oh man these just don't
they're not doing what I want them to do
so it's a it's a weird thing that the PK
brings to the table
um the PK also brings a certain level of
instability to the table which is the
same deal if you grow them a certain way
they're fine if you grow them another
way once again which I can't really pin
down
it's like when I had the the Hindu
the big red on the Hindu on the PK
um
I call it OG cuddler or red Hindu Kush
cause big red Hindu pure kush
um
people would grow them
grow them indoor they're all perfect
grow them outdoor they're all perfect
somebody grows a pack indoor or outdoor
the whole pack has [ __ ] sexual
instability
you're like well there's already been a
whole bunch of these have been grown
perfectly fine and now these ones they
freaked out so that's like OG crosses
diesel crosses cookie crosses you'll
talk to somebody they'll go oh those
seeds are [ __ ] they're all Hermes and
then you'll talk to somebody else
another I agree with three or four packs
they were all great so whatever it is
that makes these things freak out it
makes them freak out but it's something
that's coming from
in the case of like uh red Hindu Kush it
was it was uh
you know coming from that
PK clone
so the PK clone is this weird thing
because it either gives you the best
thing ever or it gives you stuff that
[ __ ] up on you and um the nature of how
I grow is so simple that I don't ever
see that I don't ever have plants that
are [ __ ] awful unless I grow
something that's really
outlandishly shitty and you just know
it's going to be really bad because it's
a weird [ __ ] auto root or Alice or
some [ __ ] that's like the only things I
can remember that were really bad
but um but the PK is a trip like that
and that is the OG that really is the
most prevalent in my work then the ghost
I took the skyjaro which is jarrow
um so that's Hindu
crossed with a black Affy male and I
called that black coffee at the time but
that's a dead what I call the deadline
it's not it's it's not out there
anywhere so you know right now people
like uh biovortex Black Dog crossed with
coffee from Kaya at Green Source Gardens
they have a black coffee I don't give a
[ __ ] because my black coffee is a
deadline it's only been used in
um something that is later so I don't
have a black coffee I had a black coffee
but I don't use that anymore so that's
the Hindu the AFI on the Hindu I crossed
that with a Hollywood pure kush
and then I put that on the sour diesel
that made jarrow I took that I put that
on the Skywalker the Skywalker I really
liked it was stretchy it was vigorous it
had the really clear OG smell different
from the ghost where it was more
chemical less Earth less skunk
um I liked it I liked the shininess of
it I like the Vigor of it and then
um so I had that I had this guy jar I
grew those those were killer they all
came out like really nice OG and some OG
plants breed more OG and some breed less
pure kush is more transparent you don't
get a lot of OG from it
um you get a lot more of what the male
side was Skywalker I got a lot of OG
from it which leads me to believe it was
more bottleneck it was probably a S2 or
S3 or something like that
um
so
that made the sky jarrow I took that and
I put that on the ghost because I had
grown
um
I had grown The Ghost s1s and they were
really consistently all kind of an OG so
I was like okay well I know that the
ghost is throwing a lot of OG whereas
the PK wouldn't have done that the PK
throws a lot more plain stuff it throws
some purples that are like lavender it
throws these cotton candy type of things
it's really nice but it's not allo G the
ghost growing the S1 ferment was like
okay you get a lot of the real OG
so
skydrawal was all OG basically with a
little you know a little bit different
not not all the loudest
um and a little bit more Vigor longer
canes
um a little faster finishing and then I
put that on the ghost to make the ghost
cross Sky jarrow because everybody
wanted like a Kush seed that would be
vigorous and better than a OG clone as
far as how it does in your garden so
um so I did that and that was The Ghost
and then I also did the Ghost with the
lime pop those came out really nice I
like those a lot I handed them almost
all out as testers
and then I lost the Line Pop Mail
so I had very few of the seeds left back
to continue the lime but I went ahead
and did that and this year I kept that
going to the f2s but
I gave them all almost all out as
testers so I figured if everybody grew
them and they were great then I could
take the lime Pop Mail I had as a clone
and I could put it back on The Ghost and
I could produce those and that could be
one thing that I kind of had as one of
my my Staples because it was such a nice
weed when I grew it um Outside Inside
It's a little bit unstable so it's going
to keep getting worked
um hopefully by F3 F4 I can have
something that's nice and I'll put that
back out but um
the ghost is killer to me it's the real
heavy [ __ ] OG the real deal real OG
Kush Skywalker is a little bit more a
little bit lighter of a high a little
bit
bigger hardier of a plant I really like
it it makes these really big pretty
seeds it's kind of neat and then the PK
really brings
a lot of potency
and it breeds a little bit more
transparently which I really like
because I'm most the time I'm not trying
to breed an OG in seed form I'm trying
to use what's good about the OG and Tack
it on to what I already have on the male
side
um
and so that's cool and the PK unlike a
lot of OG's it drops Hash a little bit
better
um because of its uh what's in it as
opposed to where the OG is
fairly greasy it'll drop some hash but
the PK drops hash closer more like a
Bubba so that's the
um
no that's the reason for there being a
lot of PKS that was the first one I had
and I believed it to be really old pure
OG based on the way the weed was
when I got it but later on kind of found
out that it's not uh you know it
actually has other stuff in it
wow what a detailed breakdown of what
sort of each of the ogs you work with is
bringing to the table in your crosses
since we last spoke uh it feels as
though the backstory is behind the OG
cush itself have been fleshed out a fair
bit more with TK Origins kind of coming
out of the shadows and explaining his
story the thing I wanted to ask you
about was that a lot of people might be
aware that he speaks about how he was
growing a strain called Emerald Triangle
and he suspects the male involved in the
pollination was probably a Hindu Kush
when he was pushed to give some sort of
guess about what this Emerald Triangle
strain was he frequently says probably
some sort of Hindu Kush sort of thing
and it makes me wonder could you believe
that like or do you believe that OG Kush
is possibly just some sort of Hindu in
Cross if we are to if if what TK origin
says is correct could you say that or do
you have a suspicion that maybe there's
some other genetics in the mix
okay so there's there's an interesting
thing at play here that uh
this is a this is a multi-layered thing
um
so Hindu Kush okay Hindu Kush
I've always kind of wondered about this
Hindu Kush is a region
um
within that region are tons of different
micro regions where different
uh strains would have come from
so
um
I always wondered what is Hindu Kush and
there was a sacred seeds Hindu Kush that
came out
marketed as being skunky in the early
80s
and there was
um
originally Neville had a uh
this is where it's hard to kind of sift
through
originally Neville had a Northern Lights
one in the Northern Lights two
um
I believe Greg McAllister says the
further towards the one you go the pure
more pure The Afghani is
and
um
so there's a Trippy thing so
Northern Lights one then would have been
just straight straight broadleaf
gnarliness uh Northern Lights too would
have been two based on everybody's
descriptions of what those were at the
time
um
now Neville had those
originally he marketed those
I believe
and
this is this is info from seed banks
that
um I have the catalogs and I've read
about them but this was brought up again
by by my buddy uh not so dog
and he pointed out something which was
pretty interesting that
in one year Neville has Northern Lights
with the description
uh Northern Lights too I think maybe one
and in the following year
now it is I believe Scentsy seeds don't
you know don't take that as the gospel
because it could have still been his own
thing but I believe what happened was
when he shifted his stock from seed bank
to Sensi seed bank
um
the names changed and so what was
originally Northern Lights to
and once again this is just how I
remember it and I never put too much
into really remembering the details of
it because I know I can access that
um
it changed from Northern Lights to being
labeled as Hindu Kush
so
apparently there's a Hindu Kush
as a strain and like I said before it's
a region so there would have really been
a lot of things but what we would have
had in California labeled as Hindu Kush
or Florida labeled as Hindu Kush would
have either been Hindu Kush from sacred
seeds in like 83.
or it would have been Hindu Kush which
was Northern Lights renamed as Hindu
Kush by Scentsy seeds or by seed bank in
which would have been more like 8687 I
believe
now in terms of seeds the these time
frames these are right next to each
other you know like
someone who got cookies in 2016 or 2013
and [ __ ] cookies you know but
somebody who got those two things back
then
seems like it probably would have been
two different things because I don't
think the Hindu Kush sacred seeds had is
the same as the Hindu Kush that Neville
had I think Neville knew that this heavy
Afghani type would have been from the
Hindu Kush region and instead of calling
it Northern Lights because he at that
point had had the Northern Lights number
five and stuff that was a little more of
a hybrid type
he had named the ones that were closer
to being a pure Afghani type as being
Hindu Kush probably because Hindu Kush
sounds different than Afghani and
Afghani number one was out at the time I
believe
um so anyway
that is all to say
that
when I have my Northern Lights and I
started breeding it
in the mid 90s
um originally
before I had actually made seed I
started seeing these ones that would pop
out in the compost pile when it would
seed itself
and the seeds would get thrown away
um
that my uh my dad
at the time
was every once in a while I'd be like
oops something got [ __ ] up all right
there's some seated stuff all right it
gets pulled out when it gets trimmed
they get thrown in the compost pile
now
George would have a plant in the compost
pile pretty much every year and they'd
be these really nice things they'd be
just pretty much like the Clone but they
were very Indica they seemed a little
more broadly when you groom from seed
than when they did from clone which I
think is kind of typical of plants in
general uh the first big fan Leafs that
come up on an immature plant before it
Sexes they really want to get Big And
Chunky and fat because I think probably
they're trying to do their best to
really get a [ __ ] head start
um
so
I think the northern lights that we had
would have probably been like a Northern
Lights five cross Northern Lights too or
something the plant itself to me was not
what I would consider to be a pure
broadleaf as a clone it was
very very similar looking to an OG Kush
clone
so when I made things like when I bred
through the jarrow or skyjaro
Etc
I would look for these things that were
like the Northern Lights we had and it
was very dark dark green the leaves they
were shiny
they
would usually have five or seven
um leaflets
never more
um
they had crazy the the Clone itself it
had crazy amounts of resin on it it was
resin that liked to fall off like an
Afghani
um the potency was just insane
definitely right up there with something
like an OG or a sour or a chem
um
and
you know I kind of had this structure
that was
uh you know fairly thin stem not what I
would normally consider to be a straight
Afghani but Afghanistan has a really
diverse gene pool I'm just saying that
um
the Northern Lights we had wasn't like a
Bubba now something like a Bubba
is exactly
I mean almost
impossible to tell the difference
between good bubba and good
Hindu which we had around here which we
called Hindu Hindu and the guy who had
it the most around here was my buddy Jay
Law and Jayla
he
had this Hindu clone that he called
Hindu Hindu
and it was [ __ ] bomb and it was like
Bubba but more visibly white and frosty
um it had that same kind of a thing
where it had this smell that was like a
coffee
Earth soap
I don't know it's a really trippy trippy
thing almost had like a plant latex
smell to it a little bit like um like
when you break open like milkweed or
dandelions or
real cocaine which I personally have
never done but which I have seen in you
know certain situations where people had
it and I was curious about what it looks
like
um
it just never was my thing I tasted it
made me angry I never really tried it
again uh
I had a toothache one time I put it on
that real effective but it has something
like that that plant latex thing that's
hard to describe and so anyway this is
all just digging in to kind of give an
idea of a backstory of all this kind of
stuff
so
um also it really liked to drop resin
like my clone did but they were very
different and then in about
2003 I would say my buddy
uh Big L used to like to come up and
grab weed from people in Mendo
to take to LA and he would buy the Hindu
from the Hindu clone and he would sell
it in LA as Bubba
and he would get major top dollar for it
like unheard of [ __ ] but because it was
Bubba and the people who wanted it knew
their [ __ ] but they still were like yeah
this is Bubba but it wasn't Bubba
it was Hindu
the back story on the Hindu it turns out
before Jay Lau got it it went to his
buddy up there and Leggett
and
the person who gave it to him it turns
out was a friend of mine who was an
older lady who's probably about 65 70.
really cool lady and she said she got it
from a guy named Frank
who had a heroin problem who lived here
where I live and that was around 84 or
85. now I believe that because it was so
long back
she had actually mixed it up and it was
probably a little bit later because I
personally think that she got it from
Frank and that Frank probably got it
from
Neville once the Northern Lights name
had been changed to Hindu Kush in 86 or
87 or whatever now if you
if you get something
30 some years ago
it's really easy to think you got it 32
years ago instead of 34 years ago or 36
years ago instead of 39 years ago so I
think that what we called Hindu Kush up
here which is the same as Bubba
was probably from that seed bank release
which was Northern Lights after it had
been changed to be called Hindu Kush
and
that
Bubba Kush is almost the same thing and
if you hear the story that people tell
about the earliest Bubba Kush they say
they think it was a Northern Lights
cross
and if you hear the description from
Origins TK who I've talked with a lot
because at one point I almost wondered
if the Emerald Triangle had been the
Clone that we had that my mom popped
because she popped it in 89
but he said that the Emerald Triangle
they had had since probably about
87 which would make it impossible that
it was that clone
and why would my crazy ass think that it
could have been our clone was only the
fact that when I bred with things
from OG and I was looking for OG I had
really good luck finding males that
would throw OG by looking for the same
look as our Northern Lights clone but
Northern Lights had been very consistent
so
I wouldn't be surprised if what he's
calling Hindu Kush
is what is in fact Northern Lights and
never was taking Northern Lights and
calling it Hindu Kush
and what he used could have actually
been Northern Lights cross Northern
Lights and that OG Kush could be
Northern Lights cross Northern Lights
which I have been saying since long
before his story ever popped up
I've been saying that I believed
OG Kush to be
some type of a cross of Northern Lights
so
I don't really know exactly
um
the real stories of whatever everything
is the reason why I believe Origins TK
after talking to him was that he doesn't
put any ego on it
he doesn't say oh well I took it and I
grew a thousand plants and they were all
pretty shitty but I found a crazy one
and I did this and I did that he's like
oh no dude I grew some [ __ ] and there
was like these couple seeds and then
there's [ __ ] [ __ ] and it just
happened and all the stories that I've
ever heard of the best stuff seem to
come out of stories like that that are a
little bit more random
a little bit less self-involved
um
usually if someone has an elaborate
story that makes them look like a
mastermind
you know it kind of makes you seem like
you're probably full of [ __ ]
and if you say that you just had a happy
accident that's seems to be kind of
where stuff comes from more often than
not and uh so that's why I
I give his story
um
some air time in my brain of going okay
well let's see what that means if this
means this and that means that and uh
all of the all of the details kind of
add up and that's the reason why I go on
such a big cluster [ __ ] convoluted story
of this and that and this so that you
can kind of picture how it looks in my
head with my experience because
um
it it does all it does all make sense to
an extent and
I'm like somebody needs to make a meme
of me with a stupid face with the
letters where it's Capital small case
Capital small case and it says
everything and it says Northern Lights
is in everything because I'm the dumbass
who at this point does think that it
isn't everything because I believe that
at some point cookies has Bubba in it I
believe that at some point OG has Hindu
and Northern Lights which it turns out
are probably the same thing
um I think that Sour Diesel has it I
think chemd has Northern Lights in it
somewhere
um and I have my Northern Lights oil can
which is oaxacan Afghani on our Northern
Lights clone not crossed to the Northern
Lights several times
and anybody who's had a lot of chem can
smell what I'm pulling out of those
seeds now
and
without it seeming like it is chem
because it has different it has
different aspects to the kind of the
resin and the way the resin looks under
a loop and all that I'd like to kind of
I should probably get into somebody to
Gene test it like
even though five of us is full of [ __ ]
they have they probably have the bigger
Gene uh the bigger bigger uh database
right now to look at genes
um
it's very there's a lot of what I call
Hot garbage that's like the chemd smell
um it's in there from that Northern
Lights and uh
you know I don't know it's it's a really
interesting thing but that but but but
with that whole story
um
in my delusion at one point
talking to Origins TK I had been like
well Emerald Triangle
[ __ ] I live in the Emerald Triangle
late 80s who had clones in the late 80s
I remember in 94.
I brought a clone to my buddy OG
foundation's farms and most of the old
timers from the neighborhood who had had
dank [ __ ] starting all the way back in
the 70s even the 60s going into the 80s
when what we wound up getting from from
those old timers
um
everybody came to see what what does a
plant look like from clone and this was
94 you know
and uh
it was a Northern Lights clone and we
had had it since 89. and my point to
that is that most people had never seen
a clone I'd only ever seen two clones
by the time I was 15. one
maybe by the time I was 14 one was the
purple one and Leggett the other one was
Northern Lights that my mom took and at
that point everybody else popped seed
every every time because what a lot of
people don't realize these days is in
those days you didn't have to have a bag
of weed that was all one thing
so you would have a bag of weed and you
would be like oh look there's a purple
bud there's a green bud there's a leafy
bud there's a hard bud and those pounds
that's how pounds looked all the way
until
2002 or 2003 it didn't [ __ ] matter
until Urkel hit and then all of a sudden
everything had to be all one clone
all in one bag the way people had been
used to indoor all the way until that
point you only saw pounds that were all
one thing if they were indoor an indoor
all the way until
95 96 maybe out right into there indoor
was always worth less than outdoor
because everybody got it and they're
like it's cool but you don't get high as
long the flavor's not as deep it doesn't
look quite right it's too bright it
looks all white it doesn't have that
real [ __ ] look and so indoor was like
a bad thing all the way until the late
90s most people don't know that and the
only time it was different was maybe if
you were in a place where there wasn't
outdoor
so weed was just weed and if it was
chronic it was chronic so you know
people in the mid 90s of course who were
buying like indoor diesel or whatever it
was yeah they're you know they're
they're buying that and it's and it's
super high dollar ten twelve thousand
dollar pounds on the east coast and [ __ ]
but in California if weed was worth 36
outdoor indoor was worth 32. it was
always worth less to have indoor weed
all the way to a point and as soon as
indoor really caught in caught on it was
only a matter of time before outdoor had
to follow the indoor Trend which was to
be growing all one thing and having all
one thing in a bag and then all of a
sudden that's how it was
but back in the days it wasn't really it
wasn't really like that it was all just
a mix in a bag you know
so um
I don't know where the [ __ ] I went with
this now I'm I'm I'm I'm a [ __ ]
Stoner trailing off but uh but this is
all true it's all true even if I don't
know what I'm talking about even when I
even when I lie you know
um
but no that's that's amazing I mean you
covered both you know the the OG the
Northern Lights the Hindu the indoor
outdoor just so many things in that
answer I think I've got to ask you a
bunch of follow-ups on that but I mean
the first one is do you think that that
change in like outdoor being worth more
to suddenly end or being worth more do
you think that was because of Like
Rappers and people talking about it and
maybe even a growing focus on the
Aesthetics of the plant which I'm
guessing maybe at the time indoor
started to out Edge it or do you think
it was other factors
well so I mean I I I spaced out on what
I was talking about there but
um I realized what I was talking about
was
um the reason why clone weed from clones
became popular
right so the reason weed from clones
became popular was because of because of
indoor and I think indoor became popular
because people were growing from clones
and so when you got indoor at a certain
point people were growing if they were
growing indoor they were growing a clone
because indoor was more sketchy to grow
from seed because if you grew from seed
indoor they're all you might have
different heights some of them might be
unstable whatever happened right but if
you grew from a clone that was proven
like that purple clone or that Northern
Lights clone then it was like okay now
you have a predictable crop it'll all
have an even canopy it'll all finish the
same day you know electricity is
expensive you need to know exactly what
you're doing like indoor was a different
game so clones
started to have this advantage and so I
think at a certain point that's why
clones became popular
and then once that happened what people
started to realize was when you buy
indoor
the whole bag is the same [ __ ] weed
so if you really like a pound of indoor
diesel you like it and that is something
you can get that's more like a branded
product whereas before it was like oh
you want a soda here's a [ __ ] soda
but once indoor came in it was like okay
you want a Coca-Cola get a Coca-Cola but
before that when you'd have your your
garden would be done and you'd be like
oh
oh there's that one all right go ahead
and pull out a little bit of that and
swap it out with this right here because
we want to stop that was the good one
you know and it wasn't like this stuff
wasn't so particular weed was worth so
much money that it wasn't like uh
in a lot of cases you couldn't you know
years later it was like I started
smoking 10 pounds a year or something
you know because it was like you could
just take whatever you want and go okay
we want this one this one do that
separate but originally it was so
valuable that you'd be like all right
well the odds and ends after all is said
and done we'll we'll put that aside and
if it weighs a quarter pound
then maybe we can dig through the pounds
and find the ones we want and we'll take
this stuff and we'll swap it back in and
wind up with a quarter pound we really
want instead of the one we're left with
but um but I think that part of what
popularized indoor was the fact that
When people grew indoor it was all one
thing and when you buy something and
it's more predictable
um I think that's kind of a value-added
product where you're like okay well
you know it was cool to get a sack of
weed great but then you're like I really
like that one and so
the fact that people weren't doing that
outdoor because outdoor people were
growing off from seed unless you were
like the people who were getting clones
from us back in the day who were growing
Northern Lights
um
you know it's I think I think that had a
big influence with being something that
you knew what you were getting exactly
and I think indoor it's one thing
outdoor it's mixed and I think that had
a big
um
I think that had a big a big role in
kind of dividing the markets and making
indoor be something that was more sought
after and then of course people figured
out how to grow indoor really well
um in Mass believe it or not a lot of I
mean right now still a lot of indoor
sucks don't get me wrong I'm a lot of
[ __ ] Outdoors a lot of outdoor sucks
I'm not saying you know like indoors
worse than outdoor but
in all the way through the 90s A lot of
times if you saw indoor it would be
people would be like all right we need
to get it out to get the next run and so
what does that mean let's cut a little
early
um
it's handled it's all green trimmed and
handled a lot so they can get it out the
door it's dried a lot faster because we
need to get rid of it and so
like at a certain point when people
started doing connoisseur level indoor
that really I think helped to drive up
the value of indoor and I think as funny
as it is that that happened
in places where there was less weed
faster because people
valued it more highly and would have
less and so would handle it better and I
think that's where like East Coast
indoor being so [ __ ] good in the 90s
was the deal where the people who are on
the East Coast who were the real
connoisseurs happen to be growing indoor
and the people on the west coast in the
90s who were the real connoisseurs were
growing outdoor and the people who were
growing weed on the in the indoors on
the west coast in the 90s were more
uh were more concerned about it as a
product and so we're kind of just
busting it out busting it out you know
and I think that that kind of uh
I think that that kept it that kept it
not being as good of a thing and then
when people started like okay let's
really do really nice indoor
um
then then it stepped it up a lot you
know and I think that's I think that's
that's part of the dynamic and that's
not to say that's the answer to all of
it but I those those are things that I
noticed and looking in you know uh
retrospectively like the the difference
and how the East Coast had this really
killer mid 90s indoor and I'm not saying
that the people I know didn't have it
then it was just that
in like 1993 you were almost better off
saying if you have really nice indoor
just being like yeah this is killer this
is killer outdoor and you'd get a better
price you know because people were used
to it being that
um indoor in the derogatory sense where
you go dude it's just like not you know
and I still see that kind of indoor
from people where I'm just like I don't
really know what you did but you know
and then the insane indoor that you see
that you're like this is the greatest
weed on earth a lot of people have that
but it would typically be like the lady
with one light or the lady with three
lights or the dude with eight lights or
whatever and those would be the ones
that you'd be like whoa holy [ __ ] like
man and that that was the stuff that
that you that you look at and you go
this should be worth more than outdoor
but because it wasn't the norm
it it didn't um
it didn't represent itself enough and so
there was like it's like you know kind
of like a boutique market like people
who know they want these three pounds
from this lady
that only has three pounds every two and
a half months you know people who know
but at the same time if people are just
looking for a bunch of indoor they're
like yeah my price is this for this and
it's this for that and you know outdoor
was more valuable all the way until at
least the mid 90s for sure
yeah I mean that totally makes sense the
way you describe it it's really
interesting to hear how things kind of
changed in the Emerald Triangle from
outdoor to indoor and I mean obviously
Outdoors still very possible and I love
the little anecdote about you know the
old lady with the three lights I mean
speaking of uh I'd love to if you're
willing to chat about
um some history from your mum if
possible because when I talk to the real
heads like Bodhi and Mr Bob Hemphill and
stuff they always tell me they're like
man you want to know a real OG of the
Emerald Triangle mean Gene's mom she was
laying some groundwork did she ever tell
you any cool stories about like you know
bud from yesteryear that she was able to
smoke or like sort of the way she and
her friends used to do things back in
the day
well so it's interesting you know my my
mom it my mom is not somebody who I
would say is
uh there's a there's a funny thing and
I've kind of addressed this a little bit
because of of people being full of [ __ ]
and not really understanding the reality
of of uh
of things you know people go oh
well you're you're [ __ ] second
generation so you just had it all handed
to you and blah blah blah it's like just
to break down the reality of it is
honestly my generation was the first
ones
and not even you know unfortunately not
even me but
my generation was the first people who
realized how to actually make money off
a weed
um my mom's generation was like they
would grow a little bit and it was
almost impossible to have anything and
if
you know it was all a learning process
so the deer would eat your crop the
rip-offs would take your crop
you know the neighbors would take your
crop [ __ ] your crop would be done and
someone would pull the [ __ ] Windows
off your [ __ ] house and take your
crop
um
you know my mom's not somebody who's
ever made any of her money like she she
didn't she's not like a a big
um
a big farmer who made money off of weed
and [ __ ] you know it was like she tried
to survive working you know other jobs
and and and trying to have a couple
plants so that maybe she could
um
so that she could be a little bit more
normal in the country because here
there's not
uh there's not a lot of opportunity you
know my mom trimmed other people's weed
my mom washed dishes uh she she opened
the first recycling center in this area
and you know barely made a tiny bit of
money off of that
uh
so
you know the the the the the the first
gener the first generation of people who
were the real who were the real people
who really
figured things out they they didn't get
to really reap the rewards of all this
[ __ ]
um
so
you know when when people say like oh
whatever you know your [ __ ] your parents
were Ballers and grew weed and [ __ ] you
know
they don't understand that there was no
uh
there was no
coolness there was no oh I grow weed I'm
Mr cool I'm gonna have a brand I'm gonna
look fancy I'm gonna be [ __ ] you know
people are gonna kiss my ass because I
got some [ __ ] weed and all this [ __ ]
that [ __ ] people come in carpet bag
and trying to [ __ ] do their little
[ __ ] with you know
um
his [ __ ] was rough it wasn't anything
it wasn't anything that you would do
because it's your dream and all this
[ __ ] [ __ ] with these Jokers you know
it was basically
um survival and it was risking your ass
knowing that
you might be [ __ ] up and you might be
you might be destroying your [ __ ]
chances of having a a good life by
taking these risks but at the same time
you're putting yourself out there
because you don't know what else to do
and there really isn't anything else to
do because you live in a place where
it's nice
and you know it's safe for your kids
because you're in the country and you
have a lot of different opportunities
for the things that we as a species do
really well with but we as a society
you know it wasn't really any of the
stuff that most people get the benefits
of who live in places where things are
nice it was the woods and uh
you know it's a Trippy [ __ ] thing so
I gotta throw that out there because of
how people like to perceive things and
these people I'm talking about are not
Bodhi and these guys because they
understand that they know they know what
the [ __ ] up you know but um
but the trippy thing is that uh
my mom the first thing I can remember
her talking about that was really really
stand out was the was what they called
the Missouri
which was weed from Mazar in Afghanistan
and uh she said it was big big tall
[ __ ] plants but then they budded with
these huge
fat [ __ ] Buds and it was just the
most gorgeous [ __ ] and they grew it in a
creek bed out in Woodman Canyon and it
had a
it had these big
um
these big beautiful buds on it that she
said were just they had never seen
anything like it and it was just so
[ __ ] incredible and they grew it for
a year or two this is like 84.85 or 85
and then in making the seeds at some
point the wrong one got picked
and my dad my my stepdad
um
who I don't like to really call my
stepdad but that's just for
technicalities but my my dad who I grew
up with my mom's boyfriend
um he said that at a certain point it
just turned into lettuce weed and it
really wasn't anything that all of us
all of a sudden it was like well you
can't grow this [ __ ] and they lost it
and they were super bummed and then he
started growing what he got from his
buddy Charlie which was oaxacan Afghani
which he later gave to
um our buddy Ted
who who passed away
um years ago now
and Ted ended up giving it to this other
guy who was out there in the canyon
and he was the one Ted and his worker
who's this other guy they would get
clones from my mom which was the
Northern Lights all the way starting in
like maybe 92 or 91 and they grew him
and then he would grow it and he would
back cross it
to his
um
to his oaxacan Afghani which he called
the oil can and the soil depending on
what it smelled like and he back crossed
and back crossed and bat crossed and
that's what my buddy ended up taking and
giving it to our other buddy who bred it
a couple times gave it back and that's
what we call
p-o-g
or
uh Northern Lights oil can and that's
what that that's what that actually
comes out of so that's like tracing it
back going back to whatever 87 or
something when George got that and uh
then you know like uh my mom wasn't like
a heavy smoker or anything but I mean
some of the special stuff I remember
seeing was like when she took me up
there to leg it to that lady's house
and uh
I saw that perp not purple and then um
you know the various things but really
after 89 the Northern Lights was like
our workhouse plant our Workhorse plant
and that was what was around all the way
really until uh the mid 90s
we moved to Hawaii
we came back and it was still around but
I had some other stuff we were we were
doing other stuff
and uh then
I thought it was gone all the way till
like 2004 2005 and then I talked to my
buddy down in Healdsburg and he was like
yeah no we still got we still got those
and I was like oh I want to get them
back and then he brought him to me and
it turned out he thought I wanted the
the dirt big bud
um
and
he didn't know that I wanted the
northern lights so I got the dirt big
but I seeded it and that's what the Pina
comes out of but he had the Northern
Lights still at that point and I talked
to him that was probably in
maybe July or something because I
remember I seated those plants they were
still small and they were done so I had
to be fairly late in the year and then I
ended up talking to him
when he gave me those and telling them
you know I'd like to get those other
ones he was like cool cool we'll figure
it out and that winner down in Sonoma
County in Healdsburg the Russian River
flooded and his buddy had a trailer
where they kept their moms and it was
just a mom operation where they would
get all their clones out of
and the whole [ __ ] trailer washed
away in the [ __ ] flood down the
Russian River and they lost it all and
that was so that was like the the one
real the one plant that my mom really
kept
um was gone at that point and she had
already not had it for like 10 years but
they had it and that was just like this
huge tragedy and to this day it's like
every time someone says they have a
Northern Lights clone I'm always like oh
well what's it look like because
that's what I was getting into when I
trailed off and I forgot what I was
talking about earlier was that the
Northern Lights was really one of the
only things you would see around that
was a clone and I saw the exact same
clone we'd come back from Chico I saw it
come back from up further north
um it circulated a lot because back then
it was like oh if somebody wants clones
they would get something that was
already grown from clone they knew was
good indoor and then once people got
those they would mother them up and they
would they would sell clothes and so it
kept it really limited because clone you
know clone cloning
um it wasn't really a popular thing to
do and uh I know I know different people
did kept a couple clones all over
because there's clones from the 90s
but
cloning became much more popular in the
2000s than it when the late the late 90s
than it was in the 80s and the early 90s
so I like think probably someone still
must [ __ ] have it out somewhere
because it's such a good plant but I've
never been able to find it but that was
like really my uh my mom's thing that
she found that was really really good
and other than that you know
um
really the only ones I can really
remember her talking about was that
original Missouri and and then knowing
that that Northern Lights and she got
that Northern Lights and a manila
envelope that just said Northern Lights
seed bank on it and she got those in in
89 when we lived where the uh area 101
where the emerald cup started now is and
then we moved and we had this little
shed and she used to just have like you
know a little a little thing with like
two 400 watt lights or something like
that and uh it just basically kept us
from [ __ ] starving you know so uh
that that whole era was a lot different
and some people had had the magic pieces
of property where you wouldn't get
busted and you could grow a lot of weed
and some people made a lot of money but
um it was hard and it was a completely
different thing than people think of it
as and some people thought a good tricks
and some people you know were able to do
[ __ ] my mom was a single mom she had two
kids and uh you know her whole uh her
whole thing was just you know putting
putting everything on the line to be
able to do that [ __ ] she got busted in
1982 with a couple small plants on the
back porch
because her roommate started a big
argument with the [ __ ] landlord and
the landlord called the cops because he
knew there was weed and uh you know she
got locked up in 1982 and probably
my earliest memory is driving behind
with this lady Joey
in the car looking at my mom waving at
me from the back of a cop car on a
[ __ ] dirt road you know
so uh
not you know not the uh
not the Glorious [ __ ] hand-me-down
um
you know type of lifestyle that people
want to make it out to be when they just
show up here to try to [ __ ] make a
quick buck and during the [ __ ] 2 15
year and then talk down on on on me for
being uh you know the dude who just
[ __ ] grew up with everything because
I was from Mendo you know
yeah wow what a powerful story about
what mums will go through to follow
passion and put food on the table and
you know major props to your mum for
that and it's I guess yeah continuing on
what you said that's a bit of a bummer
that people assume that just because
you're second generation that everything
was given to you it's based on that
story you could almost argue it's the
opposite like things are probably a bit
harder in fact yeah well it's it's
pretty what it is is it's projection
because they showed up and everything
was easy as [ __ ] and so they look at me
and they go oh well you know you things
must have been so easy for you because
you showed up even sooner and I'm like
yeah you showed up after the drug war
had pretty much [ __ ] disappeared for
most people and I showed up and turned
[ __ ] you know two years old my mom
got arrested and four years old [ __ ]
you know Camp campaign against marijuana
planting started
and uh
you know it's a [ __ ] real different
thing you know I got buddies who you
know used to
used to go to school you know or used to
go to their house and I was like oh you
know where's your dad like oh my dad
he's he's uh you know he's hiding in
Mexico or where's your dad oh he's gonna
be in jail for [ __ ] couple years or
you know [ __ ] whatever it is you know
like oh your pop had to had to [ __ ]
log his property and he's still gonna do
six years or whatever it is you know and
then dudes show up and [ __ ] make a
bunch of easy money and then wanna want
to talk [ __ ] to to us like we're the you
know we had everything handed to us on a
platter and I'm like you guys didn't
even you guys didn't even [ __ ] earn
earn [ __ ] they didn't make their bones
doing [ __ ] they just showed up carpet
bagging and then talk a bunch of [ __ ]
you know so
yeah yeah totally that's a bummity here
and hopefully this can help shed some
light on that sort of fallacy something
I definitely took away from that story
that I thought was interesting was how
you know this amazing Northern Lights
that your mum came across came from some
seed stock from like a seed bank I think
a lot of people including myself in the
past have made the mistake of assuming
that all of this sort of mythical
strains and seeds that existed around
that area in that time were like all
from like brothers of eternal love and
all that sort of Mythology do you think
that Trope kind of gets played out a
little too much and some of it is a bit
less exciting in its Origins and it's
just like good stock from a seed bank or
do you think that the brothers of
eternal love did in fact contribute a
lot to the genetics in the scene at that
time
I mean I assume they did I don't really
um I don't really know too much but I
can tell you there's an interesting
thing where we
I mean imagine back in the day we first
got interested in weed it was the mid
90s me and my buddies are like 14 or 15
right like as a parent I look at I look
at you know kids I look at my
nine-year-old and I go yeah you tell
them things but you don't tell them
everything right it's just a natural
thing to be like yeah these stories
aren't for you to walk around holding
they it might be kind of heavy
especially in our day when things were
still really considered criminal and you
know you don't you don't want to tell
your kids like all this heavy duty [ __ ]
that you know they can't tell anybody
you're like that that's just a
disservice in a sense you know
so
talking to my buddy
um OG Foundation Farms a while back
he's he's telling me you know I'm
talking to him about like some different
strains and he's like yeah you know I
was talking to uh I was talking to so
and so
and uh you know he was he was not well
and I wanted to know some stories and he
was of that older generation and so I
started kind of you know talking to him
and digging a little bit to try to you
know just kind of learn more and knowing
that now it's two grown grown men
talking and [ __ ]
so he started opening up and saying more
more of the stories
and he ended up saying that like things
like what I call what I call uh dirt
which is
um which is an old Afghani
he's like yeah you know well that came
from that came from so and so uh
the computer guy and we're like oh yeah
yeah yeah you know like back in the day
they had told us oh he was the guy who
brought the stuff back and we knew that
and and that had been told to us in the
mid 90s he goes yeah but you know what
you guys didn't know because it's kind
of crazy was that he also was one of the
guys who was letting them out in the
back of the valley make a lot of acid
back there
my buddy was like oh really and he goes
yeah you know the the guys who did who
did the sunshine acid they they used to
make a lot of that Sunshine acid was
done out there in the back of the valley
like oh well that's interesting
you know he's telling him and he goes uh
he goes yeah you know they they right
then around that time 84 or 83 or
whatever you know whatever it was
those seeds showed up and they told kind
of the ladies around here who were
growing their like little yard patches
and stuff like hey grow this and and
we'll give you twice what you're getting
now for your other [ __ ] and you'll have
a lot more weed and it finishes really
quick
and that was kind of the introduction of
like The Afghani like what we call dirt
you know
and uh
so interestingly enough as much as I
don't want to be the guy who jumps on me
like oh well the stuff I have it it came
from mold too like it's like it just
turned out that really they did have a
hand they kind of had their hand in a
lot of Pies because it turned out that
the computer guy had actually got his
seed from Bull and
um
and that they had been they had been
batching up sunshine back his place in
the in the mid 80s uh or the early 80s
or whenever I don't know that the that
the the acid and the I don't know the
time frame but that in the same area
um was these things going on you know
which was really interesting and then he
said yeah then we took we took these big
things of seed and we put them inside
the tire of our car and we and we we
filled up the tires and we we actually
drove me and your dad me and my buddy's
Dad we drove to Mexico and we took these
seeds down there and that was the year
that Mexican weed the price doubled on
Mexican weed too because all of a sudden
it was this chunky beautiful weed
instead of reinstreaming and uh that was
really interesting to me just to hear
you know these kind of trippy stories
and if you talk to people in Humboldt
they have the same kind of stories where
you know whatever 78 they these guys got
it and then 82 these guys got it and you
know as a younger person I would have
thought oh that's a big span of time but
now I know like the course of six or
eight years or whatever it's [ __ ]
nothing you know it's really a trip so
uh
I can't downplay what they did because
it turns out that even stuff that I I
use came came from them you know and uh
I don't really think that that adds any
value I think the plants have their own
value
of whatever their value is you know
um
but uh
I do think that um
you know I think there's certain
it was a very very very small world and
to this day it's still a very small
world as soon as you get before the
internet I was talking to somebody today
and he goes man I have the Sauer cut in
2003 I got it out branscom I never got
another one like it
um and I was like oh it's probably the
same one we had because I think I got
mine like 2004 or something and it's a
small area and there's not a lot of
people and stuff and he goes oh do you
know so-and-so and I'm like yeah I grew
up with his little brother you know and
and he has some killer you know sfv
diesel seeds now and
he's like oh yeah that's what he was
talking about last time I saw him and
his brother must have continued it or
whatever and I'm like yeah you know like
it's somebody drops a name and you're
like yeah they I used to
I I pulled my groin muscles sledding
down his Hill when I hit a [ __ ] stump
under the snow you know like in 1988
1989 you know like that's my boy you
know
so it's it's it's trippy like the uh
things really are a small world so
somebody like Brotherhood of eternal
love who brought in a lot of stuff
you know how many people were
circulating it back then it was it was
like almost like
um it was almost like you you might be
ruining your life anytime you hand
somebody some seeds or or a bag of weed
back then that might be it for you you
might be doing 12 years you might be
doing seven years you know like you
didn't [ __ ] know back then it was it
was sketchy as [ __ ] so the people who
were like that they were
um they were pushing the boundaries they
weren't normal [ __ ] guys now you can
be a normal guy and have all kinds of
different stuff and you know whatever it
is what it is and sure there's a risk
factor there but you figure you could
probably work it out back then it was
like no if you were in the 80s or the
90s it was like you
you know that'd be like right now if
you're gonna oh I'm just gonna smuggle
to Japan that's like how it was just to
[ __ ] tell people in California you
had weed you know
yeah wow different time different time
indeed and all of that really
interesting stuff something that I kind
of wonder about a bit is often you hear
about people reminiscing about strains
that used to exist and maybe they don't
exist anymore maybe they exist just in
sort of like an S1 of the original sort
of thing and this all comes to the
foreground because you mentioned sour
there for the longest time I've had the
suspicion that the fabled sour you hear
people talk so fondly about particularly
the East Coast guys who you know really
just got swept up in the sour sort of
fandom do you feel like the sour that
they talk about is that one still around
or do you think they're just working
with their swans or it's just a case
that you know back in the day it was the
best there was and now there's better
but they still think like looking back
that what they had was better like
because you hear this sort of idea
Expressway with a lot of strains do you
think people lose the originals or it's
just like rose shaded glasses looking
back
no I think people have the originals but
so many people don't and think they're
The Originals that it's hard to make
sense of what's what
like I think that pip from souvenir
seeds because I've seen crosses that he
made with his sour
um
I think he has the real Sour
um there's a certain thing about it you
smell it it's skunky it's gassy it's got
a thing to it that's like that that's it
you know like you just know that's it
it's
um it's so much like the super skunk
that
you just kind of know like uh
that's [ __ ] sour and then you see a
lot of people sour and you go yeah you
know that just doesn't have it and then
there's even ones that are not like I
haven't seen his salary I've just seen
what came from it but I can still tell
it came from the real [ __ ] sour
because it's just too it's so much more
sour than everything people think is
really sour and it's a cross you know
you're like all right well this guy has
you know even if it wasn't even if it
wasn't the exact plant
the
phenotype of it it's like that's it you
know what I mean like it's it's got to
be it it's like if uh
I don't know it just
it's just it it's just the weed you know
it's it's it's skunky ass weed and it
um and that's really what it should be
like like the real real sour stuff that
I originally had it was skunky and
metallic and earthy and it smelled like
coffee and it smelled like super skunk
and it has like this cushiness to it
that's not OG but the same thing you
like about OG it has some of that and it
drops resin and
um it gets you high immediately and you
feel it in your head
and it tastes a certain way and
um
they're just certain there's certain
things that sour is you know and then
there's certain things that not sour
where you're just like you that's just
not sour you know and um I think it's a
type of weed
and
in my opinion if you can find the exact
same type of weed I really don't give a
[ __ ] if it's the same plant or not if
it's the same type of weed what do we
care you know what I mean like not to
say that um not to downplay provenance
and all that like I I care about it
myself
but like the reality of all of it is is
like what's in your bag the reason why I
want these particular plants is because
they really are that kind of weed and if
you get a plant and someone says it's
sour and you grow it and you don't wind
up with that weed that you expected and
you know what that really is it's
different then it's different but even
if the Clone was different than what
it was supposed to be and it's actually
a one-off or an S1 or a cross or
whatever for the sake of having the weed
it's the same [ __ ] weed you got it
right there the only thing that's
different that's the same that's that's
you know phenotype and that's
you know bulk phenotype or gross
phenotype where it's like they that that
all that it's all the one thing even if
it's a different plant
and then
you know genotype Wise It's like well if
it breeds different then it's different
um so it's a different genotype but it's
the same phenotype
um
that's like a weird that's where you
start to get into that funny genotype
phenotype confusion where people don't
know what's what
it's like well you can have the same
phenotype and go it's sour this is sour
that's sour now if you S1 both of those
plants that are both exactly like sour
and one throws a bunch of [ __ ] that's
not sour and the other throws all sour
that's where you have your different
genotype you know that's where it
actually counts in the conversation as
far as people like cloning something and
being like Oh don't call it a phenotype
call it a genotype it's like well every
plant is a genotype and a phenotype but
what are we talking about here because
you might not be even talking about
something where you need to even use
those words just call it a [ __ ] plant
or a type or a throw or you know what I
mean but that's that's where it really
comes down to it for me is like
if I want to smoke it I only need the
phenotype but if I'm going to breed it
and say it's the original and I'm and
and and that's what's going to get
preserved and that's what's going to get
spread and you know the provenance and
all that that's when you need that
genotype it needs to be what's inside of
it that it actually possesses for its
progeny that's when genotype counts you
know and uh
so you know like I said it is it is it
really do people really have it I don't
know but if people have it and it really
breeds that way where things come out of
it that are the real deal like that's
all you really need
um
but you know I mean the coolest thing is
if you know like somebody's like yeah I
popped the seed and this is the real one
it's always been in my hands and you
know but um other than that there's
really no way to verify a cut without
having it without being able to go I
gave it to someone so they never got
another thing similar to it they gave it
to so and so that person never got
to this guy he never had something
similar to it then you can get it back
and know it's that but if you gave a
sour if you popped the sour from seed
and you gave it to this guy and he's
like yeah I had it and then I bred it
and I kept this one and it was like sour
but it was even bigger so I kept that
one but I kept the original but then at
one point I think I mixed them up like
you've already lost it you've lost your
provenance and you don't really know you
don't really know [ __ ] because you could
have a plant that the phenotype's
exactly the same
but it ain't actually the same genotype
because a different [ __ ] plant you
know so
um
yeah I don't know it's all it's all it's
all interesting interesting thing the
whole sour thing because there's so many
sour cuts and then was the one I got in
the early 2000s was it ever the real one
I don't know but it's what I consider
the real one and when I see people with
something that's like that or that has
tons of that super skunk smell that I
knew from the super skunk that my buddy
got from his buddies back
because he had it before and then he got
it back from his buddies in Arcada
in the late 90s that's the super skunk I
know to be skunky and I don't even know
is that the super skunk that that
everyone else is talking about when they
talk about the the mass or the the six
or I don't [ __ ] know I just know
that's the one that I know and when I
smell really good diesel if it smells
like that then I think of it as being
real diesel you know and that's what the
LA Kush Headband that's what the real
Sour they have that smell from that
super skunk and the difference between
them and super skunk is super skunk
tasted great smelled great it wasn't
really that gnarly a weed but it was
really tasty and enjoyable the real good
headband and sour were like
the sour would get you really high and
it was clear the headband would just
[ __ ] you up like you could get really
high off of that weed
um if you didn't have a real strong
tolerance to those kinds of weed and um
you know those are those are the cool
ones to me
oh yeah
that's interesting you you bring all
that up because I mean a lot of it
obviously really valid points and on the
topic of like strains that people may or
may not have and you reference the skunk
in there I noticed on a recent CSI
Humboldt Post of all things seeing as
we've already referenced old inspector
um that there was a post about roadkill
skunk and I noticed a comment you left
there saying that the skunkiest thing
you had smelt in a while was a strain
Called Death coast and I actually hadn't
come across that one at all can you tell
me a little bit about that one so that's
one that comes from those seeds that um
that uh souvenir seeds made and
um you know I grew it I have my what I
call grape lime skunk which I'm not
gonna say is roadkill skunk but that's
the one that like
um
you know like I don't not to like just
put it out there just like as a as a
name drop but like skunk VA had the
skunk back in the day for a long time
grew it knew what it was and he said
that the grape lime skunk had that smell
in it with other smells of course which
is what I think too
but that it was the closest he'd smell
since he had smelled that stuff in the
90s
and
um so I had that
I had a cut that is supposed to be Death
Star whether it is or not I don't know
but it's very very skunky
um I had Sour Diesel cut I had some Sour
Diesel back cross twos that I got from
skunk Tech that were popped from Karma
seeds I had
um some other stuff you know some pretty
funky stuff and breaking down taking the
seeds out of the death Coast was like
burnt garlic
burnt rubber
coffee onion skunk
just funky super skunk
as much as I can remember it just
smelled like super skunk to me like what
I call what like what I called pissy
pungent back in the day
um but a little different but like
really really what I know to be what I
ever smelled that was what I ever
thought was the skunkiest weed you know
um and so that I believe was a death
star crossed Sour Diesel
or it might have been a Scentsy Star
Cross Sour Diesel the remake of the
Death Star Cross but it's one of those
and um
it was nasty and then I got some weed
from from the same guy and it was what
he calls Rubber City and the Rubber City
I believe is the Death Star across with
the sour I think the death Coast is the
sourcross Scentsy star so the Rubber
City I think is three-quarter sour and
the and the death Coast is half but I'm
not sure about that but that's that's
how I remember it I don't know
it might be the opposite but um it's
it's uh
it's just it's it's skunky like it's
just the skunkiest [ __ ] like if you want
skunky stuff and I I haven't
um
I don't know I haven't seen other stuff
that I that I would say really
smells like skunk and I haven't grown
everybody's so-called skunk but when I
ask people when they're growing it out
kind of everybody's like oh so-and-so
said it's skunky it's not skunky and I'm
like okay well there there you go they
said it's not skunky like you seem
you know CSI on that he's like I don't
know if there's a way to make him stunky
but they ain't skunky so I don't you
know I don't really know
um
you know I don't know what to make of
all that but uh but that that stuff is
that's bomb like I would recommend if
people want something skunky get those
and then I think people have this weird
thing of
of wanting like something to appear
that's going to be
like literally smell like a dead skunk
and I just someone I don't know I've
seen thousands and thousands of plants
and for back in the day when skunk was
really common and we didn't even really
think much of it and I didn't ever
really smell anything that was more like
a dead skunk than like super skunk or
death Coast or you know like this grape
lime skunk thing that I have which I
would say is is way not as skunky as
death Coast but which is it has another
little Dimension to it which is kind of
this wet dog
um
coffee thing that I get from when I
smell a real
skunk spray like I I had a house where
there was a there was a place where like
some some wiring got off of one of the
holes and I had a skunk go under my
house and spray my house twice it's like
I'm very familiar with a [ __ ] skunk
you know what I mean I've I've been in a
car
that went over a skunk that was an old
car that was pretty rickety and it
sprayed us directly under the car and
like your eyes burn and there's certain
smells and like those particular smells
there's these certain aspects
um and mine I wouldn't say is the
intense like dead skunk like that but it
it has some it has those things that I
think make up
um
that smell but I'm still I'm still not
like this is the [ __ ] roadkill skunk
I don't even know what that is I never
saw anything called roadkill skunk in
the 90s I saw a lot of [ __ ] weed but
I didn't see everything
um but I you know I I question a little
bit this whole
uh I questioned the whole
you know hunt for it a little bit and
think that um
weed smells a lot skunkier to you when
you don't have very much weed you know
yeah definitely definitely I mean
there's a lot of a lot of different
angles we could work that one from but
I'm glad you brought it up that the uh
the grape lime skunk of yours I remember
still to this day you know being at
Emerald cup and you gave me that bud to
smell and I took it over to skunk VA and
we both immediately agreed that was the
most insane skunk Turks we'd ever smelt
in a long time do you have any plans to
try to lock that one down in seed form
at all I mean whether it be just you
know to do the f1s which was what I kind
of smelt or to Line work it to back
cross it anything sort of like that up
your sleeve also I had that one and it
was funny because I only had one plan of
it and it was this gorgeous plant so I
ran through a bunch more
and uh I found some nice ones so I let
out a little bit of f2s of those from a
nice grape skunky one
um with a lot of the great Funk to it
and then from those same males that I
pulled out of those
um I put those back on the lime one and
I put out a little bit of that as lime
one bat cross because it was lime one
cross grape soda skunk was what the
grape lime skunk
um clone was that you smelled
so I took its brother and put that back
on two twin brothers actually
and put that back on the line one
um for line one back cross so that
wasn't so much shooting for the skunk
side as it was shooting for more of the
lime
um
and then I did
uh I made f3s
with everything that I got that was real
stable out of those so I think there's
maybe eight of those
uh three different males done separately
in that breeding one of them that was
just very loud skunk plant the whole
plant just smelled really really skunky
um two more that smelled a little bit
more like the original grape lime skunk
clone that you saw
so I took that original grape lamb skunk
clone that you saw I crossed it
with
three different males separately so
there's three different lines back
crossed
I made f3s with three different males
separately so there's
um I guess maybe there's 10 lines of it
in F3 now
eight of which are with my favorite male
two of which are with the
the females that matched the other two
males I kept most closely
um
and that's just an attempt to do that
and I gave those actually to skunk VA
because he said he'd pop them and I know
he knows skunk chirps
um so
you know we'll see if he finds anything
and uh you know if he doesn't cool and
if he does right on
and
um I had the f2s
I had a lot of them everything that
didn't smell where the whole plant
didn't smell like a skunk
I gave them to one of my buddies and he
put them in like 200 gallon pots
and I think I gave him
30 of them
maybe 25
and I went out and checked on them when
they were really chunky
and some of them had butt some colas
that were like damn near like loafs of
bread you know they were huge [ __ ]
colas where you're like that's got to be
rotten but they weren't because it just
has really the grape and the line both
have great mold resistance because
they're based on Old gorilla strains you
know
and um
out of those
25 that I thought wouldn't be skunky
there were
probably
five or seven
that were like really skunky like whoo
[ __ ] that's skunky bud you know and um
then out of the ones that I kept
that were the ones that I really liked
the most which I think was 10 of them
out of mind was the same deal probably
the same only the same ratio which means
that
the whole plant smelling like a skunk
doesn't necessarily determine whether or
not the flower is going to smell like a
skunk that's kind of [ __ ] just keep
track of because some strains the stem
rub means a lot and some it means less
so
um that means that just because the
males I kept are skunky doesn't mean
they'll necessarily throw skunk but
I back cross now
to the one you smelled and then I'll
plant that and out of those I'll find
something that's the closest to it and
I'll back cross to it again
and what I'd like to see is that the bat
cross has more of that plant in it than
the f2s
and if it doesn't then
I'll try another bat cross but if it
doesn't increase at that point then it's
kind of an indication that that plant
doesn't like to breed true
it could also mean that I'm just not
picking the right males
um but it's pretty you know like you
want to see when you back cross to
something that the frequency of that
type goes out fast and if it doesn't
then it makes you
know that you're probably better off
going f2f3 F4 rather than going back on
a back cross
um so you know that's my experimentation
with it at this point people are growing
out the back cross people are growing
out the f3s
um
and you know we'll see what works out of
it and the cool thing is I have the
Clone you know so I have a plant that
smells like that weed I just uh you know
I'd like to see it in seed form I'm not
going to take that not going to take
that and say oh yeah you only have to
grow six six [ __ ] uh
packs to get one that smells like this
and then put skunk on the label that's
like doesn't make any sense I'll call I
can call it grape lime skunk you need a
grape lime and skunk but
um
you know if it can get to the point
where it's skunky skunky that would be
that would be cool and then I took that
too and I crossed it with a death star
because the Death Star was really skunky
almost as skunky as the death coast and
uh
out of that there might be more skunk
but for me I feel like that's cheating a
little bit because it's using super
skunk from the diesel
and I what I want to do is bring skunk
out of the old
um Afghani stuff that's in the grape and
the lime
um just it's more of a kind of like a
challenge uh but in the meantime I don't
mind doing doing a cheat and just seeing
if that will make it work too you know
because they both if they both have it
coming from both sides you might get a
lot more of it should get a quarter
taken to two things that have it in
there
um but that's not necessarily true
because it might not be frequent but all
in the gene prayer but we'll find out so
that's the that's the uh
um that's where I went with that this
time
sure and I mean a question which kind of
stems off what you were just talking
about but I'll make it a little more
hypothetical so that hopefully it makes
it easier to answer let's just say
someone out there who's listening has
managed to find themselves uh they've
made a cross and they've final hunted
the seeds and they find one plant in
those seeds which is totally unlike the
mother or the father you know like let's
say mum's mango dad's OG it's blueberry
you know like it's just really left of
field to both parents and you you're
really not sure what traits are coming
from what parent because it's just that
really unique sort of phenotype would
would you try to Line work that or back
cross it like how would you go about
trying to lock in that super super
unique phenotype would it be trial and
error or do you think for those super
like one in a thousand phinos it's
probably actually not very easy to get
that into then a seed form
well some people won't like to hear that
the way that you really want to do
things like that is you want to take
that blueberry plant
and self it
find the same exact plant again even if
it was out of one out of a thousand when
you self it it should be a little more
frequent than one out of a thousand
then you want to grow those out find the
plant that's the same again
and
if you have to self that one again every
time you self you're going to lock it
down more and more
and then
you know you can take that blueberry
plant and take a male out of the same
cross and go and and and and agreed to
that and you know make your make your F3
and then take your F3 mail that you
think is the closest to the blueberry
plant
put it back on the blueberry and then
hope you get some blueberries out of
that
and then
out of those seeds find the one that's
the closest once again and go back and
then if you see that you're starting to
get more blueberries every time you can
just continue black you can continue
back Crossing to the blueberry
you know until you want until it winds
up being you know really frequent and
you just get a lot of blueberry in there
then at that point would be where it
would be better to breed It Forward
because you you you're basically
targeting in you know you're getting it
to the point where there's more and more
and more of this one thing that you want
um
and then
you know if that if that didn't work at
all then like I said you know selfing it
is really
the best way because if you get one out
of a thousand is blueberry then you self
it and you get one out of whatever that
next time but you find that one this out
of the s1s and you self that one and you
find that same one out of the S2 by the
time you make the S3 or the S4 you're
going to have something where that's
what it has they're just mostly all
blueberry right
so then at that point you might be
better off
Crossing
to the S3 or the S2 or the S1 you might
be better back Crossing to that lots of
times because it might be a lot more
um true breeding you know
and uh you know there's just a question
of finding those those right things and
I mean as far as like modern breeders
would look for they'd look for whatever
those genes are
and just go okay we're just gonna test
this plant and see if it's the right one
test a thousand males and find the one
that actually has those same genes and
that's how you would do it if you were
like a real
um you know a real
breeder in the in the most advanced
sense of of the of the of the you know
discipline or the job
um
but you know in reality if you were
somebody like if you were big
Agriculture and you want this crop to
get ready and you want to be able to go
okay we're going to get this into seed
form as quick as possible you would self
self self
so you would you would you would make
the S1 then you would find the exact
same plant may be improved ideally
definitely you don't want to settle for
one that's not you don't want to settle
for one that's worse and then you want
to take that S1 and you want to sell fit
and then you want to find one of the S2s
that maybe is a little bit improved or
maybe a lot improved if you can and then
you want to make the S3 and then you
know by the time
you get something to be in like you know
five generations seven generations of
selfing that's what they're really
talking about when they tell you about
our true inbred line there's different
ways to to to Define an inbred line or
an IBL but like in the most true true
sense it would be like selfing for
several generations and then you could
get to the point where you basically had
clone in seed form where the plant would
be exactly the same now if you just bat
cross seven times and the plant you were
back Crossing to doesn't ever want to be
super it doesn't want to be the only
thing in the mix anyway because it
already has a it's coming from a diverse
gene pool then you sometimes will make
it work but it's more likely that you
won't and you'll want what you'll wind
up with is
the same
gene pool that came from just coming
back again and again as if it's an S1
s1s aren't really consistent back
crosses aren't necessarily consistent
s1s are very consistent if they came out
if that you take an S1 out of something
that's already super consistent yeah
then you get what people think an S1 is
but that's not the case when you when
you S1 something from a really
inconsistent gene pool or where you back
cross to one plant from a really
inconsistent gene pool unless you get
lucky and all the traits that you wanted
from that plant happen to be dominant
and then it doesn't matter if it was
inconsistent because dominant traits are
just going to want to pop out frequently
you know more than other stuff but you
have to kind of you have to kind of play
with them to know exactly what the
individual is you're working with to
know if it's just gonna throw everything
you want like you might back cross back
cross back cross and then turns out well
now you've just made a super consistent
strain but it has one thing locked in
you can't get rid of like it's sexually
unstable or it's prone to a disease you
hadn't even maybe you didn't even have
that disease and now you get it you go
[ __ ] the whole population gets it
whereas that the s1s from that plant
might not even have that because you
still have some variety so like
you know I don't know there's there's a
lot of different
a lot of different ways to go with it
and that's what's so trippy about
anytime you want to work with something
is you don't you don't necessarily know
what's the best way to do it
um
without trying so that's why it's really
good if you're going to work with things
to work with things you really like
because if you're going to wind up
having a lot of failures you want to
have failures on your way to something
that means something instead of having a
bunch of failures on your way to
something where even if it works perfect
you don't even you know not even going
to Value it that much you know if you
want to work with your favorite stuff so
if you [ __ ] up or you waste time or you
do the wrong thing and now you have to
start over you're still excited you know
because if you're just following
whatever you're trying to chase you're
trying to make rks because rks is hot
right now you know you know let rks pop
up for 10 years and see if it stays
popular after a while people will go
that's good but it's you know it's
actually not really I mean and then in
back in the day
a lot of stuff was skunky and we didn't
even we weren't even that excited about
it unless it was like what I said like
the pissy pungent or the the super skunk
where it actually smokes good and
translates just smelling like a skunk
not necessarily anything it doesn't it
the weed also has to be enjoyable and
have a good high and taste good and Burn
Right and hopefully grow good and yield
well and you know like I like what is
rks rosin tastes like you might [ __ ]
taste like nothing nobody even knows
there's a whole new generation of uh of
of uses for stuff so
um
you know make sure you like something
before you go [ __ ] chasing it because
everyone's talking about it
[Music]
and there you have it gang what a great
first half of an epic interview with the
man himself meme Gene thank you so much
for coming on the show Gene we
appreciate it as always likewise we
appreciate our sponsors seeds here now
number one seabank in the game they got
some Freeborn selections go check them
out if you want all the hottest genetics
in the game they just got a fresh drop
from CSI Humboldt that's my pick
likewise copper biological systems
they got that beneficial Army to keep
your garden happy healthy and the next
crop on track to be the best today
go check out the website I guarantee you
it pays to keep the garden happy and
healthy profit biological systems
they're the one you know it
[Music]
and last but not least a huge shout out
to the patreon gang you guys are the
lifeblood of the show you know it I hope
you enjoy getting early access to this
episode hearing it before the rest and
if you want to become a part of the
patreon family please go check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast you'll get early access to
episodes unheard unreleased content
giveaways and so much more
thank you so much patreon gang I
appreciate you and the sponsors so very
much
[Music]
stay tuned for part two of our epic
interview with the meme Master himself
reader extraordinaire me and Jane of
mendocinos I'll see you there
[Music]
foreign