hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
buding enthusiasts as always you're
joined here by your boy heavy days here
from the upside down library and as
usual we want to give a massive shout
out to our incredible sponsors who
helped make the show happen seeds here
now your number one seed bank in the
industry a guarantee on satisfaction not
just germination with all the hottest
breeders and the latest drops why would
you go anywhere else
if you finish a grow and you're not
satisfied with the end product hit them
up they'll make it right they only stock
the highest quality breeders and I know
they got some fire packs from your boy
heavy days there check them out before
they're gone guys massive shout out to
C1 now your number one stop for all your
genetic needs but in order to get your
garden pumping on all cylinders and
producing the best crop to date you got
to make sure your rooms dialed in to do
that check out our friends at Pulse
sensors Number One sensors and
integrated hubs in the game game
measuring all of the variables PPD VPD
temperature humidity Duo all the extra
variables you don't consciously track to
help ensure your next crop is the best
to date whether you're running a single
tent a single room or a multi-state
operation pulse sensors are the number
one in the game and they've just
recently released the pulse Hub a
central unit to integrate all of their
monitors to make sure that your rooms
are the best they can possibly be
massive thank you to pulse sensors we
appreciate you so much
likewise you got to keep your garden
Pest and pathogen free and to do that
you got to check out our friends at
copit these guys are the world leaders
in Sustainable biocontrol Solutions for
pests and disease if you're battling
spidermites check out their new spidex
vital plus sachets these are new pilis
breeding sachets that release predator
mites into your crop consistently over a
period of several weeks providing you
with sustained spidermite control now
you don't have to spread carrier
material through your garden just to
introduce predator mites just hang the
sachet on your crop let the personis
walk out and do the work for you trust
me guys you don't want to have to go up
against a spidermite infestation without
spyx vital plus these are truly the best
predators in the game I promise once you
use it you'll see the quality you'll
never go back massive shout out to copit
likewise you got to check out our
friends at Organics alive if you're
growing
organic and want to use high quality
powdered organic fertilizers you simply
cannot go past Organics alive these guys
truly walk the walk and talk the talk
they have been picking up cups left
right and center with Growers all around
the country sweeping categories using
their products that is the ultimate
Testament in my opinion if homeg Growers
are winning competitions using their
products the proof is in the pudding
guys no matter what stage of the plant
cycle you're at veg transition flour in
need of micronutrients or a very
specific sort of boost in late flour
they've got it you got to check out
Organics alive guys truly one of the
best in the industry we're super stoked
to be working with them because we know
how amazing their products are using
heaps of breeder Gardens that we have on
the show again check them out Organics
alive massive thank you massive shout
out for supporting the
show finally a massive shout out to the
entire crew at dap these guys make some
of the best vaporizers on the game I'm
really passionate about this one because
they helped me to get off combustion and
smoking bongs if you have any concerns
about your respiratory health or Heck if
you just want to try a different mode of
ingestion maybe try to get a better
flavor hit you've got to check out the D
ofap these guys units are cheap they're
incredibly welld designed and most
importantly they're very customizable
you can take your Vape game to the next
level getting insane turps all while
retaining the potency you'd expect of a
combustion or a bong truly I was smoking
bongs for over 10 years I'm now Vape
only massive shout out to DAP they're
one of the best in the industry and we
owe them a massive thank you shout out
again dap massive thanks for supporting
the
show finally a quick little mention to
Our patreon Gang truly the lifeblood of
the show if you want to get early access
to episodes unheard and unreleased
interviews as well as going in the
running to get amazing genetics each
month and fortnite come on check out the
patreon at
www.patreon.com
slthe podcast we do live smoke with
heavy sessions every fortnite and give
away heaps of Swag every month come
check it out we love you the patreon
gang thank you so much we are so
[Music]
appreciative and on this one today we
got a fun one the first
ever with the man himself Marty TK
Origins Florida
native creator of the
TK
OG here to talk some his
history some plans for the
future so much
more let's get into
it all righty gang thanks for joining us
we're back for another one and on
today's episode we have an old school
Weed Head a surfer an incredible artist
a Florida native a big big thank you to
Marty of Origins TK for coming on the
show
today thank you thank you nice to be
here I know you and I probably five
years ago about doing this yeah look it
all good things come they just take a
bit of time uh I'm grateful to have you
on the show today the first thing I
wanted to ask you as we've been asking
all guests recently what have you been
smoking on lately that's a good question
I always have uh triangle cush Andy Kush
obviously around um lately I've been
going through some new flavors here at
the legal grow I've working at stuff
that I made from seed
um but the most recent thing I've been
smoking on and enjoying is actually some
Colombian gold uh Panama Red that a
friend of mine gave me a little jar of
and actually it brings back super good
memories from this strand in Florida we
had the early 2000s called Juicy Fruit
uh which I always thought was a Thai
Afghani cross I want to say but whatever
is in this particular bud has that exact
same like turps and Aroma after you
smoke it and it leaves that lingering
smell in the air you looks like it too
has very orange hairs on top of like
green flower and on little spinny um
sticks kind you know it has a very
similar look so I've been enjoyed that
lately that also answer the question
usually ask people about
sativas yeah I love it is that the um
the lumbo you posted uh yeah exactly I
don't know why they call it that but um
it's basically I think it came from
Alaska I want to say people hunted up
there or somewhere and my Budd here up
in near Jacksonville had at both City
seeds and uh yeah he came through the
other day and I gave him a pack of
seedar too to look for some males and he
gave me a jar of that so that was a nice
gift Ah that's beautiful did you get a
chance to try much of those like Mexican
and South American sativ is growing
up um as far as Mexican goes not per se
like in South Florida there was so much
brick weed that would come to Florida
and for some reason I couldn't even sell
a house stuff but a lot of my friends
were like moving truck Liv that stuff I
had friends who make 50 60 Grand a pop
doing like one deal with like a bunch of
Mexi brick and like I said I could
barely even sell an had to much l a
pound or more um we smoked it early
early on as kids here and there when
there's nothing else around but
definitely wasn't my favorite um and I
know obviously there's some good ones
that came from parts of Mexico but uh
yeah nothing like these Colombian and
Panama smoking I've ever seen now as far
as
Asian uh back then as a kid when I first
moved to Pomo I had met a group of
friends and we would actually pitch in
once in a while to buy like an ounce
between us from this guy that had a
connection and he called it Hawaiian hay
or no sorry Hawaiian skunk and it was
just some of the stinkiest butt ever it
was super fluffy would fill a giant bag
and uh the guy that would go get it the
guy that was selling it lives in a
high-rise condominium building full of
old people and the people the guy that
we knew was little older than us but he
knew the guy go over there and get an
ounce but back this is back before seal
meals or jars were being used so he
would always come back with like a lick
seal bag with like this big fluffy ounce
and the stories were always about some
old people that get in the elevators
with them and just get these crazy looks
and probably within a year so after that
connection basic I think the guy got
kicked out of the condo or maybe got
busted or something so that was we lost
that connection but that was a that was
definitely some sort of sativa hazy type
stuff like really really funky and
different had lots of colors um one of
my good friends of this day actually
Angelo he's SK by see Green Lounge um on
Instagram we he was one of the ones with
pitch in on that stuff with me when we
were probably like 14 15 15 years old
I'd say yeah we were young oh epic what
was the effect like of that Hawaiian
skunk well it's been many years but uh
obviously um I just remember to this day
I would say it's in the top 10 weed
we've ever I've ever smoked um variety
wi I don't know uh I can't say exactly
what the buzz was like but I'm pretty
sure we all Lov it a lot and you know it
was like as kids it was just like some
of the best stuff we'd ever seen and
still this day like I said if I had a
bag of that stuff people would be like
what the hell is that um it was really
exotic and I have no clue if it was
actually Hawaiian or whatever it was but
that's what it was called ah epic epic
let me um let me take you back for a
moment because you you referenced you
know you've always got some TK you got
some OG Kush on hand that's uh exactly
what I imagined I want wanted to ask you
do you have a favorite out of the
two um on any given day not really I
pretty much smoke them equally I pretty
much a bong hit person so always doing
bong hits one after the other and
basically I never really choose one a
day is pretty much mixing stuff up like
a salad all day long I got seven or
eight different varieties and pretty
much smoking through on a regular basis
um as far as triangle I've a lot more
familiar with that because that's the
one that I've had the cut that me and fr
my friends have had for years um and the
OG Kush I only found out about five
years ago when I went public and then
met Josh and a bunch of people that you
know involved with the OG Kush and
that's when we kind of tied all the
story together but
um uh yeah they're on their day they're
pretty equal um the triangle seems to be
a little bit more finicky these days
than it used to be like I used to always
pop used to use 600 wat lights back when
I was growing it mostly and I don't know
if it just like like less light like it
does um but once you get under thousands
it just seems like it's a little bit
harder to get you know to where it's
perfectly tasty and way way we used to
always get it um so yeah how would say
the triangle if I had to pick one
because like I said it got a lot more
time with her and OG K I've only had her
for like five years so wow there's a
there's a lot to go into there the first
one I want to touch on I've seen a lot
of people posting recently about how
they feel OG comes out way better under
HPS than LED has this been your
experience absolutely um it's been
definitely tricky with the
LEDs uh like back you know when I first
started I learned using checkerboard
back in the day we used to use HPS and
highight um so for sodium and highlight
sorry and uh we do a checkerboard setup
so actually where I'm at now doing stuff
bigly they have a few rooms that are
checkerboarded and that seems to be some
of the best quality in the building I I
believe anybody as far as LEDs go um you
can get super beautiful looking nugs but
there's just a little something that's
missing um and like it really you have
to really validate I've had a couple
batches that come out super good but
it's not consistent it's like you know
like one out of three will come out way
you want it so it's definitely something
to do with the LEDs that's missing still
maybe something to do with like a little
UV light or some UVB light that's
missing from the LED still I know some
companies are throwing bars in out and
adding that stuff so we'll see if it
progresses more and they get better and
I've also seen some really good batches
come out you know when they do come out
good out of the ls they do come out good
so it's definitely possible um it's just
for some reason it's more consistent in
the
HPS yeah interesting okay certainly a
sentiment I've heard echoed by a few
people so that's that's something I'll
have to take in I I wanted to quickly
ask cuz you mentioned that you know the
TK is a little more finicky now than
before and on past episodes we've
discussed in detail how the same is said
quite a lot about the chem dog I wonder
have you seen any other like the common
thing with the chem dog we hear is like
it takes longer to root the flavor is
not as strong anymore it's a little less
vigorous would you say that you see
those same sort of reductions or is it
just maybe in one specific area and less
in
others um it definitely Roots fine still
um the V is good
still I mean it's I think it's just
because the last few years I've been
using LEDs and like the times I've grown
it in the last few years at home or in
Central America where we're living it
was you know just a little harder to Fig
out the LEDs compared to what I remember
so but then we've had a couple batches
come out of this grow with the HPS
recently that like went way back and
tasted the way they should and stuff so
we had a couple tests that you know we
never did lab testing back in the day
but hour I'm seing lab testing on these
things and we've ranged between 19% THC
to 32% THC you know depending on how
good the B come out and uh so yeah I've
seen that hit 32 actually recently and
that was one of the tastier ones we've
had yet for some reason the rooms we
have are pretty much are all a little
bit different one room would produce
better than the other we have two LEDs
there's uh there's 11 rooms total at the
gr I'm at now and out of those 11
there's two LEDs and then the rest are
HPS but then some have checkerboard with
um Allied and some are just all HPS so
each room has his own little personality
I guess you could say so some of the
rooms definitely put off more fire than
others um and since I've been there
basically it's been almost almost a year
now I was working with these guys here
in Florida and we had a hurricane Ian
came through last year and it was right
about before I got to L my brand and uh
basically it wiped out power and flooded
the entire Zone and wiped out the entire
Coastline where the storm hit and it
basically the eye went right over the
Grove we were at and power went out the
cameras went out the backup generators
went out and so nobody could even get to
the place for 3 days so that definitely
set the whole building into a tail spin
a lot of stuff had to get killed
actually funny because most of the MS um
from the West Coast that they had all
the genetics from the West Coast
actually had hard time with the power
being off for a day or two but some of
the stuff I brought from the East Coast
like TK and OG for example were actually
survived the power out of like no
problem but most of the babies that we
had going that were getting ready to go
in flower um my brand whatever they
pretty much all died and we had to reset
everything it took another six months to
get up and going actually what what a
what an incredible Testament to the the
power of the TK and the
OG that's cool okay so I I um I wanted
to ask while we're on the topic what
style of growing do you
do well I've always been more of a salt
grower because here in Florida we're
always indoor I mean we didn't really
have the luxury like everyone out west
does of growing outdoor because first
off the humidity second of all back in
the day the they had drones and they had
clear helicopters and they go out and
you know do like sweeps with their
helicopters and find like every single
plant outdoors they you know out it
seemed like every plant that would be
outdoors would get found I don't know
how they did it but I tried a few times
there some patches here and there and
like we would crawl through Hedges and
bushes and put little plants in the
ground we come back a couple days later
and there'd be ATC tracks that we go you
know quag tracks right to the spot where
they were and they would cut them down
before they were even growing so we
never had a chance in outdoor basically
what I'm saying um I've had a couple
bashes here and there in Central America
outdoor but just like experimental and
like five gallon pots and soil so my
whole life has pretty much been indoor
with hydro and it's as far as indoor I
prefer salts obviously I've tried just
actually I'm smoking I'm just trying
right now which came from Organics alive
which I'm enjoying so I'll probably use
that again in the future um but yeah
we've always that's basically how I
learn and that's basically better for
indoors how always learned as far as
like living soil and stuff that's more
always thought it was more for maybe in
a bed or if you're growing in you know
Big Greenhouse or outdoor plants in like
giant containers where you know the the
living soil will actually starts living
in benefits from everything you're doing
to it versus you know an indoor
situation you're usually growing in
small pots um so yeah we've always been
I've done rock wall I've done cocoa I've
done clay pellets that's basically how I
learned years ago and you know lots of
different nutrient Brands over the years
and we've always produced fire weed I
smoke it myself all the time um so yeah
happy with it what an epic answer and
massive shout out to Organics alive one
of our sponsors that's so cool to hear
you grown a batch and smoking it and
it's good yeah it's a group of surfers
too so we actually I met with a couple
of them and um actually at the Aral Cup
this last year I went and met with Eric
from Organics live he super cool guy and
uh we plan on hanging out again soon
once it comes to Florida so definitely
good headcut that's epic yeah my um
interactions with Eric have been really
awesome as well I wanted to quickly ask
for our listeners out there you got any
tips for growing the TK or the OG I
think in the past I've heard a lot of
people say like whatever cow mag you'd
normally use like double or triple it
when you grow on an OG what's your take
any tips for the
listeners well
me personally when I was growing my best
TP ever back in the day we were being as
simple as can be and I wasn't really
adding any cow mag um this was under 600
watt sodiums I was using flood and drain
tables this is for years I did this
probably 10 years and we had the same
brand I learned on actually um was a
two-part liquid called rockol Formula 1
and they stopped making it years ago I
think Sunlight Supply bought the company
out and then they changed the formula
and it was never the same again and then
they just got faded up
but that's what I learned on basically
all the way back in like 1990
91 and I used that stuff all the way
till I got in trouble um in
2011 so I know the company's gone away
since then but that was the two-part I
never had any I me basically I would
find you know there's all these like
snake oils I just called them you know
at the hydro stores that were $50 a
bottle for this that and the other and I
tried a few things here and there some
bud swell and all the different products
cool Bloom and different botanic eares
and different you know additives but I
always had the best results from just
being simple with that I thought you
know like just the two-part nutrient the
right PHH and just that 600 watt light
which they seem to love and in Florida
we always grew you know I my style
growing was always like in a house in
bedrooms or a garage where you didn't
really have the luxury of having Mass AC
systems added you know unless you
install yourself so a lot of times we
just run your central AC unit so your
house could only get so cold your
bedrooms only get so cold unless you had
AC but a lot of times I would do like
two or three lights per room and you can
only get you know your your house as
cold as you're living in it so it seemed
like the best batches obviously for
years are always in the winter months in
Florida because it would actually get
pretty chilly in Florida especially
Central Florida get in the 40s and 50s
at time sometimes even lower so those
nights that time of year um for whatever
reason TK always thrived and I was like
when the tastiest stickiest than is
batches would always come out in summer
months you get bigger plants obviously a
little bit warmer and they just never
taste as good sometimes they be a little
more bland or almost like cardboard um
you can just almost tell it was just
like you know it took time but over time
we just realized that it was they like
the cooler temperatures and I started
adding many splits and smaller like
window units to my room and it really
set it off like year round where it was
always good that's awesome to hear I
haven't heard about it grown in Ultra
cold conditions have you ever got the TK
to go purple or is it just pretty much a
green plant uh you can get the leaves
may have to turn dark but like I've seen
I give it to a friend of mine in
Michigan who actually grew it last year
and I guess it get super cold up there
obviously I don't know how cold his room
got but it looked as dark as I've ever
seen it um but down here no we always
had it it was always green um for the
most part like you might get some
coloring on the leaves during the winter
mon I was talking about when it got cold
enough you get your room down to like 55
or 60 sometimes if you tried
um and you know basically the lights on
it wouldn't be that cold but at night
that's when you wanted to have it really
cold back then it seemed like um so
whatever combination we used to do in
the winter months here just made that
stuff taste like magic it's some of the
best weed ever and I tried it warm I
tried it cold I tried it you know all
different ranges but like it definitely
likes it cooler not cold cold and I
definitely like some warmth in the
beginning to get going obviously you
know like that's what we that's St we do
it now um get it growing for like the
first month kind of warm especially with
LEDs you got to have some warmth up to
like 84 85 degrees even on the LEDs um
but half the way you know halfway
through we pretty much start dropping it
down I would anyway um all the way down
probably like say 70 for daytime T high
and 60 to 65 for night time would be a
good Target and that always seems to be
a magic formula for
it ah okay beautiful and out of
curiosity what's like the single most
memorable batch of TK you've had and do
you remember how it was
grown uh well like I was saying most of
the time I grew it I was using clay
rocks um and doing flood and drain and
then at some point I switched over to
drippers and it just made the plants a
lot thicker and just blew up actually so
I kind of like got out of the whole
flood and drain thing and switched the
drippers at that point and then then you
started learning a little bit more about
prop steering and drying them out a
little bit more at the end and and it
seemed like there were some batches that
were just incredible from from that um
there's a couple times timers went out
and the plants almost died on the stick
and they just ended up being like Oh my
god what happened it got so good so
that's about the time we started
learning you know how to like starve
your plants and basically help bring out
more flavors and oils and and you know
the cooler temperatures combined
basically was a nice combination for
sure that's beautiful that's beautiful I
want to talk more because you you
mentioned um some seed projects a few
questions ago but before we get there
let's go back and set the scene because
I know everyone who's listening is
really Keen to hear exactly what your
name is TK Origins so let's go back to
the start what was your first experience
with
cannabis uh first experience was uh I
think I was 12 years old like
1984 U my parents had split up and my
dad moved to a nice house on the beach
he rented like a few hours North
actually she book Ron and my brother and
I were still living at my mother's house
and we go visit him on the weekends and
he apparently smoked a lot I didn't know
it then but um that that trip one of
these trips at his house basically I was
being nosy and him and my brother were
out for the day I guess or do and
something and I was going through my
dad's room and I stumbl across a change
basket on top of his dresser and on top
of there was this huge roach um clamp in
a clamp in a r flip um device like one
of those metal clamps so I knew what for
some reason what it was I guess I was in
seventh grade at the time and just knew
what it was I knew it was drugs you know
but I didn't didn't think it was I
wasn't scared of it but whatever for
whatever reason that day I found a
lighter and got curious and I took it
out back on our patio and took a little
hit off it and put it out right away all
paranoid immediately and I was actually
worried immediately like I was going to
get seen by The Neighbors The Neighbors
was going to smell it it was the smell
at the house my dad was going to see
that I smoke some of it so it just hit
me immediately like paranoia style and I
didn't see weed again for another year
until nth
grade ah okay and and what was that next
experience like uh nth grade well for a
couple years in a row my dad was we
moved in with my dad and he was running
houses every year moving us from school
to school um so ninth grade I went to
this real nice um high school that was
full of surfers and skaters and like all
my type of people basically and that was
I had just started surfing the year
before in eighth grade um in b beach and
so I started going to this new school
met a bunch of friends and they all had
Brothers a little older than them they
were all smoking weed already and
basically I just kind of ran into it
that way again parties or go to like a
football game with some of the guys at
the school and smoke under the beachers
and stuff like that we all skated start
getting into skating at the time and go
to skate parks and built little half
pipes in our yards and um that whole
scene of people are all on smoking weed
at the time so that's basically when I
got into it ah and and do you remember
were there any names associated with the
stream back then or was it just like the
days where it was like the kind and
stuff like that yeah it was definitely
no names I remember from back then the
early days there was always somebody
else had it and they would pull it out
and roll up a joint or um had a pipe or
something on them ah interesting
interesting and and you've touched on
the surfing aspect and this was
something I wanted to talk to you about
because much like the Grateful Dead I
feel like surfing in general is very
intertwined with cannabis culture was it
is it one of the cases with the Chicken
and the Egg like which one came first
for you the Cannabis or the surfing or
was it sort of at the same time no it
was definitely surfing I started surfing
that year before like I said it was 8th
grade um I bought my first uh surf board
out of a pawn shop and I live like maybe
a mile from the beach in b beach so I
started going there all the time on the
weekends and my dad was always against
me surfing he always knew that it was
like a stoner type sport you know it's
just maybe because of the Fast Times
movies or whatever it was but he just
always frown on it at first um for years
actually so um I almost like had to do
it like secretly I'd go to the beach you
know my surfboard type thing uh so yeah
it was surfing first skating next and
then smoking weed pretty much came next
after that the uh the holy Trio I love
it so skating Smoky yeah no it is
interesting because obviously you know
like there's that history of like the
brothers of eternal love and their
connection with surfing so it is I guess
maybe that's partly where your dad got
his perception of it from maybe it could
be he just always wanted to be me to be
a sports player like you know like
either baseball or something soccer
whatever it was he had me playing
baseball real young and stuff I didn't
want to do basically and he was always
on the TV watching sports growing up
which actually got me to not like those
kind of sports too much um so that's
probably what actually let me to surfing
and skating to begin with there you go
right we tend to Rebel from our parents
that's uh that's that's pretty part for
the course so from that second
experience when did the penny drop for
you that cannabis was something you
wanted to get really involved
with well let's see ninth grade I was
just kind of I wasn't buying or anything
yet these guys always had it you know so
we would get high with them but um we
moved my dad finally bought a house for
10th grade but it was like an hour south
there 45 minutes south there so we moved
from like I said all over the place and
I finally get settled in Meet bunch of
friends and they moved me to another
place like south of there which the
waves weren't as good uh that the school
I was supposed to go to was all super
nice and new so that's the reason you
bought the house and then we we moved
there over the summer and they Clos that
school down so then next thing you know
I'm getting shipped to like this crazy
Public School in the middle of the real
bad neighborhood and uh wasn't liking it
one bit basically it was like small all
click of Surfers that I met you know in
that first year and uh basically we live
close to the beach so I like that part
about it and he bought a nice house on
the water actually so I enjoyed that and
I guess eventually I started making
friends and stuff so anyway that first
year I met a bunch of kids skating
surfing and that was probably the year I
started actually buying weed that was
actually the group of friends I was
talking about earlier we were buying
that Hawaiian skunk from the guy um and
that was actually before I was even
driving a car yet so I was 15 and uh
yeah that was the year I first started
buying and selling a little bit of weed
here and
there ah incredible so were you just
like sort of selling and middl Manning
it for a while before you started
growing or what was that progression
like to them become a
grower yeah definitely um started out
just kind of like buying it for our
personal and stuff I never thought about
growing it or seeing plants until years
later but um actually at some point when
I was I think I was 16 or 15 or 16 still
someone had gave me this thing called a
Phototron and my dad had a pretty we
moved into a pretty good sized house and
the house was like divided into two and
I had my own like room on the other side
of the house my own entrance SL glass
door so I can kind of come and go and
sneak in and out of the house easy if I
wanted my dad was kind of lenient wasn't
very strict with us um it was just me
and my brother other with them and he
actually had a place going on in okopoko
he had a condo with a couple friends of
his and he would go visit there all the
time and leave my brother and I and
leave me in charge of the house
basically so at some point somebody gave
me a Phototron which was like this
little octagon box um that was like size
of a little mini refrigerator and all
the sides had these like um tinted
windows that you could lift up or slide
up and then access the center which had
a bunch of these fluorescent lights that
were running up the center along the the
walls and I think someone gave it to me
because it had a fan that had broke on
them or something and they didn't want
it anymore so I took it home and stuck
it in my little master closet and
covered it with like 30 laundry and a
surf for and stuff and actually popped
some seeds that I found bag of weed I
had no idea what it was but basically
got him going and flowered them out on
that little thing actually did a couple
bouches of it a couple of my friends I
still talked to this day actually
remember that it's super funny but um
never got caught pulled it off threw
that thing away at some point it was
pretty much garbage oh man the Phototron
that's a blast from the past I love to
hear that and uh that's cool that you
managed to do a few crops from those
seeds do you do you have any memories at
all about like if you had to guess based
on the structure or the smells like
looking back what do you think those
genetics might have been I really don't
remember they're tiny plants they
probably you know it might have been
like quarter ounces or something that
came out of there per plant like that I
might have done like three or four
plants each batch and you know it was
just just it's kind of like a little
hobby learning thing it's almost like a
if I see if I can get away with it here
my my house kind maybe H look kudos to
you that that's Epic and you mentioned
that um you know the property in aapo
did you ever get to try any cool weed
down there um I never have to been to
aapco myself my dad was going down there
all the time he would always that's
probably the reason my parents separated
I would imagine because he was going
down there partying with his friends and
my Mom hated it so he'd always come back
with like knockoff clothes for us my
brother and I like Levi jeans and this
polo shirts and this that and the other
um so no I never actually spent time in
alapo I've been to Mexico three times
different locations surfing but not to
aquapa um more recently actually I've
been to southern Mexico which is
probably one of the better surf in my
life there you go Okay cool so so you
got into it pretty early so you know how
did things progress because for anyone
who's been following your story online
they'd probably be aware that you were
involved in the whole TK story quite
young you know sort of around 19 to 20s
it sounds like it wasn't too long of a
time period before you transitioned into
that story is that right yeah well it
all started um
actually going back a year I was
15 and I wasn't driving yet and I was
skipping school one day and we lived on
like a dead end Street or my dad had his
own job or he can come and go anytime he
wanted so I never knew when he would
back out of the driveway I'm supposed to
be going to the bus stop but I always
sneak out my surfboard and try to like
run down the street where he wouldn't
see me and that's how I was get to
school and get away with it um so one
day I'm walking down the street with my
surfboard trying to like avoid my dad
and I get to the end of my street and my
neighbor from across the street was a
surfer also and was a little older than
he was like 10 years older than me and
he pulled up in his little Mustang and
hun the horn asked me if I wanted to go
to the beach with him I was like looked
and see had surbs in the back I was like
oh yeah so I jumped in and then that day
was basically the day that I would meet
my whole crew later on that was like the
day that would change my life so we went
to uh the beach that day a beach a
little further north that I normally
would go to I lived in Papo he took me
to Deerfield Beach like the town north
of there and there was a pier there and
basically a whole scene it was
volleyball courts and chicks everywhere
and bunch of surfers and the waves were
good that day so this guy who's 10 years
older than me starts introducing me to
his friends um some of these guys were
actually Pro Surfers and Surfer you know
companies or whatever already already
had sponsorships and stuff and they had
a video camera going on that day on the
beach on a big Tri Cloud so I'm hanging
out with these guys I'm surfing myself
and then basically at some point I get
asked if I wanted to run the camera for
a while and video everybody he pointed
out everybody who to video and show me
how to use the camera real quick I like
H yeah let's do it so I started messing
with the camera and videoing all these
guys you know I was like super young
looking up to all these characters that
were like 10 years older than me at the
time and I've already knew who some of
these guys were from seeing them surfing
at my local Beach so that day we uh we
rallied a bunch of people up and went
back to this guy Taco Joe's house who
was one of the guys that was surfing
with us that day um they called him Taco
Joe because he had a Mexican restaurant
right there there near the beach called
Taco Joe's so he ran by that name for
years Miami mangoes actually knows him
really well there's actually a video of
him and Miami mangle fighting in a
boxing ring at a at a nightclub years
ago so anyway we get back to that guy's
house and I'm just a little young kid
there everyone there walking around with
boms and rolling up joints fat you know
fat bags of weed and rolling up joints
with and there's girls coming and going
in bikinis and there's a trampoline out
back or the pool and the guy got a pack
of pit and it was like big fat Jeep and
I'm like oh [__] these guys are the [__]
so that day I uh I met a couple other
people that I never seen before met um
and basically I had already been buying
weed at this point so I started
conversation with one of the guys that
was there that didn't surf he was like
one of the guys that didn't have any son
he was like pale and he had an English
accent so we started talking about
something I forget what it was about but
one thing led to another and he gave me
his information if I ever wanted to get
a couple oun of weed here in there from
him he said no worries to hook you know
he hook me up so that's basically the
person I met that day that would end up
becoming my mentor later on um that same
day at that place I met a few guys that
were end up you know being Growers I
would find out later on but I had no
clue of the time
obviously wow and and was it a pretty
rapid transition into being involved in
their whole world or did it take some
time to build some more Rapport no it
took a little time for sure I think like
I said I was 15 then um and just buying
like an ounce here and there with some
friends I Got a Car shortly after that
and started hooking up with the guy and
got buying maybe quarter pounds he was
Fring to me at the time and like over
time a quarter pound we lead to a half
pound and half pound lead to a pound and
it started to get stinky in my house and
I was still live in my dad's house so um
at that point in time I think I was
around 17 I want to say um I was still
living there and I had to go get a
little Warehouse little mini warehouse
uh what you call mini storage unit and I
had to find one that had power in it
that I could put a little refrigerator
and and store the weed in that was my
whole goal so I found one did that so I
was able to buy a pound at a time and
not have to worry about my dad finding
so um yeah that's basically how I
started ramping up these guys selling
weed for them um and at some point in
time later on guess I
was yeah middle 17ish I was asked by the
English guy if I wanted to go on a trip
to Amsterdam and that's how that thing
came up basically offered me he offered
me to pay for everything to go there
with him and if I would carry seeds back
for him and the reason he asked me that
is because I had already gone on a
couple surf TS by then with some friends
and we've gone to Costa Rica Puerto Rico
and a few other places by this point I
always carry we always carry weed on our
pants back then because the was before
9111 and it was easy to travel with weed
and it was basically like brainer we did
it like easily so I guess my friend was
super paranoid to do that himself so he
brought me along thinking like oh I'll
bring them seeds back for him no
wores so that was uh the year I got
asked to go to Amsterdam but before I
could even go there I had to ask my dad
for permission and I couldn't tell him I
was going to Amsterdam obviously because
he probably would have said no in a
heartbeat um so I made up this whole
story about how I was going to visit my
friends family in England or we're going
to go skateboard some some of the
streets maybe some some skateboard parks
there and do some sightseeing and all
this stuff and my dad let me like had no
problem with it so and back then there
was no passports needed to travel over
there just all you needed was a birth
certificate so um it was pretty easy to
do um so I think we went I definitely we
went like uh right before the holidays
so I had like some school time off I
want to say um and that was like my last
year in school there and I was getting
ready to move out of his house soon
anyway so it was pretty close to the end
of me living there um so yeah that's
when went basically the first time so
how how old were you when you went over
what year was
it uh it was 1989 the very end of 1989
so I was 17 still um when I got back
from that trip it you know turned 1990
and I think the end of that year by
summertime I had moved out um so
basically I when we got back from that
trip I kind of had figured out that this
guy was growing at this point along with
a couple of people that came on the trip
with us so I kind of had a feeling what
was up um I wasn't I didn't see anything
yet at this point but I got home and
started looking for a place to move out
to and I had this friend that I had
surfing with all the time named Joe um
and he was actually a couple years older
than me and was one of the ones that was
actually buying some of the weed from me
and it you know Grew From like like I
said a quarter pound to a half pound I
you know he's buying a couple pounds at
a time and we were singing good amount
of weed together so he had an apartment
that had an extra bedroom and he he
offered me a place to move in so I
jumped on on it and we started living
together and going out partying together
and selling weed together he had
connections that would come from Central
Florida um from like new Samina Beach
and Orlando area and that's actually how
I met Craig because Craig would drive
down with this guy Mike Luke um together
like basically to buy as many pounds
they can get from us cash um so we had a
pretty good thing going for a while
until one day we came back home from I
don't know what it was lunch or
something too
and the apartment had gotten broken into
so uh he made it look like basically I
come to find out later on it was the guy
Joe that set it all up but I'll get back
to that eventually um so the house
looked like it was Rob both rooms got R
they found four pounds that I had in my
room and they found some cash basically
all I had um they he made it look like
they stole stuff out of his room too so
I believe it you know was like we got
randomly robbed by somebody so we both
moved out I found my own place um
because of that robbery though my friend
that I had been buying the weed cash at
that point because I was getting better
prices for it um and because of the
robbery my friend felt bad for me and
basically offered me to come to his
house one day which I did and took me
for a ride and we went to his Gro which
I had never seen before um so that day
walked into this nice house and Boke Ron
like a think it was a four bedroom three
car garage two or three car garage house
um
and it was furnished super nice and set
up like somebody lived there but I could
smell weed immediately when I walked in
so I knew it was up and he asked me if I
wanted to be a helper on the next
Harvest trimming and manicuring and
cleaning up the bash that was about to
come out of this garage he showed me so
this was all like whoa you know like hit
me like a ton of bricks I was like oh
yeah this is sick so I jumped on the
offer he offered me I think like $2 or
$3,000 it was like be there for three
days straight trimming with uh his then
step brother and step brother's best
friend who were like actually like a
year younger than me so yeah that was
around uh 18 years old I guess when I
got offered that job and started doing
that and it was basically every two
months two or three months I would go
there for three days and make a couple
Grand and not only that but I was also
selling me for the guy and making money
off that um and that's how things
started I mean and actually started
learning you know little things about
the house and he started teaching me you
about cloning and getting plants vegging
and Mom plants and cleaning up and all
the important stuff that you need to
know um so yeah that was that all
started around
18 um and then I think it was
uh yeah I turned 19 I had my own place
at this point and that same guy Joe um
was moved he moved back up to Central
Florida where he was originally from but
he was still coming down and buying
pounds and bringing cash so so uh he
came we set up something one day where I
had grabb I think almost yeah it was 10
lbs and I couldn't get to my warehouse
in time that day where I would normally
store if I had to start or whatever
because they Clos the gates at 8:00 pm
they open up at 600 every day type thing
and I got there late so I had to take it
to my apartment so the guy Joe gets
there he gets to Hotel um we go plan on
going out that night he comes over my
house and I had the weed sitting in my
refrigerator and a big seal meal bag and
a garbage bag and uh he didn't know it
was there but he asked me for a beer at
some point I didn't think twice and I
told him just grab one out of the fridge
I should have grabbed it myself thinking
back but he's seing the weed in there
and then we went out drinking and on the
way out I stopped at the gas station to
get gas and he gets a page from his
girlfriend at the time blowing him up
and he had this crazy chick um so he
gets out of the car and go make a phone
call saying you know talk to this chick
about something and shut her up so that
basically he was off making arrangements
to have somebody come to my place and
Rob it while we were out that night so
we got out drinking he had some friends
that own some nightclub or he had a
friend that was like a bouncer at a
nightclub and another friend that like
was a manager there or something so we
had connection to this night we go to we
come back like 3 4 in the morning pretty
late night all drunk and he comes to my
house where he would normally would come
in and at least come in and smoke a
joint or do some bonit with me before he
would leave but this night he decided to
just drop me off and like tell me he'
meet me in the morning and we'll do the
deal so I didn't think anything of it
you know it was pretty late I go
stumbling in the house and the first
thing I noticed is my sliding out door
was broken into um so I ran straight to
the fridge and seeing it was gone the
weed uh the house they went through
everything they found my head stash they
found a few grand cash I had a nice
watch somewhere in the house they took
everything I think they left me like a
little gr nugget like a joke so because
of that the same guy the man guy from
England he felt bad again for me and
then that became um my opportunity to
partner up with him in that house
basically because he was actually trying
to get another house going somewhere
North like a couple hours North he found
10 acres a nice house on it he was
starting to set it up spent a lot of
time there and it was a perfect perfect
opportunity for him to have a partner at
the time and so I he got me uh he got me
to move out of that place obviously and
I did um realized pretty quickly that
the guy Joe was the thief it just didn't
make sense a lot of things that happened
and I called him out over on the phone
and you know basically admitted to it
kind of told him me to [__] off and come
to find out he was smoking Coke and
doing free base and like really [__]
up in life so that's why he got to be
that type of person so I didn't know
that side of the guy at all you know I
just kind of was making money and kind
of blind to it all
so it was actually that guy I guess we
could all thank for my situation and the
OG Christian TK because of those
robberies I was given the opportunity to
run a grow and that's where that se
mistake actually happened in that
grow wow thank you free based
Coke no let let me just quickly jump in
for a second there CU there's so much
interesting details there the first
thing I want to quickly ask you was that
first time when you went over to
Amsterdam did you bring any genetics
back and as a followup was there any
interesting weed you tried while over
there the first time I went uh we didn't
find the that good of weed actually the
first trip and the guys I was with were
kind of arrogant I guess you could call
it we already had good weed in Florida
so we went there with high
expectations um so all the coffee shops
we hit up the first day or two were just
like generic orange Bud that seemed like
it the same stuff getting passed around
all the coffee shops like gu tourist
weed and I mean we actually found some
good hash that everyone was like stoked
on but uh as far as actual flow no um
actually it took two days and that trip
it was kind of a short trip I think we
went for like six or seven days that
trip um but like maybe day two or three
we're out drinking at a pub playing pool
a couple of us and we met this couple
and we we knew we were there for the SE
Bank we didn't know where it was yet uh
we don't knew about the c bank because
it was in the back of High Times
magazine they had these little articles
back then all the time and sorry just to
confirm you mean like Neville's The Seed
bang the seed bang yeah this is 1989
yeah cool keep going
so this couple had some good weed on
them and they are actually rolling up
cones and mixing tobacco in it so we
refused to do that but we took a little
nog and roll our own joint it was really
good I can't remember what it was but it
was that couple that basically gave us
um told us how to get to the seed bank
which was at the Cannabis castle at the
time and we thought we could actually
walk to it but we found out it was like
an hour hour and a half away by a taxi
which we had no clue where that was so I
think the next day some of the guys
contacted um the seed bank made sure
they were open before we tracked off we
got directions and there was like four
of us got in a van and and went there
that day and grabbed a bunch of stuff
and you know when I first came out I
might have said I met Neville back in
the day or whatever but I mean I
knew we didn't know who never was back
then straight up nobody did I mean maybe
some people that Liv there whatever did
but we only knew of the SE bank and all
the stories of Neville didn't come out
till many years later so we had all the
packaging we had the catalog from there
and you know that's what I meant by we
shopped at Neville's place the seat Bank
basically um so yeah I don't know we
could have met him but I was so young we
went shopping there we went in the
castle there was like a little it was
kind of like a living room you walk into
it seemed like somebody lived there and
that's where they had their little shop
and I later find out they had like a
basement where they were grown but I
never saw any of that we seen a big
Greenhouse out back um but there was
people working there there's two or
three four people working there in the
front of this the time that's who we
dealt with don't know who who they were
or names or Neville is one of them
probably not so I know that right at the
end of 89 apparently it was close to
when he was almost getting in trouble or
indicted so who knows where he was at
the
time but it was it was definitely the
the Cannabis castle that we shopped at
um and we grabbed a good majority of the
stuff we could we grabbed like um
there's I think five Growers out of the
group and they were trying to get like a
couple packs of each for all of them so
we're trying to get I think like a dozen
of each variety they had in the
menu um and a lot of it I didn't even
see later on like basically we got back
to Florida and that stuff all got
divided up amongst everybody um and
basically the Hindu Kush that I ended up
popping with a real small pack for some
reason I don't know maybe it was like
they were low on inventory I know it
wasn't in the catalog and I know a lot
of people claim that wasn't in the
catalog and trying to prove whatever
stories I lying about it wasn't the
catalog that then but whatever reason it
was um he gave us a pack of hind seeds H
cush seeds and they ended up being the
ones that made the pollen and the
Emerald Triangle room that you know
created the triangle and you p with the
sorry I I'll just drill into some
specifics because I know people will be
interested do you when you say a small
pack you mean like there was only like
six seeds and not like 10 or something
no no it was like a single pack you know
like maybe 10 or 12 seeds it was I think
by then I want to say okay and for some
reason they charged less for those then
everything else I think they were like
$2 a seed or some of the other stuff on
the menu was like five a seed um he
actually had a couple other fush um
varieties on the menu I remember that
one was sold out it was like Kush times
Kush and then another one we brought
back was like skunk times Kush and for
some reason those were $2 a piece each
you know so we didn't even think they
were that good to be honest we thought
they were based on the price that they
you know he was like giving away a
freebie type thing ah okay and and the
Hindu Kush seeds that you ended up
popping were they in like packaging that
said Hindu Kush or was it just generic
packaging or was it in like a pack that
said something else but he was like oh
by the way this is actually Hindu Kush
uh I'm pretty sure they were all in
actual seed bank packaging but they're
we had to like consolidate them when we
were out there back home and like little
dime bags and then we hand rode on
everything and I don't know who kept all
the packaging on that trip I know some
of the packaging came back with us I
know some the catalogs did too um and I
kept the catalog myself you know was
like a porn magazine I kept looked at
all the time but uh as far as the
packaging goes I can't remember um if it
was if they're all basically the seat
Bank packaging that we took back and H
Kush is one of them or we just you know
I just know that I we had a pack of H
Kush that came from there that day and
it was written
on um and did any of the other packs you
got end up turning into anything
memorable or was it really just that
Hindu Kush that ended up being the
memorable one for obvious reasons no we
were we did a bunch actually for there
is definitely some prior to that we were
doing some Northern Light 5 testing um
we found a really nice early Pearl and a
real nice Northern Light 5 Haze um that
was actually a quick finisher like 70
days or something and they you know the
guys I was with they're all about the
the big yields and the fastest finish
they can get and and bang it out you
know that's and basically trying to
squeeze five six bouches a year so it
was all about making the money you know
I'm not going to lie um if if we had the
opportunity back then in Florida was
just that way if we had the opportunity
like in California or Washington or
place Hawaii or whatever where you could
actually get away with growing upd door
I'm sure we would have been more into
the you know that side of it but it was
all about crops you know making crop
making money out of the crops and fast
as possible these guys roll off for the
speed clones and S you know genetics
basically that were done in eight weeks
nine weeks Max and then beyond that they
pretty much give away or throw out um so
we went went through a bunch of nl5 haze
and only kept one um and some of the
guys actually that had a little more
patience than the guy I worked with and
would actually do some of their stuff a
little longer so when it came time to me
buying some of the weed I didn't always
get just our stuff my friend was getting
it from his little like Co-op of friends
that he had you know to get from so if I
needed five six pounds a week one week
and we didn't have any he would get it
from somebody else for me and some of
those guys grew that Haze way better
than we did for whatever reason I'm sure
they let it go longer like for us the
guy would take it down in like 60 days
and it was still like a lot of white
hairs and just kind of like real hairy
orangey in the bag type look other times
it would go a little bit longer it
seemed like it would swell up more maybe
in the winter months or something but
yeah we ran that a couple times we ran a
northern light that was real short squat
big fat leaves and it didn't yield that
good um we found a a big skunk that was
good they found a Shiva skunk that was
good from that that was a huge yielder I
didn't like the weed actually personally
but a lot of people liked it and they
sold tons of it because it made you know
like giant plants for whatever reason I
think you know like back then we were
getting an average around two pounds of
light and this this stuff for whatever
reason was getting three pounds of light
so it got all these guys all like
psyched to grow that one um I didn't
like it like I said and then there was
uh what else comes to mind some of the
genetics these guys had when I came on
board were actually some of the better
stuff still that I remember growing back
then it was like the anald triangle the
guy that we got the anald triangle from
came from Washington State and he was
probably 20 years older than me so he
was 10 years older at all my crew but I
think he might have been the guy that
taught these guys the whole method of
growing the nutrients and the whole
setup basically because he brought it
from Washington I want to say like
around 86 or so 87 and that's when he
took these genetics over here um so he
was the one that gave these guys uh the
Emerald Triangle they had Williams
Wonder they had clone big bud and I want
to say the original G13 that we had came
from him although I can't confirm that
um but that one I've seen around Florida
for years um what else there was a
couple others he might have brought over
but um yeah he was the one that
basically started these guys I think in
their path of you know how they did
their thing wow that's that's so cool to
hear what a what an awesome range of
genetics that was sort of going around I
want to quickly ask before we jump into
the Emerald Triangle stuff cuz I know
everyone's itching for it you mentioned
Williams Wonder I'm a sucker for
Williams Wonder I love it what was your
memory of that special clone was it a
good one I loved it it was uh it was the
first time I've seen like real clumpy
tallic stack you know like neon green
colorful weed like that it was one of
the first things i' seen growing
actually the first house I went to trim
um that I asked I was asked to go trim
was I think it was a room of Williams
Wonder and big bud and something else I
can't remember um but yeah that was the
first time I ever seen like a full 12
light room going of anything I love
smoking that stuff it was always
tasty interesting that that's really
cool to hear and the gentleman who you
describe as like possibly the one who
introduced your friends to the whole
growing scene what was he like was he
that typical old school like you know
kept his head down didn't talk much
about it or was he like willing to chat
to you a bit about things I never got to
talk to him much I met him a couple
times and my friends just like coming
and going and and he my friend would
tell me you know stories about him and
who he was but he was to himself he I
think he had like a 20 acre Plant Farm
up in Palm Beach I want to say and one
crazy story I do remember for sure about
him was he had like a 30 or 40 light
like steel building going with a propane
going for CO2 and I guess the guy had a
big plant nursery and this was like in
the center of his property and it was
next to a big lake that he had and I
think something happened with a propane
tank where it blew up the building like
made way through a batch and the guy had
like a bunch of excavators on the
property and tractors and stuff and I
heard that he pushed the entire building
that night into the lake after like
burned down or I don't know maybe it
went out real quick or something but
like the whole building imploded and he
took his excavator and pushed it all
into the lake and then buried that Lake
a few days later and that was the last
of
it so that's that guy was pretty pretty
heavy um and back then hearing about a
40 lighter or whatever it was that he
had it was just like holy [__] that's
crazy because 12 lights was already
sketchy as can be wow yeah I can only
imagine back at that time 40 lighter
would have been Insanity so let's just
quickly jump back to it then so you've
got back from Amsterdam youve got these
new genetics how did things progress
from that point to when you eventually
began involved in the house where uh you
know you started popping some of those
seeds such as the Hindu Kush
um well
basically once I got robbed by that guy
and moved out I got myself a place maybe
a mile away from that other girl house
my friend had he actually own the house
and uh once he let me start taking over
and sharing a batch with him and started
doing this thing up north I would start
riding my bike there or drive we had a
car par there every night like a decoy
car but I I was able to ride my bike
there even walk there if I wanted to so
I started going there daily um taking
care of the place he would still come
down like once a week maybe twice a week
some sometimes to make sure everything
was cool and checking on me um check in
on everything was going
on um so yeah I was at that house that
we would start popping those seeds and
at this point I was like you know I was
starting to get really into it and I was
super intrigued to find new flavors all
the time so I was probably more into it
than these guys were as far as finding
that new genetic and they normally would
we had like a little space I'll explain
how the room was set up eventually but
we had a little space by our doorway
where we had like a little space for
four plants five plants Maybe
and that's where we would do our testing
at so we didn't even have like a
dedicated area it was just kind of like
a little extra space um we had a little
closet somewhere where we would sex
plants to see if they're male or female
but then once they they were sex we
would put them in there and test them
and if they didn't turn out like
phenomenal they would usually get canned
like on the first batch or given away to
somebody if they were good um so there's
only like a handful that we really kept
and like lots of stuff that I really we
went through that I wish we kept like
there was one called Hawaiian snow that
to me was like the first time I ever
seen a bag like squeeze the bag and it
just leave like a super shiny shiny coat
on the bag and it was like real neon
green some sort of satif cross I can't
remember what it was but they killed it
immediately of course you know I had
like head stashed of it for a while and
got to enjoy maybe a half pound of it or
something but that was one they killed
off I wish they kept there was a handful
and a bunch of them I think there was
like a Northern Lights times skunk there
was a you know handful of good ones that
just never made the cut because like I
said these guys were sticking to those
big yielders and you know they seem to
be happy with what they already had
seemed like for the most part that's
interesting to hear yeah I can imagine
that like stuff would have been quick to
be C back in those days so what was who
was it who decided to pop the seeds did
did you have a feeling about these Hindu
Kush seeds or how did that all go down
um I don't exactly remember why I think
they were just maybe next in line or
something I know for a fact that like
the one before that like when I first
came out I wasn't 100% sure it was a
Hindu I told a couple people that it was
either Hindu or Northern Lights or a
couple different things that I wasn't
100% sure on but then once me and my
friend Craig started talking about it
all because he he was super into all
these different genics like me he would
come down and I had this little tackle
box with like these little dividers and
it kept like a real sealed um lid and I
kept all these different flavors in
there for I don't know why but it was
just something at the time and he came
down and we would basically go through
these like little like mini Cannabis Cup
and Sample them all out and Bong Hits
and joints and so for sure he talked
about the the seated Hindu Kush and the
Hindu Kush that that we grew it was like
there was like probably five plants
there was like two real short mutant
ones that had to like prop up off the
ground because they weren't getting any
light and there's two that were like
kind of reaching up to the trellis so
there was definitely not
inconsistent as far as the G structure
there's like I said there's almost like
two indas and two almost like
hybrid kind of leaning stretchy plants
but whatever it was they all tasted just
super different and incredible like I
was so bumed and my friend killed them
all off after he did because I would
take him all home for some head stash
grun or something if I you know if I had
to but he basically killed them all off
because he didn't want to take a chance
of any more seeds coming out anywhere we
we never found the hermit plant we
basically just cut everything dried it
and that's we found out the seeds were
in there afterwards so I ended up taking
I think those plants smoke basically and
uh we killed off he killed off all the
moms that we kept from seed and that was
the last of the do basically but it was
definitely different and Craig and I we
had SE over for a while um that was
probably you know cross with itself or
whatever and uh I had a seeds collection
this hollow Coke can this years later
this happened but this coke can had all
these seeds from that batch and other
batches theal triangle batches that were
seated here and there just a collection
I have from Amsterdam still from 93 when
I went back and this girl I was dating
at the time I went to like a on a surf
trip and she was trying to like clean my
house and like do me a favor and like
surprised me and I come home and the
Coke can was in the refrigerator and I
guess she threw it out but she'll deny
it to the day because she never admitted
to it um but she was probably cleaning
the house and tried to pop the can and
it wouldn't open and she probably it
looked like an old can and she just
tossed it but that that can had so many
good season and it's
ridiculous die to have those things back
that that sounds so there's like a lot
of critical information in there I'd
love to get a few specifics so um you
know for anyone who's not familiar like
the the idea is that you know the TK um
and OG Kush came from an accidental
pollination involving this unknown clone
called The Emerald Triangle and the
Hindu Kush that we're speaking about so
so just to confirm there was no males in
the room it was it was a a hermy Polland
never saw a male we never had SE before
in in the Emerald Triangle and there's
definitely no leaks because that was
something that I was always warned and
never open the doors and so there's you
know there was no flashing lights in the
room or anything we never found we never
found a culprit so it had to be we just
assumed it had to be from one of those
plants that went hermy and I mean never
even knew what a Herm me was at that
point I was pretty young it was my first
year really growing weed on that kind of
scale and I had never really seen a Herm
before that so didn't really know what
to look for didn't know that some small
plan like that can make so much pollen
with pollen most of a room but the way
the room was set up we had an AC um
added to the room like a 5 ton AC unit
and it was like 4 feet away from the
door so in the way I gu the we had the
fan set up so it circulated the room um
like like cyclonic and apparently it
just sucked all that pollen right
directly into the AC vent and then
spread across through the vents across
the whole room so that was you know
something we never thought about when we
were testing C's there obviously at that
point we obviously thought you know I
only thought males could do that and so
once we realized we had no males we
thought we were good to go so yeah so
based on what you're saying there was
like quite a fair bit of seed produced
in the overall crop well I was pretty
consistently seated but some people said
they found a shitload in there other
people said they couldn't find but maybe
one so it wasn't like really really
spread across the room there's Craig
remember had on a batch that was like
said he opened up a butt and every
single little Nugget had a seat in it so
maybe that was closer to the vanent or
to the the pollination or something but
yeah it wasn't really really bad like
like Alec Anderson for example the one
who found the OG push seed he swears
that there wasn't many seeds at all he
had like I think he bought four ounces
off Craig back then that came from me
and uh out of out of those four ounces I
think he said he found one or two seeds
I want to say so he'll sit there and
argue that it was not many seeds at all
but that was definitely from the same B
weed yeah wow okay um sorry I'm going to
have to keep pulling us back cuz there's
so many interesting details here so um
so when you talk about the Hindu having
those two different sort of phenotypes
generally speaking the squatter ones you
had to prop up and the lankier ones
those lankier ones did they sort of have
a structure that resembled the OG and
the TK to you that I can't remember I
just know that they were really small
plants when I put them in there there
was kind of like last minute kind of
thing I tossed them in um and they just
kind of grew like single stock Bean pole
and threw like little nuggets across the
whole Branch um no sidearms really
because I never really had a chance to
veg out much um so that's why I was
really bu when to get to run him a
second
time sure and and in terms of the uh the
smoke you know you said it was good
smoke were there any of those four
plants four five plants of the Hindu um
when you smoked them was there anything
about them that reminded you of the OG
or the TK or do you think maybe the end
product is more reflective of the
Emerald
Triangle um it's hard to say it was a uh
the Emerald Triangle had kind of like a
much thicker structure and we we would
top those and the way we grew was off
the ground um I I'll get into that real
quick the way the room was set up so
this this I think it was brought from
Washington also this blueprint of how we
did everything with stolen power and a 5
ton AC with 12 lights that particular
nutrient brand and everything so we
would get into a garage you know these
guys did anyway I helped a couple later
on but they would go into a clear garage
um clean it out and then run a hose
across the floor and find where the
water would puddle the most and then
that's where they would drill like a
half inch hole would go through the slab
of the house to the ground and it would
do like 12 or so holes in the room so
basically once you set up the room the
plants are grow on the ground and they
would do drip to waste and the water
would find its way to those holes and
that's basically how these room set up
so off the ground um basically well
first off they would set up
three um garbage cans where like the
stations with like a big Pickle Barrel
where they would feed from and each one
controlled 100 plants on the ground and
there was a divider wall where the the
barrels were and like the hose and
everything was usually where the garage
door was we build like a little divider
wall and then beyond that was where the
grow room was so those three um barrels
would control 300 plants that would sit
on the ground in rows in one gallon pots
in clay Pebbles and we used to use these
little skinny like black drippers um
like a little spaghetti dripper they
call it about then and we used to use
common Home Depot timers like hardware
store timers and run them at like every
two hours for like one or two minutes I
want to say so that's basically was the
dripping the water the watering system
the lighting we used to have these round
um Chinese hat style hoods and you put
them together and they end up being like
four feet around and they had vertical
lighting by then in those so we had
checkerboard highlight sodium um in
those lights and they're super
lightweight and you can control them
from a single string so what we would do
is at the doorway of the garage um we'd
have these like dock cleat where you
could tie off to and each light had its
own little pulley attached to the
ceiling and so once we built the trellis
in the room um you could control all the
lights like height and low or whatever
from the doorway and basically that's
how the lights were set up we had like
two D minifiers up pie on the wall where
the water just ran to the floor and we
had a 5 ton AC and all this needed extra
power so back then obviously everyone
was stealing power like it was no big
deal which was sketchy in itself because
everybody knew that if you got caught
just doing that you're facing some sort
of federal felony by the power company
and um they could you know cuu and all
this stuff so that that part Al was
sketchy but uh you could do 12 lights in
Florida back then without stolen power
unless you had like a
mansion wow that's that's really
interesting I mean gosh a lot I'm sure
it's well thought out when you had those
holes on the ground and the plants were
on the ground did it not get like really
cold uh I'm sure it did but you know it
was Florida um so we like I said it was
that was South Florida and it was hotter
down there than than other places I've
grown but um I don't seem to remember
any issues all the Bates turn out pretty
good in there and like the weed was
always fire um as far as temp and I
could see if you're up like in Northern
like New York or up north that would
probably be too cold on the ground you
almost have to add heating or something
to to the floor if you did it that way
but Florida we didn't have that problem
um and and going back to that room we
didn't quite finish the trellis
basically we would put these first
strips of wood around the entire room
two different levels and go around and
attach little eye hooklets every like
foot or so and then it would take two
people we go in a room while the plants
were small and have a roll of twine we
would toss back and forth with each
other and like Loop through the IH
hookus and make like a weave trellis
basically and we work our way and the
two weave all the way out to the door it
took a while but once we got to the door
that was like the last time you could
get in the room basically so once you
got it all trell off so I mentioned that
before in the past about the homemade
trell weed to do because you could buy
trellis back then um so basically this
whole 12 light room was completely
trellised off with two layers of Nets
you know and then they didn't come down
until Harvest basically that's a cool
setup gosh you got me thinking I could
probably integrate some of these
practices into my
gr as far as the veg back then what we
did was uh we would take clones into one
inch cubes it was ruckles already around
in the 80s um so we would put them in
one inch cubes they would take like 400
at a time to get 300 good ones and then
they would go in a 3in cube with holes
in them and then from there we didn't
have grow tables back then so we built
our own um so the mom room was built on
these big wooden grow tables that had
shower liner um on top of it like glued
together to keep the water from leaking
and uh they had like two or three th000
watt lights in that room with big moms
on in containers getting drip drippers
with the Rocks then the small vegro
where the the babies would go into was
like a like a bit probably like a 8 by 4
by8 table they built with wood Lightwood
with sides and they also Ed the shower
liner on that too and they would be on a
tilt and they would put all the the
3inch cubes on there with a th watt over
those and to water them they would just
you know dump water down one side of the
table and it would run down through all
the plants to the other side of the
drain we had so we would get them like
about a foot tall in there pretty much
before they would go into the main room
and that's when they would go into the
one gallon pots with the rocks and the
drippers and they would get pretty good
size in those 3in cubes I mean they'd be
fully white Roots you know busting out
of the bottom of them you know by the
time you put them in the Rocks um so and
then we would start off with the lights
all the way up at the ceiling when we
put first put them in there because back
then there was no dimming or whatever so
we we're using thousand watt lights so
we kept them all the way at the ceiling
and the lights would know work the way
down first week you know slowly bring
them down off the
pulley nice nice and I'd love to ask you
before I forget tell me a bit about um
the Emerald Triangle strain itself you
know I think a lot of people would be
really interested in that one do you did
you see like how would you describe it
was it a Kush type plant was it a more
lanky plant what's your
recollection uh well the first time I I
used to buy it before I seen it growing
for a couple years so I know it was
around before I ever seen the grow um
these guys were growing probably think
from like ' 868 s or whatever when that
Guy brought the genetics to Florida um
so that one off the floor off the one
gon pots top of the pot would grow to be
about four foot tall on average maybe a
little bit taller um we topped it and it
would grow four or five heads but there
were thicker stems and definitely way
bigger leaves than any of the triangle
or ogs that I've seen actually I've seen
a couple big leads on some of the ogs
but this these seem to get pretty big
and as far as smell I se remember it
definitely had more of a floral sweet
scent to it it was definitely super good
it had like more of a candy kind of
leaning turs I want to say um and
knowing where it came from you know all
the story since then there's a good
chance it has some Northern Lights in it
because I mean that's the Northwest up
there in Washington we got to give them
props because first off that's where
most of nor lights came from um you know
I've heard multiple stories now
basically that's where they originally
origin from and even Neville supposedly
got a lot of his seeds from there that
he took back to Amsterdam and started
breeding with also um from the Northwest
was uh Emerald Triangle um from auson
and then there's years prior there's
this cryptonite strand here in Florida
that was the rumors uh that the Clone
came from Seattle area as well from like
a scientist that worked at a college
there or something um that was more of
an 80s genetic but uh yeah there's
definitely been a lot of stuff coming
from that zone between there and Santa
Cruz and their triangle of California
that whole Pacific Northwest out there
you definitely got to give him credit
for a lot of the stuff a lot of it went
full circle to Amsterdam to Florida and
back and whatever um but the perfect
salad came together in the house that we
were
growing yeah no huge credit to the
Pacific Northwest they they've done a
lot some of my favorite strains like the
blue meoo come from that area so huge
huge work done there by those guys I
guess I'd be interested in terms of the
Emerald Triangle itself if you had to
pick do you feel like the OG and the TK
lean more towards the Emerald Triangle
maybe the Hindu or like some sort of
unique combo of the two that's not
necessarily like one or the
other H it's definitely a mix because
the emerald definitely wasn't making
like popcorn nuggets I don't remember it
was more like Spears like bigger spear
Buds and like I said it definitely was a
bigger yielder and and definitely bigger
stems I remember we used to have to use
like um yard loppers to cut them down
they get so fat you know versus like the
TKA and the OG you can cut them down
almost almost with scissors at times um
so there's that it definitely made
bigger leaves because it was actually
some of the bigger leaves I remember
seeing at the time growing at all stuff
we were growing at that particular
moment or air um but like yeah I really
can't say as far as like the gassy notes
I can't I don't remember it having too
much gas to it now the the Hindu um I
can't remember I can't pinpoint if those
were gassy or not either but they are
extremely different than anything we had
or smoked before um so you know the the
fact that I I kind of Point towards
those is because like years later in the
last few years there's a lot of
information came out from like Neville
himself and other people um that have
claimed that his Hindu Kush work was
basically nl2 cross with Kush 4 I've
heard a couple other different stories
too too but they always included
Northern life Tye genetics so there's
that yeah yeah I I've heard some of
those comments as well so you know I
think that's reasonable I'd be
interested to know so when you did this
crop was it basically like a room full
of Emerald Triangle plus these Hindu
plants or is were there other plants in
the room like were you doing a mix sort
of thing or how was the
setup we try to do one main genetic at a
time for whatever reason I think just
based on how big our moms were that we
had and we only had limited space and uh
this group of guys would pass genetics
around the tribe between us and we would
grow out two or three big moms of them
and then that would be the one that we
would take clowns off of for example so
for whatever reason that room I did was
all Emerald Triangle it was like 300
anal triangle plants and then those five
or six uh hinges ah interesting okay so
when you got to the end of the Harvest
and you're seeing there's these seeds in
the bud were there enough seeds that you
thought oh this is going to to affect
the ticket or was it like you know you
couldn't really tell unless you cracked
it open and did you pop any of those
seeds um it definitely affected the
ticket and the owner of the house my
partner he was definitely pissed off at
first um because in his mind we were
taking away tons of weight from the
plants focusing on energy towards making
seeds so he always had this set thing in
his mind where he had to get at least
you know like 24 PBS per room two pounds
per light or he was pissed off type
thing and I think that room ended up
being the like 20 pounds or whatever I
want to say um so yeah he was pissed but
at the same time I sold it all
immediately to my buddy Craig up in
Orlando and to my buddy Mike Luke up in
that same area too and uh so luckily
that's who got those because was Craig's
friends that would end up finding the TK
and the ogc later
on yeah okay I mean I want to hear about
that but I want to quickly ask did you
pop any of those seeds immediately or
did you sort of just put it on the back
burner and then yeah tell tell us a bit
about how the weed went from there and
where the seeds ended up
going I personally didn't pop a lot of
those seeds a lot of those seeds end up
going into that cook pan like I talked
about I collected thousands of them and
I had like this huge ziplock baggy of
them um I never had a chance to pop many
of them because like I said they got
tossed out a couple years later um I had
a few friends that tried popping some
here and there I don't remember anything
that came out like super keeper style
we've you know seen some stuff that had
similar structure maybe to the OG and TP
like round popcorn like a acorn shaped
like clumpy nuggets you know dra up the
main shaft and had that same pushy look
to it but definitely wasn't like super
dank like some of the stuff we already
had at the time also there was a well
there was another strain I'll get into
that story as well but there was another
strain that came into our group called
The Hatch plant and went by um so
basically this was like a couple years
later it's like 93
94 um so a friend of mine one day called
me up and he's telling me he has this
plan at his house that his [__]
girlfriend wanted out of there
immediately so he like asked me to come
over and get it if I would um I guess he
knew I agree with the time it's kind of
reason why he asked so I went over there
his place it was this little ceiling
that was probably like six inches tall
and like a solo cup so I took it and he
swore that it came from some of the best
weed he's ever seen in his life some of
the stinkiest [__] ever and I had to try
it I had to make sure I didn't kill it
whatever so I took good care of it for a
minute I took it to my friend's house
that Grove at this point in time I had
moved on I was doing my own thing and
and like we stopped doing the
partnership thing together but I was
still helping them do the triming and
helping them sell the weed so I took
this plan over there um to his place and
I set it off the side in the mom room
and I came back a couple days later and
it was gone and I asked him like where I
went he said he tossed it in the trash
because it had this like mutated looking
leaf and he usually thought that this
kind of SE linges were [__] so he didn't
want it anymore so he's threw the trash
on me so I go to the trash which had
like the lid was half open still and
there's like light getting in there and
I pull it out it's still alive it's like
trying to grow through some debris in
the trash can I take it home with me and
it did have a weird Lea but I nurs it
back to heal to where it started growing
normal leaves again uh so at this place
in point in time I had two lights at
this house I lived in and it was just
more for like Hobby and personal stash
and facing bills and once that plant got
big enough to take enough clones to fill
the two lights up with I flowered It Out
by itself and it ended up being some
super stinky like really really good
weed just like the guy said um but it
made its own seeds for whatever reason
there was no other plants there that did
it there was no light leaks nothing um
it made you know probably 10 20 seeds
per plant or whatever it was small
amount and uh those seeds would go on
the be some of the stinkiest best weed I
have ever seen to this day and I would
literally almost like trade my truck
right now on heartbeat for anyone one of
those that we had that's how good they
were um I know we're jumping around all
over the place time time frame whatever
but just going talking about met here um
so anyway that that particular variety
we never ran in the big rooms because we
knew it made seeds but I kept it around
anyways for personal and those seeds
from that for whatever reason I decided
to start popping um once I bought my own
house like a year later 20 or no
1994 U I bought my own house up in
Jupiter and we started going through
those seeds and it took a long time to
realize it and we named a bunch of them
with numbers it was like HP4 and nine
and a bunch of different numbers and
pass them around and like some of the
best stuff they ever the number four was
this like skinny Leaf Jagged sharp edge
with like leaves almost like razor sharp
almost like a soft tooth or something um
and I've never seen plant with like that
before and that was the best one of them
all and it happened to be the one that
got some sort of virus like within a
year or two and died off unfortunately
um that was my favorite um there's three
or four others that went on to be like
extremely stinky and good that like
people would grow it and almost almost I
like run with the law immediately
because it was just so strong so come to
find out years later I ran into the guy
that the original seat came from and he
we were at a strip club one I we're
drinking out conversation about this
stuff told him a story about that
seeding he laughed he's like you know
what that was from a super skunk cross
with a hatch plant that made its own
seeds for some reason the room made a
few seeds and like that's where your
buddy found that seed from so yeah it
was actually Super Skunk cross with
hashplant I don't know where the seed
came from he didn't know where it came
from but everything that that those
seeds you know almost everything we
popped out of those seeds whereas like
keeper style there's probably a hand
that weren't but like the majority of
the ones we kept were just some of the
alltime my alltime favorites um and
there might be one still around this day
that somebody made seeds with I'm trying
to track down and uh we just had a hard
time finding us so far yeah shout out
get in touch with Marty if you know
anything that sounds cool
man so I I mean I'd love to know what
was the path from you know the point of
your first sale to I believe you said
Craig and another guy how did that then
transition into having t the OG to the
best of your
knowledge well uh that seated B ofo
triangle that happened in 1991 that was
the year I was living on that house um
and at that point Craig was coming down
and getting stuff from me directly and
or I would bring up stuff to him
sometimes maybe few mon five or 10 pack
on the front if he didn't have the cash
for it and we had a working relationship
like that um so at some point in time he
got a hold of like 10 of those seated
pounds took him back up there and his
dad at the time was helping him sell the
weed his dad had a karate studio in a
surf shop and had a lot of clientele and
Surfer friends that smoked so they had a
lot of people they sold to um so they
sold you know three four pounds every
couple days basically piecing them out
so they would go through a 10 pack in a
week or two weeks pretty fast that then
um so it was out of that batch that
Craig um had sold to his good friend who
I met a couple times over the years and
he's the guy that found the TK and
another guy was Alec Anderson which I
never met him back in the day but or
never heard of him really until recently
but um he also had bought a quarter
pound the other guy bought like a pound
or a couple pounds of it and found a
bunch of seeds the guy Alec Anderson
only found one or two seeds from like
four ounces um so the other guy was one
that found the TK um he's the one that
first told us many many years ago like
mid 90s that like he got a hold of Craig
and like hey I found this killer seed in
that batch of ammo triangle that you
guys had years ago a couple years ago
and popped a couple seeds out of it and
I found this super keeper you guys
should check out and that was around the
time that he had brought Craig a fresh
plant of it that was like just cut down
shoved into a brown bag like took a
couple these off it but there's like
stem and everything was in there and I
drove up from Jupiter where I was living
at the time like an hour drive and went
to Craig's house and basically thinking
I was going to get some weed to smoke
and it was this wet plant we could we
had to split up and like dry it out
ourselves and smoke it so his whole
theory was we'll give you a quarter
pound we'll dry out to an ounce and uh
me and me and Craig shared it and split
it and it ended up just being fire
regardless I was smoking on it when it
was still wet like little little hits of
it in the bong and it was just so tasty
um and we knew right away we had to have
it but he told us right away that it was
it was super skin skinny growing it
didn't make much and I don't expect much
of a yield from it type thing so that's
we went into it looking at like that um
so shortly after that happened he had
brought Craig some clones of it and I
drove up to grab some um and I met the
guy at Craig house a couple times he
stood out to me then because he was he
was a tattoo artist and he actually
worked in Orlando at then cornbread
cornbread Ricky tattoo parlor out there
in Orlando um which I never met those
guys till years later but I met this guy
that found the TK seed and he was a
tattoo artist and basically that's I met
him at Craigs house multiple times and
stood out to me so later when all this
stuff came out five years ago um Craig
and I started talking and at first Craig
had all totally forgot that it was that
guy and he was for some reason thinking
it was Alec Anderson that gave us our
cut which I had never even met Alec so I
had to like refresh his memory and
immediately he you know he thought back
and like felt like an idiot because I
think he went public a couple times and
told people came from
the triangle but it wasn't um so yeah he
fixed his he fixed all that his in his
memory bank and we've we've laughed
about it since then and we've gone over
all the stuff but um it was definitely
this other guy who doesn't really want
his name to be told anymore and I guess
you know for whatever reason he's just
kind of to himself and quiet so um yeah
that's how that went yeah wow okay so so
you actually had the the TK quite early
or how how long would it have been after
it was found did you get it
then it was a couple years I think he's
I want to say they found it right
afterwards probably around 92 93 92 or
something um I don't think I got it till
I moved into my house in Jupiter in 94 I
didn't think I got it to like the year
after that so 95 996 I think is when I
got it me and Craig both interesting
okay and then when did you hear about
the this you know the OG Kush found by
Alec
that was many years later that was uh
that wasn't until I created my first
Instagram account it kind of went public
um and at that point I only knew about
the triangle being related to me um and
then my buddy Miami mango made a comment
on his post on Instagram at this point I
was living in Central America kind of
like Lan low had I had an art page
because I was sound art and that was the
only I had on Instagram but then one day
I started getting all these random like
cannabis accounts following me for
whatever reason I had like a 100 new
followers that day I didn't know why
then he goes by Miami mango everyone
knows him as I'm sure you know him as
that too um I grew up with him in South
Florida like going way back to like 11th
grade I've known him that long and we
used to SED each other occasionally here
and there and uh he kind of ousted me on
one of his posts talking about triangle
cush and mentioned my art page on his
weed page and that's where all those
followers came from so that's kind of
how I came out and at first I was a
little bit mad about it you know I was
kind of eggy um didn't really want to be
part of the scene yet didn't really care
for it we were happy Liv in Lan low in
Central America and uh he taught me into
creating an account on Instagram and
like you know joining in with him
whatever and causing a ruckus so that
was when I created Origins DK and that
was the first name I came up with when I
created the account basically um so it
was after that that I started meeting
people through through him for example
he introduced me to JH D and he told me
about this train that Josh D had called
the OG Kush that he thought was very
similar to the triangle Kush and that I
should maybe meet him and see if we
could figure that out so at that point
in time shortly after I created Origins
Josh and I started talking he invited me
and my fiance to California to go visit
his farm in h Santa Barbara So Charlie
after that we did that and that's when I
met Josh and we started trading stories
and um that's about the time I started
seeing seen or hearing podcast with Alec
Anderson and talking about Bubba
bringing the cut out from him out to
Florida from Florida to California to
Josh and you know I did all the research
and talking to Josh back and forth
that's where I learned more and more
about all that um and it wasn't until
even a couple years after all that
before we put more pieces together where
like Alec Anderson finally admitted that
the seed came from us because at first
he was making up different stories
saying that it was a it was a plant that
died and somebody that died that had
plant so he kind of like dead ended the
story there you know and then years
later it came out on another Adam dun
show that Mii mango and my buddy Craig
actually called in on and they started
talking to Alec in person it was the
crippy episode and on that episode Alec
was like oh man I didn't want to say any
names or whatever and I was being
respectful towards you know the surfer
code and basically he admitted that that
seed came from our weed um my weed from
Craig basically back in the day
wow him coming out and and admitting all
that just kind of like put it all you
know that piece of the puzzle together I
already known from from Josh's side of
the story about how um he got the cut
from Matt Bubba Burger who somehow got
it from I think there was a story I
haven't talked too much to Alec but
there's a story on one of the podcast he
talked about where one of his old
roommates had like robbed him at
gunpoint for some of their genetics or
something um and then it was like a
mutual friend of him and B that had
gotten a hold of those genetics or
something like that and so Bubba had
taken him from there um I guess I guess
he was already living in California and
he was teamed up with Josh somehow in
Hollywood in AO and they're growing a
few different things out there but
Bubba's like hey I got these genetics
and Florida Ang go grab that would just
blow the stuff away he was talking about
a fish plant that he had out here so he
came out in Florida and he grabbed a few
cuts of it along with a couple other
things they had here and brought them
back out to their grow and that's how
Josh got a hold of it
and that's where the story started in La
like at that point it was only called
Kush and according to Kenji and be real
and Josh and some of the other people
involved once it made it way out there
it became like super popular because it
was really really good and basically
they started touching Crazy Prices like
talking like $800 an ounce some some uh
predicaments so because of that people
started naming everything Kush seeing if
they can get higher prices stuff
according to Josh and these guys um and
so because of that they had to change
the name and that's when the OG thing
started um OG being for original and
that was Josh and Bubba and Kenji and a
couple other friends and be real is
doing
Bly and like how does it feel to see
like the way these two strains have gone
on to like become like top tier list of
every smoker out there oh it's super
super cool super humbling for sure I get
a lot of people that are super
appreciative of it all I get a lot of
thank yous all the time and um just
really warm welcoming for the most part
you know there's been a couple
characters that I've had some runin with
here and there but for the most part
everyone's been really cool Josh and his
whole pack that I met we've become like
really close friends since then um he
was actually just visiting my place in
Central America last week um and he he
had a place down there as well himself
for
years um for some just random reason he
doesn't even surf but he has this little
house on a beach that me and Craig used
to go to as kids like on our first
couple surf trips and surf this little
random Beach um far from everything and
we used to go there to get away from the
crowds and Josh just so happens to have
a house there so this a weird
coincidence we have a lot in common um
so he was down there with his family and
for his wife's birthday and they visited
all my my little area and basically got
to check out some restaurants I set him
up with and some hotels and stuff so
that was cool yeah shout out Josh D
whenever I've um met him at like events
he's been super nice guy always enjoyed
hanging out with him so definitely
definitely on board with that and I
guess I wanted to quickly ask while
we're on the topic cuz I do want to get
back to the story um you know there's a
myriad of OG kushers that have all come
out since the originals you know like I
guess some of the more famous ones like
you know like the Fire OG the face off
OG sfv do you have any favorites or have
you tried most of these ones and what's
your thoughts do you think like to a
degree some of them are s1's of others
or like where do you see that when I
first met Josh um him and a guy named
Mojave that were at the farm the first
day we met Mojave was actually partners
with Adam D in Amsterdam in their C
company years ago so he's he's like a
wealth of knowledge he's I learned a lot
from him about history and he was
actually part of the uh big holy sir um
strain I want to say his family was so
he knew a lot um that day at the farm uh
basically they were growing all ogs so
that was the first time I ever got to
see OG um Josh OG ghost OG Ryan OG
Marathon OG he had the TK going he had
like a whole two acres of like all OG's
going so I was like a kid in a candy
store that day um so we were walking
around checking them all out and like
basically he had bashes that were like
three four weeks old and then he had
some there were like maybe two three
weeks from being done or something maybe
a little longer so I got to see a couple
different different phases of them as
well but to me first like our our thing
at first was we were trying to figure
out if the triangle and the OG were
basically the same plant that maybe had
mutated over the years this is prior to
the whole Alec thing coming out you know
this five years ago when I first met
Josh and we first started talking so
before I met or talked to Alec um and
you know there was still a lot of like
discrepancies about
which cut was which and a lot of people
seem to think they're the same thing but
in person you can see there's definitely
height differences and I mean they smell
very similar to the to the finger R but
like once they got a little closer to
being done you can see they were
definitely different you can see all the
different variations according to Josh
and Mojave that day they claimed that
there majority of them the good ones all
came from the same cut and were just
renamed over the years and they grew in
different locations and they might have
morphed them a little bit and it be a
little bit different than the original
so that was our first train of thought
um and since then we kind of realized
for sure the TK and the OG are from
different seeds so they're like sisters
um and they definitely if you grow them
side by side they definitely have a lot
of differences to
them so yeah we figured that much out
since then um I haven't grown a whole
lot of them I've grown a handful i've
smoked a lot of them uh unfortunately I
haven't had a large area facility to
like collect and store a bunch of
genetics since all this stuff started
for me like when I first came out of
hiding and was on Instagram I was living
in Central America we had a small place
and then you know I had like a couple
little tiny rooms I was able to do stuff
in down there but taking big risk down
there if you get in trouble obviously um
and we actually had a home invasion down
there too which I'll get it get to
eventually um so yeah there was I
haven't really had a chance to to
properly grow out all the ogs myself
like Josh has um like I was more
familiar obviously with the triangle but
they grow very similar to each other um
very similar structure very similar like
traits and leaf look and stems and
everything they both are a little bit
they like less light than most plants um
so yeah those are things that uh I've
come to learn last few years but about
the ogs and stuff you know are
definitely very similar as far as the
TPA goes um as far as growing most of
them I would love to I'm I'm looking
forward to the day where where Florida
eases up on hom grow and I could have
all the ogs in my collection here and
get to try them all myself but as far as
favorites go that other than the
original OG and the TK I've had a really
good bag of Face Off that was insane um
I've also had some crosses that were
made with that in Costa Rica from C that
I like a lot a couple other ones I had
down there from the archive that were
crosses with his uh this face off Rec
more recently we had a zace we went
through here A bunch of genetics or a
bunch of seeds of it and found some real
nice gasty couple Skittles type ones um
so definitely I like the face off I've
definitely the first time I actually
seen um any of the ogs on that trip I
ran into Josh was actually a San frano
Valley and my friend had in Santa Cruz
which actually reminded me of the
triangle when I first saw it um and I've
smoked Fire OG the marathon
OG um pretty much everything that Josh's
grown I've had and
tried yeah beautiful stuff beautiful
stuff so there you have it friends what
did you think make sure to come back for
part two huge huge huge thank you to
Marty again for taking the time to come
on the show a massive shout out to you
guys for getting to the end we
appreciate you so much just like we
appreciate our incredible sponsors if
you want to help support the show
support our sponsors CT now number one C
Bank in the industry you know them you
love them from all the best breeders the
hottest drops guarantee on satisfaction
not just germination why delay guys I
promise you will be stoked if you get
some seeds from them they only stop the
best in the
game likewise a massive shout out to our
friends at Pulse sensors all the best
and latest sensors in the game including
their New Pulse Hub which integrates all
of their units together to ensure that
your operation is on point producing
bigger yields better turs higher potency
whether you're running a single tent a
single room or a multi-state operation
pulse are here to help you guys get
serious get a
pulse further shout out to coper the
number one leaders in Sustainable
biocontrol Solutions for pests and
disease if you're battling spidermites
please check out the spyx vital sachet I
can't tell you how annoying it is to
have to spread carryer material in your
garden just to get the Predators out
these new sachet circumvent that just
hang the sachet in your crop let the
person millist walk out do the work for
you trust me guys you won't look back if
you give it one go you will see the
quality you will be converted a massive
shout out to copit we appreciate your
support so much these guys are industry
leaders check them
out huge shout out to our friends at
Organics alive number one for powdered
organic fertilizers if you're thinking
about giving Organics a go get on board
their products make it so easy whether
you're in veg transition or Bloom
they've got products that make it easy
to dip your toes in the water likewise
if you're a seasoned veteran of Organics
I promise their products will help take
your next crop to a whole new level
massive shout out to Organics alive they
have some of the best products on the
market really fast release because
they're small particle size you will not
go wrong with Organics alive hit them up
massive shout out and thank
you finally a big shout out to our
friends at dap just a week or two ago
they came out with some new models the
titanium M Series in two different col
you can get yourself the nebul or the
quantium I've been rocking the nebul I
love it guys please give it a go if
you've ever tried a vape and felt like
it didn't hit the way you were looking
for it these ones will truly a game
changer based out of the US owned in the
US dnov truly one of the best vape
companies on the market I really really
love their products and we are super
appreciative of their support massive
shout out to
dyat last but not least massive shout
out to the patreon gang thank you so
much for your support if you want to
help ensure the show continues to happen
please consider checking out
patreon.com theep podcast you will get
Early Access upcoming episodes unheard
exclusive interviews and you go in the
running to win a whole range of Swag
each month we give away genetics
cannabis artwork a whole range of
awesome products all while ensuring the
show continues to happen again a massive
shout out to the patreon gang we love
you so so so much thank you thank you
thank
you that's about it for this one my
friends I will catch you for the next
one thanks so much for hanging out heavy
days signing off from the upside down
Library we'll see
you