foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
welcome to the next episode of the
podcast the Cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts as always you're joined by
your host heavy days here from the
upside down library and we would like to
give a big shout out to our sponsors who
helped make the show happen see it's
here now number one in the industry not
just for genetics but also they're
incredible customer service if you're
not happy at the end of The Grow hit
them up they'll fix you up the only
stock breeders they know and vouch for
and they got all the biggest latest
drops hottest breeders everything you
could want go check them out see it's
here now likewise in order to assess
your genetics and find the best
phenotype you need to have a happy and
healthy garden and in order to do that
we recommend you check out our friends
at coppet biological systems these guys
have all the best predators and seeds in
the game to keep your garden has some
pathogen free ready to give you the best
crop to date check out the spydex vital
or the Appy param both designed for
cannabis environments to help your
plants Thrive and be Pest and pathogen
free copper biological systems shout out
guys
[Music]
likewise shout out to our friends at
promix you know me love and they've
produced great media over the years but
now they've got incredible mycorrhizal
product for you Pro mix connect with the
highest guarantee on viable Spore count
in the game it is the best option check
out Pro mix connector increase resin
increase terpene increased yield
increase everything I don't need to tell
you about mycorizer guys you know it get
the best on the market you won't regret
it premise connect thank you very much
finally huge shout outs to our friends
at Charlie's cannabis
family-owned veteran operated craft
flower everything single Source
production nothing sourced from outside
everything they sell from the pre-rolls
to the flower is absolute top quality
trust me guys you really want to support
a good brand good people behind it
Charlie's kind of get all over it guys
top qualities
and last but not least a huge shout out
to the patreon supporters you guys are
the lifeblood of the show you helped
make episodes happen please go check it
out at patreon.com forward slash the
podcast unheard episodes
exclusive content
check it out
on this episode we're joined by the
crowd favorite
skunk Warrior himself the head honcho of
dominion seed code Duke Diamond VA
[Music]
here to chat genetics plans for the
future what he's been up to
so much more
[Music]
let's get into it
alrighty my friends we are back for
another one and on this one a huge
welcome to the true skunk Commander The
Man Behind Dominion Seed Co Keeper of
the fire a very special man to me indeed
Duke Diamond welcome back on the show my
friend thank you buddy good to be here
as always good to have you on how you
doing today ah man doing squishy no
one's perfect how are you yeah not bad
not bad I um I had like uh the probably
the first dab I've had in probably years
last night and I feel like I have a bong
over so hard right now
that will happen and something oh it's
not going away
yeah like it was good in the moment I
was like oh yeah I'm pretty high again
um but yeah wow I can because it's like
I when it sometimes when you talk to
people who don't smoke weed often they
say that they're like oh the next day
you feel real foggy and it's like I feel
that right now
oh yeah tolerance is good and down but
yeah save a lot of money that way
right and how about yourself have you
been able to partake in anything or you
still need to abstain for a bit yeah
that's why I gotta gotta abstain for the
uh for the time being probably this time
next year I'll be I'll be good to go but
I'm gonna say that tolerance would be
good and new it'll be like the first
time again that's awesome
uh dude I'm I'm jealous I took a
two-week break about a year ago even two
weeks I can only imagine a year is going
to be so good oh man I remember what
happened the last time I got off the
paper and then I went and blazed and uh
[ __ ] before I mean the second Coke out
man I was like I should probably left
that at one holy [ __ ] you know it was
[ __ ] blasted when you when when that
happened last time what was the first
thing you smoked was it something where
you were like oh man I'm just so itching
for this
um well I've done a uh I had an outdoor
and by the time I was chopped and ready
that was about the time when I was off
off the paper and it was uh [ __ ] some
outdoor Jack the Ripper
ah there you go shout out so cool
yeah man he uh I right when I got out he
was like yup you want some beans I was
like yep
so he said I'm on the send them on the
way and back in 48 hours later they were
popped you know [ __ ] um ready to rate
a rock and roll man
beautiful stuff beautiful stuff and if
we sort of fast forward now
is there anything that sort of front
runner in your mind where you're like
once I'm able to that's gonna be the one
I'm hitting first
yeah I've been thinking through it
through my mind and I think
I think it's gonna be some Eagle some
Screaming Eagle
I was thinking like oh it should be some
free bird but yeah
there we go with the eagle though
yeah I I still so fondly remember that
eagle from years ago you I don't know if
they're all like this but the one I
tried from you it was like had that sort
of citrus vibe to it beautiful stuff
yeah it's like that rainbow candy lemony
citrusy type type [ __ ] going on yeah
that was the that's definitely a
dominant one amongst all the all the
olafinos you know
out of curiosity I thought about this
years ago and I was looking at the
genetics and I was like oh man where did
this flavor come from because in my mind
I was like I can't see the clear parent
where it's like oh it's from this what
was it in your mind
um that that purpley candy rainbow type
thing was coming from that from that 88
and then that that citrusy side that was
definitely how the how the Airborne
ah there you go that makes sense because
I don't know why but for the longest
time I thought is this Kandahar got like
something funky going on in it
nah nah that was uh it was like I could
like distinctly face it you know
especially from blazing each one you
know individually I was like yeah you
can it's like the perfect little blend
of you know it's like Harmony symmetry
thing going on I was like wow that was
super cool because that doesn't happen
much where you get you know a good mix
of flavor you know that's very rare
thing and it worked out really good that
way
yeah beautiful stuff beautiful stuff
I guess the first thing to maybe clear
the air although probably everyone's
aware is you recently got out of jail
would you be able to tell us a little
bit more about that if you're willing to
yeah
um
yeah it was a star was down I was you
know it was in the jail for a while
while I was you know going through the
motions and you know fighting [ __ ] and
um
just waiting on them because like
literally everything came to a screech
and halt normally the process like goes
through a whole lot quicker
um because the code that they were
shutting boards down and everything else
so amongst every other thing that was
you know [ __ ] up uh that was that so
stayed uh unusually long time uh there I
think it was
just over a year just just sitting there
in the in that [ __ ] jail
and then uh
once I did that and you know they they
come to you you know you can sign off
they you know whatever guilty so it's
like kind of an option it's like once
they got you there you're not getting
out
um you can either you know take the next
three to five years fighting up spend
[ __ ] tons of money and have your pride
and be like yeah let's see I was right
or you know it's like you're the chances
of winning are not good they have like a
99 conviction rate even if you're right
they're like no you're wrong because uh
we say so so
um you can either do that or you know
you can look at like the time and look
at the maximum that you're that you're
looking at losing so if you're looking
like say 24 to 30 months or something
like that you're like all right two and
a half years and I'm already you know
about a year into it with good timing
everything and I'll be about another
year
um do I do that or do I spend three to
five years on a [ __ ] ton of money stand
here just to lose you know and and that
ensures that hey you're definitely going
to get the high end either way so it's
like you know you got you gotta make
that call you got to put up your fight
you know what I mean let them know like
you know you need business and [ __ ]
um but there comes a point where it's
just you know you're gonna you're gonna
you're not gonna get the fair shake at
it so once I sign off get truck and you
know plead guilty
get sentenced or whatever
um it's 29 months
um so I got like you know a year already
you know knocked off of it you know with
a good time and everything you know it's
like gonna be another year
um so then it's like all right now you
can finally like start your journey at
getting done so I'm gonna throw you on
Con Air you can go to the you know go to
prison
um and there's like an intermediate step
um there's like a Transit Hub in
Oklahoma but they closed it down because
of covid so it was all Maximum Security
State joint that they had closed down
the private Corporation bought it out so
they were just sticking us all there we
were we were doing normally in transit
you're doing like a day to three days
but this turned into many months and uh
that place was just [ __ ] Off the
Chain man and um so then uh once you're
getting shipped out of there you get
back on Conair and then you hit your uh
your final destination which was uh
Florence uh Florence Colorado and
um then you know just wrapped it up
there and uh yeah got out on the eye on
the second
and that was uh it was pretty awesome
pretty awesome and it was good to get to
be back and get a hold of everybody
you know see everybody's gun everybody
hitting you up you know because it's
real nice a lot of a lot of love out
there so it's pretty pretty awesome
thing
yeah that's so fantastic to hear you're
out I'm sure a lot of the community sort
of rallied behind that just to clarify
because I know a lot of people had asked
are you willing to disclose with us why
you ended up going to jail
yeah of course uh yeah I guess telling
you earlier it's like it's free it's on
the internet you read all about it you
know all the all the sentencing [ __ ] and
everything
[Music]
um felling in possession of a firearm
and like some people like why why it's
like straight up you know
um
it's a [ __ ] crazy place
people are shooting up [ __ ] Walmarts
and [ __ ] whacking people in [ __ ]
grocery stores and [ __ ] like that
um
you know I was very adamant I'm not
going to be that guy that's gonna get
[ __ ] shot up I'm not gonna watch a
bunch of you know random people just get
[ __ ] mowed down my family's not going
to get [ __ ] hurt or friends are not
going to get hurt if I'm there and I'm
like you know they'll say anything I'd
rather uh rather get caught with it than
without it unfortunately you know got
caught with it but you know that's the
that's the price price that you pay now
was it a good decision uh I don't know
probably not but that's you know given
the the
for the way the climate was then
um yeah it wasn't it wasn't it was kind
of it's a gamble but at the same note
and [ __ ] was [ __ ] going nuts man so
you know I made my made my decision I
stand by it and uh you know had to go
away do my time and you know I can do
say you know I did my time and walk
around with my with my head up and my
shoulders back you know so
um
can't uh can't make that risk anymore
because then they hit you with like that
repeat repeat offender basically is what
it is so and then that's too much time
to look at you know like you can look at
it like a risk and reward thing and um
yeah that it would just be too much so
uh just have to keep it at uh keep it at
a knife and um just I guess stay away
from Walmart and you know Miss the
civilization I guess if uh you know yeah
world's just yeah world's going crazy
you know just have to you know flip the
tip coin toss and it's like all right
[ __ ] it gotta go to the grocery store
you know
yeah no look that's that's brilliant to
get clarification on that and I think a
lot of people can understand where
you're coming from with that and you
know as you said the world's going crazy
and something I specifically wanted to
ask is you've uh For Better or Worse
been away pretty much all through covert
and I wanted to ask you specifically I
remember seeing some news stories about
how people in jails weren't really being
protected or looked after properly in
regards to covert do you have any sort
of experiences or insights around that
at all
oh yeah
I mean just flat out like you know your
your society's unwanted
um
I mean just cut and dry man they don't
give a [ __ ] about you you can live you
can die they don't care
um you're in human storage
you're just you're there
um not saying that everyone owns a
cold-blooded piece of [ __ ] there are
some caring people but even uh even if
they do
um the rest of that machine isn't going
to cater to that one personally how well
yeah this guy's drowning in his own lung
fluid over here you might want to get
them out like Yeah well yeah we'll we'll
look into it got a pencil amount or
something so yeah Jesus yeah they were
just yeah it was uh it was pretty bad
it's cramming up you know people
together and it's got to the point where
like especially right when it happened
they're just like looking in the units
they don't even want to comment
um it's looking like it's a room full of
zombies you know what I mean so I just
let everything fly and like normally
like there's a big fight or you know
some people stabbing each other they're
gonna run in and stop it not in there it
just is ran ran [ __ ] rampant uh at
first there were times where they
wouldn't even uh feeding us they didn't
even want to come near
um I guess they were just scared
shitless you know about the stuff you
know the thought covered you know
spreading around pretty pretty rapidly
and uh you just had guys trying to look
out for guys to do the best but there's
nothing you can do you know it's not the
extent of it is like try to get them
some water out of a toilet sink to make
sure that at least they got they can
stay hydrated
um there's really not much else and
medications or anything like that so you
just kind of
just watch them die or you know get
really sick and slowly recover and
that's about
it's about the end of that you know
wow it really does sound as Bleak as lot
like what many of the news reports said
yeah it was it was really uh
it was really bad man really really bad
and like you know there'd be a TV on and
the whole time it's on
um they have the [ __ ] death toll
number that's going out throwing up
going up and everybody's just sitting
there thinking like oh [ __ ] you know
this is it you know and here we are
we're stuck in here and there's nothing
nobody can do so uh it was it wasn't
looking good it definitely was not
looking good for for everything and I
was like man you know this can't be this
can't be the slacking out again it can't
go down like this so
um
you know you just uh just kind of you
know cross your fingers and um I feel
the best and hope you don't uh you know
catch that [ __ ] but you you crammed in
so [ __ ] close like in this one unit
there's like 80 [ __ ] people and
there's two toilets too [ __ ] tall
it's one for pissing and one from [ __ ]
and there's nothing around them they're
just like kind of just sitting in the
middle of the floor and there there's
industrial ones you know so hit the butt
it shoots a huge aerosol effect up in
the air so that's spreading [ __ ]
um
there's no soap available you know like
to give to you so people that got no
money or whatever they can't even afford
to get some soap to take a shower let
alone wash your hands so it was just
filthy filthy [ __ ] place too so it
was like well you know it's definitely
definitely not looking good uh I didn't
end up uh I didn't end up catching it I
was thinking thinking like you know as
all them years being like Emerald cup
and everything and that [ __ ]
walkthrough that would go around every
year I think like and build up some type
of super immunity or some [ __ ] like I
didn't uh thank God you know
who would have thought all those years
of hitting random joints and blunts
might have paid off for the Cannabis
Community it might have man it might
have I don't know about everybody else
but yeah yeah I thought about I was like
you know I've been exposed to a lot of
[ __ ] up [ __ ] man so maybe my immune
system would stay Rock Solid and I won't
uh I won't get this [ __ ]
yeah we look very happy to hear you you
didn't end up uh Contracting it yourself
you know it's sort of funny you
mentioned that because when when like
sort of in the early stages of when
covert came out a research paper came
out from China which basically showed
that people who smoke cigarettes are at
a reduced chance of Contracting the
virus and I won't go too much into the
details but basically one of the
receptors in your lungs gets down
regulated from smoking cigarettes and
that's the same receptor the virus uses
to enter the cells
and there was a lot of controversy
around like do we announce this because
we're worried you know is everyone going
to start smoking to a point yeah I'm
gonna stay in this this Public Health
Service Announcement sponsored though
Philip Morris sponsored by Philip Morris
yeah
oh good stuff good stuff well I mean
look obviously having never experienced
it myself I said this with a grain of
salt but I'm sure there's rarely uh an
abundance of overwhelmingly positive
things to occur from being in jail but I
was wanting to ask you did you have any
sort of Revelations or insights is is
there any sort of new views on life you
feel like you've sort of developed since
having had this experience and now being
free
um
not like the first time
because after the first time yeah
definitely you know
um get all that self reflection time and
see things do things and then you get
out and you know everything smells
better tastes sweeter you know all that
good stuff
um so I already had that and that never
that never went away
um
out of it you know I've always tried to
you know make the best of every day no
matter what I'm doing or where I'm at
um and I just took the time to uh come
up with ideas and I was doing a lot of
writing at night time when it was uh
doors locked and it's safe and quiet and
you're able to you know concentrate and
uh yeah I was working on working on
writing a book and
um like I said this coming up with the
what's a good good solid uh game plan
though so when I hit hit back home you
know I could I could hit the ground
running and everything
um and just like on the last bit
um it's it's the same anybody that ever
gets locked up and got us on the same
thing you really get to see who's with
you and who ain't with you right and um
you know it's it's the same every time
you know I got to see that on the last
one when I got to see it on this one too
so it was good to like you know you see
where people really stand people are
like really really with you in a ride or
die [ __ ]
um they're gonna be there
um people that are against you
um you know of course they're gonna take
those opportunities to hate or [ __ ] [ __ ]
or whatever and then you're gonna have
people that you thought were gonna be
there that end up not being there so a
lot of people say
you know it's a bummer you know and yeah
it is it's like it's bad don't get me
wrong like the you know it's hurtful
right but at the end of the day it's
like well [ __ ] imagine going through
life
uh with people that you think are like
that just to find out that they're not
way later down the road and um I'm
always I'm I'm actually you know I'm a
thankful thankful person just it's good
to know you know so that way when I do
move on like I you know I know who's who
and that's that's a great that's a great
[ __ ] thing so out of all of it yeah
just you know the time management coming
up with you know things to do and then
um you know there's a little working out
you know the normal normal [ __ ] you know
but
um writing that was cool and just uh you
know seeing like you know some real got
some real solid [ __ ] uh in my
corner you know
yeah so many uh relevant topics you just
touched on will come back and touch on
some of them other other ones shortly
but I did want to follow up quickly on
your book I think you really generated a
bit of a buzz because many people like
myself have seen you know little bits
and tibbards of the book come out
through you know maybe you've posted a
soil mix here maybe you've posted or
something else there
when do you anticipate it might be
finished and what sort of things can
people hope to learn from this book
wow I hate to put a timeline on it
because like it's all written you know
and I gotta tape it up
my spelling is just atrocious man like
I'm just horrible there's so many
grammatical errors I'm sure like so
um
I'm guessing you know like between Titan
and all back up fixing all that
um continuing to add to it because there
was like some a lot of things I didn't
have access to some art supplies so
there's a lot of things I wanted to draw
you remember my old sketches and
everything I would draw up when I
include stuff like that good charts and
like things that I really need access
like printer and you know a computer to
to do certain charts and things like
that because it's like a big it's a
reference type thing it's a how-to plus
plus a reference so you got to put all
that together and then you've got to uh
you know have somebody look at it you
know last you know outside eyes do any
you know editing needed after that then
go through to the Republicans um and I
couldn't couldn't put a definitive
timeline on it but what people can look
out of it is like if you were and maybe
not necessarily new to Growing but
you're setting up a new spot
um you know guiding people through
literally setting up the space just to
begin with plumbing electrical teaching
a little bit of electrical electrical
Theory like things safety
um you know so it's like if you gotta
delve into some electrical you can go to
that and if you're comfortable with it
then by all means you can you can go
ahead and do it or if you just want to
know you got your friend doing it that's
cool too but literally setting up the
space for Success before you even get
started because so many people would
just jump right into a space and start
duct tape and super glue and velcro and
all around them and then they're
struggling the whole time and you never
catch up because they didn't you know do
the important thing first get the space
straight the Environment Straight
um yeah soil mixes
um a couple of different regimens that
people could choose from depending on
your you know what's in your pocket
availability you can mix and match
whatever but trying to keep it very
definitive like
this isn't like you know if you're
reading this it's like just do this do
this do this do this do it this way do
it just don't mediate from it after you
do it then at least you got you got a
good you know Baseline of you know
success so if you do said okay well I
want to try this try that you can do
that but at least you know like hey this
did better this did work you at least
have your Baseline so it's good for the
like so the new the new person wanting
to want to get into their Organics and
everything plus like a lot of references
and [ __ ] like that to you know
um you know like a metric metric
conversion tables and stuff like that
that you know it comes in handy I mean
we all got smartphones and [ __ ] like
that but sometimes it's good just to
have it having a book real quick where
you can just highlight it or go right
back to it and in a nutshell that's it I
was gonna do include some of the other
writing I did with it but I think this
is too much so we'll just keep that as
one thing and then the other book just
keep that as uh you know a book all the
time
uh when you say writings what sort of
writings are we we're talking like
uniboma Manifesto type stuff
[Laughter]
no man just uh personal personal stories
um things like that
um my thoughts you know thoughts and you
know [ __ ] about uh you know variety
variety of different things
the world scene through you know another
another set of eyes and a crazy brain I
guess
I love it like the the modern day Marcus
Aurelius meditations that sounds sounds
good and I I want to put it out there
now so everyone knows I officially call
dibs on editing the book
oh man you be my editor
we gotta do it do it like
you know like it's cool because like I
still use like in uh color and favorite
and stuff like that so it's cool because
I think y'all still do that over there
too so it'll work out
sounds good sounds good one of the fans
submitted questions we got was they sort
of wanted to know first of all was it
going to be a more general or a specific
book about growing and you sort of
answer it's going to be more General
it's going to be like laying out all the
options and people choose their own path
but one question that did get asked was
for some of your more notable strains
particularly uh people were asking about
the hoodoo I think that's just become a
really popular one will you maybe
provide like a specifically dialed in
sort of info page or you just want to
keep it quite Broad
um yeah with something like a book like
that you kind of you kind of gotta keep
it broad but with with every pack that
they got there were like specific
tidbits always on the back of every pack
like what to do week to week
um if you needed to supplement more or
less or something
um so they can kind of you know if they
just if you were to stick to like the
Baseline of like Tom growing in this
book and it's not going to deviate from
what I'm I'm personally doing so if a
person isn't deviating from that your
environments you know in the in this you
know span of acceptable
um the same as mine ultimately at the
end if you do everything as as said me
and this other person we should have the
same result
so anything in detail that I would write
about it was already you know it was
already on the back of that back of that
card
yeah certainly I I think that's one of
the things people view you as notable
for was giving that really sort of
in-depth information around the
cultivars well the final sort of uh fan
submitted question we got around this
topic was they sort of asked the
question of along the lines of like you
know there's so many different ways you
can skin a cat in relation to Growing
organically they were just sort of
wondering obviously you've got your own
style do you have any thoughts on the
alternative styles of growing like you
know I know that you don't do like a
pure no-till thing but you do obviously
do organic amended bases do you have any
thoughts on the other styles or do you
think it's just personal preference sort
of thing
um personal preference and like what
works for you
um you know I've I've just like I said
whatever person wants to do
um by all means like whatever works for
you and your space on your budget like
no two people are exactly the same so
like let us know I like the way
the way I do it and I've tried you know
different other ways
felt that for my space and my style and
you know what what I was doing was
working best for me
um
so like and that's that's the thing is
like there's like so many ways it's
gonna cut and a lot of people will get
info from here and info from there and
they kind of muddle it up and sometimes
it runs them into a uh into a jam so
that's why I was like I wanted just to
keep it very definitively and like the
differences is like like I'm talking
about different different approaches to
it and when I say different approaches
it might just be you know here's here's
a regimen but the alternative to that if
you don't have any money you know you
can do this and and still get to that
same same part and even alternatively to
that if it's a dire emergency and you
know it's going to be more with um you
know fixing problems it's like here's a
source of this that you can go to that
could be found at a at a grocery store
you know what I mean
um things things like that put on
MacGyver [ __ ]
yeah that's going to be very helpful I
think because a lot of people will find
them in those situations
but we do I think one of the it's sort
of an obvious question to us but I I
want to ask in a sense is you know
people are also curious on top of my own
interest do you plan in the future to
return to your breeding to get Dominion
back up and running or do you plan to do
things slightly different to how they
were before you left when the time's
right that is
yeah yeah exactly and you know when the
time's right yeah Full Speed Ahead
um yeah it's just
the same thing
um
you know just uh taking my time through
it and not being in a rush and putting
out but not good work for people
um
you know and I got a lot of other like
you you've already heard you know I got
a lot of other projects like that both
uh you even inspired me I'm gonna do my
own little podcast but it's gonna be
different yeah it's gonna be way way
different uh type approach and
everything and it's not going to be 100
um Hannah based you know what I mean so
um I just know you know I met a lot of
interesting I know a lot of interesting
little people and talk about different
[ __ ] because like
we're all into all types of different
stuff it's like that the scene or
industry or whatever you're into it's
like people just look down like tunnel
vision like oh that's all this person
does like well no like I had so many
other things surrounding this in my life
that you know I like to do and stuff and
like you know you know me so
um you know I'm into all types of cool
different little hobbies and [ __ ] like
that interesting fun stuff and uh I
think a lot of other people are too so
um it's just that while we're talking
about something we're really passionate
about that's all it really gets brought
up you know but once you really get to
talking and knowing somebody you might
find out you know and then we're a
professional bass fisherman or whatever
you just you never know so
um from biochemist uh you know I can all
man they'll just have to you know and uh
keep it suspenseful
that's exciting do you have do you plan
to just sort of some point in the future
or any sort of plans specifically yeah
yeah here in the near future I'm gonna
start working on it but I'm gonna Jam a
few out before I ever start
putting them out that way I don't I
don't miss any like lapses so that way
every week you know people can look
forward to it being there you know
maybe a follow-up question to the
breeding one a lot of people were
interested do you have access to you
know some of the old genetics some of
the old seeds some of the old clones or
do you envision that when you do get
things back up and running it'll be sort
of a fresh start so to speak
um a little bit though so like I still
have all everything I had
um backed up so you know and I and I did
it in a Fail-Safe fashion too so it's
like in two places so if anything
happens one the other one the other one
had it you know and because you know
life happens [ __ ] happens especially
when you eat regular right so
um yeah man so you know I still have all
all that all that stuff to you know
continue any future work along lines I
might have already dealt that too to
continue on I had a bunch of projects
that I had to put on hold that a lot of
final steps were done and it was ready
for that that final that final thing so
um you know we uh
I don't know man like it's just
I got a lot of plans man and you know me
I don't I don't like to uh I don't like
to give too much out I want to show my
hand too early
you know it is you know how it is out
there man like people are uh always
looking to copy or empty rip off or
whatever so um there's gonna be some
there's gonna be somebody some new
things
I don't know how to yeah say it without
giving away so
you don't have to wait and see
here I mean on that train of thought I
think there's probably a lot of people
who in the community have been sitting
on some of your packs for a while and
I'm wondering do you have any
recommendations for people you know like
if they're sitting on a certain thing
like oh man you should really pop that
one
um that was the thing like you know if
you ever came to a show or
talk to me personally I'm like well
and what should I get I'm gonna say well
what do you need like what are you
lacking in life what are you what are
you looking for you know and I'd go from
there it was a medical necessity or a
certain smell of taste you're looking
for or you know and go from there so I
would say just uh you know dead pretty I
did a pretty good job on descriptions
and everything so
um
kind of just look at and see what you
what you what you what you want uh what
what you're lacking in life and
um and you know just go from there I
would say like if you just been sitting
on them for a real long time
um maybe get if you got one that's like
real old maybe get those get those pop
in first because they're not getting any
younger but outside of that man just uh
just stick with uh stick with your gut
what you're what you're wanting or what
you want or need right now because
obviously they bought them for some some
kind of reason you know
yeah definitely and look you gave me a
great segue there because specifically
obviously all of the Dominion releases
have been very successful but
specifically I've had a lot of people
message me and tell me that they've
found some gold and stuff out of there
the Vault series and I guess I'm
wondering do you have any future plans
for sort of some Vault stuff to or do
you think it'll be more like the
stricter minion stuff going forward
the I mean that could happen again but a
lot of the Vault stuff was like you had
things that may have been intended like
all right you know I want to try to do
this I want to I want to work this line
or whatever and then you go and you try
it out you make you make a hybrid you're
gonna find a meal out there you're going
to go to the next step make the next
step you grow them out you're like wow
that totally did not work out at all
however the original hybrid that she
made for that male the female's [ __ ]
name right so it's it's like well
they're not gonna do anything else that
project it's not going to move forward
any anymore but this [ __ ] all all aside
was awesome so you know let's go ahead
and let some let some people people
enjoy that so that was kind of the whole
the whole thing with that
yeah definitely I know specifically
something I wanted to ask you and I
think I already know the answer so I'm a
I'm sort of cheating myself here but I
remember you made some hybrids with um
specifically you did the Eugenics male
to the skunk Northern Lights five
females yeah oh my God that um that that
female like because I found a clone in
those seeds and in my opinion it was one
of my best clones for ages and sadly I
lost it when I was moving but I just
thought man if there's ever another
chance for me to find like a Fino like
that I would jump on it do you have
access to that sort of plant anymore or
is it is it gone
um yeah like I've given some seeds to a
friend that said they had a bunch of
bunch of stuff in mine and um they do so
when uh when I get around to him I got a
[ __ ] Amish buddy he loves that [ __ ]
too it was a long story like Bagon was
working at a steel mill in Pennsylvania
and
he was getting a weed out of this this
bar and [ __ ] so ever since Sunday's been
kind of stuck on it so
um when I get to those I have to make
sure that uh oh Queen's mail uh
it finds it finds their way to you
uh look you're you're too kind you're
you're too kind I don't know why this
jumped into my head but for some reason
it did when you were sort of talking
about where you've been in the past I
was wondering I'm not sure if you've
been like 100 up to date with it all but
uh you know did you have any thoughts on
the progression of the medical cannabis
laws around Virginia you know because a
lot of people have been excited about
that since it's happened and I was
wondering what's your thoughts
oh man it's uh super awesome what's
going on there
um I would say like just the biggest
biggest thing I can say to him is like
you fought hard to get it there don't
stop fighting because just look at the
history of every other state
we'll look at the progression of how how
they work it's basically the corporate
and government
game plan you know they want to
so just look at the mistakes of everyone
before you right and uh you know fight
fight like that plan you know don't
don't let them take that from you it's
hard to get there don't let them take it
from you through the guys of you know
different wreck laws and [ __ ] like that
um they put a law in front of you like
don't don't decide oh yeah that sounds
great read the whole [ __ ] thing read
the fine print the devil's in the
details so you know the second you
forget history like that's when [ __ ]
starts to repeat itself so just stay
very adamant stay very Vigilant and you
know keep it keep it strong you know I
know I know how my Bros sisters are out
in uh Virginia they they're a Rowdy
[ __ ] Bunch man so uh you know they
ain't gonna let nothing go easily just
you know stay stay vigilant and uh don't
don't let them take [ __ ]
some brilliant words of encouragement
there and I guess there's a follow-up do
you see a time when you might head back
to Virginia to do your breeding work or
the law is just not quite where they
need to be to allow that yet yeah it's
it's it would still be a little too
early on but I I saw like
um the mode of action and like how how
things are supposed to be implemented so
like it's gonna be a couple years down
the road before it's there but I'll
definitely be back there just just
hanging out and you know
just you know making trips and
everything but before I get a get to
move back to the motherland uh yeah it's
gonna be a couple years before it's
for its proper ready
yeah sure I mean if we look at
California under the same sort of lens
and sort of analyzing the legislation
they've brought in a lot of people have
been critical of 215 including myself
I'm sure yourself for like a long time
in California
and recently uh had Ed Rosenthal on the
show and he he made an interesting point
where he said look you know could the
laws be better sure but at the end of
the day if you're keeping people out of
jail for cannabis that's a net win no
matter how much it could be improved
that you have to view it as a net win
that we're keeping people out of jail
for cannabis and I thought given your
recent sort of you know uh departure
from jail would you say that this is you
know as much as it might be a bit of
taste in people's mouth because there's
a lot of people who don't like the way
their business has been affected because
of it would you agree with Ed Rosenthal
in that sense in saying that keeping
people out of jail should probably be
the number one priority
um yeah of course because like
you're saying
the words legal
recreationally legal like the word legal
how in the [ __ ] is anybody going to jail
or something they call Legal you know
what I mean like that's that's kind of
absurd to me so yeah like yeah people
definitely shouldn't be uh couldn't be
getting hauled off for it
um does it does that happen you know
yeah absolutely you know so um
and you know maybe it's changed since
they first implemented it but um like
sun Grand mids and a few other guys that
are like real Savvy with everything
going on these laws and everything they
were like my go-to's and since I didn't
live in the state either
um you know I'm I'm only gonna know what
you know what's being shown to me and
you know sold to me
and um you know when they had met or
whatever
um I guess like when they went rack like
some of the penalties or certain things
change and it was it was worse
right than it was beforehand so you know
I um I don't know if that was in the
proposal or if that's actually what went
through it was a long time ago but I
thought that you know I was like hey
let's kind of kind of [ __ ] up man and
how is it going to be legal and still
like somebody's gonna go to the good of
the [ __ ] joint over it like [ __ ] up
you know
yeah I mean you raise a brilliant point
there you know it's almost a
contradiction right the fact is legal
but people still go to jail especially
when you think about the the Sackler
family the the guys who put out what is
like oxy and stuff and it's like those
[ __ ] aren't going to jail and
yet people with a few pounds a few
plants over that yeah it's it's such a
contradictory isn't it yeah yeah big big
time man so
um so yeah like yeah I definitely
believe like nobody should be passed
down over over a plan like if you want
to like make the argument like well
they're non-regulated grower and they're
growing and doing all this well I don't
I don't see that as a crime like
you know but if they want to like you
know further it and say well the reason
why is like dude was making a million
dollars and not paying it back so okay
not paying taxes on Revenue okay cool
right of course like dude broke the law
what whatever but you know everything
before that like if you want to grow a
[ __ ] plant should be able to grow a
[ __ ] plan you know
um
yeah that's just that's just my my
opinion on it you know
no I I think that's that's a very
insightful take for sure another one
that's weird is uh like Washington DC
it's not a state District of Columbia
like where they make the laws and
everything you know that's where the
White House is and all that so since
it's not a state it's governed by
federal law
um so the other argument is like oh you
know and I'm going through that now
that's the reason I can't Blaze I'm a
federal probation so since weeds
federally illegal
um they say it doesn't matter what the
state because the feds are going to
Trump over you know what the state says
so okay so how in the [ __ ]
as we'd still federally illegal when
it's recreationally legal
in Washington DC a land Government
Federal Law they riddle riddle me that
yeah yeah it's very contradictory isn't
it very yeah very very contradictory and
very frustrating you know
think about it you know it's like we're
almost in 2022 and still having that
still having that thought why why
like how like how how is this still
still a thing you know
do you foresee a time in the near future
when you know some of these
inconsistencies get ironed out or do you
think it's just gonna naggle on forever
um I think as long as you got a lot of
a lot of the old guys that are still
hanging in there
um that are influenced by Pharma and
stuff like that lobbyists and everything
special interest groups you're gonna
have a lot of foot Dragon even though if
they know damn right that they're dead
and wrong they're still going to do it
because you know money or promises
whatever and it's going to take a while
because a lot of these guys start
getting out or dying or whatever
um
you know it's weird because like a lot
of the people that are
lawmakers and everything they're like
really old people really old multiple
ways of excuse me old school ways of
thought and they're kind of uh you know
they're kind of [ __ ] up bummer you
know I mean it's like proven fact you
know they take all the special interests
money and stuff and see where they come
from like yeah of course you know like
Mark Pharmaceuticals is like super huge
and you know donating all this money
this person they're very adamant about
like hey you know no I don't think it
should be legal oh why oh well
you know the kids because they're like
oh actually it shows that like you know
the smoke has gone dramatically down the
under eight people blah blah blah and
like there's there's some facts
no no I'm just nah I don't think so all
right because you know as I say so so
yeah maybe next time boys you know that
type of [ __ ]
it's insane isn't it how many people are
Guided by
just feelings or religious views or
contextual Society stuff of like yeah
it's wild yeah yeah it's really uh
really
really insane man especially they keep
people like fitted against each other
all the time too
um you know division you know that's a
good way to to keep doing what you're
doing to keep people divided from coming
together and you know it's
that's a that's an old school trick they
do it every day people still falling for
that [ __ ]
maybe maybe we just need to get our own
kind of us lobbyists and get some equal
representation yeah yeah that would be
that would be cool
um yeah a lot of money for that yeah a
whole lot of money for that we're
talking a lot millions and millions and
millions and millions of dollars that
they're pumping all the time so like you
got to be able to keep up with that
that's a hard thing to do man
yeah it's interesting right because you
sort of painted an actually quite a
clear picture in my mind there where a
lot of people in the community are
really critical of brands that aren't
striving to be the absolute Pinnacle you
know we always hear about how people say
oh if you want to be the Bud Light of
cannabis go for it or whatever and you
sort of just made me realize maybe we do
need more of that so that there are
people who can throw millions of dollars
at lobbyist because maybe maybe that's
what you need like you know the mass
production mid-tier because maybe yeah
like you know maybe jungle boys is never
going to do it themselves
well I think like
that's the thing is like
people automatically associate anybody
doing it big with beds because I mean
you know that
primarily yeah I mean that's that's kind
of how it is that's not to say that
there aren't going to be some people
that come up and just [ __ ] kill it
and do it the right way you know
um
you know and do it and do it without any
like outside like corporate money
there's people that self-start but you
know that's the that's the bad part
about being a slow starter is like you
don't have all these investors you don't
have a lot of money you're like walking
around in our Grassroots to make it big
right so and there just hasn't been
enough time for a lot of these people to
shine they're out there slugging it out
and like they're getting there but
um you know that time's still gonna it's
still gonna come and I think yeah when
you do get there and it's not going to
be like you know he said the Bud Light
weed I mean yeah you know it's right but
yeah it's not to say somebody can't you
know take what they're doing and still
be quality high and then also keep
reduction out like there's ways to do it
it's just
a lot of the Chads that had all that big
investment money that went in and it's
through you know millions of dollars out
and blew up big they're not they're not
craft type Growers they're not really
Growers at all you know they're just
kind of hiring mediocre people for a
mediocre pay which is going to end up
being a mediocre job so
um it's the same like skilled labor
isn't cheap cheap labor isn't skilled
and they're paying cheap man so you get
you kind of get what you pay for so but
I think I think we'll see a change you
know in the near future and especially
you start looking like States like
Virginia coming online
um it has a lot of farm boys there and
and girls all right including y'all
um that really know how to they know how
to do big things you know so I got a lot
of Hope and I got a lot of faith uh
faith in Virginia
hell yeah that's exciting
if we just sort of uh change the topic
for a minute I was hoping to get into
some breeding stuff because probably the
the majority of questions that were
submitted by listeners were related to
that and I think you know if I sort of
amalgamate many of the questions slash
concerns together I think I can sort of
embody it with the question of you know
have you changed your mind at all in
regards to the direction you want to
take your breeding because in the past
you've always felt that there's a
certain importance around certain
cultivars like notably sort of some of
the chem family the skunks for example
you've worked extensively with some of
these lines 88g13 do you think that
you're going to continue with that
direction or do you have an inkling to
welcome some new blood into the Haram
well I do uh I don't have any uh
anything
really uh against anything new and there
are going to be some new things but um
yeah man so you know yeah definitely
some of the new
um back then you know I just had I had
goals in mind you know start off with
what you want in a bowl and you know go
from there and I had some some things I
wanted to see things I wanted to do and
some goals
and I worked hard toward those goals and
then I made those goals happen so um
there's some some that aren't aren't
finished you know that I still got
um
so we'll you know pick up there but yeah
there's a whole bunch of other things
I'd like to do and yeah it involve some
some new things something new something
old type of deal
yeah nice I mean is there any specific
lines of yours that you're really
itching to get back into or it's going
to be more open platter and evaluate
um well I wanted to uh I wanted to
finish up
primarily like a couple of couple of
projects that I had like I said I was on
that last step so I want to get them
knocked out first and foremost after
that point
um
I got a couple in mind but I guess I
don't wanna I don't want to show my
hands too early man
yeah no understandable for sure well I
had
um some questions from listeners who
were hoping maybe you could give them a
little bit more sort of of an
explanation or just maybe some thoughts
on some of the the packs they got from
you and one of the ones that caught my
eye was someone was interested to know
what are the differences in your mind
between say the skunk band and the dead
band given you know they are fairly
similar
yeah very similar
um once one's given more more of the
narcotic knockdown Stone and you're
getting a difference in the flavonoids
you know more the more the hashy hashy
funky orag side of things and also like
structure and girth like half to it too
that dead band has definitely had the
more the more heft to it
um skunk band had more of that headband
type sour uh consistency to the book
um that band definitely had more the
more the knock down knock down type stun
too
yeah beautiful stuff there do you have
any plans to re-release any of the lines
or you just want to focus on new things
going forward
well there were certain things
that are made and I thought I made
enough
but the problem was like every not a
problem I guess it's a good problem is
like people are really digging work
and as it was like it was catching on as
I'm doing it so they they get onto this
new thing to them it's like it's been
out for six months or a year and they're
gone
you know
um and I was just all about moving
forward moving forward
um so there were certain ones that were
very exceptional that I was like it's
it's
worthy of the time to you know take it
to an F3 or an F4 and and put it put it
back out there you know so there are
there are some of those that I'll
definitely go that route but
that's that's going to be a hopeful
answer to a lot of people listening
because I was going to say I did a quick
little tally of the strains that got
mentioned from the listeners and the top
three that people had questions about oh
we're just in general really excited
about was
the Polecat back cross which I think
might sort of fall into the category you
just mentioned where you know people
only really realized about it you know a
month after the release but the other
two that made the list was the local
skunk and the hoodoo were those some of
the lines that you know you were
thinking in that last answer
um yeah absolutely absolutely those are
definitely one Screaming Eagle
definitely definitely would make the
list for me too because and you see like
a lot of people don't know but people
that do know they you know they know so
um yeah that's definitely another one
you know there's only so many people had
that one as well
yeah nice I've I've actually got a
personal question for you that I've been
wanting to ask you for a while but I
never got the opportunity but basically
use Pantene that's what I use
beautiful stuff that's how you keep it
silky smooth
that's right
I ended up growing out uh some of your
chemd cross c99 feminized yeah I found
this pheno which to me is like bang on
chem 91.
and I just always was like man that's
crazy it's like chemd and c99 and I'm
getting this plant that has like no real
sativa characteristics or influence in
the effect and not only that it sort of
tastes and looks like chem 91 more than
the chem D and it got me wondering I was
like do you think you know because some
people try to say maybe the chemd
actually came from the chem 91 and I
thought that's the only thing I could
think of which maybe explained it a bit
do you have any thoughts or do you just
think look chem D and the chem 91 are
similar like that's that's it
well the 91 you know being related you
know yeah of course and that is that is
the correct line of thought but let's
let's take it back a step further all
right so
all right when I was working with
Princess when we were doing the doing
the brothers Grim thing you smoked the
bud and everything you've seen it you've
seen it grow
and there was no question in my mind
that that magical you know backseat or
whatever was an NL hybrid like that that
princess reminded me a lot and women
like so
when when Saul or Sly who whomever was
doing that
um they they they chose a male to start
that cubing process right and if she
discovered as Northern Lights and skunk
me personally I felt always felt like
and I was gone would be a good nominee
for the mystery pollen donor to make
come anyway I was just always my gut and
you know I still still feel that way I
still think that way all right so
he takes uh
and he hits it he hits that princess he
does his cubing process right so now you
got those jeans in the pool so and to me
like when I smoked princess that the
first time this is [ __ ] kind of
narcotic [ __ ] weed man I got nothing
nothing sativa out of it basically a
shorter plant doesn't stretch crazy it
doesn't it definitely doesn't scream at
me
so with having those jeans in the pool
and then ultimately that clone that was
used was just I mean you remember man
you've been to my shop you saw me
growing it and doing it right you've had
the Bud you smelled the jars
um it was [ __ ] Funky Man kind of you
know that gassy
[ __ ] nasty nasty smell to it you know
and it was like as close to that
princess it wasn't exactly like it by
any means you know but you know it was
as close to it as I'd seen and any
anything else so having that
as a pollen owner and solving that that
plant and using that reverse pollen to
hit chemd you know it's passing passing
everything I could out of that out of
that original female that that could be
passed on so
Bob getting all those jeans back in that
pool that doesn't you know it's like no
surprise to me that you would see
females that are spot on you know some
more like you know the the mother you
know the Kennedy some being like uh the
Cindy and then you know Glenda the two
ones that mean slightly one way or the
other but also expressing the the the
parents and the and the uh the sisters
if you will so that that doesn't doesn't
surprise me surprise me at all
yeah no that's a brilliant explanation
and I I think I really resonate with how
you were describing a princess was more
of an Indica I think yeah you definitely
notice that disorientating factor of the
high
yeah big time Big Time man it would it
would slump you slump you back dude
yeah you know it's it's only now that
you say it that I think to myself if no
one ever told me and you put princess
and genius like the buds at least next
to each other I definitely would never
have thought they were related
yeah
and with with genius
you know I was like if I had my guts
like it reminded me so much of Super
Soul cakes I mean so much man and um
you know so that led me to think like
hey maybe you know maybe it was like uh
maybe like you know Haze or something
like that that it was the diner like
there you know tell me what what
happened you know it's supposed to be a
bag You Know Jack air or whatever but
you know that that mystery donor uh gave
us something like
like uh like princess and that one was
so different so that's not to say what
if there was more donors right well if
it wasn't just one donor
the multiple pollen sources
yeah I guess that's actually a
possibility that's never really been
discussed very much has it
no
I got sat there thinking many a night
like
this doesn't make any [ __ ] sense
yeah yeah especially off such a small
number of seeds popped you just wouldn't
expect to see that variation
right and this wasn't like
you know bud that he grew
this is purchase Bud from a coffee shop
in Amsterdam so I used to say like it's
not you know a bunch of different buds
homogenized in a in a tray from a
harvest and some plants were near one
side of the room and then the other side
of the room and
you know only got hit with one one got
hit with the other and one bud had some
seasonal but had some seed but
two different plants two different
pollen donors
I think that might be a very well new
possibility right
yeah I mean it makes makes sense to me
you know so I felt that like I said that
the jeans was a lot like super silver
haze and the uh the princess I mean is
just totally totally different
yeah yeah hugely hugely
you got me thinking now that's
interesting
yeah man while we're on the topic I mean
the last the last episode we recorded
together was a number of years ago and I
think at the time it was still pretty
fresh and raw so we didn't really delve
into it but a lot of people have been
wondering for the longest time that the
circumstances in which you departed
Brothers Grimm and a lot of rumors
floating around about sort of you know
money being owed and things like that
would you be willing to set the record
straight on why you decided to part ways
with Brothers Grimm and maybe some of
the circumstances yeah yeah for sure
um
so
the guy wasn't
who I thought he was and and that that
[ __ ] happens you know if you talk to
somebody on the Internet or whatever
that's one thing but
being around somebody seeing them in
their everyday life and working with
them and seeing how they interact with
people
um
just I guess to me uh be as nice as I
can about it like I didn't Jive at all
with the guy and um just some really
really really bad practices
um
[Music]
ethics
um how I treated people
um and it just turned into like a mess
after mess after mess
um problem after problem and we're just
talking to dealing with people here
um and it just got to that point where
it's just
yeah so frustrating so so frustrating
um and then when it came to the work and
everything else
um
it just it would there would be
just things that would really really
really really piss me off
um so it got to the point was like just
just please just handle
um you know talking to vendors and stuff
like that but you know please don't
don't just start cussing at them and
flipping out on them and feels like
somebody owes you something
um quit being cocky put the egotistical
stuff be a little more humble man
um I'll handle I'll handle this don't
don't worry you got the right guy
um but you you know you got it you gotta
tighten up and if you if you're gonna go
out you do these shows you handle the
banking and the shipping and all
um that's cool it's cool by me because
that's what you like to do you like
attention uh you like these shows and
everything
um
do do you you know stick to stick to
that but just when you're doing these
shows like
please stop offending people because
every time you're to show my DM box
shows up like this [ __ ] prick you
will not believe what he said or what he
did
um
uh this you know I could go on with
story epic story of the story of people
at shows like where I would go and it
would just straight up come up to him he
was like yeah I had this big fat wad of
money I wanted all this for me I cannot
rightly buy this from you knowing that
any of that money is going to go to that
to that guy
and I'd have to like I I understand
um
just very rude guy you know I don't know
how else to put it and it just got to
the point where like even like him just
doing shows
was just it was just a bad just a bad
deal man
and I was like this is just something I
can't
I can't continue
um being associated with
um I can't really
be around this dude this is so
frustrating and that's the thing is like
around me like to me personally right he
wasn't he wasn't like that you know it's
just to other people but
um it just a very very frustrating very
frustrating thing so
um so I decided I was like look man
um at one point he's like look I want to
I want to bring on this guy uh he wants
to buy
um you know part of the company he wants
to you know be doing this that this and
that
um and we need to do this we need to do
that and I was like okay all right so
you just you just came from a show where
I got a whole DM box full of full of
messages saying like you're blowing them
off being rude to them and you couldn't
be bothered because you're flirting with
some girl who's next to you and um
furthermore you couldn't be bothered to
drop the seeds off at the hotel so he
parked it in some restaurant and busted
your glass and got all that stolen
and now you're coming back with some guy
I don't even know or never met saying
he's he's buying his way into the
company and this is what we're doing
this is how we're gonna do it so it's
like wow okay all right it seems like
it's been quite a bit uh over this over
this weekend I was already at my Edge
anyway
so I'm like I'll tell you what
how about this you buy whatever you want
and you
uh Rick you're you're you can buy the
rest of it like um I'm good
so what you're gonna do if you're cool
with this
you you got bankers and lawyers and all
that [ __ ] you have them draft up a good
contract
figure out whatever his percent was
going to be use that as a multiplier for
you know 50 percent
you know give me that right so he's like
all right cool so about two days later
comes out he's got a contract or
whatever I'm looking at it and I'm like
all right yeah that's that's cool uh
that'll that'll work you know
so
um and it's you know it's pretty cut and
dry so sign off on it boom
uh payment one happens you know upon
execution and then ask for everything at
once I'm like that's a good chunk of
money man so you know we'll we'll split
this down into quarters you know over
over a year
so I'm like it makes it easy for you two
to continue doing what you're doing uh
do whatever type of marketing whatever
man do y'all
um y'all got this you said you got this
cool so time for payment to comes around
and he's like I don't know like sales
are down this and that I'm like look
dude the last post we had on media
um you posted one post after all these
months and it was middle of the evening
on day two of the show
how in the [ __ ] do you think that's
that's promotion right
and I go down like this list of like 13
or so things like this is what you're
doing wrong do this instead do this
instead do this instead blah blah
all right I'll do that I was like but
look in all jokes aside like you you
need to pay me my money like flat out so
it takes some time like some weeks or
whatever but but he does okay we're cool
then on the next one he's a squat out I
can't make money
um I don't feel that I owe you anything
and I'm I'm just I'm not I'm not gonna
pay you I was like yeah that's that's
not gonna happen man so you know
you you can't go and buy a [ __ ]
NASCAR race car right and you're buying
that to to compete but you don't know
how to race a race car you can't tell
people that you suck as a [ __ ] race
car driver and you're not winning and
not be like Oh I'm not paying you for it
because I can't win no man like you got
it you got to pay like whatever failures
are happening that's on you right now
you're not doing any new work you're not
promoting it anytime you do talk to
people they're they're incredibly
offended and you're not going good for a
lot a lot of other reasons which none of
which have anything to do with me so
he's just like yeah yeah not not gonna
do that so I was like okay so now I'm
like well I need to need to figure some
figure some things out so basically
um that's where that's where it ended
off was uh right there and uh just
trying to you know figure it out
um
you know I'm not big on courts and and
going going that route but uh if you get
an alternative route you're gonna find
yourself in court anyway for something
altogether different so
um you know so I don't know
um you know maybe try to talk to the
dude again now that I'm now that I'm
home and then and I have to figure it
out from there because I you know I
really don't like going to uh any type
of court court system and stuff like
that you know I've just always been like
you know you should just be a man of
your word and honor honor your
agreements and you know do it like that
um but then at the same time I'm looking
I'm like wow you're buying an awful lot
of lavish [ __ ] for a guy that doesn't
doesn't make any money so all right so I
didn't have much uh much sympathy in
that regard so he said hopefully I'll
talk to him again
um maybe shit's change or maybe he has a
different outlook on on things I don't
know we'll just have to have to see
that provides a lot of clarity to the
situation and like he's still selling
[ __ ] that I made like back then like
somebody showed me the other day it was
like 187 for sale and you just renamed
it Murder By Numbers
and it's just like old seed stock that I
was supposed to get paid for that never
did you know somebody showed me he's
like yeah they had uh polecat f2s and I
was like Wow and he was like yeah name
the strain and I'll give you a pack and
somebody like popped on his way I get
his name for you how about Duke's work
it's like oh golden best name ever
that's how dude you know that's how dude
operates man like I said from outside
looking in like and I'm not like a drama
guy I don't want to like air out a bunch
of [ __ ] like on you know Instagram or
something like that you know it's like I
can handle these things so by that same
token though it's like people don't
don't know who and what's going on
because a lot of those people
to mess with him you know they're all
newer people you know I don't know who
the [ __ ] I am which is this is fine you
know but
um they they have no idea of you know
what the past has been and [ __ ] like
that and yeah nobody's a mind reader so
so it's like you know one of the things
is like you air that out you know all
over the place or do you just you know
just work through it and you know call
it call it a day because I don't want to
like you know put a bunch of negative
negative [ __ ] on there you know and
especially if it's something I just need
to hash out with a person individually
um you know I'm gonna I'm gonna do that
too you know that's just the way the way
I was brought up
um so yeah you know but I guess you know
like I said I'm glad you're glad you
asked that because
um after all these years and everything
uh yeah bigger [ __ ] you know you
might as might as well let people know
know what's up with the dude
yeah totally well I mean maybe maybe the
the silver lining of this is that we did
have a lot of people ask will we ever
see cap G again I think it was one of
the most hottest strains when it hit the
the scene that year
that was only 40. yeah it was only 40 uh
40 packs of it and you remember at the
at the show man like because it was gone
you know a lot of it was even like
spoken for like right off the bat so
um with uh with that going on it was
weird because later it was like you know
I saw like you know it seemed like 200
uh 200 packs of it in circulation like
that's uh that's a coincidence
very peculiar so um but the thing was
with that
um it was it was just a beginning step
you know moving forward to making that
Dominion so no I don't I don't feel well
you know back it all the way up
um you know I kind of hit my goal you
know where I wanted to be
yeah certainly I mean as a bit of a
follow-up and it might be hard for you
to pick just one but I was curious to
know what do you think is the most under
recognized Dominion strain in terms of
quality where like you know maybe the
sales don't reflect it but it's truly a
killer
and they were man they were quite a
there were quite a few
um the granny Scott was one the Virginia
Beach Afghani
um that one was [ __ ] killer but
nobody knew it Virginia Beach candy was
it's like
people only know what they want based
off the kind of what they like and that
wasn't like some big circulated thing
like people in Virginia would beat it up
because everybody knows what the [ __ ]
that is
by everybody else say yeah
I don't know what that is you know they
just keep it keep it moving like oh what
kind of dog yeah I like I know I've
heard that one before so they'll go go
that way that was probably the most the
most slept on
yeah no that's that's a great answer I
remember having smelt that and it was it
was almost equally as impressive as the
cap G but I think many people smell that
cap GM were just sold yeah man that was
like nasty garlicky rubber skunk you
font to it man that was that was some
good that was some good [ __ ] man and you
know that was something that that was
lacking around everybody was going like
super fruity [ __ ] and you know going
just for like straight straight down you
know
um at the time
and it was you know something different
you know and something that hadn't been
hadn't been in plenty I guess you know
for a long time so it's cool to be like
yeah you know that those those types of
things would still you know strike a
strike a thing with people's nose and be
like yeah that's that's something I like
that you know so along with all the all
the work coming after that and you know
uh projects I did along with it it was
cool to see like yeah you know it's not
just me or a group of friends that are
indignant like a lot of people are
digging and after I've come back I've
had so many people who are like they
bought all that stuff up but they didn't
pop it
and I guess while I was gone a lot of
people were popping packs and the DM box
built up like most amazing [ __ ] ever
that's [ __ ] skunky [ __ ] gas come
[ __ ] I got going on with us so I'm
keeping them forever thank you so much
he's going outdoor you know just a lot
of good success stories happy people and
I like yeah I bought them just because
and you know he's been kind of sitting
on them and just just now years later
you know getting into it so it was kind
of cool cool to see all that good
feedback you know I was getting some
from people you know immediately jumping
into the work but there was so much more
that those people were sitting on it now
coming back and then showing me pictures
that you know from last year or whatever
the year before or here recently this
guy has killer you know people who do
podcasts
purple values like uh Sangria's all that
[ __ ] man just [ __ ] like man you
please keep doing keep doing what you're
doing you know I'm down whenever you're
ready
Yeah a hundred percent and you just
named a few strands I wanted to ask you
about but before we get there I just
wanted to quickly loop back because you
mentioned the VA Afghani we actually had
a few people ask about that and the sort
of Common Thread was do you have any
information on the backstory around it
at all
see like that's always been like the
like a mystery mystery plant you know
um I'm gonna do a live on it at some
point with a few different people from
that time now they can they can talk
freely on it
um but man there's so many there's so
many stories
um you know as with any anything
anything with any Lord man you got got a
whole lot of [ __ ]
um I always felt it's a whole lot
simpler than you know a Vietnam vet and
uh I can't say uh what's the new word a
little person uh like there's been some
[ __ ] crazy crazy stories I heard but
I think at the end of the day it's just
some old seed bank uh Afghani Stockton
to really really killer ones and it's
still the test of time it's like
anything else that's real good if it's
been around that long it's the reason
why you know people aren't going to risk
uh you know getting hemmed up and going
to prison over some every some swag
yeah certainly I mean but it stood the
test of time which I think is sort of a
testament to its its quality
yeah strong [ __ ] man that's potent
definitely I definitely remember the
first time I tried it with you and it
was everything you said you know very
sort of paranoia and juicing for an
Afghani which was cool
yeah man and then you just I just want
to shut you just want to sit down
um we had a someone who hails from VA as
well asked the question did you ever try
the Skyler skunk from Nelson Virginia
back in the day
absolutely absolutely and that's the
thing like I mentioned that on a couple
shows I mentioned it once like before I
even run away and I kind of had a slip
you're like what's that I was like
nothing don't worry there's nothing to
see here
so yes yes yes I have and um had a had a
buddy that used to live out that way and
you know he he knew the old dude with it
you know they got they got the point of
it and all that [ __ ] and um [ __ ]
[ __ ] killer dude
but more on that later
okay I mean is it is it like a standard
skunk but better or is it very is it
sort of different to a normal skunk
it's definitely more more on the Indica
side of things
um
aside from the the strong smells and all
that [ __ ]
um very very strong narcotic uh doesn't
grow huge stretchy type type plants you
know so
um it's definitely definitely more in
that blend of Leaning a little more on
the uh on the Indica side of stuff and
uh just absolutely [ __ ] stanky man I
was a stinker you know it's got that
lingering effect too on the mouth like a
iconic Coffee Bean hashy uh slight skunk
flavor
um to it and kind of like it's almost
like that Sour Diesel effect a little
bit so it's definitely definitely a
[ __ ] killer it was great outside too
that's that's awesome to hear I mean if
we loop back to your answer before you
mention the the purple Dahlia among
other things and we had a few questions
about it I guess people must be sitting
on packs and they're sort of curious you
know what sort of things can they expect
out of it and what's your thoughts on
the purple Dahlia overall
um really good it's just like I think
like oh like what put people off
is
you know I put a warning on the pack if
something's like subject to her due to
something I'm gonna I'm gonna put that
on there so that way you know somebody
can avoid it so you got a lot of people
oh wait I heard him like well yeah a lot
of [ __ ] well if you you know if you do
something [ __ ] up and this one has a
little Bugaboo about this so just don't
do that and you should uh you should be
cool you know and out of that honest
deal I'd be like no no so it's like cool
like you can go buy this other [ __ ] like
you know it's whatever I tell you that's
going to hurt them out but they're not
going to tell you so they get you get
your money or whatever but it's it's
it's whatever man but out of the out of
the phenotypes
um
they were just these these Blends man
um and and it's not like something it's
like oh you gotta pop a bunch of packs
for it is multiples and and every pack
out of the females that were incredibly
incredibly dark purple on this black
Screaming Eagle style frost on it that
just tasted like [ __ ] great candies
man and Boston tastes awesome and they
affect on it
s [ __ ] design man I really am really
like that one that was another like that
another ever ever looked one or maybe
looked at and just you know
just just starting to decide instead
because you know I had worries or
whatever
yeah I mean it's interesting because I
remember when I smelled uh the jar of it
at the cup a few years back I think that
was one of the ones I was most impressed
by I'm having trouble remembering if it
was that or the sangria punch but I
think it was the purple Dahlia yeah the
purple dye was definitely very extremely
dark purple and had like that eagle type
block but purple if that that made any
sense at all purple grape bee also had
that that citrusy incensey type type
Blended in with the
um the sangria very very frosty stuff
but I mean yeah yeah it's not spot on
there's a sangria punch like spot on and
everybody smelled it was like holy [ __ ]
that's angry a punch it's like yup
that's why we get the name
you know
yeah okay there you go
well I mean if we move on sadly since
you sort of been away on Hiatus uh
there's sort of been a bit of a change
in the Cannabis landscape and
specifically we've we've sadly had to
Bid Farewell to two friends of both the
industry but yourself as well you know
notably Monty sub cool and and also bog
yeah and Josie Wales too
yeah Jersey well that also happened and
I guess my sort of question is how does
it feel to come back and to see that the
Cannabis landscape has changed a little
bit or do you feel like it actually
hasn't that much
um
and it's weird because like for me it's
kind of like the grow room thing if
you're in there every day you don't see
a whole lot of change but if you go in
once a week or something like that you
see a lot of Dramatics
so from being like totally totally away
from it and coming back my man
it seems about the same like honestly
but like that's as far as like maybe
Instagram goes I haven't been to a show
or anything like that now from what I've
seen going on yeah I mean the shows are
definitely
um
going downhill I guess but I already saw
that coming many many years ago that
last one that was at you were at or
whatever you remember when they told me
they're like yeah you're not on that
panel anymore you know that you're like
yeah they just want me to interview
somebody else man
[Music]
um you know I saw it you know even
coming before that point but then once
that that show happens yeah it's bad so
yeah I hate to see it in a few years
now I have kind of vicariously you know
the others and they're showing their
videos and [ __ ] so
um yeah this is you know other than that
I mean yeah it's basically the same
uh as far as like you have people
passing away you know how to project at
that show uh because me and Bob we ended
up uh we shared a booth space or
whatever and I thought it was like real
[ __ ] up it was like people were lined
up and they even know who he was so I'm
like no like you know you see this man
you need you need to get stuff around
this is like uh like I grew this [ __ ]
like if I literally had space and time I
would continue growing this [ __ ]
um like you you really you really need
to you know get this guy so I ended up
like kind of bending been in for him as
well and just overall it's really really
good dude too
um so I was like look man like we need
to we need to do something together you
know so
um we came up with a good solid solid
plan or like two things that would
really drive together that would be
knock your socks off so I'm like yeah
cool we'll get to it you know
and um you know as time goes by it's
like all right well it's about that time
buddy that [ __ ] all went South for me
and then I went away finally I died and
I'm like oh [ __ ] you know I didn't get a
chance to say goodbye and that's like
probably one of the worst things about
one
friends or people you know or care about
or think Holly when they die
um you know you don't get that chance to
say goodbye or you know anything else
that you wanted to stay home so
um and the same thing goes for you know
Josie and you know money and everything
it's like
um
you know you wish you maybe you'd said
more uh with the time you had so just
for everybody you know it's her memory
and I was like it can happen at any time
so uh you know um
tomorrow's not promised right so yeah
definitely definitely but cool thing is
uh his son his son's keeping keeping
things kind of going and uh I'm gonna
get with him and you know we're still
still gonna make that make that happen
yeah yeah that would be awesome to still
see something happen because yeah Bogue
Jr and Pat are still still around and
need to be taken care of yeah man yeah
exactly and it can be a good honor honor
to honor to the guy you know
um yeah certainly well I probably should
have asked this a bit earlier but I was
curious to know do you have any advice
for people who maybe not in your exact
circumstance but just sort of you know
trying to get everything back together
dust themselves off get back on the
horse so to speak have you got any
advice in that respect
yeah absolutely man
um
don't be hard-headed and or I mean do be
hard-headed I should say uh refuse to
stop refuse to lose refuse to give up
and as your mistakes come across as long
as you're learning from them you're
becoming stronger you're becoming better
um don't don't give up uh just whatever
is faulting you
along your way you just gotta sit back
and look at it outside looking at it and
really in a lot of things and then go
from there so that way when you when you
do succeed it'd be the best thing ever
and you'd really refine yourself
you know and you've grown as a as a
human being as well so just anything you
want to start or do you know just go all
out man really you know just go all out
and don't focus on money and fame and
things like that those are the the worst
things that you know you're getting into
something for the wrong reasons if
that's the goal I've seen people do that
as well and uh it doesn't it doesn't
work out well
um if that's your thing like go to
Hollywood maybe try to be an actor or
something like that but
um just whatever it is that you're going
after
um if it's something you're passionate
about something you really love in a
really
really delve into that man and
um follow that love follow that passion
and do it for those reasons and a lot of
the other things are gonna are gonna
follow behind
and um you know and follow your six P's
um come up with a plan plan your work
work your plan follow your six P's the
proper planning prevents just for
performance so if you if you stick to
that
um and like I said be you know very very
adamant about not not giving up moving
forward you're going to succeed you know
and I'm cool simple as that
some brilliant advice there
I I know that in in your absence there
had been some rumors surrounding
Dominion Seed Co and I think
specifically some of the things that I
saw posted was that there was supposedly
some seeds that didn't end up with the
vendors they were meant to and others
say they were sort of stolen it's a bit
unclear and then other people had been
involved I know that your wife had been
dragged into it at one point and I think
skunk VA had been sort of dragged into
it would you just be able to clarify a
little bit around what happened because
I think the the toughest part about what
happened to you was that you didn't have
the opportunity to to discuss any of it
yourself you know it's all sort of
second-hand knowledge so if you could
maybe clarify some of those things and
just help set the record straight that
would be phenomenal
oh for sure for sure for sure because
man it's like
you know there's nothing worse
than you know you when you can't even
speak up for yourself you know so
um
essentially like what had happened was
um I had all this planned out in case
[ __ ] went South I didn't get a bomb or
whatever and everything was laid out you
know these are supposed to go this way
another
um Monies to be done like this so
everybody's still you know making it
with everything the projects were
already ready to go uh the seeds were
ready
um everything should have been nice nice
and smooth and then uh you know I'm
losing contact with people not being
able to get a hold of people and like
literally none of his planned is
happening whatsoever
so you know it led to me he's thinking
like huh like you know what what's going
on here you know because if there's a
problem you know like like I can fix it
you know I can figure [ __ ] out even from
from my position
[Music]
um but like I said every not everybody
but some people were ghosted out so
I had you know just call it an employee
Apprentice or what have you that the you
know the like see counting packing
making the vials and everything did a
great job and all that
um also you know helping along with
watering later on like in that last half
year before all this is going on
doing some water and doing some
gardening I'm relocating down south so I
definitely needed to definitely needed
the help with that
um and just kind of be the best teacher
that I can be you know and treating them
like an apprentice
um so they're supposed to be handling
[ __ ] uh they go they go [ __ ] ghost on
me
um and everything is not being handled
in the way that's handled and then like
all these like you know rumors are like
starting to come about like people are
telling me that I'm in contact with and
I'm like well that is a uh that's a load
of horse [ __ ] so like like one of the
the biggest ones that that [ __ ] got
me was I didn't do any of the growing or
any of the breeding and I was like what
the [ __ ] up
oh hell no hell no like that one that
one was just the most [ __ ] ridiculous
[ __ ] I had heard and especially like
in a community like
where people have like like you
personally like you've literally been
there in person like watching it
watching this go down and uh like and
they're even claiming they did all the
work for grim and everything else and
like I said like
I mean you can you can speak up if you
want you know I mean you like literally
personally
yeah every every day for two weeks I saw
you doing the work
yeah and you did you see anybody else
doing anything no it's just me and you
there
yes correct and like people could even
like go to Seoul and ask him and like
that dude don't like me for [ __ ] and
even he'll tell you you know like yeah
dude was it was [ __ ] doing this thing
like you got Robbie from nerds genetics
he was my neighbor there like where I
was doing my thing for a long time to
hang out over there every single day
right
um had a lot of other you know people
that just like to come by and hang out
while I'm working I mean there's a [ __ ]
ton of work but you know people can hang
out and I can talk while at work and
people just thought it was cool and fun
you know they got to see me do the
process you know James Bean's been there
witnessing it uh like propane Jane was
right around the way she would come by
and just hang out you know you know just
learn stuff
um a few other people they're they're on
IG and everything
um like I said they were just
you know come and hang out shoot the
[ __ ] I'm a triple uh sticky lungs on IG
an old friend of mine he was by there
all the time the big dang Corey he was
always over there you know
um just dude there's so many [ __ ]
people that were just like that is a
load of [ __ ] you know but a rumor is a
rumor and a rumor doesn't value it until
it's killed so
another thing is like yeah they're
claiming to be a stud breeder I'm like
all right
well like is anybody actually asking
them any any questions about breeding so
oh I bet you about you a dollar they
don't they're not going to have the
answer to it you know so because they
they weren't they weren't ones doing the
work so I was like yeah so obviously
like this is this is not not good and
like this is the source of you know
what's going on and like some people
um I won't even throw his name out there
but even though I probably should but
I'm not
um like buys into a lot of us
like another one like any type of it
because like I needed to talk to him
recently and he's like bought into this
[ __ ] he was like yeah you lied about uh
going to going to prison back in the day
I was like what that's level the thing
to lie about anyway but whatever so I
luckily I got like some paperwork nearby
it's got like my original you know date
and everything else so snap a picture
I'm like all right yeah that says 2007
you know explains a lot you know and you
know once again you have old friends
that used to literally talk to me you
know over the phone at this at this
facility they you know help me out
through money on my books back in the
day and they all they all knew what was
up so and and the worst thing is is a
person that's like you know spreading
his lie
um saw me like right when I got out of
prison and like was even around like
with me going to the probation office to
take my piss test like they they know
all this so like they're just obviously
just trying to come up with [ __ ] so
much [ __ ] just to you know
accomplish their own goal so that was I
guess at the time you know saw the
remaining because of stock and then they
said they were going to start up a new
company and like by all means like you
want to do your thing like do your thing
like start your company like good for
you right but all the line and all that
extra [ __ ] like uh you you didn't need
to [ __ ] do that and then another one
he was like oh yeah you're a mess dude
I've only seen that [ __ ] one time in my
life and I wasn't doing I even got in a
fight with the guy like two days later
on a job site because he's a [ __ ]
piece of [ __ ] like I don't know if I can
do that anybody that really knows like I
don't do drugs and these even cases of
people that could do drugs
um and uh straight up I tell them like I
can't I can't hang around you like
that's just you know it's not good so
and you know what I say to that uh
anybody that knows me could tell you but
anybody wants to say some [ __ ] like that
go down in your [ __ ] pocket pay for a
[ __ ] hair follicle test from me you
know put you put your money where your
[ __ ] cop holster is and [ __ ] get
that test he didn't go back I think like
seven years or more so I've been gone
too so that gives you a good five
[ __ ] year so if I was on any type of
drug it'd be on there and I'm gonna come
up hot as [ __ ] for THC that's it so you
know I can squash out whenever you
[ __ ] there and like I said having
this paperwork and [ __ ] like that to be
like nope that's where you're [ __ ] up
oh you weren't here you couldn't have
done that boom here's a check stub boom
you know like I got like literally like
the disprove every single [ __ ] thing
and like I said some of it was so
[ __ ] absurd the people in the know
which are out there like they obviously
know like it's [ __ ] because they
were [ __ ] there you know so um
very very you know
very disheartening you know to to see
all that you know especially after
somebody
uh that you really looked out for you
know so much and obviously you know they
you know I felt some kind of way and
we're gonna do what they were gonna do
and they did it and you know that's all
in the past it's whatever like you know
you don't [ __ ] you know ruin me you
know I'm gonna keep doing me I'm gonna
keep moving forward but
you know they're not going to be around
for it which is you know bad bad for
them but the worst part is like good
friends that you're really trying to
take care of and then ultimately one of
them's like yeah no [ __ ] cash cash
the [ __ ] out and then spread a bunch of
Lies so I have somebody to help me cash
out and the worst part is like the good
friend that actually like believes this
[ __ ] you know and was very adamant about
Oh no you're lying you're lying you
always should just go stop lying get
your life back together
like no like literally I can literally
prove all this right here and just with
what I have at my at my hands length
right now like a piece of paperwork with
the [ __ ] dates on it boom here when I
get to the house I got my whole [ __ ]
PSR you can read the whole [ __ ] thing
like everything in detail like
discredits the [ __ ] out of it but why in
the [ __ ] are you [ __ ] gonna believe
some wild ass crazy [ __ ] like that from
somebody you don't even really know
right
some some years right and that's what is
more mind-blowing you know and hurtful I
guess than anything but yeah like you
know I could definitely definitely
squash out
you know any any of that [ __ ] so it's
just like I said it's just you know like
you were saying it's just you you're one
of the people that's actually been there
you know seeing this so it comes off as
just pretty pretty absurd anyway you
know
yeah look you hit all the questions I
was gonna follow up with before I even
had a chance so thank you for painting
you know a clearer picture and I think
that you've always got to take stories
you hear with a grain of salt when you
don't have the ability to hear all
perspectives and I think that must have
been a really frustrating aspect for you
not being able to reply throughout this
whole process
yeah and like that's what they count on
well I was just saying that's what
people like that count on it's like you
always hear the sayings like people are
going to kick you when you're down and
furthermore like being down is like
you're muffled your silence like you're
physically actually restrained like you
can't do a thing and then when people
see things and then they come out with
it and like hey something's [ __ ] up
you know then you got people bickering
and fighting amongst each other
um which is you know [ __ ] up and then
because one side's gonna pick one or the
other and it gets [ __ ] up and then
unfortunately you know you get other
people drawn into the middle and then
they get really pissed and frustrated
with the whole thing and it's just it's
just a whole cancerous thing and it
grows and grows and if you're not able
to like really get out there and stop it
um it just gets worse until you know
time and we'll iron everything out
without you even having the you know
step forward and obviously like I've
looked back and everything and you know
like a lot of good people out there that
knew this [ __ ] was going on they're
screenshotting they're recording they're
doing all this stuff so like you know I
was well informed like right when I pray
when I got back and put it all together
but
um you know it irons itself out really
especially when you got stuff it's just
so absurd it just comes off weird
and it's like obviously it's like yeah
it's obviously uh obviously a lie so um
you know but
now being able to actually deal with it
and talk with it
um it wasn't really that widespread or
that big of a deal
for real
um but still just the fact that somebody
that close was trying some [ __ ] like
that that's what bothered me but like if
anybody did hear anything like yeah it's
I mean most everybody anyways like yeah
that's that's a load of [ __ ] so that's
that's cool too it's good to know you
know you got people in your corner that
know that you're you know a solid dude
unless you're doing what you're saying I
mean it's just you know the good thing
if you live a good good life and you you
know do that you don't really have
nothing to worry about when people do
you know talk outside like that and um
and now they're back and be able to kind
of iron that out and be like yeah you
know straight up bro you got you got
Hoodwinked man and here it is here it is
here it is and then by the end of it
being like yeah now I kind of I kind of
see what you're saying so I just wanted
to you know get it get it very apparent
to them you know it's just so they know
and then you know that that should that
should kill that right where it [ __ ]
my eyes you know
yeah look hopefully that can help set
the record straight for anyone who maybe
had heard some of the incorrect rumors
circulating around but I think you know
on the other end of the spectrum there
was what I thought at least was some
good things that sort of came out
regarding like Community banding
together in that there was at least what
I know of two breeders who were very
keen to try to help you out financially
and uh good old ODI of Heroes of the
Farms as well as sulfur genetics both
came to the table and wanted to offer
some strains to help raise some funds
for you was this something you had any
idea was happening or was it sort of a
pleasant surprise when you found out
just I won't even say pleasant surprise
like just
static
um they'll splint away
um by all the people that came to the
fat for me and like I had friends
telling me they're like you're getting
hit up from people all over the world
these people are just like you know
whatever whatever they can do whatever
help that you need because and then they
all had a story oh there's this one time
this dude took two hours to you know on
a DM to teach me a new a new uh approach
and then I gave him an address and I
sent him you know a whole lot the whole
[ __ ] menu just on the house or
somebody that was down and out and I
donated to their fundraiser for Wildfire
fundraisers are just kind of not I don't
I don't do things like that because I'm
thinking like oh well and you know I
might get something I do it just to do
it you know what I mean
and I guess I'd done so much of it you
know it didn't really cross my mind it's
just the right thing to do and then when
they're you know I'm hearing back from
them I'm like wow yeah I guess I guess I
was getting I was getting out there you
know and um and all these people just
came out the woodwork came to bat for me
and I can't I can't thank them enough
you know the only thing I can say is
yeah thank you thank you all from the
bottom of my heart
um y'all helped me make it through like
seemingly like the impossible and
um only thing I can say is you know I
promise to do a
do some more good in this world and
um do a good job
and I won't uh I won't uh need the
services anymore I will not be going
back to the open ever again so um you
know thank you thank you all for for
everything that you've done from kind
words to donations to just anything and
everything that's truly you know thank
you and love you all
yeah what a what a brilliant sentiment
there I guess it uh makes me curious to
know is there any chance we may see any
collaborations in the future now that
you've you know you got I mean you you
already knew before people liked you but
now you really know that for sure you
know it's raining chance you want to
maybe do collabs or you're more just
thinking you know I got to get myself
going first
nah man gotta you know put others before
yourself uh especially on stuff like
that so
yeah I'm working uh
been working basically the day after I
got out I've already done uh on it like
stink on [ __ ] man so yeah y'all
definitely look forward to a whole lot
of that
well you know what I was a little bit of
a selfish segue on my part because you
know the the hoodoo it's been such a
such popular strain really cool collab
between you and the skunk VA are there
any sort of breeders who since getting
out you're interested in or more
importantly since you know you've gotten
back out are there any I was thinking
about are there any strains that have
caught your eyes and like oh that wasn't
really a thing when I went away and I
was thinking about it and I was like I
don't know if anything major has hit the
scene since you left it hasn't it hasn't
the only things that I've seen that
really really you know like caught my
eye or attention and I'm like oh yeah
yeah I'm gonna need to get on that it's
all work from you know like my buddies
um
I don't know I've only said his real
name that's probably no big deal now but
uh Bob Hemphill
um for sure he's been doing some great
[ __ ] and it's like my type of style too
so I'm like yeah and he doesn't need to
beat some of that
um and my buddy AKB brains for sure like
he's been doing some really cool [ __ ]
and all his uh history with dudes
um do a lot of work with like Williams
Wonder and F5 of that and so you know
you know work and stuff like that but
I'm yeah I'm all about that you know so
uh that's that's that's got me got me
actually pretty pretty excited probably
more excited than I should be able to
pretty stoked for both those dudes
anyway I love them guys but uh yeah they
yeah my interests Pete you know a lot of
stuff some of the stuff's not VA come
out with was pretty pretty rad looking
too so but yeah no not really a lot so
really a lot of change a lot of dessert
stuff and kind of the same things that
were hitting when I was away you know
they're still doing doing their thing
yeah that was sort of the vibe I got but
you know what brilliant you you
mentioned both those two breeders
because I was gonna ask you questions I
was gonna say you know have you seen Bob
penfield's Park back cross it's looking
pretty cool
hell yeah I've seen that [ __ ] popular
Puck Lebanese too today oh yeah yeah
oh yeah that that plant is a special
plant for sure I was curious to know
though uh this is actually a fan
submitted question and they've got a
good memory they basically said that
they remembered uh some time ago you had
mentioned that you'd lost your Durban
Thai high flyer and they were wondering
the cut you had was that different to
the one that AK beam Brands and skunk VA
use or is it the same one and you just
like hadn't got it back off them
I'm not sure
about 8K being brains one
I would think so but I'm not 100 sure
but I gave the uh
the high flyer to uh VA so I know that's
that's the right one and uh I got
another buddy that's got it got it
backed up for me
um
my buddy uh Savage Gardens up in uh up
in Portland even did a little hybrid
using it it's called the Thai iced tea
it's like super super popular up there
right now that's true I do some [ __ ]
gnarly [ __ ] yeah he's got some cool bee
with hybrids he's made I I still follow
his stuff ever since meeting him at
Emerald cup 38 does nice stuff I guess
what I'm interested in asking is
do you have any reservations about the
authenticity of the Durban Thai high
flyer because I remember when I spoke to
um Bodhi he actually said to me that he
he wasn't speaking for certain or
anything but he said that over the years
there had been people who had come out
of the Woodworks with Durban Tire high
flyer clones and often he was skeptical
of the authenticity and he sort of said
that he suspected it was maybe like a
Durban tie leaning
um hybrid of the Durban Thai c99 because
that was sort of a more recent release
more accessible
have you ever thought maybe that's the
case and again this isn't anyone
speaking about the specific clone in
question it's just a general sort of
question yeah so I would say like well
as far as like that exact thing before
I made that DC 99 like the re-release
you know using a just a regular Durban
uh we had that that cutting like bar
beyond that point so it wouldn't be for
that unless it was the older DTC 99 from
what 2001 I think you know when they
when they did that something like that
um
I highly doubt it because that would be
a rare jump on its own and it would
probably be
um called and named as such so I kind of
kind of doubt that
um also
when Saul was you know smoking it you
know when I when I had gotten it
um he was like yeah that's that's it you
know that's what he remembered
um as well and I was like yeah it's
pretty pretty spot-on to me and it's
kind of the way it grows and
kind of a little different influences
from just a straight Durban so but the
thing is at the end of the day and I
mean this could be safe for him or
anybody that gets phones from somewhere
like do you really know right
do you really know what went on in
Holland do you really know that their
tie was authentic do you really know
this you really know that and that's
that's a that's a great thing to say
because there is a lot of uncertainty in
what what is what isn't
um and I was you know I won't I won't
say it but there's been a lot of
breeders to go on and get something and
breathe the [ __ ] out of it and then
years later you know after we've been
told year after year be like yeah well
that wasn't really this I guess it turns
out it was you know that right so you
know you gotta gotta be be weary for
sure you know and you you know always
try to stick to you know authentic
authentic sources and everything but
sometimes people's authentic sources
turn out to be uh be all [ __ ] up then
it comes out later you know and I've
seen uh you know I won't put their name
out there but you know
um I know I've seen it happen happen to
you guys man so
um you know we just gotta do our best
and
um you know just take uh take with what
we got and
um you know if everything points to yeah
this is legit and cool then you know you
can uh you can move forward that's what
I just try to do with you know straight
up people and people I really know and
you know it makes sense you know
especially if they gotta you know this
is hot right now that's where I got it
you know
um that's definitely a good thing
because there's so many people out there
that have this or that there's just so
many so many red flags I think you know
you're talking about that that dude
earlier like yeah [ __ ] old cornbread
Mafia roadkill skunk clone uh right here
when we go and change the game you're
looking at this picture and it says
[ __ ] plant it has a lot of readings
on it it was it was literally just the
seedling and you're talking like this 30
year old time taking pictures of them
but I was like you can literally see the
god of winds on the uh on the picture
so you know you got a lot of a lot of
[ __ ] people out there too so you
know it's definitely it's definitely a
tricky tricky situation a lot of times
but um yeah so
as best as I can say yeah yeah it's a
it's yeah it was a legit one
no I feel you for sure and uh I'm
definitely gonna go back in
post-production and like audio affect
his name out
which one which one was it what did I
say oh we'll we'll take off uh oh oh oh
oh oh oh
I [ __ ] that [ __ ]
you know so it's it's sort of
interesting that you mentioned many of
those things uh that you know talking
about when you get clones you know do
you really know what they are things
like that sort of vibe and I guess it it
segues well into the next question which
was that although it was around before
you went away I think it's really come
to the climax in the past 12 months but
the the Hop latent viroid is what I've
been calling recently it's it's the
covert of the Cannabis world you know
it's it's really really spreading around
do you have any concerns around your
plants having it and would you ever look
into any sort of like tissue culturing
to try to get rid of it if so
yeah I would definitely want to test
everything
um
first and foremost and I really would
like to uh
this tissue culture the whole the whole
collector one for backup purposes two
if anything's gone astray since I've
been found it was nice it'd be nice to
start cleaning spray from scratch you
know plus you know that is bigger and
all that stuff
that goes on as well
you know I feel like a good good way to
start you know what I mean
yeah of course and I mean I guess it's
probably too early for you to really
give definitive answers but are you
going to be much more apprehensive and
skeptical taking in clones moving
forward
oh absolutely I was always sketchy but I
was a real sketchy kid anyhow you know
so um yeah man that's the number one
thing that people thought about is they
just take in whatever they don't
quarantine and stuff but hey I guess now
the code's been going on everybody's
doing quarantines on themselves you know
it's like the same with those plants you
know keep them out of the population and
keep them locked down you know keep the
uh I don't know not just you know just
throw it up in the mix and ruin your
[ __ ] you know
yeah definitely I mean I know you've
spoken about it on the past so if you if
you feel like there isn't anything
really more to add I certainly
understand but we had a lot of people
ask about if you have any new tips or
trips for sort of your IPM or is it
still largely sort of what you used to
do
yeah it's it's generally like the same
you know kind of what always was anyway
and was going right back
[Music]
um just the basics are gonna keep you
away
fixing so you know don't take in strange
[ __ ] don't let this dirty ass people up
in you grow and help it don't play
anybody
um just the the basic keep it simple
um process you know just be clean uh
don't let the animals run around the
yard
um so many things
broad Minds the rest of my
um spider mites uh epithium a lot of
other the more the more common things
that people are dealing with that just
all starts with good clean practices and
it's not taking anything
uh that you don't know about especially
without
um
so just keep it basic and all these
basic principles and you'll find you
don't have to uh you don't really have
to deal with a whole lot other than
concentrating on this growing you know
yeah yeah I think that's that's really
it you got to resist the urge to bring
in the uh the new silver gelato runs and
and keep the keep the Haram safe so a
question that was both submitted by fans
and me personally I was interested to
hear about unfortunately
um you ended up going away sort of not
too long after one of the releases from
dominion and so I guess people didn't
really find out as much about the figure
four crosses as maybe they were hoping
and so I was wondering could you give us
any sort of description slash details of
the figure four and what you are hoping
to bring to the table with that mail oh
absolutely yeah it was a shame because I
didn't really get to speak on and
everything was tested and ready and
packed up and went out but it was
literally right at the same time I'm
like
[ __ ] he had a good deal with this right
quick and you know they lied about that
that Bond of course they did you know so
um I didn't get that chance to come back
out and talk more in depth about it but
you you actually if I'm not mistaken not
to witness at least one of the steps
um that was in in making the mail
so
you remember the ass man Airborne
skellystone yep
so that was that was the boy that ended
up getting developed and then hitting
the train
and the whole the whole process of
selecting that final nail out of that
height
was to hit OG type plants chem type
plants thick structure and still still
not take too much away from what was
there originally and though like have
you did you get to see any like Savage
headbands
I don't know if I saw them but I saw the
the Osman and the pollination from it
yeah yeah big beefy big beefy
[ __ ] so I really like the main
things I wanted to really get into
outside of like you know the of course
the main Terrapins and the potency and
all that good stuff I wanted to take
away from a lot of that that internodal
spacing and I wanted to make the
branching a lot stronger so that was
that was the the main the main goal with
that and just and it's alive I'm not man
just reinvigorate them and get some [ __ ]
that was coming out extra extra snake
but also extra extra strong higher
wielding and everything too
yeah that's that's a brilliant answer
and uh we had another listener who was
wondering you know they say look I I see
Duke's work with a variety of different
OG cushes over the years and I was just
wondering what do you prefer personally
and what do you think all day yo I knew
it I knew it I was like writing that
question and I they they'd been like
does he like headband ghost triangle and
I was like it's just triangle yeah that
TK and then as far as like because like
I never considered like headband being
an OG you know but you know if he did
then yeah
of course yeah nice and out of a
personal curiosity I remember a while
back you you toyed around with the
Blissful wizard just as a like a freebie
slash a little you know muck around sort
of project is that the cutting of
cookies that you think is the one you
would most breed with if you were going
to or it's not necessarily your favorite
cut of cookies
um it has really killed me I ain't gonna
wow that is some pillow weed
unfortunately it veggies slower than
blood
um and like yield wise you know it's
like yeah but and it and like I said
pokey's never really been my thing and
like when I did that
I just uh you know Savage you know he
was the one that wanted me to do it I
was just making some means for him and
he's like yeah dude's at school or
whatever and you know we made some for
him he's like yeah
you know just to be a cool guy so yeah
it was just a
just a thing man
yeah nice we had uh a customer who had
grown out the funky town freebie and
they were like I love it I just would
love to know what are the genetics
never
I thought you might do that
yeah man if you go into the genetics
then people start trying to get it and
it's just better just leaving leaving
that part out and just stay just enjoy
it you know there's something that could
have been could have been sold for a
high dollar and that was the whole point
was to give it away and uh
people enjoy it yeah okay can I can I
take one stab at one of the parents
go for it I don't know why I have no
idea why but for some reason I just
always remembered you did that Urban
slice like slice and urban slice and for
some reason I just my heart's Telling Me
Maybe that's maybe that's in it
somewhere
no no
either one of the parents there and all
the see all the urban slices were like I
had the the tequila if you know
smelled like you had a bottle of tequila
open and then the other ones are just
like some [ __ ] really insane one yeah
beautiful beautiful stuff I I know it's
like just most of them were better
versions of Tangy I think I only tried
one or two slice Finos but they were
they were great beautiful stuff
exactly exactly
and uh you know that was a that was a
real good one that was one of the
one of the projects that got left on
hold you know that I have to have to
pick up when I get out because I was
like yeah let me put some some Dominion
type orange out into the world
so
yeah hey before it leaves my mind you
know you you mentioned asked man a while
ago will we ever see that pop up in
another form or it would just be through
the figure four
um through the figure four but we did
something super cool and I did it I did
it for being brains because he hooked me
out with that MTF you know just to grow
out and [ __ ] yeah and I decided to be a
cool thing it's like [ __ ] it I'd ask man
would go really really really good on
that and uh so I hit it and I just sent
him a huge huge bag of seeds
[Music]
whatever you want this is just always
saying thank you or you know passing
something really special and old to me
to you know grow and enjoy and um and
did that so I guess
um
I guess probably by the time this comes
out it'll probably have already already
have happened he uh being the good dude
that he is is like bagging him up
sending them to James bean and we're
gonna we're gonna put them
put them out there you know to hook you
up I was like man you're too much man
that's awesome stuff
yeah the MTF crossed with the ass man
[ __ ] Christmas tree [ __ ] bugs some
like orange citrusy crazy [ __ ] going on
and just put your dick in the dirt take
potency on the on the heavy narcotic gun
that's awesome yeah you know as you as
you call thunderhole
as you started saying that I was like oh
I forgot to mention AK beam brains
earlier because he he had mentioned to
me that he was going to do that and I
was like oh he he donated some strands
as well
um yeah that's cool that's that's really
cool to hear I dig that a lot now you
got me thinking I think there was
someone else
anyway who knows probably not important
but um yeah Kudos AK band brains are a
really lovely guy who's always been very
lovely and helpful I mean now let's go
back to what we were talking about just
a moment ago and we're sort of in the
Realms of skunk and you know the slice
has got that skunk in it stuff like that
a lot of people are wondering do you
still have you know original skunk seeds
available to you or are you working with
the hybrids now
um I still have uh seeds from the last
time I did Ophelia on them
um I've done so much work you know
hybridizing them and and working them in
different ways seeing what's happening
what's not happening
um I wouldn't I wouldn't go back to the
starting point unless it's a whole a
whole another another project that I
found myself into
um and I don't I don't really have much
of that on my on my mind up at the
moment you know so
um I would use something I've hybridized
to them to go forward in a project if I
was going to go go that direction you
know
um now like with the slice for instance
you know it's like I would it was like
so like Calio it was just a weird stunt
number one you know type so that's what
like my curiosity felt that I was like
if I hit it with more Scotland like what
what happened you know and it was it was
pretty pretty [ __ ] awesome
yeah I I agree and you've you've sort of
got me interested now what are your
thoughts on the reincarnated version of
super sativa seed Club that's popped its
head out I don't know if you've paid
much attention to it or even got a
particular opinion on it but I'd be
curious to know
and it went it happened right after
or I mean excuse me right before I went
in and it had happened a couple times
prior to that and then people found out
it was just like a fake or a scam
um so I heard it and then then I was
gone so I never I never got to really
look back into it and it's kind of just
kind of
like you just reminded me about that so
I have to have to look at it like it's
legit right yeah well look I mean I
don't know it's it's hard to say but I
guess the the if I sort of wanted to
give you the dot points and have you
reflect on those I would say number one
there's no strain they're currently
selling now that was one of the former
ones what they're selling now are new
strains and there's only one or two that
I can see that uh of older lineage so I
guess with those dot points in mind I'm
sort of a little bit skeptical and and
likewise it hasn't made any waves since
releasing those strains
I would uh I would uh I could see where
that would happen
um
like the thing that I saw like before I
went out which kind of was just like
well I just kind of didn't really think
about it was like when I saw it and
somebody went to it they had like a
cookie hybrid and like you said there
was nothing
at all from from now yeah
all right all right so um so yeah I mean
that that's that'd be that'd be my
thoughts you know it's a little a little
odd I mean [ __ ] you got let me say back
to it
AK beam Brands probably God he's been
talking about me but uh I mean he's
going back to home and some other other
folks that he hangs around like and even
they got old stocks that they're working
with and bringing back like how are you
the the main the main company you know
so that would
you know because like that's what people
would ideally want I mean not to say
they wouldn't want anything new but you
know you would like to think you'd see
some of the old or at least some of the
old hybridizers some of the new or you
know some all New Creations something
you know but
yeah I don't know man I think I'm I'm
probably good on that
yeah I was surprised when I saw the
cookie hybrids and stuff and I was like
oh well but you know the other thing I
was thinking about is all of the notable
SSC sorry sssc strains were ones that
were pretty confident like they weren't
breeding in Amsterdam like you know like
the the skunk comes from Virginia and
Williams Wonder from Oregon and so it's
like they weren't the Breeders anyway
right and that that was the thing is
like they were like a Distribution
Company and like even like in a Solo
work for him uh for a while as like one
of their Distributors you know like he
would nail you know mail the packs out
and everything
um but all the the company was like it
was like a collection of breeders from
all over the place
that all put their put their words under
under that line like uh like a record
label or something and that's what made
them really awesome as what I felt was
like because you got such diversity in
so many different people Styles based
that made that awesome you know so
um yeah like that that was a cool cool
thing so yeah it's like it so it's not
surprising you know
um a lot of those guys probably like nah
I think I'm good I'll just hold on to my
[ __ ] or they're just not giving a [ __ ]
anymore it's just not what they do you
know that was a long time ago yeah
certainly
I mean sort of in that same vein I'm not
sure if you've seen But Todd McCormick
is selling what looks took realistically
be like real deal Northern Lights and
including the predecessors because he's
been able to strike up a relationship
with the guy who seems quite
legitimately verified as um well I know
and I'll uh Greg yeah and so I guess I'm
interested to know does that sort of
pique your curiosity at all given it
does seem to be some reasonable proof
that it could be legit or not so much
absolutely
yeah yeah like because especially like
when it's you know like I got I don't
know I'm like you know personally or
anything but
you know he's a stand-up dude has a good
reputation of being a stand-up dude and
stand-up people deal with the guy like
you know that you know there's a
reputation proceeds him you know so
there's that
um you know I know Greg you know like
that that's that's legit right so that
that tells me like you know hey for me
like that's a go for sure I would get it
I would grow it absolutely
yeah no it's like I guess I was just
curious like particularly because he's
also selling like skunk and I was like
oh I wonder if that had caught your eye
either
I haven't I haven't got really it's been
so busy just answering all the DMS I'm
still answering once from almost two
weeks ago [ __ ] um
so yeah just catching up with people and
working on like some real new projects
like the soil line on the new line
other other little things
um it's been taken up a lot of time plus
doing the whole song and dance of here
so
um yeah man I'll definitely definitely
have to work it at all man
yeah look I I you know what I sort of
feel bad as a as I hear you say that
because I I understand where you're
coming from you probably probably still
figuring out what way is up and down
time to do that sort of stuff one of the
more lighthearted questions we got was
uh how much did you miss barbecue
a lot God so much like just raw food
this human food in general
funny is is greatly greatly missed you
know so uh yeah it's a good General man
but we have already especially
definitely a big one on the list very
barbecue deficient in my system now
so we had another person who was
wondering they sort of we're hoping to
get some clarification on what exactly
skunk you were using and I think that
maybe what they're referring to is like
maybe sometimes it said basic skunk
sometimes it said skunk and are they the
same thing because I think if you look
online something says Basics Gunk is
like nl5 skunk or something but yeah
just hoping to get some clarification
around like what was it that you were
toying with exactly
yeah so like if if it was you know stump
one it was you know noted as noted as
comp one and it's just old DVC Club
Scott
they got Billy old uh building a link in
red
um they were the forces of course the
ears just maintaining it or whatever
um and then the basic side yeah it's
like you know skunk and I was going for
a Shiva Stone to uh you know you know
she was a nice time so that was a that
was a hybrid of totally totally
different different
ah okay yeah no that makes a lot of
sense
yeah more Indica in Florence you know uh
and more a little bit heavier on the era
on the narcotic you know side of things
yeah look in that same vein we had
received about three questions from
people who were just curious about
specifically one of the parents in the
Local H the Cuttlefish hash plant they
were just wondering if you could give us
any information on these there's even I
myself looked around very little info
about it online
oh yeah it wasn't and like when we had
this back in the days before the big you
know legal weed world and all that
really blown up and it was kind of a
tight tight little cut being held you
know back then
um
really really really strong [ __ ] uh
skunky nose on it
um nice fat fat [ __ ] buds
strong Branch like it you know it's it's
hard hard to beat
um and unfortunately like I don't know
that's that's not my not my possession
anymore you know so that you know the
closest thing I have any relationship is
the one thing that it's done and I don't
I don't know anybody that's got any more
than one dude that hooked it up you know
he's he's dead now so
um yeah I really couldn't tell you I'd
be surprised I ever ever see it again
but who knows he calls somebody's
holding on to it out there
yeah maybe but I mean like the Local H
it feels like that embodies some of the
characteristics I'd have to imagine
right
oh yeah absolutely it came out a lot a
lot on the smell and the effect you know
um and then having that that Sour Diesel
on the next two and just you know really
really brought all these good points
together like you you smoke local and
it's pure you know what I mean so uh you
kind of know what I'm what I'm talking
about some funky ass weed
oh yeah and even the local hybrids I've
tried are all killer like consistently
yeah yeah it was definitely uh
definitely just it's a good breeder too
and it's just non-chenic plant first day
great got about everything that you want
in it you know it's like a no-brainer to
uh you know toy around with a little bit
so you know let's see what happens you
know and then
Crystal winner
that's awesome that's awesome
so someone had a question about the
shine apple and it's interesting because
I'd sort of noticed some of these things
they raised myself but they say what
percentage approximately of the shine
Apple Finos have like that leaf mutation
where it's like just you know one or a
couple of leaves and specifically the
reason why they were asking is because
this person likes you know those sort of
mutant plants and we're just wondering
what's their chances how many packs
would they need to buy to be sort of
reasonably certain they might come
across one hey you found a freak in
every pack man that was definitely a
freaky one
oh really it was it was that sort of uh
high oh yeah oh for sure like it like
even in my testing phase like when
they're in bed I was like oh [ __ ] what
we got going on here it's like oh it's
gonna be really good or really bad so
let's uh let's see what goes goes down
here you know and uh yeah man came out
came out killer but yeah definitely you
see a lot of freaks freaks in the mix
and how do you approach that
commercially as a breeder where you're
like look there's killer seed line but
there's some people who just might not
like they might just think oh it's a run
I've got to call it and like then and
you know what I mean they're sort of
preemptively doing things without
realizing do you have to consider that
or it's just irrelevant to you
I mean what you know whatever people who
are gonna do uh and ultimately
ultimately they're gonna do uh if they
see freaks or rods or anything and they
decide to call it it's like
that's generally I've always been a bad
move like most of the best plants I've
ever grown were a little bit slower
um a little bit freakish you know and
it's just I always figured like you know
ones that were a little slower is like
they were taking their energy it's going
to go somewhere it's got that energy in
the plant that's going to be producing
something and obviously it's not biomass
and fast edging so wow I'm thinking uh
it's going to be later on in flower and
uh typically yeah it's always super off
the chart Frosty and stinky or something
you know like that energy went somewhere
just
you know like that like dog must be whiz
early like I should Frosty's spot steak
and as we really kill her the slowest
vegging thing I think I've ever grown
and definitely a mutant noise
yeah definitely well I was wondering
have you ever seen any other cuttings
where like when you do a certain
combination you equally get these weird
mutants
yeah
um I used to always notice uh when I was
growing a lot of bogs work I would get a
lot of patio buds you know like little
weird things like that
um
there were certain other things I've
read like where I get like the flat the
flats down you know that's like you know
not rounded black
um weird Leaf mutation a little [ __ ]
like that you know I've always kind of
encountered it fairly fairly regularly
you know
um
and even like when you start growing out
larger larger numbers and [ __ ] yeah
you'll see a lot of little odd odd
little things you know
um yeah that's really interesting
interesting you'll have to make like
your own Ducks foot out of it yeah
long term long term while we're on the
topic of cultivation I want to quickly
get this one out there earlier on you
mentioned with the purple Dahlia that um
you know you put the warning on the pack
saying you know this can can Herm and I
was reading about it and you're sort of
saying you know if you feed humic acid
with these G13 hash plant hybrids like
it can just sometimes happen and I guess
the question is well it doesn't like it
yeah like how long did it take you to
figure that out that seems like it would
have taken me like a lifetime to be like
it's the humic
nah not not one man
um
so
you know when when testing you know
as you know like you know I would I
would try to put things through the
ringer like go on purpose you know and
there were other things that I would I
would do where I'm like not feeding at
all you know just plain water just to
see what like are you still gonna get
the results of this straight up water
um and when when doing that the ones
that we're getting a feed with the uh
with the humic and everything certain
ones would pop up like hey what what are
you what are you doing there you know
and
you know one with the one with the plane
plain amount of water wasn't you know so
I'm like all right it's like the feeding
thing so let me uh let me back off on a
lot of things you know and I think I
just went
just straight up
dragonfly got flowers
and then I think I just made like a back
one of you some earthworm castings and
then it didn't happen
so I'm like all right so I doubt it's
just Allied water or you know anything
else that that might have might have
been hit with it I was like what about
the human so then I reintroduced hammock
and and boom that happened again so take
it away nothing
and not every single you know you know
but certain ones it did happen like that
when you do it does and you don't don't
mean like hey you know you know he makes
uh he makes doing it right here and I'm
discussing with the
the
more uptake of uh phosphorus at that
time and just it didn't like that you
know it just wasn't wasn't digging
interesting yeah I mean that's actually
it makes sense like you're able to sort
of systematically figure it out like
that I I like that a lot yeah because
you know I don't feed much you know it's
pretty pretty simple pretty simple
approach so it's not a whole whole lot
of things to really diagnose you know
yeah yeah now that that actually
simplifies quite a bit well we've just
got a few fan submitted questions before
we get into the final ones I kind of
like that it's a new thing man that
you're doing
fans
didn't have that before that I mean a
bit we'll go on from our buddy true
cannabis and he says what's your
favorite chem dog cutting and what's if
you had to give just one definitive
answer or what strain do you think was
the bud that the first chem seeds came
from
oh animals good good question so
and second one threw me off because I
don't know what I must say but um
what was the first question what's your
favorite
oh that's right uh 91 91 hands down
um that was uh that was nothing you know
to me I think it's the that's the best
one here here so on the Kim where do I
think it came from as far as like just a
mom or both parents if if he yeah just
the female what was the actual bud that
the seed came out of
good answer good answer and so uh the
next question uh what's your overall
all-time favorite strain
oh
[ __ ] up question
you're a monster
um and that's so impossible
you know that's such an impossible
because it depends on you know the time
of day and everything else oh man
all right how about I make it a bit
easier for you one of the final
questions we normally ask is if I'm
gonna drop you off on an island and you
can take three strains with you for the
rest of your life they can either be
clones or you can just take a pack of
the seeds what are you gonna take okay
[ __ ]
yeah real fast
um
I'm gonna say Local H Screaming Eagle
and 91. nice you got you got a lot of uh
different bases or maybe even
yeah like but yeah that that would I
think that would be good to go there
good and would you take just your clones
or would you take a pack of seeds of
each if I was taking uh Voodoo
definitely a pack Screaming Eagle it'll
take a pack of seeds just because you're
on a desert island like you know I don't
know what you got to do if you get
something to do it right
um
and yeah then if it was like 91 and
local it would just be good yeah yeah
okay so the next one this is an
interesting one that I've sort of been
wondering about myself do you have any
idea what's causing more and more weed
to have those tiny little premature
seeds in the calyxes
yeah so me and my a boy pig farmer
um
we had this talk back in life
it was like
2016 even and we call them like micro
beans you know
um
I I really went with
because it wasn't every genetic
you know what I mean there's a certain
thing
and
we were really really in like it's a
beating a feeding thing are we are we
pushing too hard
you know what I mean is that what is or
is it the actual thing that we are
feeding you know so we got the got to
thinking about that and what I came to
was like look
you grow your clone your way on the
regimen that you're doing and he was on
like a very
strict regimen you know he's he's a real
producer like that dude my God that [ __ ]
pump some [ __ ] butt out and I'm of
the highest highest quality you know so
um
I take the same stuff and I'm growing it
growing it on my on my own doing it
totally on my way and when I was doing
it I wasn't I wasn't getting up and he
still was
um same type of lighting right the same
same environmental so we could we could
scratch scratch that part
um but it's it's something to do with
the nutrient and I I guess I feel like
if it's not a very particular
ingredients and a nutrient that was in
their mind that wasn't you know
something I was doing
or it just came from just pushing too
hard because the weird thing was you
wouldn't see any bananas
you didn't see any herbs but you got
these little bastards would pop up from
something somewhere you know so and like
I said they never developed I don't like
your beans so that one still to say that
one would kind of elude me but it's
something something to do with either an
ingredient that you know certain people
have in a regimen that they're feeding
um or pushing hard so if you're if
you're that person and you know you're
not pushing hard
um
look look at look at what you are
feeding and then just try to
start pulling things out you know one at
a time until you that you figure it
because if you figure it out then you
say well a lot of people a whole lot of
trouble you know
yeah I I hadn't actually thought of that
but that's that's a pretty reasonable
explanation isn't it
another question we got which is
actually something I would love to know
the answer to Is what is your preferred
way to collect pollen ideally to sort of
store so storing pollen is kind of kind
of kind of tricky
um long term I guess you know like when
I think storing I'm thinking like you're
putting it away for for a later date and
time
um the main key to it is
when you're sifting it out like you
really got to sift that [ __ ] there
cannot be any any plant material at all
um preferably in a low humidity
environment you know that would be a
bonus because the your main enemy is
going to be moisture than the other day
that's going to sterilize it so
make sure that you got no plant material
in it
um because of course that plant there's
no moisture in it and you're [ __ ] and
then uh keep it away from moisture and
when you're putting it away
um and I'll make sure that it's
not not going to incur any any moisture
there either so very well sealed up to
where uh you're not rapidly changing
temperature because one thing I noticed
with a buddy put some away did
everything perfect
brings it right out of the freezer sets
it down on the table and he's just got
it got it in this little Rubbermaid
thingy
cuts off the FoodSaver bag it sits there
hey what happens when you get real cold
coming in through a warm warm area in a
condensation
nice [ __ ] kills it all
I know don't do that so um
my little tip of the day and huh
that's cool I just realized it'll be a
play on words
tip of the day you tip
so there's your Q-tip of the day
um collect pollen on a few tips like and
this is like you know for the small
batch like you're just making [ __ ] at
home just to see what's up not for
making a fun OC before yeah but I'm just
taking it
and getting two tips and getting them
all nice and covered and Hauling and put
them in bags seal them up and then put
them away for for a later time I could
take those out and uh pollinate you know
just single buds you know to get you
know 50 seats so you know so you can you
can do that for the hobbyist
um for the guys who are making uh [ __ ]
tons of seed
good answer good answer I tried to do it
in the past myself with flour and that
that is not a good method
I don't like that either man I'm like I
don't like to add anything to it you
know yeah yeah I think the flower like
sterilizes it and is maybe even
hydroscopic in itself but anyway this is
one that like it's almost redundant but
I feel like we have to ask at this point
do you think that we're ever gonna get
like a roadkill skunk that comes out to
the community or do you think we're
going to recreate it or do you think
it's just maybe not entirely what we
remember
no I think I think that a lot of times
people will have some
some really skunky weed and like I hate
the word or the term red kill skunk you
know
um just from all the [ __ ] that goes on
with it from that especially like that
one guy anyway so
um I think a lot of people don't really
hit the genetic potential on a lot of
their growing
um certain plants are more forgiving and
the terpenoid range like
you know durbins and cookies Jack hairs
and a lot of things it just doesn't
matter at all the smell always comes out
there's a lot of things you really gotta
nail it man and you're not going to see
a whole lot of that outside of Organics
that are done like really really Primo
so I think a lot of times people get the
stuff and they they don't hit the uh
they don't hit the marks and they they
add it they just didn't quite get it
um
I do believe that yeah somebody somebody
could definitely put it out there you
know and work it take you know years of
work and put it into a seed form and you
know have everybody ran Rave try to rip
it off and you know act like [ __ ]
[ __ ] about it
um but you know that that's gonna take a
special type of person who wants to do
all that
and uh that ain't gonna be me thank you
so so yeah I mean it's it's there it's
there to be worked it's just you know
somebody somebody's gonna have to put in
the work to do it and decide what
they're going to do at the end of The
Journey if they're going to put it out
there
just hang on to it be happy it's kind of
kind of preserved you know but there's
just so many things that could be you
know skunky weed you know it doesn't
have to be like you know it's not a pure
skunk variety or anything like that
there's a lot of you know Afghan hybrids
Ash plant hybrids and
all types of stuff they can give them
the desired fact at the end of the day
but then ultimately it's going to be up
to the grower to you know do their thing
and grow it because back when yeah I
lost skunk you eat you know people grew
up a little bit differently too so
um you know I think there's a lot of
inputs that people don't don't use
nowadays that we're being being used
back then and people miss out on a lot
of that stuff too uh it's just doesn't
matter
yeah that's an interesting take I
definitely think that the style in which
we grow Now versus then has something to
do with it for sure but that brings us
on to the final quick fire questions and
I'm gonna have to word this one I'm
gonna have to think a little bit about
how I word it but basically I'm
wondering if there were theoretically
people in jail who did smoke weed
was there a particular experience that
people thought was quite memorable
[Applause]
yeah so
I kind of I got a story about a friend
and a legend friend she might have
allegedly got that right
and instantly he's like oh man because
like by the way they pissed us back
so just you know like it could it could
get hit randomly if you you just dirty
like it's a very bad thing so all the
time he's like hey man okay all right
you think I'm good you think I'm all
right you think I'm fine oh no dude
you're [ __ ] yeah you know like they're
gonna say oh man damn I mean this is
like within an hour his eyes are already
oh man like should I just drink a bunch
of water what should I do they just
total [ __ ] paranoia and this goes on
for weeks like I mean you think I'm okay
by now like I'm you know and I'm like
yeah mine's effect well I'm not really
fat I'm saying I don't know man I don't
know a couple pounds
I don't know man it's pretty iffy off
man oh you think they're gonna call me
uh it dude and I enjoyed [ __ ] with
them every [ __ ] day because I passed
on the on the opportunity allegedly
if that ever happened and
um and for for that reason because I
know that that would be this is probably
the worst thing to [ __ ] do like it'd
be great it's been on the same token man
or where you would instantly regret it
from the exhale it would not be
enjoyable at all you know for sure man
that's that's an interesting one I hope
uh your friend was it was all good
oh yeah yeah allegedly he was he was
fine
yeah it was all he walked in so the next
question is what's the one cutting you
missed the most
um like currently in this in this moment
if I had one just rock it out real quick
well like just overall something you had
at some point in the past that just
isn't around anymore and you're like man
I missed that that cuttlefish was a
pretty big pretty big hit and we were
already talking about it earlier so
you know
that's that's definitely
definitely that one and I had a uh had a
female
um out of a sour IBL
um from back in the day that was like
way better than the original original
sour and uh I missed that one a lot yeah
it was awesome
yeah good one to pick Ubuntu pick
so the next question is
is there a question that you wish you
could ask one of the other breeders out
there alive or dead
oh
I would probably if I had the
if I had to pick one
I'll pick somebody who's no longer with
us because they're alive so I still got
that chance you know
um
and there's a lot of dudes you know
alive I'd still like this ticket with
and just
you know talk to like I know shiny
bottles always want to always kind of
wanted to
I was picked as pick his brain a little
bit he's a good one no it was a few but
probably have to go for another one to
sit down behind I'd have a lot of a lot
of questions too because he got to see
so many things growing on such a large
scale back then
um
and be you know asking about all types
of little little traits you know that
that he was picking on
in these large populations that led him
to do what he did because they were they
were truly starting from
very very swaggy Beginnings man and to
see the work that he ended up with at
the at the end that was being released
[ __ ] amazing those guys were really
[ __ ] doing it man
you know yeah so yeah that that would be
one my one probably
brilliant answer brilliant answer I'd
probably have to likewise do the same
second last question what's the most
disappointing weed experience you ever
had so maybe it's like something that
was really hyped and just fell short
um
[Laughter]
oh man that's a dangerous question
um
there have been so many
yeah
I don't think I could say just just one
I'm thinking like things that I've I've
learned personally but
um
probably say like you've been with me
you've been with me at the shows before
yeah so can you remember people like
just bringing it bringing random Buds
and everything else yeah
um there's a lot of [ __ ] up bud that
would come our way yeah it's not taking
this out and telling me yeah
don't feed coping off after the whole
cycle you're [ __ ] yourself up here
and then laterally come back and be like
wow I made all the difference in the
world like yeah for sure
um
and sometimes these stuffed with powdery
mildew on it and everything
um
I guess
man
I don't even want to say it because oh I
used to hate her you know because
it wasn't even the real so like back in
the day like I got turned on to like to
smoke some cookies that was like the
real the real legit cut I like that like
that was pretty good but it was like
some of the offshoots or the knockoffs
is like wow this is just you just get
kind of like a little buzz for a few
minutes when it's gone you know tastes
good but it's just nothing no sustenance
do it man it's just not not doing
anything and like
when you hear the person with this guy
just raving about it you know and we're
just like ah I don't know man that real
one was you know kind of kind of kind of
what's up you know but
I was let down by a lot of the a lot of
the hybrids and [ __ ] like that
yeah look certainly not a sentiment new
to us we've heard that before for sure
and there's like a few of them that
stood out like really good like exotic
Mike had that cookies and cream that was
like really good
you know
um there were like a few that stood out
I was like wow that's actually good
um but yeah a lot of them and they're
just like yeah whatever
yeah yeah I think everyone's grown out
of cookie hybrid before and usually
you'll find some weird mutant in there
that just totally fails and you're like
okay okay we're done here
so our final question for this one
if you had to pick one genetic or strain
that's just gonna be erased from
existence and all the Prodigy from it
are gone
which one you're gonna do
oh my God
um I'm gonna I'm gonna answer this
and everybody's like oh yeah no
[Music]
I'm gonna take out pieces all right I'm
gonna take out the [ __ ] beasters the
top 44 or whatever I'm gonna call it the
Viking that [ __ ] clone
and the beasters yeah that needs to be
striking stricken from uh from existence
for sure but yeah
that that was that was a bad heavy
non-resonated shitty buds yeah it's long
for way too much money across college
campuses and heady boys you know like
yes
half [ __ ] the beasters dude now it needs
to be gone freaking from the record I
love it man a humanitarian at heart
doing something for the people it's
beautiful
yeah it needs to be put with Lex Luthor
in that [ __ ] plate glass thing or
another dude some Superman or I put them
in the glassy cinnamon outer space
that's when the beasters needs to go
with them
well I I think that just about brings us
to the end for this one were there any
comments or shout outs you wanted to
make
man
um
just everybody that you know is
supported before during and after
everything
um thank y'all so much and I've got a
lot of cool [ __ ] coming uh in the future
and thanks for uh coming along on the
journey uh
any of the [ __ ] out there you know
what I mean
uh eat [ __ ] and [ __ ] die
straight up
um luckily that ain't paying very many
people you know what I mean but uh you
know I don't want to be a negative guy
so
um just thanks to everybody and uh a lot
of cool stuff coming in the future and
uh definitely gonna pay it back and pay
it forward and uh do a good job for
everybody and a lot of cool [ __ ] coming
down the pipe always and upwards
and it's just you know how it is man you
mentioned one person right and you start
going down the list you [ __ ] slip
forget that one person man they're gonna
be [ __ ] pissed so I'm not gonna go
down that route everybody knows you know
I love for me and uh I know I got a lot
of love to run back so y'all know who
you are and uh yeah thanks for
everything
so again you know a huge thank you for
coming back on the show The the skunk
commander and The Man Behind Dominion
Seed Co Duke Diamond thank you again
and thank you for having me on buddy you
know I like I like your as you would say
I'm very very keen and keen on you and
your uh your podcast
[Music]
so there we have it friends what'd you
think
good to hear from our buddy Duke
I've got a soft spot for him as well
as always huge shout out to our sponsors
seats here now number one seed bank in
the game copper biological systems you
know me love them check them out for all
the Predators to keep your garden happy
and healthy Pro mix connect
the best mycorrhiza in the game
[Music]
shout out good buddies at Charlie's
cannabis best counter in the game you're
in Oklahoma hit him up guys you will not
find better quality trust me
[Music]
and last but not least a huge shout out
to the patreon supporters you guys the
lifeblood of the show we could make
episodes happening without you if you'd
like to help support the show and ensure
future episodes happen please go check
out the patreon at www.patreon.com
[Music]
exclusive unheard content additional
episodes so much more check it out
[Music]
I think that just about does it guys
I'll catch you for the next one
[Music]