hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts
as always this episode was brought to
you by
seeds here now you know they're the best
in the seed game guarantee not on
germination but on satisfaction as well
as well as 420 australia your premier
store for 420 lifestyle and apparel and
finally organic gardening solutions your
one stop shop for all those gardening
needs
[Music]
on this episode we're joined by the one
and only odie of homegrown natural
wonders
talking all things homegrown natural
wonders breeding time wrecked males and
more
let's get into it
alrighty so a huge hello thank you and
welcome to odie of homegrown natural
wonders thanks so much for joining us
today
well hello there how are you doing today
i'm doing good so first question what
are you currently smoking on
right at the moment i just loaded up a
bowl of dr who
from geek farms
master cut it's one of my faves to go to
it's very relaxing
you know the doctor who's very high
immersing so
it's i find it really relaxing
you just jump straight to one of my
questions so one of one of the biggest
things i wanted to ask you i think a lot
of people including myself gained a lot
of familiarity with your brand through
the exposure that geek mic
gave you guys kind of with that doctor
who cut so the question is
how impactful has it been to have
something like that happen to your brand
to kind of have a really good grower
find this killer cut and run with it
well pretty good um doctor who's
definitely one of our top sellers
yeah everybody that grows it seems to
like it
um there's quite a bit of it around
and uh yeah i know i'm
i'm i'm a huge fan of geek farms we're
obviously really good friends
and uh yeah i'm
excited for all their success and future
success as well as i know he is for ours
as well
so
did the success of the doctor who kind
of immediately make it a candidate in
your mind for like maybe a male in
future breeding crosses or was it
not the immediate thought
no it was definitely an immediate
thought um actually the one that came up
the whole doctor who thing and did the
original doctor who crossed was my son
donovan
um
him and him and his brother and my
oldest son um ray they got together and
did this whole thing and
planned out all kinds of plants that you
know we had to make stuff
multiple times before we got to their
end game of what they wanted it to be so
as we started you know cruising through
that yeah
we knew we would always want a doctor
whomel and we picked one now
okay and so what type of females do you
think would pair well with doctor who
so actually um we just recently did a
bunch of crosses with our doctor who mel
um
17 different strains different moms
cross the two
uh sfv lemon g
um just a whole slew of uh
standard old goodies you know old cuts
and whatnots and uh most of them came
out pretty well
the doctor whom male that we picked uh
was chosen
for specific structure and smell that it
had
and uh we're wanting to do the doctor
who down to about an f5 f6 to get to
where
the actual what the doctor who is going
to be when it's completed you know kind
of like how it regen how the doctor
regenerates all the time right
um
i like that so um he he was picked for
how close he was resembled the grape
high chew cut that we run
um it uh very sweet very grapey
and it's very dominant in the crosses
that we saw
it was kind of interesting
we even we even crossed them to a
forum cut
cookies the one of my friends asked me
if i would do so
there you go and so just as a quick
little side question out of all the
cookies which one's your favorite
honestly i'm not a big cookies fan um i
would not have i've never grown cookies
um
i
would not have done the cross if my
friend would not have asked me
so
obviously he's a pretty good pretty
close friend
yeah there you go okay and so just as
another little cookies question
do you feel like at this point
it's kind of been able to solidify
itself as one of those elite clones or
do you think it's still just kind of
like a hypey thing
well you know it's probably an elite
column sure it definitely is in certain
circles especially here in california um
you know a lot of there's a lot of
places that are cookies everybody likes
the cookies and don't get me wrong the
cookie dough flavor is nice um
i only kind of wish that some of them
produced better
the different cuts right
so automatically you want to find a mill
that's going to add your size and your
weight and you know try to keep the
flavor
but instead of hitting him yeah instead
of i'm just not a big fan of it it was
uh
i was something that i was offered at a
very early age when it came out and
turned it down and haven't grown it
since i've never grown it actually
there you go well on that note early age
let's take us back what was your first
experience with cannabis
wow
seven eight years old probably
um smoking uh cannabis with the cousin
of mine actually
um
our parents grew um and uh it was all
over and all around you know we're
talking the 70s so
it was
at that point in time in the in the
family the family that i was in and
there was plenty abundant
and it wasn't like
my parents didn't know that i was
smoking but my cousin and i sure were
taking some to smoke so yeah
haha there you go and do you know what
strains they were back then or it was
just whatever
oh yeah i just it was just whatever you
know yeah we had no clue
um we're never really in on those
conversations really to know what was
what uh we found the hash stash every
now and again you know that was always
nice
um but yeah normally just buds here and
there they were definitely nothing like
what we smoked today looking at these
yeah okay and so what was the
progression to you becoming a grower
yourself
um
lived with my mom for a while and then
uh hip teenage years she couldn't handle
me anymore so she sent me to my father's
at the age of 14
who was living in northern idaho and
growing
garage fulls of marijuana
so he kind of handed me a book and
said get up in the attic start doing
this start doing that and that pretty
much started me growing was when i was
14.
nice and which book did he give you
you know
um
right off the top of my head i don't
remember but it's one of the old clouds
it's an old classic yeah i don't
remember right at the moment yeah maybe
like an rc clark thing or something
um
no it was um
frank mel frank and
rosen i want to say it was rosenthal but
um grower's bible
yeah okay
like a 1982
version or something like that had a big
old pot had a big old bud cola on the
front pitch on the front cover and
yeah i had that book for a long time
cool yeah that's a good good mentor
i actually uh re-found it at pal pals
books there in uh portland
and in the used book section and bought
it for my father so you could
have it back
that's neat full circle
so during those early days when you were
growing was there any notable strains
that went around in your area or was it
just really everything wasn't having
names at that point
well and we're i was living in a
northern idaho point in time and skunk
was king i mean
there was there were several really good
strains not really any names with much
of them then
um
but yeah i mean i was still in junior
high so we weren't really that concerned
with it we were more concerned that
five bags later and you're still
smelling it and pretty ridiculous to
walk anywhere with it
yeah so did you have any recollections
of the roadkill skunk or what are your
thoughts on it in general
um
scott yeah i know i i love skunk i've
been searching for it ever since i've
left idaho
um
the closest thing that i've seen is what
duke is putting out
and i think that if anybody's going to
find the old old-school roadkill it's
going to be him they have it
and do there's there's a lot of kind of
discussion around the whole idea and
something which i'm interested in is the
idea that maybe there was not
necessarily one roadkill skunk but it
was more of kind of like a profile which
maybe popped up in one or two different
strains do you think there's any maybe
credence to that or do you think no it
was very much just one clone
yeah no i would totally agree with that
um myself i kind of look back to uh
the popular strains and go back a year
or two and see what war was happening
and most likely that's where it came
from as whatever region we were having a
war in
yeah okay interesting
so what are your thoughts on the land
races in terms of like would you
consider working them or no um i have a
good buddy too he's doing a bunch of
work with some land races right now
we've all donated a bunch of latin race
seed stock that we had so that he could
uh start working with that
um
yeah you know
so i think that the plant has used us to
progress itself along as most things do
right i mean we take it everywhere we've
given it life in existence and
we've done a lot for the plant as far as
the plant also does a lot for us don't
get me wrong the least bit um but it's
manipulated us to where we do all this
crazy stuff for it
and uh
is it progression the way that it should
be uh with us doing all the inner
breeding and cross-breeding and
multi-quad
polyprop you know poly breeding and all
that um
you know i
i think that it's progressing away as
long as what you're making is better
than what it was
but to work with land races a lot of
land races are run really long
and uh
you know
there's a reason why the when you look
at a picture of the buds in the high
times from the 70s
and you look at a picture of the buds
from the high times now
it's a huge difference which would you
rather you know it's which would you
rather smoke first off negan and land
races are nice they're very unique highs
very unique flavors
um but nowadays we're more about the
strong potencies and maybe even stronger
or more isolated flavors
um
but yeah to work with some land races i
have a few ibl's in stock and we play
with them every now and again but uh
that's that's a long project because you
need to
you know outcross land races are strong
you see those for and ibl's are strong
you see those for generations down the
line obviously but what characteristics
are you looking for and what
characteristics do you want
to grab from it and get it to express
well i guess it begs the question right
what would you like to bring to the game
because i think the modern criticism of
cannabis is that there's this kind of
same same amongst everything and that
there's also
like this ceiling where you can only get
so high whereas a lot of people would
argue that with certain land races you
would just you know the more you smoke
the further you would go
are those the type of things you would
be looking to bring into modern crosses
yeah no absolutely um
i've
you know
when when people describe that and i
remember you know i started smoking
fairly young so i started smoking
mid to late 70s
do i remember everything no do i know
all the names you know
but i do remember a lot of the effects
and a lot of the ways that it made me
feel
and i'm able to use that
to uh kind of guide me in what i
what my memory is
so
if i could find the land races from back
then that made me feel that way
absolutely i'd love to play with them
because yeah they were
you know but then again was it my age
was it because i had nothing else to
compare it to
you know that all comes into a factor as
well but
um
yeah i would like to uh definitely get
there are some land races that i would
like to play with if i could find
you know
true
seeds of
and which ones are they
more of your afghanis more of your
hindu mountains areas more indicators
i'm more of an indica guy
um i'm not much into the sativas
yeah okay
um you may or may not have heard about
this it's kind of been on instagram i
got tagged in it a few times there's
kind of been some talks about like the
origins of the triangle kush
having coming out recently and basically
you know to cut a long story short it's
meant to be some old-school cali strain
called emerald triangle across to hindu
kush i don't suppose you've heard about
this kind of little saga at all and if
so if not what do you think about you
know kind of that as a potential
genetics do you see any hindu kush in
the triangle kush
well you know i actually i have heard a
little bit of read a little bit about
that my kind of thoughts on that is that
they're just now coming out without
information
right you know um what
all of a sudden you just woke up oh yeah
we crossed that for this and created
this yeah you know
i don't know that's that's kind of hard
to swallow
um the people that are saying it though
um you know i know them and uh
they have done a lot of things you know
there's a lot of good strains that
they've done um
so i don't know but having you know
um we just had chrome over at the garden
here a couple days back looking at some
of their genetics that we just
germinated over there and uh
you know he's pretty infamous for the tk
and a lot of tk crosses and stuff so
um i didn't talk with him about it but i
do know what you're talking about and
there's a couple of things that you know
come to question in my head
yeah okay so i think people are going to
be wondering out of the swamp boys gear
which ones did you decide to jam
oh good guy i don't have the list with
me so we did two different germinations
of seeds the first one was 6 300 seeds
the next one was 2 800 seeds
so
it was several breeders and several
strains
unfortunately i could not rattle them
off without having my list in front of
me um i could tell some of the breeders
but i couldn't definitely tell you all
the strains
yeah i don't think anyone would expect
you to remember with a list that big but
the question which jumps to mind is
how many seeds of each strain would you
like to run when you do a pheno hunt of
that size
at least a hundred
great answer
you know um that way you're getting
50 to 60 females to look at
pretty harsh you know they fall over we
don't stick them up it's cloudy to
school when you're a seedling
um we don't baby them in any way shape
or form and survival with fitness
out of all those seeds we came back with
3 700 females that we looked through
and um have picked maybe 400 to bring
back out of
to reveg
wow yeah because that's that was going
to be my next question when you do a
phenomenon of that size how long does it
take you to actually discern the winner
because as you just kind of implied
there's probably going to be a lot that
are really neck and neck at that end
point it's like heart you've got to do
them again and again type of thing
most definitely um there is several that
are neck connect
um you know and that's the thing is you
grow them out to
almost completion before you want to
re-veg them or clone them and re-veg
them or however so that you can see all
its final traits
um but yeah it's really close on a lot
of them um one of them might have just a
little bit better structure or you know
because it got bent here or something or
restrained here maybe it didn't perform
as well as it could have
and you think maybe it performed better
next time
so it's two pretty much
three within three runs we'll be down to
maybe one percent of the 400
so maybe 40 strains
wow and and how many end keepers would
you ideally like to keep at the end of
it all
that's rough at that point that's when
you're getting down pretty nitty gritty
um
you know so i mean because we've got a
lot of counteratta we've got a lot of
caramel we've got a lot of swamp boys
we've got oni we've got
i mean you know a whole bunch of the
great the great breeders out there that
were that were
privileged enough to germinate a lot of
seeds of
um
and uh they are all just so fantastic
it's really hard to pick one you know i
would rather window it down to maybe two
or three per breeder
than um just two or three strains
overall kind of a thing
um just because
you know because a breeder is more more
of an artist and you know they're
they've painted this picture for you to
kind of color in so
um
i would definitely i think
i'm shooting for that rap we haven't
completely decided all that way yet um
but yeah that's kind of where i'm
thinking
and so the end goal of doing this big
phenohunt besides obviously having the
clone is it to kind of offer that to the
market or more so as a breeding queen
oh no it's for market um it's um
we're doing this at one of our
clients
facility
and
yeah it's totally for their market for
them to be able to bring to the market
and have variety and diversity
yeah nice that's a great answer and so
one of the things i'm thinking about and
i often hear is like a complex issue so
to speak is
the the idea of how people want more
sativa being offered and more variety
along those lines but there's a whole
bunch of issues that come along with
that in regards to price points flower
times
all things like that what's your stance
do you feel like people are asking for
something but they're not willing to buy
it on the other hand like you know how
do you feel about it all
oh yeah i know absolutely um people talk
about land races but most land races
most land race sativas are going to take
you 16 to 20 something weeks to finish
um
unfortunately on a production scale type
of a model that just really doesn't work
because there's nobody out there in a
market that will pay two to three times
the amount
for the same eighth if you're already
complaining about paying 30 or 40
for an eighth from the market and now
all of a sudden it's 60 to
you know 120 dollars for that same
eighth just because it's a land race or
something of that effect um at this
point in time the market is not there
for it
it would be
a little i think that it is possible in
the future to definitely see a craft
style market for it
um
which is a big thing to come yet i think
the whole craft thing is
going to stick around for a while and um
you know the big scale people it's hard
for them to do craft
yeah of course
and so
in regards to the craft market do you
think that that's
good like it's still kind of to emerge
um
just depends on where you're at
yeah right
um is it
in oregon craft market is king um
that's i think i feel that that's
you know and uh price point i feel kind
of proves that um
most pounds in oregon are 12 1600 for
indoor
um if you are considered
craft and you have the brand and you
have the recognition of said craft
you're still getting 24 2600 a pound it
hasn't really changed that much
but if you don't have that brand and if
you don't have something special
um
yeah you know
here in california this market here is a
lot different you know a lot
it depends on where you're at some parts
of it they want fruit some parts they
want gas the other parts they want
cookies
so you got to be able to appease all of
those on a larger scale market
but as far as
craft for many of the large guys
yeah
you'll probably see some coming
um but uh i think that it'll take a
little bit for everybody to dial it in
yeah so i mean
perfect segue on that issue of craft
cannabis how do you feel i'm sure you've
heard about it about the infamous 100
eighths of mac
we spoke to aficionado leo not long ago
and he said he thinks that's the biggest
thing that's happened in the cannabis
industry in a while and it's kind of
maybe not getting the recognition it
should what do you feel about the whole
issue and maybe as an extension of that
how do you feel about kind of mac sorry
cap's kind of general unhappiness with
the pricing of it
well you know i look at it as anything
else it's only worth as much as you get
somebody to pay for it
so if somebody's willing to pay it then
why not
that's you know i it's sad to look at it
that way but that's kind of where it's
at
i could go buy a
10 000 bottle of wine or i can go buy a
hundred dollar bottle of wine they're
both probably gonna get me just about as
drunk
yeah okay and so how do you feel about
like the idea of
you wouldn't want say
one of your strains reaching a certain
price point with the implication being
it's kind of like price gouging at that
point
um you know that would be for the farm
to decide at that point in time we don't
really um
you know we're we're a seed company once
you buy the seeds you do with what you
want you find something that people are
willing to pay that much for once again
if you can get it why wouldn't you
um
i see i i can see both sides of it
because you know that it seems
ridiculous a hundred dollars an eighth
but once again you don't have to buy it
yeah yeah i kind of feel the same in a
lot of regards like in terms of that
pure capitalist view on things right
right
you know
it works in every other market it's
going to wind up being the same in this
you know look at how much do some nikes
go for i mean
yeah or even just expensive cars
right exactly you know what is it
mercedes or uh
volvo this is the safest car out there
but not everybody drives one
yeah let's uh rewind back for a moment i
would love to know what was your first
breeding project and how did you get
into breeding in general
oh good golly um
so a friend of mine and i had a house
in colorado in the early 90s
we've been growing hash plant and doing
quite well with it
um got a hold of some seeds out of
california of some california red hair
and uh we popped the seeds
chose between a couple of different
mouths and used those to pollinate a
couple of the hash plant
huh and so did you end up growing out
the offspring
we did we only wound up getting a couple
hundred seeds and we popped the majority
of them but didn't necessarily really
find anything all that great
okay and what do you think that is do
you think that maybe is because
like uh the genetics back then just
weren't as kind of refined as they are
these days
um no i would think they were more
more so refined then now they're a
little bit more you know
for lack of a better bastardized out
um
but uh
the um
i think that uh it was a it was a land
race that we hit it too and the land
race was just so dominant that it
overrode
the hash plan
um but the hash plant you know back then
it was
a super fast plant so we had a hash
plant that we could take a clone within
a week it had roots and it went right on
the flood table
six weeks and flower chop it down a week
to dry once again we're in colorado
so an eight week cycle from clone to
done
um we wanted to find something that
would maybe you know add a little bit
more to it but
yeah that wasn't the ticket
interesting and so when you say hash
plan is it just like it's just any old
hash plan or is it like a specific one
you're referring to
um it came to us as hashman
you know
shortly after that is when the arcade
cut came to us train wreck derek katrina
came to us a little while after that and
we all grew that for a long time
but uh yeah the hash plan was what we
all grew for quite a while 92 93-ish
there in denver okay
and so i don't suppose it might have
been the skelly hash plant
it's a very good possibility
i'm not exactly sure
interesting i mean i don't suppose
you've tried scaly more recently since
she's kind of made a re-emergence
i have not
so yeah i wouldn't have any reference
all right we'll have to line that up
yeah yeah that would be great cool yeah
that's that's insanely fast flowering
time in your opinion you know do you
think it was truly done that quickly or
maybe you were cutting corners a little
bit
yeah it might have needed to go a little
longer but we were doing flat tables and
pushing everything right along you know
that was back in the day the
simple salts in the tanks and
ripped and let her go you know um
yeah it maybe needed to go seven or
eight i could totally see that
but yeah
okay cool and so
do you grow organically nowadays or are
you still a soul guy or
oh no it's all organics
we mix most of our soils
um
we use a few things out of a bottle but
they all say organics on them
yeah
bro you know you can take that as far as
you can throw it um
we pay extra for water obviously but uh
you know
um
yeah so we we try to stay pretty organic
we don't play with salts that much but
yeah
cool and do you feel like it's just kind
of a personal preference thing or do you
feel like it's just truly like you know
a superior option like
yeah no i think uh you know if you want
mass you're gonna do salts if you want
flavor you're gonna do organics
okay interesting we've heard some guests
in the past argue that
if you kind of you know really
on point so to speak you can get the the
yields to be quite on par with the hydro
guys do you feel like that's maybe a
little bit stretching the truth or that
that is accurate
you know i don't know you know i'll
refer back to uh geek farms they do
about
two and a half to three a light with
that doctor who and that's all organic
soil that they create themselves
yeah it sounds like it's matching it i
mean
so you know i have plenty of friends
that just smash
do fantastic on organic soils
um
i just think that with the good cocoa
and salt system you can see 15 20 times
a day
you're going to crush
that's there's no
you know
the more food you can get it to uptake
the bigger it's going to get it's basic
physics
yeah for sure
so
on the issue of growing
grow lights what are your preferred
brand you know it seems like there's new
technologies ever constantly emerging
what are you currently using
yeah we jumped on that gavita train in
the very beginning kind of been riding
it ever since i'm a big fan of the
gavitas
cool cool and so
like just uh the 1000 double ends or
which ones you rocking
yeah we ran the 1000 double ends because
we bought them way back in the beginning
before they had the 750s
would you use the 750s if you could
um absolutely
uh before we went to the uh gavita 1000s
we went we ran 600s
due to the fact that instead of
six
thousands i would stuff in 10 or 11 or
600 to get to the same point pretty much
with power so therefore you just have
more points of light and you they run a
lot cooler so you can run the plants a
lot closer i run them a lot closer to
the plants
and so
just to kind of this idea put forward by
dj short is that like metal halides
brings more flavor hps brings more yield
or maybe it wasn't dj short specifically
but he's the one who i remembered
bringing it up initially do you agree
with that and if so what type of system
do you use like a mixed a pure how do
you do it
you know so
what i've learned from
doing different mixed spectrum rooms is
that
a 50 50 is usually pretty good
um
you know but you'll get certain strains
that under the blue light they'll show
different colors um to wear under the
halogen they won't so now you got a bud
that's half say pink hair and the other
behalf of its white hair because it's
getting the metal halide or it's getting
the h the
hps right
um
the metal halide though does from blue
light promotes vegetative growth so you
wind up getting a leafier more open
product i feel um
so
you know
a 50 50 mix but now with the ceramics
and all that stuff i haven't played with
ceramics that much
but i see a lot of people throwing those
in nowadays as well instead of the metal
halides
so
i think i don't know that
flavor wise on the blues probably so um
just because
it's more of the cool color um
it's more of a promoting vegetative
growth
but i don't know for sure
yeah
okay so
if we kind of just jump back to that
initial story where you had the hash
plant and you did the pollination at
that time were there any kind of
breeders you were looking up to or was
everyone just kind of
self-sufficient and given to themselves
yeah pretty self-sufficient keeping to
themselves um high times cups had just
kind of started over in amsterdam right
so uh you know the big guys at that
point obviously were
greenhouse
and adam dunn was doing quite well back
then um
you know since he sees there's a few
different seed companies you get but
everybody was too scared to order them
especially out of the back of high times
or call them you know i mean that was
still back
we would get stuff at the grocery store
and then go camping for a three-day
weekend before we went anywhere kind of
thing you know borrow somebody's car and
meet him at a campsite to grab your your
nutrients and all that stuff that you
needed for the next month
um
it was still pretty pretty harsh in the
early 90s late 80s
so
it was definitely a little bit more to
yourself
okay and so
did you go to like you know those extra
efforts to try to throw the you know
cops off your trail or did you kind of
always view it as a bit of paranoia
oh no um definitely we would i've spent
i didn't mind spending time in the
mountains
so that was a bonus anyways right an
excuse to go fishing for the weekend um
you know yeah it was just the way that i
was raised because my father even was
the same way i mean anytime he would
order stuff we lived in northern idaho
so the panhandle so we would go over to
spokane to buy all of our nutrients or
anything like that we'd only go to
garden stores
you know a long ways away
um
and uh yeah it was just you it was still
it was such a paranoid type
uh
time for sure
and so what was the first cup you ended
up going to yourself
um first cup actually the first
competition i went to was the omcas
oregon medicinal cannabis awards
um and actually we wound up taking first
place with a mad scientist
okay so that was obviously a bit more
recently
yeah that was 2011. i never went to
amsterdam i've never been into amsterdam
so um yeah my first cup was here so
that was it it was a small local state
thing
uh first high times cup was the first
one that was here in l.a
interesting and and did you ever
have uh you know a lot to do with the
the following cups after that in
california and whatnot
um did the high time circuit quite a bit
did a couple of the other ones um
but yeah no mainly just the high times
and do you feel like they they kind of
help the scene develop over the years or
maybe not as much as other avenues like
say forums or things like that
i think the forums did a lot they had
their place
unfortunately once again i'm not a
computer guy i wasn't on the forums
so i don't know much about the forum
life
but i meet a lot of people now that
that's all they're about is forum this
and
you know i was so and so on this forum
um there's a lot of great people that
were on those forums
as far as high times i think it
allowed an avenue for people to come and
uh yeah see everything that they
were reading about and hearing about
in the beginning
towards the end
they've changed a bit but yeah
yeah okay and so how do you feel about
things nowadays i mean emerald cup has
been a hot topic in the sense that last
year i remember being at the cup people
were almost predicting like you know it
was the last one that'll ever happen and
it was all doom and gloom what's your
forecast for cups going forward and
specifically the emerald cup this year
so
yeah i've been doing him cup for a long
time
i'm good friends with a lot of those
folks um
and we'll be there again this year um
but yes it won't be like it was last
year last year was the last cup of the
free will of where you could freely bust
up
and do pretty much kind of what you
wanted
um that's not happening anymore now it's
all regulated
um if you're not licensed if you're not
from a nursery there's all kinds of
things that you have to be
even to be able to get the booth
so
i think it's going to be a little
different but there's you know once
again there's always loopholes around
everything
uh as i just mentioned we will most like
we will be there um i do believe that we
were talking with jinx proof about
sharing a booth with him actually
uh-huh that was going to be my question
will you have your own booth or just be
represented with seeds here now
um i haven't spoken with james um but
most likely seats here now does a
fantastic showing at those um
we normally like to have our own booths
uh just that way we get a little bit of
time to talk to the people that are you
know
supporting us
and uh
but you know then again it's sometimes
nice just to let james and his preview
their job and just go and have fun and
enjoy yourself
so that's kind of where we're at now
um
but jinx drinks proof just hit me up
here in the last last week
and was talking to me about this so
that's kind of a new development that
warren talks about right at the moment
yeah okay i remember last year cruz
passed your booth a few times and every
time you're locked in a conversation is
that what it feels like to you
yeah no
that is that's why i love doing them um
is so that i can get locked into
conversations with the supporters
because
it's great to hear what they think or
what they're doing or how it's going and
you know just hear their stories of
how your strains did for them for the
following the prior year
um or the future of
um so yeah you know that's the thing
that's why it's kind of nice to do your
booth that way people can come and talk
to you
and how often is it that someone will
come by the booth and bring you a sample
of your work and you're like really
blown away by it
quite often
most shows
actually we've uh unfortunately i've
slowed down on doing shows i think
emerald cup's the only one we're pretty
much doing this year
um
but uh yeah no it's there's there's some
amazing growers out there and
um you know i would like to think that
we're providing them with some fantastic
genetics to grow
so
it's really nice to get something back
that just is like wow that's fantastic
yeah i mean on the topic of providing
genetics how do you feel when people
want to breed with your work do you feel
like you're all cool with it you know
just like maybe give me a little hello
how you doing or what's your stance on
it
absolutely um
if if it's something that i don't want
the public to have and or work with
um i wouldn't release it i have lots of
those things
um
but there's
you know so it's it's more of an honor
and a privilege for somebody to use your
genetics in something because
it takes a lot of time to do to create
genetics and test them out and you know
and have a vision of where you're
wanting to go with it
and if that works in somebody else's
head and it's one of our genetics that's
awesome
but yeah always you know the head knots
great
cool cool and so if we kind of jump back
to the emerald cup for just one last
second um do you ever get a chance to
cruise around with the intention of
trying to find like eye off what the
next kind of trend is or like find some
new hot breeders or do you find it's
just too chaotic to really be able to do
that
yeah you know it's pretty chaotic um
there
there's definitely a lot of new good new
breeders out there i'm always as always
will be
um
yeah it's kind of chaotic
um you know we're creating we create
so much that for us to pop somebody
else's genetics
at this point except for at our clients
facility um becomes rough
yeah okay so i'm gonna put you on the
grill for a second
whether you've got to do it
imaginatively because you're not able to
in real life or whether it is the real
life answer let's just say for your
personal grow you're gonna pop a pack of
seeds you know just one pack what's it
gonna be
quantum
ha ha easy choice
i pop quantum everywhere i go
so like do you
do you like to
find new keepers of things or do you
like to hold on to old keepers
um you know if there are strains that we
created yeah um in and out
you know if we find something that's
that's special
we'll have it we'll have it tested and
if our thoughts are right then it is
special then we may hold on to it for
future progress
um
but most of the time yeah we've got a
whole bunch of moms in a library already
we don't need to keep a bunch of stuff
we make in c form
that's i mean that's a that's a good
answer if you've got that much
confidence in the seed stock is it true
i might be wrong but i think i'm right
that uh geek mike actually found that
cut out of just a single five seeds
yeah yeah that's true i gave him a five
pack
um
he wound up getting five females
and that wasn't even the best female out
of the five pack
uh the best yeah the best he said the
best one didn't clone
jesus
yeah so
yeah you know um he got fairly lucky not
everybody has that you know gets that
luck unfortunately that tells me that
somebody out there got a five pack of
mouse
yeah yeah you know it's probably a
breeder and they're probably stoked
right
[Laughter]
all righty
so i just wanted to loot back a while
back you mentioned um that like you know
scentsy were the people advertising in
high times and stuff like that i'm
always interested to know what's your
opinions on scentsy in regards to like
when and why do you think they went to
[__]
um
you know so
they cross bred out too much right i
think and they just got
they they also subbed everything out to
people in spain or somewhere else to
make their seeds
right
um
yeah you can go to spain and they're
sitting on five gallon buckets full of
seeds they'll sell you all day long um
just big old totes you can buy them by
the tens of thousands
are they really what they are or are
they something different you know it's
hard to say and i think that's kind of
what crushed them a little bit was
once they went to that model they kind
of lost control of what they were
actually
getting back in seat for
yeah definitely i think i saw a post a
few months back i i wish i remember who
it was because if you're not familiar
with this post it would totally allow us
to go look at it but basically
someone in the community
um
posted that they had a plan they were
calling kush for
and they were saying that it was one of
the supposed parents of the original
hindu kush offered by sensei and it just
got me thinking like
do you think it's even possible that
like a parent that like scentsy was
breeding with do you think like
realistically it's possible that a
parent like that is even around anymore
or is not the whole implied point of the
last question that like those parents
are gone
yeah those parents are gone i think
there was a couple of raids in between
those and i think that a lot of them got
cut down by little boys in blue kind of
thing
so
you know
a lot of people that's that all of a
sudden reappear and say oh i still have
this
do you really
um
you know
we'll never really know because
everybody's opinion is always changing
and you always have new reference points
so
is it the same is it not hard to say
yeah interesting
so if we kind of fast forward to today's
scene
i feel like it's categorized
predominantly by like a terpene or like
a flavor emphasis
in this modern era would you agree or do
you feel like it's still predominantly a
potency emphasis
um within connoisseurs it's definitely
terpenes within uh the market cells it's
potency
okay so like with that being said
how do you feel the cbd is going to work
considering that
you know there is this emphasis on
potency and cbd strains generally
speaking uh kind of lacking in that
do you feel like cbd is on the way out
so to speak
um i think cbd is on its way out but not
because of that reason
um i have some friends that do some
fantastic cbd work they're all the way
up to 25 20 6 25 to 26 cbd with no thc
and then flavors of all the rainbow
skunks fruits
lemons oranges
whatever you want um
but there's other things on the horizon
that i feel that are going to interrupt
the cbd
program
would you care to shine a little light
on those things
absolutely recently here in america cbd
was taken off of
scheduling
and now has received a fda approval
for a specific pharmaceutical company
and they're going to now they can sell
you cbd direct derived from plants
um
prescription wise through your doctor
um they're still talking about it and if
insurance will cover it or not
but most likely it will
and they're going to gouge people
and uh yeah but now it's going to be
legal and controlled by them
wow okay and so you think that yeah just
controlling interest will
try to implement some legal changes so
that it's just not being produced
outside of them
absolutely um what i would be concerned
with is
if all of a sudden they came back and
made it the schedule two which schedule
twos can only be made by pharmaceutical
companies
that would take care of it right there
so
interesting and do you feel like that
would just
also be a stepping stone to then do the
same with thc afterwards
um no um
you know i
i don't think i don't think it's going
to happen with thc
um
too many people like smoking the flowers
and the concentrates just freshly
derived
but
you know cbd most cbd is taken in pill
form tincture form
so
it's a little bit different
yeah i guess it kind of lends itself to
the pharmaceutical model a little more
right absolutely because it's an
isolated molecule
right the bad part is is that we
nowadays you know we've known for a
while that you need cbd along with thc
so they're still going to be depriving
their patients of what they truly need
yeah yeah and you know we all know the
same is true for the opposite end of the
spectrum with the whole drogono thing in
the pure thc that was no good either
right absolutely not
interesting so i mean if we're on the
topic of uh interesting cannabinoid
profiles i had a nice little question
for this one
worked with like some cbd lines before
notably the one that caught my eye was
the kana su
and um
the the thing which i noticed about this
is you crossed it with a thc male so
you're going to end up with like a like
you know a hybrid type of end product
whereas some thc some cbd obviously
there'd be some variation
do you find that these lines in general
fare well in the market or they're just
really not received to the same degree
that say a regular thc line is
absolutely they uh do not they're not
they're not as marketable as a regular
thc strain is even though the uh the one
you're talking about is our canary
canna c by timeric
and uh it tests two to one to one to two
um cbd being first
um
but uh
you know it uh it added a whole lot of
structure and
bigger buds to the plant um canissu
itself was pretty largely and lay out
laid out didn't really stand up and grow
grew fairly ugly in really small beds
um so we hit it to our with our time
rack mill
that increases bud sizes adds
strength within stem
and uh potency so we really didn't know
what to expect there but it wound up
turning out all right we hit anywhere
from
13 14 cbd to
you know
half that and thc or vice versa you know
that and thc with
four or five percent cbd
so when you talk to your customers who
grow out these crosses
generally speaking what do you find is
their preference in regards to the
keeper phenos are they the more thc
dominant phenos or the more cbd dominant
phenos
most of them are more cbd dominant
and
you know cbd is a unique counterweight
that cannabinoid that
matures early
so if it has too much thc just
pull it a little bit earlier um
it'll still be higher cbd with lower thc
so you know i explain that to them when
they're when they're looking for the
right ratio
of what's going to work best for them
okay
and so do you find that one thing i've
heard is this complaint of a lot of cbd
strains or the pure ones at least having
this common denominator terpene profile
which some would describe as cherry
have you found that yourself
absolutely the old the old older cbds
when you extract them they all taste
like cherry
um and that's how you know is always
well known that you were hitting cbd
um nowadays i would you know but they're
all hybrids
you know we've hit them with other
things and then outcross them back and
you know just to pull
certain terpene profiles
um to to get to the fire to where people
hopefully would want to smoke the flower
yeah okay and so this idea i've been
kicking around for a while it you know
i don't think it's right or wrong it's
just an interesting idea is like
embedding kind of a little bit of cbd in
the back of what we would regard as
regular strains so there are a lot of
strains out there which do this where
you know maybe there's like two two and
a half three percent cbd you know it's
just kind of like you know hiding in the
background but enough to actually do
something and the idea is like
you can subconsciously you know get some
of those benefits into people without
them knowing and then hopefully
eventually people start to give it a bit
more credence what do you think about
that idea do you think like could ever
possibly work or there's just maybe some
issues with it
yeah i know it could possibly work um
obviously i i definitely agree the more
cannabinoids and terpenes you have the
more effective all the medicine is um it
really just comes down to what works
best for you
um you know that's the great thing about
cannabis is it's so diverse that you
eventually you'll find one
but you know
um
i don't know how
i don't know if that's enough to get
people to want to try cbd more or not
okay
so
do you think that some of these more
rare terpene profiles are the way of the
future i remember reading in some of
your strains you're getting cbg and cbc
showing up you know some of these more
kind of exotic ones do you think that
that is the way of the future or it's
just kind of like a cool tibbet that's
probably going to go by and we won't
talk too much about it
yeah no i think that uh
rare cannabinoids is definitely going to
be a big thing coming up
um one that we're working with is thcv
and the cbc
our quantum kush we find good amounts of
that both of those in it
um
what i consider good amounts is two
percent plus
um the highest we've seen so far is
three percent we see a lot
below two percent in between that two to
three percent we see quite a bit as far
as ghcv
um cbc
um one percent one and a half percent is
pretty much the highest that i've seen
but with the new technologies we have
it makes it a lot easier
to
know if it's
transferring in the crosses the way we
want it to or if it's not
yeah okay
so i think some of this curiosity
stemmed initially from reading some of
the information around tardis
specifically where it said there's been
some you know research indicating that
some of the profile of the cannabinoids
has got tumor fighting properties
was this like something you guys looked
into a lot or is it just kind of like a
peripheral thing you noted
just kind of more of a peripheral thing
we noted um
i was fortunate enough to work with a
really good lab in oregon for a long
time and they worked with me and
educated me a lot
on what we had um
and kind of explained to us you know how
our how special some of our crosses were
so the witch intrigue just to figure out
well what's bringing those to the table
so which intrigued us to more testing
and more learning and so you know we've
i followed them a lot i have several
years worth of lab results
um on a lot of our strains full terpene
profiles and full cannabinoid profiles
all from the same lab
um and uh it definitely has helped a lot
i think now
if we can find a genoming
one that works well um that could even
help even more
how do you feel about phylus
you know so philos i've been involved
with them for a long time sonny chiba
and i
um
worked on the uh the seed laws in oregon
when we went recreational
and we met um
we were introduced to phytos at that
point in time um so i've dealt with maui
for quite some time um
i have several of our strains in there
um they wanted us to put in specific
phenotypes and i'm like no i'm gonna put
in moms and dads
that way any of our crosses can be
traced right back to the mom and dad
so that's what we did
so our
all of our males and most of our
breeding moms are in the fido's library
and we did that a while ago um as i said
we've been talking with them and
whatnots quite a bit
um so yeah you know i don't know
the information that they give you is
kind of
not really clear
yeah okay so a common feedback i've
heard is that there is this kind of
there's a degree of hard to operate
within the universe and how to like
actually understand things
do you feel like that is something they
should really be focusing on trying to
improve or do you think that it's just
like a learning curve people need to
adapt to
well
so what they're doing is they're doing a
short path so from my understanding i'm
not i'm not a big science guy i'm not
good with big words but uh
um they're doing a short path technique
which is just breaking it down pretty
basically and there's a long path
technique which i know there's a company
out of colorado working with um they ran
a few of our strains they actually were
the ones that informed me that in our
quantum kush
we have um
russian rudorelli
or russian him sorry russian hymn
which
um provided apparently in this in this
specifics you know
russet might resistance
uh they found this planet that didn't
seem to have hardly any rusted lights on
it when everything else was infected
really bad turned out to be a quantum
coach so they went ahead and ran a long
path on it and found out that it had
russian hip in its lineage
so that was kind of the conclusion that
they came to
but i think that there's definitely ones
certain ways that they could get us the
information that we need
and i just don't know that phylos is
doing that for us
yeah so a lot of people are
kind of a bit skeptical of the idea that
by getting your samples done at fire
loss they're now you know kind of in the
open domain you don't have to worry
about
things in a legal sense as much do you
believe that is the case because i find
it still hard to get a clear answer on
this
well so
there's some people out there already
that they did some utility patents and
they got them and they cover such a wide
array wide array
of cannabinoid and terpene or
cannabinoid and terpene profile
that it covers a lot
so
to protect us from people patenting
plants first off it's kind of hard to
patent a plant
because there's so much variety in it
even in ibl's when i pop
seeds of ibl's there's still varieties
in it um
you know so there's an issue there but
with crispr systems coming and stuff
like that
you know it's possible to do it all
but will it protect us in the future i
hope so kind of
you know
um but does that include like offspring
from said
what's in the galaxy or is that you know
does all the sudden offspring now become
open
when you shouldn't have made that
without this to begin with i don't know
how all that works
yeah okay
let's just loop back for one second you
mentioned the russian hemp does that not
kind of have something to be said for
the reuteralis genetics and how
sometimes they're just brushed to the
side
yeah you know i think um obviously
everything has a good purpose to it and
it will as a land race will create
resistance to whatever the pest is and
continue to survive
it's a weed
we do still have to remember that
and uh it definitely adapts very quickly
so i think that uh
there's most likely some traits there
that are good
um
i just know that
on actual rear ellis coming up out it's
very
it's like headache from my understanding
yeah well i mean have you heard of any
of the more modern companies doing it i
mean some of them are certainly getting
really good reviews
oh yeah no um i hope i say this right
with manchester
um genetics
they kill it um you know there's
definitely a few companies out there the
autoflower game is doing fantastic
um
a lot of people still it's a huge market
you know a lot of people that's what
they prefer
yeah definitely
so
in terms of photo period we'll jump off
the autos for a sec
i uh i want to know what do you think is
the absolute longest photo period strain
that would be commercially viable
um
you know i think if you're commercially
if you're pushing 11 to 12 weeks
you you're kind of you're kind of there
is that more what you're asking is
what flower time or yeah yeah definitely
yeah um i think that uh
you know and that's where you come into
the market you know
um
it will so a company that can put out
strains in an eight-week cycle is going
to get
six cycles per year right so
um and a company that's doing them every
12 weeks is only going to get three and
three and a half cycles a year
so somewhere it has to equal out to pay
all the bills because no matter what you
ain't growing for free and you're paying
a lot
so
if the market will allow it
i can see it going longer
but it really kind of depends on what
the market demands
and so what do you predict to be the
next big thing the market demands
yeah that
is changing so rapidly right now that's
that's a loading question
um there's
it's really hard to say you know it's so
it's so
i hate to say a bit more and less
unstable
of what how things are going and what's
going to happen next and you know here
in california
medical goes away in january
they lose their 2 15.
so how is that going to affect the
market
um
we don't know yet it's hard to say it's
kind of hard to predict that
i think that uh
eight nine weeks is kind of where the
market's gonna have to stay to be
competitive
at least on a large scale
so do you think then that if something
as in maybe a strain
would come in and be that next game
change or slash paradigm shift it would
essentially be confined to those
flowering times
uh yeah i don't know you know there's
always a new hype strength
um
who's gonna have the next big best
biggest thing hard to say
it could be anybody
so do you feel like the market is still
dominated by numbers in regards to
percentages or do you think that that's
kind of fallen off of it
yeah no it's definitely still still by
percentages all day long
people walk in what's the strongest
every shop owner i know will
tell you that
so i've spoken to a few readers in the
past and they said if they make some
stuff
generally even if they love it if it's
not tested above say 20 22
they're just not even going to consider
it for release
do you sit in the same boat
uh yeah i know and that's where the
market is absolutely 100 if you if
you're
pushing strains out that are below 20
percent they're going to sit on a shelf
for a while
that's going to be all concentrates
yeah interesting and so are these the
type of things that are in the forefront
of your mind as a breeder or are you
more considering other attributes like
flavor and things like that
i don't concern myself with all that
i've always been about you know
more medicinal effect and flavors you
know kind of what we like um what
everybody else likes what we like really
doesn't matter as much but
what everybody else likes and
um
yeah is kind of where we go
the you know the hype thing is cool and
all but yeah we don't do a lot of work
with a lot of the new hype strains or
anything to that effect
just because of that
um
really not into that hype thing
yeah okay so what does it take for you
to bring a new clone into the library
then
uh normally it has to be an old cut that
i've been looking for
at this point in time i've got pretty
much what i want to play with and now
it's just reworking itself upon itself
so it begs the question are there any
old school cuts you would love to get
but you just don't think they're around
anymore
yeah obviously the road cap
or whatever you know as we discussed
before whatever that may have been
um
yeah you know
i'm privileged enough to where
most the breeders
i can ask them and get access to pretty
much whatever i want
so
you know um having that accessibility
um
frees it up a little bit to allow us to
uh
you know
play a little bit more
like i said we have a lot of classes
that we've done and have not released
um just because
they were we felt they were really good
too good that we didn't want to release
them or obviously they weren't good
enough but
yeah access to cuts for us is pretty
easy fortunately enough
so
i'd have to say not really
yeah okay sounds like you're a very
lucky man
yeah i i definitely consider myself that
to be absolutely
so my last little question in regards to
testing and things around that nature is
have you ever considered or do you
currently engage in you know some of
those like um kits which like are now
offered by the labs in regards to early
cannabinoid profile testing and early
sex testing and things like that or you
just old school
definitely don't do the sex testing i'm
super old school with that the plant's
going to tell you in a few weeks just
chill
and
as far as
cannabinoid ratios and stuff like that's
more for cbd guys
um you know
as i mentioned before my buddy too and
then my other friend adam jocks
they both use those and it allows them
to cruise through their stock really
fast but they're popping thousands of
seeds you know so
i can see where that's helpful
um
we're doing thousands of seeds as well
but i'm fairly old school with that i
like to see what it does
yeah okay cool
so i mean you mentioned crisp and
crispers some cool technology you know
kind of can hint to the past of some
things but one thing it's not going to
tell us is
who picked that time wreck mail was it
your sub cool but before we get into it
let's go back how did you first meet sub
we you knew it was coming let's get into
it
yeah
so actually um i originally first met
dioxide
he was manager
at a growth store where i lived um
the first time that i met subcool
dioxide brought him out to my house to
see my oregon diesel in my backyard that
was done
in uh
september first week of september
um that was the first time he was ever
at my house i had never heard of tga
before
dioxide or any of that
but dioxide throughout the time that i
had met dioxide and before the sub came
out
had given me a lot of packs to pop and
we popped them all so when they came out
we had a room full of all their genetics
in full flower
um
yeah and that was the first time that i
met him so
after that you know their dioxide kind
of talked to me and um
we talked for a while about
him about us producing seeds on a larger
scale and then distributing them for us
and we're like
sounds like it could be fun sure let's
check it out
um so that's kind of how that history
went one of the test restraints that we
did back then for them
was dioxide's creation of time wreck
um
so even before i was obviously a tester
um so we popped some my son donovan
found a male that he liked a lot
the branching came up within a couple
inches from the top including the bottom
branches all the branches that beautiful
structure great smell
we talked with dioxide if we could use
it for some crosses uh mushroom mouth
just
described to him what he wanted to do
and the line that he wanted to go
through and uh
doc says yeah absolutely not a problem
so um
that's kind of where we started with the
doctor who and the quantum and the
mickey
the jtr mill actually came to us through
dioxide as well
and that was to do some crosses we had
the medicine woman
which was a strain created by a
gentleman there in oregon for his wife's
fibromyalgia and he wanted us to cross
the jack the ripper to the medicine
woman
so that was nurse jackie that was one of
our
first releases as well
um
but yeah throughout that time we started
doing cops started working with sub had
moved to california by that point in
time i never really hung out with them
or talked with them much
other than on the phone or whatever my
main person with tga was dioxide
um helped him with the soil company and
you know a lot of that kind of stuff but
uh
you know worked a lot of the cups my
sons and i
ran the booth for several years um set
up we would i'd bring in a crew we would
set up the booth and tear down the boots
and run the booth and
all that good stuff
um those were back in the day good old
days when heroes of the farm um
joined in and he was making stuff with
dioxide as well and that was the heroes
of the farm
collab thing
um
so once that got going then uh
pat's like
hey do you mind if i use the time rack
mill to do some crosses so i'm like yeah
sure no problem
so we worked out a collaboration and all
that kind of stuff and
um
he went ahead and used the time wrecked
mel and that's the locomotion and
a few of those other ones right that's
our time wreck now
um
yeah so as far as the mail the time
wreck mail yeah no it was not found by
sub it was found by my son donovan and
it was while it was in testing mode
we have we got permission we talked to
dioxide about it beforehand
and uh yeah everything was good gravy
um and all that
i know now that sub likes to claim that
he gave it to me
and that he found it and all that good
stuff but uh yeah that's far from the
truth unfortunately
why do you think he wants to take credit
for it
you know
i'm not really quite sure
i would think you know as i explained
earlier with people using our genetics
for strength for
making stuff um i feel privileged and
honored about it if they mention it's
cool if they don't cool either way they
paid the money for the seed that i was
offering they bought their goods
i think right now the biggest issue is
that
he has uh got himself into some places
where he went bragging that they were
all his and he owned all this and he
owned all that
when he doesn't he never grew that time
wreck now he's never
seen
grown any of the stuff that we make
um same with pat same with um heroes of
the farm same with jinx proof
um you know there's there's been several
i hang out now with sunny chiba sunny
chiba was the original person that
helped miss jill bring sub cool to the
west coast
he's the one that created
dope purple doja black tray black cherry
soda lemon freeze this whole list goes
on does he get credit for him very
rarely
now that miss jill and sub are separated
miss jill has actually come out and
explained a lot of the truths and i i
really i appreciate that and i love her
for that
um
at one point in time she was part of the
issue but she's
changed and
has you know come full circle as far as
i'm concerned as far as that goes
um i would give some more credit because
he is a great man he has done a lot for
the community
um and he did definitely help us in
marketing and what not to that effect
but that was part of the agreement that
was part of the distribution agreement
that's why we put their names on the
back
of our covers you know we all have the
little tga little circle on the very
back of our covers up in the top corner
all of our names are on the front
they're all of our strengths
so why he sits there and says that he
claims the creation of all them and this
and that i really don't know it's the
same that he tells him tells people that
he taught me how to grow yeah my father
heard that and was kind of like really
so he was around when you were 14.
he's like no he wasn't you know that but
at any rate people will believe what
they want to believe and i'm okay with
that i don't try to defend it i don't
come out and talk a bunch of trash or
anything like that about subpool and i
and i won't um
we had some issues and uh yeah um
that was it i you know
so what was it ultimately which
catalyzed the decision for you to part
ways
so what it came down to is they brought
in another group that was starting to
run the cup they were extremely rude to
me and my children
me and my boys um that have been running
the shows for years
um at uh the next show coming up was the
denver show and i asked him i was like
so i think for the denver show i'd just
rather do my own booth
and he freaked out i was like well you
know
this is what it comes down to is you
have our seeds being sold all over the
place in other booths throughout the
show i don't see why it's a big deal
that i have our own booth and we sell
our own seats
um he couldn't see it and i said okay
well then that's it we're done
that's pretty much it
yeah i mean it seems pretty simple
i mean you know we all have the same
agreement so
heroes of the farmer bring a set amount
of seeds high green set amount of seeds
drinks perfectly set amount of seeds we
would sell all the seeds we'd split
everything equally pay all the help
and go our separate ways after each show
after everything was covered
um
you know i've i've heard ridiculous
things come from him as far as like
i paid him forty thousand dollars a show
to do this and he never paid me that we
never made that we had one show in la
one year or
san bernardino one year where we did
over forty thousand dollars
only one and uh yeah i didn't get it all
but far from it but i mean i could sit
here and go on about a whole bunch of
different stories but
what it comes down to is we definitely
just didn't see eye to eye on where i
wanted to go and what i wanted to do
and uh
she was unmoving and willing to move
then compromise
yeah it's interesting you made that
comment um about sunny cheever's work a
sentiment we've heard in the past is
that you know some of the best work to
ever come out of tga was from the
canadian crew do you kind of echo that
sentiment
um
yeah i don't know what what work came
out of the canadian crew because that
was all in order
yeah i think i think they're pretty much
just referring to sunny cheba
that's sonic it was oregon
oh there you go
so yeah it wasn't and it wasn't canadian
at all he was there in portland oregon
there you go and a final little thing i
wanted to quickly ask you about this
dioxide's an interesting character to me
this is going to sound like a weird
question but i had to ask it because i
had always i i i'm familiar with him
through his involvement with um the
chernobyl and i love it you know it's
super energetic really gorgeous hi i
love it i've got a really nice keeper i
found and i can't remember who told me
but someone was like oh man you should
meet dioxide like he's like real high
energy like he makes weed like his
personality
do you find that to be true or is that
just some random story i got told
yeah you know he's pretty hyped up most
of the time he's pretty kick-back though
he's fairly level-headed
um as far as i was concerned he
definitely made the best strains that
tga offered
as far as the tga company
him and sub as partners
um you know he's the one that found the
jtr male he uh
he made he
i watched him go through a three-year
search of kush's before before he decies
before he decided to use the hell's og
to make the jesus you know so i mean he
was definitely really into what he was
doing
and he was really good at it um
but
yeah as soon as it wasn't long after
him and subs split up
the sub and i split up as well
yeah okay
so
do you feel like it's a bit of a weird
situation given that you do use that
jack the riffer mail or you think like
not really
um actually we don't use it anymore we
haven't used it for years
um we were the ones that gave it back to
so after
dioxide did all the breeding so after
dioxide and sub separated sub did not
have the jtr mountain
so he had to hound me for it and how
many for it and i kept telling dachshund
i'm like hey man he's bugging me again
for that jtr mill dioxide finally tells
me he's like hey i put you in a really
bad situation here go ahead and give it
to him
so it was at that point in time that i
took
the jtr mill back to sub
um
we read with it one more time after that
and that was it
i knew that our separations were coming
and that was their mail that they had
picked from their company so yeah i
didn't want to use it that was theirs i
get that
um the time wreck yeah no we found that
we take claim to it it is ours
made by a dioxide
yeah for sure
so final little question on the whole
saga i've asked this to some other
people because this seems to be i'm not
going to say a common occurrence but
it's not you know these guys certainly
aren't the only example but
you know
do you feel like kind of in a sense you
would like things to be you know cool
given that you know some of that work is
embedded within your own work even if
it's not a direct descendant it's kind
of almost like a little bit of a
tipping of the hat given that it is
embedded in there how do you feel about
that
um i would not have i don't have a
problem given dioxide credit any day
yeah cool cool easy answer
yeah no absolutely easy
all sub is is a salesman
he doesn't breed
um and yeah that's all there is to it he
may he did at one point in time
but once he got to diox once dioxide
came in that was it um after dioxide
left he talked to me about doing all his
breeding
and that didn't happen so he went to
joel
northstar genetics which is who makes it
all now
and uh i've been to joel's place so i
know what kind of reading he does there
and when people sat there for the last
three years after i left and come up to
me and say hey the seeds that i bought
from tga last year weren't what i had
got the year before what happened i
couldn't answer even though i know what
happened but i still wouldn't answer
and is that to do with like uh the issue
that miss jewel was pointing out with
males being lost and replaced
yeah no we learned about the males being
lost same time they did they ran them
through filos
yeah so when i spoke to sub about that
he said that what had happened was the
person who had sent the cuttings in made
a mistake and took five cuttings of the
same plant
seemed like uh an interesting answer
though maybe a little hard to swallow
what did you think
absolutely not
no um
yeah that they don't
that just goes to show the kind of of of
how they how he does everything he
relies upon everybody else to do
everything
so once something goes wrong it's a
blame on somebody else
it's never a fault that he ever made
yeah okay
i um i had a good friend send me this
question to ask you so hopefully you're
gonna have more idea about it than what
i do because i have no idea what this
means at the moment but he said
um the time wreck he got from dioxide
was it a female except only one branch
that hermied
so yeah actually absolutely so um
yeah the uh
some of the genetics that uh that could
put out of there
have high height
her mafidation results
um
so more or less if if just one branch
did it though i would look more towards
a light leak of some sort around that
branch
but uh it is definitely possible they
have some stuff that you know the the
the jtr mail the space dude which
if you ever get um
if you ever get sunny on here maybe
he'll explain to you about the space
dude story
um but uh
it's you know it's a super cost of
multiple things you know and as you
continue to cross it it's super unstable
so it creates unstable genetics
yeah okay
and so i think he had a bit of a
follow-up and he says
do you think that this accounts for the
occurrence of hermaphroditisms in nature
um
i don't i think it more so comes from
stressing of
meshed together genetics
yeah
okay yeah i think i kind of get what
he's getting at now giving your answers
right
some stress in the plant out to where
it's getting the signal that it's going
to die
um cannabis is fortunate enough to be
able to produce both male and female sex
organisms and reproduce itself
so when it hits a point to where either
a light leak or
the gases are off or it's something that
it doesn't like or something that
stresses that it's going to cause a
hermaphrodite which has produced both
parts so that it can pollinate and
produce seeds
to continue to live once again it is a
weed
yeah okay so on the topic of producing
seeds are there any little extra perks
or little kind of icing on the cake you
like to give to your female plants when
you're creating seeds
uh
not really
so you just yeah you just kind of treat
it like it's a scentsy crop except the
fact it's not
well um
yeah i i will uh a different feeling
right i don't want to deprive it of
nitrogens
because it's it's no different than
a female that gets pregnant they need
prenatals
they need different nutrients than what
you're given a regular flowering plant
at least in my opinion
and that's personal you know and that's
mo there's probably going to be a bunch
of people say oh you're just crazy
possibly i could be but it works for me
and i'm happy with it that way
cool and have you ever noticed a
difference in the end outcome of a seed
based on the different medium or
nutrients that's being fed or do you
think overall it's same same
we've pretty much used the exact same
soils and exact same nutrients
for the last 10 years 12 years so most
of our breeding has been done on the
same regimens
yeah okay i mean maybe to play devil's
advocate i don't suppose you've ever
seen like
a bit of a questionable grow or maybe a
better way to phrase it is you pop some
seeds and got some you know some funky
germination ratios or some bad
germination ratings and then maybe you
went and saw the grower and you know you
weren't too impressed by their setup and
you're like this is maybe why
yeah no absolutely we uh we germ test
germination test all of our seeds uh we
make our seeds fresh every year
we don't like them to sit we do small
batch and that that's the reason why
because i have fresh seeds are way
better than five-year-old seeds they're
going to have a better germination rate
so you know
we don't really seem to have problems
with it so when people call me or
contact me with that issue
i have a set of questions that i run
through with them
and uh
normally it's something on their end and
we
usually send them back out a pack and uh
um
the next round they usually don't have
the same problems
yeah okay that's a good little answer
so
going back to a bit earlier you
mentioned the medicine woman that was an
interesting one i wanted to ask you
about but thankfully you filled us in on
the backstory
but i also had written down the sweet
irish kush this is another one where you
use it not a whole hell of a lot of a
backstory on it would you mind filling
us in a little more about it
yeah so sweet irish push was created by
my friend that i was living with in the
90s when we did the
uh um he continued to do more breeding
throughout his time but sweetheart chris
was one that he created and he's a hydro
guy colorado's a lot of hydro especially
back in 90s 2000s
so
it's a fairly quick strain um
it's a
it's an oat so
hit from him it's an og
by
sweet leaf
so that's the cross
um when we put it through filos it came
back fifty percent og and
you know a few other things here and
there but yeah it's it's 50 og
so but it's a it's an old one because he
created it in
late 90s 96 97 i do believe
something like that and i've had it
i brought it to oregon with me and i
brought it back up
and so how does she compare to say your
more typical ogs like say maybe the sfv
which you mentioned at the start
um you know sweet irish fish is one of
my favorites um i really like that a lot
it has a fantastic high it tests 25 27
pretty consistently
um it's a fast strain once again he was
into the fast drains for the hydro
systems
we did lab tests on here
six weeks seven weeks eight weeks nine
weeks and ten weeks
six weeks with our highest thc and
degraded from there on down
but uh it was fast it's fast and veg
it's fast and flower
and it's kind of ugly to grow it's all
over the place so it's kind of like a
typical older og where it's floppy and
skinny or branch
um but it produces fairly well for as
fast as it is
interesting and what's kind of the
flavor profile just straight og
no it's a more of a really sweet emoji
um to be honest it uh
it um really sweet with uh with a bit of
a funk to it
yeah
okay so the other strain i mean there's
a few i want to ask you about but one
which really caught my oregon blues and
the part about it which caught my eye
specifically was how it uses uh what you
say is the in-house ibl jamaican
blueberry sativa what is that you know
because like when i first read it i was
thinking is he kind of talking about
like a dutch
acclimatized jamaican type of thing or
just straight land race
um straight ibl from a from a plantation
in jamaica on the in the blue mountains
um they've been growing it there for
generations
a friend of mine brought me back seeds
and uh
anything that it touches it passes
strong blueberries too
the bad part about it is it's an ibl and
it's very dominant so you see a lot of
it for generations out
um
so
we're still playing with it a little bit
um
but yeah that is the so the blue
mountain kush
is a
is that was the one you asked about
right
yeah yeah i see oregon believes yeah
organizes the oregon diesel by the
jamaican
um
that you either get so we have some a
few phenos we found that are really like
i want to say cat pissy you know very
ammonia
um
but then a lot of really blueberry you
know so
um that one was it was definitely
different
it's not one that we put out to market
because we didn't feel that it was
up to par
as of you know at this point but yeah
okay so what to you would be the ideal
mating partner for the jamaican
i don't know yet
whatever it is it's going to be a few
crosses out
um just because as i say the jamaican is
super strong and it's not necessarily
it's what you would think of when you
think of a land race it's very airy it's
very loose buds it's very stretchy it's
you know it has a few different thing
characteristics that
don't necessarily make it very viable
viable in a market that we have today
okay and so the next question that
stimulated in my mind was this idea of
different blueberry origins because i
remember when i was looking up some
information on the infamous vikkai he
claimed he had blueberry that was of
different origin to dj short and i guess
that was the first place i started to
think like
was there multiple sources of blueberry
or did it all come from dj short um
what's your feelings on it
you know
from talking so i'm friends with dj he's
one of my favorite people to sit down
and talk with actually one of the one of
the old guys that i
really enjoy talking with um
but yeah vic high from my understanding
took his blueberry and said he was going
to make it better
so yeah i would almost have to say it
was probably
more so from
dj than i would vic but
i wasn't around back then so i who knows
for sure right you'd have to get both of
them
in to find out you know
who was first and where did you source
it from kind of a thing but according to
dj it's a jamaican thing so
yeah okay there you go
so it also brings up this next question
in my mind and you kind of referenced it
at the very start of extremely isolated
flavors part of the reason why i think
tangy and blueberry and a few other
notable ones have got such traction is
because they're such dead ringers for
this isolated specific profile
do you think that that is maybe
something you could aim for as a breeder
if you were like well if i can you know
if i've got a strain and it kind of
smells like raspberries and i can refine
it to the point where it's just banging
on raspberries like that'd just be a
market winner or do you think that it's
just that would be an oversimplification
of things
you know
i think it almost but it's kind of an
oversimplification but i think we need
the variety and being humans as we are
we all want different so
um just a little bit different or a lot
different is definitely dependent upon
the person but uh
yeah um
you know it
you
not everybody can get the right fruit
combinations once again it's what pairs
up together what lines up together you
know i've smelt
several different strains that smell a
lot like our grape high chief you know
of our doctor who but once you get into
smoking i mean you look at the blood
structure there's quite a bit of
difference
so
you know i don't know that's uh
i guess you know
it'd be nice to find the ultimate one
but i don't know if it truly exists
what's the flavor profile that you wish
you had in cannabis form
um
you know we've had we have flavors from
dirt to watermelon
to rotten fruit to ripe fruit to
souly to cat piss
i like them all kind of just depends on
what kind of mood i'm in or what i'm
getting ready to do or who i'm getting
ready to go hang out with
we've always been a group that we like
to grow a lot of different things
yeah perfect segue
what type of weed is your favorite weed
flowers
any and all um
you know obviously right at the moment i
have some
two different kinds of doctor who in my
stash i've got some scooby snacks some
dog walker
some
gorilla glue some
wi-fi some uh
banner number five bruce banner number
five some i mean
right at the moment i've got a whole
slew of flavors and you know just
depends on what the day is what kind of
mood i'm in is what flavor i grab
damn you do have everything in that bag
yeah no i uh i make sure that i have
choices i like choices
i gotta i gotta take a guess here do you
have also docido
i do not uh i got some sfv and i have
some chem 4 though
oh how do you feel about cam 4 we were
getting around to the chem dog topic
yeah jim's nice um
all the kim dog lines are really nice we
uh
we have a kim 91 that is the other chem
91 i don't know if you know that story
or not but
there's another chem 91 that goes around
swerve worked with it
we've been growing it for the past
10 11 years maybe more
um
you know that's a weird one every time
we try to do any work with it there's
there hasn't been much that has came out
that i was happy with
um but uh
we did we hit it with the male doctor
who
and i actually found several that i
liked so there's potential there
um
but there's still a lot more testing to
go on with that one but yeah i know the
chem lines are fantastic they're very
potent um
they don't always cross very well though
i don't think
yeah i can um i can attest to how
they're potent and i think that part of
the potency comes from the fact that
they are kind of like
a bit of a winning lottery ticket and
it's kind of like the cookies you know
like
not everything's going to come out
exactly as good as the parent because it
is the anomaly in itself
with that being said which of all the
chem cuts is your favorite
i don't know i like the 91
yeah i like the real 91 and the other 91
so i like both the 91s quite a bit they
have more of the fuelly flavor for me or
the the kimmy funk right
the four is great for production
because it gets nice and big but i don't
think it's as flavor it's the flavor
isn't as strong it's a little mute on it
but if you're looking for weight that's
where you want to go
if you're growing for your head and for
a stronger flavor than 91 is where it's
at
i think you're the first person ever to
have not mentioned the chem d
yeah you know kennedy yeah
yeah
it's good um
but i wouldn't i would i think that uh
the 91 is
is the best out of the bunch
kim's sister is super hard to find and
try to get to smoke any of so i haven't
smoked any of that um
but uh
you know i've smoked kim d kim 4 and the
91 and
out of them i like the 91 the best
yeah well i mean depending on which
camdee you smoke you might have smoked
the sister
that's very very true
but um that's interesting you say that
because i think at the end of the day 91
rules for sure
yeah
yeah alrighty so
with that being said final question on
the chem dogs
no one really knows what do you think uh
the genetics behind it we hear a lot of
speculation of northern lights and hash
plan just things of that general nature
what do you think
yeah i definitely could see it being an
afghani of some sort um
just because of structure and growth um
it's hard to say
you know um speculation is a killer
you know you can speculate on a lot of
things and most of the time neither
one's right so
you know i don't know it's it's hard to
say what the
if they can figure out the whole
genealogy thing
maybe we'll know someday
yeah okay
so
on the topic of cannabis that you like
what are you more of an indica or a
sativa guy overall
definitely
interesting the reason why i asked that
was kind of like a bit of a setup to
this question it's because when i was
looking at a lot of your offerings i
think more of them lean towards the
sativa side of things were you aware of
this
yes i am very aware of that um but a lot
of people like those fast sativas you
know they like
just because we breed them doesn't mean
that i smoke them
you know obviously i've tested them and
you know once again it comes back to
where i said it doesn't really
necessarily matter what i like what
matters is what everybody else likes um
so you know obviously i i gotta like it
in the beginning to create it
but if i create it and put it out and
nobody likes it then obviously it's just
something that i like
if i create it and put it out and
everybody's like wow that's [__]
awesome
then i know that hey okay well we might
have something here
so then you expand your
your tester group a little bit larger
and a little bit larger you know back in
the old days
the way we did it was we filled a jar
sold jars multiple jars in the first jar
empty that was the win
yeah that's a good way of sorting the
the cream from the milk
yeah yeah so with that being said
do you ever get people asking you to put
out more indica dom crosses and if you
were to do so what would be some of the
parents you would look to use straight
away
um yeah you know we're already working
we're already doing a mad scientist back
cross we just did the bad scientists
back across just around the first set of
those those are really nice short
squatty plants
um
you know we're more into we work in our
lives more than you know stepping out of
what we did a lot of the moms that we
use in our crosses were stuff the
crosses that we made
so
at this point in time we're still
working with our lines to get them to
where we want them
and then maybe looking for a few others
to play with and tinker with a little
bit
but
it's got to be pretty special for us to
want to work with it
yeah okay and so overall do you like
kind of creating 50 50s or do you like
more doing them leaning one side to or
the other
50 50s are ideal you know because so
sativas you get a little bit of that
stretch um indicators will bring you in
your your uh stiffer stronger
stems and tighter intermodals
sometimes you need to stretch them out
so you hit them with a heavy a sativa
mill
sometimes you need to make them stronger
and shorter so you hit them more with an
indica mill
that's more the diversity that i like to
look at is
which direction are we trying to take
the mom
in are we trying to
stretch it make it more bigger beds or
are we trying to make it shorter or
maybe a little bit faster
um
yeah kind of goes from there that's why
we're trying to we've got we've got
several males that we've spent the last
few years picking out we just haven't
gotten around to working with them yet
so what what are some of these strains
that you you know got these males from
and the question i guess absolutely love
what are some of the characteristics or
traits you look for when selecting a
male
selecting a male definitely a uniformity
size of flower pod you know size of
the the palm the flower cluster at the
end of the cycle coloring potencies
um
yeah just depends on if we're you know
are we looking for a mel that's going to
even out branches make so make
more so for
um
you know multi-head type crop or we're
looking for something that's going to be
more just two or three kind of top you
know two to four tops or whatever it's
going to go more straight up
um just depends on what we're really
looking for is where we're wanting to go
is what we look for in the mail
um right at the moment we just we've had
a uh like i said it took us three years
to find our doctor humel and we actually
founded it a friend's in a friend's
garden it wasn't even a seat that we
popped
it took us
four years before we found a quantum
mill that we liked
we're getting ready to start playing
with him
now with him we're going to bring in a
different a few other og's
and hit him with just because the sweet
irish kush
lineage there
um
and just kind of see where that goes
mainly with the quantum metal we're one
to more isolate into the thcv and the
cbc and a few other of the
you know
the finer cannabinoids that we're
now discovering or figuring out what
uses they actually have
yeah okay and one of the things we've
heard of in recent episodes in terms of
like the cutting edge things people do
with males is reversing males and being
able to express
the male as if it was a female and you
can't smoke it because you spray it with
some pretty toxic chemicals but you can
certainly get uh
a possible indication of the terpene
profile and things like that is this
something you've ever thought about or
even potentially engaged in
um i know about the practice
uh personally i wouldn't do it because
of like you just said you have to spray
it with some pretty harsh chemicals
i don't like bringing those anywhere
around my car especially for something
like that a male will produce its own
smell at the end of its flower cycle
and throughout its flower cycle
um
a lot of people
you know it's a cool thing to look at
and it looks cool in a picture and all
that but you can't smoke it
so you know and it's not fully expressed
so
i don't know i haven't done it due to
the fact as i said i don't like the
chemicals that you have to use to do it
and uh
i just don't foresee
with you know i i think you see a lot of
the same stuff if you just let the mouth
flower out to full cycle
yeah okay so i mean
very much in that topic how do you feel
about residence males do you feel like
it's a positive indicator for the male's
potential to pass on
good traits yes once again um it's male
dependent due to the fact that some will
and somewhat
um not everything transfers one it's
still a 50 50 mix
right so
just because it transfers with this
female it may not transfer with that
other female
um
so once again it's going to be
and well-dependent upon
you know whether or not a resinous metal
is going to make a non-so resonance
female more resonance
you got a 50-50 chance
yeah okay
so how do you feel about the idea of
breeding with hermaphrodite prone
females is it kind of like a challenge
you're willing to take up or do you feel
like you may be setting yourself up for
more trouble down the line
yeah
if there's something that's already
prone for her malfunction yes absolutely
it's all you're doing is passing along
that genetic
um
now if you have steady females and you
light link them or you stress them in a
way to where they produce flowers
i feel that's a little bit different
because they're tried and true
females that you've ran flour
that didn't herm or didn't produce any
bananas or anything to that effect
until they were stressed to a point
where they thought they were going to
die
and wanted to live
how do you feel about feminized seeds in
general
it really depends on how you go about
doing them um if you're doing it with
the chemical spray on
on
females that don't show any mafidation
signs beforehand absolutely that's the
proper way to do it um if you have a
plan that's hermaphrodite and it seeds
out your room yeah you're not a breeder
yeah it's interesting because some of
the earliest breeding programs i heard
about were apparently
more a result of the later of what you
said than the earlier ones like i
believe i heard from a credible source
that
some of the original og kush
fem seed releases from oregon kid were
were like not a
an intentionally feminized
project but more of like a potential
hermaphroditism type of thing
yeah i can totally see that you know it
it happens a lot you know i mean
anytime you find a backseat
there was hermaphrodite somewhere
right so when you think about it on that
logic
kim the kim line we were just talking
about those are all backseats they were
all from hermaphrodite crisis process
gorilla glue hermaphrodite cross
um cookies hermaphrodite cross um you
know a lot of the great strains that are
out there the popular strains that are
out there were hermaphrodite process
so is it a good thing or is it a bad
thing well
from what i see it could be either or
so how would you feel about the argument
which some people put forward and which
i'll admit i'm starting to buy into
myself that arguably the most memorable
and influential strains of all cannabis
history were
bag seed hermaphrodite
yeah i would you know
um that were
mark they're all good strains absolutely
i would have to agree with that there
were accidental process that nobody
intended to do
yeah it certainly says something for our
legacy as breeders
[Laughter]
absolutely it does
so
on the topic of
being a breeder this is one i definitely
wanted to run by you and people are
probably scratching their heads why i
haven't done it so far someone in your
camp clearly has to be a doctor who fan
given all the strain names right so
the question is who's the who's the big
doctor who fan who initiated the idea
more importantly do you think that there
was kind of this advantageous marketing
side of things given that there was this
kind of household recognizable name
involved
originally it absolutely was um
my father
i grew up watching doctor who with my
father my sons grew up watching doctor
who with their grandfather my father
um
and they we just always it was a very
memorable point in time we all would get
together on a sunday and watch doctor
who on pbs
um
and it was just something that they were
really into it was originally the kids
came up pretty much with the idea and we
kind of just ran with it
um
now though that we've found a doctor who
mel
now we're it's
who's about our valley who or who's
cookies or you know we're calling
everything who's this or who's that kind
of thing
who's boss our frost boss cross
yeah we have a whole bunch of those
and so how much effort do you put into
the consideration of marketing when
naming a strain do you just think no i'm
naming a strain what i want to name it
or do you sometimes think to yourself oh
but i also need to ensure that it does
have some sort of commercial flyability
sorry viability
right um you know it uh
it helps to have a catchy name for sure
um there's some names out there that are
really long
that just don't roll off the tongue so
well
but
you know normally when we do a name we
try to include both parents
but a lot of them we you know it's
obviously someone we haven't but
they're somewhat of a reference you know
because i mean so doctor who is across
of
a mad scientist
to a time wreck
kind of self-explanatory when you look
at it from that point of view right
um
the tardis is a time wreck it's an
oregon diesel by a time wreck
i thought we kind of thought that was
you know
pretty viable as well there too
um
and now with the who's this and who's
that the kids don't necessarily like it
i think it's funny as can be
is it marketable we'll see i don't know
we haven't released any of it we haven't
taken any flowers to market yet or
anything like that and it's just what
i'm calling them right now so we can
kind of keep track of them
but uh
yeah marketability and a strain name is
great
um seeing as how we're in our own
industry trademark infringement you know
stuff like that kind of goes away a
little bit right there um we actually
have all of our strain names and our
names company names all that stuff
trademarked for use in the cannabis
industry
um
have had for a few years at this point
um you know and
actually the funny story was we got two
days
we got it we received our okay for
trademark within the cannabis industry
for doctor who two days later the olcc
which is the
who runs the cannabis in oregon
came out with a list of the 100 strains
that you couldn't use the name of and of
course doctor who was one of them
so
we have trademarks within state giving
us to the by the state but then again we
have this independent group telling us
we can't use it so you know i kind of
found that to be weird but
it is what it is
so what do you ultimately call it
just depends geek farms calls there's
the doctor
dog house grows our grape hi-chew cut
and they call that gray poo
okay yeah so they do skirt around it a
bit absolutely everybody knows what it
is
you just can't have it on the label at
the store
yeah yeah i understand
so
next thing i wanted to kind of ask you
what do you feel generally speaking
because i mean i think a big component
of what you've been saying today is that
individualization is a huge part of
stuff
but
just generally speaking what do you
think is the best type of weed for
anxiety and what do you think is the
best type of weed for depression in
terms of the characteristics you might
be looking for either to embody
so for um
i i prefer high mercy for anxieties i
suffer from anxieties quite a bit
i find indicas are a lot better for that
and for anxieties and relaxation
if you're depressed though a good sativa
you know to get you uplifting and
feeling good and
um sativas make you feel really creative
and wanting to go go do stuff and i
would explain to people it's not
necessarily that you're wanting to go do
stuff you just feel good
you know it's you don't feel your pains
you're not
you have a better outlook on because
you're not in pain you're not in
in distress you're not you know
depressed you want you actually are
looking at life a lot differently
yeah okay so if someone was looking to
take up growing to kind of help with an
issue like what we just mentioned or
something kind of similar do you think
they should consider cbd as like one of
the first things they should grow or do
you think that just regular strains is
probably a better first protocol
once again it would
excuse me once again it really depend
upon what the issue was that they were
trying to address
what i would tell somebody with ptsd
would be mercy
with pains with same thing
or cbd's
somebody that has cancer or
has
arthritis or fibromyalgia or you know
body aches pains joints so on and stuff
like that cbd is wonderful
obviously it's fantastic for
um
seizures epilepsy
we're finding great works in it and also
in autism
um you know so
you really have to curtail around each
individual patient at that point in time
um
yeah well i mean it brings us to kind of
the master question of it all in that
to what degree do you think that
cannabinoid therapy as a general term
needs to be individualized and i guess
maybe a specific way of phrasing that is
you know like people will hear that a
certain strain is good for something
maybe let's just say depression do you
think that someone with depression
should should look and try to get those
ones that are well known or at the end
of the day you're still going to have to
do some individual searching for it just
kind of clicks with you
yeah i know i would definitely start
with um popular strings that are known
for
and see if those work for you
and then um if those don't work for you
um or parts of it works and parts of it
doesn't you know like the onset is great
but then towards the end you're too
couch locked or whatever you know maybe
you need to move more towards instead of
a 70 30 indica sativa maybe you need to
go to
a 60 40 or something of that effect get
a little more sativa in there so you're
not the lag down isn't so bad
um
but yeah i would definitely start out
with with known
um
strains genetics that help the
symptoms that you're suffering from
and kind of go from there once again
it's so
personalized and individualized that uh
you know at least on a medical side i
think that it's
it's almost overwhelming i would believe
for the patient
and so what do you think are some
medicinal strains that commonly get
overlooked from your offerings
well we just did some cbd crosses we
acquired a uh
a metal harley suit from levi which was
og ringo's son who was his own o.j
ringo's son
and we did a bunch we did a few crosses
to our normal
setup of moms and they all turned out
pretty much two to ones um which is
fantastic
um
they're definitely i'm definitely
getting rave reviews from them
from a lot of our patients that that's
the ratio that they're looking for
um we're getting
upwards of 14 to 18 cbd with half that
in thc
just depends on what flavors you're
looking for what terpene profiles you're
looking for
you know
those are really good
um
most of them you know so our
sonic sonic screwdriver is really good
um we get uh
we find we get a lot of people that um
it helps with opiates quite a bit
um there's a couple cannabinoids in
there cb
cb10 cb9
that are like a opiate molecule but
they're laid back over upon themselves
so we're wondering if maybe it's working
as an opiate blocker or
similar enough to where it allows the
person to get off opiates to where it
stimulates the same receptors there as
um
but obviously a lot healthier for you
yeah
okay
so
one of the last questions i wanted to
quickly ask you about a random strain
orange cream soda it's another parent
haven't come across it's not in many
other crosses what's the back story on
that one
orange cream soda so um we had gotten a
clone from a
gentleman some seeds from the gentleman
he created
called daddy's girl it was a
sour diesel by um
mk ultra
and it was a fantastic strain and then
we crossed it with a
new york diesel and
the progeny from that
it was the only orange flavored one out
of them they all kind of had like the
soda creamy
flavor to them but that one just was
nice and orangey um
so yeah it's it's it's not one that's
very potent
it's definitely a daytime smoker for a
light smoker
it doesn't get you too
hyper it doesn't get you too low but
it's nice and mellow and keeps you uh
pretty pain free and works works quite
well and has just this fantastic
orange cream soda smell and flavor to it
fantastic so can we expect to see it pop
up again in the future
oh yeah yeah yeah we just crossed there
to the doctor who
um and uh we're gonna probably we'll
wind up being doing we're crossing her
to uh our quantum kushmel as well ah
nice nice and when can we expect to be
able to maybe get that is there still
some testing to come
yeah oh yeah
we're slow when it comes to that you
know we release maybe one or two strains
a year
i like to grow
that strain multiple times
and the reason being is normally i just
pop a five pack at a time
the reason being is because that's what
most people buy
so i want to see what somebody's getting
in a five pack
so i'll pop
i don't know eight nine ten
five packs
um
and see what i see you know
um so
realistically 40 to 50 seeds at a time
pretty much
[Music]
just to see what i see
and
that takes a while we send them out all
over the country for testing as well
and then we send them off to our larger
operations where they can run 100 to 500
at a time kind of thing
just to see how they do all across
so our testing is pretty tight and we
got to see something we really like kind
of thing
yeah of course so it brings up an
interesting point in my mind of pricing
seeds given you only do you know one or
two projects a year
it must make pricing hard for you
because you know there's a lot of work
going into it but i noticed you know you
guys are certainly no
aficionado seeds in regards to your
pricing
how do you feel about the whole topic
and do you struggle sometimes to kind of
you know feel a pri reach a price that
maybe you feel comfortable with in all
regards
you know
so
i remember when i had to buy seeds
and how much they were and how hard it
was for me to come up with the money to
buy those
so when we decided to come do the seed
company thing i was like you know we
need to keep it low to where anybody can
buy them we're doing this for the
patients we originally got into it for
helping in patients
patients can't afford 500 10 packs
they're doing good to afford 100 10 pack
so
i i really see that and
i don't want people to be denied good
medicine because they can't afford it
you see that in real life bad enough as
it is
once again if you can get somebody to
pay a thousand dollars for a 10 pack 800
for a 10 pack
why wouldn't you
you know i've never attempted it i don't
know that i would
um
but then again um
you know
if somebody will pay it why not
if the market will allow it
yeah definitely
so
what type of new or just special
offerings do you have coming up and do
you have anything you know i guess
special in regards to say
going to be released at events but maybe
not online or anything like that
um yeah actually
probably our next one is going to be our
mad scientist back cross
um will be our next release
we're really liking how it's turning out
it's definitely showing what we want to
see
it's cut genotypes down to
two got short and you got tall so a
couple more back crosses and we'll have
the mad scientist where we want it
um
but you know it uh it definitely has
some very beautiful things going on
so i think that we may release that
um we may have a few special things with
this down in uh emerald cup
uh as i said before that that's the only
cup we're doing this year
um
so yeah you know there's definitely
stuff that we do small batches of
that
you know maybe i'll bring some with me
just to
see if anybody wants any but the next
big release will most likely be our mad
scientist back across
okay and you got a new idea on an eta of
that
you know we might do a small release of
emerald cup
um but
we'll see um
we're still we we're waiting on some
coas right at the moment
but
everything else in grow rooms and grows
here and grows there has come back very
positive
also we did a
medicine time which is medicine woman by
time wreck
so uh
that uh
we're liking a lot of people are liking
it as well so that might come out as
well at the same time we try to do two
at a time
um
possibly emerald cup um as far as like
uh
one seats here now or something like
that i'll get it
maybe in the spring
yeah
cool
okay so on to our last one or two
questions before we've got our few
little quickfire ones it's probably a
bit of a a large question so you know
feel free to think about it for a minute
but what type of a legacy do you kind of
want to leave on the industry or
specifically that like you know
homegrown natural wonders would leave
uh
i haven't really thought about a legacy
i'm not quite done yet
you know i think uh legacy is
not really decided until you're done
doing your work
and with the group that i've joined up
with now the dutch consulting company
we're pretty far from being done
so uh yeah
that's interesting i i noticed that i
guess the obvious thing to state is that
it's not exclusively dutch
no it's not exclusively dutch but there
are a couple of dutch members so uh
yeah um
you know we're a consulting company and
working with george is just phenomenal
uh
he's
he's definitely on another level when it
comes to growers for sure
the the scale that he's done for a long
time um
is just amazing and the way that he
breaks everything down and makes
it's pretty cool it's i'm really happy
working with this company
and uh yeah we're just getting started
so
i don't think our legacy will be for a
little bit but
you know we are part of the pioneers in
this industry so
hopefully that'll be the legacy that we
helped make sure that everybody got a
fair
you know safe access to medicine and
or just
recreational marijuana whatever you want
to look at it as
but yeah
yeah good answer good answer so we'll
move on to our last little quick fire
questions
so
what is the best canvas you've ever
smoked in your life
oh good guy
um
you know
i don't know that that's a really tough
question because
you know you can have bed the most
flavorful that you've smoked and you
know the different specific high that
you've had but if i was to kind of look
at an all around combined
wow i'd have to go back to the mid-80s
and back to the old school roadkill
skunk i mean
you know granted it could have been my
point of references from back then
but my father was a grower so i was
growing a bunch of different pot
and when that came to town it was just
yeah um there we weren't growing
anything like that that's for sure
um kind of wish we would have been
but uh
yeah i'd have to say the 80s the 80s
roadkills
the 80s skunk or afghanis or whatever
they were
yeah okay
so
kind of a flip side question
what is in your opinion the worst strain
to have gained a heap of momentum
purple punch
i feel like there's not enough punch
yeah definitely not
it's purple but there ain't no punch
uh yes maybe it's good marketing
yeah no completely symbiotic is really
good about marketing and hiking up
strings um
when you actually do a lab test on it or
whatever you come to find out that uh oh
that's all lipids that's shining there
in the picture not
cannabinoids or anything to that effect
so
right it's all lipids and waxes and
that's the problem with a lot of those
strains like that they look great in the
picture
um and they can get hyped up all you
want but when it comes right down to
smoking them and doing coas and doing
extractions
well if you if you
de-wax your your
your extractions um yeah your your
returns on those strains are super low
because it's all waxes
and all fatties and lipids
well there you go
all right onward so
desert island top three you're gonna
take with you
siege of flowers
it's a good question right you've got an
infinite infinite supply of flower no no
explanation how but it just it is
just uh you gotta you gotta figure out
the rent-out point
um
so uh
wow
that's a rough one
you know i i probably sound it probably
you know
wow only three huh
i used to only give people two
what a nice guy he went up the tree
that's nice
um
you know i probably have to throw some
doctor who in there um
the kim
um
that's hard for the last one
yeah um
i could see why i was only two the third
one's kind of rough realistically uh
yeah i get you um
i probably want something a little bit
more um more uplifting so i probably go
with uh
i don't know maybe like a maybe a haze
an old silver super silver haze or
something to that effect
yeah that's a solid pick solid pick
all right so
what is a cut that you used to have but
you've lost and you wish you had it back
yeah that daddy's girl was pretty nice
and that was that sour diesel
by uh
mk ultra um that was pretty nice i wish
i kind of kind of wish i had that one
still
um
there's too many
you know that's why you just cruise
through i'm hoping that you'll find one
that will replace that in some kind of a
way
um
yeah we've already been fairly fortunate
about keeping backups and
you know giving to tight circles so we
haven't really lost a whole lot
that hash plant back in the 90s
that would have been
fantastic nowadays
um
but yeah
those would probably be my main two
nice answers
so lucky last question if you could go
back in time anywhere any place
presumably to collect some land race
seeds where and when and what variety
wow um
so probably um yeah the afghani the
afghani mountains the hindu kush
mountains
um the silk trail i guess is what they
call it a lot
um
i think that that's where a lot of the
really good stuff comes from but then
again you got the chocolate ties you've
got
you know
the whole continent over there can we
count that as this one place
[Laughter]
just broader asia just a broad broad
broad spectrum of it
um
yeah you know it's
that's a really good question
i've never really thought about that one
much if i could go back in a time where
would i go and what seeds would i want
um but yeah
africa afghanistan and
the hindu mountains pretty pretty much
i'm thinking
yeah good two very good and popular
answers
so
bringing us to the end of things do you
have any shout outs or comments you'd
like to make
obviously a shout out to dutch
consulting company
um
for
providing me with
probably the happiest i've been working
in a long long time
obviously shout out to my sons
because without them we wouldn't be
doing what we do
and of course their mom my wife
um who has put up with a lot
other than that
shout out to all my friends they all
know who they are
thanks for all the support for over the
years
but yeah
fantastic great answer so thank you so
much for coming on the show od and uh
setting some things straight and
dropping some awesome history
absolutely time it was a pleasure i know
we've been working on this for a minute
um as you said we spoke last year at the
emerald cup and discussed it then and
here we are almost a year later and
finally talking so it's been great being
on here thanks for asking us to be on
and uh allowing us to maybe hopefully
clear up some things
yeah no problem i can't wait to smoke
some doctor who with you again soon
absolutely absolutely i'm assuming you
will be at the emerald cup this year i
will i'll come swing by for sure
absolutely please do
most definitely
so there you have it folks a big big
thank you to odie for taking the time to
drop by
and a huge thank you to you guys for
sticking around to the end as always
seeds here now organic gardening
solutions
420 australia you know them you love
them
go show them some love
if you want to get access to a little
bit more content help support the show
make sure to go check out the patreon
page
they're the mvps
let's hang out at emerald cup game
see you
[Music]
la la la la
[Applause]
[Music]
la la la la
[Applause]
[Music]
la la la
you