[Applause]
[Music]
was
[Applause]
[Music]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast
your casual budding enthusiast thing for
people who like plants
on this episode we have the master of
the microbes himself jeff lowenfeld's
here to answer all our questions on
organic gardening
goodwin
and the future of the counter industry
as always huge shout out to our sponsors
seeds here now your number one seed bank
in the game guarantee on satisfaction
not just germination all the best
breeders
go get the new duke diamond drop figure
4 on point
likewise check out radio ridge nurseries
your one-stop shop for all the best
clones in the game exclusive breeder
cups you can't get elsewhere and just
some great people in general
[Music]
and finally a shout out to organic
gardening solutions and the patreon gang
holding down the fort down under we love
you guys thank you for all the support
[Music]
so
let's get into it alrighty so a massive
welcome to a man who simply needs no
introduction a friend of mine and the
author of what many consider to be the
organic gardener's bible and the man who
reminded the world the importance of
mycorrhizal fungi jeff lowenfels thank
you so much for joining us today well
thank you thank you i guess you know i
got my brand new hat on here you know
maybe i could take it off so people i'm
really kind of bald
whatever uh anyway yeah hey thanks for
having me uh what fun uh you know this
is an amazing technology we have we can
meet from all over the world and you
know that's just an amazing thing but it
makes sense when you think about it
because microbes are ubiquitous too
they're all over the world so i can talk
about
alaskan microbes you can talk about uh
australian microbes basically we're
talking about the same thing which is
amazing
i love it i love it the connections are
there far and wide so the first question
we like to ask our guests what have you
been smoking on recently
well let's see uh a little citrus sap
someone someone gave me uh
just a just a couple of days ago uh you
know when you go around give advice to
people about what to grow and how to
grow things and whatnot sometimes they
they give you a little gift here and
there which is kind of fun uh
but i i really i've really
been smoking
i don't really smoke i vaporize
flour i have haven't really had a
combustion situation with a joint in
about four or five years because i i
find it to be much more enjoyable i
think it's probably a lot healthier if
you don't carbonize
the flour but in any case i've been
doing this you know now that my parents
are gone i can say it uh
a long long long time and it's finally
gotten to the point where
the stigma is gone where the
quality has improved where we're not you
know smoking or vaporizing sticks and
sticks and seeds uh and of course the
effort to legalize all around the world
has just been absolutely phenomenal as
you know so uh it's a it's a new world
we're living in um i think there there
are a couple of rules we all need to
follow and uh uh some of them we are and
some of them we aren't and i think i
think we'll get there but uh uh we we've
got to prevent
governments from looking at cannabis
as the gateway to taxation that it has
become in the united states
and
start treating this plant more like a
tomato plant
than something else
this is this is a plant that's easy to
grow that everybody can grow
let's not treat this thing like it's uh
a fourth branch of government for
goodness sakes you know it's crazy yeah
yeah okay i'm off my stool
no i love it and i've definitely got
some stuff up that alley i want to jump
into but let's just quickly rewind for a
minute what was your first experience
with cannabis
well i was uh
actually uh in college in cambridge uh
massachusetts and uh my brother came
over to me
uh freshman year he was a law student
about to graduate and his girlfriend he
said had just tried to commit suicide
and he made me promise i would never
ever smoke cannabis of course we called
it marijuana back then uh and so i i
went a year while he was off in europe
getting a fulbright scholarship and when
he came back i was helping him unpack
and the first thing out of his suitcase
was a gigantic beautiful inlaid
hash pipe that he picked up in morocco
and i said what's this
he said oh oh wait you could buy a can
of hash for five dollars in morocco and
i went what
you made me not smoke can i have
marijuana for a year
that was that was it so i went back to
college uh one of one of my great
friends uh we just we just got stoned
and i haven't looked back since
fantastic so
when let's fast forward a little bit
when was it that you grew your first
plant
well let's see i probably first got
stoned about 1967
68 probably about 1975 i was in law
school at the time
and one of my law professors had a bunch
of plants that had
uh mealybugs on them
and uh
she knew i was a gardener she said can
you do anything with them i said i don't
know about you you know give them to me
and i'll try
and i did
so the alcohol took care of both me and
the mealybugs on the plants and we we
did just fine
fantastic so
what was it ultimately that kind of
stimulated you to write teeming with
microbes
well i've always been a gardener and uh
i've been uh in fact
they tell me i am the longest
running garden columnist in the world
i've been writing a garden column in
anchorage alaska
since 1977
every single week i never miss a single
week because they put your picture in
the paper and they say he's not there
he'll be back in a couple of weeks and
to me that always said rob his house so
i always have a column and um
i
you know i
wasn't writing for cannabis i was
writing for people in anchorage alaska a
place
not unlike for example i would imagine
perth
where most of the people are new
they've never gardened there they don't
know what can grow there the climate is
different there and so i was sort of the
the the advisors to here's what you can
grow and once a week i wrote a column
and
every now and then i would write a
column about tomatoes and tell people
that you know wink wink this is about
tomatoes but it might be about cannabis
as well but i was a chemical head i was
a chemical head for sure
uh
my family had a intricate relationship
with the founder of miracle grow
he used to work for my father and my
grandfather and so we we were always big
into the miracle grow and it wasn't
until
oh probably about 1990
uh one of my friends sent me a a picture
of a nematode being strangled by
uh uh a fungal hyphy that was trying to
protect the root it's in the first book
team with microbes and i saw that
and i said oh oh
and i figured out
that maybe being organic meant something
and maybe these microbes which we were
always trying to get rid of
made a lot of sense and so
i
ended up finding dr elaine ingham
who is the guru of all things soil food
web as far as i'm concerned and became
quite the disciple let's just put it
that way
and it's impacted my life ever since
it's really been quite something
so just to clarify when you were growing
your first plants were you using
something like miracle grow or was it in
absolutely
oh sure yeah i was using miracle grow up
until uh up until i wrote the book
basically i mean the book came out in
2006. i really started writing the book
in about 19
oh
1998 or so i had to write it a couple of
times because the first time i wrote it
i wrote it as a comic book and the
publisher looked at it and said you know
this may make sense but we don't dumb
books down we we make them smarter so if
you rewrite this book in more scientific
terms will publish it so they did
i did and they did and anyway so it
wasn't it wasn't until about 1998 or 99
that i realized that the miracle grow
system the system of using chemicals was
not the right way to grow plants it
didn't matter whether it was cannabis a
tomato whether it was a flower vegetable
using using chemicals does not make
sense and of course this was long before
you know we had greta and other people
telling us yeah it doesn't make sense
for other reasons on top of what you
think so
yeah it was quite something and it was
quite a turnaround
i had to
basically admit to my readers that i had
been giving them bad advice for 25 years
and i remember the newspaper ran a
series of ads i wish you could find in
the newspaper boxes and just had my back
my back
and it said you know in two weeks jeff
lonfels is going to turn his back on 25
years of advice and i did thinking that
all of my readers would abandon me
immediately what i discovered was
there's an incredible thirst for
organics that people
want to be organic they don't want to
use chemicals
and it's only because they get forced
into it that they end up i think
succumbing to what we call a new way of
gardening which is actually uh you know
a destructive terrible terrible way of
growing ruining soil and ruining the
life in the soil so
long long long answer for for a quick
quick question
no they're our favorite type of answers
so i've got to ask you you know a
favorite kind of topic amongst all
organic growers do you remember your
first organic harvest
um
yes i do because the taste was
completely different
i can taste those chemicals right you
know maybe it's my head maybe not but
but the taste is different and of course
now we know that it's not just you're
not just doing this for the
for the plant you're doing this for the
worker
if that may be yourself
and you're doing it for the environment
as well so it's become become much more
important than just simply growing a
plant that tasted
clean and pure and that you knew did not
contain any of these things that
probably are not that good for you so
um yeah i remember and and
i i think that most people do and i
think when most people go into a
supermarket if the price was the same on
food they would buy the organic over the
non-organic period
the organization that i belong to of
garden writers
it's a big national us organization
i'm sure there's a counterpart in
australia and there is not one of us not
one of us
that isn't organic
nobody
willingly writes an article or does a
television show or a podcast that says
hey
here's what you need to do go out to
your nearest hardware store and find
that smelly section and buy that crappy
crap it's chemical and mix it in you
know now the nearest we get to that from
my perspective and you're going to get a
lot of mail over this one is hydroponics
you know i mean i don't think
hydroponics is the same thing as soil
either
it's certainly a lot better than
uh
the pesticide herbicide chemical
situation but i i like the idea of good
living soil period
100 i can get down with that so
what was the initial response from the
cannabis community in regards to the
book did it take off or did it take a
little bit of time before the wheels
started to turn
well i wasn't really paying attention uh
when the book came out
uh i was
inundated with or and it was
frankly the subject matter not the
writing but the book got great reviews
uh you know uh most important book
written in the past 25 years and maybe
ever hold it you know i mean like
you know
really uh you know i mean and and you
know
horticulture all these magazines and
things picked it up and uh big and it
became quite the topic for uh what i
call uh the garden club circuit and i
run around the country in canada and i
gave lectures on how to use microbes to
grow your vegetables and everything else
and i wasn't paying attention to the
cannabis market frankly
because it was underground uh and and it
wasn't as organized as it has become
uh it became evident oh
probably around 2010
2012 when colorado started to legalize
uh here in the united states
it became evident that this book was
being read by people who grow cannabis
as well
one time i was sitting on an airplane
going to a conference and somebody came
up to me and said
hey i read your book grows the best weed
ever
and i was floored first of all that the
person recognized me
second that the person read the book but
third that you know they were using it
to grow cannabis and now of course uh i
think my publisher has come to realize
uh that the cannabis market is quite
large and they read a lot of books in
the cannabis world so um
it's become a bible and then and then
the other two books that that go with it
it's a tr i call it a trilogy series
teaming with microbes was the first one
and i really wrote it for dr elaine
ingham i didn't write it for myself or
anything else i mean she asked me you
know what could i do to help her and i
said i could write you a book and so i
wrote the book
teaming with nutrients i wrote for
myself because i was sitting in a
restaurant with my wife
i was looking at a picture of a bunch of
women eating spaghetti and i said to
myself you know you're you may be
america's longest-running garden
columnist but you don't have any idea
how plants eat
you know how plants get their food
because that's what that first book told
you
that's how plants get the food but how
do they take it in and what do they do
with it once it gets into their cells
well
that was teeming with nutrients and it
was to me
sort of a metaphysical
trippy holy crow i mean the numbers of
cells in a single plant
what happens in each individual cell the
number there are 10 000 individual
kinds of enzymes in each individual cell
in a plant
there are 10 000 of each one maybe i
mean there are gazillions of i mean
you know and so all of a sudden not only
did i understand how a plant starts to
work and how it gets put to you know
how it works how it eats how it takes
the food in but then i started to
realize wait a minute enzymes
enzymes are proteins
you know
you know maybe we need this and that
maybe the terpenes are and all of a
sudden you can start to think
like a cannabis plant uh or any other
kind of plant and you know how to take
care of it better when you realize that
these enzymes that i just talked about
work best at 74 to 76 degrees oh
oh okay well maybe now i know what the
right temperature is to grow everything
not just cannabis but uh so yeah it was
a fascinating ride and then and then
after that i was asked to
revise teaming with microbes because
mycorrhizal fungi were coming onto the
scene when i wrote him with microbes
there were a paragraph on them i mean we
couldn't grow them they couldn't be
duplicated people thought they were
ubiquitous you know if you've got them
in australia i got them in alaska
so uh
but but that turned out not to be true
and so i revised teaming with microbes
while i was doing that it became very
evident to me that over the next four or
five years there was research going on
that was going to result in a need for a
special book on
just these particular
fungi uh in general and so that that was
teaming with micros it's not just about
uh um
uh
mycorrhizal fungi it's about
fungi in general but oh my goodness
gracious when you take a look for
example at the far fires in australia if
those mycorrhizal fungi live you're
going to get trees coming back if they
don't live forget it
those trees are not coming back you're
going to have prairie land well that's
kind of an amazing thing and now we're
able to grow them we're able to
duplicate them and we're able to use
them in growing specific plants and so
we know which one
is the one that feeds cannabis
and if you use it
your cannabis plant is like no other
cannabis plant you've ever seen so yeah
so that's the trilogy they're a lot of
fun but they all start with the microbes
yeah what a really comprehensive
overview of them all so i guess the
obvious kind of follow-up question is
your more recent book diy autoflowering
cannabis what was it that stimulated to
do this one
well
you know it's a good question i
i was influenced by the in on the first
book by a friend of mine tom alexander
um he was a very early cannabis grower
during the illegal days uh he helped
coin the term
sansamiya
back in the day and
he's the guy that that sent me the
picture of the of the
nematode being strangled by the fungus
he and i are very very good friends uh
one day i was at his place in california
and he showed me these these tomato
sized cannabis plants and he said these
are called autoflowering cannabis plants
and they're really kind of cool uh you
know look at these cute little flowers
blah blah blah this was 10 years ago
so
i
decided to try to grow them and and they
were fun uh nothing spectacular
but i live in anchorage alaska and in
anchorage alaska you don't get
days that are shorter than nights until
september 21st
that's about the day of your first frost
so you're not going to get flowering
cannabis in anchorage alaska unless you
have a light deprivation situation etc
etc but these autoflowers don't have a
photo period they go from seed to flower
based on genetics
so you end up with a flowering plant
that's harvested after seven to nine
weeks
so i'm thinking again i'm thinking like
australia now in australia in the
capital territory
i guess it's now legal to grow cannabis
if people aren't growing auto flowering
cannabis there they're making the
biggest mistake australians have ever
made they're making the biggest mistakes
since bringing in the toads is that i
don't know if that's i can say that um
because these things grow
from seven to nine weeks to harvest seed
to harvest
that that means you're limited to six
plants well they think they think you're
going to get one or two harvests a year
they don't realize with your autoflowers
you're going to get
you know so many more but it turns out
that these plants are now better than
indica and sativa and once that happened
i decided it was time to put my
reputation on the line
and and sort of help the autoflower
industry get going uh because
they are so much better than regular
indica sativas with which they're bred
um
so let me list let me list the things i
like about them and and i i should
preface this by saying the book is
called
diy autoflowering cannabis
it is not a book for the professional
grower this is a book for the
professional grower's mother
or brother or aunt or uncle uh it goes
from soup to nuts on cannabis but it
centers around this idea that
we now have a plant that doesn't have an
oral period
that goes from seed to flower based on
genetics that's easy to grow in fact if
you fertilize them
in good soil they won't do well because
their soil is too rich
they uh are small tomato sized plants
and yet today
not true
four years ago but today
the yield on them per acre is
better than the yield in sativa uh uh
indica uh yields unbelievable so um i'm
predicting right here on your show that
in the next five years
nobody will be growing except
occasionally
the bigger plants everybody will be
growing auto flowering cannabis and i
wanted the world to know about it
i believe this is a plant you're going
to be able to get at your local nursery
every spring i believe this is a plant
you're going to be able to buy seeds
from the seed rack you grow it at home
in a five gallon bucket
you reuse the soil you don't have to
spray it with anything it grows so fast
that it grows through cycles where it
would have problems so you know if
there's a bug that wants that plant by
the time the bug gets settled in the
plant's already grown through the next
stage oh my goodness gracious they
flower after two weeks
so you know this is a terrific terrific
new plant i felt it needed a book this
is again
not a book for the professional and
it's not what i call a cannabis porn
book
we have so many cannabis porn books you
know beautiful buds and beautiful colors
and sizes and you know but
but you know this is a how-to for your
mother and if it's legal where she's
growing you should buy her this book get
it on amazon just like the other ones
and and get her some seeds and get her
into this plant because it's a fun fun
plant to grow autoflowers uh you know
it's fun to grow a
sativa in indica it's a hundred times
more fun to grow an autoflower they grow
right before your eyes unbelievable
indoors and outdoors
yeah that's amazing you basically
answered the most of the next question i
was going to ask which was did you kind
of like you know without necessarily
thinking about it right this is
something which would kind of get the
older generations who might be a little
more skeptical and just kind of bridge
that gap for and make it that little bit
easier for him to get into it well
yeah yeah part of my thinking was this
is a book for my mother even though
she's no longer here but uh no this is
the kind of book my mother she was a
gardener she loved to grow things and
she'd try anything new the last time
something new came to america it was the
snap p i don't know if you've got him
down where you are but this the snap p
came and everybody went nuts for him
everybody went nuts for him you know
nobody had to write a book about it uh
unfortunately cannabis has had such a
bad rap
that i that i i think
the book needed to be written because
uh
it deals with the stigma it deals with
why it's illegal it deals with all the
silliness uh but it also introduces
people to the notion of strains and land
races and uh
you know all of those things in fact uh
one of the pictures i've got in there is
a strain they call it here in the united
states the australian bastard
and it's a spectacular looking little
plant it's got millions of little leaves
and people are breeding it right now
with autoflowers developing some very
interesting plants from it so uh
it's just a it's fun and i think i think
this is the next tomato uh i don't i
don't know if where you are tomatoes are
a big hobby plant but but here in the
united states they're the you know
they're the holy grail of gardening you
know to get a fresh tomato and to give
it to your neighbor you know you know is
like where in the sheriff's badge in
town you know i'm a gardener
and so so you know this is this is i
think the next tomato plant it's a lot
of fun to grow and frankly i would say
here here in the states
oh maybe a quarter of the growers
commercial growers are now using these
the they've they're replacing the bigger
guys because the yields are bigger it's
hard for people to believe that
particularly people who've used
autoflowers in the past
not the same genetics they used to be
yeah okay so maybe a slightly redundant
question and that you could maybe infer
your answer but are you kind of on board
with the no-till movement is that the
the kind of absolutely absolutely uh
uh
the no-till movement is
a part of soil food webby uh thinking uh
if you till
your soil and and i'll relate this to
cannabis in a minute if you till your
soil first of all you're breaking up
that wonderful mycorrhizal fungi which
is described in teaming with fungi uh
your your
when you cut a worm in half you don't
get two worms you get half a dead worm
uh you know two half's a dead worm uh
when you
unless you hit it at the 18th segment in
which case one half might live
when you have bacteria that are up here
you rototill you put them down here
they're supposed to be up here
actinimocities are supposed to be deeper
in the soil not anyway
rototilting is a very very bad thing to
do um
and when you grow cannabis i would go
one step further i reuse my soil i'm
regenerative um
i reuse the roots
i leave the i cut the stem
i plant right in the pot without pulling
the plant out that's how much no-till i
believe in
those roots have been putting out extra
dates into that soil attracting and
feeding the right kind of cannabis
microbes
those roots provide pathways for new
roots to travel down
and by not breaking it up of course
you've left the mycorrhizal fungi that
are there in place with spores so that
the plant becomes infected as it grows
into it so yeah no-till i'm really big
on no-till
and and i'm i
i love to till it's so much fun
it's one of it's one of gardening's joys
and yet
it's the worst thing you can do do not
rototill after you garden the first time
fine after that never again now why do
people rototill
well this is a this is an interesting uh
thing and it applies to places like like
alaska and uh uh
the united states during the colonial
period australia
new zealand places that were being
settled
during the early 1800s
late 1700s an english
guy
codified what everybody thought and that
was that plants ate
soil it's called the eumesterium of
growing and if plants ate soil this guy
said
let's just pulverize it up if we
pulverize it up it'll be easier for him
to eat it so he invented rototilling now
in the united states in australia in new
zealand uh in in places where there was
old growth forest and settlers came
they didn't want to grow old growth they
wanted to grow vegetables to eat
and so they cut the old growth down
and old growth forests are supported by
soils that are very heavy in fungi
vegetables like cannabis are supported
by
bacteria based soils some fungi but
mostly bacteria and when you rototill
you convert old-growth soil into
bacteria soil
and once you do it you've got bacteria
soil you don't have to do it again and
again and again and again and again and
we do
and we're losing soil all around the
world as a result it's a bad bad bad
thing to do
so uh you should you reuse the soil in
your pots at a minimum just you know
compost it and then reuse it after three
months
but you can grow three four times in the
same pot uh without without changing it
at all
you feed the soil with compost and
compost teas
uh but but you don't rototill
yeah great answer so what's your
thoughts on some of the new quote
organic companies we see coming out that
kind of have these long lasting granular
solutions you put in the soil and water
over time you know have you come across
these and what's your thoughts
yeah it depends on what they're using i
mean you know uh
uh perlite's getting a bad wrap these
days because it doesn't go away uh
people are using a lot more cocoa choir
which is a good recyclable product it
can it's porous uh so it's good um
you know the
the companies i worry about are the ones
that use the word organic without any
certification
uh i don't trust those companies at all
and and organic is a word that people
kick around and regenerative as well uh
you got to have
country standards and they got to be
followed then you know you're getting
something good um there are a lot of new
products that people are bringing on
board uh some of them are gmo products
some of them are
[Music]
made by gmo
products in other words they're not gmo
themselves but they're made by gmo
bacteria so you got to be very careful
about what you're using i'm i'm pretty
pure about about the term organics uh
i'm pretty old-fashioned about it as
well now
mycorrhizal fungi wow they never had
that as a when i was a kid uh is organic
uh so yeah so there's there's new things
coming into the organic field uh that
are certainly worth following and and uh
uh
a lot of ipm kind of stuff
you know coming in as well and
fascinating some of the great stuff
that's happening so
very excited about it and the cannabis
field is the field i think that leads it
all uh used to be the viticultures
uh not the not the farmers i'm sorry
but now i think it's the cannabis
growers uh really some of the best
gardeners i've ever ever worked with uh
i do advising uh all over the place i've
got a team of people uh you know it
doesn't matter whether you're in
colombia mexico alaska canada
you know kansas doesn't matter
if you're growing cannabis there's a way
to do it that's the right way and if
you're open to it wow
really is something else the results are
incredible absolutely incredible so
that's been the best thing about all of
this stuff is that people come up to me
and they and they tell me that they've
converted
uh and that they've never looked back i
go yes
uh because i don't make any money off of
this stuff i can tell you my publisher
might make some but uh you know it's
when somebody writes a letter or you
call up and say you know let's do a
podcast or you know you give me a nice
introduction there uh you know that's
that's what this is all about because
we we've screwed things up
uh i'm you know 70 years old and right
now my my goddess is greta uh you know
we've got to make sure that she gets the
garden and her kids get the garden
period uh and it doesn't matter whether
it's cannabis or tomatoes uh if we if we
don't do it organically
um you know they're not gonna make it
period simple as that
yep the sentiment i can get behind again
it's kind of the theme of my side of the
comments but
a question i'm sure a ton of fans want
to know would you be able to give us a
little basic excuse me would you be able
to give us a little basic rundown of
your growing setup and by that i just
mean what type of amendments do you like
to use when you're doing your soil and
you know do you have um you know just
little things you like to do
sure uh well first of all i travel an
awful lot so
that's one of the nice things about the
autoflowers
is that i can come back and they're done
um so i do a lot of i do a lot of tent
growing in the winter
uh so i've got a nice line tent that
i've made myself uh using electrical uh
poles you know that i've
rigged together using the little circuit
socket things you know they fit in
anyway uh
so i've got a tent that grows about four
to six plants and then outdoors uh i
live on i live on eight acres and i i
garden on about three or two or three of
them uh i've got a small outdoor
greenhouse and an indoor greenhouse as
well um
the mix i use is is is based with
something called alaska humus
this is a very rich
natural
soil from alaska
in anchorage we have
earthquakes all the time and this soil
has to be removed
80 feet of it and put into landfills
where it's no longer available before
you can build
the giant cabbages that people associate
with alaska they're grown in this stuff
in a in an area outside of anchorage
where it's it's you know got a little
six inch layer right down in the root
zone uh so it's very very rich rich
a microbiol biological soil in fact dr
elaine once said it has the highest
microbiology of any soil she's ever seen
now uh i basically plant in that
with
uh i'll put in some cocoa in it
just for just for good drainage
i'll put a little green sand in it uh
i'll put a little bit of
uh
fish
fish hydrolyzite in it uh but that's
basically it now for most people
good compost
is is a good starter because it provides
the indigenous microbes from your own
area these are microbes that are going
to live in your area so the fact that
i'm using alaskan humus and basically
what alaska yumus is is compost uh it
just happens to be from from out in the
wild every summer it thaws every winter
it freezes been going on for ten
thousand years and this is beautiful
beautiful black
smells delicious
um that's streptomyce that's a
streptomycin cell smell that's in there
that's ah beautiful stuff anyway uh
you've got it all over all around the
world but if you don't you make compost
and that compost you make on the ground
you don't make it in a machine because
you want indigenous microbes come up
from the soil in the ground and get into
your compost pile
or you make vermicompost
and and uh you put in indigenous soil
into the verma compost bin if you use a
bin vermicompost is terrific because
it's got concentrated uh uh nutrients in
it that that compost doesn't have um
that should be the base for everybody's
everybody's uh grow now if you've got a
big gigantic farm that's hard to do uh
and so you you just have to constantly
make compost you gotta constantly amend
you gotta constantly uh uh you know feed
and take care of stuff and it's
important uh that once you once you get
your soil you keep it alive i use
compost teas and compost extracts a
compost extract is nothing more than
taking compost putting it into a a uh a
cheese cloth
you know
set up and just squeezing it in warm
water
for 15 minutes you end up squeezing out
the microbes you don't multiply them but
you you extract them out and so you feed
them i always have a layer of compost
down on the base of my plants
not on the base but at the base of my
plants
and
once every five or six grows
i will
actually dig in
depending on what the tests show that it
needs what it needs i use a living mulch
usually a sweet clover mulch
which is which is easy to do
and i test with something that most
people have never heard of called a
microbiometer
i advise this i advise this company
because once i saw this thing i went
crazy i've always looked for something
that i could say to people
your product teams with microbes
buy my seal i'll give you an endorsement
now how do you do that well you know how
do you show that something teams with
microbes you can look it under a
microscope and everything else but that
really doesn't tell you anything what
this this does
this tells you the changes in biomass in
your soil biomass is basically the
microbes in your soil
and so
uh to do a biomass test for most soil
tests it's
it takes a month maybe three weeks if
you're lucky
this is a test that this woman has
developed that you use your iphone or
your your android doesn't matter which
you use a phone you uh
you take a sample you
mix it out in the field in about seven
to ten minutes and then you do a reading
right there cost you five bucks
and it tells you what the biomass is of
your soil now if you're putting a good
organic fertilizer on your plant
the biomass increases because the
microbes go out and eat it up and etc
and you can tell what's happening to
your plant what's
by looking at the microbiometer
test so if you're a grower you can tell
when the plant begins to flower the
exudates slow down and you get a lower
biomass so it's a fascinating new tool
that's being tested here in the united
states uh it's being sold in australia
actually and you can get it on the web
go look at the www.microbiometer.com
fascinating new tool
and and
basically if i do a test and i have a
test that's over about five or six
hundred i don't do anything to my soil
nothing
i'll just take the the alaska humus put
a little choir in it for drainage and
that's it simple as that so it's a very
interesting new tool that i think is
going to help people test their soil and
know what to do with it particularly
when they're growing cannabis because
let's face it you know it's not that
hard a plant to grow
it's it's a
plant you can screw up easily but it's
not that hard to grow if you if you do
it right so yeah brilliant and i i've
actually bought some of those tests
myself and i can definitely vouch for
what you're saying they're very good
aren't they
yeah
it's
fascinating absolutely fascinating and
the difference for example i use it in
in alaska in the spring it tells me when
spring hits i see it as an increase in
the biomass when the trees start to drop
the you know the the extra days start to
increase that tells me it's time to tell
my readers
you're about to be outdoors soon
because the trees never never lie
it's fascinating it's a great new tool
and great things are happening and
my understanding is it's even being
improved so
i wish i wish i knew who the
distributors were in australia but
anyway it's it's a great new tool
yeah fantastic i just wanted to loot
back quickly to a topic we were talking
about earlier when you mentioned that
you're fond of products that have the
organic certification and whatnot
are there any that you
basically recommend to steer clear of
because in the past and particularly in
the cannabis industry some of our guests
including myself have been quite
skeptical of the omri registration which
is
yeah a bit sinister do you think there
are some that aren't as good as others
yeah i don't think armory sinister i
just don't think it's as comprehensive
as it could be
um
there is a company that i don't i you
know that uses the word organic all the
time i would never touch their lights i
would never touch their fertilizer i
would never touch their soil i would
never listen to the nasty scots guy that
yells at me and tells me to put the
stuff on uh in the in on my lawn in the
spring and i think you know who i'm
speaking of
and i don't like them because they make
people see
yeah so you got to be careful omri i'm
breaking is very simple to get that's
the problem with it they won't give it
to just anybody but it's too simple to
get to be very very comfortable uh very
often it makes sense to actually now
that we've got the web go on the web and
contact the companies and and ask for
the uh they call a manufacturer product
sheets and and things like that and
tests and a lot of these companies have
it uh so i think that's that's
what you really need to look for find
one that's good then and stick with it
um
and then i i also like i like to go into
uh nurseries and to grow stores
and find out what's what are people
really getting good results from what's
what makes sense what do you guys like
you know and i look at it and i smell it
and i you know i try it
uh so it's
fascinating how many new things there
are out there whoa
and the big guys are getting in there so
i i won't mention the name of that
particular one uh but but i will mention
bayer uh and you know what they're doing
now is they're trying to figure out how
to how to modify a plant so that it'll
produce its own nitrogen which is a
great thing
i'm not i'm not sure how they're going
to do it
they're trying to make plants
uh
give off the signal that attracts
mycorrhizal fungi so they can it's you
know the things that they're doing
part of me says gee that's interesting
and maybe it's going to be good but the
way they go about it may be not good so
we've got to we just got to keep our
eyes open and we have to talk to each
other about this stuff that's why i love
giving talks i love going to conventions
uh we have them here in the united
states all over the place i mean my
goodness gracious you you know every any
place that legalizes cannabis ends up
with
a good conference every other month
and there are lots of them and and so
it's very interesting to see
who
who thrives who doesn't uh who people
frequent and who they don't and it's
it's
the bad guys are getting known out there
pretty pretty well
yeah
well that that actually perfectly segues
into the next question in that we do see
commercial ag kind of moving into the
cannabis scene what do you think is a
role they can play that's not going to
be the downfall and more importantly do
you think there's anything that they're
already currently doing that could be
brought to the cannabis industry that we
just haven't adopted yet
well let me let me let me divide the egg
thing into two the first is sort of the
information egg you know the magazines
oh my god there are a gazillion i'm
sitting on the floor here
there are gazillion a gazillion
magazines on cannabis too many and of
course uh i've written a couple of
articles that have not been printed
because i write articles like uh no
don't use this product don't use that
product uh you know these are bad people
anybody associated with glyphosate
shouldn't be trusted you know that kind
of and and they won't print them
why because the space has been invaded
uh and we now know of course that big ag
and you know and big hydro uh has
invaded the space and uh so as well as
big uh
bad guy good guys you get bad guys as
well and and that has happened so so the
informations that you get
may be wrong in the first place
and that worries me quite a bit um
when you pick up a magazine you can't
trust the advertising
don't
don't trust the advertising i don't know
what else to say
so that's the first problem
the second problem of course is that big
egg
tends to have
the idea that they're gonna do oils in
mind uh you know that's they're not
they're not in it for individual flowers
yet i don't see
you know a big tobacco company uh saying
okay we're gonna make tobacco
then we're gonna make cannabis joints it
will come for sure and i'm sure there'll
be
cigar companies that'll make blunts
but right now it seems to me that what
big egg is interested in is uh being
able to produce enough leaf
that they're able to
uh you know make oils out of and waxes
and that kind of stuff and and uh
i don't i don't know whether that's
healthy for the industry a i don't mean
that in terms of lung problems and all
kinds
the ability to be able to grow indoors
in a greenhouse is phenomenal
the ability to be able to use good
lighting is phenomenal
um
and i think that big egg can bring that
and
the
electronic the electronics that they
have associated with them into the
cannabis world
uh i mean you you know as well as i know
that when someone sits in a tractor
these days
it's more like sitting in a living room
than it is you know it's like being in a
tesla
television sets and
satellite navigation and all that kind
of garbage and stuff and so but you know
a lot of that stuff probably makes sense
uh light deprivation new greenhouse
materials uh the ability to be able to
control water and save water uh and
purify uh the ability to be able to
control
mildew all that kind of stuff i think
makes a lot of sense a lot of the
genetic testing uh not associated with
the cannabis itself but genetic testing
associated with the
the diseases and the viruses and the
bugs uh so the the things that
that feed it all that kind of stuff is
going to be helpful and and is being
applied already so i don't know if that
answers your question but i think there
is a lot in big egg i worry they don't
know what they're doing
i worry about the little guy
uh but then i you know i'm always
reminded about the wine industry and
that there's always room for the low
label and the little label and et cetera
et cetera well
okay
but i don't i don't want to see cannabis
turn into a mass-produced
uh
uh chemically sprayed grown
bad for you
uh item i mean i don't think there's any
excuse for that and and
i'm a little bit embarrassed about how
we've how we've gone about legalization
because i don't think we've done it the
right way uh we haven't we haven't
looked at this from any other any other
way then
uh we need
we need to convince governments and the
only way to convince governments is with
money taxation that was the wrong way to
go about it so
that was way off track no it was it was
perfect and i want to even follow that
up with a kind of a complex issue we
haven't been able to dive into too much
in the past but i think you're going to
be perfect for it so we know for a fact
that there are companies out there such
as molecular farms and their parent
companies who are genetically modifying
cannabis specifically to do things like
so that every plant is expressing the
exact same phenotype same height and
everything so the idea is that like they
can be perfectly harvested by like a
combine in the field that's just going
to optimize to pick them all the fear is
that one of the things they're doing is
modifying the terpene profiles so that
for example there's zero immersing
and the fear is that these are such
genetically dominant plants that if they
do hermaphrodite which you hope they
wouldn't but if they do and there's a
big field of this
if that pollen were to get into some
regular stock it would essentially wipe
out the gene for say mercene in this
situation and over time you know worst
case scenario has man gone too far we
could lose certain things do you think
that's a realistic fear or it's a bit of
paranoia
well i think it is a fear i think i
think there's some realism to it i mean
people in oregon for example worry about
hemp
you know the the the pollen from hemp
uh getting onto the pollen from count
you know to a to a medical cannabis farm
etc etc and it can be a problem so i
think we have to we
we you know we treated this thing so
badly for so long you know that there
aren't enough lines of communication so
we can talk about these things and kind
of kind of make it work out but yeah i
think there's a i think there's a
potential problem we just have to pay
attention to it and we have to have
control of it
not
government that's interested in money we
shouldn't care about the money we should
care about the health and the impact on
ourselves in the environment that's got
to be number one when it comes to
cannabis let's not fall into the trap
where it's just money talks because
that's what happens as we know uh
and and
the idea of genetic genetic modification
it may turn out right now i i think the
jury is is out uh in terms of part of
the genetic modification pro issue but i
think the jury is right on on the market
genetic modification is being used so
that they can spray the plant with a
pesticide
then it's absolutely no way
if it's being used to make the plant a
better plant and you can control it
than possibly but even then i'm not sure
i'm just not sure uh
you know for years and years and years
and centuries and centuries and
centuries we've been able to breed this
plant the way we want to with regular
breathing methods
what's wrong with that
exactly until we can figure it out until
we can figure it out let's not screw
things up
that's that's the scary thing yeah so
last little question on the kind of
legal side of things recently we've
heard the sentiment that 215 in
california was maybe not the best idea
what legal changes would you like to see
to kind of create a more conducive
environment for the cannabis market to
thrive for all growers not just the big
ones
it's a that's a really difficult
question well
now i always say this is an alaskan the
first thing is no bill gets passed using
the word marijuana
this this is a word that i cannot stand
and i don't think anybody who ever
touches cannabis should ever use because
in the united states
this is a word that was drenched up by a
guy named harry enslinger harry
enslinger was head of the tobacco and
and uh alcohol administration when
prohibition was ending and he went oh
what am i going to do and what are my
people going to do and he's the guy that
started the worldwide paranoia over the
the use of
cannabis which he called marijuana so
when you use the word marijuana you're
putting a uh
you're putting a statue up to harry
inslinger harry ainslinger caused
australia bolivia colombia
london
you know ottawa
pass these draconian terrible terrible
laws
so the first thing i would do is make
sure that everybody uses the word
cannabis that's what this plant is it's
cannabis i know marijuana is a word in
spanish that was used once
but not very often um
i would i would uh
uh
reduce the taxation element i think this
has just become way out of hand
i would definitely in the united states
we have a serious problem where where
the this disproportionate number of of
minority citizens
have been put away as a result of
cannabis
problems in the past the prohibition and
i i would uh have laws that give an
advantage uh
to to uh minorities that have been
impacted for a certain period of time
um
and and
beyond that i don't have enough
expertise but i know the system's broken
i know that in california there is a
wild
wicked uh you know
illegal market and it's very viable
and it's and it's very healthy
and so i think i think
the fact that that exists tells me that
the law
failed um
we got a terrible problem in
[Music]
alaska that i think most other places
have there's way too many restrictions
on this plant way too many restrictions
it's just a plant
if you grow it next to a school so
what
that's just the way it is uh if you grow
it next to a church sorry uh it's just a
plant i mean there was a period of time
when people in the united states thought
that tomato plant was poisonous
uh and and you know you couldn't eat a
tomato plant
this is just a plant folks and and as
such we need to start treating it like a
plant uh if we need to get a little bit
of taxation okay i can understand that
but so far we've seen that crime rates
have gone down
drawer grates among teenagers has gone
down
there's probably been an increase in
driving uh i would imagine although i
don't know whether whether that's
necessarily bad but if it is
then let's do a little bit of taxation
so we can we can ameliorate that a
little bit um but goodness gracious this
is not the b wall answer to ever this is
this is not going to pay for my health
care uh it just shouldn't it's not so we
need to treat we need to treat the plant
like a plant we need to have laws to
treat the plant like a plant
not like this is some kind of a
syndicate
we need to be very careful that we don't
give licenses just to a few
which which a couple of states in the
united states have done um you know we
just we just got to pay attention so
i don't know
uh it's a wide open thing i'm i'm too
old to but i am so thankful that it is
legal in so many places in the united
states
and and it will be around the world no
question
yeah it seems like the the tides are
turning so
for the next section we're just going to
jump on to some fan submitted questions
so
just some more kind of short ones i
think so first question is
do you know if plants release root
exudates if they're being fed salts or
in a hydro environment
uh
they might but they might not
they put the extra dates out in response
to a need and if they're being fed then
they don't need to waste their synthetic
their photosynthetic energy to produce
the extra dates in a hydro environment
you can get uh you can get extra dates
uh but you don't get nearly as many uh
and they of course they don't have any
purpose
uh so you know that's you don't want
them
yeah
so next one looks like from a reader
who's maybe read your new book they've
said do you have a favorite
autoflowering company and do you have
any tips for training auto flowers
well i like mafesto genetics
yeah they're they're a good you know
international company
they really have some terrific seeds uh
and boy oh boy are they on top of their
genetics as far as training what i think
i'm coming to the conclusion is that
it's it's best not to train
um
i don't i i
i
i wish that the
people like mafesto and they're getting
much better at it would would tell you
this is a plant that should be pinched
or this is a plant that should not be
pinched um but other you know other than
pinching i i think that training is is
really counterproductive
uh and even in pinching i don't think i
don't think really
that much
yeah so let me answer don't train your
plants
after the after the first grow if it
looks like it could it could have been
go ahead and do it
yeah yeah great answer so and i've tried
i've tried it all i mean i've tried
tying them down and pinching and
you know squeeze and all i can you know
it's
yeah i spread the stuff out a little bit
but you know these are such a great easy
plants to grow
and they're so fast they don't need very
much training
yeah definitely
so next question kind of similarly
related
have you ever noticed an increased
prevalence of intersex traits in
autoflowers or have you noticed what
some describe as a common terpene
amongst autoflowers
um
yes and no
if you get different different growers
you get different terpene profiles for
sure
um i i think some of the the smaller
newer growers
are using a smaller gene pool and so
they don't have quite the quite the uh
that's one of the reasons why i like
mafesto i like the big guys
i don't you know i love mephesto don't
get me wrong i think they're terrific
people but there's also a thing called
autoflowering.net
which i think people might want to go on
to uh which has lists a lot of different
growers a lot of different different
things uh and and and you can find them
as well but you tend to get
yeah you tend to get kind of the same
out of the same grower i i think that
may be true um
i haven't i haven't really grown enough
to really know that whether that's uh
but i got to tell you what i got was
good enough i couldn't complain yummy
yummy
yeah fantastic i'm a huge fan of the
festo as well
so next question this one i should have
asked so very near and dear to my heart
is this is how i actually found out
about your book
what do you think about the revs true
living organics
oh i like it
yeah i know uh
i met him i met him when he was a young
kid
that's not true but uh yeah i know
there's a there are a lot of great books
out there uh and and i think it's
important that people get a good library
uh of different kinds of books uh and
and and refer to them as as many times
as they possibly can yeah there's the
the the
the library field is
i mean the cannabis field is getting
incredible again i tend to stay away
from the from the pornographic
good answer so
recently we've seen a lot of discussion
around the topic of defoliation and i
think you've said in the past your
anti-defoliation would you mind giving
us an explanation as to why you are that
well two reasons
one is if you've got a good light
you want to have as many light receivers
as you possibly can period
and every one of those fan leafs that
you're taking off your plant because you
think you're getting better air
circulation is a is a factory of
thousands of gazillions
you know of chloroplasts that are
feeding your plant and so it's just
counterproductive to remove those unless
you absolutely have to move your fan
get a different air system
but do not take off
leafs now if you've got a really good
light set up
you're way ahead by leaving those those
leaves on
if you're like and if you've got a lousy
light set up you're way ahead by leaving
those lease
they're just
factories you want to have as many as
you possibly can
yeah great answer so next one is a
really good question in my opinion have
you ever considered getting your books
turned into audio books and would you
consider doing the voice if so
i'm not sure i could pronounce all the
words for goodness sakes yeah i mean i
would i would certainly consider it but
i'd rather have it in spanish or chinese
uh
yeah
it's it's in electronic versions but
it's not in audio
i don't you know i don't know what that
process is i'd have to ask my
my uh my publisher uh
i don't know whether whether they do
that stuff but yeah i would certainly do
that i don't think you'd want my voice i
think you'd want uh let's get some
some really
you know somebody really good
jimbalushi i don't
great great
um so
have you been keeping up to date with
any of the new lighting technology and
if so have you got any thoughts on the
new plasma lights
yeah i love plasma lights
i advise a company uh called
second song light on demand
it's it's just incredible the plasma
lights are phenomenal the old days you
used to have to have two different kinds
of plasma lights
one for flowering one for vegging not
anymore uh and this particular light
that i'm that i'm interested in it
weighs about
i don't know 10 to 15 pounds
and it doesn't put out any heat it uses
about half the electrical output wattage
um it is
the cat's meow and it grows the finest
cannabis you have ever ever ever ever
seen uh
just spectacular and and
i can't wait i don't i don't have one
yet but i want one so i can grow my
autoflowers uh autoflowers by the way
i'd like to keep mine on a 24 hour 24
hour light cycle uh when you go 24 hour
light cycle with a plasma light
auto autoflowers holy cromolo you get a
yield like you cannot believe and the
tastes though though the
uh i mean my god it's just incredible
it's just unbelievable so uh yeah i i
like plasma lights an awful lot
they last a very long time the thing
that that people don't realize when they
buy an led light
they break
they don't last forever
they end up in the landfill
these these plasma lights are a little
bit more expensive uh and again i would
i would highly uh encourage people to
take a look at the second sun knowing
that i i do advise these guys this is
this is the light
it is the sun
and and uh
you know there's no substitute what we
do as growers very often is we try to
skimp
okay now normally you're growing a plant
outdoors that's where it's supposed to
grow under good sunlight the last thing
in the world you want to skimp is your
light
and people do that and they shouldn't
just a terrible thing growing cannabis
is a three-legged stool
and if you want to grow good cannabis
you have to have good genetics that's a
given you've got to have good soil from
my perspective it's got to be a healthy
healthy living soil and the third thing
is you've got to have good lights if
you've got those three things you can't
fail to grow good good cannabis
great answer
so last question from our little fan
submitted ones is what type of things do
you like to to do to get rid of bugs
like for example if you had russet mites
what might you do to help get rid of
them
yeah i'm a big believer first of all if
you're if you're a commercial grower you
have got to have on call
an ipm specialist simple as simple as
that if you don't have an ipm specialist
you're crazy i can never pronounce the
names of any of these things uh but i'm
a big big believer in ipm uh when you
when you start out however with a good
healthy soil
the opportunity for the soil food web to
start taking out your problems uh
on its own is increased
many many many many times
but russet mites yeah russet mites is
one of those things what did i hear
about rusted mice rusted mites were
sprayed in the united states by
one of the utilities this is the rover
utility companies in order to kill the
vegetation underneath the wires
wait a minute uh you mean those rusted
mites in california all come from and
people have it like crazy uh
if you can use uv lights you know that
kind of stuff i always like to do that
kind of stuff you want to out compete
you want to know what life cycle stages
the the problem is is going to go
through and you want to find something
in the soil food web medicine chest that
out competes that guy for a space for
food
and you know that puts out an antibiotic
that it doesn't like
there's something out there for anything
but the best place to go is is get on
the web right away and contact an ipm
specialist
because they know what they're doing and
chances are that whoever you're
contacting he that he or she has already
been contacted by 13 people
your neighbors and everybody else
because they got the same problems that
you have so
they know how to take care of them
that's that's how you do it
a brilliant answer so on to our last two
or three questions before we wrap it up
so
favorite one we like to ask people what
is your favorite or the best weed you've
ever smoked in your whole life
i love durban poison
durban poison
[Music]
from oregon's finest that's a dispensary
here in town
one of my friends has a farm he grows
the durban poison for it it's a
delicious
uplifting terrific terrific cannabis
plant
just simply
love it
again because i vaporize
flour i'm always looking for good flavor
and by the way hemp is pretty good to
vaporize i gotta say it's uh it's
delicious uh the hemp the hemp that's
grown in oregon is
all gonna is all cbg hemp
uh very interesting medical properties
uh to it so very very interesting stuff
but german poison that's without
question my favorite
very good answer so on the other end of
the spectrum what is the least memorable
or the way that least impressed you
well you know that would have to be the
weed from the very very first time
very very first time i got stoned my
good friend jeremy platt and i we must
have gone through 30 40 pipes full
before we finally got stoned because
back in 1970 let's see what was that oh
my god
ah
there you
uh this was right before thai sticks and
all sorts of great weeds started coming
into the united states from vietnam uh
but boy the early weed was terrible
stuff terrible stuff
awful never want to go back to that
again
sticks and seeds
headaches common sense for those who
have never tried it yeah
uh so if you were sent to a desert
island you could only have two or three
strains with you which ones would you
want to take
well i think i'd probably take uh
i would depending on whether i was
limited to autoflowers or not
anything you want
i would take i would have to take a
couple of regular plants to do some
breeding so i would want to have uh
because i think it's probably a pretty
quick grower
i think blue dream is very good very
good easy grower
i would like to take uh any of my
festo's uh wonderful plants i like hubba
bubba uh
hubba bubba shmello
yeah hubba bubba smelloscope good one
yeah yeah yeah oh i love that one that
was just terrific i would i would take
that god i don't know it's just i would
grab whatever i could get uh people give
me seeds you know i get seeds all the
time i i i just like to grow any of it
all it all turns out to be good and you
know again if you grow your cannabis
organically and you provide those
necessary elements that go into those
terrific
enzymes that are in your plant
those 10 000 individual enzymes of which
there are a thousand of each are going
to do some incredible things uh and and
that's that's just all it really takes
this is such a wonderful hobby
uh it's just so easy to do and it's just
so much fun god i love it
you can hardly shut me up as you can
tell i love it i love it so we're gonna
do a modified final question just for
you so if you could go back anywhere in
like the history of time any place you
want and you can get some humus from
anywhere where and when are you going
humorous from anywhere
um
boy that's a tough one
i would like to go
to siberia
and get some good humans from siberia
untouched by human hands
untouched by
pollution or anything
we got pretty much a lot of that in
anchorage i mean in alaska but i'd like
to go some really remote siberian
location that was just fully humus
and get it from there
brilliant great answer great answer so
do you have any shout outs or comments
you'd like to make
well you know i hope everybody uh
uh
certainly talks up as soon as we hang up
the the skype um
my books are all available on amazon i
certainly buy them my publishers will
really appreciate it i do not make very
much money off them i can tell you that
um
i
am
gardener jeff on twitter not very often
on it instagram gardener jeff uh let's
see what else
jeff
gardner.com if you want to ask any
questions uh if you've got any advising
that needs to be done i got a great team
we can send your way and uh let's see
i'm going to dublin in
march
3rd and 4th
and then i hope i'm going to be in
australia uh sometime in
the first couple of weeks of april maybe
we'll set something up
sounds exciting sounds exciting so thank
you so much again for coming on and for
sharing all your knowledge and just in
general embroider for all the things
you've done for us
well it's a lot of fun let's do it again
for sure
[Music]
[Applause]
as always a big thank you to jeff for
taking the time to stop by the show chat
and share all the great knowledge
[Music]
big shout out to seeds here now
radio ridge
nursery organic gardening solutions
and the patreon gang love you guys long
time if anyone wants more content go
check out the patreon
[Music]
until next time my friends
go see you
[Music]
oh
i'll get the hell out of here
[Music]
is
uh