foreign
[Music]
to another episode of the podcast the
Cannabis podcast for budding enthusiasts
and as always you're joined by your boy
heavy days here from the upside down
library and as usual we want to give a
massive shout out to our incredible
sponsors who helped make the episodes
happen seeds here now you know them you
love them they got all the hottest
breeders all the latest drops if you're
looking to get some quality genetics
look no further with a guarantee on
satisfaction and not just germination
why would you go anywhere else if you
buy seeds from them you do a grow and
you're not happy with the results at the
end hit them up they'll Square you up I
heard you can get some heavy days packs
a few of them even sold out so get in
there quick seeds here now your number
one seed bank
likewise check out our good buddies at
coped biological systems if you're
looking to produce a Next Level Harvest
you simply have to keep your garden Pest
and pathogen free it makes sense to
periodically release beneficial
Predators if you're worried about spider
mites check out the spidex vital if
you've got aphids check out the acupar M
these products are second to none copit
are the world leaders in Pest and
predation technology huge shout out to
our friends at Copper biological systems
we appreciate you so much thanks for
helping to keep both ours and
everybody's Gardens running on all
cylinders pests and pathogen free
likewise a massive shout out to our
buddies at Pulse sensors these guys have
the latest sensor technology to ensure
your Garden's parameters are in check
from VPD to ppfd all the variables you
can't measure with a simple thermometer
or your eyes will help you to fine tune
your next crop to be superior if you're
looking for increased yield resin
cannabinoids terpenes trust me guys
you've got to get yourself a pulse
sensor and they recently released the
pulse Hub you're gonna have to pre-order
that one guys integrating all of the
units together to make sure that whether
you've got a single tent a single room
or a multi-state operation your crop is
going to be the best to date get serious
get a pulse
you've heard me talk about it guys shout
out to the new sponsor Organics alive
truly incredible organic powdered
fertilizer if you're looking for an easy
solution while growing in soil they have
it it is not hard to see why they are at
the top of their game I highly recommend
it for all the organic Growers out there
give it a try you will not be
disappointed your plants will be next
level
and a massive shout out to our newest
sponsors dinova they are an incredible
Vape company based out of USA producing
some of the most coolest engineering and
vape technology you've seen for a while
I cannot speak highly enough about
dynavat's products if you've ever had a
vape and wished it was able to replicate
the hit of a joint or a bong check out
Dinobots they're second to none for good
reason we're really stoked to be working
with Don about huge shout out guys and
last but not least a massive shout out
to the patreon gang we love you so much
truly the lifeblood of the show if
you're looking to get early access to
upcoming episodes if you want to hear
exclusive patreon only content with
guests the like of Mr Bob Bodie Mean
Gene trichome jungle 707 seed bank it
goes on and on we've also started giving
away genetics on the Discord every
fortnight come check out the patreon
guys
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast we really appreciate it much
love to the patreon Gang
so here we are guys back for an epic
part two with the NorCal cannabis
historian and librarian not so dog
I know everyone absolutely loved the
part one
we promised a part two the man delivered
so without further delay
all righty my friends we're back for
another one in this one we are grateful
to be doing a part two with a notorious
man in the scene the originator of the
Mendo perps you might have heard of his
name attached to the headband and one of
the hosts behind the incredible breeders
Syndicate a big welcome for our part two
with not so dog thanks so much for
joining us again
oh thank you
it's a pleasure to have you back and as
usual I'd love to hear what have you
been smoking on today or if you haven't
puffed yet what do you plan to smoke on
today
uh I haven't puffed yet mostly because
it finally stopped raining around here
so I've been doing a bunch of yard work
but
um I have a I have a embarrassment of
riches right now uh mostly from Friends
of stuff
um and uh some of we chatted about last
time but
train wreck Blue Dream
Loompa headband my headband Sour Diesel
uh chemd
um a bunch of uh some death Coast diesel
I have a bunch of stuff
really I I don't actually repeat very
often
uh these last few weeks because I've
gotten enough samples that life is
pretty good right now as far as that
goes
I love that sounds like you're spoiled
for choice and it's probably not
surprising to any of the listeners that
that's the way it is you mentioned a few
really interesting names in there I
would love to hear which of those lot do
you think is the standout to you so far
out of all those
um I would say that uh
I mean this might sound like a little
bit of homerism or whatever but the the
what I call the LA the headband that I
have like it's probably in my top three
or four things all time so
um especially like when I'm at home and
I don't have to go out in public uh I I
really like it a whole bunch
sometimes
um if I'm out in public I get too baked
on it and it makes me feel like I'm a
little bit in the Twilight Zone and like
I shouldn't maybe be at a grocery store
that lit up or whatever but
um
yeah I like uh headbands chems
you know I'm almost out of chemd just
because I keep smoking it so much I've
not been very good at regulating my
amount you know so
uh yeah it uh it's gonna be a sad day
soon when my little my jar is gone
uh we'll all have to pull one out for
the homie at that time I would love to
ask you well before we get to the chem
stuff you mentioned you know the LA and
in the past episode you mentioned that
it's a very Afghani sort of plant
if I had to put it to you and get you to
tell me your the absolute best Afghan in
your opinion be it a line or a
particular cutting what would you go
with or even if you just want to say
like a certain region you know but what
would be your pick best Afghani
uh
it's it really hasn't changed in a long
time it's it's pretty much for me it's
the chem 91.
um and the reason for that is basically
like it's got like my favorite Afghani
High
when I smoke it I feel like you know
that feeling you got like when you're in
high school and you get really baked and
you know like you're you have the
munchies and you're gonna watch a comedy
with your friends and you're like just
warm and happy and content right not all
weed is Happy some of it's anxious some
of it's a little racy some of it can
have these different elements
um but the chem 91 to me is just really
potent and it's also like very warm and
very comforting
uh you know and it's interesting too
because it's it's ugly and it's not very
frosty and it kind of looks like
dinosaur weed in the sense it looks like
some kind of ancient throwback plant
um especially by IG standards today if
nobody knew what it was
I don't think you would pick it out of a
lineup in terms of what you think via
pictures would work the best you know
yeah it's certainly it's undeniable that
uh I the chemd looks a lot better than
the chem 91 and also you know the chem
91 is is really unlikely to win a beauty
contest
no it's it's ugly and I mean you can
make it look pretty but it's dark it's
not really that Frosty
um you know it's smell comes and goes
kind of sometimes you hit it out of the
park and it tastes and smells delicious
and then the next three times you grow
it it you can you know it's in there but
it's not very prevalent
um but you know the most important thing
to me generally speaking with any weed
is effect
and it has effect in Spades it really it
packs a punch and it does it repeatedly
and you don't really get a big tolerance
to it to me like it works pretty
regularly you know certainly certainly
look you've you've sort of stumbled into
this question I I wanted to ask you but
I've got to unpack it a little bit but I
love the way you described that it makes
you feel like you know when you're in
high school getting high for the first
time those sort of nostalgic feelings
what I've noticed is that exotic weed is
a broad term tends to be all the craze
among the younger Generations those
people who are in high school whereas
chem dog is often thought as being more
popular among like the older heads I'm
wondering do you think this will ever
switch and we'll get to the point where
like chemdog has some more meaningful
popularity with the younger generation
and sort of in line with what you're
referencing that you smoked back then
and you were like wow this is the best
thing ever it's interesting that these
days they lean more towards the Exotic
like
some of that is not their fault
um in the sense that you know it a lot
of it comes down to access
right
um you know I'm sure like for instance
you know episode one of of your podcast
your access has probably gone up
exponentially
with interviewing all these people and
making friends and connections and all
that type of stuff and getting to try
different things and so
um you know being that weed is still
illegal uh and then it is you know it is
even in the states where it's quote
unquote legal here it's not really legal
it's pretty much like highly regulated
and highly taxed
so a lot of people that are producing
stuff are producing stuff of what they
think the market currently wants
and so as a result of that like a lot of
young people like maybe 90 of their
options that they know what to get are
exotic
I'll I'll use a different example right
imagine if old people were telling you
that one of the best bands that they'd
ever they'd ever heard was Led Zeppelin
but you couldn't go out and find a
record or or listen to it yourself it
wasn't available anymore like you hear
rumors of people having albums of it but
you actually couldn't experience it
right and so I think a lot of the
popularity
is access and I also think that you
could take almost any strain forget
about chem for a second you could take
dozens of different strains that were
that we consider to be elite
that maybe have sort of fallen off the
popularity where the vast majority of
smokers have never tried it
they've just heard about it right and so
in order for for some of those Classics
to outpace uh the Zaza or the Exotics or
whatever you want to call it today
people would have to be able to like you
know vote with their wallet
and get it you know you'd have to be
able to walk into a store or your dealer
would have to be like do you want some
gelato 45 or do you want some chemd or
do you want some dog [ __ ] or do you want
some jealousy by you know like they'd
have to have the option
right certainly look I I wholeheartedly
agree with you and in part this sounds
like a call to Arms you know everyone
listening to the show you need to grow a
bunch of chem deseminated into the
community
um but no like to play devil's advocate
here the jungle boys have put out a crop
of what they called chemdog 91 and I
don't know if it was popular enough that
it merited it to come back but what I
will say is I also heard a rumor from
someone that they were using the uh the
JB cut
well I mean it's also kind of one of
those things where it would take some
time and like you know I you know a lot
of times people it's weird because in
the past things that were really good
sort of organically got the elite label
which is it slowly spread and the more
and more smokers that desired it that's
where how it gained popularity to some
degree
where now modern marketing exists and so
people get told what's good and that
affects perception in my opinion
two right like if you know maybe a
better way to judge you know if we're
going to use chem 91 as an example take
some kind of exotic
and take chem 91 and put them in a joint
and don't tell people which is which so
they have no indication right because
then you're not bringing your biases
into it and I don't think the jungle
boys grow very good weed to be honest
um you know you know I don't I think
they grow
you know a commercial quantity and I
don't think that
you know we haven't gotten the pressure
yet for Quality to really win out in the
marketplace
it's more like who has licenses and
who's able to do it and then the
economics sort of dictates that they
blow out large amounts of good looking
weed to try to stay ahead of the taxes
and all the fees and all the polls on
the on the money so I don't really think
we've hit like a legal connoisseur grade
yet
in my opinion
um the weed you could get in clubs in
the 215 era was you had a chance of
getting nicer weed on average than you
can get today
and I don't think it permanently has to
stay that way but it's that way
currently
on this topic and you know you mentioned
earlier having the licenses and the
legal capabilities to go ahead a lot of
Growers who were producing the killer
Bud that you used to be able to say get
at a dispensary a lot of them are
feeling pushed out of the market the
overwhelming majority of them haven't
been able to secure like a larger
license and facility that would allow
them to keep going
what would be your general advice for
any of shall we say you know the uh the
old school Growers who are feeling like
they're being pushed out of the market
do you think they need to maybe find
like a unique
um space like a niche or something like
that they can fill or like what would be
some general advice you might offer
uh that's actually it's that's kind of a
big subject man
um so I'll try to break it into chunks
and where I live in Mendocino County it
sort of is the question of the moment
because unlike a lot of other places uh
this place sort of rose out of poverty
post logging with the the rise of
medical cannabis uh and so it's like a
lot more important to my local area than
it might be to a lot of other places
um you know because I mean I think about
it all the time and I talk about it with
friends and like even if we make it
what if the community as a whole falls
apart around us
and then the place that we love and the
place our kids go to school and you know
and all this different stuff becomes
like you know just very difficult
and
I uh
I might sound a little political here or
a little punk rock or any something like
that when I say this but
like I mentioned before I don't think
weed is legal
yet
um I think it's highly taxed and highly
regulated like the idea that name one
other legal plant
that you have a plant limit and grow in
your backyard right like if I'm a tomato
if if I'm into heirloom tomatoes I I can
take my my backyard and I can grow
thousands of heirloom tomatoes I can
breed those tomatoes to try to make a
better one that I'm into I can share
those seeds with my friends
you know the only rules or regulations I
might hit upon are if I try to
commercially sell them then I might need
like a tax ID or some kind of like but
in terms of just like non-commercial
aspects
there is no con there's nobody get
nobody cares right so the way it is now
legally where you're like oh you can
have six plants
you've been doing this podcast long
enough that you can't have a mother room
with six plant limitation
you can't you can't breed and make
selections for what you want with the
six plant limitation
um it's not legal it's world will allow
you to do it if you give us a bunch of
money and jump through a ton of Hoops so
my general gist is like
maybe I'll put it this way right uh for
my whole life they've been telling me
you shouldn't do this you're a bad
person you shouldn't do this you
shouldn't do this you shouldn't do this
you're a bad person stop doing this
don't do this we're gonna put get you in
trouble if we catch you doing it and
we've been fighting this whole time
to make the rest of America be like oh
that opinion is dumb
these people should be able to do
whatever they want because they're not
hiding they're not harming anyone this
is preposterous right and so now they've
switched it and they're like man this
thing you've built is pretty cool we'll
take it from here
right but the direction that they're
going to take it is not the direction
that most people that have been involved
in cannabis a long time want it to go
so to me the fight hasn't stopped
the fight is gone from you can't have it
to we want what you have and then you
can go away
right so for me it's like you're still
fighting now the problem becomes is that
when we were fighting to just have it
before prohibition made having it
lucrative
so it's sort of like funded the
resistance if you were
you know what I'm saying
um the whole concept uh you're familiar
obviously with uh one of the first
forums overgrow yep do you know why they
named it that
overgrow the government
overgrow the government which is
basically laws only work if a majority
of people think the law is a good idea
and respect it
right one of the big reasons why they
ended prohibition when alcohol in
America was because so few people agreed
with it on average that it led to a
general breakdown in trust but for cops
for the government for law making
you know what I mean and eventually if
enough if you live in a democracy you
can't have laws that the majority of the
people think are total [ __ ]
like it's a it's a there's a friction
there right and so now we've gotten to
this idea that it's happened in enough
states where I think it's pretty I don't
think we can ever go back to Prohibition
in turn with cannabis like full
prohibition because too many people use
it and like it and too many people have
seen it Go recreational or medical in
their state and it's not like it's gone
Mad Max and Society has fallen apart
right so now it's more about
for people like us how do you steer it
in the direction that you want
right that's the that's the fight so the
fight hasn't really stopped it's just
changed now the the part of it that
becomes difficult is that before when we
were fighting like I said prohibition
made cannabis very lucrative so if
you're willing to risk your freedom to
grow cannabis you probably could make a
good living and then you could sort of
fight the system as it were
you know
um but as they've you know as they've
legalized things and the prices
collapsed
you know where do you where do you get
the funding to keep pushing for things
as it is
I mean I don't I don't know if this is
necessarily the show to talk about this
or whatever but what the government
thinks is happening with weed versus
what's actually happening with weed in
terms of recreational and legal is so
different it's almost it's almost silly
you know like they have no idea what's
going on they don't and you know so the
question becomes for people like us
right uh is you know we're probably both
in the same boat of we would we would
prefer as many old and important things
to be preserved as possible
for it's fine to have a bunch of what we
would call mids or kind of boofy stuff
or whatever because some people just
want to buy a big case of cheap beer and
they're happy with that like there needs
to be
cheap weed hopefully that's still pretty
good quality but cheap weed
for people that that's their economics
but what I'm hoping is that eventually
we'll be able to get a higher grade of
weed will lead to a higher price
just like with watches or cars or
Italian leather shoes or organic food or
whatever else there's like grades right
and I can go to the store and I can buy
a three dollar bottle of wine
or I can buy a 300 bottle of wine
right and legalization really hasn't
allowed that quality to happen yet it's
basically like who can do it and the
economics of it are really messed up so
then who can survive while doing it you
know
and I don't know how politically you
want me to get on that one but it's
basically it's a really tough time right
now I've never actually been more scared
of diversity surviving than I have right
now
um and I do feel for everyone
um because most people
you know most people aren't uh I don't
know how to put it the right way this I
don't want this to sound the wrong the
the like elitist or anything like that
but most people aren't like us
and what I mean by that is that
most people are gonna even Growers and
stuff like that most people weed is
gonna fit within a certain framework in
their life you know what I'm saying yeah
like there's only going to be a small
group of people that weed is like their
hobby it's their passion it's what they
spend a ton of time thinking about and
pushing forward like to use a different
analog analogy or something like there
might be some people that fish right and
then there might be guys that like own
all this specialized fly fishing gear
and they plan their vacations around
where they can fish and they just like
kind of you know it's important enough
to them
that it means a lot more
than your average fisherman right you
know who might occasionally go out there
and do something or it might be the same
with classic cars or stereos or anything
else you might want to name there's
people that are not interested mildly
interested
kind of deep into it where you start
learning about some things and then
there's a small core of like die hards
who really live and breathe it
right in almost any hobby
yeah yeah yeah like you're just sort of
talking about like let's talk about
anything Leo like plus two standard
deviations above the meme you know like
you're in like the top 0.3 percent gets
the most extreme end of the spectrum you
can get yeah and that and that's not
making me like that just might be like I
mean I joke about it like that like a
lot of a lot of weed people might have a
touch of the Chisholm you know or
something like that like we like you
know like we we're like rain man out
there like we're in this one little area
like we know a lot
right uh and then people that aren't
like us they're like why do you care so
much
about this thing
right and so I get that even up here
even in Mendo people have a
misconception about Mendo and Trinity
and humble I would say most of the
Growers up here
like it did fit like they did it because
it was the biggest economic driver of
their area and it supported their other
interests in their life but a lot of
people
figured out a way to grow a certain
Style with a certain couple strains make
money off it and they didn't care to
learn more than that like that was fine
for them it fit their movie
and so those people
are going to have a much harder time
because they s they existed basically
because there was Prohibition and there
was inefficiencies and and all that
there's people that have been growing up
here for 20 years that haven't really
been refining their craft
the whole time it'd be like it'd be like
if you were a I don't know if you were a
you know a doctor or something like that
and you never bothered to learn anything
post-med school yeah okay fast forward
20 years and you might know a chunk but
some of it might be kind of outdated and
there might be new techniques and new
things going on that really matter that
just slipped by you and most people up
here and in weed in general it's like
they liked you know it was like one of
the things with it was one of the things
that got it made a decent amount of
money you weren't around a bunch of real
criminals it like gave you sort of like
a freedom to be independent
uh and there's nothing wrong with weed
works for you in that range
most of the people that you talk to not
all of them some of them fall into that
category in my opinion I won't say who
because it doesn't matter but
a lot of them that you talk to are are
weed nerds
right like live and breathe it yeah like
if I if I want a hundred mil there's a
bunch of weed growers that if they want
a hundred million dollar lottery they
would probably never grow wheat again
and I would hire my friends and start
some kind of like Nursery art research
and development thing and start messing
around right
um and so you know it it that's the
reason why a lot of strains get lost
right because it's only a few weird
nerds holding on to why are you holding
on to something that's old and unpopular
right
that's sort of really good advice for
like you know the advocacy needed and
the direction to help steer things
moving forward I guess if we had a more
sort of um how shall we say like Savory
look at the future accounting for the
way things have gone thus far
when we're talking about diversity do
you think it is that unreasonable that
in like 20 years time the big
corporations may have Consolidated where
smoking glass house mountains if you
want the mids we're smoking alien Labs
if you want the ZaZa and like there's
just not really any home Growers left do
you think that's possible at all or do
you think that's like a bit too
far-fetched that's possible but that
would be that would that would be uh
Regulators stomping us out in the sense
so look at it from a look at it from a a
related but a different perspective okay
um in America
when when I was a kid uh up until not
even really all that long ago but for a
long time you could go into grocery
stores and
you like you know we were talking about
it offline before we started but you got
the vegetables and the fruits that made
the most sense for the producers to
produce to put into that grocery store
right
and they had production models they had
cucumbers and tomatoes and all these
different things that fit that
production model but because it was
totally legal there was this whole small
little group of weirdos that was trading
heirloom varieties of every different
kind imaginable and they did that for
decades when the only place you could
get that kind of stuff was at farmers
markets right and then eventually people
were like man these tomatoes taste
pretty watery and Bland
and there's these other tomatoes and
they taste delicious
and they started going to like these
co-ops and these hippie you know places
that had some better grades of food and
stuff and they started tasting these
different veggies and they were like man
these are incredible
and then some of these big grocery
stores start carrying these lines
because enough customers demand I want
heirloom tomatoes in this store why
can't I get summertime seasonal
delicious
that's not just this one type and so I
think if they open it up and they
actually make it fully legal
whether or not
um whether or not it becomes like
commercially viable there will be a a
small group to a medium-sized group that
will be breeding and trading and saving
things and pushing it forward and doing
the stuff that interests them and they
won't give a [ __ ] about
what's going on in the bigger world
the way that that doesn't work is if
they make it illegal
for anyone but the large producers right
so it's like big corporations
controlling all of it is fine as long as
you allow the little guy to do what he
wants now would I prefer big
corporations to control everything no
but I also live in America and I watch
how most Industries are controlled by
relatively few groups
think about uh think about another thing
which is not an exact analogy because
it's not plants but it is kind of
similar after prohibition ended uh for
alcohol
um for about 70 years Americans had
their choice of what kind of crappy
pilsner do you want to drink
sure we've got bud Bud Light cores old
style Pabst you know like the heady beer
when I was in my early 20s going to a
bar was Heineken
literally
and then now what's happened is probably
30 percent of the market is what it's
it's craft breweries
bringing all this different diversity
that was always there it's just big
corporations offered you here's
um here's a bunch of schwill do you know
that Budweiser like for actual Budweiser
beer it makes about half the barrels of
Budweiser that it used to from the 90s
on
and it's replaced that by buying micro
breweries because they're this whole
segment of the population that likes to
drink beer but it doesn't want to drink
that great of beer anymore
it wants to drink a different grade it
wants to drink you know Stouts or ipas
or ambers or box or you know some kind
of thing like that and it's they become
economically important enough that you
have to cater to them to some degree
so what can happen to weed is still wide
open
but
um the way I look at it is kind of punk
rock in the sense of like we we haven't
been given what we want yet
so the fight isn't over this is sort of
like legalization and wreckweed is sort
of like they're losing and this is like
their fallback position
of like okay okay okay we'll give it to
you but it has all these rules and you
have to do it like this and we need to
keep saying no no we want it like this
like we want it like this right because
even like even Stores
um eventually what probably is going to
have to happen in order for Quality to
really rain is you would have to allow
um you know direct to Consumer sales
because what happens is right is that in
the current model
if you walk into a dispensary to buy
weed
you can only buy the weed the dispensary
has pre-chosen to buy to sell to you
they could be like I don't want to buy
this Neville's Haze
doesn't look nice and you want more for
it
what does that mean that means the
consumer doesn't get a chance to buy it
so by only having these certain
regulated stores that can sell it you
give those stores a lot of power over
what the consumer gets to gets to see
and then the Growers are going to want
to grow
what the what the middle man and what
the dispensary is willing to buy but
that that shouldn't be who's determining
what weed is out there consumer should
yeah yeah certainly it seems like I mean
to me it feels like there's a lot of
parallels with yeah the beer and the
wine Industries you see where it's like
you know a lot of people are getting
into like these natural styles of wine
and these craft beers and it's really
about accessibility I certainly have
wondered with cannabis specifically I've
always felt like the wine especially in
Europe they were really there was
something about the the appalachas which
allowed there to be like to put it
simply in wine you know someone goes for
like thousands and thousands of dollars
a bottle and there's a decent and the
people who own those Vineyards make good
good money off it oh yeah and so I sort
of thought how can we do the same thing
with cannabis where you can still grow
it yourself and maybe if you're in a
good area you can fetch a pretty penny
for it because I think if I try to and
correct me if I'm wrong from extracting
all of what you've said it's basically
that the the more variety the better for
everyone in every regard but also never
see the right to personally grow because
we need to have the small home Growers
yeah I mean
I mean I'll use I'll use the analogy
again imagine if uh if your record store
refused to carry Led Zeppelin and you
didn't have the choice you couldn't buy
it so you couldn't hear it
right you know
um but I do think that you're right and
that I don't know if I use this analogy
in the in our previous chat so if I did
I apologize but I think it does matter
and that if you go back to like say like
the 70s and in the United States
most people had almost no knowledge of
wine
the the regions that are famous for wine
now like in California and stuff like
that we're just kind of really getting
going back then you would say that like
most Americans their knowledge of wine
was like white wine is for the wife and
it goes with fish
red wine is for is is like meats and
roasts and steaks and they kind of knew
red and white and after 40 Years of you
know education and the populace now
there's people that are like they know
what Napa is they know what regions are
they know like oh I like Zinfandel I
like Merlot I like this appellation for
my Pinot Gris I like you know because
there's all this information and then
you get enough nerds that are pushing it
forward and you go into like a a heady
wine shop and the guy working there has
his favorites and he knows tons of
information about it and he's like
preaching to like the customers about
what his favorites are and why
weed needs to have that kind of thing
because what's happened with weed is
that in the beginning you only had
access to like what the dealers you knew
had
and then it was like what they had
access to and like what they wanted to
buy and now that we've got stores it's
opened up a bit but it's like the choice
there's the taxes are so high and the
pressures are so big they really haven't
opened it up yet to choice they really
haven't graded out
like what the differences are in weed
and a lot of times with these mylar bags
and everything like that like people
don't even see the weed until they've
purchased it
right so there's a lot of improvements
that need to be made I would say that
like all these laws that have happened
right now
a lot of them need to go but they're
like the first baby steps
right and the other the other
interesting component which I don't know
that
um
Australia is a pretty big country so
maybe you get this there but in America
we're so big that we grow crops where
the climate suits the crop
right like we you know we used to grow
oranges in Southern California or
oranges in Florida
we grow you know maple trees grow in in
New England right we grow almonds in
California we grow potatoes in Idaho
right we figure out where the climate
suits the crop and that's where the
majority of the crop gets grown
because it's cheaper to do it that way
because the climate suits the crop what
we have right now is we have this weird
thing where every state that goes legal
or recreational or medical is its own
Island
because the federal government doesn't
allow interstate commerce right so
California can't send its weed anywhere
else Montana can't send its weed
anywhere else you know Massachusetts
Colorado Washington so it's almost like
you've got this captive group of people
that just have to take what's on offer
in your little state
and there's nowhere for the
overproduction to go
and so as a result of that the best
states there's going to come a time when
it becomes federally legal where most of
the places that are setting up to grow
cannabis won't grow commercial cannabis
because the the climate isn't as
suitable as other areas of the country
you know and they'll probably end up
growing indoor where the power is
cheapest
once you can ship it anywhere in the 50
in the in in the 50 states or you could
ship it International or whatever
they're going to set it up where it
makes the most sense and you mentioned
glass house or whatever that's like
their whole business that's their old
business plan if if it stays the way it
is for the next 10 years they'll
probably fail as they burn through
investor money
their whole point is to have a hundred
acres and eventually they're going to
start to ship to other parts of the
country that can't grow as good a weed
as California can that's their hope
there's big corporations that are
setting up that are hoping that we go
federally legal because otherwise
they'll fail in their little state that
they're in so like I guess what I think
about though is like people like Bud
Light and Heineken maybe some of these
more sort of you know everyday man beers
they're very much accepted in the
community from us heady guys there is
still a lot of sort of um you know
grievances with some of these mid Z
brands do you think in time that'll
equalize out and it'll just become
accepted that this is in fact like you
know beer and wine and these guys are
trying to be literally the Bud Light of
cannabis and
um and there's nothing wrong with that
no there's nothing wrong with that the
problem is is that because of the way
modern marketing works every single
license Holder will tell you they are
trying to grow the best cannabis on
Earth
and they have the terpiest flaviest
highest THC best weed you can buy and
that's why you should buy it from us
right who try to find a brand that wants
to tell you oh we definitely want to be
the Bud Light of weed that's a good
point try to get him to say it right
they won't say it they might grow Bud
Light but they're going to try to tell
you that it's the most exclusive rarest
fire on the planet
this might be wrong but I think that guy
who wrote three a light has come out on
the record being like yeah this is not
going to produce the best quality like
this is volume yeah I mean and the the
problem too this this this might get
into the weeds right
um so I apologize for that but
one of the issues with legal cannabis in
America is that
because it's illegal at the federal
level Banks won't touch you I'm sure
you've heard that like even getting even
getting and maintaining bank accounts
for like quote-unquote legal businesses
can be very difficult because these
banks are like multinational
corporations and they don't want to get
in trouble with the federal government
so they don't care that it's legal in
California they care that the feds say
it's not right
so what happens is is that means that
unlike almost any other business you
can't go with a business plan to a bank
and get a regular loan
but they're very very concerned with
black market money making its way into
the legal system so they want you
guaranteed to have banked money to start
your legal business
okay well where do you get legal banked
money if the bank won't give it to you
you then have to get it from private
individuals that have that money in the
bank which means that the way that we
Legalize It in this country all of a
sudden made
private investors some of the biggest
movers and shakers in cannabis
because they fund all of it and you
can't you can't like have I mean imagine
there's there's scenes in like you know
in Southern California where like the
licenses just for the amount of of
licenses they have is like eight hundred
thousand dollars a year to maintain
that has to be a check cut to the
government
you know and so all these all this
infrastructure all these build outs all
this different stuff that's happening
right now that you see whenever you see
it it's almost always private money
that's been raised and then you have a
business and the taxes are through the
roof the regulations are crazy and it
makes you do all kinds of inefficient
stuff to like deal with the regulations
right banking is a huge issue and you've
got these private investors that have
been told that weed is basically like
cocaine in your Pablo Escobar and it
should be rolling in cash and we want a
big return on our investment
and that's where you see a bunch of
people starting to grow boof
beca or mids because maybe they don't
want to but it's the only way they can
keep their head above water with the
taxes the regulations and then the
investor group breathing down their neck
for return and profit
and so there's a lot of things that are
that you know that are stacked against
mod like you know recreational Cannabis
actually getting fire on on the Shelf
um that three pounds of light you were
joking about you know when Colorado went
went recreational it was one it was one
of the first places in the country to go
full recreational I believe you know uh
Washington State and Colorado not just
Medical but actual like full wreck right
all these indoors there the most
important thing was getting three or
four pounds of light
because your accountant or your CFO or
whatever is like dude you want to get
paid you want to pay your staff
well we got to give this enormous chunk
to these investors that help you build
out this huge facility that cost a few
million bucks they're breathing down our
necks what they want is they want you to
make the most money you possibly can
now that's not the same thing as the
best weed you can possibly grow
doesn't mean there's not a balance there
but right now it's been weighted towards
survival
and I don't know if you've seen it but
like in California obviously where I
live there's enormous amounts of
licenses right now that aren't getting
renewed
because the people have decided it's not
economically viable
yeah certainly
because the taxes are too high and the
way they set the rules up are too
restrictive
uh you know proposition 64 most people
don't know this it was written by a
bunch of tech Bros
uh you know who Sean Parker is
yeah yeah
the guy who invented Napster
um he's one of the guys that that he's
one of the guys that funded the prop 64
movement
um and it they didn't they didn't you
know I don't know I don't know what the
best way to put this is but
it's not like a bunch of lifelong
cannabis enthusiasts were brought
together and said hey
why don't you write out
a proposition that would be good for the
consumer good for you good for the state
it was a bunch of dudes that might have
been very smart in other fields
thinking that they could be incredibly
smart
in this field and as a result
you know they made it you know imagine a
bunch of Rich Tech Bros or whatever made
it so that like you needed private
Capital to exist
you needed them
it's almost like they wrote themselves
into the movie right and I'll tell you
that I you know I don't talk about it
all that much but you know I've done
Consulting and I I definitely have
rubbed shoulders with the legal scenes
in California and I've tried to help on
projects and stuff it is a very weird
cultural difference to get a lifelong
weed person in a room with a rich kid
whose parents are worth tens of millions
of dollars
talk about a culture Clash
talk about people that don't understand
the other person and so uh you know look
at look at um you know uh
Dennis perone or whatever the First
Medical in in America happened in
California
right and he wrote this law you know he
was this gay activist trying to get
medicine to a bunch of his friends who
were suffering from HIV and various
other things and they pushed through
this law that was very vague
okay
and very much towards the consumer and
very much towards the grower and it
sparked a 25 a 20-year 25 you know at
least 20 year 20-year boom like nothing
anyone had ever seen
and then these people come inside and
they decide to write this wreck thing
that was basically benefiting the
government the rich people
um not benefiting the consumer not
benefiting the grower and we're four or
five years into it and it's collapsing
under its own weight
because no one bothered to talk to the
people that were intimately involved in
cannabis for a long time about how the
structure of it should work
right so now it probably will take a
whole bunch of investor money getting
lit on fire
and a whole bunch of failure for them to
start adjusting the rules
and you know I don't I don't exactly
know the future is very uncertain
because
um a lot of these places are only
surviving off investor money
and when investors decide to stop
investing you get failures so I think
it's very up in the air and probably
most of the people you talk to
I would imagine because you talk to
people like me aren't very happy with it
right and so it's like it's cool in the
sense that yes America should get used
to the fact that recreational Cannabis
should be totally normal
but we really would like to scrap most
of the rules around it and come up with
a different more successful model some
brilliant thoughts there for sure I
guess we will have to wait and watch and
see who does for you're certainly not
wrong about people operating on investor
money
with little change of pace though I was
hoping to ask you last episode so I'm
going to get in now before I forget this
time
I uh like to consider the the followers
of the show along with myself maybe a
bit of bias there just from me a pretty
passionate bunch of organic fans and I
know you've been around the block long
enough to have tried the whole gamut of
different grow Styles I'd love to hear
how are you growing at the moment in
terms of your style and inputs and
what's your thoughts on the whole
organic versus synthetic debate
uh
uh it's a big enough topic that I
actually if I talked to Matt about doing
like a couple of like solo episodes on
it because I think it's like one of the
most poorly understood
um parts of cannabis and it also is a
little bit like religion in the sense
that people get like their belief
systems in place on something and then
they get very very hard to knock off
what they think of
and so I I think I would say simply
uh there is no one-size-fits-all
solution
right
um and you know and what I mean by that
is that
uh
you know organic versus salts
I think is is poorly understood and I
don't think one is Superior in all
instances to the other
like I'll just say that simply
right
um you know even just even just the idea
of organic indoor
right think about that
okay like you know you have let's say
you have a backyard garden
and you're growing veggies or weeding it
or whatnot and you you know you're
tilling it up and you're amending it and
you're working with like a certain
amount of native Earth
right and you're adding some stuff to
that maybe or maybe you're bringing in
some soil and you're dumping that on top
of the Native Earth and you're churning
it up and you know you're growing
organically outside according to methods
that have been around for a long time
and then you're trying to grow
organically indoor in a two gallon pot
I'm gonna tell you that like there is no
like soil food web that's complete
that's going on in a two gallon pot
right it's just too small you know so a
lot of times you know and I I mean it
I don't want to get too in depth here
maybe because I could go off into the
Weeds on it but I think that organic
weed is the best possible weed
I also think that it's harder to grow
organic weed and there's lots of organic
weed that is not as nice as salt grown
weed
does that make sense
yeah yeah certainly I can certainly
relate to having now been to a few
bigger facilities both organic and
synthetic that um a big thing I you know
I'm I'm DieHard organic right but I
totally acknowledge that on scale you
start to see some problems that are sort
of inherently addressed in salts so yeah
it's it's certainly no one size fits all
well look at it this way this is
something that people don't consider but
I've done a decent amount of Consulting
in the in the legal scene and one of the
things that is a huge problem with
Organics that people don't want to deal
with right is that
um you know cannabis comes with there
well there's two parts to it one is that
cannabis uh comes with testing where if
you have too many heavy metals it fails
testing
right and then cannabis is also a bio
accumulator of heavy metals which is a
fancy way of saying it absorbs more
heavy metals into its you know vascular
system than most other plants do
okay
so uh what are you know you have this
situation where
you know uh heavy metals
I've done so much testing on inputs
it is really really hard to find any
kind of input that's derived from the
ocean
that won't fail heavy metals testing
and heavy metals are heavy right so they
have a tendency to accumulate and
persist
so you make a bunch of compost
and you compost down your organic matter
into this like delicious food source
the heavy metals don't go away they
concentrated too
right so and most compost is made from
commercial agriculture waste
so it could also get sprayed with all
kinds of chemicals like the whole
organic name is really funky so
for instance I don't know if you're
aware of this but do you know that bone
meal and blood meal are organic
right
yeah
they don't have to come from organic
cows at all yeah yeah but I'm on growth
hormone so you could get bone meal from
the store
that came out of a McDonald's
you know a massive
you know uh massive factory with 25 000
cows
getting fed antibiotics all kinds of
chems all kinds of different stuff this
and that whatever else
once they take those bones and grind
them up it's organic right you know
um you know blood meal is the is this is
the juice that comes off the cows that
goes into the sluices when they do the
slaughterhouse
that doesn't have to that doesn't have
to be from an organic cow you know so in
in like
in my world like sometimes salts might
actually be cleaner
depending on what organic inputs you
might use
right
um and then the other part of it that is
really is really simple is that I look
at it as like the plant the plant
absorbs nutrient salt
okay
um So when you buy salt you know you
know uh salt nutrition that nutrient
salt is in a form that's ready to ready
to be absorbed
when you're growing organically those
salts are trapped in longer organic
chains
and bacteria and and fungi and different
things need to break that stuff down
to release the salt to make it available
for the plant
so when you're growing the plant is
either getting all of the nutrition that
it needs when it needs it or it isn't
it can be somewhat simpler to feed it
salts because you can quantify how much
food you're giving them
where Organics you're hoping that
there's enough stuff in there
right
does that make sense
yeah yeah but you still have skirted the
question how do you grow at the moment
um I do it all
so to be perfectly honest I feel like
the best in go indoor is something that
I call synganic yep which is basically
you know a mix of Organics and stuff
that wouldn't necessarily qualify as
organic
right
um but I still think of as really high
quality
yeah give us give us some ideas what are
you doing I'm always Keen to learn
um so you know I uh
you know gosh this is gonna sound
this is going to sound like I'm avoiding
the question again but
your how how I feed would be very
different if you tell me I'm gonna be
growing in a one gallon to five gallon
pot versus I want to set up a two foot
deep by 50 foot long bed
you know of of organic soil in my room
versus I'm gonna grow in a 50 gallon
container you know what I mean like
there's there's differences in
um an approach
right that that don't just meet that
label
but the other thing that's weird okay
and let me just throw this in there
before I forget it
because we smoke cannabis that means
it's a little different than other
things
right so you know I'm sure you've heard
talk about how like you know you want
your veg your fruits and vegetables to
be as mineral rich as humanly possible
right because you want to be able to eat
those vegetables or fruits or whatever
and you want your body to get that
healthy form of all the nutrition that's
in it and there's been a big worry that
like you know
um the levels of nutrition in our food
are dropping
which means you're not getting as much
nutrient dense food as you used to
well that's eating things right
when you're growing
um
you know uh generally speaking most
smokers don't want a plant that's chock
full of nutrition
when they're smoking it
right that's where the whole flush thing
comes into play right it's like you want
to feed your plant
to where it develops the right way
and then it's like you almost want to
like drain your plant of that nutrition
before you harvest it so it's not chock
full of that
and here's another weird thing
is that what you're tricking the plant
into doing something that it has no
interest in doing
the plant does not want to be Smoked by
you
the plant wants to soak up as much
nutrition within itself as it possibly
can
hold on to that nutrition until it gets
fertilized by pollen
and then use that nutrition to make
viable seed so that its species
continues the plant does not consent to
being harvested
right it does it's not it's it's like
it's you know what we're doing with it
is not how it developed over its entire
lifespan
at all even like what you said there was
really interesting like that Paradigm of
getting it to the end of flower and then
getting it to try to drop all of its
stored up nutrients like it's it's so
the antithesis of what it's trying to do
so if I have a I have I have a um we're
not friend we're not friends anymore not
because we're not friends but just
because life pushed Us in different
directions but some of the nicest weed I
ever grew
or not or sampled was my buddy had this
style of growing in a one in one gallon
pots organically
and he put enough food in there for the
first five or six weeks of growing
and then the last you know he mostly
grew things that were eight to eight to
ten weeks that last two or three or four
weeks it would just start to slowly it
used up all the food in the soil then it
started like using up all the food
within itself and I'm sure you've seen
like you know or a lot of times when
you're growing salts and you flush a
plant it just goes yellow but a lot of
times when you're growing organically
and you and the plant starts to run out
of nutrition it's almost like fall
colors it starts to get all these
beautiful burgundies and Amber all these
different color schematics start coming
out and he would starve that plant
right and he had beautiful white ash
perfect smoke every time
and he would always say if I grow in too
big a pots or I grow in beds how do I
how do I flush it
when there's so much nutrition
in there
right and so you know CSI and I talk
about this all the time like if you're
growing for seed production
you're going to feed the plant vastly
different than if you're growing for
smoke
right because if you're going for seed
production you're essentially
wanting to have Healthy Mothers
that have a lot of nutrition so they can
make a bunch of babies
yeah right you want robust nitrogen you
want excess nitrogen you want excess of
all these different things so that they
can suck up as much food as they want
but often that smoke like like on a
reversal failure you know him and I joke
that like that smoke isn't nearly as
nice as if you were growing it for smoke
because you would feed it differently
yeah then if you're trying to get a
bunch of tiger-striped robust seeds
so maybe I'm copping out on it but it's
like it's such a big subject it's like
really hard to do a one-size-fits all
um and you you think about those people
right like you know there's people that
brag oh I've got living soil and this is
my 26th cycle
how do you flush
your your
um
your your weed is going to have more
nutrition in it
because there's no there's no excellent
like the plant doesn't naturally be like
oh the human that's growing me is going
to want to smoke this thing in in five
weeks I should stop uptaking food and
start to starve myself so I produced a
type of Bud that he prefers
and most people don't think of that
right
yeah I mean I think I've found with a
lot of my plants they tend to like fade
and do that senescence thing regardless
of the food levels I've found well I
mean
kind of but I bet that you don't send
off your leaves for analysis
yeah that's true
you know you don't know how much is in
there you're just guessing I mean the
other part that's interesting is that
you know because we you know if you want
to talk about like white ash crew or
something like that well it is like such
an interesting debate in the community
isn't it and also like the fact that
um some stuff I've smoked that has black
Ash has Still Smoked really nice you
know it's like great High Yeah it it is
something that uh
it often has a lot more to do with how
it's dried and cured
than how it's fed
but people wanna people wanna say it
proves how you fed it
um when feeding it that way can
influence it one way or the other but
it's probably not the biggest thing you
could feed it organically and starve the
crap out of it and then dry it too quick
and not cure it right and it won't burn
the right way
you know like it's it's there's multiple
steps in the way and the other thing I
should probably mention is that a lot of
my friends we find that uh
um stuff that's grown without CO2 to be
superior smoke
you know because you you think about uh
you know what is a plant doing
when it's uh
when it's absorbing excess CO2
it's sequestering carbon
you know what does carbon look like when
it's burned black generally
so you run a high CO2 room and you get
bigger yields and you're happy about
your weight it looks all nice
it's got more carbon in it
then
um then a plant grown without CO2 or
with a naturally occurring like
atmosphere CO2
because the atmosphere is 400 PPM
but if you pump it to 1500 PPM
it's going to absorb a bunch of that
carbon into itself
and then how do you deal with that at
the end
you've got you've got a lot you know it
got bigger flowers you've got bigger
weight you're happy
but there's more carbon in there
because you fed it carbon and it sucked
it up
I don't think people think about that
either
right
um where in in some cases I almost think
this this isn't the only reason so don't
hold me to this but like in some reason
when people say that they prefer outdoor
I think one of the reasons why some
people prefer outdoor is that it's not
you can't pump the room full of four
times the ambient CO2 level
and they end up preferring the smoke
it's not the only Factor the sun
obviously exists and all that so I don't
want to say it's just one thing but it's
definitely a thing that matters
and so I guess I'll close by saying that
like organic versus
salt or indoor versus outdoor or
whatever there's a big push in the
community to think the way that I do
things is better
and it doesn't have trade-offs
where most things in the world have
trade-offs
you gain some things but you have to
deal with these other things
and so the goal to me
when you're growing weed obviously is to
grow the healthiest plant you can
starve it a little bit at the end
dry it and cure it the right way so that
it comes out the type of smoke that you
want
and there's a number of different ways
to achieve that
and everyone wants to think oh I grow
organic so I'm better than every salt
grower
I've grown a lot of organic and it's not
always as nice
you know and then I've grown organic
that I don't think salt could ever be as
good as
yeah certainly look a very balanced
comment there I um I can certainly agree
no one size fits all and it's it's
interesting to hear you got experience
on both sides of the the table I'm I'm
actually considering doing some more
salt experiments myself in the future
did did I talk about on the previous one
did we talk about the experiments I did
with salt and organic side by side I
can't remember why not let's touch on it
well let's let's chat about it because
you you brought it up there was a there
was a time
um where for about five years or so I
had a section in an indoor okay
um that I would grow the exact same
strain
uh under the same type of lighting same
condition same everything and one would
be the best salt and additives regimen I
could come up with
and the other would be the absolute
headiest organic I could think of
and I'm talking like I would I I owned a
cement mixer I mixed all my own soil and
inputs you know what I'm saying like I I
went to all my friends and we like we
would try to come up with the nicest and
and what I would do is I would grow
strains I was very familiar with three
four different strains and you know they
would be grown in the same room at the
same time some of them were organic some
of them were salt
and
then I would take it and I would roll
joints
and I would sit down with my friends and
we'd have a sesh
and people would just smoke joints and I
would ask their opinion
and often sometimes people preferred the
salt version
which would frustrate the piss out of me
because I put so much time and energy
and effort into the organic one
and there was some strains that came out
better organic every time
there was some strains that came out
better
um you know salt almost every time
and there was some you know that it you
know you change certain things and it
kind of depended and so I did these
experiments where because it's like most
people grow one style at a time
and then you don't actually get side by
sides you like are basing enough memory
or other things
and so I grew the same five or six
strains you know for a number of years
because it was like some of my favorite
smoke
and I would constantly at parties and
stuff I'd have them labeled a b you know
whatever
and people wouldn't know
and I would have friends
that swore that they could taste
when they smoked salt weed
that couldn't pick out which one was the
chem
when I gave it to them
they couldn't in a blind taste test you
know they could not
right
um and there was so there was certain
things that I found were much harder to
feed organically than Salt
and as a result of that if you don't
feed the plant everything that it wants
when it wants it it's not going to be as
good
I was gonna say do you think that plays
into the idea of like how some people
say well if the original clone was like
Fino hunted in soil like it's always
gonna like that that was the ground in
which it proved best if they did the
final hunting rock well it might not
have been as good do you think there's
much Merit to that or it's like a good
plan it's a good plant
I think there's some Merit to it and I
also think that if you're Fino hunting
and you're giving everything one shot
right the bigger Fino hunt the harder it
is to taste test and actually make a
good determination
and then what happens if you are
feeding if you know what happens if one
strain wants more food than another
but you're feeding it all the same and
then so one of them is hungry and
doesn't come out as nice and one of them
is getting plenty of food and comes out
nicer because it was fed better
um it's one of the things that makes
Fino hunting hard is you know you know
the smaller Fino hunt the better the
judgment
the bigger Fino hunt the harder it is to
give each plant individually what it
might need
because if you're honestly like I'll put
this in a in a different context
um I have charts you know of like the
strains that I have and one of the
filters that I apply to them is whether
they're a light a medium or a heavy
feeder
because I've done things like I've done
light depths and stuff in the 215 era
where I'm feeding everything the same
and then this plant's hungry so I upped
the food
and now I'm slightly burning these other
plants because they don't need that high
level of food
so then I realized it was actually kind
of important to group strains that fed
the same
it was really important to do that
because if you put something that
doesn't need much food
like say a cookie
next is something that wants to eat a
lot
like a camera a sour
one of them is going to by Nature be
unhappy you know what I'm saying
yeah
so you kind of have to like
um
you know I I mean there was there's
there was times too like some of the
best herb I ever grew
was I gave everything like really light
salts
and then everything was in organic soil
and then the stuff that needed more food
I top dressed
well I had that good
it went really like I said it's some of
the you know it allowed me to
individually you know individually deal
with different strains
and so the light feeders just got light
food
the heavy feeders maybe I would top
dress some different organic stuff on
them once every week or 10 days and then
when they got watered that water would
hit that top dress and go down and they
would get more food
that's cool I haven't heard of that I
would have thought you would have done
it the other way but yeah that's really
interesting you know well because it's
like it's way easier to it's way easier
to get every Everything a light dose
and then the up individual beds or pots
or something with the stuff that needs
more
than it is to give everything heavy dose
because there's already some things that
don't want that much food
um yeah
I mean and then the other part comes
it's like
you know if you're growing things and
you're doing it you know on a certain
level it's like what happens when you've
got strains that are eight weeks and
you're growing in them off the same
reservoirs and stuff that on plants that
need 11 weeks
no flush for the plan two one eight
weeks you need you know you need some
flexibility in there to be able to give
the individual strain what it wants
I might want to be backing off food on
this strain because it's done at 6 56
days
but this other thing is going to take 75
and I can't back off at 50 at when I
back off the other one I need to feed it
for a few more weeks
before I start to taper so you know
actually I'll tell you I'll tell you a
story
um
I was Consulting on a a bigger Farm down
in uh in Southern California
and you know I was dealing with these
big AG guys
and they thought what we were doing was
nuts because what they would do on a
farm like say a farm of blueberries or
something is they would grow one variety
unlike 40 acres and they would take Leaf
samples and they would dial in what that
one varietal needed exactly in nutrition
but the idea that like the California
Market required us to grow like 80
different things
they were like how do you dial that in
how do you figure that out how can you
feed the right way how can you give the
plants what they want
you know
um so
it becomes tough like
sometimes I'll tell people if they're
trying to grow
a whole bunch of different style a whole
bunch of different plants maybe the best
way to grow is pots because you can
individualize the watering you know
that's not even talking about how fast
things drink versus not right because
things don't even have the same root
systems
so there can be times when like if I
grow say like sour diesel next to next
to OG Kush I'll have to water the sour
diesel twice as much as I do the Kush
or twice as often
right
so if I have them in the same bed
one of them is either getting under or
over watered yeah
just the way it works
so
figuring out what your plant needs for
water and food and all that different
types of stuff you'll kind of how I'll
have to piece it together
and if you're growing like like behind
you if you're growing in a little tent
or something like that like it can be
pretty easy
if you're growing it over you know some
licenses or some acreage or something
like that it can be a real logistical
challenge to figure out
what to group together and why yeah
certainly sounds like there's a good
couple of episodes in that topic alone
ready for you to crank out yeah I mean I
told it to me I was like man I'm gonna
go I'm going to ramble just because it's
like so big of a subject but
um and in a nutshell it's paying
attention to the plants you grow
and trying to figure out what they need
when and figuring out are they heavy
feeders are they light feeders do they
need something specific you know do they
need you know to do they
you know all that kind of stuff plays
into it and so the more things you grow
the more complex that becomes
and the bigger size you grow the more
complex that becomes
so you got you know you got a tent or
you got a little four lighter or
something like that you can probably
give a lot of individual attention
yeah hugely but you start growing in
bigger levels and you really it makes a
big difference because it's like I've
definitely grown things where certain
strains are hungry and certain strains
are burning from too much food
and now how do I like how do I give this
plant these plants less and these plants
more
because that's what they need
yeah certainly it does there's a lot of
value in what you say grooving them
together and I'm sure from those big AG
guys point of view what we do is all
very quite unscientific right
oh I mean I actually think I used to get
worried about big AG taking us over
right
they have Decades of a learning curve
and like I said in big AG is used to
being able to force feed the consumer
whatever is the most profitable model
for them
and that's not weed
so they're having a rough go of it
because they're used to like they're
used to the only consideration is like
did I get more tons an acre or less
and that's not weed yeah they don't
understand most of the most of the
little things about weed that lead to
good quality smoke they would consider
to be an inefficient mess that we need
to eliminate
and then you grow boof
that's uh the lot at the end of the
tunnel for the corporate takeover at
least I wanted to chat to you about some
chem dog stuff but before we go there I
wanted to do a little something
different I've never sort of asked this
style of question before but I think
you're the perfect person to do it with
so we recently did an episode with skunk
VA and he made an interesting comment
later on in the episode where he
basically said something to the effect
of I don't really engage in the internet
detective work I don't think there's
much value in that now given both you
and I have podcasts that very much
engage in the internet detective work
I'm going to state that up front that we
might have some bias here but I would
love to hear you both Steel Man and
straw man this statement so what could
you say that would sort of say yeah
there's that's true and then on the
other hand what could you say that is
like well I like that doesn't
encapsulate the whole story
boy
um it's a little bit of a loaded
question but
uh I would say that
um the reason
why we have everything that we have as
humans is curiosity
right curiosity is what is what drives
us you know uh inventions pushing things
forward
um you know and so there is a you know I
talked about earlier on the show okay
how
there's a small conjugate of weed nerds
that like you know dives into this stuff
super deep and there's a larger group of
weed growers that just doesn't care
that might be
a division right there
you know in the sense that we're trying
to unearth you know we're interested in
history you and I uh we're interested in
getting a lot of this like oral history
that could be lost you know down on on
recordings perhaps or getting different
viewpoints before they're they're lost
to time because it's the it's the world
that we're in and most of what happened
happened underground and it isn't
written down anywhere and it's all it
could be lost you know and so we have
this interest in delving into this
curiosity
and trying to find
every little bit we can
about the history of something
and for a lot of people the history is
sort of not relevant
you know like maybe you know I'm not
going to speak for him or anything like
that but like maybe he's going to be is
like well it doesn't put any more money
in my pocket
how does it affect like how does how
does like the lineage of chem 91 affect
me today
it probably doesn't in his mind and
maybe he's not curious about that
right uh there's nothing wrong with not
being curious about it
um you know but
um I think the reason why
you know and it's also interesting too
because if you think about weed Fame
think about how many people you've
interviewed
that you probably interviewed because
they got associated with a famous strain
early on
right
and the reason why that matters is
because people are interested in the
history and they're interested in who
knew what early
oh if this guy had it early on he
probably knows more about the real deal
you see what I'm saying so you know
like I said there's
um a lot of people up in Mendo they'll
be like give me something that the buyer
wants and I'm gonna grow it and I'm fine
with that
even on a lot of the hills up here there
might only be one or two weed nerds
you know uh most people just want to
crop it and sell it right and you know
with chemdog specifically
I think that
you know he might be right in the sense
that after 30 some years there probably
isn't a lot of new historical
information that's going to come up
there's also people that have gotten
famous on it
and like they're not interested in
they're they're interested in history in
the sense of like well if it makes me
look good and it makes me money I'm into
it
if it doesn't then I'm not into it
either
right and so people get touchy about
these debates and sometimes
um and you know I deal with this all the
time actually is people that were
involved early
like not only do they not care
but they don't want the debate to even
happen
it's sort of like I was there you
weren't this is what happened
accept it
right
and
you know but then there's questions
because the way that weed happened is
like most of us were like young Partiers
and nobody knew that what they were
doing was going to be famous I mean
think about think about uh chemdog for a
minute
right
how many 17 year olds popped seeds in
America
and never got famous for it
all of them except Kim dog you know I
mean
and you know you can talk about the sour
diesel thing too where it's like there's
a bunch of young kids
growing a little bit of weed in their
closet or with their friend or whatever
else making these decisions and nobody
was considering man you know 25 years
from now all these steps all these
choices I'm making are going to be
important to a large group of people
so if we let's just cut to the core of
it do you think that the story that goes
around online you know that Greg got 13
seeds do you think that's accurate or do
you think that's accurate to the best of
his memory
um well I'll start by saying I wasn't
there for any of it so I'm not about to
say that it didn't happen the way that
they described it
um
and what what seems to be generally
agreed is that he bought some weed at
Deer Creek at a dead show in 91 and then
he hit dude up and he bought a little
bit more weed that got sent to him it's
never been completely clarified
if all the seeds came out of the first
or the second batch right
um I don't know if that's 100 percent
certain but it is generally agreed that
he got two different little batches of
weed I tend to think that the seeds were
in the first batch right and you got to
remember that we know who they came you
know he bought the weed from Joe brand
and peabud
okay
but the problem is is that Joe Brandon P
Bud didn't grow it they were hippies
buying and selling weed on dead tour
and a lot and they didn't find out that
anything came in these seeds for
probably 15 years after they sold the
bag of wheat
I mean it's interesting right because
sometimes I think about that now when
you say and I I agree in a sense that
it's very unlikely we'll find out the
lineage of chemdog now but there is that
little bird in the back of my mind that
says yeah but Joby and Peabody didn't
know about the chemd for like 10 years I
mean he might get they might he might
get mad at me for saying this but
um I my understanding at least is that
Joby and Peabody sold the weed to
chemdog
and then discovered something came of it
on icmag in the forums say like 040506
Ashera
I believe it was it's exactly what you
said and JJ was online and he was the
one who linked them back with Greg and
in fact you know
um that's kind of why they call they
used to call like the one through the
four
the reunion the reunion batch because it
was like the band got back together
so
um you know Peabody and Peabody and Joe
B sell this weed
in 1991 and then 15 14 15 years later
they hear something came of it
right like people didn't smoke chem 91
until 06.
yeah there was definitely a big time
delay and and so there was and that's
not dissing them or anything like that
it just means that like
you know they people dead tour brings
people together from all over the
country
you know they weren't from that little
part of of they were significantly older
than Greg they weren't from that little
part of of Massachusetts that Greg was
from you know they lived in different
places they met up in on summer tour and
dude bought a sack
so let me let me cut to the next
question that everyone's going to be
wondering then which is that a lot of
people and by a lot I mean a small
number have suggested that maybe there
was only four seeds in that first batch
of weed the first iteration of the chems
we saw which was you know the sister and
the 91 really and then when they met up
later
other essential breedings had taken
place
um what's your thoughts on that there
may have only been just four seeds or
something close to that number
well
um I
there's no doubt that
you know uh regardless of how many seeds
you think there were they were popped at
very different times
right
so you know
I I wasn't there
um but
I will say that probably the only thing
that will put this debate to rest
is if we actually get like genetic
testing that works
to where like you can prove if these
things are full sisters or not
right
um because the thing is is that you know
I've talked to you know there's I won't
say their names or whatever but I do
think that that chemdog has gotten a
little a little gun shy about the story
because no matter what he says he gets
attacked
and people are like oh well you said
this thing on icmag and o5 and it
doesn't totally line up with what you
said in 2013 and then this doesn't get
said and that doesn't get said and what
ends up happening is it ends up
you know
um it just ends up shutting down the
debate right so all the stories that
I've told you basically came from me
talking to Staten Island
um and some of the loudest people in
chem fam online
are you know aren't necessarily people
that were there when all that stuff
happened I mean skunk VA he didn't get
he didn't get the the chem until Staten
Island gave it to him right
um you know uh Peabody was very
important in the gig he he sold the weed
but then he didn't get it till years
late you know until decades later
um and so you know and then you have a
situation where you have Greg where
you know
um he was a 17 year old kid
popping some seeds and so maybe I'm not
answering the question but I will say
very directly that I think that if it's
all from the same 13 seeds the only way
I could possibly see that happening is
if there was multiple phenos which was
very common back in 1991 the the ounce
he bought wasn't all this the same weed
it was mixed weed
right and that who's to say that all the
pollen was the same pollen that would be
the way that Greg and his close friends
could be absolutely telling the truth
I do not believe the chemd the chem 91
and the four are full sisters
I don't I think they're too different
you know
um and I've grown them all for a long
time
um I've had a lot of experience I've
made a lot of seeds with different ones
of them I've seen their progeny
I I personally do not do I have proof
that they're not full sisters no
but
um that doesn't mean I'm calling Greg a
liar
right
but I I just look at how different they
are and look at how different their
progeny is when you breed with them and
look at the different aspects and I just
don't see
um them coming from the same exact mom
and dad
yeah I I certainly agree with you and
the thing that I do always think to
myself though is that you know often we
hear the sort of line of like certain
stories are kept the way they are
because names are tied to it things like
that but then I also think to myself
like Greg is a glass blower by trade and
I really don't feel like his income is
necessarily tied to the story so that
sort of helps me to feel like I think
what he says probably is the truth to
hit like I don't see why he would have a
reason to lie per se because he was
honest right he killed the male from
that first lot like if you're going to
be really analytical about it that sort
of makes him seem like oh you know that
wasn't a good call and he was been
pretty upfront about that so I don't
know do you think that there's like
Merit to that sort of line of thinking
of well that like it doesn't seem like a
super obvious reason to lie about any of
it and make me and that's also taking
into account that maybe like everyone
his memory is not perfect well your
memory definitely isn't perfect and you
got to remember too that like
I mean
how do I say this and be polite
uh
think about back when you were 17 18 19
20.
imagine you were a hippie who liked to
go to dead tour and smoke weed and do
drugs and you're pretty much
probably mostly into partying and
chasing girls
right like what was your focus at 17 to
Hedonism most of us that developed into
weed nerds weren't weed nerds then
you know we were trying to have a good
time
and I think what happened is is that the
chemd and the chem 91 are two of my
all-time favorite strains
and I wouldn't have them if it wasn't
for Greg
so I am very very grateful to Greg for
as a teenager in an illegal state
taking risks
um and you know but I also think to
myself because I started growing in 1994
so a few years after that the level of
Education the level of knowledge that
existed back then compared to now was
Tiny
there was High Times there was a few
books you mostly didn't know anybody
there was no internet
there was no way to just get a bunch of
good information right
and I know stuff that I'm hesitant to
say
um just because it it's like you know
there's a political element to some of
this stuff
you know where what if I say that's the
truth but all of a sudden you know I got
you know pea butter skunk VA or somebody
else or Greg mad at me
you know
um and you know and but it's not like
I'm dissing anyone or lying it's like
and it might not be the truth it's
probably a truth
because let's face it right
Greg has
you know I won't name them but Greg has
some close friends that were like around
him
when he was popping those seeds
I wasn't
you know skunk VA was not
um we encountered the the chem in
California
because Staten Island brought it out
like so
um you know I mean there's you know
there's people that like everyone would
consider chem fam
that barely even know each other
and didn't know each other at all and
had never met back then for long periods
of time
so it's like there's different people
that have different little pieces of
things
you know so I want to be real careful
like from California because Staten
Island told me this stuff and I didn't
encounter the chems until the late 90s
which is a long time ago now
but it's also kind of a long time from
when those first things were popped
two right
um you know Matt posted this thing where
we're trying to do this like lineage
thing and we talked about like potential
um lineage of the chemd
right and I was talking I was I was
talking about it uh you know where I I
have I've stated before that I think it
it's reasonably likely that it's it's
chem skunk
okay and I got and and certain people
got heated on that right
and then JJ hits me up
right and he goes okay let's say I take
everything you're saying is true
why does it have to be 91 skunk why
can't it be sis skunk
and I was like well crap JJ you're right
you know it could be
how would we know and so there's a thing
when philos first came out the way they
raised all this money from all of us and
collected 300 for test kits was because
there was this Core group of nerds that
like wanted
scientific proof that some of these
stories and these lineages were true
prove or disproven
and it ended up that they couldn't do
the testing specific enough to give us
the answers we were craving
right one day we might be able to get
chem 4 and chemd and chem 91 and what
not tested
and genetically it might prove some
things to us
but until then there's just going to be
various people you know
getting mad at each other on the
internet
endlessly
about this [ __ ] right
um I just as a breeder and a grower and
I've had a long-term relationship with
some of these chems
I honestly think that there's some
different lineage in there
and I don't I'm not and that doesn't
mean that it could be as simple as like
let's say that everything that Greg and
his friends are saying is the absolute
truth and he has this little
wooden box of seeds that he's collecting
right and he's got all these different
things labeled
and he pops you know the story is right
that he pops five or six four you know
four five six seeds
um a b c d e whatever right in 2000. and
that's where the D came out of
you know what if you know
um I don't know you know what if what if
he just grabbed from the wrong bag
what if it was smudged
what if he honestly believes that it is
but it's like he grabbed something that
was like a hybrid of of chem skunk
and so it's like he's not lying
you know
at all he's totally telling the truth as
best as he recollects
and it just ends up that a few of those
seeds that he popped weren't from the
original 13 they were from hybrids that
got made
yeah you know
and so
I don't
I we were talking earlier on the show
about if you grow the chemd and the chem
91 side by side the chemd is much more
attractive
it's much limier green it's much
frostier you know
um
uh you know it just looks like a way
different plant
I love it you know but if you grew them
side by side and said you know do you
think these are full sisters to people
and they knew nothing of the lineage or
the history or any of the controversy
they'd probably say no
does that prove that they aren't full
sisters no
you know but that's what we're doing is
we're taking 30 year old stories
from kids
young kids who were Partiers and what
did they do
you know I do know I will say this and I
don't know if this has been publicly
said before but I'll say it whatever I
do know that
um in
you know a few years after a little
while after the exchange happened I know
that Staten Island and chemdog had a
conversation
where chemdog told him that the
um the skunk had hermed on the chems
and he had grown up some of these seeds
and they were unbelievable like he liked
them better than either of the other two
hmm that's interesting 100 and that was
actually statins inspiration for
starting the Superdog project
yeah
we didn't know about reversals back then
we didn't know how to like make the two
females
me you know make seed so we had you know
we had to go it was like a much more
roundabout way of like how it got
started or whatever but
um and he he told he told Staten Island
that you know they were filling their
rooms with these hybrids because they
were just so much
frostier and danker and and smelled
amazing and they were running rooms of
it
now granted when he told Staten Island
this he was probably 21 or 22 years old
and it was the mid 90s
yeah look I've got a ton of questions to
ask but first before it leaves my mind I
want to give a all honor and credit to
Greg the 17 year old popping you know
the quintessential cannabis plant you
know we're all super grateful and we're
all just genuinely curious that's why we
talk about this stuff I agree with that
statement a hundred percent uh the
without him I would not have the chemd
or the chem 91 and they're literally in
my all-time favorite list of strains I
grow and smoke them often uh and my life
would be diminished without both of them
so I am incredibly happy that he took
the risks he did when he was young and
he did all that type of stuff and I
honestly think too that it's like I
don't think this is a negative thing
with him at all it's it's like he got
really famous for something
and I think if you ask them he would
probably tell you that his passion is
more in glassblowing and other different
things than it is in actual growing and
breeding and wheat
it's not like he didn't do important
stuff with it but I don't think it's
like he doesn't have that burning Drive
yeah because people you know and I don't
think there's anything wrong with that
because like people people can have a
wide range of hobbies yeah truly and I
think to encapsulate you know sort of
both our point of views here you know
like all of this comes from a place of
love for the plant and genuine curiosity
not because we necessarily doubt you or
anything like that but I wanted to ask
you a few times it's come up we keep
saying chem 91 the chemd the chem 91 the
chemd why do you think the chem 4 isn't
always in the same breath whenever we
talk about Elite plants 91 and D same
sentence everyone accepts it they're
both up there like if you're rating
plants out of a hundred they're both
within 95 to 100 somewhere in that area
you know why what is it about the four
do you think that doesn't quite leave it
to be the third one
um
I would say that
it's crazy
honestly that the chemd and the chem 91
are generally regarded as all-time
greats by a lot of people
so it's really difficult in in the same
family to just keep adding all-time
greats
you know statistically even having two
of them come like that is probably
unusual right
um
you know the four I think the four has
two things going for it that make a lot
of people not not maybe get the full
thing out of it one is is that the best
four is usually taken about 12 plus
weeks
84-ish days
it looks done before that but it's
really done around 12 plus weeks
there's a lot of Growers that won't take
it 12 weeks
so you take it 10 weeks it's not as good
right the other thing that happens to
the four that makes people have an issue
with it is that it cures to a
are golden
a little bit of a light brown at times
and in weed
when it comes to Brokers or consumers or
whatever else anything that goes a
little golden or a little brown or a
little yellow that means you messed up
they just don't accept that some weed
does that
that it oxidizes a little bit that way
those colors are associated with old bad
burnt messed up not good
just as a general rule so the fact that
chemd tends to go a little golden brown
after it cures a bit
visually it's a big Downer for people so
you get something that's a little off
you get something that's harvested 10 or
14 days before it needs to be it's not
going to be as good
that being said
you know
um the I think the four
I think the four has some nl5 Haze in it
or something like that I don't know
because it it's got these big long colas
it stretches like a champ it takes
forever
um you know you grow the D It's like a
short squat Afghan it takes a while to
get going it's pretty much done at nine
weeks there's a variety of people that
pull it but it mostly gets pulled in the
early to mid 60s I would say some people
pull it in the high 50s Maybe
and the four really takes I mean it
takes a full 12 weeks
there's not very many strains that
people are willing to take 12 weeks
this isn't a chem thing but the amount
of people that would pull sour around
here 10 days 14 days early because it
had the nose and it was good enough to
go
a lot of Growers don't like going over
eight nine weeks
10 weeks on the outside you start
getting into 11 12 13 weeks they're like
what are you doing
I do not want to grow weed that long
and so I think that's
I think most people don't take the four
long enough
um and I also think that it's got a
little bit more of that like Zippy
sativa high and like you smoke enough of
it it kind of gives you like a little
raciness in your chest and it's a very
different Buzz than how the chemd and
how the dog hits you
maybe I should say this just before I
forget but uh did anyone ever tell you
the reason why we all call it the dog
because it makes you roll on the ground
like a dog or something no
no because when Statin Island brought it
West
he was a hundred percent fully organic
grower
and he didn't want to call any weed that
he grew chem
so he shortened it to the dog yeah okay
him dog you know he's your your organic
chem dog you know it's chem and so as a
nickname uh the four or five of us or
whatever who had it out here
I will tell you that like me I see
Collective Staten Island skunk VA
I never heard any like in the in in that
era the late 90s early 2000s before the
forums or whatever we all just called it
dog or the dog yeah that was what we
call it was the dog
you know
um we never called it chem dog
I mean we I knew obviously that that's
what like its full name
but that was our nickname and you know
Prem 91 the skunk VA cut all those
different things those are all forum
names
those are all names that came up as a
way to identify it when people were
typing out sentences online
yeah sure
you know and I've started using them
um just because it's it how it's
Community you know communication Wise
It's but it took me a long time because
the fir I mean we just called it
straight dog for
forever
and there you have it gang what do you
think
as always massive shout out to not so
dogs for coming on for this epic third
installment
thank you for making it to the end
what do you guys think
I loved it as always my man lots of
knowledge to share hope you'll come back
to the next part of this chapter
if you like this episode please go check
out our patreon the only way to get
early access to content
www.patreon.com the podcast our patreon
supporters have had access to this
episode for a while now be sure to check
it out if you want to hear more content
before it goes live for the General
Public
likewise we would love for you to go and
support our sponsors by supporting them
you help them to support us seeds here
now best seed bank in the industry
whatever drop you're looking for they're
gonna have the latest and greatest from
all the best breeders people who I vouch
for as well a guarantee on satisfaction
not just germination please go check
them out seats here now your number one
seed bank just like I want you to go
check out Copa biological systems these
guys have the best predators in the game
I cannot stress this enough if you want
to keep aphids and spider mites out of
your garden please get the happy param
inspired excavitals a hammer on about
these products because they're so bloody
good thank you so much coper for
supporting the show we are such big fans
of your products and truly grateful to
have you supporting us
likewise a huge thank you to the ongoing
support we get from pulse sensors these
guys have the best units in the game I
run them in my garden there's absolutely
no doubt it's helped improve the quality
of my crops and with the release of the
recent pulse Hub there's no reason not
to get on board get excited and get
yourself a pulse as I say from a single
tent to a single room to a multi-state
operation get serious get a pulse
you've heard me talk about it guys shout
out to the newest sponsor organic Salas
truly incredible organic powdered
fertilizer if you're looking for an easy
solution while growing in soil they have
it it is not hard to see why they are at
the top of their game I highly recommend
it for all the organic Growers out there
give it a try you will not be
disappointed your plants will be next
level massive shout out again
[Music]
and a massive shout out to our newest
sponsors dinova they are an incredible
Vape company based out of USA producing
some of the most coolest engineering and
vape technology you've seen for a while
I cannot speak highly enough about
dynavat's products if you've ever had a
vape and wished it was able to replicate
the head of a joint or a bong check out
dynavat they're second to none for good
reason we're really stoked to be working
with Donovan huge shout out guys
and that just about does it for this one
my friends thank you for making it to
the end as always
much love from your boy heavy days
signing off from the upside down Library
I'll see you for the next one see you
[Music]