[Music]
hello and welcome to another episode of
not in my bag as always you're joined by
your boy heavy days just want to give a
quick shout out before we jump into the
episode please please please consider
checking out the patreon of both myself
and mean Jean if you want to get more
access to upcoming episodes we've also
got our side show not in my side pouch
discussing all the bides and takes that
didn't make it into the formal episode
of not in my bag for this month if
you're interested in supporting the show
and want to see episodes continue to
happen please make sure to check out the
podcast on patreon as well as mean Jean
of menes from patreon we appreciate your
support so
much so without further delay let's get
into
it all righty hello and welcome back my
friends for another episode of not in my
bag your number one place to get all the
latest news hottest takes deeper
analysis on the current affairs within
the Cannabis scene as always I'm joined
by my co-host Mr mean Jean and today we
have a good friend back for another
episode seeing as the first was so well
received Mr Noto dog thank you so much
for joining us today how are we doing
gentlemen well doing good doing good
good evening and good
morning as always I want to know what
are you guys smoking
on what you smoking on there Francis you
know my buddy just down the street from
me me pulled down a bunch of his summer
depths and so he gave me like 10
different things to try and they're
about they got harvested maybe a month
ago so they're like right at the point
of like being you know good at this
point so just a bunch of a little bit of
he grew a little bit of my Sour Diesel
he grew some lemon haze he grew some
cookie hybrids because that's what the
market is and stuff like that so I've
just been puffing on all that fresh weed
that he was kind enough to want me to
try it's kind of been going down nice
yeah I'm in the same boat I just I'm
just hitting the point where uh I had
some plants that were at the top of my
potential keeper list and I wanted to
rev them so I went ahead and uh cut them
a little bit earlier than I would have
normally probably let them like max out
but they were good enough to really know
what they are but I wanted to give the
plants the best shot at revegging you
know because I like have good results
like they really quick if you don't let
them get all the way done um and so uh
those first tops that I cut off there's
probably like I don't know maybe 20 of
them or something that are just like
nice you know like long sticks of weed
with just those nice pieces building up
to the top it was so hot this summer
when they were flowering that the very
tops of the buds actually look like they
were like too close to a grow light or
something they don't look look very good
so the buds that are right I always like
the buds that are right a little lower
anyway more but um it's crazy because if
I judged by what the tip of the bud
looked like I'd be like this [ __ ] all
sucks you know because it was like a 100
plants were budding and and getting
close to finish week six week seven was
100 degrees 105 degrees 110 degre every
day for like two and a half weeks yeah
it was harsh yeah so um anyway so now
I'm pulling off like the little branches
that are the driest off of those
and um just bonging some of those to see
which ones are uh are really cool and uh
so that's like Hindu s1's which are
really neat there'll be some types I got
one that's kind of similar to
like I mean it's been so long to really
say for sure but it's like kind of
similar like to the
effects that kind of like old like
Afghani with the really big features and
it's like was ugly in my gr but I can
tell if I could grow it right it's that
old it's the purplest it has the fattest
leaves it has the whitest resin and it
smells like kind of like gelato without
this without the sweetness or the cookie
part quite of it but it's like that kind
of like old meno humble Afghani smell
but like but not like monkey balls it's
different it's more gelato but it's
really cool that one I really like and
it's looking like it's going to rev and
uh and then you know like random other
Hindu hybrids and those are all the ones
that I have that's like my fresh weed
and as they dry like it's a lot easier
to keep up with sampling them it's like
okay this one's dry enough to smoke and
this one let's try these and then as
they go because at a certain point I'll
wind up swamped and be like okay now
there's 600 plants to try and at that
point you kind of have to sniff your way
through the wires and see what's the
most promising and because you know it
just gets like overwhelming but uh but
it's cool because there's more you see
the identity better and that's what
where I'm at right now with this time of
year it's pretty
sweet that's awesome I I love that I
love that I'm actually puffing on some
Abracadabra from my buddy Eli cash who I
did a little collab with making this one
but he's done an awesome job growing it
it's like sour TK cross to uh chem
sister by Neville's Hayes which comes
from Wick's family farm so really like
chem sort of structure overall I thought
there'd be a bit more sativa influence
in it but like I guess the sour TK is
just such a solid looking structure
beautiful stuff I'm loving it shout out
to my buddy Eli he's actually got a seed
company called local bird seed everyone
should check that out as well let's jump
into our first story let me see if I can
uh navigate us to the right screen this
is a good one I wanted to bring this up
first cuz it's so
awesome uh here we go Glass House
mountains famous for being CEO by the
former law enforcement officer Kyle kin
who advertised himself as a drug
detection and eradication specialist
when he used to be in the service glass
house has backed down from their legal
claim against cannabis uh sorry Catalyst
CEO Elliot Lewis after Lewis made claims
that they felt were defamatory accusing
Glass House of selling their cannabis
product into unlicensed cannabis
markets glass house has withdrawn the
defamation claim but still vem denies
the statement citing that they've just
analyzed the situation and they don't
feel it's in their financial interest to
pursue the case and that is the only
reason they're withdrawing it uh they
just don't feel like they're going to be
able to get enough money and they even
went so far as to say that they think
pursuing this case would end up
increasing the cost of the product
passed on to the end consumer and their
overall philosophy is to offer the
lowest price
possible I guess this does make me
wonder uh what does this say does this
suggest that maybe they weren't able to
prove that their product was not making
it into unlicensed cannabis markets or
do we believe them that it simply just
wasn't financially worth their time to
pursue the case what do we
think what what do you think there oh I
have a lot of thoughts on this one I
suppose I mean I will freely admit that
I did not read all of the legal filings
by any means I did follow it because it
is it is interesting um how all this
kind of stuff is shaking out and
um I
mean what is Glass House supposed to do
right like you get Elliot goes out there
and says you're one of the largest black
marketeers in American
history right like you have to sort of
act
outraged especially if you're one of the
large larger black marketeers in history
you know you really have to sort of like
um and I mean I I would say
that that glass house was created for
federal legalization and I think a lot
of the big big farms made a play in
California that Federal legalization
would come faster than it has and
there's just not the market to absorb
ABB all these giant
Farms so then the question becomes like
where do all these giant Farms excess go
to and that is a great unanswered
California question right now it's not
just glass house there's something like
1 1600 licensed acres in Santa
Barbara right uh glass house isn't even
in there they're like in Ventura or
something so if I had to guess what
happened is that neither company really
wanted Discovery or bunch of like on
record digging around and what's going
on behind the
scenes you know what I mean because uh
California legal is like it's it's a
little weird and I mean I as far as
glass house goes obviously their
products make it all kinds of places
they
shouldn't and you know whether or not
they have plausible deniability or
whether or not they know or don't
know you know they're obviously never
going to admit that they
know they have to act
shocked in a way right so it's like I
but but I mean I I'll tell you that
probably like if you looked at all the
legal sales in California probably like
one or like one 100 Acre Farm could
probably Supply most of California's
needs you start adding up one huge farm
with all the little Legacy farms and
then all the like two three four 500
lighters around and stuff that are
licensed
like you know there's a big thing with
glass house that has 100 acres and it in
green houses and it pops off multiple
rips a year and where does it
go and that's essentially the fight
between Catalyst and glass
house is he just called out the where
does it go part
yeah I
mean yeah like numbers wise I mean I
don't know anything about how
everybody's everybody's um you know I
don't know all I can't crunch the
numbers with any of that but I do know
that like one of my buddies up here is
like the number
two um
wholesaler in
California and he buys all of his weed
from small farms
and he buys it at a very low price and
he sells it at a very low
price so basically what he does is he
buys like quality outdoor and depth
mostly depth but you know whatever's
good and he sells e and he doesn't have
fancy marketing he basically has weed
that is consistently what we would
consider to be pretty good weed from
people who have been growing weed for a
long time people who we would know from
the old days and basically buys untrim
weed for $100 a
pound and uh comes in and takes
everything from people and it's
basically from people who otherwise
wouldn't be able to sell weed at all and
would have quit so they wind up still
having a fairly functional um business
because it's not that hard to grow a
thousand pounds when nobody's trying to
stop you so um if you can grow a 100
pounds and th000 pounds and not have to
trim it and sell it for $100 a pound
then it's not so bad compared to being
completely out of the game like a lot of
people are so he's actually him and his
brother have been able to keep people in
and I didn't know any of this was going
on it's been going on for years but I
didn't know it even existed so I was
talking to him and um he was like yeah
you know I'm we're we're doing good I'm
proud of my brother and you know he's
good good really good at business and
I'm really good at finding the good weed
and everything and
you know nobody like for me like I don't
wanna I don't I won't do that I don't
want to grow weed for $100 a pound but
some people um it's it actually gives
them something they can do but now
imagine that the guy who is the number
two provider of weed in California to
all the shops buys all his weed from
guys like us who probably the bigger of
them only grow maybe a ton of weed a
year which sounds a lot if you don't
grow a lot of weed but if you grow a lot
of weed you laugh at a ton of year a ton
of we I knew people in Humble who were
pumping out five tons a year under prop
215 and they were making a dent in any
kind of a market but in the legal Market
within California trapped within these
boundaries that you have to stay within
my buddy who's buying weed from small
farms is number two in the state yeah
and he is truly legit getting weed from
the small farms who people like Gavin
Newsome said would be the people who
would provide all the weed to everything
and then other than them who were number
two who are probably buying
supplying the second most amount of weed
in all of the state with probably a
pretty small acreage I imagine they're
probably buying all their weed from you
know 20 acres worth of people at the
most and that's number two so now when
you're saying these numbers like 160
acres in one County where 1600 acres in
one County 1600 Acres 1600 Acres so and
glass house isn't even in Santa Barbara
they're in ventera they don't even count
towards that total so just just imagine
that so are they so are they so these
other guys who have whatever they
have five times as much the acreage as
whose number
two where's the they're they're all
number one are they all number one
together are they and how is number just
if you think about the numbers it
doesn't make a lot of sense so and
that's basically what yeah I don't know
how CEO would rant about is he would
just screen because he has all the
numbers and he put him up on his
whiteboard because he's in the industry
and he knows what sales are he goes and
looks at like it's all public right and
I mean I will say maybe I I'll say this
before I forget about it it just came
out recently that glass house has
announced they're making a big move into
hemp right which is curious because it
comes right after like the Catalyst
going what are you doing with this 100
acres of green houses and weed and hemp
is something that they can actually sell
in all 50 states and maybe it's thca
if yeah so there might so there might be
a situation where they pivot because
like my opinion is is that if you set up
a huge scene intending on things going
National you can't sell enough in the
legal California Market to sustain
itself so you're burning investor money
and how many years can you burn investor
money you might have investors that are
like oh we'll wait it out but one year
turns into three turns into four and
they just keep burning and they don't
see any legislation coming down the pipe
that makes it look like it's going to be
soon and you have to
Pivot so I don't know I don't know if
we'll ever know because they dropped the
lawsuit on on they didn't want to move
it forward but um they changed their
practices after the lawsuit because now
they're going big into
hemp yeah and I mean that's the question
the hemp the hemp thing is really
interesting because I keep hearing
people talking about oh yeah thca hemp
and I'm like yeah
um weed before you heat it up in general
I mean I've had stuff that if it's you
know the certain strains it sits around
for a little bit of time like you'll
you'll start to see some some
numbers uh that aren't thca but in
general when you see people's weed get
tested it's just all
thca I heard there's laws dude that they
might block the THC from hemp as a
pathway I mean they already have is
what's crazy is that it's this it's this
little detail of people going well it's
thca and I'm like yeah I mean my whole
Al the I grow is thca hemp like OG Kush
you heard of that thca hemp Sour Diesel
pretty good thca hemp like until it has
actually turned into to Delta 9 which
only happens sometimes like and it
doesn't generally happen while it's in
the field you know so that's all the
funny thing and now what's really weird
was I go to I go to um the store in
Willets where I buy dog food and on the
counter is a thing that is THC Delta 9
hemp Edibles and I'm like I've heard of
Delta 8 and I know a a Trippy trick with
the hemp but Delta 9 Edibles on the the
counter at a store that has no kind of
anything there I'm like I don't know if
it's a typo or what but like this is
just weed guys so the regulation I'm
like What's even what are what the [ __ ]
is anybody doing right now it's crazy to
see like okay thca hemp THC Delta 9
Edibles and the store you know like it's
just like I don't know the the whole
thing's really weird it's a lot of um I
don't know there's not a lot of clarity
on what the
um the real lines and andies of all of
it are so all this to say that yeah I
mean like you know like if you're if
hemp is easier to produce and hemp you
can ship Nationwide then like you know
then just ship whatever weed Nationwide
and say it's thca because it probably is
and so I'm I'm sure at a certain point
they'll go wait THC it's like back in
the day they're like oh no this isn't
Cannabis sativa this is cannabis
IND and for a little while people got
away with being like no no no look at
these plants are not the illegal one
this is cannabis indica and that's
what's going on right now and I wouldn't
even want to talk about it except that
it's so ridiculous that it even exists
that there's no way it has any legs on
it the time frame here is like the
windows gota it's the windows already
basically got to be closed and it's
happened to certain people in certain
places already but like uh the whole
thing's weird it's it's really a weird
weird time and um you know everybody can
always figure out some kind of a Trippy
loophole and then everybody just blows
it out and then it's shot and like by
the time I know about it because I'm not
involved in any of it I'm like it's it's
got to be shot I don't see how this is
Gonna Keep um going like that but hey
great way to Pivot right now to go yeah
H I mean yeah the the funny part about
that would even be is if they just kept
doing what they were doing but then they
just brought it above board and they're
like oh yeah we're shipping it
everywhere but it's
hemp yeah so this this whole time as
long as we've had a hemp permit we've
been shipping thca hemp
everywhere you know and then it's like
oh what kind of THC hemp oh I don't know
runs I would I I would and the only
closing thought I really have on it
would basically be is that glass house
is a funny name to be talking about or
whatever because the
California weed industry is kind of a
glass house where you're not supposed to
look around certain corners and like
there's a blind eye turned to like a lot
of the inefficiencies and a lot of just
the reality of what they've created you
know and and so yeah I think that
um uh obviously glass house is not like
us you know whatsoever they're not
stocked by People Like Us they're kind
of the people that are trying to come in
and take it from us and they might have
just timed it wrong I think they opened
up Glass House in an already sat
completely saturated California Market
when all the news was already on how
much more Supply there was than demand
and then they brought a 100 acres of
greenhouse on and so they obviously I
think they thought that legalization was
a good chance within a year or two and
it's just stretched and now they're
stretched because they're not returning
their money to I think there's a bunch
of not just glass house I think there's
a bunch of huge California cannabis
companies that their investors are
starting to get nervous about the lack
of returns and the money
expended and we could see a lot of
weirdness in the next five or 10 years
that that that shakes out yeah and with
some of the biggest you've already seen
it you know we already um I think the
last one we already talked about you
know medmen gone Vegas the biggest the
biggest thing ever it's GNA they own
Vegas you go everywhere you go it's the
those are the stores you want to get
something pretty much you ask somebody
where's the the store that's the store
and they're shot like it's loana by us
yeah right here that one was done that
was the biggest one up here and the one
that was like 275 million they raised
you know and then yeah we talked about
before I think cookies and cookies
investors getting all mad at them and
different lawsuits filed and then
dropped quickly kind of like this one
where there's a lot of money sloshing
around and there's not a lot of money
being made yeah and it's all yeah it's
those huge those huge machines you know
and it's like I'm talking about my buddy
um who comes from a family who's like
you know like his his dad's like like a
world famous weed guy from like the 60s
from down south like the whole like all
kinds of lore in their family and all
this and um that he got into it and I
didn't you know I always see him doing
his little hustle and stuff and I never
talked to him and knew what was going on
and he's like yeah we basically we're
selling weed to stores by the eth buying
it by the pound buying it really cheap
by the pound selling it really cheap by
the eth and it's good weed and we don't
do any of the fancy [ __ ] and we don't
even they don't even white label it they
put it in the stores on the shelves in
their simple little bags and it's the
best value it's good value weed and that
is actually working and it's keeping all
these little Farmers going and they
actually still have pretty good income
relative to what's going on for
everybody else and they're really really
big in the scheme of what is actually
going on at the stores and um the same
with some of the Buddies like from up in
um humble you know like um you know like
uh to up there redwood redwood Roots
like they put together little stuff and
uh what's the other one humble homegrown
like they're able to like just keep
going there's always like you'll see
these posts where he's like dude I'm
losing my mind I'm so stressed out and
he's like tearing up and then like
pretty soon he's back he's like all
right I figured something out come hit
me up you know and then they're like
keeping it going and that's like the
nature of like reality but it's not
reality when people come in and they're
just like oh yeah we're GNA be we're
going to be the you know the Amazon of
weed or whatever it's like H good luck I
don't think that you can just keep
dumping money
endlessly into doing all that stuff and
I don't even mean like within California
I'm like go ahead and figure out
whatever however you can make it work
cool fine with me I just don't think
that it's sustainable I don't think it
does work you know and it's a trip
because um you know that's like the from
the outside that's what everyone thinks
is the thing to do and it's even you
know like it was I probably back around
the time when Medical came in in the
early 2000s I started telling my friends
I was like dude going small is the new
way to go big now going big is just such
a huge risk and then you get screwed and
you get nothing and it's like basically
like okay do you wanna it's like the
difference between getting a job
painting houses and being like dude I'm
gonna go to the casino with everything I
got and put it all on one number you
know and it's like oh [ __ ] all right
damn all right I'm out you know but then
somebody else is just doing their job
and they're like I don't know everything
seems okay to me and that's kind of how
it is is these guys are going for these
huge pushes and these huge things and
then like the people who are like ah
it's kind of rough I'm kind of broke but
they just keep plugging along like they
they can do it because like it's like
that's what's real life you know as bad
as it was uh when prop 64 passed if they
would have kept the acre cap it would
have kept all this giant waste of money
from being poured in l before it was
ready for that kind of investment anyway
yeah I mean the only thing that I saw
when they first did that is I know how
people are and it would have been like I
as soon as they were like oh there'll be
a one acre cap and I was like yeah and
there's G to be a lot of names on
paper that are all vaguely if you really
look into it they're actually all the
same thing you know like somebody would
be holding 100 permit and they would be
you know it's like we you remember like
in the days of medical people would be
like yeah dude I have 1300 scripts yeah
went down and collected all of them and
I got all these patients and stuff yeah
and then you like you like talk to
somebody else they might have the same
1300 scripts you know like you know
really I called it the paper Shield yeah
yeah because if they landed it was like
you bring out your paper shield and
you're like I got I'm safe I'm on base
yeah and it and you know that was still
um
in those cases that's what's weird is
like a lot of people can grow a couple
tons of weed people smoke a lot of weed
it's it's it's you know it's perishable
and it's consumable so when you have
things like that you can be like yeah we
can produce a lot of products and it can
still you know be used as opposed to if
you were you know you really have to
control um Supply when you have
something that's like you know like like
diamonds right if you just have them all
out and they're all over the place then
it's just going to everything's going to
crash but people could do people could
have a lot of weed relative to um demand
and it would still be okay but at a
certain point you just it's just stupid
and that's you know like it it's it's
trippy because I think
in the legal Market there's
probably uh small enough po of people
who if they were clever enough and they
really could understand like the nature
of [ __ ] everything or anything for
that matter they'd be like hey you know
what we could completely control the
price because we are the biggest and
since they're big enough to control the
price what do they do they drop it out
the floor and overproduce and it's like
when you able to have such a limited
pool of production there's only so many
people with huge permits all those guys
could go hey let's put let's put 95% of
our permit to sleep let's follow it and
let's just make the price go through the
roof and maybe they will eventually when
they get enough control but I don't
think I think no matter what they're
still going to all just be like how how
do we make more $30 pounds of weed like
through the up to this up to the Moon
they're just going to try to do it
without ever thinking about it and I
mean you know
it seems like that would be impossible
that they would do that but they've
already done so much of it it makes me
wonder you know it's a tsunami of mids
yeah that's what it is it's it's the
it's the tsunami of mids all right we
probably have chatted that one to death
oh for sure yeah it's terrible uh yeah
but I expect more
lawsuits anyway I expect more lawsuits
between more people fighting in
California over the next five or 10
years yeah for sure this is just is just
the first wave of arguments about how
it's all going yeah for sure of course
now look the whole time we've been
chatting I've been thinking I'm just
going to draw us back to the original uh
question for a moment it feels a bit
like in the first episode I think we
were talking about how this issue was
like the emperor wearing no clothes you
know like we know we know this weed's
going somewhere and we see a lot of weed
popping up somewhere else so I guess my
question is now that someone's finally
called it out and seemingly nothing is
going to happen as a result do we think
Glass House product will just continue
and nothing will happen what do we think
it's actually going to happen if
anything or do we think business as
usual I might get a little
conspiratorial here I suppose but do it
aliens um I think the I think the reason
why a drug cop is one of the top people
in the company is because it bu immunity
from other like they they're kind of a
click and a club they don't go after
their
own and despite that I also think that
there is just a big push in California
to like not expose anyone big because
those people pay a lot in fees and
overhead and taxes and all this stuff
and they just don't want to admit that
the system that they developed isn't
working very
well or as designed and so there's a lot
of management going on and it's like you
know I mean some of those farms in Santa
Barbara probably pay this the state over
a million do just in license
fees you
know like you know small farms pay a
tiny amount it might be a big amount to
that small farm but like the bigger
places like really spend a lot of money
and so there's all this investor money
pouring in and there's all this taxes
getting made and all these local
municipalities are making money it's
almost like a I almost see it as like a
financial bubble that's going to
burst
like this might be getting off Target
for a second but imagine right when
Federal legalization does come there's a
bunch of states that have a lot of
infrastructure money spent on their
personal legalization that aren't going
to be able to compete with other states
because of their climate and
whatnot you know
like seriously like are you like you
know are you really going to are you
really going to have a bunch of outdoor
in New York compared to California or
Southern Oregon probably not just like
every other crop we grow in this country
we'll probably find out where the most
advantageous place to grow it is based
on the climate and whatnot and it'll get
shipped everywhere
else the only reason why people are
growing in Missouri and New York and
Maine and here and there and everywhere
else mostly is because it's a
state-by-state thing and it all has to
happen within that state so I think each
state has been sucking up a whole bunch
of investment and like buildout
money and blue collar and unions getting
built and electricians and construction
and all this different stuff and then
it's like you know is that stuff going
to persist once there's competition from
Arizona and California and places where
it's sunny and dry every
day
maybe I doubt it
though so I I think it's like a m I
think it's like a I think it's like a
state-by-state money grab in a
way because each state is building out
but like think think about it on a
different level right like you don't
grow Citrus in New
York you grew it in Orange County in
Florida right like you go crops where
they're suited yeah for sure and then
related too to the legality of it and
the same thing of state by state like
during alcohol prohibition there was a
time
um
when there were certain counties and
certain places where you could pay the
local
authorities and you could basically
bribe them and then you could operate
your operation there legally and then uh
the value wasn't as high there because
of that but once you took it somewhere
else your alcohol gained huge amounts of
value and so um you know it's like one
of those things where even now although
There's real
um regulation on these smaller levels
and people are like oh well it's State's
rights and you know County rights City
rights which all that is cool but at the
same time if you really look at it it's
kind of like yeah but being that it's
not really legal legal um it's really
kind of just a big extortion plot if you
look at it in relation to how things
were during that time because you go
well what's the difference really is you
get some paperwork doesn't really mean
anything because it's not really you
know it's not really legal but I mean it
is in is in a different sense but um you
know the whole thing of it being these
little place bypl things it's like it's
all kind of uh it's it's kind of like
you're just paying to do a crime
otherwise why is it a crime you know
what I mean like it's doesn't I that's
the biggest thing I've never understood
is you hand somebody a piece of paper
and now it's not immoral anymore like so
it's illegal because it's dangerous and
immoral that's the whole reason why weed
is illegal and then if you give somebody
a permit to grow it and sell it then all
of a sudden it becomes like fine totally
fine this is going to tie into one of
our segments of uh of uh you know when
it's legal it's clean yeah for sure yeah
of course
well saying as seeing as the cat has
been L out of the bag we will move on to
our next discussion point which is that
let me see am I am I
quick the LA times has published an
article where they have slammed a bunch
of extremely well-known popular hype
cannabis companies accusing them of
being riddled with pesticides as well as
being quite substantially off in regards
to the stated potency the end conclusion
is pretty much that a lot of the weed
being sold by some of these top
companies is basically being given to
them by the same Brokers the weed is
sort of sold between them sold to them
um and then they basically end up
selling it to the user I guess the
question becomes is this really that
surprising is this something we truly
didn't expect so to
speak I mean I think
that all the uh I don't want to say like
uh cannabis insiders or whatever but no
I don't think it's surprising it
certainly is 180° around their rhetoric
of what they thought the differences
were going to be um but no I wouldn't
say it was surprising at
all you know I I think that um I mean
for one thing you know it's like we
should say there's a lot of brands that
are not vertically integrated and do do
not grow and control their product from
the be they they source source material
whether that's flour crude or distillate
or like whatever it might be they have a
brand and there's a lot of brands that
like they might have like business
arrangements with Farms but they don't
run the
farm they're just buying on the open
market like stuff that meets their
criteria right and so as a result of
that the cheapest weed that you can buy
for your brand is probably some of these
huge
farms that we were just talking about
because they have the most volume so
they can offer it at the lowest price
and those large Farms have a tendency to
just they want to win and whether
they're spraying stuff themselves or
whether there's another large farm next
to them that's growing conventional
stuff that gets sprayed or you know any
number of ways um it's the problem it's
a good thing cannabis has much more
stringent testing requirements than our
food
but when you start growing in an Agland
surrounded by that kind of thing the the
chance for it being contaminated is
high there's even a lot of these Farms I
should mention that um their ground is
contaminated and will be for
decades as far as like stuff that that
tests hot for cannabis you could grow
cauliflower on it or whatever and
probably be fine but for cannabis
there's a lot of ban pesticides for
cannabis that is just persistent in
Agland and these huge farms are all
growing on Old Agland for the most
part you know so it doesn't surprise me
at all no because most of these brands
are probably not sourcing it from small
farmers that have less of a chance of
using some of that funky stuff they're
probably buying it on a much larger
market in
bulk and just as a quick side point I
wanted to add because someone actually
asked me why is it that like you can use
certain pesticides and even like pgrs on
certain Edibles and whatnot but like
it's so bad on cannabis and um you know
many of you will be aware of this but
it's just as simple as like because
cannabus has ended up being you know
volatized or vaporized in some form it's
it's going to get directly into your
body whereas a lot of these products
when they're on the surface of like a
tomato or whatever you eat it it doesn't
really get absorbed so it's it's not as
concerning but just a quick little tibit
I wanted to throw in but Mr main Jan
fill us in on your thoughts I could
actually add something before I forget
that's kind of cool about what you just
mentioned so there's this product that I
don't like at all called Eagle 20 that's
a Fungicide and the reason why they
approve it for food is they say the
chemical is broken down by your stomach
really quickly right but if you burn it
you know flow that has it on it it
creates a byproduct of cyan
right and so obviously you don't want to
be inhaling hot cyanide on any level um
so and then two I think which is good I
think cannabis has a stricter testing
regimen and that our food should move in
probably in that same direction too it's
almost like they made it more strict but
that's positive and we should be moving
away from a lot of those harsh chems in
our food supply as
well yeah yeah because when you do that
it it gives people an incentive to try
to figure out something else the problem
with the way that um the legalization
and regulation went is that it's leaning
toward that big a model like he's saying
where you use all these crazy harmful
chemicals and they're not made for
combustible products they're made for uh
consumable edible products products and
when you eat things your digestive tract
is really impressive like if you drink
chlorinated water very little chlorine
goes in your system but if you bathe or
swim in chlorinated water you can absorb
a lot more you know so it's like the
there's there's a difference between how
everything works in your lungs really
take things in super gnarly you know you
could eat small amounts of things things
that are really toxic and your body
will'll deal with it you know your body
has your kidneys it has your liver it
has these different systems of
filtration and purification in your your
um you know everything in your gut and
everything that lives in your gut but
your lungs are just this clean area of
something that just everything goes
straight into your blood through your
lungs basically because they're meant to
take in the oxygen and the oxygen has to
readily be sucked into your lungs which
makes smoking weed great you smoke it
andam the thing that should be mentioned
about that is that right after that all
that oxygen oxygenated blood go straight
to your heart yes so whatever's going in
there is going to your heart as fast as
your body can get it there because and
then push around the rest of your body
yeah for sure and then it goes
everywhere then it pumps through your
whole body and then it and then it winds
up after that going through the
filtration after it gets into your blood
you know where so it's
interesting difference but yeah the um
the question of was it is it a surprise
is it's like no if
you if you want to get things from the
biggest producers of something that's a
plant anybody who grows knows the bigger
you go the more likely you are to have a
failure of your crop and the bigger the
failure the more costly it is so when
people find out that okay we're about to
lose this whole crop and this crop is
eight tons of weed or whatever it is
they're like okay so can we get away
with this stuff is this gonna you think
this is going to pass testing I don't
know have you seen it I don't know and
then they grow the whole thing they hit
it with something really nasty and they
get all the way to the end of it and
they're left with all this tainted
product but guess
what you can't test a whole batch you
can only test a sample from a batch well
is this sample from the batch yeah of
course the sample's from the batch you
know we would never uh take a sample
from a different batch that we know is
100% clean that we got from a much
smaller producer or from a different
section where we had a little bit of
weed that wasn't even supposed to be
sold but hey we know it's at least clean
so you know maybe sometimes that is
happen or even like even like uh
there's certain band things that get
pulled out when you just turn it into
distillates so like if you're knowing
that you're growing a a a big ass field
just for basically for disty as they
call it like you might even be able to
like hit your stuff with some nasty
chems because you think it's all going
to get pulled
out yeah you know and so it's just being
it's one of those things where it's
like it almost makes me feel like like
with food or whatever it's like don't
ask how the sausage was made
yeah right um a lot of rules and
regulations right now are sort of
bumping up against the reality of what
people want to
do um and the pesticide thing and the
herbicides and all that like people just
don't realize that like when I met a
bunch people in big a that I thought
were going to crush us I didn't realize
how Reliant they were on all these chems
in their toolkit to be able to grow and
they almost felt helpless when some of
these chem and some of these you know
ban pesticides or whatever are removed
because they've literally leaned on them
their whole career and they don't have
another method to solve whatever problem
it might be so it's like they almost get
insulted when they find out they can't
use it on
weed
right um and
then um as far as the as far as the THC
inaccurate testing goes as long as
there's a Marketplace that stupidly is
basing pricing on THC content
there's been a THC
creep um you know for going on for a
long time now and it's it's just going
to continually get worse um and then the
other thing I should say too is that um
some of these big
farms they're the they're the lab's
biggest
clients and the lab the lab might be
testing for THC and tpes and all their
pesticide and herbicide and heavy metals
testing and all that so some of these
huge farms like literally like could be
the difference between like a lab
surviving or not because they're getting
hundreds of thousands of dollars from
this company so that everything's
clean so there's like it's not
independent I'm I guess what I'm saying
and there's a vested interest within
multiple parties to get a
result that's kind of how I look it have
you ever seen this uh documentary about
the Russian doping in the Olympic called
Icarus uh I haven't no no I have not
it's really interesting so you watch it
and basically it just is a great example
of how when you have when you have
organizations that are established and
exist over time right and everything
kind of keeps up the same pace and
status quo over a long period of time
they start to gain this relationship
where everybody knows how everything
works and after a while it's not hard to
game the system in one way or another
and it's not also if things are in place
long enough then you actually insert
your own people into these organizations
to make sure you know that's how police
corruption often works that's how you
know you might be able to get you know a
judge or a DA or a congress person or
whatever it is that you need to be able
to put these things in place and like in
our in our in our you know the greater
system of the United States it's not
uncommon to see that oh the guy who used
to work for Monsanto and cell Roundup
now he's the guy at the at the FDA or
the USDA or there's all these conflicts
of interests that arrive naturally and
like in this documentary you see that
it's like they were able to figure out
like the unbeatable system there's no
way around this system and then they're
like yeah we we know how to do it you
really want to do it and and so they
they basically gamed the system and
figured out a way to where they could
they could tamper with these samples and
then they would you know they would just
do this little just this little dance
that was really simple you know and um
they were able to figure that out and I
mean that's naturally always going to
happen with any kind of a testing
organization at a certain point you're
going to get Bad actors in there and
that's not to say even that I have so
much a problem with that type of um
corruption because it's not so much to
me it's not the issue it's just the fact
that they The Regulators are going to
pretend that everything is completely
bulletproof and we know exactly what's
going going on and they're going to make
all the Growers jump through all these
hoops and in reality anybody who wants
to game the system can game the system
and all the people who want to be honest
are just going to be like all right we
just have a bunch of Hoops to jump
through that only keep us from doing bad
stuff and we're not the guys who are
going to use the pesticides but we still
have to test for them to show that our
stuff's clean when anyone who knows us
knows it's clean but these guys who you
just obviously are going to be the ones
with the dirty weed because you see how
they're how much weed they're growing at
scale those are the guys who are going
to wind up faking the test test testing
this they don't even have to do any of
this [ __ ] like in the movie that I'm
talking about it doesn't have to be
complicated they just give the lab a
sample of some weed they already know is
clean and they're like this is the batch
and they're like okay we tested the
batch you know and they can just test
the same they can just put one clean
pound of weed away that has super high
THC and go this is the test for all of
it and then they can go oh and here's
the sample for the turps here if they
want here's the sample for the T and
they can do it like that if they want
the whole system's a joke you know
essentially what the LA Times found is
that real world testing showed far
different results than the piece of
paper that you needed to show to make
sure that you were approved and clean
yeah and there was a vast discrepancy
between getting the piece of paper that
allowed you to make the sale within the
legal system cuz you and now you have
plausible deniability too right like you
know you didn't know you tested it you
didn't sell dirty stuff you tested it it
came back clean yeah their test was
clean so who knows what happened here in
the middle and is it cross could it be
that brand had dirty equipment yeah and
they dirtied our weed yeah and when you
have um when you have smaller
producers and all the weeds coming from
them it's like there's not even they
don't they don't even really have the
incentive to want to use all of these
chemicals because there's just not
really very much use for them because
you don't have anything that gets that
far outside of what you want to do like
when I grow weed like any that I can
that I get is either like I'm gonna take
a loss on it and it's not that bad or I
know how to fix it with something that's
not harmful there's no big deal but if
you're looking and you're going oh my
God we have all these Acres you're going
to be like all right what is what can I
do for for fractions of a penny for a
square foot like what can we get and
then they do it and then they just game
the testing and that's that's just
something that is fully incentivized at
large scale and so it would have been
great for them to really keep large
scale for being able to operate because
then you'd have good stuff you know you
go to the farmers market there's people
at the farmers market who are selling
organ organic produce and it's not
organic I had a friend back in the day
his family used to used to run uh big
farms in California with produce and
they would sell all their produce in
bulk but the kids to get money would get
a bunch of organic stickers and stamps
and they would take them they would load
up their car and go to the farmers
market and sell all this conventional a
[ __ ] that was left over from their
family's operation and they'd sit at the
they'd sit at the farmers market and
sell it and they would do that but at a
farmers market they were the they were
the minority most people at the farmers
market you can like go up and check
stuff out and you go okay I mean one of
the great things that's funny at like a
farmers market is if you go to like buy
some broccoli and it's got like three or
four aphids on it you're like all right
I know they didn't use anything that bad
because these [ __ ] would have been
smoked if they used the [ __ ] people are
spraying on these weed crops you know
like you can see that this is like
regular
stuff it doesn't look quite like the
stuff at the store maybe the varieties
are different it's these it's a
different thing and usually you can
trust the smaller people but there's
that there's still going to be a certain
aspect of of funkiness to that but like
the reality was that the reason these
people I knew had funky not organic
produce selling along with the rest was
because they were the guys who were
growing conventional Fields full full of
food and in order to do that like
organic just it wasn't it wasn't
unsprayed
um organically grown you know fed with
compost and green manure and manure and
all these things it wasn't practical for
them at all because they were at scale
but for like my grandpa who wants to
have like some crates of tomatoes it's
super easy he doesn't you don't ever
have to spray your Tomatoes a gopher
eats like a quarter of your tomato
plants you're like dude we still got so
many it's no big deal but when you have
a massive tomato Farm you're under the
gun what are we going to do what are we
going to use and so it just is you know
it's a bummer but it's no shock when you
see that the biggest guys are the ones
using the most [ __ ] and there and
they're yeah and the thing that sucks
about it is that those are the most
economical people for the brands to
purchase the material they need from
because they have the largest volume and
they can offer the most aggressive
pricing and so a lot of brands are
gravitating towards like the biggest
farms because they have the cheapest
stuff I mean you mentioned glass house
again they have been undercutting hard
because you know um these Brands need
these Farms need to sell stuff on the
legal Market too right and they compete
with each other on how cheap so you come
up here to Mendo or humble and people
want one price you know but there's big
groups down there that like you know he
was just saying you know his friend will
buy it wholesale for a hundred bucks
there's people that'll sell it for
30 yeah which yeah which one are they
going to pick they're like I mean if my
if my buddies didn't have a working
model and they were not ethical the way
that they are because they're cool dudes
but if they weren't like that they could
really easily just go oh so right now
let's just uh let's leave all these guys
hanging for the 100 because they that's
as low as they'll go and let's just go
ahead and go down there and we'll buy
this other weed for 30 but they're not
doing it luckily and they're not going
to change their their pricing wholesale
so they just dropped their their
overhead a ton twoth thirds almost
basically yeah and I mean these guys who
I'm talking about by not doing that
they're probably missing out on another
couple million dollars a year or
whatever you know these guys are killing
it they're doing really good and um
that's a lot of money they're leaving on
the table to be ethical and and you
can't expect everybody to make that same
sacrifice when they crunch the numbers
but you know you can expect more of that
from people who were the people who were
really growing weed and actually like
have an attachment to the ethics of
having a good product because a lot of
people take pride in the fact that
they're giving people the weed that's
making them feel better and they want to
give people good clean weed and so these
guys are still doing that but that there
there's no uh
there's no reason for these huge
companies who don't come from any kind
of a cultural practice at all they just
crunch the numbers they go it's cheaper
to Eagle 20 it it's cheaper to hit it
with this it's cheaper to hit it with
that cheaper to dry it in this many days
all this stuff just to get the prices
down and then they're like yeah our
numbers are up we made more money you
know and it's like well that's cool but
it's one of the reasons why a lot of
times weed was expensive
when it was expensive a lot of people
could have grown a lot more weed but a
lot of the best Growers friends of mine
they looked at it and they we they go we
got a lot of space you know but we don't
have quality drying space for more than
80 or 12 pounds and we could build it
but I tried to grow a little bit extra
and it like everything the quality on
everything was just not quite there I
feel like I'm topped out growing this
much weed and maybe they get some help
and they can grow a little bit more but
when people really have pride in [ __ ]
they're more likely to like want to
stick to a a real number that they know
is where things line up to be topnotch
and a lot of people in the old days you
know were like okay this is what I can
this is what I can manage and there's
still a lot of people like that and
that's like what these guys are buying
the weed from those guys because the
because there's a lot of people who are
like we could grow 25 500 lbs of crap
but we're just going to keep growing 800
pounds we're just G to keep growing you
know 1100 pounds of weed that's coming
out like really how we want it to come
out you know because they're doing that
over three or four runs it's not all at
once so they're having these batches
that are coming off and they're just you
know a few hundred pounds and that's
really manageable with a small team of a
few people you can have the best weed
like that you know it might not be quite
like the lady who you know who has one
you know 600 watt light and you're like
oh I'll buy that to smoke or whatever
but it's still really good weed but I I
know that when you're at huge scale like
that it's just you know even if the weed
seems like it's its best it's GNA fall
off in one one way or another you know
it's gonna it's going to get treated
industrially by something I mean there
could even be a thing and we can move on
again but um the reality is when you're
growing at large egg places most of
those places hire out their sprayers to
come in and spray whatever so there's
even possibilities that like let's say
that five days a week these sprayers are
out there hitting conventional farms and
using different kinds of chemicals and
then they come on your farm and they put
in whatever they're going to spray that
night but there's there's enough residue
in the lines in the tank in the sprayer
in the whatever that like it's it's not
even like a full dose but it's enough to
pop enough one worker I'll tell you that
all those big farms most of them don't
have all their own personal equipment
and their own team out there all night
long they hire it out as a
service most of them and so then what
are those Services doing in their and
all their equipment all those other days
a week that they're spraying
conventional Farms that are allowed to
use all these camps yeah there's even
room for honest mistakes where it's like
we we didn't even want to do that but
there it is there it happen it is it
Happ think that doesn't happen to
somebody like me who was growing a you
know 25 plants medical and had a bunch
of weed on those plants and they were
beautiful and it was just like I didn't
have to do anything like oh one plant's
got tons of bugs just [ __ ] chop it
down if it's not good enough it ain't
good enough who cares you got more you
know and you don't need you don't have
you know when it's you're losing your
whatever 4% right now by chopping this
it's not like you're you know losing 4%
of you
know 400,000 plants or whatever in that
run so yeah totally different
thing look I think we've thoroughly I
think we've thoroughly hashed that one
out um let's change the pace a little
bit I want to talk a little bit about
how Germany recently passed an adult use
Bill I'm sure you guys have heard about
this it was I think probably about 6
months ago maybe getting close to that
now but it's been reported that it has
absolutely opened The Floodgate for CIP
Pacs flooding into Germany anecdotal
Reports say that they're going for
10,000 Euro a pound uh it's not
particularly surprising but I guess the
question is do we think other countries
in the EU are going to follow and as a
followup do we think this might be the
first sign of a global cannabis culture
which is essentially going to eventually
wipe out you know sort of the individual
cultures for a long time you know there
was sort of the Dutch scene more
recently the Spanish scene but I mean if
you take it on face value if if Cal if
California bud is dominating it's it's
hinting that that that may well be the
global culture going forward California
Cannabis culture will be exported all
over the world what do we
think it's I mean this is kind of a
theme I think of what we've been talking
about but like every state in America so
far that goes legal uh it's a grand
mystery what happens to its its
excess right and it is going to start
going all over the place I mean I know
that like when they opened up Thailand
last year all of a sudden there was all
these California Brands and people and
opening stores and there was jars of
purple weed over there you know and it
wasn't all traditional Tow and Li and
Cambodian you know sativas and that
stuff it was it's going to go places and
I think that's just the nature of like
you know it's really sad but like I was
reading about how like you know there's
barely any Moroccan weed left in
Morocco it's all Dutch and Spanish
Imports and they give them all that's
where they're getting their seed stock
and that's what they're growing and then
they're turning that into hash and then
it's going back into Europe and so I
think probably like it's a good time to
say that rules are rules but then
there's always going to be if there's
profit involved and there's this and
that involved there's always going to be
people bending them and uh it sounds
funny to think that like America would
have an excess of something that it
would be smuggling into other countries
because we're usually the gobbler that
just takes the world's supply of sub es
and send it here for money uh but I
guess we could reverse the stream and
start sending um you know packs all over
the place and uh you know I think every
country and every state that wants to
legalize is going to have to deal with
the fact that there's this robust
underground you know and I don't know
how that's all going to shake out but
it's going to every place it's it's
every place it's going to it's going to
be
different you
know I mean I would imagine since
Holland is right next door wouldn't
there be a bunch of weed from Holland
and Switzerland that would start to pour
into Germany like on a more on a on a
you know I mean You' think that
too their production just can't keep up
I wonder but I guess I'm interested you
know like historically the Dutch scene
you know people would say oh you know
hazes and um she some of these more
European oriented VAR would generally be
considered to be kind of the the
prevalent strains in the Zeitgeist
whereas you don't see that you know it
seems as though C like let's just be
blunt like gelardo runs these household
Nam strains it feels like they're going
to become the dominant and synonymous
names with these regions and I wonder if
we'll lose that sort of more localized
culture that you know like I think his
yeah yeah I mean to go back to what we
were talking about before about huge
farms over producing is those things you
just mentioned part of the reason why
gelato and runts and these different
things have swept so much is because the
largest Farms are growing them and so
there's just more production of those
Str like the amount of that being grown
just dwarfs anything else like once
you've got a bunch of huge farms growing
purple candy gas and all of a sudden
purple candy gas starts showing up in
every Market legal and illegal and gray
and whatnot it just floods what's out
there to some degree so it's like
whether or not people want it that's
what's happening you know and there's
only the weird thing about the
California Market that people might not
know is that most Farms are flowering
farms and they end up buying their
clones from a nursery and they don't get
these huge lists where they can just
choose 50 or 80 strains most nurseries
are like for the next four months these
are the 12 strains we
offer and we're going to be cutting
clones off them regularly and selling
them repeatedly to all kinds of
different farms and there's only so many
big nurseries so a few big nurseries and
a few big farms if they decide to start
to grow certain things all of a sudden
it's all jealousy gelato runs various
hybrids and that's what most people see
because that's the vast volume being
grown yeah you know there then there's a
there's the feedback loop too of like um
you know it's like whatever is uh the
most
popular with people in general like you
know it
always it always comes down to like when
people show up like when they're going
to buy all the weed what are they asking
for and so when there starts to be a
trend of people going okay well we want
this then people are like okay I got to
grow that and a lot of times it'll swing
like people will finally catch on to the
trend and they'll grow that and then
it'll be like no that's the old [ __ ] now
yeah oh no we're not going to give you
that money sh so hard and the weed takes
so long to flower and get processed and
everything so a lot of times it'll be
like oh it's you know everybody wants
you know the original one really was
everybody wants purple urle then a
sudden people started showing up and
they're like no we don't want that
anymore we only want sour and then
people were like no sour is not [ __ ] we
don't want that we want OG then people
shift over to OG and then people start
being like no we don't want OG we want
cookies then people had cookies and
everybody started going no no we want
sherbet we want we want Skittles we want
whatever it was and it kept going you
know Skittles and then it went we want
runs and then we want Lemon Cherry
gelato which is just runs and then like
it kept going to the point where now
it's like witch runs which Lemon Cherry
gelato and it's like this bag seed cut
that is a little bit more like this or
whatever but the problem with it is
that um when people go to sell their
weed they have to have the weed that
people want to buy and what people tend
to want to buy is the weed you know that
the easiest thing to understand is
always going to be what sells the best
so like you're not going to like make a
jazz album right now with a bunch of
[ __ ] you know math music where you
have to like know the theory to know
what it is and but it's like that [ __ ]
to musicians is crazy they're like oh
did you hear that you know and that
would be like you know me and Francis
looking at some weird ly Haze hybrid
that you smoke it and you're like oh no
what have I done you know but like the
market is going to want you know
bubblegum pop they're going to want like
the music that is the most relatable
that's the most accessible and very weed
is very pretty looking and very frosty
purple weed is very pretty looking and
then when it smells really crazy like
whoa that doesn't smell I expect wheed
to smell like hay and I expect it when
it's really good to smell like like kind
of skunky and fuy or something and then
people smell weed that smells like crazy
C gas per and they're like whoa this is
just so far from what I expected that it
has this knee-jerk reaction where people
are like that's what I want then once
they like it they know what they like
and then they're just like people are
creatures of habit they just stick to it
so when buyers show up they're like they
look at everything and they're like uh I
just want the Obama runs I just want the
Lemon Cherry gelato they don't even want
to look at any of the other stuff you
show it to them they go yeah no that's
not it and then they smell something
they go that's got some of it and what
they're talking about is just the thing
that they know really sold for them fast
and then it becomes this endless
feedback loop where like the the buyers
want this so the grower wants this so
the nursery supplies this and pretty
soon you get stuck in the loop and all
of a sudden then you get the people who
are like I really want to smoke some of
that weed like that [ __ ] I got back in
the day I don't even know what it was
and you know in the in there like you
know [ __ ] I I don't want to smoke no
[ __ ] like blue dream or no [ __ ]
you know and then like if you actually
showed it to them they go this is that
[ __ ] from back in the day and you'd go
yeah that was the real blue dream cut
the one that's the weed that you liked
that you never could find because all it
you know blueberry Haze when blue dreams
stopped selling and now you've never
known what your favorite weed is and of
course some people hate that weed but
some people hate runs you know like it's
it's a Trippy you know it's a weird Loop
that people get stuck in though maybe
one angle that we could talk about for a
second with Germany and then pop off to
the next thing is that Germany is a big
very populated very wealthy country so
for them opening up to weed if they drop
the penalties for weed quite a bit there
could be this big demand of all these
people that want cannabis but there's
not the supply within Germany at all to
give them that and there's excess over
here in America so straight capitalism
is just basically like oh well there's
excess over here and there's demand over
there the Invisible Hand is going to
come pull it and there's going to find a
way that it's going to show up and so
it's probably temporary it's probably
going to bridge the gap until Germany
gets its own sort of little engine going
right and then those prices will drop
but probably what happened is they
loosened the penalties a huge surge in
demand not that much Supply and The
Surge got the price up to a bunch of
people were like oh I I have a clever
way I think I could make that happen and
loow and
behold you know the excess gets to where
the the drought is yeah I think that's
kind of it's B it's it's like that's
like classic that's like Adam Smith that
you learn in grade school or whatever
about like how capitalism works yeah
right like yeah it's like alcohol
prohibition you know all of a sudden it
was like oh well did you know Ireland is
still making stuff so how do we get that
here so they would bring it in to Canada
and then over the lake I'll use I'll use
a right now weed example dude when I was
out in New York setting some stuff up
when they went
legal they distillate was going for
$8,000 a liter in New York but you could
buy distillate for6 or $700 a liter in
California and if you don't think that
there were some entrepreneurs somewhere
that that made some cheap California
distillate show up in expensive New York
past his New York distillate and they
made 10 times their money you're nuts
yeah people figured out how to do that
on some level that's what an
entrepreneur is looking for they're
going okay where's the where's the
supply of something and the and the
market for something else and there's a
difference and when there's a difference
then you're the one who comes in and
capitalizes on the difference and it's a
huge you know a huge thing and that yeah
but talking about the um talking about
the the way that everything moved
towards being like Oh it's all you know
like now the market the buyers The
Growers the nurseries the runs the Lemon
Cherry gelato all that that's like a
smaller version of what I think just
kind of always is in is happening all
the time with um because what I didn't
say about those things too is that all
those things are easier to grow a lot of
people don't know that it's not hard to
produce weed that looks like the weed
you want from those things if you grow
sour diesel a good Sour Diesel grower
might tell you yeah it's going to be one
or two out of four runs you know three
or four out of five runs that are going
to come off the way you really want it
but when you grow like gelato or a lot
of these things like they just kind of
come out how they come out pretty close
and so they're really easy to produce a
lot of and I think uh worldwide that's
where the Trends have gone a lot over
the years was it was like okay you have
like this weed if you take it over here
you can grow it here you can take weed
from India take it to Jamaica it grows
really good there now you have this big
Supply now it goes here now that
influences what everybody thinks of as
weed that's their first in New York the
first weed you got when in Miami the
first weed you got was this Jamaican you
know so you know what that is and that
like sets a paradigm and then and then
the California weed started and it was
like okay what everyone can grow
everywhere it turns out are these
afghanis or these afghanis that are
crossed with a Colombian or a Mexican or
a Tai or whatever it is and then that
becomes the thing that's easy to over
produce and that becomes the understood
thing of like okay so for production we
want to do something like this and so
then everywhere you go everybody's
constantly all around the world it's
like everybody's trying to always keep
up with okay what is the best way to do
this and where does this thing work and
where does that thing work and I think
like now that everything's been in the
US for so long and the US it takes up a
pretty big chunk of of the you know
basically when you're when you're
looking at like the the the area that it
takes up when you look at it you go okay
well you can grow pretty crazy weed in
Southern California that you can't maybe
grow in Montana but there's something
you can grow everywhere and so the US
has become a place where it's a really
good place to figure out what those
possibilities are and so it's going to
be hard I think to ever get out of what
you're talking about where it is going
to dictate a lot of the trends and it is
going to dictate a lot of the greater
the world uh the weed world because it's
always been that but the United States
has been a little bit more successful
with figuring out these things and if
you look at the way that like um animal
crops or grain crops food crops were
when you when you had like Eurasia you
know because now we go oh well you got
Europe over here and you have Asia over
here and it's like well when you look at
the map it's all one place just like the
United States is all one place it
stretches from way over here to way over
there it stretches from way up here to
way down here here and so all of our all
of the food Trends and everything are
the most most not all of them but a lot
of the most popular ones all came from
over there because it's like this is
this place where you can grow these
things over a big uh area and have a lot
of um you know there there's a lot of
like Evolution going on with culture
with these particular things and that
happened a lot with weed in um the US so
like I think like like naturally Germany
is going to be more likely to mimic the
US than where else would they mimic like
the Congo or southeast Asia or it's like
more likely whatever is the most
successful is going to continue to just
be the model and so I won't be surprised
if everywhere that everywhere that sets
up new legalization a lot of them are
going to look to the US and go how do
those guys do it over there you know
people will even look at Colombia and
Mexico um anywhere that play people have
been real successful uccessful with this
particular kind of crop is going to be
like you know going to kind of set a lot
of the pace in all those places for
sure well look we uh we quickly
referenced it earlier in the answer so
why don't we quickly touch on our next
story uh which is that you know we spoke
in one of the prior episodes about
Thailand reversing their stance well
guess what they have done yet another
reversal on their reversal signaling
that they may indeed not re criminalize
cannabis this is obviously a breath of
fresh air for many of the people who
have set up operation over there after
the initial calls for Banning it
happened a few months ago it's not
entirely clear what the new plan exactly
will be but the overall message is that
it's largely speaking going to remain
legal I guess I'm wondering do we think
this will stick do we think there might
be yet another u-turn on the u-turn on
the U-turn and as an extension do we
think other Asian countries will
progress towards legalization or is this
a sign of the general
instability I mean I was going to say it
about Germany but I can say it about
Thailand too it's good for obviously
people that believe what we do when
large populist countries decide to like
that their approach to cannabis is
misguided and they need to like you know
decriminalize it Legalize It change
their approach to it treat it in a much
better fashion so in general I think
these big countries deciding to like
take it from you know a criminal side
and be like oh it's normal I think
that's huge I think Thailand got
scared because I can tell you from just
a bunch of people I know that as soon as
they opened up they got flooded with
foreigners looking to take advantage of
the new weed rules and that's sort of
going to happen in places as they open
up is essentially cannabis people from
oversaturated markets are going to look
at that and be like oh I could go there
and kill it for a minute and they're
going to flood in I mean to be honest
mean jeene and I saw that happen in
Mendo like once people really we passed
this law called measure G which made us
pretty much like the most open place to
grow weed in America and I would say
starting about 03 or ' 04 like the
floodgates opened of people moving here
to blow it up and go big and I'm sure
the same thing happened in Thailand it
like overwhelmed all of a sudden it went
from like it always existed to like holy
crap it's
everywhere and it caused our real estate
to boom and Spike around here it created
an enormous
bubble and I know literally probably
over a dozen people just personally that
went to Thailand to blow it up and to
and to and to change these laws and so
I'm sure there there was thousands of
people that went there and so they
probably got a bit freaked
out at how fast things exploded clamp
down for a minute then realize they
didn't really want to clamp down they
just need to figure out a path
forward you know um and I think that's
probably going to keep happening because
look at what we just talked about 10K
weed in Germany Germany like takes its
foot off the gas a little bit and all of
a sudden there's crazy like it's just
going to keep happening until more and
more of these places like go through it
I think and so it's good that it's
spreading because Asia has some of the
absolutely most Draconian drug laws like
there's places that you land and they're
like if we find you with this we'll just
kill you like we just and that it's like
it's just on the sign you know they're
not they don't mess around so it would
be good at least for some of the lesser
lesser harmful ones especially cannabis
for them to take a more normalized
approach what's really funny is that
it's likely that those places over there
were mostly influ I mean sometimes it's
not the case because sometimes it's
religion or or whatever is going on but
a lot of the reason why like the whole
War on Drugs has
affected uh cannabis is it's because of
us and us being America and we basically
like went around the world and said hey
like if you guys are going to be smoking
all this dope don't [ __ ] think that
you know you can just count on us for
[ __ ] and you know if uh you guys [ __ ]
around a little worse we're we're not
going to show any Mercy because you got
the you know like they we've pushed
those drug laws as the American
government has pushed those drug laws on
the whole world and it's crazy because
um it's a real it's a real weird form of
insanity when you um make a war on
something that is not actually dangerous
unethical immoral there's really nothing
wrong with wheat it's just a plant it'd
be like if there was a war on corn right
now people would be like this is so
strange I mean the weird thing about
that too is that at least in America we
didn't really have a cannabis tradition
but southeast Asia does yeah they
literally had a
longstanding you know tradition yeah but
you convince part their cure yeah you
convince one generation anywhere that
something is super immoral and dangerous
and all of a sudden they're like oh man
I don't want our kids doing that this is
crazy like this is going to destroy our
country or you know the people who are
incentivized by that because they want
you know foreign Aid or because they
want to just at least be in good
standing internationally in the
community like they basically go oh well
we can't we we don't want to be like
this country that's left and you know
we're still our everybody else has moved
past this and we're still doing this
like we need to step into the Step Into
the Now into the modern times so we need
to start enforcing these laws that these
other countries are enforcing and you
wind up with this weird thing but what's
crazy about it is that um
when you make something up like that
it's not like like you can go anywhere
in the world basically and they're like
hey guess what it's not legal to steal
people's [ __ ] unless you're maybe like
in California or something it's
loosening up a lot but you go places
that are like it doesn't matter where
you go people know that certain things
are immoral dangerous and unethical
basically anywhere in the world you go
you can't steal people's [ __ ] and
anywhere you go in the world you can't
kill people
senselessly anywhere you go you know
like there's these certain things that
everybody can agree like these are bad
things and so when you enforce against
them it all makes sense but when you
make a huge War that's enforced by
violence and threats of violence and and
you know turning people into captives
and all this [ __ ] and then you only have
it in some places then you cause this
odd type of insanity where people leap
frog from where it's acceptable to where
it's acceptable to where it's acceptable
and there's all this weird change in the
prices and values of everything because
over here now it's like still kind of
considered bad but you can get away with
it so that's where the big prices right
and then where it's where it's but but
it's not dangerous enough to keep people
from wanting to do it and so the thing
that happened to us right was people we
should mention that's been going on
forever yeah like Holland got started
because permissive California and
America started cracking down on the
drug war and sending helicopters and all
these breeders fled to this like
essentially cold gray kind of dark place
but it was more permissive and then as
soon as Switzerland opened up they
flooded into there and then as soon as
Spain opened up they flooded into there
one point I want to say before I forget
is that one of the positives about
Thailand is that their climate is so
different that it is very very unlikely
that purple candy gas is going to take
over in Thailand for a length of time
because that [ __ ] will rot there they
are going to need to develop different
cultivars that grow well in a hot humid
thick climate and a lot of the runs and
a lot of that kind of stuff I don't
think is going to and that kind of uber
dense cxes and buds I don't think it's
going to go over well there unless you
have some very expensive climate
controlled situations so they should
they might end up there might be some
places as they loosen up where they
become like areas where sativas are
cultivated simply because that's what
works in the climate that they're in
you know it really could be because I
don't see like I don't see in Thailand I
mean I don't know if Thailand is a lot
of like it's 90 to 95 degrees and of
over 80%
humidity you can pull off more than you
would imagine there like I gave a a
friend of mine back in the day a bunch
of different seeds and the only things
he couldn't grow in Thailand was the
stuff that was uh monkey balls hybrids
yeah those he couldn't grow there that
extreme Afghan and I was like you could
grow the other stuff he's like yeah I
grew candleabra I grew the lime I grew
you know he was able to pretty much pull
off everything but not you know he
wasn't a commercial grower either you
know the the Monkey Ball stuff that we
could get away with growing here that's
still challenging for mold and
everything he was like the whole plant
mold the whole thing just melted you
know um but uh but the other stuff was
like yeah you know he got a little bit
of mold but he was able to he was able
to grow it so you can get away with
stuff that you might think wouldn't
wouldn't work but I don't think on a big
enough level that it would that you'd
want to have that be what you supplied
over you know something that was like a
more um narrow Leaf equatorial at least
influenced you know they can make
hybrids though the same way we did here
yeah take that stuff they will make
hybrids I just mean that they'll they'll
probably try to like but I was even
thinking about like New York and stuff
like that like should probably be
looking into like Canadian genetics for
their outdoor stuff that did well in
southern Canada and survived well not
necessarily bone dry California and just
trying to like take that over and switch
switch it yeah but that kept happening
too there was this famous thing uh Sam
talked about it a long time ago where
most of the Afghans that got brought
over from Afghanistan and Pakistan early
in like the late 70s and 80s and stuff
over here
a lot of them
molded and because they came from a much
more mountainous dry climate and a lot
of the Afghans that like got famous or
got well known were simply the ones that
didn't rot and didn't breed rot into the
sativas they were mixing them with yep
you know so that kind of stuff
matters figuring out what suits where
you're at I so I think it's awesome that
Thailand I think it's awesome that land
is is uh is loosening up and I hope it's
it
spreads you know and I think it could
last if it's you know the the big the
big thing was that I think you know like
you said we talked about it on a
different episode that we did but it I
was just saying like [ __ ] Americans
you know like just run well we have
power too because if we made it legal I
bet it would go legal in a lot of places
and then there would be a lot of
countries that already get a lot of
money in American tourism and they'd be
perfectly content to just sell us weed
too when we're there on
vacation I think places like Colombia
and all those guys down there are
eagerly anticipating America loosening
up even
further and that's why they're there
that American money-making Market drives
a lot you know how many Americans go to
Thailand you know how many Europeans go
to Thailand to party and have a good
time
a lot yeah and they probably would be
totally down to buy weed while they're
there especially if they could do it
legally and not get in trouble or go to
tie jail it'd probably explode and then
there'd be all this excess imported
pouring in money coming in it' just be
another tourism thing yeah it should be
great you know it should be great like
in and when you look at it and it's just
like well you know just it's got to be
handled right I guess but yeah hopefully
it hope hopefully it can stay in cuz
it's you know there's nothing wrong with
it that's for
sure there you go nothing wrong with all
right um look in other news let's jump
to the next story uh let me get the
banner up all right here we go
so where's our
picture the Californian government has
announced that a special California task
force has seized over 2.2 million
illegal cannabis packages all of which
they deemed to be too similar to being
marketed as candy for children now they
say specifically these packages were
designed to mimic popular food and candy
brands and the concern was raised that
you know it's obviously going to appeal
to kids this is obviously nothing new
we've been aware of this for a very long
time I guess the question becomes when
you can actually see the numbers this is
just over a short period of time They
seized this I don't believe it was over
a oneyear period I think it was just
over like a short t targeted intensive
period where they scan the ma and the
companies uh they pulled up this many
you know a surprisingly large number so
I guess the question is do we think the
trend's going to slow down and more
importantly you know we heard of people
getting ceas and assist for copying
certain brands but it seems like it
might be getting to the point where even
the companies would be too overwhelmed
to really try to tackle all of it
especially when you consider that um you
know and no no shade being thrown here
out buddy sticker farmer he probably has
many customers who have products similar
to what we're talking about you know
somewhat similar in marketing do we
think it's just going to just overwhelm
the companies and will just people will
just stop even trying to Market it where
do we go from
here yeah I mean I think there's
a I don't know there's an interesting
thing
like
in in music like if you imagine
imagine like people sample
People's music right somebody takes like
oh I'm going to take this little piece
and it's like oh you can't clear it
you'll see there there there will still
be like places where it's like Kanye
took this song and he didn't clear it
and you're like he knows better he has
all the lawyers as but it's like if
somebody knows that they have a hit
they're going to get a lot of momentum
off of the hit until they get shut down
so it's like like imagine the difference
between having a package that is just
very simple and nobody really notices it
and people don't really want it but it's
totally honest and legit and it's done
the right way and it's all by the book
and then you don't really sell anything
versus you have a package that sells
like hot cakes right now for a little
while and then it gets shut down
like a lot of people are going to go
ahead and go with that package that they
probably shouldn't really use but they
know that it's gonna hit and so they're
like all right well we'd rather get a
lot of momentum for six months than have
a brand that's going to just trickle in
for the next 20 years like what's the
point because it's not even going to
sustain sustain itself so a lot of
people will just keep going from one
thing to the next going oh this is a hot
idea this is a hot idea and they'll just
basically either kind of steal things or
twak them a little bit or you know do
something and have it be like oh it's
cartoony you can't do that because
that's not how you can but they're like
yeah but like this this is what's
testing the best like with people people
see this they buy it so they're just
like all right just run this up and just
do it and do it and do it and then be
like all right that's it that's as much
as we could do with it now we're screwed
and then you also have a lot of people
who um there's no way to know what it is
anyway like there's you can imagine like
hash when people used to sell stamped
hash bricks for a long time and they
never they never knew who did it they
just knew that it was there and they
would find it and they'd be like oh it's
a big mystery we don't know who's making
the whatever hash you know and uh so
that's the case too so like the people
who are known and their faces on it and
they're like all right when we get a
cease and assist we'll stop and then
there's the people who are like they'll
never know who we are anyway let's just
keep selling this product you know so I
mean that's how that's how I see that
kind of thing going as far as the basics
of it you know I I don't want to sound
like old man yells at cloud or anything
but I will say that uh with
legalization the type of artwork and and
the colors and all that I'm not we're
not trying to Market to children or
anything like that but it is very bright
and it is kind of cartoony and it is
exaggerated a lot um and I also say just
totally different that like for a long
time weed was essentially underground in
counterculture and so we a lot of weed
names and a lot of things were sort of
takes
on culture Cinderella 99 you know that's
all fine and good until all of a sudden
it's legal and Disney is like wait we we
own Cinderella what what is this this is
some no no no no no no you know and that
just I don't want to you know I could go
over example example example but we in
cannabis for a long time a lot of
cannabis things got were sort of plays
on more popular culture and we got away
with it because we were
underground but as you get trademarked
and as you get legal and as you get all
these different things things you start
bumping into and like mean jeene is
right in the sense that people are just
going to do it and be underground but
then you can probably as a company and
we've seen this a few times rise to a
level that you're big enough that they
care and they shut you
down you know thin mint cookies went to
cookies there was a reason for that you
know a certain candy went to
Z there was a reason for that but you
almost have to get big enough and
wellknown enough that your merch and
everything like that is sort of
percolating up enough so that big
company with the copyright you know or
the trademark or whatever like actually
notices you you can probably do a bunch
trapping before it bubbles up Yeah by
that point yeah even if you get rid of
that like you've already that's like
what I told the Z that's what I told the
Z guys what I told Tony I was like it
was it was well worth it like now you
just change it a little bit it's
established and it got everybody know
everybody you need to know what they
know what it is yeah and then you drop
it and then you know what it is and
great Best of Both Worlds you know like
if that's what it takes to have
something get momentum it's like cool
give it that momentum and then all you
have to do is be like oh yeah it used to
be called that you've heard of that this
is that cool it got momentum you know
with Edibles it was huge like when
everything was still medical I think
Colorado was the first state to go Rec
recreational and as soon as they went
recreational um people came into their
stores and almost all the Edibles got
pulled off because all the artwork was
bites off Reese's or Rice Krispie treats
or it was really really really obvious
takes on other kinds of food that those
trademarks are like all well established
and decades old and so they just came in
and swept it and then people had to
figure out like well what kind of art
can I use what kind of name can I use
that like might skate close where
everybody that's my customer knows it's
kind of tongue and cheek but it doesn't
like cross the line where we're going to
be battling these $500 an hour lawyers
from the Mars Corporation yeah you know
and I think he's right that's just going
to keep happening and they're going to
keep there's no there's no reason to
Market weed to kids there's nobody in
weed that cares about selling to kids
that's like a terrible Trope but they
might want
bright cartoony things that grab the eye
so that adults will purchase it that's
really what it is it's just bright ey
grabbing artwork because most of the
stuff is being sold in myar anyway it's
not like you're touching it and smelling
it and and um and seeing it or whatever
so it's all just it's all the myar is
sort of like your
ad right yeah and there there's there's
also in this whole argument there's a
generation gap learning curve right so
imagine this that there was a certain
period of time when
cartoons were for kids Boomers look at
cartoons and they go those came out when
we were kids or they came out when my
parents were kids in the case of like
the older
cartoons but people who are from later
Generations their parents grew up with
cartoons and they never stopped watching
them cartoons are not inherently related
adult anymore that's a boomer
perspective that's a pre- boomer
perspective so when you see something
that has colorful characters and it's
cartoony and it's all this it's like no
guys that's the people who are now in
their 50s and their 40s and their 30s
they grew up with cartoons but their
parents still watched cartoons possibly
and cartoons are made now for adults and
there's been ever since the 60s there's
been tons of cartoons that were made for
adults specifically and that is a later
phenomenon and so the people who are
looking at it and going oh cartoons
that's for kids it's like there's not
anything anymore at all that says
cartoons are for kids kids aren't even
that into cartoons relative to what kids
like Mr Beast kids like streamers like
it'd be different if it was like oh this
is the kais sonat packaging this is you
know video game packaging that maybe
would be a little more related to kids
but cartoony stuff like cereal boxes
that's not the thing anymore those
things are old those are the things that
The Regulators think kids are into and
they don't even know what kids are into
because they they're people regulating
all this [ __ ] don't even have kids
anymore their kids are all my age now
you know what I mean like my my my
generation and mean we probably got up
at 600 or 7 in the morning on Saturday
to watch cartoons yes right but my kids
don't do that they don't have to like
wake up they can stream you know they
don't have to wake up at a certain time
they think it like that that that is
like wild to them so you know but it is
it is there is a whole thing of like all
these companies realized well what do
you mean half the weed names are plays
on our trademarks yeah because that just
kept happening all kinds of different
things you know I mean there's even like
there's even weed strains named after
famous
actors you know and stuff like that
there's we we we borrow from all kinds
of culture we grab whatever we want we
put our own twist on it we always did no
one could tell everyone told us we were
wrong anyway so we just did whatever we
wanted and now that it's going legal
it's like oh it's you're we're going to
bump into this stuff and then the other
part of it is that I don't really see
cannabis like other drugs but there's
always been this Trope in America that
drug people want to push their their
wees onto
children right and I like there's no
cannabis people that could get like that
doesn't there's no there was never any
like oh let's hit the high school with
you know this or like let's give homie
the dime bags in Middle School like that
was never even never on anyone's radar
ever it never occurred that was some
like fever dream cooked up in some Far
Away place that they had no idea but it
exists yeah dare were dare was the was
the people who brought all the drugs to
your school it wasn't anybody else they
were the only ones who showed up and
went hey have you ever seen and they
showed up in a sports car and you were
like dang they have a nice ride where
they they got that that dude got a
Corvette whoa you know
all glued to one board man this dude's
balling you know like that's crazy never
seen so many I never didn't even I
didn't even know what these drugs were
you know
like a Thor introduction I guess yeah uh
and you know it it probably will change
because right now we're in the purple
candy gas era of California Cannabis so
I would imagine candy themes every name
not every name there's some people out
there that are changing but right now
we're certainly in the can I call my
weed a candy or
dessert it's very heavily in that vein
and so you know also like mean jeene was
saying with video games a lot of older
or ancient adults that are making our
laws associate candy with
kids why would an adult eat
candy you know uh they if you told them
that the most famous weed in California
right now was stuff that was purple
candy gas they would be baffled at what
that even meant
you
know they probably might think it's like
in response to
Children yeah and generationally you
know there was you know there was there
was a certain time when there was so
much of that stuff basically when I
think it was Reagan made it legal to
advertise to children and so anybody who
was an adult in that era the people who
were adults in the 80s in the early 80s
are the people who who think that all
this advertising to children is
advertising to children but what they
don't realize is that all those children
who were advertised to then are now 40
something 50 years old and they are
still like that stuff all looks normal
to them so like if you show me something
that has like a cool cartoon character
on it I'm like oh that's pretty cool
like you can put like Skeletor on some
[ __ ] and I'm oh that sounds dope it's
your shit's called skelet
like damn that's probably hardcore you
know what I mean and it sounds cool to
me but like they would go oh well that's
for kids and it's like no kids it's not
kids don't know Skeletor it's not just
because it was a cartoon from then it's
not like that is what's hip with the
young kids now you know but they people
don't know
it's yeah they don't realize that like
kids today probably don't care about
Skeletor but there's all these cartoons
that classify that qualify as
Nostalgia yeah for people like our AG
it's for adults yeah yeah a 10-year-old
doesn't
care like what is what you like you know
like you can see behind me I you can see
what my art is for my brand there's no
weed in it it has nothing to do with
weed it's a seed it's a seed brand it's
a apparel brand it can be whatever it is
it is what it is and I made it that way
because I like to have it be something
like oh yeah my kid can wear the shirt
to school it could be whatever it is if
you know what it is you know what it is
you know it's very very much a weed
thing but it isn't it isn't like
cartoony there's nothing like that that
was how I wanted my thing to look but if
I see something that's super super
cartoony like it's it's it's like it's a
weird definition so you go so what is a
cartoon is that a cartoon it's handdrawn
it's not photo realistic it's
stylized it has bright colors is it a
cartoon I don't know for a while they
said that you couldn't have any animals
and I was like so my hummingbird is this
this is is this what kids want to this
is what kids are into is a humming bird
up here I don't think so but if it was
more cartoony does that is that
inherently appeal the CH to to to the
child mind I don't I just don't get it
you know like the whole the whole thing
is trippy you know like is this a
cartoon it's an animal it's handrawn
like look at old cartoons look at like
Snow White it's almost photorealistic in
some cases there's only a little bit of
caricature added to certain things the
backgrounds are totally realistic like
the whole the whole thing is really
strange the definitions and the more the
more they try to Define it the more
they're going to wind up going oh [ __ ]
we just need to put serial numbers on
everything and then at that point you're
like just Tak everything out of the
product and the marketing so I think the
whole thing's goofy as [ __ ] myself but
that's just my take on it you
know no certainly and look it seems like
there's sort of endless degrees of which
you can try to nitpick at it which I
completely understand one of the things
notso dog said that I think is a great
segue is that you know the fact we're in
the purple candy gas error of course
lends itself to the fact that you're
going to see this sort of marketing but
as it so
happens excuse more one of the major
movers and shakers Mr DOA himself Has
Come Out Swinging
saying the age of candy is over he says
biscotti soap gelonade permanent
marker is uh is what people are
requesting at the moment he says that
candy is not on the menu what do you
guys
think it's kind of a vague definition
like I consider all those things to be
um to be
candy you know to me I mean I don't say
I don't think that they're like
exclusively gassy I mean they are nice
and gasy don't get me wrong they smell
good they smell acrid they're nice
everything to me smells like the very
best of
um of like the really really cool
afghanis from back in the day like
uh not so NOS like the thing that they
called FX up here is very close to what
now everybody calls the candy gas or the
purple gas of now and meaning like past
the candy where it's the gasier side um
that kind of like acrid with that
interesting edge of soapiness and the
kind of like this deep kind of musky
there's this certain profile that you
know if you know it from way back in the
day and uh it was like things that pop
out of certain purple afghanis you know
the most special of the deep chunk the
monkey balls that's really the rare ones
in there um this thing I had called Big
Blue some of the stuff that would pop
out like even now when I did all the
Hindu s1s there's these things that pop
out and I'm like oh they smell like
really like they're kind of in that
ballpark
but it's still so similar all that weed
is so similar to just like cookies
gelato weed like it's not that different
to say that all of a sudden now
everything is totally flipped it's a new
paradigm I'm like it is just more of the
same [ __ ] weed like it's literally
all the same weed that I grew up with
90s I anything new it's really good
they're good versions but like I'm
literally pulling out of these ones that
I just cut down down I'm smelling them
and I'm like there's that thing there's
that thing I mean this is jarro Sensei
this is sensey Star Cross Sensi Star
Cross jaro and then I crossed it with
Hindu this smells really similar to
those things like permanent marker or
the other things with the musk the soap
the little bit of that Afghani cookies
underlying thing that like if you know
that kind of weed you know that kind of
weed and to me
I'm just like it's just we've been stuck
there we've been stuck there since
[ __ ] animal cookies in my opinion
it's all the same thing and now if you
haven't seen that original type by
itself then you can't see that
everything is a quarter that but if you
know that type you see that it's just
all modulating this one type and it's
just like this swirling thing of them
dancing around this [ __ ] thing that's
all the same weed and I honestly for
myself have no problem with it because
that weed from back in the day that t
that type was always kind of my favorite
that was really hard to lock down and I
really [ __ ] liked it and all all my
buddy had something that was
uh oh I can't remember what it was but
it was like it was something he made and
it was like Jokers crossed
with I want to say like cookies and
cream or something like that and he
handed me a butt and I went that's that
[ __ ] that came out out of that weed I
had that first Garden in the 90s that
with that coffee smell that almost
smells a little bit like Sharpie markers
like kind of opium and I'm smelling and
I'm going I [ __ ] love this type and
it's just so funny because it's just
more [ __ ] cookies weed it's all the
same it's all that thing and I love it
but to say that like it's all flipped on
its head now and it's like yeah maybe
now Skittles isn't the biggest thing and
people want things that are like a
variation of biscotti or they want like
this variation like all those things to
me when I smell them all I'm kind of
like that's it's not like it's that it's
not like it's that different it's not
like you smelled um it's not like you
smelled Jack and then you smelled
Skittles or you smelled OG and then you
smelled purple Urkle it's like no it's
it's all really close together to me
it's in a tight Target of what like
you're breeding in my opinion but
everybody I don't know it's not and it's
not to say that it's really same I'm
just saying that it's all a quarter the
same and then everything is different
around it on this Frame of this old
Afghan smell I have a quick thought and
a long thought my quick thought because
you made me stare at that picture for a
long time is I don't have a diamond
watch that makes me look cool when I
want to smoke joints and have people
take pictures of me but it seems very
important to have diamond watches down
in SoCal and be part of the weed scene
uh there's a lot of uh nice watch going
going on status symbols and you know
yeah and two I mean dude I think that
you
know the reality of it is is that
cookies became some of the most popular
weed and it became popular at a time
when people started reversing Cuts
specific Cuts onto other cuts and so we
just went through like what he was
saying at length about everything kind
of being the same same is we this
running joke that like a lot of times
when people are like oh look at this new
new and it's same same it's like there's
only so many variations of like cookie
gelato OG hybrids all using the same 8
to 10 cuts in different combinations
blending themselves together there might
be really nice weed that comes out of
that sometime but because weed boomed
and changed around then it's going to
take real effort
like I would imagine do is going to be
like oh the age of candy is over and
here's like eight new kind of candish
strains that are different but the same
and it's almost like feeding people more
of the same genre of music but trying to
say it's
groundbreaking right there's so many
breeders and there's so many people
whose start was using things that were
heavily made out of the same few Cuts
it's going to take some time to Branch
out because a lot of people those are
the ones they had access to when they
started working right and so it's just
flooded with all this same stuff you
know and it's like you know uh there's
thin mint but then you know sherbet is
thin mint you know and then gelato is
sherbet by Thin Mint and then you know
and you start adding various four or
five different OG cuts and you start
adding these different purples and stuff
and they get a million names but if you
scale it all back the genetics really
aren't that wide and that is become like
sort of the bulk Market there's plenty
of cool people that have access to like
heirlooms or stuff that are completely
outside that thing but we're like Creeks
you know we're not the main river we're
not the main tributary we're like an
offshoot the main tributary is this so
even if dudes like that over it would be
a scramble like I don't know what the
next big thing is because the market has
changed so much there's not the way that
everything became a big thing is
different you know like almost
every almost every famous Elite started
in some small group people liked the
smoke it grew it it got it sold for a
bunch of money more people wanted it
because of the money it started growing
Brokers started asking for it and that's
how the first wave of purple or that's
how the Hindu or that's how the northern
lights or that's how the white family or
that's how the you know the sour or the
cookie or Skittles worked but now we
have modern marketing so it's like where
is the next wave of weed going to Bubble
Up from there's there's a lot of same
same right now and so for things to
really be different it's going to have
to come it's going to literally honestly
have to be somebody like you know we I
mean we can mention a bunch of names but
it's going to have to be somebody
like different that comes out with
something different that just breaks
through and becomes popular and then
honestly what's going to happen is that
thing is going to get a million
variations with names attached like if
mean jeene came out and his Yaro by
Whatever by whatever became the next big
thing people would take it and reverse
it and copy it and buy seeds of it and
cross it to different things and make
their own versions of it and then that
would dominate for a bit so I don't know
where it's going to go because the whole
method of things getting popular has
changed now it's like you have
influencers like DOA or like burner like
whoever that are telling us what the
next Heat
is and it's probably something they have
a line on making money off of and if it
doesn't work in six months they'll have
the next
heater weed has been this weird thing
where consumers told farmers and Brokers
what they
wanted and they sort of demanded it
nobody nobody would have chosen to grow
Kush right like you got to figure out
how to like make these rinky dinky
little like dink dink dink dink dink
dink chunks you know you'd want to grow
like some kind of big stretchy Afghan
sativa thing a blue dream a something
that you know something that gets huge
like in mean jeene era of 500 gallon
pots and 12-footers
you know like nobody would choose cookie
from a production standpoint it doesn't
like food doesn't like light doesn't
like to get very tall but consumers used
to demand certain things and then
farmers and Brokers rushed in to fill
that demand and I'm not sure that same
Dynamic exists
anymore because of the changes and I
don't know what dynamic is necessarily
going to replace
it you know um but it might just be that
doa's is like his customer base they're
just bored of it like music you know
they're just bored of this genre and
they want something new they want
something different you know they've
been smoking the same variations of the
same thing 45 times over for the last
eight years and they're over it it
happened already we already saw it when
it was originally the purple craze of
the sweet weed and that was all anyone
would touch and it was urel and
everybody wanted that and Granddaddy and
anything that was really close to that
then it flipped we talk about it all the
time then it flipped to Kush and then
all the stuff that's now out is kind of
like all URL Kush and it's the second
purple wave Deja Vu and then it's like
if you take to me if you take URL OG and
like Bubba or Hindu and you mix that
together you're going to keep spitting
out all these things that everybody
keeps going oh this is the new new like
you could get like a Urkel and a OG
combo and if it's twe just the right way
you could have something like Skittles
it just has to have a lot of the most
special part of the urel with a little
bit of the OG part that isn't the accurd
part and you'll wind up with this crazy
soapy fruity thing you just need this
10% of this and 10% of that get rid of
all the rest of all that [ __ ] and you
can wind up with this thing that's like
this but it's just a trip to me what's
funny with like as far as like what's
the next big
thing um for my nose
like even though that's because I'm
really interested in plants and I'm
really interested in variety and
preservation and all that stuff but as
far as for products I don't even think
that it's a weird thing that we've
arrived where we've arrived because if
you took me when I was 16 and you asked
me what everything what everything
should be that's the very biggest thing
on the market I would have said what it
is right now because that was the weed
that I liked then and that was when
people used to ask me what's the best
thing you've ever seen I was like oh
it's this crazy Frosty purple [ __ ] and
it smelled like super like crazy and
deep and dark and chemically and Balm
but fruity and like there's these crazy
old kinds of weed that are really balm
like you know like yeah they're not like
they're not like you know like your
Mendo but at the same time they share a
lot of the appeal that those kind of
plants have where you're like oh if you
liked Urkel you you might think if you
liked ccle and you really like tindu
then you probably wouldn't hate
permanent marker because these things
are all kind of like this kind of like a
modern take on old Afghan weed with a
little bit of something exotic thrown in
from a rare plant that you wouldn't
normally find in a field of ACD weed and
that's where it's like kind of like this
magic combination and I think that's one
of the reason why it gets stuck like
that is because for a lot of people if
they're really into something like these
newest of the crazy things that are out
right now um whatever they are if you do
give them a bag of Blue Dream and you
give them a bag of permanent marker
they're going to go back to the bag of
the permanent marker more and the blue
dream's not going to be the thing they
want to smoke you're you're not going to
convert them even if they're not
influenced they're just going to be like
I don't know this one just has this
thing to it it's thick it's Rich it
smokes good and you know most people
people smoke so much weed they're not
going to notice that the high is kind of
lackluster because every [ __ ] high
they've had in the last 10 years is
lackluster anyway because well that
actually makes me hopeful because dude I
coming from the Midwest I grew up on
Mexican yeah right and I remember when I
first got my a sack of much better than
Mexican weed and I was like oh my God
weed can be like this and so there are
people out there that grew up on purple
candy gas and I'm not trying to diss it
all hard but like I think most heads
would agree there are some exceptions
but for the most part it's kind of got
like a medium mid-grade kind of flat
high that you get a tolerance to like it
might look beautiful taste great smoke
well or whatever but it doesn't actually
have some of the more unique highs that
other strains do right and so those
young people one day they might smoke a
haze or they might smoke something weird
and not even realize weed can do that
because they've been tough puffing on
this like this like one offshoot right
and I will say two that one of the
things that that I don't know if it's
true or not but the re one of the
reasons why people loved Crossing things
to cookie Was Not only was it so famous
but like cookie was sort of the was sort
of like where things shifted from a lot
of kind of ugly weed that was still
really nice
sold cookie made everything has to look
visually amazing and it really did up
how most things looked right and you're
on IG you're on this you can't smell it
you can't smoke it you can't squeeze it
but you can look at it and we're very
visual creatures and so I do kind of
Wonder it not because the funny part
about weed is that looks really doesn't
matter like it doesn't like looks
doesn't make it taste good or work well
you can't tell how what it looks like in
a joint really but it really matters as
far as sales right now and I don't know
how easy it would be for a phenomenal
strain that's a little uglier to catch
on in today's market it might take a
sort of a maturing of the scene for a
while because everyone's used to weed
looking fire I'll tell you straight up
dude um when the sour craze really first
hit in meno
most Brokers and me and Gan will back me
up on this a lot of times they would
come over and they would open the bag
and if the nose hit them the right way
they would just be like yes they knew
that if it smelled like that it was
going to work for them they'd still look
through it and stuff but there was this
nose and it's like if they opened it up
and they got hit with it and they knew
it was fresh and it was good that nose
was going to be like okay we're this is
going to work they were only looking
mold right so they didn't even care and
there was a lot of times where like sour
could look kind of stemy kind of you
know like it wasn't it it you know it
wasn't always the prettiest
looking
sack but it didn't matter they knew it
was potent and it smelled amazing and
that was going to work for their market
and that's what they cared about but
right now people are so indoctrinated
and weed
looking extremely visually attractive I
wonder if that's like a permanent shift
where you're just going to have to breed
weed that looks attractive or I wonder
if there's going to be openness to
like this weed looks kind of ugly but
man it's lip smackingly
good yeah you know and when I'm say like
the the weed like my favorite weed like
back in the day some of it that I'm
talking about was because of how it
smoked it tasted so good we smoked so
much weed that if it tasted really good
and it burnt right it was like that was
enough because it was like you know the
high we weren't that worried about it
because we knew we were going to get
high because we so much [ __ ] weed but
but yeah a lot of the highs are more
lackluster but more I mean like it was
the weed that I looked at and was like
this is what
I if you had a time machine you're like
oh man people would buy this [ __ ] so
fast and for a lot of people buying weed
it it it's never going to come down to
to the character of the high or any of
that it a for a lot of people it's
always just going to be they look at it
real quick and they go oh [ __ ] that's
awesome a lot of people are going to
continue to choose friends like that how
many people do you know who the the
friends who they will choose are the
people who they know have the most money
or the most access to a certain crowd or
whatever it is a lot of people don't
care about people's character at all
they continue to just hang out with
people who have the most [ __ ] and
they're like oh those people are cool
they have a lot of [ __ ] oh they can get
me into this party they they can do a
lot of [ __ ] for me and so a lot of
people that's like unfortunately that's
a crowd mentality and with weed there's
always going to be this thing where
people look at it real quick they go oh
[ __ ] yeah this is cool [ __ ] weed you
know and then that's just as far as it's
ever going to go whereas like me or you
will sit down and we'll go yeah oh wow
this is cool like it is full of stem and
it is got tiny little flowers and I
can't really see the resin but then you
like roll it up and you're like that's
crazy that made like my nose is stuck
with a smell for [ __ ] hour and it's
am tasting and that's for us you know
you're right in that sense dude is that
like if you could take a sack of I don't
know you know animal cookies or
permanent marker or something that's
really attractive and you could like
throw that into a jar and time travel
back to 19-year-old you and show that to
you in the '90s that was so much
prettier looking than most of the weed
you had access to you would imagine it
had to be as good as it looked it you
would just be blown away well in some of
the weed back then what's crazy is some
of the weed back then it just kind of
looked the same like I had this [ __ ]
called big blue and it's still to this
day like if I'll I'll show you too like
when I after I reveg and and regrow
these Hindu s
you'll be like there's cookies there's
gelato there's all the stuff that
everybody thinks are these modern looks
you're like no it was all in the old
Jean Pool from back in the day I think a
lot of it popped out from these
ancestral things that you and me had
from back in the day like the effects it
had more bag appe peel than
cookies unbelievable holy [ __ ] it looked
like you rolled it in Sugar yeah it's
insane like the northern my mom had
you're like that was cookies doesn't
even look like it has any resin compared
to that [ __ ] it was wild stuff but um
yeah it's it's it's just uh I don't know
it's a crazy it's a crazy thing but I
think that in a lot of cases when
marketing
happens you know you're marketing I
don't want to say it but you're kind of
marketing to shallow people bro like
it's kind of like you're marketing to
shallow people I [ __ ] hate to say it
but like you know who wears the [ __ ]
who wears the [ __ ] you know I don't
want to like make anybody feel like
stupid but like some of these name brand
things that cost a lot of [ __ ] money
and they have the brand written all over
them I don't want to like blow anybody's
trip but the rich people don't wear that
[ __ ] they buy the one where you can't
see the brand there's subtlety there's
Nuance you're buying it because of the
way the shit's sewn you're buying it
because of the material it's made out of
you're buying it because it's got some
reference to this or it's in this color
that means something to a certain people
a group of people that you don't [ __ ]
know about because not really one thing
one thing I should say too is because
things are so controlled
now and this is basically about like
what what would come after purple candy
gas or the age of candy is over is that
like what's in stores is what people are
growing is what the nurse
make available as clones or whatever not
that there aren't some Farms that have
their own stuff but it's like it's not
that easy for like an organic shift to
just happen right there's like like
layers now like most Farms buy their
plants from a nursery which means that
Nursery has to choose to Mom up those
plants to sell clones off of and they're
going to try to pick what they think is
the most popular thing that they're
going to sell a lot of clones of for
that era that they're going to be
offering it maybe they switch up they
like six to 12 things they offer like
three four times a year you know they've
probably got a bunch of moms that're
ramping up and a bunch of moms that're
ramping down and then moms that are in
their Prime and they switch it a little
bit you know but it's not going to be
like I'm I think that the way that we
used to get popular has broken down and
there's going to be some kind of new
paradigm and people are going to need to
sell what the work is and the work I
think part of the reason why purple
candy gas has lasted so long is that's
what the Brokers and that's what the
hustlers and that's what everyone has to
make hash with and that's what's out
there like that's the flow that's what's
there in large amounts so it's like in
order for the market to change you're
going to have to get some amount of of
new herb that people want that's getting
made into flour and hash and joints and
Edibles and this and that and that's a
slower
process yeah like I'll give like like
maybe I'll say this and I'm sorry for
ranting on it but like going to your
local grocery store they usually only
have two or three kinds of whatever
veggie it is they got a few kinds of
tomatoes they got you know they got the
dark red beets and maybe they got some
golden ones they got a cuc they got two
kinds of cucumbers they got like you
know like as weed becomes more legal
producer and stuff are going to want to
just settle on production Classics that
work and so it could kind of get trapped
in time for a bit of like you have to
convince producers to grow something
different and they're like well I've
already got all my nutrition dialed in I
already know how much EC to give I know
when to flush I know when to this I've
got it dialed I'm getting 3.4 pounds of
light with my LED bro I don't want to
mess with some new new why switch and so
you could have a situation where weed
sort of calcifies a bit in the center
because the people growing it and
selling it and hyping it like don't want
to
change and they don't even know what to
change
to yeah and I think that's been kind of
the standard like forever like I mean at
a certain point it was like if you were
growing if you were growing you know
weed in Jamaica you were growing this
Indian variety if you were growing weed
in Colombia I assume it was whatever
that first import was and it came over
and they all had one thing at one point
if somebody was growing weed it was
probably skunk number one and then at
one point it was probably Northern
Lights and then at one point in some
places it was probably like sweet tooth
or yeah you know like like Cindy or
whatever like I think it basically we're
they're we're constantly in these little
waves where everything is all the same
and the only reason why there was a
little more variety was because everyone
was isolated and that isolation was
protecting cultures you know isolation
protects cultures to an extent and it
evolves cultures to an extent and as
soon as you got the internet it's like
it it's going to get rid of some of that
naturally but at the same time there's
always this the the the the small amount
of people who are more into all the
really weird [ __ ] and I feel like right
now more than at any point in history
there's probably more people who are
into weird [ __ ] than there ever was
because they're able to look at all of
history and go oh what was the weird
[ __ ] that you had back then over there
and someone's like I got the weird [ __ ]
from back then over there and then you
can get it and try it whereas back in
the day if I wanted to try the weird
[ __ ] from back then over there that was
completely inaccessible all I could get
was the normal [ __ ] from here right now
or [ __ ] from there right now or the
normal [ __ ] from over there back then
but none of the like the weird little
that it it's trippy you know like I feel
like right now is actually really good
and I don't think that you're ever gonna
see a time when it completely comes
undone like I don't think like classical
music is going to make a huge [ __ ]
comeback but I think there's probably
more people listening to it right right
now than there has been a lot in the
past because of the internet I don't
think access is going to make all the
sudden hey guess what [ __ ] the number
one album once again is like when it was
[ __ ] Miles Davis or whatever but
there's a lot of people who know what
that is and they're into it but I don't
think it's ever coming back and if you
want to bring back classical Hip Hop's
going to have to sample it if you want
to bring back Jazz Hip Hop's got to
sample it and if you want to like make
like Haze popular you might have to toss
some color on it or you might have to
make it pretty to make something that's
a huge thing that starts a huge wave but
in the meantime you're still going to
have the people who are listening to
Jazz and listening to classical and
there's still more of them it's just
that you're so overwhelmed by all the
basic [ __ ] that it's like you're like
safe to flip and I don't I don't know
that it ever will I this might be in
aide or whatever but I should tell a
funny story like 20 20 plus years ago
maybe 22 years ago I used to go to these
Harvest festivals these little private
parties right and it's actually the
first place that I met CSI or sha like
707 you know or like chip from Royal
gold you know or whatever like that does
the real dirt like bunch of people bunch
of people from like overgrow and
cannabis world and all that and I
remember getting invited to this thing
and it was like a who's who of
underground people and I was like oh my
God I'm like in my early 20s or whatever
mid 20s I'm like I'm going to meet all
the old schoolers that have all the real
[ __ ] that I'm hunting for and I went
there and it was like everything popular
at the time that you could imagine
everything was cross the White Widow
everything was cross the blueberry
everything was cross the Sweet Tooth and
Blockhead and Louie like you know
breeder Steve was big and like DJ Short
and like the first Brothers grim and so
I think in a way that's always sort of
happened is like people take popular
stuff that other people are into and
start Crossing it into
everything and it seems overwhelming at
the time you know H you know for a
minute and I think I think the the
purple gas stuff has sort of been locked
in a time capsule for a second because
it's just been there as all the changes
have been happening um but you know
there's a lot of weed that's not that
that I would imagine will become popular
simply because it's like you get to
reintroduce old hits to new
people and that weed is nice and so I
don't know how long it'll take for like
diversity to develop in these various
markets but as as markets develop like
and get more mature there's people that
are going to want to try the famous
strains of old or different takes on
this or that weed nerds you know that
want something just off the beaten path
a little bit and then those things will
get their fandom but I don't know how
quick it's going to occur because the
market is pretty um you know I don't
want to say it's collapsing under its
own weight but it's it's pretty
unbalanced at the moment you know
there's not a lot of freedom there's not
a lot of freedom of expression there's
way more people just trying to hold on
than feeling like frisky and wanting to
experiment with what the market may or
may not be interested in yeah I'm
curious heavy in where you're at is that
a thing that has happened where it's
completely leaned towards one kind of
grouping or has uh interesting variation
and kind of more old school things have
they kind of kept kept the ground and
maintained like a big space in in the
market
there yeah I think the old school unique
sort of plants are certainly dying like
they only really exist in the outdoor
landscape not not in the indoor like the
indoor space is all dominated by younger
Generations plugged into Instagram
running all the latest rs11
hybrids um and generally speaking the
culture mimics the USA culture with like
a certain time delay uh so things that
are popular there maybe popular here
like a year later or so like once it
becomes available as like an S1 or
something but in terms of the old school
stuff there are these outdoor guys who
do big numbers with the you know like
old mother sativa or um heirloom
climatized tie type type stuff and they
still do that because you know you can't
deny the yield it's just it performs
dude but it's
dwindling I if old mother sativa exists
over there still that would be lovely I
had an old friend who's passed on now
from meno that had some of that and he
had the biggest plants I have ever seen
and it was just like top to bottom giant
colas all over itself it had a it was
obviously heavily sativa but it had
enough indicia in it that it threw it it
like literally was like a 12 foot round
ball that threw bats all over itself it
was so I might even have a picture of it
I could send you if I look deep enough
it it was
incredible um and he just said it was
old mother sativa and he said it was
from Australia so if that stuff exists
that would be pretty
cool I can't even remember how good it
was I just remember how giant how
unbelievably giant it
was yeah it's it's nice sort of uh
moderately uplifting sativa sort of
stuff I've yet to have stuff that's like
profoundly psychedelic in the way like
maybe some of the ties that you see with
Coastal or bod like they can really tap
into that but and and also old mother
sativa is a term it's such a broad term
you know like it's just like it's it's
more or less just a term for saying like
this is like some sort of a climatized
heirloom tie that's clearly been grown
Outdoors for who knows how many
generations but uh yeah it's it is still
around it's probably you know in reality
it's probably getting harder to find
because the people who used to buy that
sort of stuff usually bought it because
they didn't know where to get better
stuff from all they could get was this
sort of outdoory stuff that was
generally considered second rate
compared to Indica stuff and then when
medicalization rolled in those were all
the first people who got their cards
because they had the most to gain they
like in terms of the quality jump they
had the most to gain by getting on even
though it's you know the stuff we laugh
at the the Canadian
radiated imported herb that's not
considered that great it was still
significantly better in their eyes so
I've actually heard from uh a few of
well I've seen it myself there's a lot
of grow stores in Australia that are
shutting down because a lot of the guys
who used to grow stuff Outdoors that was
bit more bulk bit less quality maybe
using some of these old climatized trins
that really did produce volume uh that
there's just the market has evaporated
for that and the medical Market has just
swalled
it that's the way of the world like I
was saying before Morocco is mostly like
Super Lemon Haze and you know and
critical mass and you know big you know
them bringing over kilos of that kind of
seed and having them grow whole fields
of it and the farmers are happy because
they're going to buy it all and hash it
it's Spain's right there yeah they grow
what's in Spain and the right there give
us the stuff that we you know like
here's the seeds we'll make take a whole
room they make tons of seeds and they
give it to them and then they hash back
you know I actually have thought and
this might be kind of controversial or
weird but like the fact that like
America went to war with Afghan and and
Afghanistan for 20 years might have done
more to protect like Afghan
Afghanistan's like traditional indicas
from being flooded with anything because
it just wasn't safe for people to like
go there and travel around very much
unless you were in the military and then
there was a bunch of resentment and you
didn't want to get your head cut off or
be in some kind of Taliban video but
like you know arjent and stuff they
weren't doing any like any like you know
uh safaris or whatever into like the
Hindu Kush mountains to like meet people
for Strain Hunters because it was too
dangerous so it kind of kept those
Farmers
isolated like they were exporting things
but not really importing if that makes
sense they weren't being influenced by
the larger Globes change in Canada over
the last 20 years because it was a war
zone and it was dangerous and it was it
was you know I that could change in the
future but I almost think that like the
Talib the combination of like the war
and the Taliban has probably like
isolated
them well the taliban's a huge problem
because they're really good at
eradicating everything over there right
now and so it's pushed things into the
real extremes um yeah the mountains and
the higher up Pakistani border
Wilderness regions but it's cool because
like I was told for years and years like
yeah there's nowhere in the world where
they still have the old things they had
it's all been watered down and all this
different stuff and then like when I
finally T started talking to people on
the internet who were like up there in
those mountains I was like yeah what's
the weed smell like what's it look like
and they're like oh it's you know it's
like there's ones they smell like like
earthy kind of accurd coffee dead neat
weird kind of stuff you know and like
describing them all and I'm like that
sounds like all the really old Afghani
that I would consider to be like what's
the definition of The Afghani stuff that
I that I knew had been kept pure here
and then you start to see the pictures
and everything and you're like oh this
is and then you see the areas and you
see the people and you see like a
marketplace with all the people and you
go this is not a place where there's
just a whole bunch of Outsiders
polluting everything nobody's they're
not going to try to and then you see the
way they grow that was a big thing that
I picked up in Jamaica was that when
they took all the things to grow in my
buddy's neighborhood in Jamaica they
planted them and they all died because
they rely on the rainfall and the cycles
of the seasons and if the weed ain't
from there and it hasn't been there or
it's not from a similar climate it just
all [ __ ] dies so you can't really
take this Amsterdam hybrid [ __ ] and
throw it out by the Handful in
Afghanistan and leave it in the desert
with two rains a year and expect it to
survive it needs to have big fat fan
leaves and thick stems to draw water
from when it dries out and all this
different [ __ ] you know and you realize
when you look at the fields you're like
they look pretty they look pretty
similar to when you look at the old
picture of like Schultz or whoever over
there in like plants of the Gods and you
see those little afghanis are like looks
like monkey balls looks like big blue
looks like the same [ __ ] that they have
now when you see like uh deot going over
there and bringing back you know like
this this book back here it's Afghan
project it's like it it kind of looks
the same as it's ever looked and I was
super excited because it might be one of
the only places left that's like that
because one of the few Jamaica Morocco
Mexico Colombia Thailand all these
different places like they don't have
they didn't go through the same things
that isolated them like that region did
and they don't have what they used to
have anymore things different different
reasons for different countries but like
a lot of that legendary herb is either
lost or reduced to such a point like
we'd have to like refind it again yeah
you know um but Afghanistan and Pakistan
and those Regions they're just so
dangerous I think they stayed isolated
to
locals and not as influenced when you
see it's pretty easy to see you're like
I'm not just GNA go walking in there and
go act like a big shot people are like
no there's not there's not critical mass
or super silver haze in the Hindu Kush
right now doesn't look like it doesn't
look like doesn't look like it no they
might have we might not have access to
it but like they they I mean I guess
there's some people on the internet
making access happen but like I mean
there's people out there there's people
in Pakistan who are growing runs you
know it is a thing but they're growing
it like indoor they're not field farming
they in the fields they have to continue
to grow what works in the field you
don't really want to risk you know your
field on some whatever it is you know
there's no reason to do it because you
already have the thing that you know is
going to make a whole lot ofed yeah yeah
and the variety there just comes from
like you know acclimated might be like
acclimated to this Valley this mountain
pass this area and it's not like those
people travel a ton so they're probably
just working essentially like you know
meene and I joke that like and but this
is true it's like there'd be Hills and
and Mendo and neighborhoods that would
all have very similar weed but if you
drove 30 minutes to a different
neighborhood maybe there was a different
collector on that road and the the
neighbors would get seeds from from him
and it would have a little different
kick to it it would be a little
different mix of things and so even when
I first moved here like weed was very
Regional based on road and where you
were in the county and all that it was
still and I think it's like that in
Afghanistan and Pakistan I think it's
very Regional I think it's very like you
could go drive for 20 minutes in a
different Valley and you're like oh
wow I love it and look I think we could
probably mute on it forever but given
how long we've been gone for why don't
we jump into the uh our little final
segment before we wrap up the heavy
thought for this week I've got an
interesting one I want to give a shout
out I've taken some musings from uh 710
labs they put a post up recently where
they sort of posed a rhetorical question
saying are hash holes
Overkill it got me thinking you know
like I mean first of all the obvious
interpretation is you know like is a
better just to enjoy your flower and
your hash sort of separate on their own
but I guess you know we exist in this
culture where hash holes are starting to
become a more standard phenomena among
those who consume doinks and we see
those even ever increasing in size I
guess it starts to beg the question you
know are we are we just starting to get
a bit too hedonistic about all of it is
it a bit indulgent for the sake of
indulgence is it better to consume them
separately I guess as a little side note
you can also make the argument that it's
sort of easier for sub quality material
to fly under the radar when you blend
flour with concentrate so there's almost
a secondary sort of conundrum there but
I'd love to hear your thoughts a hash
holes
Overkill
well I I'll say I'm pretty confident
that you're talking to two primarily
flower smoking humans uh who dabble a
bit in hash but it's not your primary
gig I will say that I think that hash
has become as things have loosened up
hash has become massive compared to like
sort of a a small corner of weed for at
least Americans in the past and that's
raised a bunch of people's tolerances
and so there's a lot of weed smokers who
basically they don't consume flour all
that often they need Hash Hash is like
what they're used to smoking whether
they're dabbing it whether they're
mixing it or what not um and I think
fads are going to happen because you
have all this excess
hash um and I would say that over the
last 10 or 15 years as hash has become
really popular I think there's been an
immense amount of fads that have lasted
a year or two and change whether for
their I mean do do you remember back in
like 09 or 2010 when everybody took dabs
off a cherry glowing like thousand
degree
Banger right like that was just common
before we realized it was
cartic you know and like the styles of
hash have changed and like how what kind
of color and what kind of this and so I
do feel you're probably right in that
low qual lower quality weed and lower
quality hash will blend together to make
like a product that works so that's a
risk but um in in Europe I would say
when I first started going over there
they always looked at me as nuts as
smoking pure weed
all their weed always had hash in it or
they would smoke the hash with tobacco
even more commonly so I think mixing in
joints you know or various things you
can call it different names but I think
mixing hash and weed or mixing hash and
tobacco um is like a practice that's
been around for a really long time you
know and and certain cultures it's like
the
norm yeah I mean definitely as long ago
as 25 years ago we were putting snakes
of hash in the middle of joints
um it it's cool I mean I don't really
see anything wrong with it I I
personally don't want to do it because a
big part of smoking joints is like for
me I really am like trying to like I'm
trying to learn about the weed because
that's like my more my job is to know
about the weed so putting hash in it
like not going to really give me any
very clear idea of what the hell's going
on with the weed um I over the years
have
like become less and less excited about
any type of mixing of anything with weed
um I did smoke weed with tobacco which
is hilarious because that's like most
extreme mixing you could possibly get
but tobacco is so harsh and gnarly that
if weed can cut through it and be still
really killer killer weed it says a lot
about the weed and any weed that is like
kind of half ass that might trick you in
a regular joint you go oh that's really
good you mix it with tobacco and it'll
just be like nope but if you take like
the very best like if you take anything
that's really tasty like lemon tree or
jarro or uh OG cush or diesel or
whatever and you mix it with tobacco
you'll still be like damn you can really
taste the weed sometimes you can taste
the weed more clearly the character of
it because it's set against this jux
toos as something really gross along
with it and it really makes it pop out
you know but um as far as like putting
hash in weed I've just never like I'll
put I'll take like hash bong hits and
put hash on top of weed and we're old I
do the same thing it's really the hash I
don't care the weed's only there to keep
that make the hash like but it's it's a
it's a carrier it's something to it's
something for it to light on and melt
and burn into as you take a b yeah but
basically for me anytime you mix one
thing with the other thing one of the
things is I'm going to look at it as an
adulterate like people are like oh moon
rocks you take the weed and you dip it
in the oil and then you roll it in the
KE and people are like dude if you do
that with like the very best craziest
oil ever and then you do it with the
very best craziest full all head sift
and it's like all super crazy products
when you put them together then they're
like then that then that's good I'm like
no then that is every every every other
thing is just in the way it's everything
is an ad ulter it to the other thing I
don't I don't look at it like oh that's
a great [ __ ] idea I always look at it
like no I want to I want to see what the
hash is like I want to see what the weed
is like like I don't I don't you know
get much about each product now if I
know him really well after a while I
might go okay [ __ ] it you know let's mix
this together and see what that does but
Mo for the most part I want to see what
things are by themselves and that to me
is like
um that's the best way to do that like
and I'm funny like that if I drink
alcohol I don't want you to put the
alcohol in the [ __ ] juice give me a
cup of juice and give me a [ __ ] cup
of alcohol and I'll drink the [ __ ]
Whatever It Is by itself and then I'll
sit and I'll drink a cup of juice like I
don't want the alcohol in the juice and
I don't want the juice and the alcohol
like let me drink the alcohol and see
what that is and then let me drink the
juice and see what that is it's like you
put them together you ruin both that's
how I feel about those kind of things
even sometimes when I'm sitting in the
kitchen making tacos I'll just sit there
and I'll like eat the meat and then be
wind up just being like I had the meat I
don't really need the taco because like
the meat was so good I'm like the meat's
already so good like a a corn tortilla
is going to make it that much better and
that's how I feel sometimes about really
good weed like some other hash from some
other thing like if it's both the same
that could be kind of cool to just have
like a stronger version of
Skittles or a stronger version of diesel
or whatever like that's cool but
generally people like mix them and all I
don't know it's all just a bunch of
jumbled [ __ ] to me I'm weird like that
you
know I love it look the art of mixing no
doubt has existed for a very very long
time I uh I think we might leave it at
that one we've we've thoroughly explored
a number of issues before we sign off
any final
words uh I don't know I mean you know
back on that one like whatever people
like to do if you enjoy it that's great
if you like your joint better with hash
upe Mill you better throw some hash in
the middle of it and enjoy that joint if
you like that that's what you like you
know same with any of it if you like all
this kind of weed we were talking about
and that's your favorite it's your
favorite you don't have to worry just
try take you know think about all these
things thing think if they maybe they
might make sense and if they don't then
don't bother for sure and I definitely
want to say as someone who is ardently
against smoking tobacco there is
undeniably something magical about a
little snake of hash among some tobacco
you can't deny it oh God very neat man
it's very neat y I'll say this uh and
then we can go when I was a kid and I
was going to Amsterdam uh to buy seeds
in the mid 90s because that's where I
knew how to get kind
bud I they they don't smoke weed over
there they mix it and so if you're in a
coffee shop in Winter and it's all
closed up and there's four or five
different groups each smoking a big
spliff with a big hash snake down the
center and a bunch of tobacco and
there's just so much tobacco smoke in
the air there was times I had to leave
certain clubs because I was like this is
the most Smoke Filled tobacco room I
think I've ever been in and my lungs are
shutting down and maybe I'm a [ __ ] but
I don't care I can't handle it it's like
like if you've ever seen a huge spliff
just being chiefed you know and like all
that hash smoke and all that tobacco
smoke and then you look around there's
like four or five more of them getting
PED in different groups it's a bit
overwhelming yeah speaking who sat in
like my buddy's old Chevy or whatever
back in the day when we were when we
were teenagers and rolled up like the
shake that's the only thing you can get
and a little resin and rolling joints
this big around and you know three
sheeters or whatever and just trying to
smoke all that in the hot box to try to
like all right we're somehow off of this
stuff how are we gonna do it you know
taking bong hits and try keing it and
trying to put that back in there and
make it a little stronger and all this
[ __ ] like I don't like to sit in a place
where people are smoking I don't smoke
inside I'll smoke a joint inside if
we're like like me and you not so can
sit in my living room and smoke a joint
and it's fine that's fine but if there's
like 20 of us somewhere and be outside
that much something like that yeah I
need to go outside and it's not even
it's like literally every like a little
bit of that smoke comes off the joint
most of it came out of somebody's mouth
and when you're sitting in a smoky room
what you're really looking at is
everybody's breath with smoke it's bad
enough that you're in there with the
breath man with a bunch of stale ass
burnt whatever the [ __ ] we're burning
all in there it's just like yeah hash
weed whatever it is especially if it's
tobacco I'm just like no dude this is
stale this is funky like you know what I
mean I want to take I want to have my
own joint or whatever it is I want to
probably be outside and I want to sit
there and a lot of times I like to smoke
by myself and kind of meditate about
[ __ ] and think and get some ideas and
some spiration and everything and I
don't know that's just how I tend to
like to do it you know I kind of lose
all the rest of it when I just sit and
I'd rather just kind of do that when I'm
doing that and do this when I'm doing
this and probably it's you know slightly
neurod Divergent but I mean you know I
said if it works for you it works for
you touch of the tism touch of the tism
yep all right a little bit gentlemen
right I love that look comprehensive as
always big thank you me
not dog signing off everyone have a
wonderful night