hello and welcome friends for another
episode of not in my bag your number one
spot for all things Cannabis News
discussion and recent events as usual
you're joined by your boys mean Jean of
mesino and Mr heavy days of The Upside
Down Library here today we are thrilled
to be joined by an epic breeder The Man
Behind the black dog lines you've no
doubt heard about a NorCal local Legend
and a friend of both Jean and myself
massive welcome to Jesse of biovortex
for joining us
today we're excited to do
it so without further
delay let's get into
it hello and welcome to the third
episode of not in my bag your number one
cannabis news and current affairs
discussion show as always I'm grateful
to be joined and carried by my co-host
Mr mean jeene of mesino and on today
today's episode we are stoked to be
joined by a friend of both of ours an
incredible mesino based breeder creator
of the black dog lines and many more a
massive welcome to Jesse of biovortex
how you doing great thanks I'm actually
up in Humble but um love myo too we're
adoped that's all right that's all right
as usual triangle yeah I'll take
it I want to know what have you been
smoking on
um I guess actually you know what's kind
of random is I pulled out uh some banana
OG from the very first wash it did with
um Adam from some actual like really
nice trim and it was a 90u and it was so
uh insanely good it was like this is
trim hash and it was like some of the
best hash I'd ever seen at that point it
was like 2014 and it was just complete
full melt beautiful hash from trim and
and it was actually the next year that
we then uh continued on and did a whole
fresh Frozen project and like made some
of the like most amazing hash those next
years with the like Coastal gr um just
in no dust just as as clean as possible
Gran from the beginning um thinking
about it from hash from the beginning
but um put put away some of that in the
the freezer for like a long time and I
found it and pulled it out and um was
actually just rolling some spliffs and
it rolls in so nice with uh some decent
tobacco and then um mixed it actually
with some gmob and some Mandarin double
Mandarin uh Cherry Lime dog uh from the
Nukem farms and rolled a several of
those up to go to the beach and
collected a whole bunch of rocks
actually have an outdoor shower and
bathtub and so collecting really
interesting rocks to to go under the
shower and the and the tub so each rock
is actually hand chosen under your your
feet and um but had to roll some splits
for that but it was pretty cool to like
find that this
90 uh uh you um trim hash from so long
ago that just it held up and it actually
cured in a a way that was just so nice
to to roll with and so the last two days
I've kept going to that even though it's
from
2014 yeah that stuff though kind of a
little bit better and go then like
having like yeah no it fluffs it's super
fluffy and then it like it just all of a
sudden is like gone once you like start
absorbing it in with your your fingers
and get that heat uh but yeah it was
kind of funny 10 years 10 year vintage
yeah I dabbed some of that with you I
think probably from the next year I
think it yeah yeah when it was the fresh
frozen and it was and that was really
good yeah it was so tasty and then I was
super blazed we were down at that thing
at the honeysuckle Lotus party when I
met those guys and uh me and Johnny went
down there and I remember I was hitting
it and I was like I had never seen the
straight banana before and I was like
wow it really is banana you know right
yeah old and then the kind of candy
runts kind of thing like all at once and
then there's that gas with it too yeah
definitely
nice yeah gorgeous and what
about I'll have to cut that out probably
gorgeous and what about yourself Mr me J
what you been smoking on the all the all
the throat stuff is definitely you know
if you're smoking a lot of weed I think
everyone
understand uh I myself have been smoking
on um as I'm doing work and stuff I've
been smoking on this little bit of
probably kind of similar to what he's
smoking on texture-wise it is um I think
it was made from dry weed but it's water
has and I got it from the dude Jerry who
I met at a at a party
up at the 101 and uh he's the dude that
does Jerry seed Swap and stuff and I had
met him before and he had this
Vietnamese hash and when you smell it
it's very like Pine and terpinolene
smelling and um it smokes really nice
but I didn't actually smoke any right
now because on the last one when we had
sticker Farmer on I was smoking it right
before the show and during the show
and then I started going into some kind
of a thing and I couldn't remember where
the hell I was at and after a while I
was like I don't know where my train of
thought was I don't know what's
happening and I realized like yeah I
probably shouldn't be smoking the
Vietnamese
hash show let's smoke it after the show
but it's great for like the daytime
because it's um really clear and I
thought maybe it might have a little bit
of like the heart racing sativa stuff
because I'm not really used to
Vietnamese stuff and uh it wasn't it's
really Pleasant and I can't say it's
mild because it gets you high but it it
is really like Pleasant and enjoyable
and um as hash it doesn't have any kind
of a flavor of being like the heavy
terpinolene or anything it just has a
nice good old school hash flavor and uh
I've been smoking it in a little in a
little homemade Oak pipe that my kid
made it's all it's all charred and
everything it's like you can see it's
got the little hat wow yeah and then I
smoke it with a um with a torch lighter
from real far away so it just kind of
like it kind of Vapes it like a like a
cold star dab in a sense so you really
get a good flavor um but you know it's
it's it's silly but uh it's just kind of
fun because it's like you know my kid's
too young to be smoking and stuff but he
saw people carving pipes and he's like
oh that's a thing to carve and he likes
to whittle so and then I I took it and
I'm smoking out of it and he's all dude
where's that pipe I made and I'm like I
was smoking out of it and he's like you
got you can't smoke out of my pipe where
do you doing I'm smoking out a b so oh
that's epic and you know what it's cool
you mentioned the tie I'm smoking some
uh some rizar which was grown by my
buddy bin chick and he's actually doing
some cool work with ABC everyone should
check that out but rizar is Chernobyl by
TGA everyone knows that um by a Str
called is by my body always be flowering
but it's like the mother is um Black Tie
which is the a seeds the black
Vietnamese cross to the tie anyway it
just channels all that so this plant
it's like a tie it's like a jungle um
and he grew it Outdoors so it's just
like got this awesome you know sort of
sativa effect I love it it uh it ties in
perfectly with your tie hash and it also
ties in perfectly with our first story
actually which is or you got something
to show and tell first uh tie Tai dog
when I was in Hawaii last year a guy had
did a double cross of tie on the black
dog over the last several years and like
realized who I was and came up and
brought me the seeds of it so kind of
super fun and called it TI Tai dog I
thought that was a really great name
that's awesome you could almost like
generate a sativa line of black dog out
of
it I don't know how sativa they'll be
looking with black dog in it but yeah
don't
F it's already yeah those would be
really cool hybrids though um oh also uh
as far as cold start dabs that's like
one of my favorite ways to go but uh
gmob from radical herbs is what I've
been uh smoking on lately and like their
last year's Harvest was insane the last
two years just so good and just complex
and diverse some of the most tpine
diverse testing I've ever seen in hash
um and just the Savory and the gas and
the dessert it's like all these things
kind of happen so that's kind of a go-to
over and over again and then I also
found some of the old banana sfv dog in
the freezer and pulled that out so it's
kind of cool because that was the mail
that uh was used in the original gmob
and so it was kind of cool to taste
those back and for it what was the uh
one we were dabbing after your Premiere
when I came up there when I stayed at
your house it was a banana
something oh do you remember
that one was good high on it was so good
I just remember like I mean of course
set in setting right and I was have yeah
well we did a few and I think we did do
Straight banana OG and I think we did do
banana sfv dog and Mandarin that night
but it might have been the simply Adam
um banana OG because he did I think I
pulled out some of those where he did
actually a a freeze dryer and a air
dried kind of uh
batch where each one was
blind uh style where just have a number
on it and he had a whole pasting note
thing but I think I pulled some of those
out um for the full banana but we also
had some green Source I think some of
the banana dog crosses which were a
little bit more um kind of full hashy
flavor but melted really nice too but
okay I just remember that it was
definitely something banana but I think
it was different because I remember
I think it was a little bit different
because I had already tried the other
one and uh I just remember that the
effect on it like I said set in setting
right like of course we were having a
lot of fun and everything but I just
remember like feeling like the the
feeling of like hitting it and just like
the warm feeling of well-being with no
like edge of anything it was just like
oh this is that was a nice one I liked
that one a lot I think it's actually the
exact same one that I just was dabbing I
think the banana sfb dog cuz I'd had
that jar it was a large one I put away
in the jar for or in the fridge for a
while so yeah sounds right yeah I think
that might be it there I'm jealous I'm
jealous banana sfv dog sounds
incredible we should probably jump into
our first story for this week which is
uh tying back to the tie we referen
before uh let me get a little sticker
out here we go so Thailand's flag that
their stance on cannabis is likely going
to change they've actually gone so far
as to say that all cannabis businesses
need to be prepared to have shut up shop
within the next 12 months this is
obviously a huge backflip from the
former government's surprise
legalization which has led to many
westerners flocking to Thailand in the
hopes of setting up their own cannabis
Empire many have been critical of this
and have cited this as possibly one of
the major reasons for the reform
although a new government has taken
power which is likely a
contributor uh this is however um there
has been further concerns raised that um
the the intention initially was that Tha
Nationals would be the predominant
players within the industry given that
currently it's run by majority expats
with ties involved in the business um
it's looking as though things are going
to shut down there is a strong vocal
opposition to the change however with
many protesting the changes hopeful that
they can get some sort of back flip on
the ruling however Thailand is not a
traditional Western Country and so you
do have to wonder if any of these
protesting would lead to any change I
guess the question becomes what do we
think is this the end of legalization
for Thailand and to the greater Asian
scene given Thailand was cited as
possibly the first domino in a chain
that may lead to more legalization in in
Asia in
general yeah what do you think Jesse
um yeah it's pretty pretty sad to see
because we definitely wanted to see the
continue domino effect of of more and
more places adopting um less
Draconian uh laws towards cannabis and
towards people being able to have the
right to to grow a plant I think it's a
human right um and so many
places still have very very intense laws
uh Asia has a lot and so and many places
near Thailand that still have death
penalties for things um and in the US it
wasn't that long ago that people were
getting death sentences um are current
president even work towards
having uh sentences be more strict for
drug offenders and now using this moment
to uh give more control towards
pharmaceutical companies with cannabis
as a as a way to say you're legalizing
something um but as far as Thailand it
was just really nice to see that happen
that that moment like maybe it can lead
to more one of my favorite things was
was seeing um farmers were using
cannabis for chicken feed and they would
stop they stopped using
antibiotics uh and we having better
results and healthier chickens just
adding cannabis so that that all of the
things that can benefit from not having
these uh horrific laws when it comes to
a plant that can bring so much benefit
to people um is is really important but
I'm not necessarily that surprised
because there's always a pendulum of
things and it's like you swing One
Direction and then things swing back the
other way instead of finding the
balanced approach that makes sense in
things it's always like oh cool we have
this way and then you go too far with it
in certain ways and it's by say saying
too far I don't think there's any too
far when it comes to freedom but there's
too far when it comes to taking um and
so like that mindset of how you you do
something if you're going someplace to
uh the green indust industry kind of
like concept of
uh um profiting off of something and and
taking from something instead of just
uh being a part of producing medicine
being a part of growing something well
or being a part of community um so yeah
I guess often we just we just see that
swing right back after we think
something
improves um but once it it already
happened and I don't think uh we've seen
too much bad from it so um I I hope that
whatever does happen um it it swings
back towards decriminalization of a
medicinal
plant yeah it's one of those ones where
um like my cynical take on it is just
like [ __ ]
Americans because I'm like
okay I really like capitalism I like the
idea of people having opportunities to
be able to make something and Elevate
themselves and their people and their
families and I like the idea of people
in Thailand being able to take because
um Thailand has a really long
established cannabis culture everybody
knows like taii weed is like one of
those things like oh Thai stick or you
know all these different things and that
part you know southeast Asia in general
has a lot of it's obviously um been
there a long time because they have
really unique cannabis that almost
stands out as its own thing that's
different than everything else in the
world and um you know it would have been
cool to be able to
see like there when I talk to people a
lot of people were like oh they don't
there they they've everything's been
held back enough that they kind of need
help to be able to produce on a level to
be able to turn have it be like a
business thing and so you go okay that
would be cool for people to come in and
help them do their thing but as soon as
I started hearing about it everything
I'm hearing about was like oh
everybody's just
shipping last year's California weed out
the back door or out wherever to go over
there and liquidate it and when you go
somewhere to buy weed I had a um I have
a friend uh from Canada and he was like
yeah I just went to Thailand he's all
guess what I bought and I'm like oh
what' you get you know he goes I just
bought an eth of California half brown
run
for
$85 and I was like that's what's going
on I was like oh my God like this is so
it was so disappointing and um it's like
when I went to then then what happens is
all around the world of course everybody
always wants to know it's not just it's
not just you looking at the magazine
Center fold and going oh that that's a
new thing I've never heard of it it's
popular why is it popular it must be
good it happens no matter where you go
so there were people in Thailand who
were going well I mean we have this
stuff but you don't get a lot of weed it
doesn't look like what people want so
people were interested in being able to
produce the kind of weed that was like
worldwide contemporary competitive weed
and um I was like the same thing in um
like in Jamaica all the
weed that is really grown for production
it tends to be the stuff that I look at
and go that
that even though it's not specifically
I'm like that is like that's California
weed that's Amsterdam weed and you can
look at the plants and go this isn't
what would have come from India that was
originally Jamaican ganja you know and
um it's a trip
because that's kind of the same deal
it's like in in Jamaica when I talk to
my friends who live way up in the in the
hills and they are like yeah my grandpa
he grew a lot of weed he was one of the
first big big weed guys in the area and
you know I'm like oh that's cool you
know like what do you guys do you guys
grow and he's like yeah it's been
eradicated so hard in our area um that
there's not a lot of weed in general
right here a lot of the weed comes from
the production centers which they grow
all this other stuff I was talking about
but he was like we still in this area
when we do grow weed we grow the
traditional weed we call the Indian that
came with the with the people from India
when first when it was first introduced
basically and when we plant that it
grows and we don't have to do anything
to it and when we tried to grow all this
other stuff it rotted it died in
droughts it wasn't as hearty it did
wasn't you know what like we would call
here we would say like it's land racy
it's like you know and and he brought me
some of the weed and it was like really
stringy and it smelled like terpinolene
and Pine and um it had a really great
high but it wasn't what you would want
to produce which I imagine is probably
what it was like in Thailand you know
but um what would be cool in Jamaica
would have been if people would have
gone there and been like look if you can
just dial this in a little bit and get a
little bit of irrigation and dry it a
little bit better you guys can produce
Jamaican weed that's incredible because
it was really good weed it just hadn't
been handled like we would have handled
it and um and but but it was so like the
identity of it was such making ganja
which was Indian weed grown in Jamaica
for a hundred years or whatever you know
and so um it would have been really cool
if people could have gone into Thailand
and been like okay you know we have
things that might have been eradicated
here that are these old Thai heirlooms
and let's find the things that are in
Thailand that are good that work here
and then let's try to dial in your
drying practices and dial in this and
try to help like them get their you know
people who want to go there really you
know as Carpet Baggers like go there and
try to build up what they have and then
refine it but instead what happens is
Americans and I'm American I can't like
say like oh [ __ ] Americans but
[ __ ] Americans we show up over there
and we see an opportunity and we're just
like let's just ship in all this stuff
and we'll sell it over here and not only
do that but take everything that they
have going on and try to kind of push in
and then have them grow all the same
things that we would grow and do it the
same way and I remember uh back in the
day hearing about how Amsterdam had weed
and you could go there and and like you
know everybody knew about Amsterdam if
you were alive in the 80s and the 90s it
was like whoa Amsterdam there's places
where you can buy weed buy seeds it's
crazy and so there was like that tourist
aspect where you know like people said
you know people come here and they do
their thing but they were just like
[ __ ] Americans and it got to the
point where after a while Amsterdam's
like we don't really want weed that much
because people eat four space cakes and
throw up on the sidewalk and they get
drunk and they're vulgar with it
everything's like vulgar like why is it
got to be so [ __ ] much you know and
it's just like such like a cultural
mindset and it kind of works where
you're at but when like the old west
lands somewhere that has cultural
sophistication and established cultural
practices over thousands of years and
then all of a sudden you're just there
and you're like hey I'm [ __ ] Billy
the Kid and I'm gonna [ __ ] roll an
ounce and eat a [ __ ] cheeseburger
with eight Patties on it and [ __ ]
throw up on the street with my friends
you're just like it's not really helping
it get established and I think that kind
of happened to Thailand and that's like
my hot take on it and then there's other
ways to look at it with a lot of nuance
which is just that it probably was like
you said with the pendulum swinging it
probably was a little bit much too soon
in a place that's so conservative and
surrounded by very conservative uh areas
where I'm sure there's pressure on the
royal family there from places where
they're like hey we're right over here
and we hang people for having seeds like
this is not this you know there's
probably a lot of nuance and stuff going
on too but I don't think it ever helps
when there's like you know people just
doing things in this big vulgar American
way you know it's like yeah it's a lot
of fun but at the same time I feel like
it uh it probably got overly exploited
and I don't think that the outside
influence probably helped I think
there's some truth into people saying
that and I I can't imagine that that's
just not a factor you know it was a
pretty fast change I remember um
scrolling through Instagram and I saw
the hashtag for black dog and these kids
in Thailand had made these shirts of
black dog and like it said black dog in
the back and they had a beautiful
picture of a black dog flower on the
front and they had all their faces uh uh
with smiley faces in front and things
like that to make sure they stayed
Anonymous um because the laws were
actually quite rough at the time um and
that's just what 2015 16 it was still
pretty pretty bad and I comment oh cool
shirts and they were like whoa wow cool
like Hey we're sorry we didn't asked to
make them but can we send you some and
so they sent some really cool Black Dog
shirts and stickers and um and the story
behind it was they actually were growing
it and it was they were growing Black
Dog seeds and made made a good selection
and we're growing wead and uh they ended
up kind of having their spot be
compromised and they were pretty worried
about getting in a lot of trouble and so
they took down the room and but they'd
got this really good picture of the
flower before the end like okay let's
pivot and do a t-shirt company with this
this picture of the black dog flower and
it was yeah just like kind of wild to
see but that was really not that long
ago that they were facing some serious
legal uh fears of going doing some
serious jail time for having a grow room
vers uh it just being
full everything kind of goes and then
now who knows what it's going to swing
back to yeah yeah and I think that is an
important sort of CounterPoint to make
which is that on the one hand it's very
clear to see and to point to what you
could argue as like a form of sort of
exploiting the the newly legalized
landscape you know with everyone rushing
in but I think the the really relevant
Counterpoint you have to make is that as
much as there is all this runs and Gary
pton being imported there is a very
thriving and um you know active younger
seen in Thailand that want all of this
you know Californian popular strains
just like young people in Australia just
like young people in America so it's
yeah I think it is worth you know
pointing out that there is there was
partially a demand for it there's
obviously a lot of people in Thailand
who I'm sure want to see like a more
Tero and a natural expression but yeah I
think it's it's worth worth uh comparing
both but you know in in terms of talking
about coming in and taking over this
works perfectly with our next story
which is that uh our good
friend Uncle burn he's back again he's
always in the news but in this time for
different news we're talking about him
today because burner and cookies have
announced their strategic news with
their intent to acquire cookies Florida
assets from a company called turp HQ the
announcement follows in the recent wake
of the Florida Supreme Court ruling that
will now allow adult youth cannabis
legalization measures to be on the
November ballot this also needs to take
into account the recent DEA scheduling
playing another vocal another big factor
so basically burner sees the Florida
ballot as very likely to win he's going
so far as to hedge his bets that it's
going to be worth becoming an active
player in Florida and for the people who
aren't aware cookies is a parent company
they license out the ability for other
companies to run cookies stores in
respective States that they're not
currently operating in so if you look at
burner's Instagram and the cookie stores
he regularly visits and shout outs those
are the ones that he and the parent
company own the other ones they're
privately owned so he's hedging his bets
that the Florida ballot is going to pass
and that there's going to be a huge New
Market in Florida on top of the
currently existing one I guess the
question needs to be asked do we think
it's going to be legalized and do we
think burner is ahead of the curve on
this one or just a bit optimistic
what do you think Mr main
Jane
um yeah I don't know I mean I think
uh as potentially big of a business as
they are and can be I think it's kind
of I think it's always it's like a a
worthwhile bet you know to just go okay
like if if it if it works it works and
if it doesn't then you know know it it's
not going to work out but if it works
out like they're they're going to win
you know and
um you know it's like it's it's
capitalism like once things are business
that's the that's the one thing like
that's what sticker farmer said last
time it's like people who are in
business they're in business they're
going to do business you know and when
you when they're looking at it they're
basically looking like okay if this is
going to be a good place to potentially
make a lot of money then get in there
and try to um try to control it it's the
same thing as you know like as that's
why I said about Thailand it's like yeah
people are just gonna show up and just
try to make a whole bunch of money like
that's just that's what like that is
that is the American thing to do is to
just try to go wherever you can and make
as much money as you can make and um you
know it's uh it's one of those things
it's like
not not what I'm into because it's not
what I would want to spend all my time
and energy on but like those guys that's
what they're into doing and um and
basically if all of a sudden they
weren't doing that then there would be a
vacuum and you would see who else coming
in you know and I've talked to Jesse
about this in the past like
um as much as there's a lot of different
details and new nuance and everything to
the whole story of all whatever
California legal cannabis branding
cookies burner all this
stuff there's like
um there's that aspect of like the
American dream you know where it's like
okay I can start here with this little
thing and like turn it into this this
big thing and it's one of those weird
things because if you're of one and
there's there's not only two mindsets
but if you're on one Far Side you're
like I don't want to see
anybody do good at
all and then there's the people who are
like I want to see people do good but
not at the expense of anything else and
then there's the people who are just
like just [ __ ] hustle and get money
you know and
um the most pure form of capitalism
unfortunately is the people who are just
like where can we get to where's the
next opportunity I'm going to take
advantage of it and as much as that's
not my natural mindset so that's not
what I do like I said if it there's
always going to be that person that does
that so you're always if you're not
there it's gonna just create a vacuum
and someone else is going to do it and
in this case um you know say what you
will about those guys but like in the
case of burner at least went from being
a guy who was like a bud tender to a guy
who all of the sudden was
internationally recognized and has a lot
of stuff under his belt that he's done
and then turned into you know now
cookies you're like it's this big huge
thing and you know it's like somebody's
going to do it they're going to do it
and when there's opportunities like this
there's no way that they're just going
to be like oh yeah whatever not not you
know brisket for the biscuit as they say
there was going to be like okay we could
maybe go down there and uh and do it so
just you know I think that's what's
what's going on is anything that opens
up those guys yeah I mean I know they in
Thailand they had a big presence too
cookies the genetics the company all
that stuff it's just there's people are
going to do that Germany just opened up
you're probably going to see cookies in
Germany and
and as much as it's like okay like you
know there was like the cookies and bod
collab you're like bod is the is like if
you know bod in person you're like he's
like the real like World traveler plant
guy makes his own perfumes sends me
incense in the mail and [ __ ] is like
what I would consider like a hippie dude
that's super cool DJ's drum and bass
[ __ ] and is just all super super cool
and like way on that side of it he
travels places he trades people seeds
you got you got him on the one hand and
then you got cookies on the other you
know and you want to see like somebody
like that be the person doing that but
people like that they don't do that you
know you're burner's the one who's gonna
do that kind of [ __ ] so bod's not going
to show up and try to take over the
German Market cookie gonna do that you
know and it's everybody you know but it
but but yeah whatever happened to that
uh it just I it I think it was not a
good fit I don't think it really I don't
think it was a good fit in the sense
that the people who want what cookies
brings to the table a majority of them
don't want what bod brings to the table
and the people who want what bod brings
to the table don't want what cookies
brings to the table and it would be cool
if there was overlap but
in I think it used to be easier for
there to be overlap a long time ago
because when you saw something you were
offered that and everyone saw the same
thing and if it was on channel two
everybody saw channel two and now
everything's in bubbles and so the
people who are going to say that cookies
is
mids are the people who are going to be
like have you seen this crazy thing have
you seen you know Pine saw and the
people I talked about this at a
different point too they're in different
bubbles so like I I don't think that
they were able to and this I I said this
before the thing before the while they
were still doing it I was like I don't
know what each bubble's GNA get from the
other because I have friends that I talk
to and I'm like oh what's the cool stuff
you have and they pull out all this
stuff and I'm like this is gelato and
this is gelato and this is gelato and
this is this is the same thing and
they're like but look at this one and
they're like this is this and I'm like I
understand like it has it's been crossed
with whatever like it's sh Banger like
yeah it's cool it's good but it's good
like for the market of the people that
are in that bubble where it's like of
all these types this one is really good
but for somebody like me there's nothing
novel about it it's so similar to what
the last thing was and then somebody
like Bo is going to like make like some
kind of trippy poly hybrids with the
same things and you're going to be like
oh that's cool that has like the gelato
color but then you smell it and you're
like oh it has that thing in there that
is different and they're to they just
kind of sit they sit in two different
worlds I think in general even if they
were to incorporate a little one from
the other it's still going to always
wind up I think kind of splitting off
and and being in two two different world
worlds really you know um I I had heard
that um burner was pushing it a lot and
that there was other people in cookies
who were not into
it I could imagine that yeah yeah so I I
heard that he that like it seemed as if
he was really Keen to make it happen but
it was other for other powers that be he
was I mean I I I was told at some point
that like bodies I think it was uh Sun
Sunshine 4 or whatever that is Sunshine
Daydream Sunshine 4 one of those things
that burner was like that's my favorite
weed and it's like cookies if they put
that in a myar everybody who is that in
that bubble is going to pull it out and
go what did what they did a bait and
switch this isn't this isn't cookies
weed this is something else even though
you got burner saying this is better
they're still going to be like I was
looking for this everybody knows that
cookies Paradigm of that kind of weed
where it's the gelato runs was able to
jump in there because it's gelato all
this different stuff but it
doesn't you know they don't have like a
I don't know I just think the the
overlap isn't there and it's a trip when
you know people like I
know people who if weed is anything like
this other weed over there it's just
instantly going to be described in a
derogatory way like if there's the
people who if they smell a little bit of
terpinolene it's like instantly that's
that's train wreck that's Jack that's
that thing and then you're like well I
know what you don't like about those but
this one is different but it's there the
same thing with green weed people would
be like no I only smoke purple or it
doesn't look visually crazy and you're
like yeah but when you smoke it and they
could smoke it and think it's the best
when they're like it but I like pretty
weed and you're like what are you doing
with you know but that's just how how it
is that there's there's big splits in
what people um consider good and then
you have some it's all subjective is
what's funny and then when you get
things that are subjective you get a lot
of people who really don't have their
own opinion so that's what tends to
happen that that's what pop is right so
like if you go okay um this is what
everybody likes right now there's always
a lot of people who are like yeah it's
what's good I can tell it's good because
everyone likes it and then there's a lot
of people who are like yeah but this
thing's good too and they're like well
but nobody likes it so it doesn't even
they won't even take the time to
discover if they like it and it's just
human nature that's what we do we go in
these groups and some people like purple
shiny flashy weed and you know and I
mean you can incorporate that too and
turn you know like it it's not
completely out of bod's wheelhouse to be
able to go okay I'm going to pull a fast
one on you and you're going to look at
it and you're going to think it's all
these things but then I Incorporated
these new
traits but most people who like the
character of different weed like me or
bod or Jesse or you like we we of course
are going to be like okay I want to have
like all of us here and bod all have
purple Frosty pretty bag appeel crazy
weed but we like it because we like it
not because it's the only thing you can
like we also have a bunch of other stuff
that maybe might not ever be as popular
with the big group but among the small
groups that are here and there somebody
would be like oh that's awesome I'm glad
all you I'm glad you don't just have
purple Frosty pretty weed you have this
odd thing I like this one this is the
one I liked because of it being a
subjective experience you know it's a
weird weird thing but um yeah I mean I I
think people just get I think groups get
stuck and then um I'm sure whoever's
running cookies is like no we're not GNA
put that weed in our bags it's not gonna
not going to work and they probably get
bad feedback if they try it you
know yeah possibly to their own
detriment there you go well look I mean
this uh this sort of works into our our
next topic which is that on the uh the
last episode we had sticker Farmer on
and um and on that episode he was
talking about how the New York scene is
actually playing a huge role in what's
currently popular in the overall picture
of the states at the moment and we've
seen a rise in their distribution
especially in the Advent of the new
sprayed pack Revolution so what we're
actually seeing is that the New York
scene is playing a major role in
determining what is popular in terms of
distribution the issue is that many of
the New York stores and little bodegas
that are selling this cannabis are not
registered and are not technically legal
so The Blacklist has posted an
interesting article stating that last
week alone 75 of these stores have been
clamped down and closed and that's just
in the first week There's plans for
hundreds more of them over the coming
weeks or two so I guess the question
becomes does this positively or
negatively affect the scene having the
police crack down on these small
supplies many people have argued that
it's going to push the distribution back
onto the street which may benefit the
community what do we think I'll throw it
over to you
Jesse uh police cracking down on
anything doesn't help anything ever no
absolutely not no
um but uh yeah just just know I I don't
know like how how can that help anything
ever let let people compete um I know
it's probably pretty rough for a lot of
licensed Farmers dealing with the
situation over there because it's like
you go through all this effort and um
and anything kind of
goes
um my main concern is when when you get
to those kind of places where you end up
doing
something to uh anything goes or
something of like standards aren't good
with potency or other things are added
and things like that and it's like where
everything could be fine especially if
you did it from like a medical
perspective or um that if
anyone has issues then that ends up
being the detriment to that kind of uh
Freedom around the plant um so yeah I
definitely worry about a bunch of shops
just having anything go selling whatever
without any kind of Standards but at at
the same time like we've never really
seen regulations or police help anything
so um I I just always I missed the the
medical days here I think that should
have always been just strengthen the
rights around medical and the testing
and patient safety and quality and it
never should have been um this
recreational kind of concept with
um yeah I I just it just loses so much
it's over taxed it's over regulated it's
a broken system something that should be
profitable in California is completely
not everyone who's tried uh has has lost
all kinds of uh money and time and
effort and has tried so hard and um I'm
New York at this moment has a a much
more a lot more freedom but when things
go too far in One Direction and then you
get police cracking down um
yeah again I I don't think it ever helps
quality or anything when police come in
and do anything I think it's more about
people should be uh educated and and you
if if everyone's educated then people
are not going to want to go to the Shady
spots right like you're going to go to
the spot where you actually have
connection and so I think uh the
competition comes through quality
through standards through connecting
people with information um so I think
the the places that dedicate to that
will probably live through this the ones
that don't will make a little bit of
money for a little bit before uh things
kind of
change yeah and I'll I'll just quickly
add before I let uh Mr meanin take over
that I think one of the interesting
things about this is that there's been
so much rhetoric from you know the the
the uh the Cannabis control policy and
the roll out of um legalization in New
York and yet it seems like the rhetoric
doesn't match like to be like yeah we're
legalizing it and and of course you need
regulations but to immediately start by
clamping down on all these like
particularly mum and pop small sort of
you know they they're like most of them
are like bodas you know like they're not
they're not these huge Enterprises it is
it's interesting to see you know what I
mean like that the first step in them
sort of trying to roll it out is to just
sort of clamp down so hard but what's
your thoughts Mr main
Jane well like Jesse was saying like
we're with when we had Medical that was
there was you know there was weed
stores and they were operational and
everything was kind of going fine and
um yeah I
mean it's I don't
know the the way that
um the way that they set everything up
it really incentivizes people to do
things the wrong way in that if you have
a store you can imagine it's a lot
easier to to just go ahead and rent a
building and get a bunch of weed and
sell it from there and if you do it that
way you're going to be able to sell it
for really cheap you're going to be able
to sell everything you know it's cheaper
because you get it for Less you don't
have to test it you don't have any
responsibility if anything happens who's
is it we don't know it's just you know
these they're just these little burner
Bo Vega stores you know and
um if I don't know I feel like if if it
would have continued under the model
that was already kind of working they
could have just Incorporated
everything like in in California it
could have stayed this way and I think
it would have made a working model for
other places too to
where um I don't know that's it's a it
was a funny thought that I had and I
understand that there's it's a little
bit more it's it's a little different
than that but if you say um we legalized
weed right and
then we legalized weed and we have a
huge problem with the black
market like just let that like soak into
the brain for a second we legalized weed
but there's a huge problem with the
black market if you legalize weed how is
there a black market exactly so they
didn't legalize weed they
regulated and they
basically supercharged the black
market because there's so much incentive
to be in the black market and so little
incentive to be
legal so if they could have just taken
what was originally going on in
California under
215 everybody had incentive to go okay
this we're going to we want to create
clean products because we know that this
is going to everybody and it's basically
a medical system but because cannabis is
inherently medicinal regardless of any
conditions that you might have you don't
have to have anything wrong with you for
cannabis to be a medicine that you don't
for for food or water or clean air to be
medicinal they're inherently medicinal
things that are healthy and clean right
and like they say the the poison is in
the dosage you know like it's like it of
course everything can be maybe a little
bit out of out of hand but weed
surprisingly enough out of everything
I've ever discovered in the whole world
seems to be about the least harmful to
the majority of people who use it and
people are like oh oh well it makes some
people be schizophrenic and I'm like
yeah I believe that but like out of all
the people who I know who smoked weed
and were crazy they were [ __ ] crazy
and yeah smoke weed you could also say
like you know potato chips cause
schizophrenia because if you look at
schizophrenic people there's 15% of them
that they were eating a lot of [ __ ]
potato chips you know and so like
schizophrenia causes schizophrenia weed
just is not the right medicine for
schizophrenia it's not the best medicine
for it that's for sure because naturally
it does make you paranoid it can be I
could see how like that wouldn't be if
you're schizophrenic you're not like hey
dude smoke a bunch of haze or something
it's not the greatest thing to do but
probably like maybe straight CBD weed
might be really helpful you might find
some novel canabo combinations that if
you give them to somebody who is
schizophrenic and you believe that THC
triggered it you might discover that no
actually this is what happened but
there's no real studies on that being
done so there's these little things that
people say is harmful about it but
overall it's coffee and caffeine can be
really not great foral
illness te it happened I just saw this
thing I can't remember who it was but
one of these companies Panera or
something uh not to you know say that's
who it was but it was a company like
that had a really strong tea and they um
it was it was whatever I can't remember
what it was but it was like you know 300
milligrams in a cup and people are like
cool and they drink 12 cups and all of a
sudden they got a gram and a half or
whatever of of of caffeine in their
blood all at once and they have heart
failure and that's like caffeine is just
completely unregulated you can buy
bottles and no do and you can eat you
know whatever and it's no big deal you
know I think the the lethal dose of
aspirin is like uh 27 of the of the week
tablets or something like that like it's
like 12 extra or whatever you know and
um all these things they're just like
they're they're everywhere and there's
no big deal about it and weed was in a
position where it was basically like you
had a lot of incentive to go okay
instead of doing anything where I'm
going to take this and I'm gonna I'm G
to ship weed to Japan or sing poor or
whatever it was it was like no I have
stores that are around me and I can take
my weed and make sure it's really high
quality and compete in a natural
American sense of true capitalism and
bring it in and be like do you want mine
and they're like no it's not good enough
and you're like okay I need to improve
my product I need to improve my
marketing I need to improve my attitude
I need to improve the way I treat people
whatever the [ __ ] making your stuff
not sell it can be solved by doing good
capital Capital ISM the way you would
with anything else that you were making
but
they legalized it and now they have a
huge problem with the black
market it really wasn't like a big thing
at the time of 215 where it was like and
I will say that things had started to
get out of control but I think they got
out of control because there was only
these little tiny you can't take the
whole country and then just make it so
that it's actually like legal in just
California because what's gonna happen
California's going to become and remain
the huge production Center that it's
always been and it's going to dwarf
everything and everybody's going to go
there as the source for this product but
had they actually gone you know what
what was working in California seems to
be working pretty good let's do it
everywhere everybody within your own
state can all sell to medical patients
who is a medical patient anybody who
gets a benefit in their health mental or
physical from consuming cannabis
products and who is that that's almost
everybody as we were already saying
except for possibly a very small
minority of people and likely it's we
don't even know if that's if it's
causation or cor correlation it's not
necessarily determined so
um now you you have this situation where
in New York they're going through and
they're busting all these shops and
there's all these different shops if
they were under a 215 model all those
shops would have already paid to have a
shop they would go oh I mean we'd prefer
not to get busted but we can't jump
through all the Hoops of this of this
form of of legalization which is this
heavy regulation so if they would have
just modeled it the way of the working
system we already had that was producing
billions and billions of dollars then it
would they wouldn't be in the position
they were in now you would just have a
bunch of mom and pop bodegas who pay a
licensing fee to carry products that
have to be proven safe and effective and
then you'd be able to have everything
work and it would just be a huge
economy money machine it would just be
like just going cra crazy in all these
states but instead this little bit of
money funnels to these big uh Regulatory
Agencies and everybody else who's
involved with that side of it and
everybody is incentivized to have a
bodega and have it just be like we're
just going to sell [ __ ] until we get
busted and then they get shut down and
they probably go rent another place I'll
bet the bodegas that just got closed
I'll bet 20 to 80% of them will get
rented back out to new people people who
just set up weed shops in those same
exact locations and they'll just
continue to bust them and it'll just be
all goofy whereas under the like the the
model of having medicine for everybody
you know regardless of whether oh you
don't have to have cancer or whatever it
is that makes it a medicine it's a
medicine for pretty much everybody you
can go byy uh Tylenol PM you can go buy
Theraflu you can go buy aspirin you can
go buy all these things that are like
yeah they're give you liver failure you
can die they're gnarly they're addictive
in a real uh real physically dependent
way where it's like you actually really
need these but everybody can get them
everywhere and and it's kind of all good
um you know which of course now
hopefully that's not what happens to
weed where you have to be the aspirin
company to sell the weed which is
another step of Regulation that now
doesn't exist but uh I I just think that
was the real problem in places like New
York is that they legalize and everybody
goes it's legal now and in reality it's
there there's too much of a barrier to
entry for everybody to be able to have
it be like it was legal because we
living here saw what it was like when it
was basically legal and the economy
flourished everybody was involved
everything was competition and
capitalism in a healthy way there was a
lot of collaboration there was a lot lot
of tears of prices there was a lot of
different things that were going on and
it kind of which led to better weed farm
farmers get paid better better
connection with medicine the same kind
of community members coming in and and
guiding their choices for what works
with them and um and fresh weed coming
in that you could actually smell over
the
counter rolling pre-rolls right then um
instead of it all just being packaged
and sitting and distrib ution and um and
the farmers are losing the customers are
losing and so who's
benefiting yeah all
around that's it that's it well look
while we're on the topic of New York
I've seen an increasing number of photos
over the past few weeks of some very
funky colored weed and I think it's come
to the climax with uh we've seen a photo
doing the recently I'll flash it on the
screen of what looks like some
artificial colored moon rocks I'm sure
you guys have probably seen one or more
of these photos I guess the question
becomes do you think this is going to
continue on I mean when moonrocks
initially came out you could certainly
say they were bit of a fad you know they
didn't really stay around for very long
as a popular idea but I have to say I
have seen more and more of these
artificially infused snugs going around
and I have to think that it's because
they've likewise being infused with the
fake turps what do we think is this
going to be like the original moon rocks
and they'll fall off quickly or do we
think this might be here to stay because
the the turps sort of elevate it is that
picture blurred out because it's just
too offensive to we what's happening
that might be I blurred out its genitals
the genitals okay yeah I was gonna say
is that was that an exposed
anus there's a rule
Yeah well yeah it goes against the
community guidelines for
sure yeah that's wild
right yeah that's really hideous uh but
I have seen a bunch of these videos too
where you'll see a bunch of like pound
bags in New York and like some will be
completely purple and kind of this blue
and this yellowish like yeah I don't
know I wouldn't couldn't imagine having
anything to do with it yeah I mean I I
think I don't know what going on or why
no right yeah I mean products I think
people just naturally are like oh let's
try this let's try that I mean that weed
right there you could have kind of used
weed that you could probably buy for $40
a pound and then you can throw that
stuff on and be like I got a new thing
and if it moves you didn't really lose
very much and then you're like okay
let's go get the rest of those and we're
just going to throw some more garbage on
here and make some more fancy garbage
wheat because like you know I assume
somebody bought that sack and somebody
sold that sack you know it's a wild uh
it's a wild thing I mean over the years
I've seen people do a lot of really
silly stuff I mean I've seen people I've
seen people who really need a need a
little a little you know a a little
advantage or they really need to come up
real quick and I I've seen people do
some some trippy stuff you know I've
seen people make fake cash I've seen uh
i' I've been I can't remember if I was
oh yeah no no I was gonna say I sold
fake cash I was not sold fake cash like
in Lots or something or like no but I I
I was I I was down on hate Street when I
was a teenager I think I was probably 14
or something and we bought some fake
acid
and we ate it which of course could have
been the dirtiest acid ever luckily it
was fake and not bad because bad acid
sucks you know then you're now you're
just Meed out a couple dollars you know
killer clowns from outer space and [ __ ]
but we were we were sold bad acid which
like whatever acid's like five bucks a
hit or whatever you know what I mean but
we went back and we found this dude and
uh you know we weren't happy with him
and he wasn't comfortable with us and so
he gave us some fake hash to make up and
this hash was like ground up shake with
like honey in it or something you know
so it's like these little grams that
were like little you know when you when
you make a square gram of hash in your
in your hands or a little square of hash
you know or a diamond or whatever they
were little squares and they were just
straight green and I was like looked at
them and like heated it up and smelled
it and I'm oh there's this is like shake
and honey or something like that and uh
people are going to hustle you know
people are going to people make people
make fake crack you know they take like
they take like a almond or a walnut and
take the skin off and then they put like
ambasal on it so that when people go to
to test it it makes their tongue numb
and they're like oh that's real crack
rock and then you know by the time then
they're they're not there I was in
Hawaii one time and um I was buying
crack no I'm just kidding we were trying
to buy weed and we were at HOA on uh on
the North Shore of Maui and uh and uh my
friend was like oh these guys got weed
over there and I was like I mean you
know you could check it out and stuff
and they showed it to him and he was
like it's really like really resinous
Leaf but but it's weed but it's Leaf but
like you know bud Shake whatever you
know so he buys it for like 40 bucks and
then we get it back and we open it up
and we're like this isn't weed it had
tons of tricomes but they were not they
weren't they weren't caped they had no
nothing they were just they were just
little fuzz and it's a plant that grows
in Hawaii that they call cucko and they
sell it to people who don't know better
and when we went
back to get the money back from this
from this little little Filipino dude he
goes oh you got to go get my get your
money from my cousins and we look over
and these dudes sitting on a at a picnic
table down there and they were all like
400 pounds and super muscular big old
Hawaiian looking dudes you know and we
were like yeah well I looked at my buddy
and I go looked like you lost your 40
bucks you know and we left but like
people always try to figure out
something to do but what's Wild is
imagine if you could take the shake and
put the honey in it and create a
business and have it actually take off
and be a real thing that's what's
happening right now because bud has
become so affordable if it's of a lower
grade that people can now go get stuff
that's of a super low grade and they're
like oh well the colors off the smells
off that's it the color and the smell
guess what food coloring and spray turps
and now all of a sudden you're turning
you know $20 pounds into who cares what
who cares if it's a $80 p pound people
are still like dude I got this eth it
only cost me 20 bucks it's great look
and it's purple or this shit's blue I
wonder what they did what strand is this
you know and it's you just imagine like
the weird scam economy now and now you
don't have to sit at the picnic table at
HOA and sell cuckoo you can make a
telegram and a Instagram and a Facebook
and all these other things and reach all
these people and hey you needed the $40
sack of something and then people get it
and when they actually get it and smoke
it it's actually weed like not to us
it's not weed but to whoever bought it
and couldn't get weed before and they
just got this on the internet somewhere
they're like dude we're smoking proper
like look this shit's so good it turned
my hands blue you know people don't know
wa wait wait wait
wait the turning your hand blue is the
point where I thought that nobody would
go back for something but I don't know
you it is it is a step above um yeah I
guess like honey and oregano or whatever
the f yeah I mean I just imagine that
there's there's there's a lot of people
who like the the standard of what is
good weed was like dude I smoked it and
like I was
high you know that's it that's like
period I know you're waiting for more no
that's it I it was a we you know like
that's we used to have a joke there was
these people who there was these people
who were selling weed at like regga on
the river in the parking lot and it was
like not it was not very good and my
buddy had this had this Mexican weed
that was like really good for Mexican
like people would think that it was we
called it pretend because it people
thought it was like real real Cali weed
but it was not but it was like the kind
of weed where if you could have got it
now and sprayed it would have been like
oh this is great this is great weed it
just kind of it didn't add up to what we
what we thought was good weed and I used
to joke there was these it came from
this from these guys sitting in a
parking lot and they had this weed and
they were selling it and it was just
like very the quality was like it was
just like this weed was just dubious you
know you're just like you just look at
it and you just wonder like what what
are you guys doing what is what is this
weed and I my joke was you know for a
little bit more than you're going to pay
for that I can get you something that's
definitely weed you know like it's
that's the thing about this weed even
though like yeah it's blue it's sprayed
it's got this it's got that it's like
it's definitely weed and people get it
and they're like oh [ __ ] this is
definitely weed as opposed to like you
know some weed that I obviously have
been I've been there on multiple
occasions where we got some weed and it
was like I think it's weed but these
guys they're getting something that's
definitely weed you know it's blue but
it's definitely weed what an upgrade
what a good
slogan it's definitely weed definitely
weed 100% guaranteed definitely weed you
know it's just like uh sometimes it's
not and those those these people who are
buying the stuff I'm sure a certain
there's a certain amount of people who
are just like depending on where you're
at you're like dude I at least it was
weed you know at least it wasn't like
you know whatever whatever else it could
be so
I there you
go maybe maybe we need to actually uh
Wrangle one of these buds down and and
get Mr Mr Jean to do do the guinea pig
for
us yeah I definitely uh I definitely uh
yeah no
no is it
weird definitely we all right well on to
our next story we got a good one right
here so I'm sure many people have seen
the post but uh basically 710 has come
out with uh quite a daming post about
how they sent the same herb to five
different California labs and got widely
varying results from 14% THC at the
lowest through to
24% at the highest let me flash the
Right image here we go um so despite the
same plant and the same batch of nugs
being sent out they got widely varying
results and this is on a background of
the already suspicious variation between
cannabis Labs along with wildly
outrageous numbers posted from time to
time including the infamous state flower
headband 41% which we discussed in Prior
episodes overall this largely confirms
what people have suspected that not only
do you get a huge variation in the
testing of weed from one lab to another
but also that there may be components of
pay to play or corruption at hand given
that THC sells weed how rampant do we
think this problem is do we think that
we can really trust the values on a
cannabis jar that we see
I'll start off with Jesse what do you
think I I just would expect to like both
those numbers to be doubled with the way
testing has been like everything's 40%
now all of a sudden um but
uh I yeah that's that's a tough one um
there's multiple things that could be
happening
um but it definitely seems like
like phc levels just got like higher and
higher because that's what needed to
happen on the to sell and the shelves
and like you couldn't even be below as
25% or something uh and have it move on
the Shelf which is just Insanity um so
it's not just
like the believing the numbers but that
concept of it needing to be a super high
THC for some reason um I think it's it's
super useful for to know for certain
medicinal things and it also goes with
um good hash producers they tend to be
higher in THC in general and you see
different varieties that have have that
but it
uh to to have it be 14 to 24 I'm
surprised I'm I'm glad that certain labs
are testing that low still I guess that
that gives me some hope even though it's
so so uh varying um
but uh
I don't know
um I
don't paying for something or like
knowing that but I've seen a lot of
tests that were actually quite high that
had multiple um Labs test them and it
still was high so
um yeah I don't know the protocols of
the test did they
say did they give what what what other
information did they give on that sample
um and what what testing do they think
is correct on it yeah good question I
guess they didn't really State who out
of all the tests they feel is correct
but they just stated they just sent the
same buds from the same plant the same
Harvest to four different Labs so it
does point to what you're talking about
that the individual protocolization of
each lab clearly has some effect you
know if you know we're probably not
going to say it's the entire reason for
the VAR ility but it has to be at least
one of a
multifactorial sort of picture about
what happens but I guess the thing that
I was interested in is sort of asking
the the follow-up question about it
which is that um you know a lot of
people have been quite vocally critic
critical of uh the purple Pro the little
handheld modular THC testing unit and I
know that uh I've used one in the past
me Jean's used one in the past there are
some people out there who have been very
skeptical if not outright critical of
the accuracy of this unit but to me
these results seem to indicate what it
is which is that they fall within the
same range that the purple Pro often
gives and like you know for example I've
never seen the purple give like 30%
results um but it does often give
results between 18 and 26% you know
depending on the quality so I don't know
it makes me think what what can we trust
with the labs because there is such a
variation how do you even know which one
to go by maybe we do need some sort of
standardization across the board where
all labs and and and I'm sure that they
do to an extent but there would still be
variation um and then finally you know I
I I still think that the purple Pro is
accurate if you you know use it a lot
and then average the results but it does
beg the question you know what's
accurate testing at this
stage yeah I for accuracy um and just
like knowing Labs one of the the things
that I did over the years was uh test
multiple different clones from different
Farms the same clone at different farms
and did this this one where it was
actually kind of designed as a showing
Terre in different locations and uh one
was like in the forest with Bryson
Forest Farms another was uh dry farmed
um shiv area um uh high water farms and
then out in the mountains at Moon um
moonmaid farms and I did
four of the of similar varieties for
multiple years and I uh went to Samantha
Miller with pure analytics and even
though they were all just numbered and
went in different um the results were I
could look at him and I immediately knew
like okay well that is that's harasu
that's black dog that's Cherry Lime dog
that's Mandarin um the the turine
percentages were so close we're talking
about like 100 um the the canabo were so
close year after year and of the same
different varieties and I could see
slightly different leaning things from
the different um actual places that they
were grown like maybe the a slight
more uh CBD or terpinolene in in the
bryand forest Farm area a little bit
more THC uh in the mountains a little
more kilene and humulene and and Sh
shely area but they were all really so
similar that it was like wow this this
testing is quite accurate like to see
something three years of five different
varieties grown on on the different
farms and all of them fell exactly where
they're supposed to be from knowing that
plant over all those years uh exactly 20
to1
um uh CBD on the Harless Sue with .5%
cbdv and to get that each time multiple
years I think is accurate some of these
Labs absolutely can do that but when you
turn something into just a complete
business and all that matters is that
you have enough THC to make it go on the
market um and at dispensaries
then it's probably not going to be as
accurate anymore because it's become a
business instead of
science yeah and then it makes me wonder
too like okay so if you they do five
different Labs you know like
from like a scientific perspective you
go okay so what what happens if you give
five samples to each of the five Labs
that would the lab still would the 14.4
lab produce the
14.4 result every time if you had them
do tarpine testing would they show you
the same exact fingerprint of ratios of
of what it is every time and so that's
what's kind of cool like with what
you're saying Jesse is that you're
you're essentially testing the lab as
they're testing the weed because you are
submitting these samples which are
actually showing you know like that
that's actually a scientific process
what what you were doing because I
already know what they should be and
then they happen to fall right in there
even though it was totally blind going
in and then after year yeah they can't
just look and go oh wow this was gelato
41 so it should be right around in here
31 just go ahead and just write that in
you know like we'll just we'll just
metric wizard it you know and just
figure it out like uh and
then I I
recently read a couple things like the
SC Labs put up and it seems like they
have kind of dropped the hammer on Labs
as far as making them go through a lot
more
standardization
and um I don't know if that would be
different now or if those results that
we just saw if that was done now after
this so-called standardization and um
I'm a little curious about that too but
uh as far as the purple Pro goes when I
used it what I had was I had uh grape
soda skunks and I had a few different
other things too we tested some various
things that I kind of knew roughly like
this is a high THC plant and this isn't
and whatever and then we were able to
see like oh okay yeah 24% cool 21% and
test it three or four times and see that
and then go okay now let's jump to this
plant over here and see what that is so
we were doing like grape soda skunks
that I knew from having smoked ones in
the population and none of them got me
high but all of them made me feel good
and I was like these seem and I had seen
tests from labs for a couple of the
plants over the years where it was like
some of the Pia and some of the grape
soda skunks that had the real purple
stems and a certain type of throwback
plant to a certain part of the the the
heritage in it it was like okay these
are just CBD plants and so I was able to
go okay let's take the green Pia that's
more of like kind of a super silver hazy
looking thing and let's test this one
and I'm like and I'm sitting there with
skunk Tech and I'm like this one should
say THC and you put it in and it comes
up and it's like High Teens low 20s High
Teens low 20s you keep doing it and then
I'm like okay this should be the same
this one like this and then go okay now
here's these grape soda skunks that I
know these and then do them and then
it's like 15% CBD 177% CBD 133% CBD and
it's just all CBD and lower than 3% THC
basically
non-detectable and then go okay now
let's test Mr Bob's um Puck bc2 and then
test that and it's like 25% THC and then
test it again 23% THC you know grinding
up new samples of the same bud and
seeing and you do when you do it like
that it's like undeniable that there's a
certain level of accuracy because
otherwise it would be like now let's
jump back to the grape soda skunk we
just tested and now it's going to say
that it's 21% THC no CBD but nope we're
right back in here 14% CBD so by doing
it like that I was able to go wow this
is cool and I don't know how accurate it
is as far as being able to tell you
there's this much of this in it but it
was useful for me to be able to go okay
so these grape soda skunk this
population has become true breeding for
CBD dominance for me that was valuable I
didn't need to know if it has 8% or 22%
and whatever it is it's more about like
that profile of knowing the ratios is
this CBD weed is it THC weed is it one:
one is it two two to one whatever it is
you know and so for me the purple Pro
was plenty useful to be worth the price
tag which you I the plants that we pl
that we tested that day they paid for it
right there in a regular lab just to
know the ratios but that was because of
what it was for me to do I wouldn't say
like if you have a store that you should
test with that but as like a breeder who
just wants to know did we go see BD did
we go
THC um it was it was really useful you
know I believe you could probably
reverse your mails and see what the
especially if you were careful and you
you pulled off the most resinous parts
and put it in there as long as you can
get above the 3% which is that which is
the floor on what they test for below 3
THC it doesn't show up below 3 CBD it
doesn't show up but if you can get like
if you could reverse your males and you
were trying to do like CBD or THC work
you could go okay well this maale it
doesn't show any CBD but it shows a
decent amount of THC or that you know
either way you could figure that out and
it could be useful for that as well um
but I don't know about like real
specific stuff and then I know too that
the
way that it works is
basically accessing a data base of known
numbers which it's been you know it's
like the correlation to what these tests
that were already done using more
traditional standards and then it goes
okay well when the laser hits
this it gave us this
profile uh this whatever whatever it was
this little graph of light of whatever
it was the reflection off of it and that
is something that always is 23% in the
labs so it's also going to be reliant on
previous
lab um numbers as I understand it so if
the labs were super inflated then the
way it works could also maybe inflate
everything a little bit as far as I know
because it's not actually testing the
weed it's finding a light signature from
the reflection off of the weed and
correlating it with known
data from previously collected samples
that were tested in a real lab and then
it and I as far as I know I think it's
like comes from mineral testing
technology where you can say oh when the
laser hits this and comes back like this
we know that this is this is whatever
this you know this is these these
certain minerals this is opal this is a
diamond this is whatever you know that
they use I think that's what it
originally came from but I'm not
positive I just think I remember that at
some point so um you know that could
skew everything too having these
previous data and that's what it's
running on but as far as a cool tool
like I want one you know and the only
reason I don't have one at this point is
because I didn't want to spend the money
on it and I don't use that kind of data
that much like you can see from if you
hear my story I'm like this Pia is high
THC test it it's high THC this grape
soda skunk super resonance doesn't get
me high it's high CBD tested it's high
CBD so like I didn't really learn
anything but it did tell me what was
going on and it could be cool for things
like I said like reversed males where
you're actually like okay I managed to
collect enough of this actual material
that had a lot of resin that I can get
above the 3% threshold and now I can see
what the ratio is on a mail or there I I
see really good uses for it what about
just sending in the the leaf sample of a
top of a mail to a lab and then figuring
out your ratio from there yeah and
that's great but multiply by 10 it gives
you a little idea or no all that's
always perfect it's just the matter of
that has a cost so like for me if I can
go ahead and buy this thing and it cost
you know a couple Grand and then I'm GNA
sit here and go and test a whole bunch
of stuff then it would be really useful
for that I could see that being like a
good thing but like you said you know
whatever it is I think you your plant
gets to be what 80 days old and it and
and at that point it has a certain ratio
the lab can detect and then you
basically just figure it was 1% THC and
2% CBD and then you know you got a 10
and 20 if it's around a 100 days or 80
days is that how that works that's
that's pretty basically it yeah yeah so
I mean that's cool but then when I do
that like if I have a super cool lab and
they're giving me a great deal as soon
as I go ahead and test a certain amount
like I'm at this I I've spent this much
money and then with like the the purple
Pro it like it just continues to work
and there's no real resources it use
it's just keeps on you can test so many
you know so but reversing males is a bit
of effort I guess it it is but like um
like um shaut at 707 seed bank he just
reverses all his males and
um if you have if you have like I have
like several males that I'm I'm growing
I'm growing the progyny from them which
I kind of would want to do anyway even
if I had already smelled it and knew
that it was pretty good and knew that I
still want to see like what passes and
what it worked with and so for me it's
not like as attractive of a thing just
because I'm always going to do the rest
of the work anyway it's kind of like the
sex testing thing like I'm going to
going to grow the Ma I'm going to grow
them till they're males no matter what
so it never has worked for me it works
for different people in different
situations but um it would still be neat
to go like right now I have a cloned
lime pop Kush mail from last year I have
a cloned grape soda skunk I have a
cloned uh Meer limsky like some new
clones that I just took last year and I
made stuff with them and I'm already
growing the seeds from them but right
now while I have copies of them it'd be
easy to set some aside and then go ahead
and like test all of them at the same
stage and go whoa this one's like really
high in THC or like the grape soda skunk
if I had like a bunch of the males and I
went ahead and just took a clone off
each and reversed them then I could go
these are all good they're all CBD
dominant but wow this male is producing
6% and the rest aren't even registering
then it would be like this one makes a
lot of cannabinoids it's cool for that
and and among males that could be more
useful because for me with females it's
all about how good they are I don't
really care about the lab result like
it's interesting to see the reason why I
like it might have a correlation with
some kind of chemical but as far as
whether or not it's a valuable plant or
a keeper like I'm I'm gonna do all that
by just being like I like the plant and
I won I won't change my mind if someone
goes dude that plant you said was so
good it's only 11% THC I'm going to be
like still 11% is some killer weed you
know like that that just I just learned
from the plant I'm not going to learn
anything from the lab results but
there's still a lot of cool things to do
with it and like um honestly beyond all
of the utility of it it's hella fun to
test you just sit there and you grind it
up and you go oh and then it gives you a
number and it's kind of just like a
video game or something you're just hey
a number a number like it's something
for your brain you know you're like 133%
oh let's do another one yeah and then
seeing the Target and seeing how it
works and it was kind of just neat like
knowing that somebody made this really
trippy invention and that regardless of
whether or not it's like super accurate
it was like whoa it's right here on my
kitchen table this is pretty pretty neat
you know yeah hit my dopamine receptors
in uh in just the right way there you go
yeah you know you're get oh there we go
look while we're on the topic of
percentages and uh turps that sort of
works very nicely with our next topic
yeah you're gonna turn on your light and
everything oh I'll have to flash back we
are we are no
long slowly disappearing yeah I I like
the idea you were you know burning the
candle oil in the midnight it was it was
good um but onto our next story uh jbzy
recently L put up a post saying the way
to set yourself apart in the current
market is to dial in your post Harvest
process and to preserve those TPS sounds
fairly straightforward doesn't it but I
guess what it shows is that clearly this
is an area where others could be doing a
bit
better is this one of the big sticking
points for small companies that are
struggling to make a crack in the market
or is this more a message targeted for
larger companies what is your sop mized
I'm going to throw it over to me Jean
first
quickly
um
well
uh
like if I was a viking right now and I
knew where to go like find unicorn horns
I'd be like dude don't tell everybody
this [ __ ] like you're ruining it for
everybody don't tell them it really is
it really is like a huge part of how all
of it um how all of it work works I mean
if if you
grow weed and you know people who grow
weed you've seen a lot of people
who
um they grow weed and they don't really
do anything wrong and you go over there
and you look at their weed and it's
almost done and you're like wow this is
one of the best grows I've ever
seen and then they say hey I got some
weed or you tell yourself hey we got
this weed and then you see it and you
you go what happened here like how did
we get from there to here and there's so
many places to go wrong you know um
basically
Harvest people say post Harvest but it's
actually also the actual Harvest timing
as well you really want to know a plant
if I grow a clone I like to like cut a
if I if I have multiple ones I'm I want
to harvest them over across the window a
little time span to see differences and
if I only have one plant of it I like to
cut part of the plant and then leave it
and cut another part of the plant and I
like to cut a little bit of what I look
at the plant and go this is too early
you're not supposed to cut it yet and
then I like to leave a little bit of it
at the point where you go don't leave it
this is going to go bad and I like to
have a few stages in between and by
doing that you can go oh this one gets
better way later than I thought it was
gunu and it actually improved when I
would have normally thought the quality
was just going to drop and with other
ones you might cut them earlier than you
would think would be what is ideal and
all of a sudden go oh I didn't you know
even if it's something you've previously
grown and you try cutting it a little on
the early side or a little on the late
side you might discover that you've
never seen this weed the way it's
supposed to be just Harvest timing and
once you cut it for Harvest Time CL in
and get it where you think it's perfect
and you've already done this and you're
actually trying to produce this plant
like produce weed off this plant
then people put it up they don't have a
good room and some people have a good
room but they don't have enough room and
then it gets to the point and they look
at it and they go this is dry and they
put it away and then they go it's okay
to put away we're going to burp it it's
all right because it's still going to
dry it's going to finish this stuff it's
gonna we're gonna leave all the leaves
on it we're going to remove all the
leaves it's okay we half green trimmed
it so it's GNA do well like this people
have all these different ideas and um in
a lot of case people cases people are
putting the weed away thinking it's dry
when it's
not extra moisture leads
to like very small time compost toasting
of your weed it's like fermentation yeah
if there's a little bit of extra
moisture then you're going to have
compounds being produced in your weed
that should have never been produced and
your weed's going to be sitting in gases
that are like alcohol based and you're
not even G to be getting it's not
sitting with what it's supposed to be
sitting in there's stuff that comes off
of weed after it's all the way dry that
when the weed sits in it for a little
bit the weed is getting like marinated
in goodness and that's what you get when
you have weed and it's all the way dry
it's all the way perfect and you put it
away and you let it sit for two days two
weeks two months three years depending
on what the weed is you know I have this
weed in my fridge and it was like some
of the worst weed I've ever seen based
on what my mind tells me about what
should be good weed it's the opposite of
when you see something that looks like
animal cookies or you know something
really incredible you just look at it
and you go oh it's really drab and it
has really dark red hairs and there's
not much visible resin and it was like
really plain and really nothing to it
and I've had it put away now
for uh 15 years in the fridge and now
when you smoke it it is the tastiest
weed to me that I've like ever had and
it must have been some kind of a haze or
other you know crazy equatorial thing
hybrid and when you smoke it now it's
like you smoked some kind of incense and
it just completely sticks in your mouth
and your nose and you just it's just
everything is this and it was because
it's sad and sat and so post Harvest it
had a really weird you know it did it
wasn't like that for a while and then it
became like that and that's what people
say a lot of times about things that are
sativas that they get better with a cure
and I haven't seen that with that many
things because I don't have that many of
them but in this case it's definitely a
thing and it just has it just is as good
as it's ever been and um it's really
common that uh people treat everything
the same and like even me tend to tell
you that weed is the best when it's
fresh curing weed to me is a little bit
of a myth it does pay off in the case of
certain weird especially like sativa
type things um and some things like say
if they have tons of tur pineline if you
can like let the terpinolene off gas for
like a whole year at room temperature
then you'll pull out the weed and it'll
be like oh this has this the craziest
thing happens when it sits and it turns
into these new combinations of these
chemicals sitting with each other and
you wind up with these crazy flavors and
smells that are amazing but
um a lot of people think and it's kind
of something that happens to you
especially when you first start growing
you think that if your weed gets too dry
it's going to ruin it but it can really
only be ruined at a temperature high
enough to evaporate off the things you
want and if those things evaporated
easily then we they wouldn't ever really
make it to when you're smoking them so
like for the most part dry is not the
enemy dry is only the enemy if it
happens too fast so in places like
Colorado where there's really low
humidity they have to really be careful
if I lived in Colorado I would have
humidifiers in my drawing room if I
lived in Washington state I would have
dehumidifiers in my drying room because
there's a sweet spot where you want the
weed to dry at a certain rate and what
happens when it dries at a certain rate
and I always tell people this is your
weed becomes tempered the way that they
temper steel using using using heat and
and Co like Stone they use heat
treatment wood they use heat treatment
Kil drying like there's these different
processes that make things be uh stuck
in in the right State and if they go too
fast to that state or they go too slow
to that sweet spot then everything just
gets [ __ ] up so if you can actually
have the right rate of it drying when it
gets to a certain point of being dry
that's it for most things it's not going
to really get worse unless it gets like
heated up and sits in the Sun and it's
not really going to get better unless it
has a really specific
chemical profile that has things that
actually have been post Harvest and they
do exist but it for the most part
there's a thing that happens where your
weed just gets perfect and now it's
perfect and you can put it away and
ideally you need to put it away like in
a refrigerator or an air conditioned
room where everything stays below 65 or
whatever it is to make it stay really
nice and if you can keep it a lot of
people used to bury their weed in the
ground in drums and if it's a really
wooded area and you get your and you put
your weed away you can pull it out and
it'll be like surprisingly fresh but if
you rush the process a tiny bit and you
put it away with a tiny bit too Mo too
much moisture and we're talking a couple
percent here we're talking like if it's
just slightly too moist then it'll go
bad so basically you want to remove all
the moisture almost without removing any
of the oil and the process to do that is
by having it be slow and steady on the
dry but if it's too slow then the
moisture hangs around too long in the
beginning of the drying process and does
the same thing it would do if you put it
away when you thought it was dry later
on in the process so you also need to
get it dry fast enough it's not just dry
it as slow as you can no because it's
going to dry too slow but back in the
day everybody always thought if I leave
it up and it gets too dry it's going to
be ruined and then what people would do
is they'd come in and they go oh the
weed it's too crispy and they would
panic and not realize like dude open the
door stuck put a fan in the door wait
till nighttime comes when the humidity
not in Colorado but here when the
humidity Rises at night and that fresh
air blows in you can go back in and
you'll discover that hey now it's at the
point point where it's as dry as it can
get without falling apart and crumbling
and crushing in your hands and now take
it down and then go take it and put it
wherever you have that's the most
controlled and because a lot of times
when you take you take the big room full
of weed and you put it all into being
like these big big wires of weed and you
now you have it in bundles or whatever
you can take those and you can fit them
in a in a in a even maybe a better
environment
so what a lot of people they see that
done and they think that the name of the
game is all we got to get it out of here
and put it in there but if you do that
and it's a little bit too moist then
same thing too much moisture it can't
leave it's all stuck and then you get
things spoiling again so people who
really know what they're doing can
preserve their weed like you know like I
always call it scientific grade it's
like this is a specimen
and this is the closest thing to being
perfectly preserved as we can get it
whereas a lot of the weed the most of
the weed you'll ever see in your life it
was either ruined 5% it was ruined 10%
it was ruined 80% there's a certain
level of quality that it was when it was
alive and then you [ __ ] that up by
cutting it too early or cutting it too
late and then you [ __ ] that up by
handling it rough when you cut it down
and then you [ __ ] that up by not getting
it hung up and processed and then it
becomes limp during the processing stage
and now you've just ruined it right now
because you know you can ruin weed
before you ever hang it up and it
happened in a couple hours because it
was laying in a pile limp or whatever it
is and then your weed becomes bruised
and gets messed up you can cut all the
leaves off and green trim it when it's
all the way fresh and now you've just
taken something that was all enclosed
and you've opened it up to where the
juice that's inside the plant which is
what you smell when you mow your lawn
that juice in the whole handling process
now if you were to be super careful and
you have the right weed with the right
moisture content at Harvest and it's
crisp enough you can get away with green
trimming your weed and having it come
out good enough to Tri trick you into
thinking it's just as good as trimming
it when it's dry but in most cases when
people green trim that's not going to be
the case because when you handle wheat
you have to cut the leaves off then you
have to put it in a tub or grab it as a
big bundle now you have all this juice
That's supposed to never come out of the
plant that's rich in chlorophyll and all
this other [ __ ] and it's all going on to
the weed on the outside of the weed and
it's just not what you should have like
my analogy for it was always if you take
rose petals and you dry a rose hole and
you pull them off you get like pop Perri
it'll smell like dried rose petals if
you dry a rose whole it'll smell like
rose petals if you take a rose and you
chop up the petals green and dry them
it'll just smell like vegetative matter
and that's another place that people
make a big mistake during Harvest and um
between all those things that I've
mentioned you can really you can really
like if you master all those little
details you can make everything be
really nice but if you do those things
and a number of other things I mean
trust me I found lots of ways to ruin
weed you can have you can dry in an area
where you don't realize your intake is
pulling in wood smoke from your wood
stove you can do all kinds of different
stuff I I had this year I had a leak in
my room that I didn't realize was there
and my humidity spiked so bad that a lot
of the weed that I had that was still in
that particular room it was all turning
in there and it wasn't as quality as it
should have been and I just did that
just now and it luckily it doesn't
really matter to me because I wasn't
super attached and I already had big you
know shopping bags full of smoke for
myself and I'm cool but at the same time
I was like oh that weed was really nice
and it's still way better than any of
the stuff you'll ever see with blue dye
on it and whatever stuff it's still like
it's weed but it's not you know it's
never you can't like pull it out and go
this is what it should look like if you
can pull out weed and show people hey
I'll bet you've never seen what weed
should look like and then you it's like
you know like of course my my fat kid
analogies with I always say something
about pizza but imagine like if you all
all the time you've only ever had frozen
pizza and then all of the sudden you
went to like a really really good
Pizzeria and you got a piece of pizza
you'd be
like oh man you know like in that same
place not going to do the same business
if they're selling the frozen pizza that
you go get at the supermarket it's just
not the same thing but when you look at
it you go it's kind of the same thing
isn't it and that's what most people
have with their weed they have something
that is kind of the same thing but that
little bit that separates it is a huge
difference and that's the same in wine
food whatever it is and people who know
no and people who don't it just doesn't
matter some people hate would hate the
pizza at the nice place and so fine have
something for them too but if you really
want to be super competitive you have to
know exactly what the finer details are
of all that stuff and so
jbz is right but he shouldn't tell
people and I shouldn't tell people
either because it starts to close the
gap and then all of a sudden all these
people it's like hash making now
everybody knows how to make hash for a
while people were like dude it's 250 a
gram you've never seen nothing like this
and people were like dude look at this
and now people are like yeah everybody
got a washing machine and a freeze dryer
and they find somebody who grows a cool
strain and all of a sudden there's a lot
of hash makers that are making hash that
10 years ago you would have been like
whoa that's crazy dude and now it's just
like you know I should say 15 years ago
but it's it's a trip because uh you know
that it does people learn and that's
cool because people should have the best
weed but I want to see people having the
best weed who are growing it and smoking
it I don't really want to see like the
mega corpse go oh so wait a second
here's what the edge we need you know
but luckily it's hard for them to pull
it off anyway
so there you go we got to make sure that
their mids stay mids I guess yeah keep
mids
mids I don't know if that's a secret
it's always been secret is like just
cure it well actually speaking of that I
I I toured the um Glass House spot one
time and it was like all of this money
to to grow all all of this we and just
huge production and all kinds of workers
and then I see the the dry room and it's
just pathetic and way too small and was
like what the [ __ ] like all of these
huge green houses and you don't and and
I see that that's been so pervasive
throughout all the years it's just like
grow all of this weed all this into like
the growing of it and then how do you
take care of it at the end and it's like
would you call it scientific weed or
scientific grade or scientific grade you
know what I me scientific gr totally
yeah and I can see those jars like oh
that's a jar that like you some jars
somebody might want you to like oh go in
and pull that nug out and crunch it up
and smell it like I can see those jars
are like oh no that's s that's that's
science grade you're like I would only
touch that with like tweezers and pull
out the like by the stem and observe it
and because not one Tricom has been
damaged in the process you know that
somebody's taken that care in it and uh
that whole like indoor outdoor thing I
think that's always been really like the
the quality is based on the end of the
Cure it's not like indoor is better in a
certain way or it looks certain but
there's but maybe put more care into
that uh that Harvest and then to make
sure that nothing's damaged because you
spent more on it and it's a smaller
scale and then you put on the line where
nothing else is touching it and you make
sure that you don't do anything to
damage tricomes and you're not
pre-trimmed
cool temperature and you know as long as
it's like between 50 and 60 both
humidity and and uh temperature although
right off the bat I always that first
day or two go a little bit drier I might
do like 45% and then go to 50 and kick
it right back to 55 and then have it
hover right there but keep it in that
like below 60 uh 50 and 60 the whole
time temperature the Le the less
fluctuation you get in that temperature
the better and then when you get it
right at that right point and that's
probably about 10 % uh moisture so 9% a
safer uh putting away 8% is going to be
really safe uh 12% you might have a
little more tpine but make but you have
to smoke it pretty quick then so you
don't use the little packs that you can
get I won't say the name but you put
them in there and they keep your weed
60% humidity correct is that a real
question is that why the is that why's
always squishy and brown I always
wondered about that no uh I don't use
those things but um
yeah but then yeah putting it into a jar
and putting it in the fridge at that
point right where you got it I I do
think um it's really about you get it
perfect and then you slow it down as
much as possible yes and and also to
your point too there's certain
terpinolene like I had some of the um
Athena sue the Harless Sue Athena
crosses from way back when I even had
some sitting in a shelf because it was
so pretty and purple just like almost
like a a flower bouquet like in a
uh just in a little jar or something
just sticking out off of its stem and uh
it like a big three years later it still
fully smelled it was so like dark purple
but certain just sitting out completely
certain uh tpin last a lot
longer um certainly trinoline is one of
them but yeah I think it's just getting
to that that spot where you you you just
put all that care into doing the least
amount of damage to it once you you've
grown it and then and then you put it
away dry enough to not actually ferment
and decompose and change colors how you
won uh three different years at the
emerald cut or third second and first I
imagine those um entries you took a lot
of care and like that nug was going to
be your entry from the beginning uh and
you did everything because a lot of
people probably like oh yeah this bag's
pretty good and and grab something from
entered that way you I'm assuming you're
like that's the nug I'm going to take
that down and I'm going to put all that
love into it because all you have to do
is put in an ounce or whatever it is so
like you're you're choosing and hand
trimming each one of those by yourself
I'm sure and right at the point where it
makes sense to do that curious what that
process is like holding the stem and
then you know I need to remove this Leaf
I need to remove this leaf and then when
it's done it's like it's you know it is
a specimen it's like if you you know
what I mean like you can go out and like
go duck hunting and and you know shoot a
duck and your dog goes and brings it
back not that I like I don't hunt Ducks
but you know if you actually wanted to
get like a specimen for like you know a
museum and go okay we're gonna Taxidermy
this duck then you're probably gonna go
out and probably like net a duck and
then you're going to figure out okay how
do you get you know you're going to want
to have it just wind up being perfect
and that's why I say it's like
scientific you know it's like you want
this thing that you've just captured
from nature to basically stay as close
as you can get it to being preserved
perfectly and that's like why the whole
hash movement now is so cool because
they figured out all these tricks to
make that work to where you're you're
basically capturing the heads and you're
just getting them and you're fit and
then you know was like people were like
oh you take it and you put it in here
you dry it it's like well now it's been
dry the weeds dry dry weed creates weed
dust green dust um it's the they they
dry slower things are different and then
you know like you you do there's a
certain amount of of course like off
gasing and different stuff that's
happening and whereas when people take
weed and they just very carefully cut it
fresh remove everything
get get that resin away from the weed as
soon as possible and then put it by
itself and then get it dried as
perfectly as possible whether it's in a
cold room and it's been microplaned or
screened or whatever or it's put in a
freeze dryer it's like it's this is as
as as good as you can get it and that's
the same concept with flour if you can
treat your flour like you're trying to
capture it like you would with hash then
it's like oh it's as clean as possible
it's handled minimally it's like you
just want it all to be just perfect you
don't want it ever L like you know with
if I want to show you like the very best
bud you'll ever see I have to go where
it's standing up and then I have to grab
the stem cut it underneath flip it
upside down without touching anything
and then hang it up on something without
ever touching anything and then when I
take it off the hanger I'm not going to
touch it it's not going to touch touch
anything and my scissors are only going
to touch it in the place where I'm
actually doing a removal of some piece
of the plant and then all said and done
you just wind up with this thing and it
looks exactly as it should it's totally
preserved and by having weed that's like
that people don't see weed that's like
that it's not what you wind up getting
and that that's just the mechanical
handling of it that has nothing to do
with the environmental factors that
cause it to be like I said like be like
a tempered Pro product you know and like
all the weed that I've ever seen from
you I could look right at it and I knew
how I I know exactly what you did I know
that you did all the stuff that I'm
describing because I look at it color
smell resin everything about it you look
at it and you go oh okay somebody who
got this wanted to preserve what it was
and they wanted to get it when it was
good and the first times I saw your weed
you had like Flats of jars and you open
it up and you go oh I know exactly what
it is genetically because there's not it
hasn't been taken down and even when we
do our best I'm sure we're probably
hitting like 80% or 83% or whatever like
they say in general with plants like
growing plants it's likely that we only
as humans the way our brains work the
way the world is we probably only ever
achieve a certain little percentage of
the potential of a plant like when we
see something and we go oh that's you
nailed that nailing it is probably
getting it like 30 or 40% as good as it
could be if we knew every single thing
of trying to get this balance of these
minerals and giving it this enzyme and
this amino acid and then putting it in
whatever like a a a lower pressure
environment like growing it in half
gravity or we don't know we only can do
this and so like when we look at our
weed we're like yes we nailed it and
it's a and it's a this is a 95 this is a
83 and we're so stoked but that's like
out of what we know and they say that
it's really likely that we've never
actually genetically achieved higher
than probably like 20 or
30% o of what plants can really do and
it's crazy to imagine like so what
people keep making all these strides in
growing where back in the day people are
like yeah you know I got 6 ounces off a
light and then people were like you need
to get a pound off a light and then
people were like a pound of light you
should be getting at least two pounds of
light and now people are like no two
pounds of light that's not that good you
know and like it just keeps on going and
going and then it gets at the point
where it's like it's supposed to be like
this and like as far as we've seen we
don't even we don't even know but at
least you wan to you want to do what we
know is good you know and not have it be
Ms you
know one
day I was about to say one day we'll get
to like the 49 day 5 kilo blue dream or
you suck at
growing then that'll be mens no all
diversity you said scientific grade but
it's also artist grade because like just
putting that kind of love and intention
into something and
sculpting it and and just that that
level of care of not damaging and
preserving the thing that you you work
towards and and that can present yeah
and I mean I consider like active
Hands-On science to be as artistic of a
Pursuit as regular art and I consider I
consider like really engaged art to be
as scientific as science is like doing
anything artistic is very scientific
because it's it's uh all cause and
effect and it's taking note of what
happened when you did this somebody who
learns to sketch really well they're
100% scientifically minded because they
conduct the experiment and they have the
result and they observe it and they
figure out what went right with it and
what went wrong with it and then they do
it again and they do it again and they
do it again and it's the same thing with
s science it's like you don't just um I
mean of course there's a lot of types of
art that are just utility and there's a
lot of types of science that are just
utility but both at their finest levels
are basically the same process because
it's all about trying to have a good
idea execute it as well as you can and
then try to you know like you you you'd
like to innovate in a way that will take
it higher and that you'll actually learn
something and in both Pursuits if you
have the Good Fortune for them to really
work out then you're going to wind up
with this thing that everybody goes whoa
and kind of um uh like that Wonder
that's really what like is the like I
believe kind of that the whole point
like people are like what's the meaning
of life I'm like well everybody knows
you know you're gonna live we all know
we're going to live we're going to die I
think like everything is kind of like
all one big
one big thing like one big blossoming
flower or one big blossoming mushroom or
those are just analogies of what's going
on and everything is just trying to like
experience something and when you can do
something that actually gives you like
that Wonder of going holy [ __ ] that's
like the universe kind of like it's
blossoming for a second you know so it
might happen in like the tiny the tiny
stuff or the big stuff but with like Art
and Science both of them are like this
thing where you know like you're
experiencing it on this with this level
of Wonder and if you've ever been like
you know super blasted on
hallucinogenics or whatever you kind of
sit there and you
go whoa you're like this thing's
happening you know and with with like
crazy art or science if somebody tells
you about it or you see it occur it's
the same thing it's this feeling of
Wonder like and and that's what magic is
you know and like you people always
think like magic is a dragon magic is
like this like no all this there's all
this magic is just constantly like like
you know it's blossoming it's blossoming
like a big giant corpse flower sometimes
and you see like a volcano go off and
sometimes it's blossoming like a lilac
where it just has all these tiny little
flowers and they're all in a big cluster
and you don't even really notice you
just see this big thing and there's all
this stuff happening inside but like
that's the whole thing of like being
really into a thing is to is for like
The Wonder of it you know and that's
what you get when you when you have like
something that you do on a artistic or
scientiic level in this case with the
weed you're just like oh man like this
really worked and it's crazy and then
when you just have like a giant massive
grow and you're like well everything
only get gets three hour three days in
the real drawing room then we're going
to put it in tubs then we're going to
burp it then we're going to run it three
through then you've left you've left
that area of Wonder and you've moved
into utility and utility has
utility but by
definition it doesn't have wonder you
know it's not there's no magic you're
like you've killed the [ __ ] magic so
that's cool a lot of people need weed
great but if you really want to you know
look Jesse's gone dark
now Sun's going
down the magic
magic point my battery might die soon
too um yeah absolutely the Magic in like
everything like I'm just like just
wandering around the the garden and I I
think it's kind of a magic it's like
you've made these agreements with these
different plants okay you're going to
grow here and you're going to grow like
that and like and they just kind of end
up doing it that way like some mint
might want to take over somewhere but
you're like no this is kind of the
boundary and that that starts to happen
and I just all kinds of little things
like that just all the magic in the soil
or like making some seeds and then
somebody grows them in Australia and
then they had the best luck with them or
something it's it's pretty it's it's all
this like wild Magic
and the science is completely part of
that too the constant observation I love
how you like talking about like
harvesting each different nugs at
different times too and leaving some on
and seeing that point that's optimal and
if it's all about production you're not
going to actually innovate to that point
that is a little bit better you finding
that it always having that W of of
observation to find own something or
just to know something better uh get
gets lost when it's just
production hugely look I think we can
tell that uh your your battery is about
to die so maybe with that we might wrap
it up for this episode so again a
massive shout out and thank you for our
incredible guest uh Jesse of biovortex
for joining myself and me and Jean for
the third episode of not in my bag
before we wrap it up any final words
gentlemen
yeah don't forget the magic do things
with
love I love it and yourself main Jean
yeah I mean agreed I I don't have a lot
to add to it except that uh yeah I mean
I think that's the that's what uh sets
stuff apart for you know people to enjoy
it and also for you to enjoy it yourself
as you're trying to bring it to other
people you know you have to have uh a
level of uh enthusiasm and and you know
enjoy what you're doing and I think it
works out to works out to make
everything
better that's it 100% And my final
message play more seeds smoke more
sativas how fitting it's gone completely
black on Mr Jesse I think with that one
we'll wrap it up I'll see you all for
the next one right on thank you Jesse