[Music]
all right all right all right welcome
back my friends for another episode of
not in my bag your number one news spot
for all things cannabis discussion
recent events and more as always you're
joined by your boys mean of mesino heavy
days from the upside down library and on
today we are thrilled to be joined by a
Man Who memes harder than mean Jean
himself dare I say it the sticker
captain and coniss Sir the OG in the
diecut game and the man behind all those
incredible bags you've no doubtedly seen
and maybe even purchased a big welcome
to Mr Sticker Farmer for joining us
today this is just a quick one today
he'll be back for another app but in the
[Music]
meantime all righty hello and welcome to
the second episode of not in my bag your
number one cannabis news and current
affairs discussion show as usual I'm
grateful to be joined by my co-host with
the most Mr mean jeene of mesino and on
today's episode we are extremely
thrilled to be joined by a huge name in
the industry a guy Who memes maybe even
harder than mean Jean which is hard to
believe a massive thank you to sticker
Farmer for joining us on the show today
how you doing thank you thank you for
having me I appreciate
it that's a big compliment comparing me
to Jean that's that's a little out of my
league there I know he me you meme way
harder than me you know I Meme here and
there try to have a little bit of meing
going on but you know you got some some
threads on there the there's some epic
there's some epic I might put up more
memes than you but your memes hit pretty
hard and you've definitely been someone
that
um inspiring
me what happened here this this was
certainly my favorite post of recent so
I got to give a shout
out I was like what H okay if you buy
stickers so yeah this is a funny one you
buy stickers are packaging for me and
then I got the little spelling error at
the end which always attracts a little
extra attention that's fun you got me
with that I was like what what just
popped up on the
screen well well played no we are we are
joined by meme royalty and I'm
incredibly grateful but as always let's
start off by asking what's everyone been
smoking on
recently uh what's in the what's in the
fatty you got there
farmer oh man this was actually given to
me by the boys at candies um down SoCal
which is actually a um turp line and
this is the weed before it's been
infused so it's topnotch man topnotch
high powerered
weed you'd be surprised what they're
spraying I'm curious this is good this
is T already taken off already going off
on a tangent with that but the the the
when they when those particular dudes
Infuse it are they infus using it with
weed tping from a from a different
strain or is it like fruit tping or do
you know okay so first of all before we
go into it I'll say that I don't know
but what I would be speaking on is like
what my understanding of it is and I
believe it's something along the lines
of
like The Vape juice you know yeah the
same stuff that they use the Vape with
and you know I'm sure the comments or
whatever would correct and I could be
wrong um that's definitely not my
specialty and I wouldn't want to speak
out of line on that subject particularly
right now while it's so hot but you know
um there's a bunch of flavors there's a
whole bunch of flavors in the world
marshmallow butterscotch Berry all these
flavors and they mix and they match all
the flavors and this is not weed flavors
brother this is fruit flavors this is
snack flavors and dessert flavors that I
know for sure and I'm sure there's
different levels of it like uh um I had
a buddy back in the day in the90s my
buddy Little Willie he used to make hash
oil and he would use this like overproof
lur so it was basically like really it
was like if you ever drank like like in
the back in the day like 100 Proof like
permafrost or hot damn 100 or whatever
it was like Blackberry lur but it was
but but it was high proof though so it
had a lot of sugar and flavor in it but
it also what had a lot of alcohol in it
so you could use it to extract weed the
way you would with regular alcohol but
where regular alcohol leaves and leaves
you only with whatever the resin was it
would also leave behind sugar and
blackberry flavor and I'm I don't know
what it was doing to the lungs or
whatever but we used to take it and put
it on rolling papers and roll joints
with it and when the sugar burned it was
delicious and it's a it was a weird
thing because I was like I know it's
probably not the best thing but it's
kind of like if you've ever like smoked
shisha in the hookah like hookah if you
smoke hookah at a hookah bar it'll be
like it just like tastes like strawberry
jam or it'll taste like whatever the
different the different shisha taste
like and I think it's kind of like along
that same line and my only real concern
always is is like you know I know like
straight Trappers might be like dude
let's just like take whatever and some
some you know let's just go buy some
[ __ ] out of the air freshener aisle and
put this in these pounds and I'll bet
they'll move and then I know there's got
to be other dudes too who are probably
like hey let's actually have like a dude
at a lab like our like our buddy uh
crybaby sent me like a kit that has all
these really high grade it has ketones
like there's this there's this
particular Ketone which is like it's
it's different to my understanding it's
not a tarpine but it's like it makes
things Tastee and smell and it smells
like Raspberry Vanilla it just smells
crazy and I'm like I know that that
would probably taste really good if you
put it on some weed and if it's sourced
really high grade then it's only a
matter of like you know like it's you're
just adding something to it but um I'm
always curious about that so that's why
I asked you because I don't you know
like I won't say I don't know anybody
who's who's infused some packs you know
but I I don't really know like the
detail of how it's how it's really done
and so I was curious about it but it's
it's a very it's a professional process
this is not a garage process whatsoever
this is medical grade devices that are
doing it people have showed these
machines online they resemble something
like a refrigerator and they have
shelves and they they put the thing in
so you know I think at first I even
myself just pictured some homies in the
garage just getting busy with some
whatever uh there's a little more to it
this stuff that is being put on the weed
is already intended to be smoked I
believe um
so you know we do the flavored blunts we
do the peach optimos and the grape
swishers and the peaches and cream and
all this these tobacco Blended flavors
it's the same thing it's very oily you
can kind of like when you even when you
smell it you can tell it's oily I bet it
has a different texture when you touch
the tree I've only come in
contact with weed that I know was
infused one time I'm in California I go
up and down the state I see all types of
people that are you know heavily
involved in all types of different
things I've only come into contact with
it one time so in California I can tell
you it's not very popular it's not
everywhere the people that work for me
for example when I show it to them
they're they're like surprised cuz like
like we're not seeing this stuff out
here in California yeah um this is a
different
demographic it's it's interesting how
much it seems to have taken over the
East Coast predominantly and just as a
side note I noticed there's now a
podcast dedicated to just rating sprayed
packs which I think is a good indicator
of like how prevalent it's becoming I
guess the question I'd love to quickly
throw out there is do you think that
it's almost certain at this point that
it's just going to become the next most
dominant or do you think it'll have its
rise and fall off it already
is it already is it's there so it's it's
there whether people want to accept that
or not um I have a bird's eyee view of
the industry I happen to know a whole
bunch of different things so it's like I
could tell what's going on I could tell
what's popular I could see it when it's
coming I could see it when it's going
right now I'd say we're you
know we're it's still going up how about
that you know um it's still has some
growth in it I saw the whole runs
movement I saw how long that lasted I
saw the explosion of carts a few years
ago I saw how long that lasted so I do
have a few other things to compare this
wave
to however
um have not seen the money move like it
does you know shout out to Dom's dooes
shout out to Young Jack shout out to OJ
and the white Bronco nation
I love it I love it you can't you can't
beat some of this stuff and God we we've
got to pick your brain a bit because
that's exactly what me and I were
talking about a bit earlier you know
this guy has a bird's eye view of the
industry um just before we move on you
just mentioned you know you got an idea
of the next up and coming Trends what
what do you think might be the next
thing or do you think it'll be another
interation of something we already
have um you know let's start at the
beginning I would say the first real
branding way
you know let's let's get ahead of dime
bags let's get ahead of Ziploc bags
let's get to branding that came in glass
jars that was uh you know for me lemon
tree Golden State banana stuff's coming
out of Santa Cruz the jar thing exploded
pretty quick that switched over to those
little tins little tin cans um that got
very popular for a
while um tin cans turned into sticker
bags
B sticker bags turned into directly
printed
bags directly printed bags turned into
die cut
bags um D cut
bags go into a box and then we Circle
back to double-sided sticker bags which
is the current humongous wave right now
which is great for sticker farmer
because we're built for this um we kind
of are the first ones to do the sticker
bag wave
so
uh that made it good for us when it
became popular again because I already
had the infrastructure to um to work off
of it uh the next
thing if I knew I'd be rich already I
could tell you that I think the
packaging is going to get more
complex um I think
the uh the layers and the levels that
they're doing the packaging you're
seeing right now like I'm working on
projects right
now to sell 1
18 127
pieces oh I don't know what that sound
was but um 127 pieces to sell 1
18 wow I'm talking box bags like
everything you could
imagine to sell 1 18 like that's [ __ ]
crazy so um the L this shit's going to
is is like we don't even know yet New
York right now the New York demographic
is
controlling what everyone kind of has to
do there's definitely some very
influential Trappers on the East Coast
who are having a heavy hand in that and
then uh obviously the customer decides
what what's hot and what's
not wow that's that's what an incredible
little anthology of the evolving of it
all and I I forgot about the Tuna the
Tuna tins thank you for reminding me
they were they were certainly a a big
part in it all and you know what we're
going to touch back on that a bit later
in the episode but why don't we jump
into our first story which is everyone's
been talking about it but um you know
DEA has uh recently announced that they
and the Department of Justice plan to
reschedule cannabis to a schedule 3 drug
this signifies that they believe it's a
low-risk substance and it's in line with
other medications such as Tylenol with
Cod in it they say the reschedule is
likely going to take a couple months to
complete the process but it certainly is
Paving the way for what many speculators
suggest will be one step closer to
Federal legalization and at the bare
minimum you can sort of feel like the
War on Drugs is almost an an end what do
you guys think about the rescheduling do
you think this is going to usher in a
new wave of cannabis as people hope or
do you think to an extent it's still
same old same
old yeah what are you you hearing about
it are you talking um yeah what am I
hearing it's like it's hard because you
hear these things every two or three
weeks to say oh so and so agrees to this
or this group agrees to this and now
this group agrees to this so it's like
the marketing's cool they're making us
feel like something's coming you know
but um you know what that is it's it's
really hard really hard to tell uh I see
I say naturally the Cannabis industry
people want to be excited about it
because it sounds good to have 50 states
that play ball right um but just like we
saw in the last few years it's not
always good for everyone regulation's
bad for
everybody not everybody but grad it's
pretty bad for most people especially
the mom and pop small farms things like
that the heavy
taxation that's that's coming and that's
inevitable because we're in Industry you
they're not going to just have an
industry that just gets to have a
freefor all and do whatever the [ __ ] it
wants that doesn't make sense um so you
know if we want to be part of the banks
if we want to be part of all these other
things that we're kind of like like
pushing the side on then you got to be
part of the taxes you got to be part of
the regulation uh the government's
definitely going to have their own heavy
hand in it so to me is it fair I don't
think is the question I think the
question is is it natural progression
for an industry
um and to me it seems like that's what's
supposed to be
happening
um I do say I do think there's going to
be some things about it that do
affect the smaller Farms that you know
in in particular are in California
because these are people that I'm
friends with and things like that and I
would hate to see them lose their
license or something like that because
now all of a sudden you have to be
federally regulated so but those are the
things that we're yet to see and we
don't know about
it there was a comment on Instagram and
I think what I really ultimately said
was that I hope it creates
opportunity and um however people want
to take
that yeah I think uh I think like all
everything you said is true it's like a
matter
of I mean you know like it's real easy
to go oh it should be like this and you
can always do that with like you know I
got a a kid and you know it's like
always it's always like trying to tell
like yeah I mean that would be cool but
that's not how things are like you know
people say well this isn't fair it's
like I don't really know many things
that are that fair you know it's things
are fair to an extent but um there's
very few of them you know so it's like
you're always going to have the the uh
you know like you said it's if it's
going to be an industry and it's going
to be a business you're naturally going
to go towards that stuff me I've always
been like yeah everybody [ __ ] up
having it be
mainstream but at the same time like you
know it it was bound to be mainstream it
was only some weird little events that
kept it uh being what it was and I think
like the the what it really comes down
to is like if you really want to have
some weed um and you don't want any of
the any of the other stuff attached to
it like just grow your own weed have
your own weed trade it with people you
know um and uh you know like try to try
to be cool about it don't tell everybody
you're growing and everything if it
comes down to being like overly
regulated where it goes back to being
basically illegal for the average
citizen again you know it's like all
right well keep it on the under you know
like don't don't just you know you can't
you you can't be like uh this is kind of
funny but I remember there was a
uh there was a time when I was getting
really really high and we were we were
actually doing nitrous and I kind of
like Snapped out for a second and then I
came back and I had this weird thing and
I was like oh damn I was like there's
like this thing where you can be way
down here and you're all good and you
can be way up
here and you're all good but if you're
right in here in the middle they're gon
to [ __ ] you and I like I kind of like
kind of like came back to Consciousness
saying it and everybody was like what
the [ __ ] are you talking about and I'm
like I don't really know but it was so
clear I just knew it was like and now
over the years I've kind of realized
it's like that it's like if you you know
there's going to be the people who are
really big and they'll be okay and
really little and they'll be okay but if
you're in the middle then you kind of
have to you're going to have to kind of
get up there or down there and either
get really organized and figure out what
people are doing at a level higher than
you or go ahead and go okay I'm content
to stay at this lower level where it's
not um where it's not as big of a thing
you know and I think with this kind of a
thing depending on how they interpret
the law it could make it to where like a
lot of our friends and people who are
not super ambitious and don't have the
most resources they'll have to just kind
of be you know small time and keep it
that way and then the people who really
um which are also some of our friends
who have more ambition and want to
really like push and get big like you
said maybe it'll be more opportunity for
them because now it is banking it is
maybe federal International all these
opportunities for everything to grow and
actually like Blossom like that but um
it would be really cool if if it um kind
of allows everything to go as it's been
and maybe over time they give a little
bit of of of extra power to the
localities like okay to go okay like if
you're you know um once it's more fully
regulated that might also mean that
there's some areas where that regulation
is less you know to where like they
might go hey look people have been
growing in NorCal and wherever Santa
Cruz or whatever for this long we're
going to go ahead and and ease things up
in those areas and make like an
available permit for small farms or
something if that could get lobbied for
and changed that'd be cool but um you
know in the meantime I think it's going
to be like uh like you said we you don't
really know but you kind of have to
expect that it's going to get more and
more complicated and you're going to
have to be more and more professional if
you do want to be way up on that level
than than right now because right now
people can as long as they bust their
ass and they jump through some hoops
they can get pretty high right now but
if they change it to where you need to
get every product cleared by the FDA and
you have to go through this process to
it could cut you know it could could
change that way too but it's a Trippy
it's a Trippy thing that's like I don't
think anybody can call it and uh you
know like you said hopefully it's good
for some people you
know yeah 100% as you said it's a bit
ambiguous
got to give a shout out to the nitrous
Epiphany you just described that sounds
epic I love it yeah you you've I've had
some of those ones where like you eat
some shrooms and you're like ah I I need
a notepad because I know this is
actually I just figured some crazy [ __ ]
out and then like you sober up and
you're like I don't know what it was I
know there was a thing or like you wake
up from a dream and you go I've got to
remember that and it's like and it's
gone this was one of the few that I
really remembered and for some reason it
like it didn't
it really didn't make much sense then
except at the time I was thinking of the
same thing I was actually thinking about
like big fish and little fish and it's
like people either have to be like if
you're a shark you're cool and if you're
a minnow you're cool but like you know
the the tuna is getting fished out like
there's just not you know it's a
trip 100% I I really enjoy that analogy
actually and um I mean we're while we're
on the topic you know if the
rescheduling um there's been a lot of
focal discussion regarding what does
this mean in terms of some of the
Cannabis patents that we've seen over
time and notably we do see the
pharmaceutical companies moving in
there's already several big ones
launching patent applications sopi mer
GW Pharmaceutical fisa all of these
companies have launched between 25 and
50 patent applications or have been
granted them many of these companies
have also been implicated or at least
played an adjunct role in the opioid
epidemic do we have any concerns about
the uh the rapid rise in companies
launching these patents in the wake of
what seems like possible future
legalization yeah I mean the weirdest
ones are when they when you read the
patents and they're like we have a
patent for cannabis that produces one:1
ratio CBD to THC or something you're
like that's how is that it's not really
like novel um I think what they might
have to do which is unfortunate is to
patent things to really get them to go
through they might have to actually
modify them and go okay you can tell
this is ours because it's basically got
our stamp in the DNA you can just test
it and be like boom it's MK boom it's
fizer or whatever like as soon as it
comes back from the DNA test it's like
yeah that's that one is ours you know
but um it is it would be really weird
now if they started graning all the
these weird ones like where they're like
uh it turns purple and it it smells like
such and such or whatever because there
were some weird ones filed like that and
everyone was like you can't they won't
push any of them through yet in the US
but if they do start and they push some
of those through it takes a lot of money
to get them pushed through and it takes
a lot of money to fight against them and
there's not a lot of people who are
going to want to spend tons of money to
make sure that other people can't get
those patents so you're it's kind of
like it could be kind of it could be
kind of weird and that could be a big
driver of that thing that I was saying
where like you might have to either be
GW Pharma or you might have to have a
backpack and sell sacks you know in
which case I think people could sell
Sachs and still be okay you know but
you're not going to be like GW Pharma Jr
because you're not I don't know how
you're G to get there you know but it
it'll be interesting to see it's just
the same how's that going to play out
you
know and either way your all your
sticker needs can be filled by sticker
farmer whether you're a backpack boy or
GW farmer yes legal in every state
International that's part of it for us
is um some of the challenging things for
your traditional cannabis businesses or
bonuses for
mine that's part of it when they change
regulation and they need to upgrade all
their packaging they call me I didn't
create the regulation I just sell what
they need to be in compliance you know
so it's it's part of one of those things
where sometimes I may see something I
may want to celebrate and it's insulting
to a mom and pop who's taking a big hit
like I [ __ ] get it dude but um you
know we're we're kind of like fishing
for different
things and uh you you know sometimes my
fish bite and sometimes your fish bite
it's just part of part of the business
and you know part of selling the pic and
shovels yeah and it's like I said you
know people like oh well that's not fair
like yeah that's life's not fair you you
bet on this horse or you bet on that
horse like at a time when everybody
thought you were nuts probably for going
oh stickers you know I understood
because I had seen like even hippies
when I was a little kid go oh I'm GNA
put this sticker on a jar and I'm going
to have like a mason jar with weed in it
and I'm going to people are going to buy
my ounces for 500 because it's going to
be just like three buds in a mason jar
and I got my sticker and it's super
simple stuff but people did it and when
they did it you looked at it you go whoa
that's cool but nobody wanted to do it
because when it was completely illegal
100% all that is is your fingerprint on
the jar so somebody goes oh I'm gonna
make this and I'm going to put this
stamp on it I'm going to do this they're
like
now everybody knows what that is it can
all be tracked back to somebody so
before like 2:15 people didn't really
want to do it and then people started to
do go oh you know what I'm gonna get a
roll of stickers made and I'm gonna
stick them on my turkey bags or whatever
and then you know you guys started
making like actually real packaging and
then like you said earlier following
like okay like because I the first
packaging that I got from you guys and
the only packaging that I ever got for
for legal wreck flour was Flats of of
jars that were like eighth jars and you
could put like a quarter in them or you
could put a eighth in them and they were
nice they were nice little jars they
were like the bottom of this basically
and uh nice labeling and I had my flats
and all my stuff and I went to take
those to the emerald cup and sell them
at a booth and I was like damn this
dolly with like five lbs of wheed on it
it weighs like 100 lb or it weighs like
whatever it was it was a lot it weighed
a lot and so as soon as I saw that I was
like yeah people aren't going to want to
do jars and then I saw why people wanted
to do tin and then everybody's like oh I
want my weed everybody now that's like
stuck with the old thing like I was
talking about oh the Mason jar with the
three buds that all sounds cool until
you actually go to go through the
logistics of the shipping and all the
stuff and that's one of the things I've
heard before about packaging with glass
was back in the day people would go oh
put everything in glass it's recyclable
and it's like yeah it is but a lot of
times it doesn't get recycled it gets
thrown in the trash and to ship it it
uses so much more fuel that it's
actually a crazy resource expense just
on our just on the world's resources up
a lot of resources to go I'm gonna put
it in glass you know 35 pounds 35 pounds
it's around 30 depending on which jar
you have which lid you have so you're
you're it's a logistical [ __ ]
nightmare yes it doesn't make sense but
when you're talking about a high quality
product you might want to transport it
in a high quality container so I still
think some of the best weeds in jars
just like the best tequila is in a
bottle and all of those fees are easily
absorbed at the top of food chain not
everyone can afford to do that you know
it's not for every one I do not
recommend it unless you're built for it
yeah it was one of those things where
like for me I knew for what I was doing
I was like I can put it in jars I
already had the option at the time put
it in bags put it in jars I was like no
I want to put mine in jars it's going to
be nice you open up the jar you can see
it through the jar you know what's going
on and um and had I continued to get
keep getting stuff I might have just
kept on getting it in jars but I also
saw that I was like damn like this is
just it it s the way it sounds in your
head and the way it really is when
you're actually holding on to them
you're like oh okay it's like I get um I
get uh seed packaging from you guys and
I was like maybe I'm gonna do tins maybe
I'll do like like it would be cool to do
like mini cigar boxes with the lid that
flips up and you know like you guys
could get me whatever I want to get and
like it's it's like you guys are the
homies so it's really easy to work
through design process do all this stuff
and then uh and then I I you know I like
to support people that I know or people
who I at least know are like Grassroots
you know smaller businesses came from
the weed stuff and um it I just looked
at it and I was like H I don't really
want to use plastic because I don't
really like having the waste of
plastic and uh I you know I looked at
all the different stuff and all said and
done I'm like I get people's packaging
and it's big and it takes up all this
space and like with seeds I take them
all and I put them in my fridge so I get
people's packaging in these nice boxes
or whatever they come in and I take it
and I put it in a little plastic bag and
I put those all in these airtight tubs
and so people make this really nice uh
packaging and then I get the seeds and
I'm like I can't it doesn't work so I
went okay I'm just gonna with my seeds
I'm just going to go ahead and put them
straight in the in the little in the
little direct printed uh myars you know
which was which was awesome for me but
it's just a trip like the
uh you know when you go to when you go
to do things like you actually you
actually get your hands on it and you go
oh okay so this happens and that happens
and I had seeds and I did little little
paper folds with a little Ziploc inside
and I went okay now this has to be put
in an airtight container and now I need
to figure out okay something needs to be
Crush proof and all this stuff and it
you know it's all it's all a Trippy
process figuring out all the logistics
for all that stuff you know yeah it's
fun though everybody's got different
stuff going on and it's definitely part
of what uh makes it
interesting yeah for
sure definitely the packaging game
itself Spurs its own sort of creativity
but in in your answer you referenced you
know sort of the Homegrown um original
sort of packaging and I mean while we're
on the topic of Grassroots I wanted to
quickly mention uh last month 420 the
famous 420 event at uh Golden State Park
was called hippie Hill sadly didn't go
ahead uh this was due to the organizers
being unable to secure enough
sponsorships they cited other problems
as well such as the city having cutbacks
which meant that they weren't able to
secure funding to be able to run the
event safely in terms of say police
medical staff and other utilities now
some have been critical of this saying
that the event really doesn't need that
much infrastructure to run and the
vendors were still Keen to go um however
there was a response from the organizers
which said look last year there was
40,000 people in a relatively small
space uh without the appropriate funding
we we're just going to trash the place
and in fact in 2019 there was sadly some
fenal laced brownies that went around
and 10 people overdosed within the first
hour so so the the presence of medical
personnel seems like it would be highly
advantageous my question though is what
does this say for the Homegrown events
and as a extension do we think that
decriminalization and possible
legalization is sort of going to
actually be problematic in a sense
because it seems like the event
organizers sort of attributed the fact
that there was so much interest in the
event that they weren't able to safely
facilitate the event going forward do we
think this could be a bad sign for some
of the more organic
events um I'll answer that from my point
of view not everything is meant to be
monetized um some things are better just
left organic and left alone it was cool
when the hippies were out there just I
have friends that used to go out they
they'd spend two three days making
cookies and go out and everybody just
sell it's like it didn't need fences it
didn't need stages it probably did need
bathrooms and and um Waste Management to
some extent which the city should be
happy to provide when people are you
know Gathering um peacefully like
[Music]
that I don't know it's a huge part of
the culture in San Francisco and the
point when they tried to monetize
it didn't sit well with me
personally yeah things like that I mean
it was just kind of a cool a cool part I
mean I
think I don't know if if people are if
people are doing it people are going
it's like you know if if you really like
you said the one thing that I can think
like where you need money for it would
be like yeah okay where's everybody
gonna go to the bathroom that's like the
main thing that always is with a big big
event like you're gonna have to have
some rows of portapotty somewhere or
something but other than that it's like
all of it you know seems like you should
be able to just do it and then you know
people who want to take part in it
should be able to keep it all cool like
you should be able to be cleaned up at
the end you have a party usually a lot
of people come to the party I mean like
a small party like a house party
everybody comes everybody leaves but
there's always like those two or three
homies that are like you know what we'
cleaned everything up we've vacuumed
everything up people stayed late people
whatever and um I don't know it's always
weird to me to see like I remember
seeing when they did one of the High
Times cup there and it was like
everything was done and over and there
was nobody there anymore and there was
still you could look around there was
still like 20 dumpsters of laying out on
the field wherever it was and I was like
this is wild like who who the [ __ ] does
this you know because people suck bro
people suck that's part of it too so
yeah for the people to the promoters who
did try to organize it and clean it up
like shout out to them yeah but
unfortunately people are not cool enough
and things that big need to be like
sanctioned to some extent or whatever
the word is yeah and if if you know it's
going to go on you need to kind of be
like all right we got a crew that's
going to be we got you know whatever
garbage crew recycling crew you know
like it it's just I if you are if it's
organized in any sense of course if
everyone just shows up then it's like
well who's whose job is it but I mean
back in the day honestly especially at a
place called hippie Hill if you had
hippies and you had weed people and you
know whatever kind of people coming out
to things like that there would be like
stuff would be I mean I grew up where
we'd have like big um when I was a
little kid like big like full moon
parties at the river and it would be
like there's like food and a lot of
people don't bring food but a lot of
people bring more food than they need
and a lot of people don't clean [ __ ] up
but you got those few people that are
like that's cool it's cool for everybody
to be able to just come and do their
thing don't have to worry about food
don't have to worry about cleanup we'll
do that that's like what that's going to
be our part of it maybe somebody comes
and does some music or people do
whatever but like I don't know it's just
crazy how you can get so many people
together and then there's not like you
don't like you don't need one person
person can take care of a couple
thousand people you just need like a few
people to be like all right we're going
to do this you know and uh yeah I don't
know like that's not in just in relation
to hippie Hill but as far as events you
know like people have the it we have it
in us to have really cool festivals and
events and be able to pull off some
crazy stuff I mean like the only thing
really going on like that I think that
is still I mean I don't know because I
don't go and I'm sure everybody who went
early on would say you would have their
critique but like burning man all these
people go they make a city and when they
leave there's just nothing there you
know and uh it seems like you could do
that anywhere with anything but
unfortunately you know like I go to the
river now and I'm like somebody left a
bag of beer bottles and dirty
diapers at the swimming hole and I'm
like what where's the how where's the
over with the people who actually want
to do some cool [ __ ] and they think you
just leave some [ __ ] there like you
know I don't know just one of those
things you know it makes it difficult
for everybody to keep [ __ ] together when
you got those kind of people wonder what
town they're
from right here the one up the road or
the one right down the road or the one
to the east or the West I'm guessing
maybe the one
down maybe
not hard to say
I love it I love it look and in your
answer you you referenced you know one
of the prior High Times events and you
know how people sort of didn't pull
their weight there well you know you you
gave me a perfect segue because in
Surprise News high times has gone into
receivership so let me pull up our
little image so um last time we spoke we
had no idea about this but it's come to
light that high times has actually been
struggling quite a bit the company has
been navigating murky waters for the
past 10 years since their cannabis cups
and magazine fell out of favor largely
attributed to poor quality management
and concerns from the community
regarding the authenticity of winners
and pay forplay Antics given High Times
is a cannabis company and cannabis
companies aren't federally legal they
say they can't file for bankruptcy but
they are able to go into receivership
it'll be interesting to see will they
get bailed out or may this be the end of
high times as we know it I guess the
question is do we think High Times is
worth saving as a legacy brand or has
the scene progressed on too
much yeah I don't know what do you think
about this one Mr Sticker
farmer did you grow up on high times at
all more than you
know more than you know I'll I'll show
you actually
OG they're right
there
look this is a collage I made out of
high
times when I was in high
school this is the name of the brand I
was making at the time 1996 that's cut
out of a High Times
magazine and uh on the back of it is a
letter from a [ __ ] art teacher
telling me to stop making weed
art and I keep this in my house you know
this lady probably also inspired me I
probably don't give her enough credit
I'm always bad mouthing her for this
letter she wrote me about making weed
art but um High time's huge subject
matter in my my life uh let's fast
forward to what we're talking about now
I feel
like that ship hasn't been driven by the
best Captain for quite some time now it
was very cool ton of very dope culture
behind
it um and probably
the the payto playay events and some of
those things I also think they crossed
over into like dispensaries and things
like that and I drive down the highway
and there's a dispensary in Oakland and
it's High Times building and it's
covered in [ __ ]
plywood like H not I'd say that's a sign
of the times not only for you know
things going on in our cities but also
for the brand
maybe I would it
up yeah yeah it's a bummer man I mean it
really is like a you know I mean I
remember being a teenager and being like
like if someone told you like oh dude my
picture got in High Times you'd be like
what you got your picture in High Times
like I remember it was
2000 I want to say 2002 or something uh
my buddy Maul uh J medy we took pictures
in his um his mom's backyard and he sent
them in of the of the of these medy
plants and uh they got put in High Times
and we were like whoa that's crazy we're
in High Times like like you know was
just thought it was the coolest thing
ever you know and uh I mean
you know it's a trip like I think in
general now magazines are not like you
know I mean there's the internet but
like I don't know I I um I still get
love from High Times They they post
pictures of mine and stuff and like I I
get like that it really boosts my Ig and
um like uh people there are cool with me
and ask me questions to check on
articles check details and stuff
and like I appreciate it and it's just
funny because like as time goes on I
don't know I guess it's like a being a
being like a frog in a in a pot of water
and it war and it warming up now I'm
like yeah somebody from High Times cool
you know but like it's just a weird
thing because like I said 20 something
years ago you know a picture is in there
with our faces covered up and Only We
Know It's us and we're like dude we're
famous not really but like we felt like
damn that's awesome these pictures are
in a big magazine and everything and um
but I don't think it only happened like
to me personally being jaded by the weed
thing I think also people in general
don't um they don't regard it's like
there's so much exposure all the time to
all this stuff that people don't regard
any of it that much I feel like somebody
could like share your somebody could
share Your Meme or something on a page
that has 10 ion follows and you'd be
like cool you know right right on like
stuff that should be it used to have a
lot more it used to hold a lot more
Mystique for sure it used to be a lot
more like it was like it was next to
like the porno mags you know what I'm
saying like it was like that and now you
could go on your phone and find either
readily available so yeah I think we're
jaded to not only the fact that um you
know this stuff is everywhere and we've
seen a zillion pictures by now but how
High Times was the [ __ ] for me dude High
Times I put in a very high regard and I
think they probably inspired a lot of
people to not be afraid to to play with
weed you know yeah and like as a grower
I used to be scouring it like oh is
there a a tip like anything that
somebody said that sounded like it might
be something cool that you never thought
of you're like damn I should try that oh
oh I didn't know that that's an answer
to something and you listen and you're
like you're use your critical thinking
and you go that solved that right there
that's what I needed to know and he
might only be every once in a while but
back then there was nowhere else to get
that unless you like go and talk to
somebody and you didn't feel comfortable
back in the day even if you knew
somebody was like a old schooler that
knew a lot you weren't like hey tell me
what you do because it was like you knew
it was kind of stepping on toes it's
kind of trade secrets and everything but
like back to the the thing of like being
jaded with stuff it's weird because I
don't even think like I I look at it and
I go oh magazines or what the media or
newspapers but then I look at it now too
and I go it seems like because of
overexposure to everything like it
almost has happened with almost
everything like if you show somebody
some real trippy kind of fruit they're
like oh yeah I seen this one on
Instagram I follow this dude in Florida
like you know back in the day you'd be
like dude what the hell is a sour soop
now people are like yeah it's a sour
soop I ordered one on the internet it
came in two days and you know like weed
is the same way like the way that we
used to look at weed and you get one
little nug of something crazy and you're
just like dude what the hell it made
like things be so everything could be
legendary and now at this point you're
kind of like there's the craziest things
in the world and everybody's just kind
of like cool yeah yeah I saw that you
know it's weird man I used to have a
bookshelf of encyclopedias as a kid and
I would look through them for cool
animals you know and that's how I saw
cool animals I love animals and now I
can go on I mean I mean I was happy with
Steve Irwin you know I was happy with
Crocodile Hunter and now you can go on
Instagram and see all the exotic animals
and snakes and birds and yeah like you
said our exposure level has been turned
way up and now we're harder to
impress yeah yeah it's trippy I I think
if you're like a media company like High
Times and you're
not ridiculously on top of it as far as
whatever's going on with management and
you know and I don't even look at it and
go oh these guys are somebody's a [ __ ]
up or whatever it is I'm like I know I
personally couldn't keep like don't hand
me High Times I'll [ __ ] it off guarantee
I'm not I'm not it's hard to stay
relevant yeah and to just just to manage
all the different details of all of it
and everything and uh you know it's just
yeah I I don't know it's a um it's one
of those it's one of those things
where I don't know that it um I don't
know I mean I I know it can be kept
alive and I'd like to see it but it you
know you
figure you know that there's problems
there has to be problems with the
management because it's so big it's this
monster it's so respected it's so
legendary to whole few Generations of
people and then it's like it's flopping
so you know something's wrong there but
at the same time you wonder too like
okay it would have to be even if
everyone's doing everything perfectly in
this day and age it's still kind of hard
to keep something like that alive and I
personally hope that it turns around
everything goes through waves just like
you know people go through waves in
their life it's like oh you got a friend
and you see him and you're like damn
he's all Manic and everything's [ __ ] off
and going crazy and then you see him
again you're like oh damn dude's doing
good or you know you knew some dude who
was like this legendary dude from back
in the day and then you see him and he's
been through some [ __ ] and he's just
like all people are all soulen and their
their Aura is all gray and [ __ ] you know
and then like then they bounce back and
you know you hope with everything like I
always want to see everything do better
I don't care what it is like doing
better is better if it's whatever it is
but uh High Times in particular I'd like
to see it be able it bounce back I'd
like to see cool High Times cups that
used to be like something where I like
really was curious what won and um of
course there is a lot of you know
there's
like ever since the basically the 80s
the dudes from like um Shanti Baba and
those guys they're like yeah it was
being bought it was being bought like
you buy the cup that's how that worked
but I also had good friends who I know
for a fact they didn't have a name they
didn't have a boo boo they had some weed
that was so good that you could they
couldn't even they were just like we got
to give this guy first IND car or
whatever you know I know a few people
who who by the metric of it being bought
they shouldn't have won and they won so
even while it was funky there was still
some some um some reality going on with
the judging and everything and so
knowing that from knowing those people
it made me be like all right so what did
win I'm still curious you know I'm
always curious about what wins because
somebody liked it and it was good enough
that everybody's not like dude what what
happened it's always like you know a lot
of guys got some really good weed and
whoever got the biggest Booth or
whatever they gave it to them and you're
like so it's still some Upper Crust [ __ ]
you know um so but it would be cool to
see it like actually like all right
here's our new standards we're going to
make it transparent it's going to be uh
crowd judged and everybody puts the
token with the one they like the best
first place and whoever gets the most
first place it wins there's somebody
doing one like that sounded cool um it'd
be cool to see it all bounce back
biggest sponsor biggest sponsor won
first place every time for the last five
years yeah it's not surprising like
that's how every every event I never saw
it go any other way like I I mean I'm
sure there's some of these other ones
that don't operate like that but as far
as the big boys that were using
marketing tools and paying money and
charging a lot of money for people to be
part of it and filling you know large
venues like this [ __ ] was a [ __ ] scam
dude yeah and you know you're like it
would be cool if it was all you know if
it could all be transparent then you
really know but the funny thing is for
me personally even after even if I know
something isn't fixed and it's all legit
I'm still not like I'm like always
curious oh who won what was it I'd like
to see that but I'm never like oh I need
to get that that's the new wave I'm
always like no I know that I still like
this old weed that I've had traditional
traditional custy looks on the packaging
and sees award winning five Time
Cannabis Cup winning you know they see
that and they respond to them this is
marketing people pay money to be part of
marketing so that um that all makes
plenty of sense
yeah yeah I mean you know like if people
go to buy a wine they're like oh this
wine has 93 points like it was but
people don't even know that that scale
has to be designed on how they grade it
and if what you like is not included in
that grading scale then you might like
the 72o wine better than the 94o wine
because you don't like what they like
some people are like no I like really
sweet wine some people are like I want
to put ice cubes in my red wine there's
all different things and everybody will
go oh it's cuz you don't know [ __ ] and
it's like a lot of people are like sorry
I know a lot I've had a lot of different
kinds of cheese I still will take
American cheese on a burger because I
think it's popping on a burger you know
like there's things where it's like yeah
it's all it's all relative you know so
it's own Everyone likes something
different hey guys I don't mean to cut
you off but I got some family showing up
now I gotta get dinner ready for
everybody I do want to do this again um
this is a super dope little platform you
have here not little platform I'm sorry
to put it that way but um I've never
done anything like this so this is cool
and convenient for me from home so uh
please have me back on whenever it's
good for you guys let's do it
man and there you have it guys as I
mentioned just a quick one today we will
get sticker farmer back to do a much
more in-depth episode in the near future
as always big shout out for making it to
the end