hey guys heavy days here from the
podcast I just wanted to make a quick
video to explain what this patreon's all
about over the past 12 months I've
received an overwhelming amount of
support and positive feedback for the
show and for that I cannot thank you all
enough it's truly been a labor of love
and something I've felt was more of a
passion than a job however with that
being said the biggest criticism I've
always got was that episodes took too
long to come out and that there wasn't
enough regular content so with that in
mind I've decided to started this
patreon account I want to be able to
dedicate more of my time to being able
to create better quality content and
more importantly more regular content so
I've decided I'm going to be creating
content on a more regular basis making
two episodes a month one being a patreon
exclusive with an additional video for
higher patreon tiers all of the
additional patreon content will become
available to the general public after a
few weeks because I never wanted to put
anything behind a hard pay wall
last year I was lucky enough to be able
to head over the states and spend some
time with some of my favorite breeders I
tried to make some really good quality
content however I fell short due to
underestimating the situations I'd be in
and bringing the adequate gear for that
I'd love to be able to get back to the
States and to be able to create some
really high quality media content for
everyone things like walkthroughs in the
gardens with breeders like BOD Brothers
Grim Matt Ry Coastal seeds Dynasty and
more ultimately whether you donate
anything or not is not important I'm
just really grateful that people watch
the show and that people enjoy it I'm
really excited to be able to create more
content on a regular basis and I hope
that you guys enjoy it as well and if
you do appreciate it again feel free to
sign up it really helps to have that
extra funding and it allows me to be
able to spend more time creating the
content that I'm hoping you guys are
going to love be sure to check out the
description box below I'll make sure
that there's some information in there
about what patreon fans can expect to
get from their exclusive
rewards and hopefully we can make this
show even better than it is
already so again a big thank you to
everyone for the support and thanks for
[Music]
listening