hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast
a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts
this episode was brought to you by seeds
here now
your number one seed bank not only a
guarantee on germination but also on
satisfaction
as well as 420 australia and
organic gardening solutions if you go
anywhere else to get your organic
gardening products or you know
tastefully subtle weed inclined shirts
kidding yourself on this episode we're
joined by the man
one eye who's gonna give us the lowdown
on so many different things i don't
think i can even squeeze them all in
hope you're ready for a good one guys
here we go
alrighty so a big welcome and thank you
to the oregon hero himself
one eye how you doing i'm doing
fantastic heavy days
how are you i'm doing great
good times so first question i like to
ask everyone what was your first
experience with cannabis
um wow that goes back uh
many years for me believe it or not
this is going to sound really strange
but when i was
growing up in virginia beach virginia
uh i had a group
of friends a few guys who were about
four years older than me
and they were pretty much my surfing
buddies uh
so they were you know all able to drive
you know
long before i was so getting down to
places like cape hatteras was uh
quite created quite an advantage for me
of having these older guys but one of
the other things that came along
with the surfing capabilities
were the opportunities to see some cool
music
and also playing dungeons and dragons of
all things
so the summer that i turned 12 years old
after a game of dungeons and dragons one
of my older friends
pulled me aside and said hey you know
we're going to go out to the porch here
and smoke a joint
would you care to do so and uh you know
you got to remember this is
roughly 1986.
the just say no campaign
was very much part of our existence
so i was pretty hesitant in the
beginning but i caved eventually after a
little bit of peer pressure
and that you know
uh
i can't remember i don't remember that i
really got too high off that first joint
but i knew it was something that i was
willing to do again
and over the next few years
uh primarily getting high
with friends and smoking joints and
taking long hits
all that good stuff of course as i got
older that
the frequency certainly increased
but uh you know not a uh it was a
groundbreaking moment for sure
because it certainly opened my eyes to a
whole new world
and way to experience the world for sure
and so
how did you transition from that to a
grower it's obviously
because you know you sound like you're
quite apprehensive so i imagine it would
have taken a little bit for you to
really get head first in so to speak
that's very very true uh being the you
know
growing up during that era it was uh
very taboo and uh certainly wasn't uh
wildly accepted by the masses
but there was a group of us and we we
certainly you know
kept to our kept to ourselves and kept
to the uh
stay dedicated to the smoking of
cannabis it really wasn't until
uh my i don't know 11th or 12th grade
year
in high school that my
a friend of mine and i decided to
sprout some seeds and put them outside
and see what we could do
this was the beginning of several failed
attempts
in you know in in the hometown where i
grew up
it wasn't really until i went off to
college
in the early 90s that i
decided to be a bit more committed to
the growing cause
and it really just started with cracking
bag seeds uh you know
as new things came through again back
then it was all kind but of course and
we certainly got to learn some of the
different names of strains
but we were just more or less cracking
random seeds
primarily outdoor but
there was some early indoor cultivation
in closets while i was in college
and you know back then we were really
winging it there was no
growth store that you could there were
growth you know there was a couple of
hydro stores
within an hour's drive of my college but
you certainly weren't going there for
any advice during that era
so we really had to just kind of figure
it out the best we could
maybe a couple of articles in high times
here there but
the beginnings were very rudimentary at
best
but we did what we could and you know
there were some good things that turned
out of some of those early gardens
but uh the success rates were not very
high
yeah and so who are the people that you
were looking up to
during that time was there anyone like
often we hear people like ed rosenthal
and you know the guys who were around
back in those days did you look to them
at all or you were really just
out in the ocean on your own i mean you
know
as far as breeders were concerned
uh or expert growers or whatever
the only access that i really had to
that world was
via the high times magazine so people
like
neville for example fascinated me uh
in his whole story of lore and legend
but there weren't a lot of uh
gurus to look up to that we were really
that aware of
it wasn't until later on you know after
college
of late 90s that i uh
that i you know started looking up to
some folks who were making impacts in
the industry and of course early on
jack herrera comes to mind he was
someone and i
volunteered with normal when i was one
year when i was in college
and was exposed to the emperor aware's
clothes and and jack's whole
kind of pursuit of legal you know why
legalized cannabis is such a good thing
and why hemp was so important
so you know between you know in the very
early days
jack herrera would be one uh you know
uh you know popular individual and then
neville would bend the other
so knowing what you know now if you had
to guess
what the origins of a lot of that kind
bud and by extension the seeds you were
getting from it
what do you think that stuff would have
been predominantly
so well a couple of them one of them in
fact i can attest to specifically
and that would have been the uh afghani
number one the wood which was
so lovely dawned the virginia beach
afghani
and this was the first kind bud that i
was exposed to when i was in high school
and it rained you know it
set kind of the gold standard for me in
those
very very early years there were
other you know of course skunk crop
skunk you know skunk was still around
then the railroad kill skunk
uh there were some northern lights that
would pop up here and there
we would see uh blueberry from time to
time
and then you know as the years
progressed into the early 90s
i started to get exposed to more
uh more of a variety i i went to school
around the dc area in northern virginia
and we would see things like g13
and pluton and now we would see nl2
and nl5 and nl5 haze crosses
black domina as you get
deeper into the mid 90s the the four-way
uh which is now
known to the cut is known as the fairfax
four-way that one just about changed my
life
and i was uh so this was right around
96 now that i
was fortunate enough to be in close
proximity
to the group who was responsible for
producing
those very early uh four-way the fairfax
four-way plants
and that strain when it hit our scene
just dominated the scene and it became
the standard by which
we judged everything else and it's
really the strain that got me into
eventually exploring the whole concept
of
breeding and creating new strains
i kind of set myself out on a mission to
kind of meet or beat the four-way which
was
a daunting task at that part of my
career but
you know we eventually got there after
several years
so it was uh
it was definitely you know a a
game-changing uh
strain and and many others you know
followed after that we eventually got
into the the white line so the white
widows
and white rhino the great white shark
some of those come to mind uh those now
we're getting a little deeper into the
90s
and then of course you know it wasn't
until i moved out west
that i actually was exposed to
things like og kush and of course you
know we're getting later into the two
mid 2000s at this point but you know we
we had i'd say when i was in that
northern virginia
area there you know just
due to location there were you know
there was quite an interesting scene
going in and around
that area with with pretty high quality
cannabis
um you know never mind the canadian
influence
which was certainly present at that time
but we
we really sought to source
the best domestic that we could find at
that time
and and we're attempting on the side to
produce
you know uh some some decent cannabis as
well
yeah wow so many different avenues we
could jump off into the first thing
you must have been friends with mr bob
hemphill for quite a while then
yes we we've known each other for
a cup gosh going on a cup probably a
couple decades now
we've definitely gone and seen some fish
shows back in the day together
uh it's really interesting you know he
and i
and this one this will kind of this will
be a great example of
how kind of deep the code went back then
so you know back in those days in the
early days especially back in virginia
you know neither one of us ever once had
the conversation
about growing uh even though we were
both
actively cultivating and probably knew
each other were
but it was just so tight back then that
you just
didn't even you know it was just you
just didn't want to breach the subject
because you didn't want someone else to
really know
um but you know he has forever
you know since those days been an
amazing
just incredible incredible cultivator i
have a lot of respect for
not only his ability to preserve
genetics and keep them over the years
but also as a cultivator he is
really spectacular in my opinion yeah
agreed
and i mean if we just touch back to a
point you made yourself the va
scene you know the more you learn about
it the more it seems like this place was
like the mecca of weed back in the day
what do you think contributed to being
such a hot spot
you know that's a that's a really good
question i think
there was
a desire you know at that point in time
at least for the circle of folks that i
ran with uh which
overlaps a lot of these other you know
virginia breeders and growers
there was a need for self-sufficiency
you know
you didn't always want to rely on
what was coming in next on what load or
whatnot you know and we certainly didn't
want to all sit around and and
have to consume you know canadian
so i think um you know
there's a lot of rural countries
especially in southwestern virginia
floyd county comes to mind that was
always a mecca for
just incredibly grown cannabis over the
years
but you know you find even in the
richmond scene you know there's there's
a lot of
a lot of really important in my opinion
you know important breeders and
some of these kind of gurus of the
industry
that all hailed from you know the
dominion state
and it's um to me it's quite remarkable
um i don't know maybe it was something
in the water who knows
but there it i you know for us it came
out of self-sufficiency we didn't want
to have to rely
you know always on others so we set
forth
you know to to do our own thing and
produce our own cannabis even if those
small amounts and a lot of it you know
was just
head stash we weren't at that time
necessarily
you know all producing for production on
a
you know certainly not on a commercial
level or anything close to it
but it was always it was always pleasant
to know that you had a nice
head stash of you know nicely grown
cannabis with
you know great flavor and stupendous
highs
and you didn't have to rely on mexi
brick or
canadian so you know and it really i
mean it just
uh but but your point is and i think
about this a lot
about you know how many of these great
individuals have um
hailed from from the home state
yeah it's kind of perplexing to see it
all happen i think va in new york is
where a lot of the best stuff and
best breeders have come from in my
opinion and i'm sorry to anyone who's
not from there if you're butthurt but um
any anyway another thing you brought up
which is really interesting
actually no sorry i want to quickly ask
this one did you get any of that uh va
super skunk
yes yes uh the super skunk
was definitely you know
available and i do remember it um
it just it's so strange you know as soon
as you
talk about as soon as we got into that
four-way
era it really became
difficult for a other varieties to be
memorable just because we kind of it's
just because it was some some of these
things were stopped at but the va uh
super skunk
is fantastic um i i
you know there's not enough nice things
that i could say about that strain
and i you know i applaud anyone who
pursues it during this era because it's
uh
you know it's a it's a special strain
so another one with the va tag in the
name you referenced it the va afghani i
think what's interesting about this one
is
it's actually making quite a comeback
notably duke diamonds worked in
some of his more recent lines i think
what's interesting about this one is
for the people who haven't seen or
smoked it in real life
i think it would really catch you off
guard that's that's the way i felt it
was nothing like what i expect like
didn't smell like what i expected the
high was nothing like what i expected
like i knew it was going to be good but
it was like a
how do you feel about that one because
it's it's really i think it's the real
anomaly and i'd love to hear europeans
so that that's a great one the virginia
beach afghani
is is a standout for
for me for one specific reason and
that's the flavor
um it almost has a
to me almost like a mentee note to it
and there is something so very distinct
about it
that it's you know it's certainly one of
those strains that if you smoke it once
or twice
you'll know it forever um
the plants aren't highly you know
and from what i remember you know and of
course going back many years to the
virginia beach days when our friends
were cultivating it you know it was all
closet cultivated
so these were smaller plants they didn't
yield an incredible amount
but they uh but what came out of that
was
you know an incredible high to me
it is uh almost you know mind numbing
and a flavor that is just remarkable
i mean it does have that kind of
slight ganny kind of hash plant taste to
it but like i said there's something
almost a minty note in it
that makes it unmistakable every time
and
i i was i actually would at the emerald
cup this year
when i saw that uh duke diamond was
breeding it with the gandy skunk with
the granny skunk or whatever i was
so excited to see that back i couldn't
resist
you know and certainly grab some for
myself to me that's you know an
homage to the old days and
uh it's like i said that ganny is there
there's just nothing like it else in the
world
yeah definitely i think the one thing
that i picked up on for me elise was
that mintiness you speak of i feel like
it's
it's one of the many components to that
jack herrera flavor like is that that's
what i found really weird like i thought
it was
really one of the more tropical like not
maybe not tropical but you know what i
mean it had
had a lot of body to it for an afghani
and it just took me back
um and the other thing i found was the
high it's like
i'm just going to quote dookie he said
it was almost like paranoia inducing it
so
so wrong yes it's not
typical of an afghani people think you
know like strong indicas would do the
opposite they'd chill you out
no not that one it is uh it is
unmistakable
yeah uh one one that hopefully everyone
gets to try the final thing i want to
look back on quickly
you mentioned the northern lights and
the blueberry being as some of the other
ones around at the time
out of all those ones that you do think
back on what's the most memorable for
you
g13 okay we don't hear a lot of that
anymore
what was it about the g13 that you liked
uh that's another one you know the real
d13
uh and it's it's a complex one to try to
describe
it is has a very distinct taste
i really enjoyed the high we the g13
that we were getting back then actually
was coming from san diego
um it was
it just i i tell you what so i got a bag
seat of it
i think this is why i like it so much so
i got a bag seat out of it
and grew a plant of it outdoors in
northern virginia
and it was the only plant i've ever
grown in my life to actually have the
magenta pistols
which when it dried when the flower was
you know dried and cured out
so g13 in itself has that kind of um
almost grayish green tone to it to me
it has a lot to do with the trichome
coating but if you can imagine that kind
of
grayish green color with uh coated in
trichomes and these beautiful like
purple hairs that are interlaced in it
it just it
turned out to be one of those beautiful
flowers i've ever grown
uh and then the the just the complexity
of flavor of g13
is another one that uh and that's what
i'm
it's work those are the really the
genetics that really get to me
are the ones that
have multiple layers of flavor you know
something on the inhale
something else on the exhale and then
those flares continue to evolve even
after the exhale
so for me the standout strains
going even going back in time are the
ones that
had that same quality and g13
certainly has that same quality
yeah okay and so i mean you just touched
on it you said you popped a bag seed
what was the first strain you ever grew
wow
let's see here
so
let me think about that that is so there
was some
seeds that we had gotten out of what was
supposed to have been
back then it was just called purple haze
who knows really what it was
um those were probably some of the first
seeds
that we cracked where i actually had
successful plants um and those were
actually
indoor and then there was also a durbin
poison back then but that wasn't
per that wasn't bagsy that was actually
purchased from a friend of mine who went
over to amsterdam and brought some seeds
back
um so there was some durban poison back
then there was the purple haze
um there was once a
bag seed from a blueberry uh
see we scored some blueberry in 95 after
a fish show
outside the spectrum in philadelphia and
there was a blueberry uh so and you know
these who knows what the actual
crosses were that's you know that's the
that's the whole fun of bag seeds right
back in the day is
you knew pretty much what the female was
but had no idea what created the seed in
that female
of course you know nobody was sending uh
lineage information with
the with the cannabis we were receiving
so
there you know
i i have to say you know just going back
i'm pretty sure there's the purple haze
and then the durbin those would have
been the very first ones that were
successfully grown and then after that
um you know i wish i wish i back in
those days i'd kept better notes
but i didn't uh we weren't certainly
thinking about recording anything on
paper back then
that would have been way too risky
yeah all too common of an answer don't
worry sure
so you referenced that the four-way was
one of the things which kind of inspired
you to start breeding
with that being said what was your first
ever breeding project
so the very first one
and i'm going to kind of skip to the
second or third
because it's the one that really made a
difference so
there was an nl5 haze
that i had at the time and
then there was some big bud and there
was a big bud
male that was used to
pollinate the nl5 haze and this would be
the first
cross and and you know of course you
have to keep in mind bear in mind here
these are names that were given to
strains and in those days
i have to be very blunt here it's
anybody's guess what it really was
you know uh unless it came out of a seed
pack it was very hard to validate
anything
i can't tell you how many you know
flowers we saw that were called skunk
that certainly weren't skunk or even for
that matter you know northern lights
that weren't truly normal lights it was
they were just kind of blanket
labels given to whatever looked good so
but that that first very successful one
was the nl5 big
n5 haze big bud cross and that's
actually the one
that i'd sent back to uh virginia to a
friend of mine who gave me kind of the
two thumbs up
you know as good as the four-way um and
from that point forward
i really didn't want to slow down the
process
once i got the the gold stamp approval
from my buddy
and from there there were um
so i started playing around with silver
pearl in the late
90s and another strain called kc36 which
was uh
from casey brains in brazil and i the
silver pearl i had was a cut
of fema that was from uh scentsy seed
bank and
casey brains pack of seeds that i got
provided me in very
interesting mail and so i
worked with that one in the late 90s
and developed a strain that i called
proof
and the proof was a
due to the silver pearl content was a
strain that finished up in about 47 days
uh it was just to prove and we called it
proof just because to prove that things
didn't have to go eight or nine weeks
so a little bit yeah just a little bit
and the proof was something that i
worked with um
you know that's the only genetic that
i've ever taken to
an f3 but it became also a foundation
that i have built off here
over the years whenever i want to induce
a short flowering period i can
generally you know crack one of them and
at this point the proof seeds are
somewhat homogeneous uh they're very
predictable in what they'll actually uh
uh grow out to so if i have a good male
donor
then i can you know throw that onto a
proof email and if i want you know if
i've got a good proof
uh mail then i can throw that onto
something else but
uh that one that that that cross was
one that made me very happy for a period
of time
and then you know as soon as we get into
the early 2000s
really right around 0.405
that's when more breeding happened and i
get
there most of the breeding that i have
done in the past
has been intentional s1s
there have been some true breeding
projects
but those are a little bit more recent
and you know sometimes s1s get a bad
rap and some you know from some folks
but i think
most of some of the greatest genetics
we've seen
on this planet are generally a result of
s1 situations yeah that's definitely a
topic i'd love to get into in just a
moment but i just want to quickly draw
you back
you referenced casey brains it's a
really
really kind of obscure breeder the thing
i am most interested in him
is is that oh you know the collective
whoever it was or whoever they were
essentially they're notable because they
never released
the information around any of their
strains and yet at the time they were
still
regarded as quite really good like you
know very good breeders essentially
and i just thought it's so interesting
it's such a polarization because you
could
never be successful in today's market
doing that and yet it just i guess it
goes to show like it wasn't a concern
back in the time
right you know lineages were
as far as i remember you know lineages
weren't something that we were overly
concerned about in the early days
i know that uh you know the kc36 and
i've you know
years gone past i've gone and tried to
look up as much as i could on it but
i haven't really been able to find much
of anything because you know he's at
that
at that air and that era you know he's
simply giving the label to the strain
of the you know during the during
whatever however old he was that year
so the 36 is the strain he created when
he was 36 years old
um but yeah you know the the that was
not necessarily something
that you know even that i was even aware
of that people were really that
concerned about back in the day
uh is you know what what is the lineage
here
more you know more important to folks
was what kind of flower is this going to
produce
and so with that being said do you think
that a lot of the stuff was quite inbred
or do you think it had like a diverse
variety within it
[Music]
you know i think that really has a lot
to do with the commitment level of the
breeder back then
i mean you know you can
take someone as certain
like someone like dj short you know he's
he's stabilized
his blueberry line was an f4 f5 across
these the one that's
touted now and you know it's a it's a
predictable strain at this point
and you know someone who like that has
worked with the genetics over a year and
year and year to try to kind of
homogenize the outcome
however then there were also you know a
lot of
f1s that get out there in the world and
you're going to see a ton of diversity
from those
so i think it kind of goes back to
the breeder and how
important it was to that particular
breeder to
stabilize that genetic um
for you know for market from you know to
put in
to put into the market i you know i i
don't really think that
you know it it had anything to do with
you know
the company so much as it you know just
just just the breeder just you know
and and how uh committed they were to
trying to create stability in the strain
i mean the further you get
you know the f1 two three and four and
five and the deeper you get into that
certainly the more stable the genetic
comes and of course that generally
reduces
the diversity as well so something you
referenced earlier
uh just a second ago in fact was uh
scentsy those were some of the seeds
that were
popular at one point when you were
buying you also referenced neville so
golden segway for me this is a bit of a
weird question a little bit
controversial but at the same time it's
so obvious i can't believe that it's
even like a bit of a weird thing
you know sensei went to [__] at some
point why do you think that happened and
who's responsible
you know i really feel like
since he kind of took the fun out of
genetics
and i think a lot of that had to do with
trying to make their seed outcome
more marketable based on what they
thought people liked
um you know the the first genetic that
certainly comes to mind here is
something like the skunk you know
every we all kind of agree that since
he's the one that added sweetness to
skunk one
uh that original roadkill skunk wasn't a
you know wasn't a sweet tasting strain
at all
um it was kind of offensive to and in
some respects
um but sensei certainly produced a skunk
one
that had a very sweet note to it and
that to me you know ruined that that let
that
strain you know forever so
you know that's what i think sensei did
is they took a lot of diversity out of
the game
and they did that over the years too
because i feel like they continued to
like further try to stabilize
you know the strain so that they could
create something that was predictable
but i don't know that you know that
which is predictable is all that much
fun
especially when it comes to something
like cannabis and
and you know growing from seed
part of the fun of growing from seed is
exploring the depths of
what that that strain can produce
and if you're you know if what's
important to you
is you know a marketable strain or a
marketable seed pack and you want
stability and you want something
predictable
it just kind of it waters it down
and i think they did a very good job of
watering down a lot of genetics
so i mean while we're on the general
topic if we do look back at all the
companies that have existed throughout
time
which one do you think was the best
that's a good question
if i had to you know super sativa seed
club
if i'm looking back in in time a little
bit
i think they brought forth some very
very important
genetics to the to the world and i
thought i think that they also provided
us
with some of the foundations that a lot
of really popular strains now are built
off of um and
if i look to more recent
times you know when i was still going
over to amsterdam back in the
2000s i really had um
i really i really had a a
a general love for uh th seeds for adam
dunn's group
oh there you go nice and i thought some
of the
strains that they were i really loved
his mk ultra especially before it was
feminized
do you think something changed beyond
the obvious
uh yes i do um so
i'd grown so i gotten some mk ultraseeds
over in amsterdam
before it was feminized and
the there's a particular chemo bar that
is just straight mothballs
and i love that uh it's a it's a complex
deep smelling flower like i said the
mothballs comes to mind
first on the nose it's a phenomenal hash
maker
so i fell in love with that particular
selection
and i had a friend go back over to
amsterdam a couple years later
and bring back some of the feminized
version
and what we saw fairly consistently out
of that
was a kind of had a
light purplish hue to it and had
this sweeter note that
kind of overpowered anything that was
chemical or fuelly
and it just wasn't as exciting
as the version we as the king of r that
we had seen come out of the
pre-feminized days
so the genetics have always been listed
as b13 and og kush
yes however you know i love you adam but
that's never made sense to me
how do you make regular seats with two
clone onlys
well so you know i
i don't know if there was a reversal
done
which is somewhat possible
uh maybe there was access
to the uh to the um
g13 seed somewhere in that vault i don't
know that's that's a very good question
and interestingly enough
if i think back on it you know i can see
both genetics in that flower
you know you can definitely see the og
cushion there you can taste the og
cushion there there's a little bit of
that earthiness for sure
um but it's something i've never really
given too much thought to
and the only thing i can think of is
either there was something going on with
the g13 or perhaps something
was reversed which
little colloidal silver who knows but
that's just going to create us ones yeah
that's a very good question
i like to hear his answer on that
actually i forgot to ask him
hopefully we'll find out one day someday
yes
just take a step back or wind down a
little
something which everyone remembers
fondly what was your first experience
with the chem dog
well that definitely goes back to the
east coast
and it was definitely
at a fish show it was
definitely at hampton coliseum
trying to remember what year i think it
was 97
probably and it was
a friend of mine who had packed a nice
glass bowl and passed it to me during
the
show and wow
that was one explosive hit back then
there was just nothing like it nothing
that had
at that point had even come close to
that
super chemical fuel taste uh
it was definitely it was definitely that
that one changed the game
uh you know it was it was interesting
because
you know i knew of kim back in the day
but i knew him only as a glassblower it
really the connection to the genetic
had not been made at that point for me
at all
it wasn't until years later that i
actually made that connection
um but yeah that flower was
just phenomenal i just i
will never forget the the nose burn
and the eyes watering and just how it
hit the frontal
of the head and you know kicked your
body temp up about two degrees
just about immediately you know
yeah you know it's kind of like it's
like taking that first you know the
first dab
you ever take you know it's it's a whole
new experience
and um you know didn't have really the
opportunity
to you know find out where it came from
or purchase any or anything like that so
i had that experience in the in the 90s
and then
it wasn't until i moved out west and
then you know met a few folks
and some folks who were um growing
one version or another that we saw more
of it but
that that was that was definitely one
memorable bull hit i can tell you that
much
and so do you think that was the 91
so 1998 you know i i'm pretty yeah
at this point of my career i'm pretty
sure it was
i don't think it was the d and of course
the no nobody was really running some of
the others
at that point it certainly was too way
too early for the four
which you know we'll of course talk
about that a little bit later but
um uh you know at that point yes i'm
pretty sure that was the 91.
i was about to say that that temperature
one got me that's i always get crushed
by that one and the other one
my friends love to say is uh you get
sweaty feet
that's a good one i might have to use
that yeah
uncomfortably high right right right oh
absolutely
don't i know about that sometimes so
hard question which out of all the chem
cuts is your favorite and just know if
you say chem 4 you are dead to me
well you know okay so can we sidebar for
a second
okay so so sidebar for a second
so there's been this whole thing where
i've had to change up the genetics on
dog walker right
i don't know if you're aware of this but
you know i did it on instagram whatever
so uh for many years i was under the
impression that i had the 91 and it
turns out it's the four
now going back to the the 91
yeah now that i have gone back and
resampled it
91 is probably my favorite but i but i
do
don't mind the four she's certainly been
a
good foundation for me uh to breed with
um so 91 is going to be my favorite
so you're saying you're half dead to me
i'm only half dead that's right only
half dead
and and i wish i wish i could say i i
you know think it's deplorable but i
don't it's
it's been good to me and i i certainly
can't complain and
you know somewhere hiding in that genome
is is a whole lot of gas
because it certainly has shown off in
some of my offspring
oh yeah i get this weird betadine taste
from it like iodine it's weird you know
interesting yeah i like that
so i guess just to kind of summarize for
people who maybe
missed what we were talking about there
i guess the reason why that's important
is because
you've gone on to create a few very
well-known strains
using your cut which you thought was 91
turns out to be the number four
so i think that's the reason why maybe
it's a little more relevant that that
post was made but just to essentially
explain it for everyone um one eye put
up a post saying hey everyone just so
you know
like we thought that the dog walker was
91 across albert walker it's actually
the chem 4 cross albert walker there you
go everyone's on the same page now
um so i guess the first thing is
that that obviously suggests that the
chem was the pollen donor in the albert
in sorry the dog walker correct not
correct
so okay so this is a game
of selfing
genetics and it's really starts off
with the uh what i call the a wong it's
actually an
albert walker og cross so going back
to we got the um og here in portland the
og question oh four
and in o5 i had a plant
that self and all that was a single
pollen spike
so i plucked that spike and
a lot of people have a hard time
believing this but this is god's honest
truth
plucked a little spike put a little ten
put it in my fridge
and later that summer or follow
in summertime had
the albert walker plant and decided to
take that little bit of pollen on a
little tiny paintbrush and just dust a
branch of the albert walker plant
and that little process
yielded a measly six seeds
and i got four of those to crack i
actually lost
two of the seeds somehow but four of
those were cracked i went with the most
vigorous one
that showed a pre you know pre-flowered
female
and that one ended up selfing
itself in somewhere around week three so
i kind of went through this process from
like pulling
pollen spikes and trying to keep up with
it but of course
certain things got pollen you know that
that plant got pollinated
and that produced about 200 seeds uh
which we called the awog
albert walker og the awog
i decided again to revive it
some years later right around 2009
and had at that point had just
acquired the what we now know was chem-4
plant and the awog that i was growing
two aw
do different aog plants one of them was
just a beast and super stable the other
one turned out
not to be so stable
so she then spit onto the
to the chem 4 and then i actually
collected some of her
stamen and kept that in a little
container that i later used
to create a another string called the
walk
crossing it with forum cut so you know
what we do have here admittingly is a
lot of instability but very intentional
uses of those
unstable plants and when it came time to
crack
the dog walker seeds the original the
original cracking
um it was just you know we i had a
few hundred of the seeds and we
cracked uh about 10 of them
and you know knowing that they
you know no males were going to get
produced out of this project
i decided to look at i think there were
four particular ones that were growing
really
nicely we liked the stem rub you know
the
the odor that came off of that and one
of those
kind of out was was a bit muskier
if you will than the others and that one
was just selected and we
and i ran with that one and you know it
so
what you have is the albert walker og
actually
selfing onto the chem 4 plant
and that's how we got the original and
current dog walker seeds
and so i guess what might be surprising
out of that whole story is that
the dog walker ag is not regarded as an
unstable plant
would you agree with that or do you
think it does throw pollen well
so here so one of the things we saw very
early on and this is only in the first
probably year year and a half of its
existence
was that it did not it was very
hypersensitive to oversaturation with
light
and so in the very early days
there were a couple of us who
experienced and you got to remember in
the early days there's only eight
gardens that are running this strain
um but a couple of us were seeing this
phenomenon where it would
try to self kind of towards the end of
the round
and so believe it or not
i think it was my
friend of mine out at heroes of the farm
who
decided to pull his lights back another
you know 12 inches or something like
that went from like 24 inches to 36
inches this is under single ended
thousand watt lights
and then all of a sudden that issue went
away
so we kind of went word went around the
small group of hey
uh you know she she gets oversaturated
pretty easily
back your lights off it'll prevent any
of these issues
and since that era i have yet to see a
single
unstable response from that plant period
uh and certainly don't hear lots of
murmurs about that being about it being
unstable
um you know whenever they're you know
whenever
someone calls or contacts or you know
comes in the store to ask me about you
know
growing it the first recommendation i
make is
put her on the perimeter if you can't
raise your lights
she does a lot better on the perimeter
around and not
and splash over crossover zones than she
does
you know directly under her in the
crossover she's a perimeter plant for
sure
or get those lights a pie
so in general the dog walker og it's
it's really kind of gained itself a cult
status along with the scooby snacks
which we'll get into shortly
how do you think that happened you know
like what do you kind of attribute it to
just just the quality or do you think
there was you know like the right people
were growing it at the right time type
of thing
full disclosure yeah go for it
okay um so it was all intentional
um oh yeah so
this was during a time here in oregon
where
some of the the best cultivators that i
knew
uh were starting to have to take
less and less and less you know chipping
away at the bottom line of what they
were getting
for their product and it was also right
at the beginning
of the cookie craze so 09 and i'd been
down
in northern california at a friend's
farm i
gotten he showed me the cookie and he
was complaining like oh people pay you
know a thousand two thousand dollars a
cut for this stuff and you get you know
top end at all the dispensaries
and when i you know when i sampled the
plant it was it was amazing flour
super tasty but i was like what what
gives you know what is the driving force
behind the craze and he said well just
you know it's really hard to get a cut
of it and they really limit the release
and so i came back here to oregon
and thought about that a bit and i said
you know
if if there's some way somehow to come
up with something here
that you know i could create
give to a limited number of people we
control the release of it
we don't give it out uh and if it's good
enough
perhaps we can kind of start this same
kind of craze
here in oregon just with an organ
produced genetic
and at that time
had the chem iv there was the selfing of
the alog
i think this is a good thing i think
this could be the cross
and it was really a stroke of luck
that the you know the king of r that we
selected was the one that is out and
available today
as soon as we finished that plant that
first you know
bong hit of it was this is it you know
we know we have something here
so i did a limited release to
eight other growers that i knew in the
area that were all friends
and you know we kind of had a pow wow
this is
the plant here is what it's worth
don't take anything less than that don't
give out
cuts this was also very during the very
first
early days of our quasi-dispensary
system here in portland or medical
you know dispensaries so there were only
a couple at that point just two or three
that were definitely operating uh very
much in the gray
but you know if these places wanted this
this is what it cost even though
there was everything else was
significantly cheaper and we kind of
stuck to our guns and that
that project worked great for about 18
months
and then you know cuts were stolen
and partnerships fractured and people
got you know butt hurt and
but to this day you know it still
is a crowd pleaser um you know for me
personally it's still a strain that i
never get bored or tired of
um and it's uh you know it's it's
kind of legend and lore was born
out of trying me my attempt to give
something back to my
friends to give them an opportunity to
do a little better
so it came from a good place but it was
certainly an exercise in market
manipulation
do you feel like that is a negative
thing in the cannabis industry given
it's so rampant in other industries
there's
a growing movement in australia that you
know people want everything to be as
cheap as possible or
that type of thing because they're like
oh it's medicine and it's like no one
can see that like
there's obviously a literal business
side of things as well and like
you know what i mean it's it's an
interesting thing because it's like
people almost
think that it all the regular rules
don't apply to cannabis because it's
for some people you know it's more than
just a recreational thing
well yeah there's a lot of altruistic
dreamers in the cannabis industry
but at the end of the day this is
now and has been for many years people's
livelihoods
uh they're you know we've certainly
watched here
in our state prices go from
you know 3 000 and this is going
like in the medical market of course you
know and now the wreck market and
medical market you know but people
years just a few years ago getting
upwards of three thousand thirty two
hundred dollars a pound and now they're
having to settle for
you know twelve hundred fourteen hundred
for the same quality
uh and it's not that it costs any
less to cultivate it you certainly have
to figure out how to survive in a lower
margin market
but uh yeah you know i i think
it has great value and i think it should
you know the
boutique side of this industry and i'm
speaking more for
you know our state at this point the
boutique side of the industry
and the mass cultivation side of the
industry will separate
and there will be added value and value
given higher value given to boutique
produce cannabis
right now that is there's there's no
dichotomy there there's just no
separation there or at least there's
very little
um so i think that
it's important to have
to place greater value
on cannabis that is produced with great
thought
great passion uh intense work
uh you know not total automated systems
and so forth and so on so
i i i kind of i don't think
you know it should be the cheapest thing
in the world because
once again for a small producer
that's that's a death sentence and
i think it should be you know i think it
should be a free market to where there's
opportunity for all yeah exactly
and the thing that i like is not taking
any personal stabs but i find a lot of
the people making these broad types of
claims are
generally people who still buy into that
whole [__] of like you know like
gucci brands and they want a mercedes
car it's like guys you want you want
premium everything else just not premium
cannabis
okay right right right right you'll pay
you'll buy up you know 4 500
handbag for your lady but you don't want
to pay more than five dollars a gram for
cannabis
yeah i i don't get that you know when i
when i
first so one of my first dispensary
experiences
in uh portland was at a place here that
had kind of a farmer's market style
approach
you pay a booth fee each day and you
could sit there and you know
pass out your wares and it used to amaze
me
how many people came in you know under
the medical program
and they'd want to sit there and you
know go to the smoking room and
roll a blunt up but then every so often
you know somebody would actually come in
in a wheelchair
or someone would actually come in who's
going through chemo
and needs help getting through the door
and it was just such a
stark contrast between
you know the people who really needed
the medicine and then the people who
just kind of wanted the medicine and and
i
you know look i make no i make no ill
claim to anyone who just wants to smoke
cannabis i mean that's primarily my my
take on it
uh but for the you know for those
those folks that really need the
medicine there should be programs for
those
individuals uh it's just there's you
know the way the state hands out the
medical cards
uh you know it's kind of hard to tell
if they need it or if they just want it
speak speaking on like the medical model
in oregon in general
i've heard whispers from people that the
general trend in oregon
is that there's a few companies opening
up really big facilities
and their production is so high that's
one of the major contributing forces to
that downward trend on pricing
do you feel that is actually an accurate
analysis of the situation
absolutely yeah absolutely there's a
statistic that came
out uh mid-december of last year where
we had about 1.2 or 1.1 million
pounds in our metric system wow now
the year before the entire state for an
entire
excuse me entire year consumed about 430
or 460 000 pounds doubled
yeah oh yeah oh absolutely i mean almost
tripled
and so there is
there is an absolute glut in our
industry here
and you know once that products entered
into metric you don't have that old
backdoor opportunity anymore
it's locked up in the system so there
are you know i think
we're gonna see a lot of folks
having hard times weathering this storm
in our state
uh you know recreational growers uh it's
gonna be it's and i think you know i
think who really survives here
uh or has the best opportunity to
survive are these smaller producers you
know their
their necks aren't extended out quite as
far
as some of you know financially as some
of these you know large
well-funded operations but if you're not
turning a profit
and it's you're still dumping more money
into something it's
it's that's a hard hole to get out of
with prices plummeting
you know i don't think we've seen the
bottom here yet oh wow
where do you think they'll bottom out at
i don't know
500 maybe wow yeah
so something i was interested in a
little kind of peripheral but it's kind
of the same band
when i was in oregon i thought it was a
really interesting place it was almost
like the twilight zone in a lot of
regards because it's extremely similar
to australia in regards to like people's
general attitudes the mood you know it's
pretty really laid back pretty welcoming
that type of thing
that was really cool the biggest thing
that stood out in my mind though was
i thought people were far more
environmentally and kind of ethically
aware of their actions and their
decisions and you know everyone wants to
be as
organic as possible things like that far
more in oregon than in australia
the dichotomy which slapped me in the
face though was doesn't seem to be that
same focus in regards to cannabis in
regards to organically grown versus
synthetically grown
how do you think that exists like a lot
of the cannabis i tried in oregon myself
was all organic as far as i could tell
so yeah that's that's a great that's
actually a great point
and being in the retail inside of the
industry i can actually speak speaking
volumes of this
so it really depends where you are in
oregon
and it can even be as simple as
what part of a county you're in whether
you're seeing salt synthetic growers
organic bottle growers organic no-till
you go down to a place like eugene
which is uh you know just a little bit
south here of portland
a college town full of loads of hippie
and counter culture folks
and you're going to see tons of
organically
produced cannabis you get back up here
to portland and the city kind of divides
between
you know portland and then the west side
which is uh
beaverton and hillsborough you see a lot
more salt growers out in that zone
but then as you go closer you go further
east
towards mount hood from portland you
start to get into
rural you know farm country and there's
certainly a lot of
a lot of organic producers there now
you know the other thing to keep in mind
here is a lot of these
cultivators 10 years ago
not even 10 years ago six years and five
years ago
were still running small opera smaller
operations and not necessarily
uh producing for
you know there were clandestine
operations they're not necessarily
producing for the medical market
so you know it was about it's all about
production and you're starting to see
that kind of turn
now there's a lot of commercial groups
that are just about production
but we actually see you know the store
that i work for we're very
as far as what we focus on and what we
kind of preach
we certainly preach and focus more on
organic and sustainable approaches
to cultivation doesn't mean that we
won't sell canada or advanced or
botanical and we certainly do
but we we try to push for the organic
thing through our store
there are other stores that rarely push
organics and you'll find
you know a lot more synthetic products
on their
on their shelves and so you know as you
skip around
from store to store in the city you can
see
really what that main customer base is
based on
the nutrients that are more than readily
available
totally i can agree with that last point
you know 100
because we're kind of experiencing that
ourselves and that previously there's
only been synthetic options and over the
past few years we've seen the rise in
organic options becoming more available
and it really is a direct reflection of
the market demand as far as i can see
yeah and it's true and believe it or not
we end up having to educate a lot of
you know growers both you know small
home growers and
uh commercial growers and how to turn
that operation into an organic operation
and you know so many a lot of your
synthetic growers
have kind of had it drilled into their
head that this is the way to yield
this is how you yield this is you know
the organics doesn't yield enough
and that you know that couldn't be any
further from the truth uh
there there are certainly you know
organic approaches
that not only you know deliver
incredibly flavorful cannabis but also
can produce
phenomenal yields and you know the
yields are so much more
you know strain contingent than anything
else
if you ask me and and so i think this
you know i think there's this kind of
uh block blockade in the salt grower's
mind that i i can't go organic because
i'm going to lose out on my yield but
you know and and even cost wise you can
get very competitive cost wise
with organics i understand what you mean
i think
the other thing i've noticed maybe this
is just you know a little bit of
personal bias because i'm organic but
i think that the learning curve with
organics is a little steeper
and that's how we got to that point
where people say the yield isn't as good
and it's like now if you get up there
high enough on the curve you'll get the
same yield
absolutely i i couldn't agree with that
uh anymore
the that's there's there is if
you're right about one thing the curve
is a little steeper and it's a little
longer
on fine-tuning organics but really you
know
one of the best pieces of iso united
that i give out at the shop
is to you know pick a pick a program you
know
organic programming so whatever you know
and really
figure out how to how that program
can bring your strains to their full
genetic expression so don't switch
programs don't switch up genetics
work with those genetics with that
nutrient program where that
you know or you know no-till approach or
whatever
but learn you know see what inputs are
really influencing
that your group of genetics or your
strain or whatever so that you can get
that best expression possible
uh and i i truly believe that
it's certainly achievable through
organics
now it's achievable in synthetics too
for to some degree
um but you know the people that are
pushing tons of foss
salts into their product and bloom
boosting with their you know
you know 35 40 you know zero 35
40 project product at the end you know
they're going to end up with a bunch of
road flare product
for sure and it's not going to be very
flavorful but it's going to heal
not not to hate on our soul growers
we've got a few out there and some of
them do a really good job still
so on a lighter note i constantly hear
this analogy i want to know if you agree
it's a bit of tongue-in-cheek but
people say to me colorado weeds too dry
oregon weeds too wet
do you agree well colorado's too dry and
we're too wet
uh sure you know i mean you know that's
i always make the comment that whenever
i because i do go to denver
you know generally once or twice a year
and as soon as i walk off the airplane i
can feel the moisture leaving my lips
because it is that dry there uh and it
is you see that
uh in colorado with you know i take
you know cannabis there and within two
days if it's not you know in a sealed
container with a
humidity pack it's turned to rock hard
and eventually
dust and you know yeah it's it's damp up
here in oregon
but you know i it it you know i i a
great example for colorado i have a
friend of mine who used to run you know
he probably still does runs humidifiers
in his drying room
you know that's that's a testament to
how freaking dry it is there and you
know here
it's really about how you how you dry
your cannabis and how you cure it after
that
so you know i i could i could understand
someone's gripe with
oregon being a little too damp
and uh you know colorado is certainly
dry
yeah okay so get back to our industry
talk
in case we didn't make it a bit obvious
you've obviously managed and run
hydroponic stores
grow stores in general for many years
i'm sure you've seen the fads come and
go
what products do you think fall under
that general fad cycle you know to me
feels like we've had you know the
shilajit trend it's almost completely
died off you know
not almost there's maybe a few
stragglers but they'll die off soon
yeah i mean
there have been a load of what i just
call kind of flash in the pan products
and i you know you'll have to forgive me
because
i i can't in good conscience call out
too many of them on the negative just
because i'm going to sell some of them
and i'll probably hear back from others
but you know they're the hype products
that
companies invest loads of money on
uh into the marketing of those products
um
some of them are here to stay for a long
time some of them have come and gone
already
um but at the end of the day
you know the i kind of split the
industry into two groups
there's the products that are made to
market and then they're the products
that
are just made and what we what i often
find is the
the the hyped companies if you will uh
products you know they all work
otherwise they wouldn't be in business
but you're
gonna pay out the wazoo forum because
gosh they have to back all that
marketing somehow
and two it's
you know it's generally pretty cannabis
but not the best tasting cannabis
so for me you know
things like uh what's a good
program to that falls into this kind of
flash in the pan
category yeah
yeah you know i look and that that book
you know so funny
when that book came out uh how
you know so many people clamored into
the store and wanted us to explain to
them how to do it like i don't know you
got to buy the 500
book you know they explain how to do it
you know of course that led to all the
stripping the leaves and everything like
that and be like oh all you got to do is
strip leaves well no there's a whole
like nutrient
feed that they put in that book that you
know compensates for the loss of your
storage houses
uh so you know it's it's
you know i i don't want to pick on
anybody in particular
but there's a few of them out there uh
and and i i keep stressing the heavily
marketed heavily marketed thing
uh you know products that that work
and produce well don't need a lot of
hype
they speak for themselves the results
speak for themselves
and so you know i have sold product
on and off for the last 17 years
and you know seen
a lot of good ones come and i've seen a
few bad ones go
you know the there was a point in time
here in the states
a few years back uh going back to the
kind of mid 2000s to
2010 era roughly where uh
there was pocobutazole showing up in all
these uh flower boosting products
phosphoload red dragon it was funny
because the companies that were creating
these products were just simply
they create one it would get banned and
then they would just
you know rename relabel the same product
and wait for that one to get banned you
know
butcherozo is definitely not a very
pleasant compound
um known carcinogen especially if you're
smoking it in fact there was a you know
a company down in california
that had been called out by a couple of
states for their content of it
uh and eventually if i'm not mistaken
the epa got involved
um you know and banned the product
nationally
so you know some of these
and a few of these products were pretty
you know heavily marketed and yeah this
is the game changer you know
increase your yields tenfold whatever
but all at what expense to the end user
and uh so it was that and you got to
remember too there was
very very very very very little
regulation on our industry until just a
few years ago
you describe the australian market right
now the you know rampant with
plant grown uh plant growth regulators
and
i guess the issue which i'm really
interested in knowing and you probably
have the answer is
you just referenced one situation where
it happened how rampant do you think the
problem is
of companies having off-label pgrs do
you think it really is a common
occurrence or it's more of a
rare i think you know
in all honesty i believe that it's
not as rampant as it used to be in this
country
if you go back five or six years it was
pretty rampant
once states like california
uh and oregon for their registration
required uh
full disclosure of contents uh that
started that ceased
the frequency of products like that ever
making it back into our market
uh you know few of these companies were
shut down and sued and made a lot of you
know kind of a racket throughout the
industry
and that that got people to notice you
know before nobody really noticed nobody
really knew to ask you know if this had
a
you know a harmful pgr in it uh they
just saw the results that it created and
thought like well
this product works let's keep using it
uh and that's
unfortunately you know a the the
the result of having
you know back then which was really an
uneducated customer base
which allowed a lot of bad actors to
thrive in our industry here
but once there was you know state
intervention on the level you know by
the department of agriculture in various
states
then the situation
started to correct itself and i feel
like we're at a point
now where it is at least in our state
and certainly in california
very very difficult to register a
product
uh that has in for our industry that has
a pgr you gotta remember uh the states
we don't have a unified registration for
the entire country
each state has its own registration for
uh nutrients pesticides fungicides
whatever
so the reason why i bring up that
question is because on your instagram
page there's like a post kind of
referencing that there was some uh i
believe the product is called azatrol
and yeah it had some adulterants in it
but they weren't actually plant growth
regulators they were more like um
in yeah what's the pesticide yeah
pesticide i was gonna say insecticides
but yeah pesticides
do you think this is something which is
a little more rampant given
and i was going to ask you this is a
question as well you know what do you
think the next trend will be in terms of
these fad products we mentioned
i feel like pesticides fungicides these
are the ones on the rise you know it
seems like every day there's a new one
especially organic ones
right so um so we have uh
we have a a registration here
through the epa uh which is 25b
compliant which is
low or minimum risk pesticides which
those
generally do not have to be thoroughly
tested you just have to register as such
as long as the ingredients that you
provide are all 25b compliant then the
epa approves your product
and it's a lot of these 25b compliant
products quote unquote that
seem to be sneaking things into their
products and of course when it comes
when when rubber meets the road with
this and the company has their back
against the wall you know they blame
their partners they blame
you know some nefarious force that slip
this into their product but at the end
of the day
they're adding adulterants for some
reason other or there's some kind of
crap cross-contamination happening at
their facility the azo12 one is very
interesting and intriguing to me because
when when i looked into the compounds
that were showing up in those tests
uh as adulterants the addition
of those particular compounds made zero
zilch
no sense whatsoever from a
ipm or uh knock down approach
strategy you know even even if you're a
big ag person
the that particular group just didn't
make any sense why we'd all be in there
together
so part of me wants to think that
perhaps there's some kind of residual
contamination that's happening at that i
mean the company that manufactures that
product manufactures
every single one of those compounds in
some shape or form
uh through their company and uh it
manufactures that load so you know it
doesn't make sense for a company of that
magnitude because you gotta remember
that's not a hydro industry company
that's an ag company uh so it doesn't
make any sense for them
to intentionally adulter their product
now
the fact that it hasn't come back to
market yet that's very curious to me
um but something that one was very
strange
there have been a couple others and
believe it or not our store has kind of
been ground
zero for the discovery of these products
what really brought
the adulterant of pesticides to light
for our industry was the testing of
finished product of the cannabis
and and concentrates and
so the one of the first major cases we
had here
was with a product called guardian
and guardian was being produced i think
out of a company
out of michigan you know lemongrass oil
cinnamon uh a couple other little
essential oils and it was being sold
believe it or not to organic growers as
a way to knock
back russet mites which had just kind of
found their way into the
oregon scene and everyone was just
having this
incredible success
with these essential oils
you know and none of us wow they've just
kind of unlocked the key here because no
one
at that point in time was having very
much success getting rid of russet mites
and eventually uh i think it was two or
three
cultivators
down in eugene or in that area uh failed
their pesticide screening uh for
because uh abamectin was present
and uh a lot of folks will know the
brand name
avid if some people said it was
ivermectin some people says abamectin
whatever so what the department of ag so
the
the lab that found these test results uh
called called all the growers and said
you know everybody write down your list
of all
your inputs and the three gardens all
had one common denominator which was
this guardian product
so that lab og analytical down in eugene
called the department of ag and said hey
we have a suspicion here so the
department of ag contacted our store
because we sold one of the bottles
and said hey do you have this product we
said yeah we do like okay we're going to
come by and
grab a bottle off your shelf so they
bought a bottle off of our shelf
they went down to eugene it's about two
hours away south bought a bottle off
their shelf and then went down to
southern oregon
and bought a bottle of those tested all
three of those independently voila
there's abamectin
so you know you call the uh you know so
then the department of bag
calls the company the the manufacturer
and the guy says oh my partner just
put some of that in no your partner
didn't just slip some of that and it's
been there all along
that's why it's actually killing russet
mites because i'm sorry lemongrass and
cinnamon oil
isn't going to kill or us it might um it
will
they they're they're great uh repellents
but not necessarily
kill factor um so
that was the first case where
pesticide screening actually
benefited the community
and it was that event that got
me very very interested in you know
looking at adulterants that were
currently in
in products in our industry and
right after the uh right after the
guardian situation there was another one
with a product called mighty wash
that was wildly and rampantly available
as a 25b
this one had frequency water in it right
quote unquote
and it was killing mites everyone just
destroying mites
spider mites too spotted right and uh
oh it's it's it's you know the the the
what was the the
a vortex implosion yeah
what was the the frequency would stun
the mite and the oil would suffocate
it and that was its mode of action
well so one of our customers comes back
to us and says hey you know
i've failed a couple tests now for
pyrethrum
oh well what are you using go down the
list oh
mighty wash huh so i call up the
department of ag and said hey
at this point we have a nice
relationship and i say hey we've got
this product here and
our customer keeps failing for pyrethrum
you want to come check this out
so i said we'll be right up so they came
and bought a bottle off of our shelf did
the same thing bottled down in southern
oregon bottle in
salem oregon state capital uh sorry
springfield
uh but then uh
they discovered pyrethrum in a product
that was 25b compliant now and pyrethrum
isn't the nastiest of compounds
really of all of the knockdown takedown
pesticides it's it's it's fairly safe to
use
but if you don't disclose it in your
product
and people are using your product to the
day of harvest and then making
concentrates from your product
see how things scale up very quickly
here yeah it's it's a problem
and you know this of course then goes
back to the micro butanol thing
and the eagle 20 and the cyanide
hydrogen or hydrogen cyanide that's
released from that
when it's combusted and that actually
got me
very heavily involved with a couple of
groups and
there's a one at least one white paper
out there that's published
that i was a part of and then i actually
went to speak
at a cannabis conference in new york
city uh
that uh
a group called bow tech analytical put
on it was an international cannabis
conference and spoke on a panel
with a couple of other individuals
specifically about
adulterants and entering into the supply
chain
for products used to cultivate cannabis
and um you know it was it was very
important to me
for at that point to you know because a
lot of these folks who came to this
conference
were very policy oriented or financial
oriented individuals
and they uh you know
it was something to explain you have to
understand that the majority of the
customers who are using these products
that are going to the grow store
are not necessarily you know they
certainly don't have pesticide
applicators licenses so they're they're
not
educated in the world of pesticides
pesticide application
uh so you know the the old you know
just used twice as much as what the
label recommends was
a pretty popular way of approaching
you know pesticide and fungicide use
uh so for me whenever a bulletin
and i'm always you know i'm linked in
with oda alerts the oregon department of
agricultural alerts
whenever a bulletin gets posted i'm
going to very quickly put it up
on the instagram there because you know
the folks who do follow me in this state
that's important for them to know
yeah okay so just kind of touching back
on
like i guess maybe a general undertone
that's been going on in the whole
conversation
do you view a lot of these new
organic-based pesticides with an eye of
caution or do you think that there is a
legitimate
kind of area of research that could be
done to develop better
organic pesticides and the reason why i
bring this up is because
you know there's obviously just such a
vast contrast in the effectiveness of
synthetic
versus organic like synthetic it's like
one application and stuff just dies
um with organic it seems like you know
we're really trying to just like you
know chase our tails but you can kind of
get on top of it eventually do you think
that's
the general situation and it's not going
to change too much
uh you know if by looking at what
you know california is allowing i'd say
that's definitely the situation
what you're dealing with once again is
an uneducated customer base
uh so until things like pesticide you
know and
if you look at so the way the or the
environmental protection agency works
here in the states
is if you have a product that you're
bringing to market you know the epa
tests it
goes through a rigorous testing 120 some
different tests
uh but they test it on specific crops
and on most
labels of most pesticides uh it lists
the specific crops that it is that is
legal to use that pesticide fungicide or
miticide on if you use it on some other
crop
let's say cannabis then you're
absolutely violating epa regulation and
you can be fined and
all kinds of horrible things can happen
right so
the the big fear of the state and
allowing any pesticide or fungicide is
that they would be
defying epa regulation by allowing
cultivators to do so
so what you find in most states
as far as what is allowed are a lot of
25b
compliant products that are safe
or you know that are that are generally
safe to you know
generally regarded as safe when they
call that grass
uh so these products are
somewhat benign in the sense that
they're they are good control measures
they are very difficult
they're not as they're not it's not as
easy to create solution from them but
they're we're getting better there's a
a couple of companies out there marone
bioinnovations that are putting forth
some pretty interesting products
uh that you know i certainly get behind
you
for me it's not about pesticides to
control pests
it's you know good practices beneficials
predatory insects that can play well
with bio-pesticides
to me that's the best approach
prevention is obviously the first step
but if you are dealing with you know
certain pests or certain funguses
uh there is generally a very good and
sound
organic approach to solving that problem
but it generally
requires multiple steps because they're
look even with chemicals there's no
magic bullet
in any of this so it repeat applications
and of certain products and of course
uh for me when it comes to you know
insects i
i love the idea of using predators
coupled with bio-pesticides
generally between those two arms
you can solve many many many problems
they have a pretty far reach so
something i
noticed on your instagram was that you
do the gas lantern method
it's a little yes yeah a little bit of
an unusual thing something everyone's
curious about but i find you know
certainly myself never tried it
what initially stimulated you to do it
and what about it causes you to keep
doing it so
oh gosh how many years ago was this
probably
[Music]
12 or 13 i was at a trade
show in denver and a
very good friend of mine
came up behind me and whispered gas
lantern check it out
and then walked away so
i was like okay so i was back in my
hotel room that night
after the event and you know started
looking online google gas lantern
gasoline
comes across you know joe's pietry's
thing okay so i'm looking at this whole
lighting schedule first i'm like wow
this is like mind-blowing i don't see
how this could ever work out but then
i'm reading
the um uh he had put together
kind of a reasoning of why this works so
well
and you know his whole theory is
that we we are constantly over
saturating
cannabis more so than it typically needs
uh to be to be lit and he starts with
you know people who like to do 24 hours
of veg for example he's like well
look at where it's 24 hours of light for
extended periods of time
that's generally the polar regions if
you look around the polar regions
granted it's cold but not much grows
there
you can even come down a little bit
further and then you get into tundra
regions but you know you're getting
lichen and grasses but nothing that's
lush and supple once again it's probably
more temperature related but
he's using this to drive a point home
and then out of that he's
he states that if you look at
plants that are veged you know six
eight ten weeks to get these large
plants indoors
under artificial lighting we generally
see
pre-flowering occurring somewhere in
that fifth to sixth week
of running like 18-6 and for a
photoperiod
obligate plant this is this is his
theory now
uh which i somewhat subscribe to for a
photoperiod obligate plant
that is a very unnatural reaction so
floral hormone should stay
bottled up in that plant until there
until that photo period triggers and
then that should release
release the hormone so he says so why
are we seeing these little
you know pistols showing up five six
weeks into a veg
well it has a lot to do with this over
lighting of plants
and it's more of a stress response so
the plants are
letting out little bits of floral
hormones uh during a time when it should
be keeping those bottled up
so that's kind of the reasoning
why he says so i read this and i think
okay well this kind of makes sense so
i get back to portland and
pretty soon thereafter decide okay i'm
going to try
i'm going to start with the veg
13 on what's it five and a half off
one on five and a half off or twelve on
excuse me twelve twelve on five and a
half off one on twelve uh
five and a half off again so anyway so
the light the light break is what kind
of keeps these floral hormones bottled
up and the way
he the way he rationalizes that is the
reason
the reason why they call the gas lantern
is you know northern latitudinal glass
houses
in the winter time trying to keep uh
flowering crops from flowering they go
through in the middle of the night
light up these gas lanterns and that
little bit of a light break in the
middle of the dark cycle would keep
those hormones bottled up so
the flowers wouldn't express or shift
gears so to speak
so i applied that
practice to my own garden pretty quickly
and was kind of amazed when i saw that
you know
eight weeks into veg there's no pistol
showing up
and then as soon as i put a plant into
flower
you know and the theory here is you get
this kind of rush of floral hormones
because they've been bottled up so long
uh when you put a plant in the flower
you get a
brush of floral hormones and so flower
set does
tend to occur a couple of days early
uh so i did the veg
side of it for about
five rounds almost for an entire year
before i ever subscribed to
the flowering in the diminishing light
on the flowering end
and i just you know i i just i i in the
beginning the first couple runs like i
just knew something bad was going to
come out of it and
fortunately nothing ever did but it was
it's such a leap of faith when you know
your entire
growing career you're told 18 6 18 6 18
6 this is how you do it
you know people say like oh you got to
have 24 hours of light over your clones
now you know when i people
suggested 24 hours of light over clones
to keep the temperature stable
that was it you know i clone under gas
lantern great great success from it
uh so on the veg side of things it's a
great money saving opportunity
especially for a large commercial grow
you know and i've heard lots of people
think oh you know it decreases your
yield or it slows down the veg and i i
couldn't that certainly has not been my
experience whatsoever certainly haven't
had any yield loss over the years and
the veg keeps up just as as good as ever
uh
so it but it is it's it's a huge
leap of faith and i can't stress that
it's it's such a hard shift to make in
your head
to say okay i'm only going to light
these veg plants up 13 hours a day
now yeah so i guess maybe
if we try to condense all that down into
one line would you advocate everyone
uses the gas lantern method
no because there are some strains
that will act adversely to it
uh equatorial strains especially um
i think that
and i've only had i've had one strain in
my life not
work with it and that was cenax cinnax
did not react very good to the veg
program at all
but cenex can be kind of a wild plant to
begin with
um but it yeah i mean
i think for someone who's coming out of
the gates maybe a hobbyist
if you want to have that you know
guaranteed your genetics going to work
fine with it then run your 18-6
but i think for someone with a little
more experience that's willing to
experiment with their genetics to see
how they react
like i said all of mine except for that
one strain
which i don't run anymore
all of mine have done fine by it so
you know i think someone with some
experience that's willing to take a risk
it's better for them than perhaps
someone who's completely agreeing to the
game
so just to completely clarify because i
only very briefly referenced it earlier
do you believe in defoliation at all
like yeah we kind of were you know
talking [__] about three a lot but
right do you believe there's any merit
in defoliation of any kind are you just
kind of not into it at all um no i mean
i do periodic
i i don't strip my plants personally um
and
and keep in mind too you know i'm a
smaller cultivator so i don't have a
giant warehouse or anything like that
um you know so i have the ability to
work very closely with the number of
plants that i do have
on a very personal level so you know
i will remove fan leaves as i see fit
if they're shadowing out of you know a
lower branch or i want to get a little
bit more light down that
you know down that that one branch you
know i will do periodic removal
throughout the bloom process but i am
not a fan leaf stripper
um it can work i've done it before
a couple of my varieties reacted fairly
decently to
it a couple of them didn't react so well
so i bagged it after two attempts
but keep in mind too that it's more than
just you know the stripping of the
leaves there's also this augmenting of
the feed
to provide you know kind of consistent
flow of nutrients because you are
removing those storage houses when you
strip them all away from the plant yeah
totally
so so let's take a step back i realized
we didn't go over and i really want to
know
the albert walker itself it's an
interesting strain it's a bit of an
enigma no one can tell me too much about
it and no one ever has any to smoke
sure so the albert walker
that we had in the mid
2000s was a very finicky plant but had
this
incredible kind of
combination of like a
rose note like from roses you know a
very floral
sweet rose note but with this crazy kind
of garlic funk
as well so it was like yeah
it was a very very strange and and
and you know interesting plant to me
it was a bit finicky so i didn't run it
for very long
um but it it just yeah it just had such
this clash of
noses on it that it was just it was just
remarkable
the high was decent it wasn't
uh stupendous or anything like that but
the the it was the flavor that really
got me and it's that unmistakable
rose note with that garlic kind of
buried in there that just it just gets
me every time and you know what
i haven't seen it for years i've seen a
lot of things come through i've actually
had a lot of folks because i've
at one point was kind of in this
headspace of
getting back to the root genetics of dog
walker
and so a couple years ago i went on a
hunt for
the albert walker and
i don't know three or four different
specimens have been brought to me and
none of them
none of them were there none of them
were it
so i i don't you know i'm sure it is
still in existence
i hear a lot of folks kind of on the
west there's a crew on the west side
of our area that runs albert walker
pretty heavy
but um i've yet to see what they're
producing
so yeah it's kind of and it is it's a
bit of an enigma string because i think
there's a lot of
impostors out there it's just like chem
you know there's so many impostors out
there
um finding getting to the to the you
know to the origin to the real
to that real cut can be a very a very
daunting task
and so do you give any credence to the
current online story which says that
you know originates from the grateful
dead i think it says roadie crew i'm
doubtful on that
but you know like some kind of grateful
dead genesis do you think that's true
and it also says that the suspected
genetics are
afghan skunk
yeah i you know look we have a lot of
incredible genetics came out of the
grateful dead scene that's for sure
um you know there's uh
there's loads of stories we can tell but
uh yeah i i do buy into the
you know i buy into the northwest origin
of it i
buy into the that it was something that
evolved out of the grateful dead scene
now whether it was the roadie crew
or someone else who really knows uh
and you said swazi skunk uh sorry
afghan skunk oh an afghan skunk
hmm not as interesting as swazi skunk
no that was just kind of thanks why this
gun sounds great yeah i mean i could
i could see that i mean it was
definitely a squatter plant
um what was really remarkable to me is
this very light colored uh
green almost like a pale green it was
never really a super dark robust plant
for us
you know that could have been part of
its finickiness and that's at that time
not being able to really dial it in
nutrient-wise
but it uh you know it
yeah i think it gets its origin from the
grateful dead scene i
i don't doubt that at all it's
interesting because it's certainly gone
on to make
you know a wide variety of well-known
strains but if we just take a bit of a
step forward to
after you've made the dog walker og
let's get into the scoobies
at what point did it become you know a
thought in your mind to cross dog walker
with the cookies
so that came out of my cookie experience
and it was very interesting with cookies
for me um
so i was running the forum cut this is
going to sound
really hard to to believe but if i
only ran one plant in the room
one cookie plant it would always produce
a tiny male cluster on one of the bottom
branches
just one though the first time it
happened i thought it was a phenomenon
the second time it happened it made me
pay attention and the third time it
happened i did it intentionally
and so it was the pollen
from that forum cut that i
used on that second event
to pollinate the dog walker because i
thought to myself
well here's this how cool would it be to
have all these purples and stuff
wrapped up in dog walker and
um i it was it was a risk
for me i didn't want though to create
like another
cookie plant you know what i mean like i
didn't want to be like grow you know
grow like
that cookie structure just drives me
crazy
so at the time i actually pollinated
with that
that little bit of male with that little
cluster that it developed
dusted a dog walker plant and then also
at the time i was running
a cotton candy kush and dusted a cotton
candy coach plant as well with it
and once again just using you know
collected pollen in a small container
little paint brush you know short
bristles
just painting it on and we ended up oh
gosh what did i have
probably close to 100
150 of the scooby seeds
and how many of those still exist
probably about 60 at this point
yeah i mean a lot of them went out for a
big fino hunt this summer out at heroes
of the farm
and unfortunately a lot of those were
lost
to a mouse issue when they were still
young and
tender a couple flats i think that
chewed up
at some point but uh there were some
others that were explored this summer
uh which i've yet to i saw them right as
they were finishing when they were still
in the greenhouse
but um you know the the original is a
hard one to beat and originally i had
two different phenos the one that i kept
and the other one wasn't very stable so
i called it the scrappy dew
yeah little tongue and cheek there and
that got actually passed on to some
folks and they did whatever they did
with it and it still kind of pops up
around town here
you know off and on but the the scooby
that was selected and there's really
kind of a
kind of a heartwarming story that
that from that one so you know that
original the one that i liked so the
reason i liked is that the flower was
more
structure wise was a little more dog
walker dominant
it had all the it had some of the cookie
coloring in it and then it just had this
just
extremely offensive nose and
i passed it off to a co-worker of mine
for safe keeping because i was running
out of room and i just i couldn't
i was exploring other stuff at the same
time so i said you know hey can you hold
this for me
and um the co-worker
passed away in an untimely time
and when that happened a small group of
us went over to his house
before his family arrived to clean up
the garden so that wouldn't be something
they would have to deal with because
maybe they didn't know he had a garden
or something
and so we get over there and
i walk into the room and i see the
scooby plant can't
plant over in the corner and i kind of
looked around there's a couple other
people there and i grabbed a pair of
scissors
and i cut i don't know maybe a dozen
cuttings and wrapped them up with a wet
paper towel and threw them in a ziploc
and then i just just massacred what was
left of that plant
because i didn't want anybody else to
get it and
i took those clones back to my house
and uh called my friend pat who's a
guy who started piers of the farm and i
said hey you know i have these cuts that
i got from
my buddy's house and i need them to go
somewhere safe
and pat says oh yeah you know i'll come
and get him and pat actually took him
back to his house
and kind of forgot about him i think for
almost a week
maybe 10 days and when he finally
remembered they were in the back of his
fridge he's like oh [__] those cuts were
in there and he actually got
i think two of them to root so
you know out of great tragedy came
something phenomenal i think you know
it's uh and those guys out at heroes
were very good to keep that strain
you know interestingly enough i actually
just got it back for the first time
about three three and a half months ago
now
so i haven't run it in all in all these
years since that very first
run and then passing it on to the
co-worker and eventually passing it on
to heroes
wow what a what kind of journey it's
taken
yes it has and uh she wears her badge as
well
so let's take a step back for a moment
i'm gonna play devil's advocate throw
you in the hot seat
i think you think archive knew what he
was doing
you know what i mean
you know i i i have a lot of respect for
those guys
they're phenomenal breeders they're
phenomenal growers they do a lot of good
work
the you know he's a fletcher's a fellow
virginian
so i've got mad respect for that as well
there's another one for you
i i i
it's very interesting to me because so
we had it working pretty heavily through
the dispensary system
here in portland and eugene
oregon in general and
you know i was doing i would always do
searches to make sure it wasn't showing
up
you know in other people's gardens and
stuff like that because that was another
one that we were trying to keep
you know super kind of contained and
i'll never forget the day
that i looked up and leafly had scooby
snacks
whoa what is this and then i go onto the
leafly page
and i'm like oh this isn't right and of
course a lot of the comments that
short were shortly you know thereafter
to follow were like oh we thought this
was this and not that and
you know to me at that point of time
the my biggest concern was you know if
someone went you know had
tried one version and then went and
bought seeds of another version and
didn't get anything that was close
you know how's that person going to feel
as a customer
and so you know i was a little concerned
at that point
and you know there was a point in time
where i was probably a little
you know more hyped up about it than i
am now i mean at this point it's water
under the bridge and
i think uh i i finally actually got to
see some of the archive scooby snacks uh
last year and you know it's a good
strain uh of course they have
i i know they have some you know other
ones that
that that one pales in comparison when
you compare them to somebody who's
really really high-end stuff
but um it's you know i i don't know you
know that the purist in me wants to
think that
or the the purest the lover in me wants
to think that it was just happenstance
the industry side of me says you know
perhaps there was you know a little
advantage taken up there
but i don't know you know we've never
had the conversation
uh we've met briefly a couple times like
i said i have a lot of respect for what
the guy what those guys do there
um but you know what really kind of
settled me on it was when i went to the
emerald cup two years ago
in 2016 and at that point i was
a little more concerned and you know
everyone that i met
there knew
the one eye version so yeah that
kind of made me feel good you know and
it calmed me down a bit and you know
they
so the people to me that you know that
eventually would matter
um they knew which one
so you know it's so it's hard to it's
it's it's hard to
i don't want to guess and like i said i
don't want to
uh you know what i mean like i i want to
i kind of want to play switzerland on
this one because like i said there's a
part of me that believes one thing
there's other side that believes
something else
and at this point i'm going with the the
do right person
yeah i know what you mean the way i see
the situation
i just think if you do boil it down the
genetics do seem really similar
although dog walk is not the same as the
face-off still kind of like og to
cookies it's still kind of similar thing
and the big thing that i noted is oregon
above
other places in my opinion has very much
kind of like
um like you know there's there's cult
followings the j1
the blue magoo and scooby snacks you
know so i i would find it hard to
believe that he wasn't aware of the
strain
given that it is a cult-followed one
oregon has that culture of
locking onto a few strains and really
loving them and so i i just tend to
think that it would be very hard for him
to have not been aware
well and and if you and i'll just say
one little thing one of the names when
you look at the
lineage is serendipitous yeah
okay we'll leave it at that yep so
this you know very loosely touches on
the idea of ownership
what does the ownership of a plant mean
to you when do you get ownership of a
plant when do you have to stop
listening to other people in regards to
what you want to do with the plant
yeah i mean my experience with dog
walker taught me a lot about that
there was a point of time for the first
couple years where
i was obsessed with you know contacting
people who claimed they were
you know they had clones of it and you
know because
at that point it was trying to figure
out how did this leak out how did it get
outside our small group of eight and you
know over time you eventually find out
the cracks in the wall occur but you
know it's
the ownership thing to me it's it's a
tough subject because
as a breeder
you know i i don't necessarily all
you know want to forever profit off my
work but at least want to you know just
be known for for what i've done
and to me you know if you've created
something
and you're using you know for example if
i'm going to be breeding with something
i'm not going to necessarily release it
you know at that time because i want to
work with it and kind of hold it back
but you know look some of these amazing
genetics that are out there
get you know start off in this amazing
realm
and then just kind of get played out for
one reason
or another and i don't know because it's
overpopulated the
you know the cannabis scene or what and
then some of them you know
are still major players and you know the
industry never gets tired of them
so you know on the ownership tip it's uh
you know it depends on i guess what the
you know and i'm very you know
intellectual property is something
to me that's very important moving
forward in this industry especially for
those who are
are creating these genetics um i think
that there
you know i wish there was some way for
someone to protect it uh you know
there's
if you think about something you know
think about all the folks who have
profited off of
you know chem dog and chem dog crosses
but you know the guy who originally
you know cracks the seeds doesn't get
jack squat from it
and there's folks out there that made
millions off of those crosses
so you know if there was a if there was
a
easy foreseeable way for folks to stake
ownership and now that it's become more
commercialized i think that's more
important than it was maybe in the past
uh but what i don't want is for you know
all these breeders to have done
these amazing you know projects with
genetics
and then all to have it swooped up in
the future by
some corporate giant that's figured out
a way to get a utility
patent okay and so what if we simplify
that a little bit because i understand
it's a
it's a little bit of a complex issue in
the way i outlined it what if we make it
a bit more simpler and it's we're
talking about seeds you
purchase so not just like you know in
the case of the dog walk
you know it was a bit of a complex issue
because it was given out under these
specific conditions but what if you just
bought seeds from someone you don't know
you know is that it as far as you're
concerned
he's a free-for-all whatever you want to
do at that point yeah i mean
i actually so when i grab seeds from
different seed from different breeders
you know at events like the emerald cup
i'm i'm i'm up front about and asking
say hey do you mind if i breed with this
to me that is a very important question
for me to ask
and although i've rarely had anyone ask
me about that about any of my genetics
some have come forward and asked and i
think that's kind of doing the do-right
rule
so i i you know i think it is something
that
if there is uh a virtual
like online relationship an existing
personal relationship
with the purveyor of the seed
i you know i i think if you're trying to
to do right in this industry it's a
conversation that you should have
as a breeder you know uh do you mind if
i work with your
work with your you know genetics now i'm
going to create something new i'm not
going to redo what you've done
right but so i i think it's
it's in to me it's important
to have that conversation with a breeder
because you know sometimes people do get
a little chat about
people breeding with their gear and
stuff like that and not
you know kind of staking ownership and
not giving credit to
the breeder of those root genetics so if
we
follow that same thought you know you
reference what you got at the emerald
cup and things like that
if we check your ig we can see nice
little stash from the most recent
emerald cup
what do you plan to pop first
so first is definitely the burmese
landrace from coastal i'm going to be
doing a mail hunt with that
and then i was actually just recently
gifted some magnerosa
which is a brazilian from brazilian sea
company magna rosa
land race i'm going to peel yeah peel
through some of those as well
right now i'm kind of on this i'm
actually not kind of i'm on a mail hunt
right now which i have to do
very very carefully in my small smaller
space
um but the other one that i would really
be
there was uh the
roadkill ganny uh from matt
ryan from riot seeds uh was also one
that i'm very interested in looking into
that that cut that comes out of the
uh they call it the heirloom afghani and
i think that comes out of the project
that maybe he and bodhi did looking for
roadkill skunk through
all these various afghani seeds maybe
the i think it's like a nine-year
project or something like that
and um they finally came up with one
that
truly is they feel it's the roadkill
skunk so uh
getting into that is going to be
interesting and uh
what was the other one i was going to do
oh well just because i have to
they get the granny skunk from dominion
you have to yeah i have to yeah i can't
resist that one at all
and then i've got
uh and then we've got a couple of them i
did a little breeding
this past summer with uh pacquiao mail
the pacquiao is one of the uh
bob hempel crosses out at coastal yeah
you just stole my next question i was
gonna say
we also see you've been growing out the
puck yeah from our friend bob at coastal
how'd you find this line and more
interestingly in my opinion is
you know the puck or the skelly hash
plants quickly becoming one of the most
sought after cuts around
do you like it and do you think it lives
up to the hype in terms of what it
brought as a parent to the cross
okay so funny thing about the puck
so i know the puck from years in the
past and it was definitely very popular
with some of the
folks who were dealing with kim back in
the day the camden dog genetics and some
of the virginia guys too that i knew
uh very big up in new england and
when i at the emerald cup in 2016
uh i walked up to the coastal booth
and i saw that on their list and i it
was
the one of the guys behind the booth i
said oh
what do you guys know about the puck and
he said well let me get the guy who bred
it and come talk to you
i said okay and the guy comes up and
he's like oh he's like hey i hear you
want to
talk about the puck and i was like yeah
you know i breed with some of the chem
genetics you know this was real popular
in the chem family
yeti he's like yeah yeah yeah he's like
what chem genetics did you bring what
did you breed and i said oh well you
know i
read dog walker and the guy looks down
at me and he says
first words that come out of his mouth
were dj rich dj is our mutual friend
and i looked up in him and i said bob
hemphill so you hadn't seen bob in 15
years
yeah wow and so
you know back when i knew him dreads and
beard
you know he's a clean shave and i was
like holy crap so we had this kind of
reintroduction after a 15-year gap
um and it was all over the puck and so
as far as
the the puck you know living up to its
height
um i can certainly say that the kimovar
that i went with
from the pacquiao definitely has that
hash plant structure the way it grows
you know so you can get some really nice
nugs off of it but
it was heavily influenced from that nl1
male
the one i have has this kind of just
straight up just about
acetate nose to it it's almost like
rubber cement
it's really really really intense now by
the look of it
you know it's it's that kind of old hash
plant look it's not super frosty
you know it's not caked and glistening
but man the nose on that thing
is just unmistakable so the
male that i went with actually had
the same growth very similar growth
pattern to the female i selected
and then as much as you can get out of
the stem rub just about spot on with
each other
so that male pollen was used uh
this past summer on some stuff so some
new things coming down the pike from
that
but yeah that the puck the puck is uh is
an amazing plant
uh bob hemphill's puck yeah is
definitely
out of this world at least what the one
that i found and the actual the the
selection that i made when i brought it
to him uh this past year
at the emerald cup uh he was like he's
super stoked he's like i gotta come up
and get that cut
which i thought was kind of funny i
think i actually got to try some of it i
had almost like this watermelon vibe to
it
okay so there was another one that has a
little more watermelon inside there was
two
that i gave him and one has a little bit
and that one actually was not
super stable so i've i've unfortunately
i've scrapped
that one the other one like i said is
just uh
it's almost it's just very interesting
like and i guess you know taking a step
back i guess you could get a little bit
of watermelon out of the
one we kept but uh that being said you
know it's an amazing plant
uh it's super vigorous i can't say
enough good things about it
uh it's definitely uh become
one of my new favorites and i i can't
wait to explore some of these new
crosses that it's providing
so i don't know if you're purposely
trying to not spill the beans but what
crosses did you make
um so we did let's see here
so we did the pacquiao on the
kim four the pacquiao on the biz which
is a doc walker's sister we did pacquiao
on to dog walker we did pakia
on to the wook 3
which is the awok forum cut
those were the puck yeah dustings and
then we actually also worked with
another
male from another cross from bob
hemphill
that was the fairfax four-way crossed
with south fork seeds
sirius which the sirius is basically
just a bunch of chems thrown back and
forth on each other
um so that we had a uh a four-way
mysterious stud that just just was
beautiful in structure and that one
it was uh used to actually
back cross or f2 and then that also went
on to the chem 4 as well
okay and so which one are you personally
most excited for
to be very blunt the biz in the puck
yeah
oh yeah that's yeah that's the one um
you know the business this is dog
walker's sister and
she definitely yields a little more
she tests a little higher and there's
an incr there's once it cures out
there's this amazing amount of limonene
that comes out of that flower
um that's pretty spectacular uh
the gas is there the woodiness is there
although the gas and the woodiness seem
to kind of flip-flop
on the biz you know on the dog walker i
feel like you get this like uh
kind of uh cedar sandalwood on the
inhale with you know loads of gas on the
exhale
and this one you get uh you know this
kind of gassy on the inhale with the
cedar sandalwood finish but then there's
this limonene thing happening in there
that's
and once again it's one of those
strains that the layers from
a flavor evolve you know well after the
exhale
and once again you know something that
i'm always shooting for so
taking that that you know that that
female
and then throwing in this very kind of
accurate astringent note to it
uh i'm hoping the sky's the limit for
that one
awesome so if we just take a jump back
to
kind of some growing style questions
this is something i've been interested
in for a while
what do you think is kind of the
hierarchy or shall we just say the
the order you know the list of what
needs to be mastered in terms of a
grower
i think the fundamental thing you first
have to do as a grower is
you have to learn to read the plan not
not on like the holistic level at like
what a crazy good grower can do
but on the most simple level which is
like when does it need water
i think that's the first thing you learn
to visually tell and then then you go
from there but anyway put put that in
the back your mind for the moment
what's your list you know what do you
think is the kind of the things you look
to master because the underlying
kind of you know how should i say vein
of this question is that
people seem to want to skip the basics
how do you see all of this
sure so i really
believe that the foundation
to all of this begins with with
observation and you bring a very valid
point you know for example something as
simple as
when does the plant need water what does
a yellowing leaf mean
and you know asking these questions and
answering them
either through research or through a q a
with someone who's a little bit more
knowledgeable
but really the you know everything can
kind of be cookie cutter for most
growers you know
a feed schedule can be provided a
lighting schedule you can look up in a
book
you know back back when i started these
resources weren't there so there's so
many more resources today
that people can utilize to
get them into those good growing
practices
uh and it and it does start with the
basics i think a small
you know at least rudimentary
understanding of
you know what are the important
nutrients you know your npk
calcium magnesium you know iron sulfur
manganese
name a few you know and you know and
an understanding at least for
nitrogen potassium phosphorus calcium
magnesium
what those elements really do for the
plant
and why they're important at certain
times and not as important as others
so you know just having a rudimentary
understanding of how
the plant uses nutrients to me is a
really really good foundation and that
does take a little bit of
brief reading to discover it doesn't
have to be super in-depth
to have that kind of general
understanding
you know and after that you know and
really you know so much of this is
and i tell people this all the time it's
just
based you know it's it's facing these
facing challenges and learning how to
overcome them
um you know when someone says that you
know they want to like well they ask me
you know all the time
how do you know all this i get this
question all the time at the shop and i
just you know it's it's 25 plus years of
trying to understand it better
and constantly wanting to learn and to
better my practices
to improve you know my results
uh it's this constant need and desire
to to do better so
you know for that for the general
purpose of you know
where does it all begin well it all
begins with having that just
basic understanding of plants and
nutrients
and so kind of a little extension of
that idea is
on on top of trying to continually get
better at reading the plant things like
that
how important is it to you to constantly
be
popping new genetics is that something
you put value on or do you think it's
fine to just run the same thing again
and again
well you know and i'll go back to what i
was talking i kind of touched on this
earlier i think it's very important
um and i tell a lot of my customers this
to work
you know your genetics with your
nutrients to see how to
best you know to get to that full
genetic expression via the nutrients
that you're using or you're provided
or the method or however your whatever
your approach is
i i think it's important
if you want to if you know it depends
what your goal is if you want to
you know see what a new strain does
you know running at one time isn't a
very good
you know uh litmus test for that you
know
i believe a lot of the scientific method
things need to be done at least three
times
to see you know to make a a
a conscious or you know try
yeah for validation yeah absolutely so
it's it to me you know i encourage
and of course this all goes back to like
skill level too you know someone who's
new i'm not going to recommend
skip around genetics every round
you'll never you'll it'll be such a slow
such a longer
prolonged learning curve with that
approach
i think that you know working with a
specific strain or two
learning that genetic inside and out if
it's interesting to you
that's how you learn now of course if
it's not interesting you're going to
bail on it anyway
but they see way too many folks who
change genetics every round or change
their nutrient
you know regimen every round and not
necessarily
for the sake of bettering but just to
try something new
and i think that's a pretty haphazard
way of going about
you know cultivating cannabis for sure
without a doubt so what do you think is
the biggest kind of mistake you
you see from customers coming to the
store
over watering most common mistake
so many problems start especially over
watering of
starter plants you know or transplanted
plants it's it's the beginning of so
many issues
and uh that's hands down the most common
one
you know i i if the way i tried to
rationalize it with my customers
especially with a younger plant you know
a lot of folks tend to over water
a clone um significantly you know
they'll put a small
root clone into a larger you know vessel
of dirt let's say a one or a
two gallon pot and want to you know keep
hammering
water to keep that pot saturated in the
beginning and the problem with that is
that you know compacted muddy media
is now you know kind of choking off the
oxygen supply making it harder for those
roots to excel
and to grow out and of course you slow
down the root process you slow down the
growth process
so down the growth process you're you
know you're
causing all kinds of you know ripple
effects throughout the life of that
plant
you know i'm a very very big believer in
starting off with
really good healthy plants and if you
start off with a not so healthy
plant then you know you can almost
expect to
face significant challenges throughout
the life cycle of that plan
so one thing we've heard anecdotally
from previous guest
jeremy of builder soil was that he
thinks there's certain plants which are
just pretty good regardless of your
skill level like as in like you know
they tend to come out
pretty good he he noted gg4 is one that
he finds to fall in that category
do you find there's some that fall into
that category and you know i guess these
would be kind of like the more newbie
friendly type stuff
what's your recommendations yeah we the
bulletproof strains
uh there was there's a strain that's
been very popular here in oregon
it's not as popular as it was uh back in
the early 2000s but still around today
called green queen
and green queen was a strain that
and back then you know as we're you know
teaching we actually teaching friends to
grow and stuff like this you could hand
green queen to
anybody and they would see marginal or
decent success from the green queen
even on their first round out and it was
pretty much you know powdery mildew
resistant it could take
an under over feeding didn't really
matter fairly decent yield
i wouldn't say it was absolutely spider
mite resistant because that certainly
wasn't the case but it certainly wasn't
ground zero for infestations
so it you know it that particular plant
was the one you know it was it was a
newbie plant you could give it to
anybody and they could see some success
so yeah i do believe that there are some
of those bulletproof strains
out there um you know i personally
haven't worked with gorilla excuse me
gg4
uh so you know i can't speak to the ease
of that one but i do see
a lot of our novice growers you know
through the store
who grow it um and and they don't seem
to be coming into me with too many
headaches
you know and a lot of um a lot of those
i i feel like kind of blue dream is
another one of those more current
strains that's kind of bulletproof it's
pretty easy
for folks to you know follow a simple
nutrient regimen
you know keep your lights on schedule
keep the humidity where it should be
temperatures where they should be
and that plant is going to turn and burn
for most people but then there are
strains like you know like
some of those ogs and even chem can kind
of be this way but they get a little bit
more finicky and definitely require
a little bit more skill
to finesse that plant into its you know
prime potential definitely i
i feel like the chem's one of those ones
for me where i
i think it's it's lucky that plant
didn't get thrown out in the sense that
you know if certain conditions aren't
right i just feel like it doesn't come
out anywhere near its full potential
like not not obviously having a lot of
experience growing the chem myself but
just through the variants and
i've got a lot of really chem dominant
leading plants and you can see
you know like for example for me at
least being in australia
the heat absolutely just destroys that
plant it doesn't perform well in the
heat and i think to myself
what if that happened with kim and he
just ran it and was like this is just
bunk let's just throw it out
oh lord what a different world this
would be uh yeah and i'm glad that
wasn't the
i'm glad that wasn't the case with with
his experience
and yet no it's uh it you bring up
actually a very valid point
um there was a
a group down in cali that ran
i think it was dog walker and scooby in
two locations
one was inland right on the
east side of the hills the other one was
more in a coastal region
and the plants grown on the east side of
the hills
more inland so in that more kind of dry
drier climate
of norcal didn't do that great
the ones at the coastal location were
some of their highest yielding plants
so yes you know it can make
a a significant difference and you know
is that because
you know of where the dog walker and
scooby come from and they've just kind
of naturally acclimated to that cooler
damper climate
perhaps i don't know you know the
majority of it's cultivated indoors so i
kind of have a hard time believing that
but maybe there's something
to it but that happened uh that that
that test that was done down there uh
run was was
it was hard to ignore the results that's
for sure
so just as a bit of a random oddball
question
what strain has been lost that either
you had or that you knew of that
you'd love to get back if possible my
sugar cookies
i lost that one recently and that was a
good one that was the one that was uh
the that one was the uh forum cut uh the
mail
the the selfing pollen that i collected
onto a cotton candy kush
and it made this the structure was still
very much cookie in the flour but the
flavor
was just there was like blueberry and
like a haze spice in there that was
just freaking off the charts good to me
and made phenomenal uh bubble hash
and that one unfortunately was lost
recently to a
uh to a cloning mix up a labeling issue
but um the other one you know it's
interesting because
bob brought it up because i remember
this one too he brought up the rapture
from yeah and that one was
always this kind of
never did not see it for very long and
only saw it a couple times but
from what i remember of it just
everything about that was just about
picture perfect
you know that one i do remember and
that's it's interesting because i've i
have some folks
back east recently that are like ah you
know if it's there we'll find it you
know
so i put them to task on the raft but i
have a feeling that one's probably been
long gone
i'm sure bob hemphill can speak more to
that than i can
but that one was absolutely very special
and it was
very short-lived in my experience
but that's one i'd love to see again uh
if i could think of any others
you know the real trinity would be nice
to see again yeah okay
you know not the trinity blueberry that
everyone else has but that old real
trinity that was you know almost velvety
and it's you know and it's trichome
production and it's just kind of
that was another one of those kind of
silver gray green plants
that you know once you got once you
once again once you've had it just it's
it leaves a mark on your palette and you
never forget
that's why it's so easy now to pick out
the imposters
you should you should hunt down not so
dog i think he's got the real deal
oh i'll write that down yeah no i tried
it at the cup and it sounds exactly like
what you're describing
all right cool that's cool to hear man
thank you yeah no check that out i'm
gonna try to get him on soon um what's
interesting though when you mention that
rapture thing
i'm actually gonna get hannah bolt to
come on soon i didn't know this
she smoked more rapture than anyone um
yeah like without trying to give away
all the details essentially
the guy who had it with the source she
was much closer to him than what bob was
so she would kind of get first offerings
before bob did and so she ended up
getting access to a lot of it oh wow
that's that's pretty cool because you
know mine
had to trickle down from probably you
know him
to another friend to eventually to me so
you know what i was exposed to like i
said was super limited but
definitely very memorable how fun for
her to have that advantage though
good for her that's awesome yeah no i
can't wait
to get the run down it's it's mythical
so
last couple questions i've got are
actually kind of more legalization based
ones and i think you'd be a good source
of this
in terms of oregon at least do you view
legalization as having had a net
positive
you know i was i was more i've always
been more of a decriminalization than
legalization
uh regulation fan you know with
plus regulation the inevitable will
happen
everywhere it will provide
opportunity for the few it will
eliminate the many factor unfortunately
i think it's
you know i've seen so many folks who are
passionate
you know for many years kind of turn
away from the entire industry recently
um shut down you know stop something
that they've been doing for the last 15
or 20 years some of them um
and i think they just get kind of jaded
by the reality of commercialization
and so you know it's kind of a careful
what you wish for scenario for me
uh you know this is this it doesn't
happen
it didn't happen of course early on in
oregon same thing in colorado it's kind
of like you know even back in montana
when things were going on there for the
legalization
it was kind of the wild wild west for a
while and you know the hustlers
out walls and growers were all kind of
you know
making the moves to make the scene work
but eventually the states have to step
in and institute regulation and
that that ends that whole kind of wild
west
situation and brings it into a very
much more controlled environment and
what you know what you've seen is
you know a couple of states oregon
washington
uh even in colorado have to kind of have
these evolutions to the law
because you know what was what made
sense or what was uh
found in good favor you know six months
ago now the sudden for some reason is
not
so we have to change the law we have to
evolve and
emerging states are having that
opportunity to see some of these other
states make the mistakes along the way
and hopefully put forth you know their
more strict legislation and restricting
legislation
that much more easily because you can
say hey well look here what's here's
here's what happened in these states
didn't work out there so
you know we're gonna we're gonna follow
suit and make
start with these laws are a little bit
more restrictive um
so you know i it's a it's a mixed bag of
emotions for me you know i love the fact
that
i can walk down the street with you know
a few joints in my pocket
or a bag of top walker and i i'm not
going to get arrested for it you know i
can have it in my car i can drive around
with the plant and
plants in my car and nobody's going to
pull me over for it
that to me is you know amazing and
mind-blowing
all at the same time but also you know
there is this whole thing lurking in the
back you know in the shadows of all this
of cour larger corporations
making more of an impact than they have
up into this point and i don't mean you
know the philip morrises and stuff like
that you know i don't i'm not a big
believer in that they want to convert
their customers yet
um but there are large
you know entities afoot and that
to me is you know the to me
you know whenever it's used to destroy
the medical situation
um that's the scary part to me and that
is kind of what happened like in
washington for example
like i hate i would hate it if they took
away the oregonians
residents ability to have a home grow i
think to me that would be
unfortunate and that's something that's
happened to our neighbors to the north
do you view that as the fundamentally
paramount
right we need to protect
i mean i see that as a
state taking creating the opportunity to
make more financial
and more stable financial gain from the
situation
does that make sense you know i mean i i
really do i think that it's
um you know because when you when you
take away home grows you're not just
taking away
you know that person or patient's
ability to cultivate their own medicine
but you're also taking away that
person's ability
to um to go to their local retail store
to go buy the grow equipment and the
nutrients and stuff you know it's it's
it's had this incredible effect up in
washington where it's really disrupted
uh the retails the hydro industry retail
stores there and so
many of them have had to close after
many many years of operation
due to the fact that home grows are no
longer legal there
so you know to me as long as you know
everybody has their right to produce
their own
and not being forced into a retail store
to purchase
cannabis grown by you know whatever
cultivation group
um then i'm okay with it but as soon as
you take this that
that individual right away to produce
and cultivate your own cannabis
um that's a that's dangerous territory
as far as i'm concerned
i guess the reason why i asked that
specifically is because the kind of
medical option that's being rolled out
in australia as much as as fast as i
believe it to be you could kind of boil
it down to be the case that
they don't want you to grow your own but
you've got to accept you know philip
morrison's
offering whatever that may be so to
speak would you
settle with that or would you just be
like no i cannot get down with that
i yeah no i that to me is um
that to me is is not the best path
moving forward for a medical program at
all
i think that it's you know i think
for a lot of folks if they have the you
know if someone had the opportunity to
grow their aspirin what you can with
cannabis right
they probably would you know um i think
that cannabis
because it is such you know
it can be absolutely personalized
medicine in the sense that
people can find specific genetics that
target whatever they want to whatever
they're dealing with
specifically that you know if
the corporate groups that are mass
producing whatever
flower or concentrate they're producing
doesn't have that particular genetic
then that you know individual may not
find
that combination of sedentary
metabolites
that hit all the right spots and i think
that's very restrictive and unfair to a
patient
you know in their you know in the
medical days here
even you know even today we have folks
who are constantly you know those are
the folks that are trying to find that
strain that really target and best
affects
uh you know whatever condition they're
dealing with or
you know gives them the best result so i
think
that's unfortunately very restrictive
and doesn't necessarily
allow for that personalized medicine to
occur i mean yeah you can hit for some
folks but you know
it's to me it's an unfortunate way to
pursue
the medical so oregon specifically has
been criticized in the past with having
what some might regard as you know kind
of some laws that are just
maybe you'd say a bit pedantic i guess
like most notably the whole naming thing
like
you can't call certain strains whatever
because it's deemed too appealing to
kids
girl scout cookies cinderella 99 bubble
gum you can kind of see where they're
coming from but where do you sit on that
so essentially a dispensary just i think
two weeks ago got it
got it we got our first cease and desist
for using scooby snacks
at a dispensary so you know hey look i
get it
i do um i i i think
one of the things you have to have as a
state that's pursuing legal cannabis
is this appearance right that you're
hitting all the things that the federal
government said you shouldn't do
right and making these and avoiding uh
attract you know avoiding marketing to
children is something the federal
government has absolutely spelled out
and so it's a it's a it's a fear
response from the state like
feds say we should do this okay well
let's do this one little thing because
this won't have a huge
negative impact on anyone really
but we've got to kind of play by their
rules to have to make the appearance
that we're doing it right or we're doing
it by whatever you know
protocol they spit out the federal
government hasn't spit out very many
protocols but that was
definitely one of them um so
you know does that make me change the
name of my strain
no absolutely not but does it mean that
the next time you go in the dispensary
it might say s
snacks yeah probably
does that make the flower any worse no
you know
it's that whole name thing you know it's
it's still it's still going to be the
same
you know genetic that i know and love so
yeah you know it's
i i get why the state did it uh
to me it's it's kind of a you know it's
sacrificing a pawn so to speak
okay and so i guess you know kind of
wrap up this whole idea
what do you think was the most
unexpected negative thing
to come out of legalization
this would be pretty unanimous with
everyone the just
the plummeting of the value of cannabis
i don't think anyone we all knew it
would drop some but i don't think
anybody expected
this this big of a tumble in the market
no way
that one was you know that's the one
that's hit everybody i think the hardest
it's unfortunate though a result of the
greed
that ensued as soon as legal cannabis
was a thing here
you know i think that states and
would do well by not allowing
out-of-state investment
as they go online to keeping those
businesses to
state you know resident businesses
uh you know everybody you know i can't
tell you how many and we still see them
and we still see 120 lighters going up
all the time and then
when you look at the glut that we had
back in december you know over a million
pounds in our rec
system what is what good
you know 120 new lights gonna do for our
state i don't know
um so yeah it's it's the the pricing
it's just it's just made it very very
difficult
for extremely talented committed
cultivators to stay in a profitable game
it's really hard right now you have to
be so con
so focused on the bottom line
that you know you start to see people
slipping on things like inputs
and you know moving it's why all of a
sudden salts are so much more attractive
to some of these you know
uh to some of these commercial growers
so this
is because it is it can't it is cheaper
now there's some organic practices that
get close but
when you get down to someone who's
actually mixing their own raw salts
it's it's it's tough to beat that
financially
you know that's a pretty that's about as
low as you can go on input cost
and like i said as the price plummets
that
focus on input cost becomes more and
more significant
so i think there's you know there's a
lot of things that are getting glossed
and passed over
um because of the cost and
like i said it's just that's that's the
one thing that's most unfortunate
absolutely as an individual you know not
in oregon
obviously but in say an illegal
environment what do you think
is your best advice to someone in terms
of what they can do on the individual
level because
and i guess what i mean by that is not
looking for an answer that's like
try to change the law because that's not
really something you can do as an
individual like you can try to be more
politically active sure but
you know what i mean more so looking on
like what what's something everyone can
do in your opinion that
will help collectively
be a responsible grower and and and
and not just responsible in
your growing practices but just how you
conduct yourself
in life you know don't don't be a beacon
of light for attention
for the wrong attention be a beacon of
light for the right attention
and i think that goes to you know
you know using not using products that
will potentially slowly kill your
customers
um you know it's reputation buildings
like building a good reputation for
yourself as
a responsible individual uh you know
even in the uh the illicit market side
of things
will help to paint a better picture
for the collective you know so it starts
on an individual level but what it does
is
you know if that responsibility is
shared and practiced between many
individuals
then when states do start turning and
looking at what's going on
perhaps there's some kind of pillars in
the industry at that point that can
cross over and become leaders in the
industry of the legal industry
i think i've seen that here you know
we've definitely seen that here in
oregon
where you know some very well you know
respected and
good uh honest cultivators
you know came out of the shadows and
stepped into the limelight
and became leaders for the state and i
think that
that's something that the state pays
attention to
um and you know and i think it also is
can be very inspirational to
those who haven't gotten there yet but
you know be
be responsible keep keep your house in
order um
you know and do things the right way um
don't uh don't don't do people
wrong it's uh definitely come back and
bite you
yeah without a doubt really it's not
profound advice i know
but it's you know it's i guess if
there's one thing that i say that i
kind of try to carry around with me all
the time is you know just
try to do things the right way do people
the right way too
yeah i mean maybe not profound but
nevertheless it still needs to be said
so i guess that says something
so final little section a little quick
fire questions so
these ones you can be as shorter as long
as you want so
currently who's the best grower you know
date farmer hell yeah shout out pig
farmer
yes indeed he he definitely
um and i base it purely on his scooby
snack results
uh he he crushes that strain as good or
if not better than anyone that's ever
run it that i know
uh so i'm a big fan of his work
um i definitely am a fan of green bodhi
his work here in oregon he's another
phenomenal cultivator
and a phenomenal breeder at that next
one is
what's your prediction for the hottest
strain of 2018
um whatever comes out with the biz
and that puck yeah i hope um no if
the hottest strange you know this is
this is such a weird question for me
because i don't necessarily pay
attention too much this kind of stuff
but um you know i it looks like uh
via on instagram looks like archives has
some cool things in the works
you know uh me and jean always has
neat stuff coming down the pike uh the
gene finder out at wilcox farms even
though you know he's exploring other
people's genetics so he's doing final
hunting
like no other so i wouldn't i can't
imagine that we wouldn't see something
amazing come out of his
his stable uh so you know there's
and you know even the guys at heroes you
know those guys are constantly breeding
turning out good stuff so i don't know
if i could pick one particular uh
strain or something like that but you
know there's at least a short
list of some breeders and groups to
certainly pay attention to um you know
i'm sure something will come out of the
cookies family or
the terp hogs or whatever third gen or
whatever you know i'm sure
something really big will come out of
those grips but you know the ones that i
mentioned prior are the ones that i'm
really
paying attention and of course whatever
coastal does
yeah well that ties into the next one if
you could only pick one land race which
one would it be
well for me because of
the effect that i really am looking for
in cannabis
uh it'd have to be a land race afghani
and i can't say a particular one but uh
land race afghani for me yeah i'm in the
same boat
i love stevens but nothing beats a good
indica no i'm i'm with you i'm already a
little high strung so
too much sativa can you know make me a
little mm-hmm
okay yeah all righty so next one
what is the worst strain in your opinion
they've got some serious traction behind
it
cynics and i just don't get it
i mean and it has a close tie to here in
portland and some very close friends of
mine
um but it's just one that and
and loads of people love it around here
i just it's one of those ones that i
just
don't get i don't get it it's uh there's
just not much appeal to me personally
but once again we're dealing with
palettes and stuff like that and you
know some people
like you know i don't know escargot and
some people don't
some people like apples and some people
think they taste awful
so so you know it's so i get that part
of it but yeah that's one that's the one
strain for me that i just i've never
understood
okay so opposite end of the spectrum
desert island weed
you can only pick two strains for the
rest of your life what are they
[Music]
well the dog walker's definitely
with me for sure and if i was going to
couple that with something else
the lemon diesel uh
nice so what's what's the lineage on
that one the lemon
d i don't know that's kind of one of
those mystery strains that
um nobody i've never gotten the full
lineage
um in fact there's only a few people who
totally even cultivate it anymore
we called it the lemon d here in oregon
seems like it came out of the eugene
scene
um but just just a phenomenal just
amazing just sour lemon
flavor that just resonates for days on
the palette
i love it indoor or outdoor you can only
have one
endor
i love it there you go
sorry one word answer there but yeah
yeah yeah that's it that's it
man after my own heart so yeah this one
you know probably going to be something
you don't sell but
what's the worst grow product you've
ever seen
the bio wave goddess you know what that
is
that's something that resonates
acoustics
and then it's supposed to get rid of
bugs and increase your yields and
we sold a couple already this week it's
weird um it's been around for
i don't know it's been around for 10
years now 15 years in our industry and
it's just
you know it's just one of those junk
science
lots of uh you know no scientific data
to back it up devices and i'm sure some
people
you know see something who knows what
but you know just
anecdotal evidence at best and kind of
tiled it is it's not one of those things
that look if this thing was so
groundbreaking and it was you know
increasing everybody big ag would have
these things all over the place and
guess where you don't see them big ag
you know if something's really effective
those guys will have it first always
so final question what is the best thing
to happen to cannabis period
since you've been involved in it
medical cannabis medical cannabis for
sure
that was absolutely a huge turning point
i know for myself
um and a huge turning point for a lot of
individuals that i've been involved with
now
for you know a decade plus the
it it gave
it finally a little bit of
validation for the rest of the for the
rest of the country for the world for
that matter
so uh the the explosion of medical
cannabis
is definitely probably in my opinion the
best thing to come out of it
since i've started yeah what a great
answer
so i think that probably does just about
wrap it up did you have any comments or
shout outs you wanted to make
um well i mean obviously i want to shout
out to if i can to my store roots garden
supply in portland oregon
i definitely want to give a shout out to
biobiz
and uh there's a few of you out there
bob hemphill
pad out at heroes pig farmer
uh you know a couple others i've
probably forgotten but
there's a good friends of mine and great
cultivators and great people to know
so surround yourself with good people
people
that's the best advice i can give
awesome so thanks again for coming on uh
thank you so much for having me too it's
been a pleasure and
uh you know i look forward to reading
all your comments here in the near
future
[Music]
big big big big thank you to the scooby
snacks master himself
why not thank you for joining us again
huge shout out to our patreon supporters
as always you guys are the lifeblood of
this show
seeds here now organic gardening
solutions 420 australia
three amigos what can i say
[Music]
la lalalala
you