[SPEAKER_00]: We have a special guest to celebrate our
100th episode.
[SPEAKER_00]: We have Bruce with us here today in the
studio.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thanks Ben for setting this up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm thrilled to be here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well we're glad to have you here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bruce, some of your videos have done very,
very well and received a lot of attention.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, the video with the most views is
the Canvas Light Myths and Facts video.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it has, as of this morning,
just under 3 million views.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're about 50,000 views away from
reaching 3 million views.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever think you'd have a video with
3 million views, Bruce?
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course not.
[SPEAKER_01]: When things happen in the world,
I guess we could say this went viral,
[SPEAKER_01]: but it's little tiny things that just
answer a lot of questions for people.
[SPEAKER_01]: And in this field, of course, they're
besieged by advertisements from lighting
[SPEAKER_01]: companies.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's our magic spectra.
[SPEAKER_01]: In science, we don't have a lot of things
we call magic.
[SPEAKER_00]: Science and magic really are counter
points for sure.
[SPEAKER_01]: So here's the principles, but it's not
like buy this light, it's here's the
[SPEAKER_01]: guiding principles to figure out what kind
of lighting you need.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then you figure it out from the
principles.
[SPEAKER_01]: People ask me lots of strange things.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, I heard that you should always
plant at the full moon.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I don't tell them that's crazy.
[SPEAKER_01]: I tell them, well, we don't have any data
to support that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, and we get sometimes into it that
doesn't the lunar pole do something to
[SPEAKER_01]: water?
[SPEAKER_01]: And yes, but these are super minor things
and there's a lot of dietists like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's thousands of diet books and people
swear by certain diets.
[SPEAKER_01]: Same thing with nutrition implants.
[SPEAKER_01]: They swear by certain ratios of nutrition.
[SPEAKER_01]: Whereas we go by just principles of
nutrition.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it is just consistent with the
principles that we know.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, Bruce, this is our 100th video.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so along the way, is there any moments
that kind of stand out from filming these
[SPEAKER_00]: videos?
[SPEAKER_01]: Certainly one of them is that myths of
cannabis lighting video that went viral.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was my first experience of something
doing something that became popular.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then you realize that it's not just a
number on the screen, but if one percent
[SPEAKER_01]: of those people send me emails,
I get a lot of emails.
[SPEAKER_01]: Could you just elaborate on this?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I can't possibly respond to all of
them.
[SPEAKER_01]: So my graduate students reply.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that led to us teaching a course at
the university.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we're getting ready to teach the third
edition of this now.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's called the Science and Technology of
Medical Cannabis Cultivation.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's been a big hit with people that
really want to dig deep and get into the
[SPEAKER_01]: physiology and genetics of cannabis.
[SPEAKER_00]: A deeper level.
[SPEAKER_00]: How is it, Bruce, that you kind of got
into research and studying and even
[SPEAKER_00]: starting a company and building sensors?
[SPEAKER_00]: How did that all happen?
[SPEAKER_01]: People sometimes have asked how do I get
started in what I do.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I grew up in a very rural area of
Minnesota, Painsville, Minnesota.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I worked on farms as a kid,
but my family ran a resort, a family
[SPEAKER_01]: entrepreneurial thing, and everybody
worked in the resort.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it wasn't agriculture.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it wasn't until I got to college.
[SPEAKER_01]: I started college in engineering because I
was good at math in high school,
[SPEAKER_01]: so you do engineering and mechanical and
electrical.
[SPEAKER_01]: And at that time, the students I was there
with were pretty straight arrow engineers.
[SPEAKER_01]: The stereotype is a white shirt and a
narrow black tie or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: Very sharp pencils.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pocket pull-up pencils and maybe a pocket
protector and all that stuff.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I took a class in plant biology,
and the subject matter fascinated me,
[SPEAKER_01]: but I think I was also drawn by the kind
of students that were in that class.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were interested in ecology and lots
of different things.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I changed my major at some point and
started to just do more plant biology.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I went to graduate school in
plant biology horticulture.
[SPEAKER_01]: And more specifically, I always wanted to
go to California.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was just mystique of there's no
absolute truths in California.
[SPEAKER_01]: We reevaluate everything every day.
[SPEAKER_01]: That to me as a teenager was really
interesting.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I got into UC Davis to graduate school,
and then I really dug into physiology and
[SPEAKER_01]: things.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I was always interested in controlled
environments.
[SPEAKER_01]: And for me, it was a synthesis of the
engineering.
[SPEAKER_01]: How do you build a box to control the
environment to make plants grow faster?
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's so intriguing with the control
systems.
[SPEAKER_01]: And back then, it wasn't a thing to grow
food indoors.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was just a research tool.
[SPEAKER_01]: We build these and we'll understand how to
modify the environment, how do plants
[SPEAKER_01]: respond to the environment.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was all about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, oh gosh, I wrote a paper in a class
on this specialized greenhouse.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was called the Morning Glory
Greenhouse.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it had big reflective panels that
closed at night and opened in the day.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it was all the energy, and it produced
a lot of heat because it reflected in.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you could heat all these buildings
with the heat.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then at night, they closed.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that paper, which was for a class,
got picked up by a journal called
[SPEAKER_01]: Alternative Sources of Energy.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they said, we'd like to publish this
paper.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it was before computers, and it had
all these calculations and hand-drawn
[SPEAKER_01]: pictures.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that got published.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was my first publication.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then that led to me getting an offer for
an assistantship, a research assistantship
[SPEAKER_01]: at Penn State University.
[SPEAKER_01]: So off I go between California and
Pennsylvania to get a PhD.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it was focused on controlled
environment agriculture.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that led to me getting a position at
Utah State University coming here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now I have more money to do more things.
[SPEAKER_01]: We got a big grant funded by NASA early in
my career, and that launched a lot of
[SPEAKER_01]: things.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, wow, we're doing this stuff for NASA.
[SPEAKER_01]: Along the way, measuring light was huge
because of all the environmental
[SPEAKER_01]: parameters.
[SPEAKER_01]: We can measure temperature, humidity,
CO2 better than the plants can sense them.
[SPEAKER_01]: But light, the plants sense that better
than our best instruments.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, wow, there was a really great
opportunity to do precision light
[SPEAKER_01]: measurement.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the sensors were expensive.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I thought, well, I'm going to fiddle
around with this.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I built, not even in my garage at my
kitchen table, built some light meters
[SPEAKER_01]: with photodiodes and modified voltmeters.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I just built them for my lab.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you have a background understanding of
electronics?
[SPEAKER_01]: I had enough of an engineering background.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I knew the basics of, I knew Ohm's
law.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what you mean?
[SPEAKER_01]: Vehicles IR.
[SPEAKER_01]: And how do I do resistors?
[SPEAKER_01]: So people came to visit the lab,
and we had these sensors.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they go, well, they were friends,
and could you build me one?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I built them one.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I start to get phone calls from
people saying, I just saw this sensor,
[SPEAKER_01]: this meter in somebody's lab, and it's
terrific.
[SPEAKER_01]: Could you build me one?
[SPEAKER_01]: And you don't know me, but I'll pay for
it.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went to the university, and I said,
well, there's a market here for these
[SPEAKER_01]: meters.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'd like to build them the meters at
home and sell them, and I'd like to set up
[SPEAKER_01]: a separate account to keep track of the
money.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the university said, no, you can't do
that.
[SPEAKER_01]: We don't want the liability issues,
and we don't want the criticism that we're
[SPEAKER_01]: competing unfairly.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, okay.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the solution is we'll have to start a
company, and we'll give you space in our
[SPEAKER_01]: research park.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, there you go.
[SPEAKER_01]: And cool.
[SPEAKER_01]: But guess what that meant?
[SPEAKER_01]: We'll take half the money.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I say, now I'm going to keep making
them at my kitchen table.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't need you.
[SPEAKER_00]: It looks pretty good at that point.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there we go.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then it grew, and I had to build a new
garage much bigger.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we were in my garage for eight or ten
years.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we weren't trying to grow fast,
and then we just got too big.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then we built this much nicer
building, and it's gone from there.
[SPEAKER_01]: So there was no bank loan.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was no investors.
[SPEAKER_01]: I put thousands of dollars of my own money
into it.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't have a bank loan to pay back.
[SPEAKER_01]: And because of that, the whole company and
all the early employees started just with
[SPEAKER_01]: a passion to build good meters.
[SPEAKER_00]: People really like your cannabis videos.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did you get involved with cannabis?
[SPEAKER_01]: Because we had a reputation for doing
precise work in highly controlled
[SPEAKER_01]: environments, cannabis growers came to us
and said, in North America and the United
[SPEAKER_01]: States, we need help growing a better
quality crop.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've got all the infrastructure to do
this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Could we give you funding to do cannabis?
[SPEAKER_01]: And until 2018, the university,
my lab at the university said,
[SPEAKER_01]: no, we can't take their money.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's illegal.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's federally illegal.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we'll get in big trouble.
[SPEAKER_01]: So in December 2017, I think that was the
exact month and year the farm bill passed,
[SPEAKER_01]: and it made low THC cannabis legal,
federally legal.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now that's commonly called hemp,
but we just call it low THC cannabis.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can't get high from it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And at that moment, the university said,
okay, now we'll take the money to work on
[SPEAKER_01]: low THC cannabis.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we got a license both from the state
of Utah and from the USDA to do this and
[SPEAKER_01]: much more security, things like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Off we go with funding from growers,
because at the time there's no federal
[SPEAKER_01]: funding.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's no state funding.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a normal place.
[SPEAKER_01]: People like me get money.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's public agencies.
[SPEAKER_01]: These are private companies.
[SPEAKER_01]: Started doing a lot of research,
applying all the things we know to
[SPEAKER_01]: cannabis.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, well, some of my colleagues said,
oh, my, this is a brand new crop.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're starting from zero.
[SPEAKER_01]: We said, no, this is the crop like any
other.
[SPEAKER_01]: It has the same biochemistry.
[SPEAKER_01]: It has the same photoperiod requirements.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's look at the things that are unique.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that helps us focus the research on
things that we didn't know that were
[SPEAKER_01]: different.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, of course, that led to some pretty
rapid progress in publications.
[SPEAKER_01]: And pretty soon you're getting invited to
conferences to speak on this, because you
[SPEAKER_01]: went from nothing to the expert,
because the bar was so low.
[SPEAKER_01]: There wasn't anybody else working on this
at universities.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that was a big jump start for the
cannabis research.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we have continued to do the NASA
research all along, but the NASA research
[SPEAKER_01]: is purely food crops, and the cannabis
research is just cannabis.
[SPEAKER_00]: So through your research, did you ever
have something that popped up?
[SPEAKER_00]: And you're like, oh, this is interesting.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, I think the public thinks science
progresses when people say, eureka,
[SPEAKER_01]: I found it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's not true.
[SPEAKER_01]: The phrase that I think is the most common
is looking at data and go, hmm,
[SPEAKER_01]: that's funny.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why did this happen like this?
[SPEAKER_01]: And then the ability to say, this is not
just experimental error.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's something here that's real.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you have any of those moments?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, they happen all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: All the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And one of my favorite quotes is from
Louis Pasteur.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, chance favors the prepared mind.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so if you know what you're looking
for, you look at patterns of data and
[SPEAKER_01]: separate experimental error from novel
responses.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Bruce, right now, as a researcher and
the owner of Apogee, what kind of
[SPEAKER_00]: questions do you have at night?
[SPEAKER_01]: What kind of things keep you up?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, many.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they're often driven by growers that
they call with things that can't be
[SPEAKER_01]: explained.
[SPEAKER_01]: And some of them you can explain,
many you can, but their responses you
[SPEAKER_01]: can't explain.
[SPEAKER_01]: So it isn't always your own data,
it's somebody else's data that we're
[SPEAKER_01]: seeing this.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so those lead us to do tests on those
things, which of course helps those
[SPEAKER_01]: growers enormously.
[SPEAKER_01]: There are lots of complex interactions.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's a really good example.
[SPEAKER_01]: We knew from reading the literature from
60 to 70 years ago that there was evidence
[SPEAKER_01]: that cannabis was exceptionally sensitive
to light pollution.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some people can sleep with the lights on,
some people can't.
[SPEAKER_01]: They have to have it all dark,
so it's intuitive.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, some plants they can have the lights
on, it doesn't matter, and some plants got
[SPEAKER_01]: to have it dark.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so it suggested cannabis was
exquisitely sensitive to light pollution.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we start doing some tests and,
wow, we confirm this old research,
[SPEAKER_01]: which hasn't been done for a while,
it's really sensitive.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, how are you going to measure this
with those instruments?
[SPEAKER_01]: So that led to apogee building,
this light pollution detector.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, so that's where that came from.
[SPEAKER_01]: And everybody measures light in what we
call micromoles.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's 10 to the minus 6 moles.
[SPEAKER_01]: All of a sudden, we build a meter to
measure nanomoles, 10 to the minus 9,
[SPEAKER_01]: a thousand times more sensitive,
to measure these and quantify them.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's been a huge help to growers who
need what we call reagent-grade darkness
[SPEAKER_01]: at night.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's an interesting term that we coined.
[SPEAKER_01]: Poinsettia is a real sensitive crop to
light pollution, too, to make the bracts
[SPEAKER_01]: turn red.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a real common crop.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we always said they are our most
sensitive crop, but now we've shown
[SPEAKER_01]: cannabis even more sensitive.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, thank you for watching.
[SPEAKER_00]: Thank you, Bruce, for taking the time and
filming with me for a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you want to learn more about Bruce and
his research, click on this playlist,
[SPEAKER_00]: and it'll show you more of the things that
he's taught us, and you can learn a lot
[SPEAKER_00]: from him as well.
[SPEAKER_00]: So thank you very much for coming,
Bruce.
[SPEAKER_00]: Thank you, Ben.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'll see you later.
[SPEAKER_01]: Great.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thank you.