We have a special guest to  celebrate our 100th episode.
We have Bruce with us here today in the studio.
Thanks Ben for setting this up.  I'm thrilled to be here.
Well we're glad to have you here.
Bruce some of your videos have done very very  well and received a lot of attention.
In fact, the video with the most views is the  "Cannabis Light Myths and Facts" video.
It has, as of this morning, just under 3 million views.
We're about 50,000 views away  from from reaching 3 million views.
Did you ever think you'd have  a a video with 3 million views?
Of course not, when things happen in the world,  that I guess we could say this went viral.
It's little tiny things that just just answered  a lot of questions for people.
And in this field, of course,  they're besieged  by advertisements from lighting companies.
Here's our magic spectra
and you know in science we don't have a  lot of things we call magic
Ben - Science and magic really are kind of, you know, counter points for sure.
So here's the principles. But, it's not like  "buy this light" it's here's the guiding principles
to figure out what kind  of lighting you need.
And then you figured out from the principles.
People ask me that lots of strange things.
I mean, I heard that you should always plant at the full moon,
and I don't tell them that's crazy. I tell them well  we don't have any data to support that.
Oh would we get sometimes into it that doesn't  the lunar pull do something to water
and yes but these are super minor things.
There's a lot of diet. Diet is like that.
There's thousands of diet books and  people swear by certain diets.
Same thing with nutrition in plants.
They swear by certain ratios of nutrition.
Whereas we go by just principles of nutrition.
And Is this consistent with the principles that we know.
So Bruce this is our 100th video
and so along the way is there any moments  that kind of stand out
from from filming these videos?
Certainly, one of them is that "Myths of Cannabis Lighting" video that that went viral.
That was my first experience of something  doing something that became popular.
and then you realize that it's not just the number on the screen.
But if 1% of those people send me emails I get a lot of emails.
"Could you just elaborate on this" and on you know. I can't possibly respond to all of them.
So I my graduate students reply and that led  to us teaching a course at the University.
It's called the and we're teaching we're getting ready  to teach the third edition of this now.
It's called the "Science and Technology of Medical Cannabis Cultivation"
and that's been a big hit with people that really want to dig deep
and get get into the physiology and genetics of cannabis.
Ben - From a much deeper level
A deeper level.
How is it Bruce that you kind of got into to research and and studying
and even starting a company and building sensors?
How did that all happen?
People sometimes have asked when you know how I get started in what I do.
and I grew up in a very rural area of Minnesota Paynesville Minnesota.
I worked on farms as a kid but my family ran a resort.
A family entrepreneurial thing,
and everybody worked in the resort but it wasn't agriculture.
It wasn't until I got to college.
I started College engineering cuz I was good at math in high  school so you do engineering and mechanical and electrical .
And at that time I the the students I was there  with were pretty straight arrow Engineers.
I mean, I don't know, you know,  The stereotype is a white  shirt and a narrow black tie or something.
Ben - Very sharp pencils
Yeah pocket full of pencils and maybe a pocket protector  and all that stuff .
I took a class in plant biology
the subject matter fascinated me
but I think I was also drawn by the  kind of students that were in that class.
They were interested in ecology and lots of different things.
And I changed my major at some point
and started to just do more plant biology,
Then I went to graduate school in plant biology horticulture.
and more specifically I moved. I always wanted to go to California.
There was just Mystique of there's no absolute truths in California.
We reevaluate everything every day. You know.
And that to me as a teenager was really interesting.
So I got into UC Davis to graduate school,
and then I really dug into physiology and things.
But I was always interested in controlled environments
and it was for me, it was a synthesis of the engineering.
How do you build a box to control the environment to  make plants grow faster?
And that's so intriguing with this control systems.
And back then, it wasn't a thing to grow food indoors.
It was just a research tool.
We build these and we'll understand how to modify the environment.
How do plants respond to the environment.
It was all about that.
And, Oh gosh, I wrote a paper in a class on this specialized Greenhouse.
It was called The Morning Glory Greenhouse.  It had big reflective panels that closed at night
and opened in the day.
It was all the energy, and It produced a lot of heat cuz it reflected in
and you could heat all these buildings with the heat.
Then at night they closed. That paper which was for a class,
got picked up by a journal called "Alternative Sources of Energy"
and they said we'd like to publish this paper.
and it was before computers and I it had  all these calculations and hand drawn pictures.
That got published. That was my first publication.
Then that led to me getting an offer for an assistantship  or a research assistantship at Penn State University.
So off I go between California and Pennsylvania to get a PhD.
It was focused on controlled environment agriculture.
That led to me getting a position at Utah State University.
Coming here.
Now I have more money to do more things.
We got a big grant funded by NASA early in my career.
That launched a lot of things.
Now "Wow we're doing this stuff for NASA."
along the way measuring light was huge.
Because of all the environmental parameters we can measure temperature,  humidity, and CO2 better than the plants can sense them.
But light, the plant sense that better than our best instruments.
So "Wow" there was a really great opportunity to do precision light measurement,
And the sensors were expensive.
And I thought well I'm going to fiddle around with this and so...
I built, not even in my garage, at my kitchen table
built some light meters with photo diodes and modified volt meters.
And I just built them for my lab.
Ben - Did you have a background or understanding of electronics?
I did. I had enough of a engineering background yeah
I knew the basics.
I knew Ohm's law that's
Vehicles IR
and you know,  how do I do resistors.
So people came to visit the lab and we had these sensors.
And they go, "well could I?" they were friends "Could you build  me one?"
"Sure" so I build them one.
Then I start to get phone calls from people say I just  saw this sensor, this meter, in somebody's lab.
It's terrific. Could you build me one. You don't know me but I'll pay for it.
So I went to the University and I said well there's a market here  for these meters.
I'd like to build the meters at home and sell them.  I'd like to set up a separate account to keep track of the money.
And the university said "No, you can't do that
we don't want the liability issues
and we don't want the criticism that we're competing unfairly"
but the solution is we'll help you start a company
and and we'll give you space in our Research Park.
Cool, but guess what that meant,
we'll take half the money.
I say "Na I'm going to keep making them at my kitchen table."
I don't need you.
Ben - It works pretty good at  that point.
And there we go. Then it grew and had to build a new garage, much bigger.
We were in my garage for eight or ten years.
and we weren't trying to grow fast.
Then we just got too big.
Then we built this much nicer building.
And it's gone from there.
There was no bank loan there was no investors.
You know I put a thousands of dollars of my own money into it.
We didn't have a bank loan to pay back.
And because of that the whole company and all the early employees  started just with the passion to build good meters.
People really like your cannabis videos. How did you get involved with cannabis?
Because we had a reputation for doing precise work in highly controlled environments,
cannabis growers came to us and said, in North America and the United States,
we need help growing a better quality crop.
You've got all the infrastructure to do this.
Could we give you funding to do cannabis,
and until 2018 the university my lab at the University said
"No we can't take their money it's illegal.
It's a federally illegal and we'll get in big trouble"
So in December 2017, I think that was the  exact month and year that it the farm Bell passed,
It made low THC cannabis legal federally legal.
Now it's commonly called hemp, but we just call it low THC cannabis.
You can't get high from it.
At that moment, the University said "Okay, now  it's we we'll take their money to work on low THC cannabis."
We got a license both from the state of Utah and from the USDA to do this.
and much more security and things like that.
Off we go.  With funding from growers because at the time there's no federal funding.
There's no state funding. That's the normal place  people like me get money it's public agencies.
These are private companies.
I started doing lot of research applying all the things we know to cannabis.
And well some of my colleagues said "Oh my, this is a brand new crop.  We're starting from zero."
We said, "No, this is the crop like any other."
It has the same biochemistry, it has the  same photo periodic requirements,
let's look at the things that are unique.
That helps us focus the research on things that we didn't know, that were different.
And, of course, that led to some pretty rapid progress in publications and pretty soon,
you're getting invited to conferences,
to speak on this. Because you went from nothing to the expert,
because the bar was so low.
there isn't anybody else working on this at universities.
So that was the a big jump start for the Cannabis research.
And we have continued to do the NASA research all along,
but the NASA research is purely food crops
and the cannabis research is just cannabis.
So through your research did you ever have some  something that popped up you're like "Oh, this is interesting."
Yes. I think the public think science progresses when people say "Eureka! I found it!"
and that's not true.
The phrase that I think is the most common is looking at data  and go "Huh? that's funny."
and "Why did this happen like this?"
Then the ability to say this this is not just experimental error there's something here.
That's real.
Did you have any of those moments?
Oh, they happen all the time all the time.
One of my favorite quotes is from Louis Pasteur
he says, "Chance favors the prepared mind."
So if you know what you're looking for, you could look at patterns of data and separate experimental error from novel responses.
So Bruce right now as a researcher and the owner of of Apogee,
what kind of questions do you have at night? What kind of things keep you up?
Yeah many and they're often driven by growers.
They call with things that can't be explained,
and some of them you can explain, many you can.
But their responses you can't explain so it isn't always your  own data it's somebody else's data that we're seeing this.
And so the those are lead us to do tests on those things.
which of course helps those growers enormously. There lots of complex interactions.
Here's a really good example.
We knew from reading the literature from 70, 60 to 70 years ago,
that there was evidence that cannabis was exceptionally sensitive to light pollution.
You know, like some people can sleep  with the lights on, some people can't,
they have to have it all dark that's so it's intuitive.
Well, some plants that can have lights on it doesn't  matter and some plants got to have it dark .
and so it suggested cannabis was exquisitely sensitive to light pollution.
So we start doing some tests and "Wow" we confirm this old research,
which haven't been done for a while. It's really sensitive.
Well how you going to measure this without an instruments so that led to Apogee building this light pollution detector.
Ben - Oh so that's where that came from. Bruce - And everybody measures light in what we call micromoles
It's 10 the the minus 6 moles.  All of a sudden we build a meter to measure nanomoles.
10 to the minus 9. A thousand times more sensitive to  measure these and quantify them.
That's been a huge help to growers who need what we call
reagent grade darkness at night.
You know that's an interesting term that we coined.
Poinsettia is a real sensitive crop to light pollution too.
To make the bracts turn red. It's a real common crop.
We always said they are our most sensitive crop.
But now we've shown cannabis even more sensitive.
Well thank you for watching. Thank you Bruce for  taking the time and filming with me for a little bit.
If you want to learn more about Bruce and his research click on this playlist
and it'll show you more of the things that he's  taught us and you can you can learn a lot from him as well.
So thank you very much for coming Bruce and we'll see you later.
Great. Thank you.