[SPEAKER_00]: I'm Bruce Bugbee, president of Apogee
Instruments, and I'm here today to record
[SPEAKER_00]: the talk, the keynote talk that I gave a
few weeks ago at the Light Sim Symposia in
[SPEAKER_00]: Seoul, Korea.
[SPEAKER_00]: This was the very opening talk of the
conference, and it was a great honor to be
[SPEAKER_00]: asked to do this.
[SPEAKER_00]: What I chose to talk about is not the
details of our photobiology research that
[SPEAKER_00]: my students have done, especially over the
last 10 years, but as the opening talk to
[SPEAKER_00]: the symposia of research scientists,
I wanted to talk about more about the
[SPEAKER_00]: process of science and how we use our
instruments and tools to create new
[SPEAKER_00]: knowledge.
[SPEAKER_00]: So these next few slides are what I showed
there.
[SPEAKER_00]: My opening slide was this.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is a picture drawn by an artist here
in Utah, James Christiansen, of a home
[SPEAKER_00]: tinkerer taking his new spaceship out for
a drive in the space.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I've just loved this picture.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's framed in my laboratory, but he's got
all these gizmos that he rigged up.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is far from high tech.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I think the title of this was low
tech, but this is what we all do in our
[SPEAKER_00]: research laboratories, tinker with things.
[SPEAKER_00]: Build gizmos, test hypotheses.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're much different than a commercial
enterprise that might all be built out of
[SPEAKER_00]: stainless steel and something fancy.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's the name of the symposium,
LightSim 2024.
[SPEAKER_00]: This drew several hundred research
scientists really from all over the world.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it was truly a great honor for me to
give the opening talk of this.
[SPEAKER_00]: And as part of that, it's light and
photosynthesis and photons.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I want to start with a review of where
we have come with creating light for
[SPEAKER_00]: ourselves over the past 150 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: This comes from a paper in the journal
Nature, which I published with some
[SPEAKER_00]: colleagues, LEDs for photons, physiology
and food.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in this review paper, we talked about
the history of light.
[SPEAKER_00]: We started with kerosene lamps.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was the energy in the kerosene and
how much light did we out?
[SPEAKER_00]: Now this is light measured in lumens per
watt of power going into this.
[SPEAKER_00]: Point four, now you can see the tremendous
breakthrough when we got incandescent
[SPEAKER_00]: bulbs went from point four to 15.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was an incredible advance.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in fact, that was a 40 fold increase
of turning energy into light.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now this is all for people, but plant
research, as I'll show in a minute,
[SPEAKER_00]: has followed this.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then in about, just after World War II,
in about 1950, we got fluorescent lights.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was another big advance from 15
to 80, but that was a five fold increase.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it was huge advance for everybody to
more light, less heat.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then in the 1970s, we got high intensity
discharge lighting.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a high pressure sodium bulb,
80 to 120, another huge advance.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now we're only talking 1.5 X, but each of
these allowed us to do more plant research
[SPEAKER_00]: with mostly with higher intensities of
light.
[SPEAKER_00]: We weren't doing so much back here with
ratios of colors as just getting the
[SPEAKER_00]: intensity up, but we still used a lot of
colored filters to create different ratios
[SPEAKER_00]: of colors.
[SPEAKER_00]: And some of my early papers right in here
were using HID and metal halide lamps with
[SPEAKER_00]: filters to get different colors of light.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then kaboom, we got LEDs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Roughly depend on when you say we started
10 or 20 years ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: And now, another huge breakthrough in
terms of ratios of heat and light.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is for human lighting, lumens per
watt.
[SPEAKER_00]: But if we do this in micromoles of photons
per joule of energy, and this is the ratio
[SPEAKER_00]: for energy and photons out, here's the
comparative numbers, and look at this,
[SPEAKER_00]: 0.005 to four.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is almost a 1,000-fold increase in
light.
[SPEAKER_00]: And even here, even if we start with
incandescents, a tremendous breakthrough.
[SPEAKER_00]: So now we get all the colors, we get very
efficient lights so we can have high
[SPEAKER_00]: intensity.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is why we're all assembled here for
LightSim to talk about our exciting work
[SPEAKER_00]: that we can now do with LEDs.
[SPEAKER_00]: This ratio, let me go back one,
this is really light to heat.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lumens is light, watts is heat.
[SPEAKER_00]: Micromoles of photons is photon flux
density, and joules is energy.
[SPEAKER_00]: So this is the ratio of these two.
[SPEAKER_00]: So what is sunlight?
[SPEAKER_00]: It turns out sunlight has two micromoles
of photosynthetic photons per joule of
[SPEAKER_00]: thermal energy.
[SPEAKER_00]: We don't think about that ratio much,
but I'll show you, it's not difficult to
[SPEAKER_00]: calculate for sunlight.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now we have LEDs that are three and they
even exceed three micromoles per joule.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just on this basis, it's staggering,
because look, we've caught up and passed
[SPEAKER_00]: sunlight with our human technology.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's just an incredible that we've done
that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And some people have said, yes,
so now we don't need sunlight anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: Electric lights are even better than
sunlight.
[SPEAKER_00]: But look at this, this joule of energy
right here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let me get that back right here and get my
pen turned on.
[SPEAKER_00]: This joule of energy right here is
electricity.
[SPEAKER_00]: We have to pay for that joule of energy.
[SPEAKER_00]: This joule is free from the sunlight.
[SPEAKER_00]: It comes with the sun.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we get two micromoles for free and we
pay for these three.
[SPEAKER_00]: So sunlight is still a tremendous source
of light because it's free compared to
[SPEAKER_00]: electric lights, but it's still three to
two.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where do we get two?
[SPEAKER_00]: This is a spectra of wavelength of
sunlight and intensity here.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a classic.
[SPEAKER_00]: Apogee has refrigerator magnets with this
spectra on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: This part right here we say visible is
really photosynthetic photon flux.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this red part out here is thermal,
doesn't drive photosynthesis, drives
[SPEAKER_00]: evaporation of water, it drives
transpiration, but it doesn't drive
[SPEAKER_00]: photosynthesis.
[SPEAKER_00]: So if you look at this, this is two and
three based on this ratio of this.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, if we include far-red photons in
this, that's this zone right here.
[SPEAKER_00]: 400 to 700 nanometers.
[SPEAKER_00]: This shifts this over slightly.
[SPEAKER_00]: So now a greater fraction of sunlight is
photosynthetic radiation.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'll come back to this in this talk a
bit, but as most of you know, this is a
[SPEAKER_00]: huge part of the research of my students
and I, of the value of these far-red
[SPEAKER_00]: photons.
[SPEAKER_00]: If we include this, this number gets
slightly bigger.
[SPEAKER_00]: 2.3 micromoles per joule for sunlight.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we're still not trying to catch up to
electric lights.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're still trying to get favorable ratios
of heat, of light to heat.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if we do that well, we can air
condition greenhouses.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now that seems cost prohibitive now,
but let me show you the innovations in
[SPEAKER_00]: glass that allows us to do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is, once again, here is our,
let me get this in black right here.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is our PPFD.
[SPEAKER_00]: Same as visible light right here,
draw a line right there.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is the good part.
[SPEAKER_00]: We want a lot of this.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is standard glass that we've had for
a hundred years.
[SPEAKER_00]: If we put a coating on this, it slightly
decreases visible, but it dramatically
[SPEAKER_00]: decreases the heat.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if we put more coating, even more and
even more, so all of a sudden we have
[SPEAKER_00]: almost pure light and very little thermal,
unusable thermal out here.
[SPEAKER_00]: When you use a low solar gain glass,
we can air condition greenhouses.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's important to quantify this.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why Apogee cell is a flotilla of
sensors to rigorously quantify these
[SPEAKER_00]: ratios.
[SPEAKER_00]: But this is a cutting edge of photobiology
and food production in highly controlled
[SPEAKER_00]: environments is to use the right kinds of
solar glazing.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we can close a greenhouse, not only
reduce the air conditioning costs,
[SPEAKER_00]: but allow us to seal it and elevate CO2,
take advantage of high CO2.
[SPEAKER_00]: That comes from innovations in glazing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now let's go back to the history of
photobiology to the 1950s.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is when we were working with
fluorescent tubes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And at Caltech University in California,
Fritz Wendt did his pioneering work.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's a famous, famous scientist
credited with the discovery of oxen.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's his work from a plant physiology
textbook on oxen of the hormone oxen.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he wrote this book, The Experimental
Control of Plant Growth.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a wonderful book about all these
discoveries of photoperiod and temperature
[SPEAKER_00]: interactions.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this is in this famous Caltech
Phytotron where they could wheel carts
[SPEAKER_00]: from different temperatures of rooms and
different lights of rooms, all done with
[SPEAKER_00]: fluorescent lights.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some of his famous quotes are he urged
everybody to work in controlled
[SPEAKER_00]: environments, do more basic research,
understand things at a very fundamental
[SPEAKER_00]: level.
[SPEAKER_00]: And now we have way better tools than he
ever had to do this.
[SPEAKER_00]: He advocated for very simple experiments.
[SPEAKER_00]: Complex experiments.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was very suspicious of studies that
needed a lot of statistics, where he had a
[SPEAKER_00]: lot of treatments and a lot of statistics.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wanted fundamental data with more clear
results.
[SPEAKER_00]: That continues to be very wise advice for
all of us 50 years later to do simple
[SPEAKER_00]: experiments with clear results,
where we associate mechanisms with
[SPEAKER_00]: experimental results.
[SPEAKER_00]: I want to build on this concept now in my
next few slides.
[SPEAKER_00]: Another famous scientist, Ernest
Rutherford, Nobel Prize in Chemistry,
[SPEAKER_00]: 1908.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's Ernest Rutherford with his
primitive tools of the time working out
[SPEAKER_00]: breakthroughs in chemistry.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did he have to say about statistics?
[SPEAKER_00]: Huh, if your experiment needs statistics,
you ought to have done a better
[SPEAKER_00]: experiment.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's still wise advice.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do simple experiments with clear results,
not complex experiments that need a ton of
[SPEAKER_00]: statistics to interpret them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not that statistics is a bad thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: We all use it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's critical, but we shouldn't rely on
the crutch of statistics to design our
[SPEAKER_00]: experiments.
[SPEAKER_00]: They should be clear fundamental tests of
hypotheses.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sometimes we design experiments that are
more like a fishing trip than real
[SPEAKER_00]: research.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're just going to do a lot of stuff and
see what happens.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good luck getting your proposals funded if
the reviewers think they might be a
[SPEAKER_00]: fishing trip.
[SPEAKER_00]: Serendipity plays a huge role in science.
[SPEAKER_00]: We still go for what we're looking for,
but people, the public thinks the most
[SPEAKER_00]: exciting phrase in all of science is,
ah, Eureka, I just discovered it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's not how it works.
[SPEAKER_00]: The most exciting phrase is, that's funny.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's an outlier here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who said that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Isaac Asimov, famous science fiction
writer, and that's highlighted in this
[SPEAKER_00]: book, Serendipitous Discoveries in Plant
Science.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can never plan for serendipity.
[SPEAKER_00]: You have to be doing good science,
but you have to have a trained mind to
[SPEAKER_00]: understand when there's good data and when
there's bad data.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we all need to train our minds to be
looking for these unusual data when they
[SPEAKER_00]: arise.
[SPEAKER_00]: Another famous scientist, Louis Pasteur,
[SPEAKER_00]: 1800s, chance favors the prepared mind.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is one of his most famous quotes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I have just loved this my whole career,
studying in graduate school to get my
[SPEAKER_00]: prepared mind for that chance moment.
[SPEAKER_00]: What that really means is when you have
data like this, and now you say,
[SPEAKER_00]: eh, here's my curve for the response.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's get this in yellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's my curve for the response.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't like that data point.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's an outlier.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm just going to take it out.
[SPEAKER_00]: How do you know that's an outlier?
[SPEAKER_00]: Just because you can draw a nice smooth
curve for the rest of the data,
[SPEAKER_00]: we should be looking at outliers and
understanding what caused them.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why this quote is so famous.
[SPEAKER_00]: And by the way, when you read his original
stuff, one, two, three, four, five words,
[SPEAKER_00]: how elegant is that?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's not what he originally said.
[SPEAKER_00]: It says, in the fields of observation,
chance favors only the prepared mind.
[SPEAKER_00]: So subsequent editors said, we can do
better than that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Take that out, take that out.
[SPEAKER_00]: We got his five words, but that was edited
from his original quote.
[SPEAKER_00]: That speaks to the value of editing in our
writing too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's a famous saying, everybody believes
a measurement except the person who made
[SPEAKER_00]: it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now this is an amazing thing to say as an
instrument company, we're all about making
[SPEAKER_00]: measurements, but some of those
measurements are so hard to make,
[SPEAKER_00]: you got to be skeptical of your own data,
even if other people believe it.
[SPEAKER_00]: No one believes a model except the person
who made it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So people that make models say,
I've modeled this, I know all about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: What this really means is we should be
more skeptical of measurements and do more
[SPEAKER_00]: careful models, but more than anything,
it's the combination of measurements and
[SPEAKER_00]: models that leads to knowledge.
[SPEAKER_00]: We need to go back and forth between these
and all of our science.
[SPEAKER_00]: Too often, we make too many measurements
without the underlying principles,
[SPEAKER_00]: without connecting them to theory,
and it leads to bad data.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if we do only models, we lead to crazy
models not connected to reality.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's the back and forth interaction that
helps us proceed in science.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I've used this analogy of a person
going to the top of a house on two step
[SPEAKER_00]: ladders.
[SPEAKER_00]: One step ladder is measurements,
one is theory or models, and you get to
[SPEAKER_00]: the top faster if you take one step on
each ladder and you go back and forth and
[SPEAKER_00]: you get right up to the top of the house.
[SPEAKER_00]: You could get there by making only
measurements, but pretty hard to jump on
[SPEAKER_00]: one step in a ladder or one step here.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's better to go back and forth.
[SPEAKER_00]: So as a sense of back and forth,
I made this little diagram.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's theory and knowledge far apart,
back and forth, back and forth.
[SPEAKER_00]: We gain wisdom as we go.
[SPEAKER_00]: But what if we move those closer together?
[SPEAKER_00]: High frequency back and forth.
[SPEAKER_00]: We make a lot faster knowledge.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then here we are in Korea.
[SPEAKER_00]: If we can conclude theory and measurement
within the same person, that's really
[SPEAKER_00]: efficient for advancing science.
[SPEAKER_00]: So my point here is become excellent at
making measurements, but become equally
[SPEAKER_00]: measurement, equally excellent at learning
the theory and the underlying principles
[SPEAKER_00]: of this.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now let's shift for a few slides on
photobiology.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is from a paper by Brodersen and
Vogtman many years ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: They did optics of light.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is a plant, a side view of a plant
leaf.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is a pretty famous picture.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's the top of the leaf.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's see if I can get this in here.
[SPEAKER_00]: There we go.
[SPEAKER_00]: And here's the bottom of the leaf.
[SPEAKER_00]: Green light penetrates better than red and
blue.
[SPEAKER_00]: We think these are so photosynthetic
efficient, but they're absorbed in that
[SPEAKER_00]: very top layer.
[SPEAKER_00]: Green penetrates this.
[SPEAKER_00]: Green is underappreciated value.
[SPEAKER_00]: And not just does it penetrate a leaf,
but it penetrates the whole canopy to the
[SPEAKER_00]: next leaf below.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is the basis for a lot of our
findings, just this simple concept of red,
[SPEAKER_00]: green, and blue.
[SPEAKER_00]: But now I would like to add another
wavelength to this.
[SPEAKER_00]: We can't really call it a color.
[SPEAKER_00]: I put far-red in here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now all of our data is clear that far-red
has photosynthetic value.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm going to show you that we've shifted
definitions of photosynthetic wavelengths
[SPEAKER_00]: for this.
[SPEAKER_00]: But far-red is also very penetrating in
plant canopies and in leaves.
[SPEAKER_00]: And sometimes we only study single leaves.
[SPEAKER_00]: We underappreciate the value of these
colors in canopies.
[SPEAKER_00]: This concept of one, two, three,
and adding a fourth category has really
[SPEAKER_00]: helped advance our science in this.
[SPEAKER_00]: And look at the profound impact.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lettuce, more than any other crop lettuce,
is really response to far-red.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cell division, cell enlargement.
[SPEAKER_00]: We add a little bit of far-red,
and we more than double growth of the
[SPEAKER_00]: lettuce.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is a combination of photosynthetic
photons and cell expansion and cell
[SPEAKER_00]: division cause associated with far-red.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we call this the shade response,
but we can trick the plants to thinking
[SPEAKER_00]: they're in the shade when they're in the
sunlight.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's just a powerful image of the
importance of far-red.
[SPEAKER_00]: This had led to a shift in how we define
photosynthetic photon flux density.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's 400 to 700, the conventional
definition that we've used for half a
[SPEAKER_00]: century.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's extended photosynthetic photon flux
density with another 50 nanometers out
[SPEAKER_00]: here of photosynthetic photons.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's this part right here that
resulted in that lettuce plant,
[SPEAKER_00]: enormous increase in growth.
[SPEAKER_00]: What we advocate is measure and report
both of these in papers.
[SPEAKER_00]: We need to understand the growth per unit
old definition, but also for the new
[SPEAKER_00]: definition EPPFD.
[SPEAKER_00]: But now we're learning when does this
apply and when does it not?
[SPEAKER_00]: This is Paul Kosuma.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got his PhD with me.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's at Wageningen now.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is the paper that resulted in this.
[SPEAKER_00]: These were studies with lettuce at three
intensities, a very low intensity of 100
[SPEAKER_00]: micromoles per meter squared per second,
doubling to 200 and then doubling again to
[SPEAKER_00]: 500.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now this is an excellent wavelength.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you can see we added far-red,
percent far-red.
[SPEAKER_00]: We added up to 30% and the lettuce
responded.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where that picture came from in the
previous slide right here.
[SPEAKER_00]: If we only gave them lower light,
that line is flat.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was no benefit of far-red if the
light intensity was low.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is with what we call substitution.
[SPEAKER_00]: As we added far-red photons, we took away
traditional photons.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the EPPFD was exactly the same.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if they were in very low light,
it was actually inhibitory.
[SPEAKER_00]: They needed those shorter wavelength
photons.
[SPEAKER_00]: So what do we do when we do this?
[SPEAKER_00]: We normalize percent of control.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this is the data normalized to one
here.
[SPEAKER_00]: And now with the trend becomes very clear.
[SPEAKER_00]: Far-red was far more beneficial with a
higher total background of photon flux
[SPEAKER_00]: than a lower background.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is gonna be followed up by a lot of
people, I'm sure, but it's a very
[SPEAKER_00]: fascinating interaction of far-red photons
and total amount of light, which again,
[SPEAKER_00]: we need to measure both.
[SPEAKER_00]: Spinach, you would think, responds like
lettuce, but it's a different genus.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a different species.
[SPEAKER_00]: All of our studies with spinach have shown
it's much, much less sensitive to far-red
[SPEAKER_00]: photons.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is a picture.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's far-red percentage, same as the
other one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Instead of data points, it's a picture.
[SPEAKER_00]: This 100, 200, 500, the same study,
far-red minimally increase growth.
[SPEAKER_00]: Growth increases a lot with more
intensity, but more far-red minimal
[SPEAKER_00]: effects.
[SPEAKER_00]: All of these pictures are similar here.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we have a lot to learn about
interactions of far-red with photon flux.
[SPEAKER_00]: These studies were done by Noah Langenfeld
in my laboratory.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're following up on these interactions
with other species.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fascinating photobiology.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now we have a very powerful tool.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're gonna hear numerous talks in this
conference about all these principles
[SPEAKER_00]: applied to plants.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm excited to be here.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm excited to hear all these talks.
[SPEAKER_00]: And thanks for listening.