I'm Bruce bugby president of apogee
instruments and I'm here today to record
The Talk The keynote talk that I gave a
few weeks ago at the light Sim symposia
in Soul
Korea this was the very opening Talk of
the conference and it was a great honor
to uh be asked to do this um what I
chose to talk about is not the details
of our photobiology research that my
students have I've done especially over
the last 10 years but as the opening
talk to the to the symposia of research
scientist I wanted to talk about more
about the process of Science and how we
use our instruments and tools to create
new knowledge um so these next few
slides are are what I showed there my
opening slide was
this this is a picture drawn by an
artist here in Utah James Christensen of
a home tinkerer taking his new spaceship
out for a drive in the space and I've
just loved this picture it's framed in
my laboratory but he's got all these
gizmos that he rigged up this is far
from high-tech in fact I think the title
of this was low Tech um but this is what
we all do in our Research Laboratories
Tinker with things build gizmos test
hypotheses they're much different than a
commercial Enterprise that might all be
built out of stainless steel and and
something something fancy there's the
name of the Symposium light Sim 2024
this through several hundred research
scientists really from all over the
world so it was truly a great honor for
me to uh give the opening talk of this
and as part of that it's light and and
photosynthesis and photons so I want to
start with a view of where we have come
with creating light for ourselves over
the past 150 years this comes from a
paper in the journal Nature which I
published with some colleagues LEDs for
photons physiology and food and in this
review paper we talked about the history
of light we started with kerosene lamps
what was the energy and the kerosene and
how much light did we out now this is
light measured in lumens per watt of
power going into this point4 now you can
see the tremendous breakthrough when we
got incandescent bulbs went from 04 to
15 it was an incredible advance and in
fact that was a 40-fold increase of
turning energy into light now this is
all for people but plant research as
I'll show in a minute has followed this
then in about just after World War II in
about 1950 we got fluorescent lights and
that was another big advance from 15 to
80 but that was a fivefold increase but
it was huge advance for everybody to
more light less heat um then in the
1970s we got high intensity discharge
lighting there's a high-press sodium
bulb 80 to 1 20 another huge Advance now
we're only talking
1.5x but each of these allowed us to do
more plant research with mostly with
higher intensities of light we weren't
doing so much back here with ratios of
colors as just getting the intensity up
but we still used a lot of colored
filters to create different ratios of
colors and some of my early papers right
in here were using hid and metal halight
lamps to uh with filters to get
different colors of light and then
Kaboom we get LEDs um roughly depend
when you say we started 10 or 20 years
ago and now another huge breakthrough in
terms of ratios of heat and light this
is for human lighting lumens per watt
but if we do this in micro moles of
photons per Jewel of energy and this is
the ratio for energy and photons out
here's the comparative numbers and look
at this
005 to 4 this is almost a 1,000 fold
increase in in U light and even even
here even if we start with incandescence
a tremendous breakthrough so now we get
all the colors we get very efficient in
uh lights so we can have high
intensity this is this is why we're all
assembled here for light Sim to talk
about our exciting work that we can now
do with
LEDs this ratio let me go back one this
is really light to heat lumens is light
watts is heat micro moles of photons is
Photon flux density and jewels is energy
so this is the ratio of these
two so what is sunlight it turns out
sunlight has two micromoles of
photosynthetic photons per Jewel of
thermal energy we don't think about that
ratio much but it I'll show you it's not
difficult to calculate for
sunlight now we have LEDs that are three
and they even exceed three micro moles
per Jewel just on this basis you can if
it's staggering because look we've
caught up and past sunlight with our
human technology it's just an in
incredible that we've done that and some
people have said yes so now we don't
need sunlight anymore we electric lights
are even better than sunlight but look
at this this Jewel of energy right here
oh let me get that back right here and
get my pen turned
on this Jewel of energy right here is
electricity we have to pay for that
Jewel of
energy this jewel is free from the
sunlight it comes with the Sun so we get
two micromoles for free and we pay for
these three so it's sunlight is still a
is still a tremendous uh source of light
because it's free compared to electric
lights but it's still 3 to two where do
we get two this is a Spectra of
wavelength of sunlight and intensity
here it's a classic ape has refrigerator
magnets with this Spectra on it this
part right here we say visible is really
photosynthetic Photon flux and this red
part out here is thermal doesn't drive
photosynthesis drives evaporation of
water it drives transpiration but it
doesn't drive photosynthesis so if you
look at this this is two and three based
on this ratio of this now if we include
far red photons in this that's this zone
right here for 400 to 700 nanm this
shifts this over slightly so now a
greater fraction of sunlight is photos
synthetic radiation and I'll come back
to this in this talk a bit but as as
most of you know this is a huge part of
uh the research of my students and I of
the value of these far red photons if we
include this this number gets slightly
bigger 2.3 micro moles per Jewel for
sunlight but we're still not trying to
catch up to electric lights we're still
trying to get favorable ratios of heat
of light to heat and if we do that well
we can air condition green houses now
that seems cost prohibitive now but let
me show you the Innovations in glass
that allows us to do
that this is once again here is our let
me get this in Black right here this is
our ppfd
same as visible light right here draw a
line right there this is the good part
we want a lot of this this is standard
glass that we've had for 100 years if we
put a coating on this it slightly
decreases visible but it dramatically
decreases the Heat and if we put more
coating even more and even more so all
of a sudden we have almost pure light
and very little thermal unusable thermal
out here when you use a low solar gain
glass we can air condition green houses
it's important to quantify this that's
why apog sells a flotilla of sensors to
rigorously quantify these ratios um but
this is a cutting edge of photobiology
and food production in highly controlled
environments is to use the right kinds
of solar glazing so we can close a
greenhouse not not only reduce the air
conditioning cost but allow us to seal
it and Elevate CO2 take advantage of
high CO2 that comes from Innovations and
glazing now let's go back to the history
of
photobiology to the
1950s this is when we were working with
fluorescent tubes and at Caltech
University in California Fritz went did
his pioneering work and he's a famous
famous scientist credited with the
discovery of oxen here's this here's his
work work from a plant physiology
textbook on oxen of the hormone oxen and
he wrote this book the experimental
control of plant growth It's a Wonderful
book about all these discoveries of
photo period and temperature
interactions and this is in this famous
calra phytotron where they could wheel
carts from different temperatures of
rooms and different lights of of rooms
all done with fluorescent
lights some of his famous quotes he's
are he he urg everybody to work in
controlled environments do more basic
research understand things at a very
fundamental level and now we have way
better tools than he ever had to do this
he advocated for very simple experiments
don't complex
experiments and he was very suspicious
of studies that needed a lot lot of
Statistics where he had a lot of
treatments and a lot of Statistics he
wanted fundamental data with more clear
results that's continues to be very wise
advice for all of us 50 years later to
do simple experiments with clear results
where we associate mechanisms with
experimental results I want to build on
this concept now in my next few slides
another famous scientist Ernest
Rutherford Nobel Prize in chemistry
1908 here's Ernest Rutherford was his
primitive tools of the time working out
breakthroughs in chemistry what did he
have to say about
statistics huh if your experiment needs
statistics y'all have done a better
experiment that's still wise advice do
simple experiments with clear results
not complex experiments that need a ton
of Statistics to interpret them not that
statistics is a bad thing we all use it
it's critical but we shouldn't rely on
the crutch of Statistics to design our
experiments they should be clear
fundamental test of
hypotheses sometimes we design
experiments that are more like a fishing
trip than a re real research we just
going to do a lot of stuff and see what
happens um good luck getting your
proposals funded if the reviewers think
they might be a fishing
trip Serendipity plays a huge role in
science we have we still go for what
we're looking for but people the public
thinks the most exciting phrase in all
of science is ah Eureka I just
discovered it Ah that's not how it works
the most exciting phrase is that's funny
there's an outlier here who said that
Isaac Asimov famous science fiction
writer and that's highlighted in this
book serendipitous discoveries and plant
science you can never plan for
Serendipity you have to be doing good
science but you have to have a trained
mind to understand when there's good
data and when there's bad data and we
all need to train our minds to to be
looking for these unusual data when they
arise another famous scientist leis
Pastor 18
1800s Chance favors the prepared mind
this is one of his most famous quotes I
have just loved this my whole career
studying in graduate school to get my
prepared mind for that that chance
moment what that really means is when
you have data like this and now you say
eh here's my curve for the
response let's get this in yellow here's
my curve for the response I don't like
that data point that's an outlier I'm
just going to take it
out how do you know that's an outlier
just because you can draw a nice smooth
curve for the rest of the data we should
be looking at outliers and understanding
what caused them that's why this quote
is so famous and by the way when you
read his original stuff one two three
four five words how elegant is that
that's not what he originally said says
in the fields of observation Chance
favors only the prepared mind so
subsequent editors said we can do better
than that take that out take that out we
got his five words but there was edited
from his original quote that speaks to
the value of editing in in our writing
too here's a famous thing everybody
believes a
measurement except the person who made
it now this is amazing thing to say is
an instrument company we're all about
making measurements but it's some of
those measurements are so hard to make
you got to be skeptical of your own data
even if other people believe it No One
Believes a
model except the person who made it so
people that make models say I've modeled
this I know all about it what this
really means is we should be more
skeptical of measurements and and do
more careful models but more than
anything it's the combination of
measurements and models that leads
to knowledge we need to go back and
forth between these and all of our
science too often we make too many
measurements without the pr underlying
principles without connecting them to
Theory and it leads to bad data and if
we do only models we lead to Crazy
models not connected to reality it's the
back and forth interaction that helps us
proceed in science
and I've used this analogy of a person
going to the top of a house on Two Step
ladders one step ladder is measurements
one is Theory or or models and you get
to the top faster if you take one step
on each ladder and you go back and forth
and you get right up to the top of the
house you could get there by making only
measurements but pretty hard to jump on
one step in a ladder or one step here
it's better to go back and forth so as a
sense of back and forth I made this
little diagram here's Theory and
knowledge far apart back and forth back
and forth we gain wisdom as we go but
what if we move those closer together
high frequency back and forth we make a
lot faster knowledge and then here we
are in
Korea if we can conclude Theory and
measurement in within the same person
that's really efficient for advancing
science so my point here is become
excellent in making measurements but
become equally measurement equally
excellent at learning the theory and the
underlying principles of
this now it's shift for a few slides on
photobiology this is from a paper by
brisen and vulgan many years ago they
did Optics of light this is a plant a
side view of a plant leaf
um this is a pretty famous picture
here's the top of the leaf let's see if
I can get this in here there we go
um and here's the bottom of the leaf
green light penetrates better than red
and blue we think these are so
photosynthetic efficient but they're
absorbed in that very top layer green
penetrates this green is
underappreciated value and not not just
as it penetrate a leaf but it penetrates
the whole canopy to the next Leaf below
this is the basis for a lot of our
findings just this simple concept of red
green and blue but now I would like to
add another wavelength to this we can't
really call it a
color I put far red in here now all of
our data is clear that far red has
photosynthetic value I'm going to show
you that we've shifted definition of
photosynthetic wavelengths for this but
fared is also very penetrating in plant
canopies and in leaves and sometimes we
only study single leaves we
underappreciate the value of these
colors in
canopies this concept of one two three
and adding a fourth category has really
helped Advance our science in this and
look at the profound impact lettuce more
than any other crop lettuce is really
responds to fared cell division cell
enlargement we had a little bit of far
red and we more than double growth of
the lettuce this is a combination of
photosynthetic photons and cell
expansion and cell division caused
associated with far red and we call this
the shade response but we cont trict the
plants to thinking they're in the shade
when they're in the sunlight it's just a
powerful image of the importance of far
red this had led
to a shift in how we Define
photosynthetic Photon flux density
here's 400 to 700 the conventional
definition that we've used for half a
century here's extended photosynthetic
Photon flux density with another 50
nanometers out here of photosynthetic
photons and it's this part right here
that resulted in that lettuce plant
enormous increase in growth
what we Advocate is report measure and
Report both of these in papers um we we
need to understand the the growth per
unit old definition but also for the new
definition
epfd but now we're learning when does
this apply and when does it not this is
Paul Kuma got his PhD with me he's at
veninga now um this is the paper that
resulted in this these were studies with
lettuce at three intensities a very low
intensity of 100 micromoles per meter
squ per second doubling to 200 and then
doubling again to 500 now this is an
excellent wavelength and you can see we
added far red percent far red we added
up to 30% and the leuce responded that's
where that picture came from in the
previous slide right here if we only
gave them lower light that line is flat
there was no benefit of far red if the
if the light intensity was low this is
with what we call substitution as we
added far red photons we took away
traditional photons so the efd was
exactly the same and if they were in
very low light it was actually
inhibitory um they needed those shorter
wavelength photons so what do we do when
we do this we normalize percent of
control and this is the data normalized
to one here and now the trend becomes
very clear far red was far more
beneficial with a higher total
background of photon flux than a lower
background um this is going to be
followed up by a lot of people I'm sure
but um it's a very fascinating
interaction of far red photons and total
amount of Light which again then we need
to measure
both spinach you would think responds
like lettuce but it's a different genus
it's a different
species all of our studies with spinach
have shown it's much much less sensitive
to far red photons this is a picture
here's far red percentage same as the
other one instead of data points it's a
picture this and 100 200 500 under the
same study far red
minimally increase growth growth
increases a lot with more intensity but
more far red minimal effects all of
these pictures are similar here so we
have a lot to learn about interactions
of far red with Photon flux these
studies were done by Noah langenfeld in
my laboratory we following up on these
interactions with other species
fascinating
photobiology now we have a very powerful
tool we we're we're going to hear
numerous talks in this conference about
all these principles applied to plants
um I'm excited to be here I'm excited to
uh hear all these talks and uh thanks
for listening
[Music]