[SPEAKER_00]: Hello, my name is Ben Crabbe.
[SPEAKER_00]: I do technical sales and support here at
Apogee Instruments.
[SPEAKER_00]: Today I'm here to talk to you about the
process to load new coefficients onto your
[SPEAKER_00]: MC-100 chlorophyll concentration meter.
[SPEAKER_00]: What inspired this process is that we have
some new coefficients for cannabis and for
[SPEAKER_00]: grapes.
[SPEAKER_00]: But in the future, as we have new species
with new coefficients, you can use the
[SPEAKER_00]: same process to access those new files,
add them onto your meter, and get the most
[SPEAKER_00]: accurate measurements you can.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the process will be we go to our
website and we download the files from the
[SPEAKER_00]: MC-100 product support page.
[SPEAKER_00]: We connect this MC-100 to the computer.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that'll allow us to access the folder
on this device with the files.
[SPEAKER_00]: You drag the new coefficient files that
you just downloaded onto the MC-100.
[SPEAKER_00]: You disconnect it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then you navigate through the menu on the
MC-100 to cannabis or grape or whatever
[SPEAKER_00]: species you please.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then you can start taking
measurements.
[SPEAKER_00]: So let's show you how to make all this
happen.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can go to our website,
apogeanstruments.com, www.apogeanstruments
[SPEAKER_00]: .com.
[SPEAKER_00]: Click on the Support tab up at the top and
find the chlorophyll meter page.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now we're on chlorophyll meter support.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right here, new coefficients, you can
click on this link and this will take you
[SPEAKER_00]: down the page to the relevant spot or you
can just scroll down and get to it that
[SPEAKER_00]: way.
[SPEAKER_00]: But here's the chlorophyll meter new
coefficients.
[SPEAKER_00]: We have a link here.
[SPEAKER_00]: We also have instructions here that you
can follow in case my video doesn't
[SPEAKER_00]: suffice.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can download the setting or the new
coefficients right here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now let's open up a new Explorer window.
[SPEAKER_00]: We can go to our downloads.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's the new coefficients it just
downloaded.
[SPEAKER_00]: Extract them because it's a zip folder.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we extract them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now we can see we have two files in here.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're .tab files, some kind of encrypted
file format that works well on the MC-100
[SPEAKER_00]: meter.
[SPEAKER_00]: And all we're gonna do is we're gonna
connect this and drag these files over.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I'll quickly just move over to the
display of the meter so you can see the
[SPEAKER_00]: buttons I'm pushing.
[SPEAKER_00]: So here's our meter.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'll turn it on.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hopefully there it goes.
[SPEAKER_00]: We plug it in with this little USB cable
that it came with the other end of which
[SPEAKER_00]: is in the computer.
[SPEAKER_00]: So now it's plugged in.
[SPEAKER_00]: You hit data and it says USB link active.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay, so this means that it is connected
to the computer and you ought to be able
[SPEAKER_00]: to access the relevant folder now.
[SPEAKER_00]: So switching back over to the computer
view.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'll open up another Explorer window and
we can see we have an option MC-100.
[SPEAKER_00]: So you open this up and you see a bunch of
other .tab files for all the other species
[SPEAKER_00]: that have coefficients already loaded onto
the meter.
[SPEAKER_00]: So all we're gonna do is we're gonna take
these two files and we're gonna drag them
[SPEAKER_00]: in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I already had them in there,
but we'll replace them.
[SPEAKER_00]: So now we have cannabis and we have grape
in the meter.
[SPEAKER_00]: When you do this, they may show up down at
the bottom.
[SPEAKER_00]: So you have to scroll all the way to
bottom of the list when we get to this
[SPEAKER_00]: step.
[SPEAKER_00]: But for the time being, they're in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so now I'm gonna switch back over to
our MC-100 display.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay, we'll just hit this eject button.
[SPEAKER_00]: It says unplug the USB cable, okay.
[SPEAKER_00]: So now we're back to the usual screen,
but we expect we should have new
[SPEAKER_00]: coefficients on here we could select if we
want to.
[SPEAKER_00]: So to get to them, we hit run.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then we hit setup.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then we hit the down arrow a couple of
times until we get to a screen that says
[SPEAKER_00]: use custom measurement.
[SPEAKER_00]: At this point, we hit edit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this highlights this units.
[SPEAKER_00]: Says yes, I think you can make it say no,
but we want to say yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can make it say yes and no by hitting
up and down.
[SPEAKER_00]: So now that we have yes highlighted,
we hit the right arrow.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now we've got 27 files with different
coefficients for a different species.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we just scroll through until we find,
let's look for cannabis.
[SPEAKER_00]: It may be down at the bottom or maybe it's
in the middle of the list somewhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's cannabis, down at the bottom.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the last two here, we have grape and we
have cannabis.
[SPEAKER_00]: So excellent, let's hit accept.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now we have cannabis coefficient selected.
[SPEAKER_00]: We can exit out of this screen and we're
ready to take measurements.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can just stick the leaf in there,
depress the arm, and you'll be taking
[SPEAKER_00]: accurate, absolute chlorophyll
concentration measurements of cannabis.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or if you selected grape, you can get them
for grape.
[SPEAKER_00]: As we develop coefficients for new
species, we'll put them at the same
[SPEAKER_00]: location on our website, that support page
for the MC-100.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you can follow this same procedure to
get them added onto your meter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Thank you very much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Have a nice day.
Thank you.
Bye-bye.