Hello, my name is Ben Crabb; I do technical sales and support here at Apogee Instruments.
Today I'm here to talk to you about the process to load new coefficients onto your MC 100
chlorophyll concentration meter.
What inspired this process is that we have some new coefficients for cannabis and for
grapevine.
But in the future, as we have new species with new coefficients, you can use this same
process to access those new files, add them on to your meter, and get the most accurate
measurements you can.
So the process will be: we go to our website.
We download the files from the MC-100 product support page.
We connect this MC-100 to the computer, and that will allow us to access the folder on
this device with the files.
You drag the new coefficient files that you just downloaded onto the MC-100.
You disconnect it.
Then you navigate through the menu on the MC-100 to cannabis or grapevine or whatever
species you please.
And then you can start taking measurements.
So let's show you how to make all this happen.
You can go to our website http://www.apogeeinstruments.com.
Click on the “support” tab up at the top.
And find the chlorophyll meter page.
We’re now on chlorophyll meter support.
Right here “new coefficients.”
You can click on this link, and this will take you down the page to the relevant spot.
Or you can just scroll down and get to it that way.
But here's the chlorophyll meter new coefficients.
We have a link here.
We also have instructions here that you can follow case my video doesn't suffice.
You can download the setting or the new coefficients right here.
Now let's open up a new Explorer window.
We can go to our downloads.
Here's the new coefficients it just download.
Extract them because it's a zip folder.
So we extract them.
Now we can see we have two files in here, they’re .tab files -- some kind of an encrypted
file format that works well on the MC-100 meter.
And all we're gonna do is we're going to connect this and drag these files over.
So I'll quickly just move over to the display of the meter so you can see the buttons I'm
pushing.
So here's our meter.
We'll turn it on.
Hopefully… there it goes.
We plug it in with this little USB cable that it came with.
The other end of which is in the computer.
So now it's plugged in.
You hit “data” and it says “USB link active.”
Okay so this means that it is connected to the computer, and you ought to be able to
access the relevant folder now.
So switching back over to the computer view.
We'll open up another Explorer window.
And we can see we have an option “MC-100.”
So you open this up, and you see a bunch of other .tab files for all the other species
that have coefficients already loaded onto the meter.
So all we're gonna do is we're going to take these two files, and we're gonna drag them
in.
Oh I already had them in there, but we'll replace them.
So now we have cannabis and we have grapevine in the meter.
When you do this they may show up down at the bottom so you have to scroll all the way
to the bottom of the list when we get to this step.
But for the time being they're in there.
And so now I'm going to switch back over to our MC-100 display…
Okay we'll just hit this “eject” button.
It says “unplug the USB cable.”
Okay so now we're back to the usual screen, but we expect we should have new coefficients
on here we could select if we want to.
So to get to them we hit “run.”
Then we hit “setup.”
Then we hit the down arrow a couple of times until we get to a screen that says “use
custom measurement.”
At this point we hit “edit,” and this highlights this “units.”
Says “yes.”
I think you can make it say no, but we want to say “yes.”
You can make it say “yes or no” by hitting up and down.
So now that we have “yes” highlighted, we hit the right arrow.
Now we've got 27 files with different coefficients for different species.
And we just scroll through until we find… let's look for cannabis… it may be down
at the bottom or maybe it's in the middle of the list somewhere…
There's cannabis down at the bottom.
So the last two here we have grape and we have cannabis.
Excellent.
Let's hit “accept.”
Now we have cannabis coefficients selected.
We can exit out of this screen.
And we're ready to take measurements.
You can just stick the leaf in there, depress the press the arm, and you'll be taking accurate
absolute chlorophyll concentration measurements of cannabis.
Or if you selected grapevine, you can get them for grapevine.
As we develop coefficients for new species, we'll put them at the same location on our
website.
That's support page for the MC-100.
And you can follow this same procedure to get them added onto your meter.
Thank you very much!
Have a nice day.