good morning this is I'm Bruce Bugbee
and today we're going to talk about air
temperature sensors this is really part
one in a series of environmental
measurement seminars that we've designed
to educate people on the key principles
I am joined in this effort by my
colleague mark blonde twist who is the
chief scientist for Apogee instruments
he isn't going to be doing the talking
but he and I have worked together to
analyze a wide range of sensors for
environmental measurement so we're gonna
start with perhaps the most fundamental
measurement of all which is air
temperature if you would ask me when I
was an undergraduate do you know how to
measure air temperature I would say yes
of course I know all about it if you
would ask me as a master's student do I
know how to measure air temperature and
I was saying yes yeah that kind of but
there's challenges and if you ask me as
a experience scientist do I know how to
measure air temperature and I probably
say something like whoo that is a really
challenging measurement so we're going
to help bring you up to the cutting edge
of just the sensors today to do this in
a separate talk we'll talk about shields
so this is the simplest thing what kind
of electronic sensors were used for air
temperature measurement and historically
we've used alcohol thermometers and
mercury and glass thermometers but those
are not electronic output you can't
record those you've got to have a sensor
that makes an electric output so we can
do continuous recording of it so this is
all about sensors that have electronic
output now let's jump to a picture that
we've made that shows sizes and types of
sensors here's a wide range of sizes and
in a minute I'll tell you why size is so
critical but let's just run over the
sizes all the way from the human hair
and look at the size of this 0.002
inches 0.06 millimeters this is tiny
just barely above that we can get fine
wire through misters that are just
barely thicker than a human hair now
these are used to in use in a syringe to
inject into an animal to measure
internal temperature of an animal but
boy they stay very close to air
temperature because they are so tiny so
this would be a nice sensor but this
sensor in our long-term studies drifts
it's not a stable sensor and that's a
critical feature of these sensors they
have to be rock-solid year after year
after year so we're not using this fine
wire sensor even though it's wonderfully
tiny because it's not solid and
long-term studies going up the scale
thermocouples are a classic electronic
way of measurement they're widely used
they're inexpensive is taken strip a
wire twist it like this you've got a
temperature sensor but they are not the
most accurate reference standard and for
long runs of wire they get expensive the
cost of thermocouple wire is about ten
times the cost of regular wire so we
mostly use these when we need to do lots
of measurements in a small distance a
small distance from the data logger even
though they can be small so then we
going down the list we get into the
category of thermistors so let's put a
line under thermocouples we'll call that
number one not thermocouples or
thermistor rather are number two and
technologies these are have a big signal
size they're easy to measure for years
these were considered not a reference
standard because they drifted in the
long term so to avoid this problem with
drift for years we've gone to platinum
resistance thermometers now lots of
people know these by the acronym
P R T platinum resistance thermometer
sometimes people say P R T D and that's
just a temperature detector those are
the same things
P R T and P R T key this one like the
typical PR T's is enclosed in a
stainless steel sheath that makes this
extremely rugged but it's a bigger size
than this thermistor slightly bigger and
a lot more expensive so finally to get
this even more rugged Apogee sells a
ceramic sheath thermistor which is this
enclosed in a big housing you could
drive over this with a truck
so for rugged places and direct burial
and soils this ceramic sheath thermistor
is a good choice
but what we're down to is the misters
particularly through misters that are
epoxy coated to nearly eliminate water
infiltration into the sensor that's what
kills sensors is when water gets into
them and the only two things that water
isn't get through our metal and glass
epoxy though is clothes the right kinds
of epoxy are almost as impermeable as
glass so this one has got a special
epoxy coating to make it water
impermeable and as a result of that
potentially very stable so we've got
thermocouples thermistors and PRTs as
the categories PR T's have long been
considered the gold standard but they
have a couple of disadvantages they're
big they're expensive and they take up a
lot of data logger channels let's take a
look at the effective size in this small
is better but boy these are still pretty
small as far as temperatures
sisqó so this next slide shows us the
effect of size on temperature rise so
we've got these are all thermocouples
now so we take the same measurement
technology and make it in different
sizes now look at the wire diameter
these are down here thinner than a human
hair in this part of the graph these are
all tenths of a millimeter small and
very small we've put these in a
controlled environment with typical
radiation loads on them and look at the
increase in temperature this is the
difference between the true air
temperature and what the sensor gave us
look at this
8 degrees C errors with big sensors in
low wind speeds this number over here U
is wind speed right there so these are
all fairly low wind speeds but they
occur on calm days so this is high
radiation coming into it this is
intermediate radiation the point of this
whole slide is these errors are dark
gancho on e if you're trying to get
within a few tenths of a degree of the
correct air temperature you need to have
a very small sensor or make sure that
sensor doesn't see the sunlight directly
these were with no shielding and we'll
talk about that in another seminar that
the value and the importance of correct
shielding but for now small is better
the errors can be enormous so let's take
a look at PR T's all PRTs are not
created equal peoples all I've got a PRT
what kind of a PRT here's the five
classes of PR T's and their accuracy
specifications and plus or minus 1.2
degrees C that is not a very accurate
sensor but you can go we can go all the
way up
to one-tenth din which is an extremely
accurate PRT so you can see these vary a
lot and accuracy look at how much they
vary in cost one X - 15 X these are
great but they're very expensive and
we'll compare these two thermistors in
our in our next slide we have done tests
on these compared to this epoxy coated
semester that Apogee uses to measure air
temperature to see how good that is so
right here we're gonna do this
comparison of thermistors to this yellow
bead PRT and what we're going to compare
in the next few slides is Class A - mr.
so intermediate accuracy similar
advertised accuracy plus a minus 0.1
plus a minus point point one five 0.01
this is still more expensive but the
specified a cure is similar so what we
did in this test is took replica class a
PRT s and compared them to replica
thermistor 's and then we cycle them up
and down and up and down trying to make
them fail if something's going to go
wrong they've got to take this
accelerated aging test it was with high
humidity it was the worst possible
scenarios so really we can get 10 or 15
years of aging in just three or four
months by doing this but we want to know
these are going to be stable for the
long term so how'd this test come out
well first PRT accuracies they're not
equally accurate over the whole range
here's zero C right at freezing which is
their peak accuracy and as we deviate
from that these accuracies get greater
and again here's the the types of
thermistors and their accuracy here's a
picture of the PRT that Apogee
sells and we've got one right here -
real then you can do the size
comparisons
Appaji uses a shielded twisted-pair
cable this is also a four wire ohm
thermistor which we'll talk about in a
minute but they're for scale it's there
it is not on the screen right at my hand
by the way so here's the yellow bead
thermistor tiny yellow bead look at the
difference in size pretty close but the
yellow bead is smaller so if it's
smaller stays closer to the air
temperature so how this tests come out
after beating these things up bad giving
them 15 years one other key point before
I show you the test results a thermistor
because it has a big signal can be
measured with one single ended channel
one I'm going to put s e on here single
and a channel that's an inexpensive data
logger channel and we can do that
because it has a big signal CRTs have
such a tiny signal at the minimum we
need to take two channels here on the
data logger but for the best accuracy we
need to have two differential channels a
four wire system to get the best
accuracy not only is the sensor more
expensive but all those channels on the
data logger add cost to the system each
channel on a data logger can be several
hundred dollars and this takes four of
them compared to one up here
that's an overlooked cost in this thing
is the cost of these channels all right
now what do these do here is 96 cycles
we went from minus 20 to plus 60 C 96
times up and down the thermistors are
shown here in blue the yellow beads the
pr keys are shown here
in red see if we can get rid of that
there we go these are shown here in red
here's the data the thermistors had a
slightly bigger error in the beginning
and you can see over the course of the
tests the number of cycles they drifted
more these are offset errors right here
so we can take those out and say okay if
they all read perfectly what would this
graph look like
so we normalize this then the
thermistors are rock-solid they're
better than the Class A PRTs so for less
money you can get greater accuracy with
this yellow bead thermistor it doesn't
mean all thermistors are better just one
just this one that has the epoxy coating
on it which is the one that Apogee has
selected to sell so now let's take a
look remember I said there was better
PRTs now let's take a look at some
one-tenth din PRTs how did they do these
are higher quality even more cycles 10
months 584 cycles up and down up and
down the class the one-tenth din PRTs
were much better this is rock-solid
these are the two replicates right here
those were rock-solid in this death so
it's possible to get good PRTs you just
have to pay more for them so how did
these compared to the thermistors here's
12 replicas thermistors against those
584 cycles and we keep going we
normalize them to 0 here because there's
some offset and the errors are less than
five one hundredths of a degree C in
drift of these sensors over time so this
is a more comprehensive test that helped
convince us that these yellow bead
thermistors were just rock-solid so
let's look at an application how good do
you need air temperature and how would
these perform in a system in a severe
climate it turns out we're in Logan Utah
so we look out the window at mountains
that are 10,000 feet we're five little
under 5,000 feet in our Valley some of
those mountain climates have very severe
weather and one of the most famous for
severe weather is a place called Peter
sinks it's in a little ball high up in
the mountains cold air collects in this
sink it gets extremely cold and it hot
in the summer cold inthere how cold does
it get look at this
1985 rerecorded - sixty nine point three
Fahrenheit up there - fifty six point
three see this record was the lowest
temperature for Utah the record all-time
low and it was the second coldest
temperature ever recorded in the
continental United States
oh great second how what was the coldest
Rodgers pass in Montana sixty nine point
seven Fahrenheit this is 1954 so these
are long-term records look at the
difference here's our second-place minus
sixty nine point three
there's the all-time record sixty nine
point seven you tell me how much
accuracy of sensors matters and extreme
cases when that we got second place by
four tenths of a degree Fahrenheit
that's two tenths of a degree Celsius
measurements matter when you're going
for an all-time record so at this site
we have set up a weather station that
continuously records temperatures and
we've done test runs with the apogee
sensors up here to see how they do let's
take a look at that site here's the site
this is practically summer up there
right if the snow really does melt off
in this summer but it's it's a remote
steer site right here is a multi-plate
shield that they're commonly used on
these and then here is the apogee
aspirated shield so what we're going to
look at is just the shield now and we're
going to take a look right up the bottom
of this like we're laying on the snow
looking at the bottom this is what the
bottom looks like and this is the
sensors inside of here two yellow beads
and two PRTs both in the same shield so
we can do a rigorous replicate
comparison of accuracy and stability
over a long term in this because they're
both fan aspirated they should both be
accurate how'd they do well first of all
how severe was the weather this is a
year almost a year of weather
up and down day and night day and night
this has huge swings hot in the day cold
at night here's last winter is two
winters ago we didn't get the all-time
record right we got to almost to minus
40 degrees C remember the all-time
record is minus 56 but it still got cold
in up and down then finally summer came
and it's not many nights it doesn't
freeze up there that's it's it's a cold
place but these swings are enormous so
it's sensors should get a beating up
there what's the data look like here's
that same graph with cycling temperature
difference between the two replicas
thermistors look at the scale on this
plus a minus one see right on top of
each other here's the PRTs they're also
very good plus or minus zero now focus
in on this right here this little spike
has happened in the spring this is
classic when it happens when a speck of
moisture gets in there could have been
even an insect and it got on one of the
sensors and cooled it off and sources
the average of the two and it's only
it's less than 1 degree C but this is
not measurement error this is just
something momentarily getting in the
shield and cooling off the sensor you
can imagine if you put an ice cube on a
sensor for a fraction of a second you'd
easily get that even a wet sponge would
easily get them right to 0 so that we're
not worried about that what we're
worried about is this stability and
let's zoom in on this just a bit now
just those two graphs big even a
narrower scale plus a minus point 4
degrees C the the replica thermistors
are very close to each other the replica
PRPs are close to each other these are
differences from the mean of all four
sensors so nobody was off by more than
about 0.1 and they were rock-solid over
this down your period of this test the
thermistors were every bit as good as
the pr T's for stability
but there's one other concern remember
we talked about small is better and the
smaller the sensor the closer it stays
to air temperature these are smaller
than these it's a round end remember are
not in our Show and Tell here
that's not much difference in size but
if the sun is shining on these this big
stainless steel one's going to heat up
more than that tiny little feet but
these are also inside a aspirated shield
so the Sun shouldn't matter but what
happened the some reflected light
bounced off the snow and heated these up
inside the screen and here's what
happened compared to the mean of the
thermistors the PRTs heated up from
solar radiation wasn't big it was 0.1
degrees C but because they were bigger
they were less accurate so this is two
examples of the same thing the to
replicate PRTs both of them heated up
this is why we really recommend using
this Apogee yellow bead thermistor in
these applications even inside of an
aspirated shield where they're protected
it saves a lot of money if you really
need good accuracy put in two replicas
yellow beads and if they only read the
same you need to go out and check the
site you've got a problem so to end to
replica yellow beads is far less
expensive than one more expensive PRT
here's the setup right here so with that
we're going to conclude this session on
temperature sensors and we'll follow up
on temperature shields in another talk
thanks for listening we'll see you again
soon