Could cars of the future really be powered by algae? Scientists at Utah
State University in Logan Utah seem to think so, and now they've exceeded a
world speed record to prove it.
At the recent time trials at the world famous Bonneville Salt Flats, the USU
Aggies A-salt dragster shocked the crowd as a race down the track, powered
by a unique fuel synthesized from one of the world's most plentiful organisms,
algae.  To accomplish this took the melting of minds and the support of a world-class
institution, capable of forward thinking and long-term support. We combined cutting-edge
expertise in engineering with excellence in biochemistry and
agricultural scientists that were willing to think outside the box.
Tthese three elements converged perfectly at Utah State University, and the result
may just change the way we all get around in the future. The idea of using
algae as a fuel was born during the crippling oil shortages of the nineteen
seventies, faced with the reality of a world running out of gas
scientists began searching for alternatives. Algae was considered but
quickly dismissed because the science to grow and process it economically did not
yet exist. So, we're excited about the USU biofuels. We take carbon dixide and sunlight and
turn into
completely renewable fuels. We think it's a potential game changer because we can
actually use this in existing engines, and the test we've already done shown
that it works just as well as a renewable fuels like biodiesel.
Of the biofuels portfolio, microalgae has the best promise for achieving
significant contributions for transportation fuels. At Utah State
University we began building a research program that could be addressed
biofuels. We focused on how to grow it, hot to extract it, and how to process it. The A-salt
was recently clocked at 73.977 miles per hour, which may not seem like blistering
speed, but it beat the existing land speed record for its one liter small
diesel engine class. This is an engine size comparable to that of a riding lawn
mower. It isn't about the speed. The real story here is the fuel. Thescience behind it. The
research that goes into it, and the fact that we have a real replacement for
fossil fuels probably in our hands right now. Here at Utah State
we worked with the College of Agriculture, plant scientists, and they
understand how we grow these microalgae. To accumulate the high levels of
these biofuel precursor compounds, called lipids.
Biochemists focus on how do we take those cells, and how do we
process them, and refine them to get the
fuel itself. Then that can be used to do diesel engine tests and to be used in the Aggie A-salt
diesel stream liner. With the screaming success of the A-salt
dragster, they've proven the concept. The algae-based fuel works. Now, the next big
hurdle for the team is bringing down the cost of production.  Alagea don't
automatically produced the oil needed to make bio-diesel, stress is needed.
We're working on getting the stress right to increase oil productivity and
bring the costs down. Currently algae bio-diesel is about $15 per gallon.
We think we can bring that cost down significantly. We are really excited about
the enormous potential microalgae has to be a player in the biofuels area.
Coming from Colorado State to join the team here in the mechanical and aerospace
department, I take data from plates like these and open raceway ponds and other
processing technologies to perform systems level analysis. To be able to really focus
our efforts in research and development to drive the cost down. We're looking forward
to commercialization in the future.  We are currently studying algae production in both high input bio-reactor and low input
opened raceways. These laboratory scales raceways are powered
by state of the art LEDs,
which allow us to provide the equivalent of summer sunlight 365 days a year.
Growing algae in a greenhouse under electric light will never be
cost-effective, but it greatly accelerates our research progress. If their past
success is any indication of the future. We could all be driving algae fuel cars
very soon.