Hello, my name is Schuyler Smith, and I do technical sales and support here at Apogee
Instruments. And today we're going to do a Quickstart video for how to connect your PQ-500/PQ-510,
which is the SQ-500-SS with the AT-100, which is the µCache Bluetooth logger. So in this
video, we're going to cover the Apogee Connect app download, the Apogee Connect and connecting
to the µCache, and then making sure your sensor is set up correctly in the app, and
then we're going to go over setting up logging to the µCache logger and then how to collect
those logs after you've come back to the sensor. So the first thing is the app. This is what
the app looks like. Over here you can see the iOS when you search for Apogee Connect.
And then over there is the Google Play — what it will look like there. So go ahead and download
that to your phone or tablet. Next up this is the Quickstart Guide that we include with
the µCache in the sensor. And so if you've lost that you can just pause on this screen,
and you can look at these directions. We're going to go through each one of these. And
then this page is the Quickstart guide on how to set up logging — how to begin logging
the first time. And then over here we're going to do the Quickstart guide to collecting logs
from the µCache after it's been logging and how to go out and get that. So again you're
welcome to pause on the video to review those. And now we will do a demonstration... Give
that a second to come up... Alright so right here you can see we have an iOS device, and
we've just opened the Apogee Connect app. So this is what yours will look like the first
time you come into it. So the first thing we want to do is get the µCache advertising.
So we hold down the green button for 3 seconds, starts blinking blue, and then nothing happens
over here until we hit add “+”. So we hit add “+” up in the corner, and then
now it comes up. It says “uc1080.” So we look on the back of this, says “1080.”
So we know that is the correct one, we click on it, and then it's going to come up and
it says SP-110. We don't have an SP-110. We have a SQ-500. So we need to change that.
And we start by clicking on choose model. And then when we're here, we're going to scroll
down until we find the SQ-500. We're going to click on it. Okay. It does not have a custom
calibration. It's the standard calibration for the SQ-500. And then if we want to rename
it, if we're expecting a couple, we can name it whatever we want. But we can just put “home”
on here for now. And then we can hit add. So we've changed the name to home. We're showing
on this screen now that it’s connected and then here not logging. So if we come in here
after it's not connected and open up Apogee Connect, we'll see an X through connected.
So now that we're here, we can go into this sensor. Alright and the first thing we see
is that we are reading accurate values right there, and we can get that to increase or
decrease just by changing it. Okay. And then if we want to go to live meter mode, we can
click right there.And it is updating our live meter as we
speak. And then if we want to collect the data, we can record the current value just
by clicking here. And it's going to record that in the table below. And then again this
table updates based on the amount of light that we're shining on it. Now you can see
that it's a very fast updating right now. If we wanted to average out that live sample
data, we can do that under settings. And we'll show you that here in a second. Now it is
important to note that on this graph it does go away if I click “back” and go to a
different screen. And so it's only live meter right now as you're looking at it. It's not
saving this graph anywhere else. So this is perfect for going around doing spot measurements
and seeing how the light changes depending on where we move that sensor around. So now
let's talk about setting up logging as well as various settings we can go into. So the
first thing... so settings we don't have a custom calibration. We can rename it here
if we didn't like “home” and we want to name it something else. We don't need to worry
about dark offset calibration with this sensor. And this is logging enabled. We're going to
come back here and enable this here in a second. Water correction — this is what you want
to turn on if you're using this underwater in aquarium and coral
reef applications. And so you turn on that correction factor, which then turns this into
the equivalent of reading the same as like a MQ-510 that we offer. You can have “notify
when full” when you're logging your data points. It can log up to 400,000 data points.
But if you're doing it for a long time in the field you can click that. This is that
setting we mentioned before “live data averaging.” Currently, it's averaging samples over one
second and reporting that, but you can see that you can increase this up to as high as
thirty seconds on that live data averaging. And then we have some information down here:
the hardware version, the firmware version, and then sensor time. Now you're always going
to want to match current time when you get in here to do this. And then that way it matches
the time in here that's logging, the time date stamps, and then to what your phone is.
So that way when you go to collect the logs later those numbers are already set and matched.
And then update sensor firmware. You're welcome the first time you get that to click on that.
When you're connected to it you click start. It will go ahead and check itself. It's now
a red LED. It's going through... you can see it's updating it to the latest version that's
available to it. Then it's completed. And then you're going to see it blink blue. And
now it’s back connected. So that's a quick process as needed. So let's go back up here
to setting up logging. So oh I'm sorry we went over dark threshold. Dark threshold right
here okay. So the dark threshold means how much light you're willing to hit the sensor
and let it and say that it is dark. Some people are willing to go up to 2 µmols or 2.5 µmols.
Some people need it less than that. So you can change that dark threshold to whatever
you want, which is important when you're logging your daily light
integrals and your photoperiods. So you can move that around to what you want. But it
comes standard at 0.5 µmols m⁻² s⁻¹. All right logging enabled. So we slide logging
enabled on, and then it comes up as 10-minute logging interval and one-minute sampling.
So that means that in this example it will take 10 readings because it's doing one every
minute, and then every 10 minutes it's logging it. So 1 reading every minute, and then it
will average all 10 of those and log that data. So we recommend 15 minutes for our logging
interval and then your sampling interval we’ll give you equivalence of that out to here.
So you can do every 2.5 minutes for sampling. Now the reason that we encourage 15-minute
logging period is because it affects the battery life. By having a 15-minute logging average,
if you're just going for the daily totals of light, your battery is going to last you
know nine months to a year depending on other conditions, temperature, and stuff. But if
we go logging interval all the way down to you know less than 10 seconds… sampling
intervals less than 10 seconds will decrease battery life. And that can decrease it all
the way down to a week — down to weeks instead of months. So you definitely want to make
sure that you're logging and sampling interval is set up for whatever your application is,
but just know it will take a toll on the battery if it is too quick. So let's get this out
to a minute or so. Okay. And then we have to hit save down here. Once we hit save now
it's saved in there okay. And it says we started right here and it will be filled by 2032.
So we have quite a ways before our data will be filled. All right so now our logging is
enabled okay. And so because we did a firmware update it came through and it gives us this
big number. But we know that those logs are not correct. So we want to clear the logs.
So we clear logs down to zero. Okay so now it currently has zero logs to gain. But how
do we set it up for field logging the first time once we want to collect logs? So we click
on collect logs. And then we come here to create new, which is what it automatically
comes on. And then new data set right here. We can rename that whatever we want. And then
we do the start time and the end time down below, and these should be auto-filled because
the start time is when we enabled logging and then end time is the current time. And
then you just hit collect logs. Well, right now there's zero. And so down below it is
giving us that there is no data collected, and so our graphs down here have not been
updated. So for our demonstration, we will grab this PQ-500 we have right here and we'll
bring it over. So it's the same sensor and µCache. So on this screen, we're going to
hold down until it blinks blue — hold down the green button until it blinks blue — then
we will add it. Searching for devices. It says “Schuyler's Yard” because that's
the experiment I was running. I was looking for the best spot for a garden in my yard.
So we can connect to this. It remembers that it's a SQ-500, but since it's the first time
on this phone it's asking me if it's correct. I say add, and we can see that our µmol value
is very similar since they're right here both on the platform. So let's go into it, and
we can see logs available for collection is 7. Okay and down here it has never collected
logs, and so we don't see any data down here. Now I'm going to collect logs, and so again
it's the first time on this phone. So I'm going to “create new,” and I'm going to
call it “2020 Garden.” So we can just rename that right there. And then its start
time and end time. Now because I just connected it, the start time says 2:15; however, I know
that the data goes all the way back to April. But I, for the sake of time, I just want to
collect about a week's worth of data. So we'll go back to Tuesday, June 9th, and let's go
to midnight... so get that to 12:00 a.m. Okay. So we set that. So that's our start time/end
time. And then we're going to collect logs. And it jumps from 7 that it had been collecting
within the last couple minutes to 2000. Okay so once it's done downloading all of this
data, it's going to auto-populate down here. And this is going to give us our µmols per
day down here. And then this is going to give us our moles per day or our DLI (daily light
integral). And then our photoperiod is going to be here. So it just takes a little while.
I’m already halfway through. And then we will see the data pop up underneath... Okay
so we can see right here a couple days it's been in the office. Before that, it was out
in the yard. We can see some beautiful clear days, and then we can see some rainy days
out in my yard. And then down here is the real gem where we can see our DLI values,
and we can see we're between 40 and 50 moles per day for the place that I'm going to put
my tomatoes in the ground. And then down here we can see the photoperiod, which is just
about 16 hours a day currently right now in June for Logan, Utah. Now any time after this
that I want to collect logs, I'm going to collect logs, I'm going to append existing,
and then I'm going to hit collect logs. And it said zero because we have zero right now,
but in a couple minutes that will have another log and then another. And so from this point
on I just want to collect logs I just want to append to existing and then collect logs,
and then it will automatically update these graphs below. And then if I want the data...
so I can view the data... and then right here is that share button so I can export it out
to myself and email all that data. So then I could analyze it under my own excel sheet
as needed. So with that, that concludes our Quickstart video. If you have any questions
feel free to email us at techsupport@apogeeinstruments.com. Thank you.