This is a user guide for the Apogee  InSight MS-100 spectroradiometer.
[ ♪ Intro music ♪ ]
Hello everyone, I am super excited to visit with you today.
Today we have the Apogee InSight.
It's a sweet little handheld spectroradiometer.
So let's get into it. Let's open up the case and check it out.
Inside the case we've got certification,
InSight device,
soft carrying case,
USB cable,
lanyard with lanyard nut,
Modbus adapter,
and power brick.
Let me show you around the InSight.
On the front, we have an LED indicator light and an LCD screen.
On the left side we've got a power button, or a screen change button,
a reset button,
the USB port,
and a micro-SD card port.
On the back side, we have the sensor cover,
slide that open to reveal the sensor.
On the top, we have the measurement button
and on the bottom we have  the 1/4-20 thread mount, or a tripod mount.
Make sure that before the first use of the  InSight that you charge the device for at least six hours.
So grab the USB power adapter and  the charging data cable.
Hook them up, plug it into the InSight.
The indicator will turn orange when  it's charging.
When it's completed charging it'll turn green.
You can tell it's charging either by the orange indicator light or by the icon with the lightning bolt through it.
The InSight is intended for lab and field use.
As a result, the device is not waterproof,  so make sure you don't put it in the water.
Now I'm going to show you how to use the device.
To turn it on, press and hold the  power button.
The LED indicator light will turn on, and the device will boot up.
If the shutter on the back is closed, it'll automatically perform a dark calibration.
Once that calibration is complete, you're ready to take a measurement.
For a spectroradiometer, it's very important to  make sure that you do a dark calibration.
To ensure the highest accuracy of measurements, make sure you do it often,
especially when you change environments,  such as temperature or humidity.
To perform a manual calibration with the device powered on, close the shutter,
and then press the measurement button,
and it'll perform a dark calibration.
Once that's been done it's ready to begin taking measurements again.
To take a measurement, point at the target light source,
press the measurement button.
It'll take about eight seconds to perform the measurement. When it's done, it'll beep.
In order to prevent inaccurate data, hold the  InSight in place until you hear that second beep.
And now you have the measurement.
The screen will show you the spectra data.
Press the power button quickly to change screens.
The next screen will  show you PPFD and ePPFD, or PAR and ePAR,
as well as other various indicators used by professionals in the industry.
If you would like to save the measurement data,
make sure you insert a micro-SD card  into the slot before you take the measurement.
It'll include all the necessary data, as well as a time stamp.
So make sure you write down your location,  so you can reference it later.
To power off the InSight, press and hold the power button.
Now we're going to show you how to  connect the InSight to your mobile device.
First, go to the app store, either Android or Apple.
Search "Apogee InSight."
This is the app you're going to want to download.
At this point, you're going to want to turn on the InSight.
Up in the top right corner you'll see an icon. It'll either be blue or red.
That'll tell you whether or not your device is connected.
If that icon is red, that means your device is not connected, and you need to connect it through Bluetooth.
If it's blue, that means the devices are communicating.
Once that icon is blue, you're ready to begin taking measurements.
These are the options that are available on the InSight mobile app.
The "Browser" feature lets you go through and review different tests and measurements that you've taken.
Press the "Home" icon in the top left corner to go back.
To take measurements, let's start with the "Basic" icon.
From here you can see the different metrics:
PPFD, ePPFD (or PAR and ePAR), and the other metrics that are used throughout the industry.
From here, with your InSight turned on, open the shutter and place it under your target light source.
To take a measurement press the rainbow  camera icon on the bottom in the middle.
Once it's done, it'll automatically populate the  different metrics that are available on the screen.
If you don't see the metric you're looking for, press the gear icon in the bottom right corner
and click on basic selector.
From here you can choose from the various  metrics that are pre-loaded on the InSight.
When you're done, press to go back in the top  left corner, and then press it one more time.
If you want to rearrange the  order that these metrics are found in,
take your finger, push down and hold on the square,
and then you can drag it around and rearrange it as you desire.
Let's go back to the "Home" screen
Let's look at the spectrum data on this light right here.
Click the "Spectrum" icon.
With the InSight under your target light source, press the capture button or the rainbow circle.
So now this will give you the spectra data on this light.
If you want to save or share this data,  press the four squares in the bottom left corner,
and from there you can save, share, or open other data.
Let's go back to the "Home" screen.
To view the plant-specific spectrum,  press the "PPFD Spectrum" icon
This will show you the spectrum that's more conducive to plant growth.
Let's press the "Home" button and go back again.
The remaining three icons: the "CIE" and the "CRI"  are used in other industries.
And because of that, we're not going to go into too much detail in this video.
For more information about those,  refer to the user manual in the link below.
And that's a quick overview on the  mobile application for the InSight.
The InSight has some added features that are  available only with a desktop application.
To get the desktop application, go to the Apogee  Instruments website at apogeeinstruments.com.
Scroll down to the bottom,
and in the support column, look for software downloads.
And then scroll down until you see the  InSight handheld spectroradiometer.
You're going to click and download  the Apogee InSight software
Once it's been installed, it should look  something like this.
From here you're now ready to connect the InSight.
So make sure the shutter is closed, and then plug in the device.
When it's plugged in, the InSight will  automatically pop up on the device list.
Click on the InSight, and then click connect.
It's going to remind you to make sure  the cover is closed on the sensor,
and then tell you that the dark  calibration has been completed.
Now you're ready to begin using the  device.
Let's go to the "View" mode first.
From here you can view the spectrum.  Turn on your light source,
open the cover,
and then on the top, click the capture button.
This will capture that data and  then display it as a spectrum graph.
If you want to save this data, share this data, or  if you want to load other data,
use the icons in the top left corner.
You can also use continuous  capture to keep capturing over and over again.
If you want to make changes to lights in real time,
in the bottom right it shows you the metrics.
If for some reason you don't see the metrics you're  looking for, click on the box in the top right,
and then move them and change them as you want.
Click on the one you'd like to remove.
Click the only one you want to replace it with,
and then shift it over,
and it'll move it over.
When you're done, hit the green check mark,
and it will update those metrics.
Now we're going to go to "Log" mode.
In "Log" mode, you can change the different parameters over on the right side.
You can set the interval for how long  between the captures and a total time,
or you can do it by how many captures are taken.
Let's go change this to seconds.
We'll do one every five seconds for a total of one minute,  then you can press the start logging button.
It will begin taking those measurements.
[Device beeping periodically as measurements are taken]
You can see they're going to start displaying as they're taken.
If you want to stop before the total interval  has gone through, press the stop button.
Let's go to "Bin" mode now.
"Bin" mode isn't something we typically do in our industry,
and so if you want to learn more about it, click on the link in the  description below for the user manual.
Let's go now to the "Checker" mode.
In "Checker" mode, you can set the parameters  for which you'd like to test the light by,
and you can see whether or not it passes or fails those qualifications.
If you notice, you can't change those  qualifications right off, you have to  unlock them.
Click the term lock button to unlock  them and from here you can change them.
After you're done changing them, click the lock button,
and then you can press the capture button.
You can see that according to these  parameters, this light would pass that test.
On the left side there are more modes available. Just use the up and down button in the bottom left corner.
Let's go now to the "Transmit" mode.
In "Transmit" mode it'll tell you how much  light passes through a material.
Click on the standard light to get your baseline.
Now grab your test material and put it between the  light and the InSight, and then press test sample,
and this will tell you how much light was allowed through, and how that spectrum might have changed over the process.
The last mode is "TM30."
TM30 is another one of those metrics that  we don't typically use in our industry,
but if you want to learn more about it, click in the description below to for the user manual and it'll explain it.
And that's a quick overview of the desktop application.
I hope you've had a chance to see just  how powerful this little device is.
We're excited to see what you'll  be able to do with it out in the field.
Leave a comment below with any questions you  have or how you would use the InSight.
Thank you so much for watching, and have a wonderful day.
[ ♪ Outro music ♪ ]