The first day of a new job is  always a bit scary...
a new company, new people  and new rules.
What have I gotten myself into now.
One year later let me show you  exactly what I've gotten myself into.
Over the last year,  I have been part of something amazing.
I have found a diverse group of unique people,
each with unique strengths.
A team of people who  turn imagination into reality.
What starts as an idea  evolves into a physical product,
that gets tested, tested again,  and then retested.
Until it's finally ready for the world.
Then manufacturing assembles those  products with speed and precision.
It takes a lot of time, commitment  and dedication from all the employees
to turn conception into reality
and we do it everyday.
We help researchers, scientists and businesses  all achieve their aspirations.
What we do every day  makes the world a better place.
At trade shows customers will go out of  their way to come to our booth
and tell us how much  they love our products.
Because of your hard work,
Apogee has grown and achieved  some amazing milestones.
This year we released several  highly anticipated new products,
including the Cloudburst,
the Guardian and the Insight.
We continue to give our customers quality products,
on time, at a great price.
Not to mention we have  a lot of fun along the way.
[Music]
... and you start to think about what a  company does.
To all my fellow Apogee employees,
Thank you for all your hard work.
We have a lot to be excited for  in this new year.
New projects and new goals
and a whole lot more fun.
To all the members  of the Apogee team
Merry Christmas and Happy New Year!