Hello, my name is Schuyler Smith, and I do technical sales and support here at Apogee
instruments.
And today we're going to talk about the Quickstart guide for the AT-100 µCache with our IRR
sensors — our infrared radiometers — that are good for measuring surface temperatures.
So in this video, we're going to cover where to download the app from, how to connect the
unit, configuring your sensor, and then how to set up logging, and then how to get those
logged values off of your sensor.
So first off, this is where you will find the app.
It's available in the Google Play Store and then the iOS App Store.
You'll just type in Apogee Connect, and that is the icon you're looking for.
And there's some screenshots that we're going to be going through later on the demonstration.
This here is the Quickstart Guide on how to connect it to it and how to add it.
We're going to go through each one of these steps individually.
This is here for a reference.
You can pause the video as needed.
This next one is the Quickstart Guide to begin logging — how to set up the logging intervals.
And again you can pause here.
And then this is the Quickstart Guide to collecting the logs.
So after you've set it up for logging and then you go back to it, how do you get those
logs off so you can view them on your phone?
And so those are the steps there.
And we're going to go through each one of these.
Okay so this is an iOS version of it, and this is what it's going to look like when
you first come in.
It’s blank, okay.
And that has add device right there.
We have our unit µCache here.
We have our IR sensor.
Now, I actually already have one added on.
So that's what it’d look like if you had one added and it’s not connected.
But if you don’t have one at all, then this is what it’s going to look like where it's
blank.
So we are going to go ahead and add it.
And the way we do this is we're going to push the green button here until it blinks blue.
So now it's blinking blue.
Now the app is not looking for it yet, so we have to hit the “+” button.
So we hit the “+” button right there.
Okay and it comes up and it says “uc1074” and we can look back here and see that is
the correct serial number.
So just for convenience I'm going to add this quick platform there.
And now we'll go ahead and add it.
Alright and we see it comes up as an SP-110, which is incorrect.
We know this is a SI-121, and we can look at our cal sheet that came with the unit to
know which model we're connecting, which one we had bought.
So we choose model, but actually it just is any — whether it's an SI-111, 121, 131,
or 1H1.
We just do the SI-1XX.
So we click there.
And now it's asking us for the M coefficients and the B coefficient, which we can see over
here on our sheet this top row and this bottom row.
And it really... as you can see these are the same.
They're just written in different multiples of each other.
So we'll go ahead and just do this.
CRBasic model.
So for the C2 it says we need... so we'll hit clear... and then we'll do 2-0-1-0-1-5.
C1 we hit clear 1-9-3-2-4-7-0-0.
Next one C0.
Clear that out, and this is 3-1-2-5-1-6-0-0-0-0.
Come down here to C2.
Clear that out.
Actually the B coefficients of C2.
So we have 1-6-8-9-.7.
C1, clear that out, 1-6-2-9-0-6.
And then right here we'll hit clear.
Now we need a negative.
So on iOS I just hit the negative button right there and then 1-8-6-8-3-7-0.
Then I hit done.
Now if I want to give it a name as well, and we can just name it right now, let's just
name it, you know, “desk.”
Okay just so we know which one we're talking about.
And then we can add it.
Okay so we see that it's at a desk, and we see that it's giving us some values right
here.
So let's go into it... and there we go.
So now before when it said 24.1 that means I had not loaded the calibration coefficients,
but now it has.
And if we went back out to that screen, now it's finally updated saying okay we're calculating
those values based off what you input.
So let's go into it.
So this is our home screen okay.
It says logs available for collection 2300.
Now in our case we don't believe that.
That must've been previous, so we'll clear that out.
That's fine.
Clear that to zero.
Now down here these values will not update until we get logged data in here.
So you can tell that we don't have any logged data saved to the app to look at, so that
is why it says January 1, 1970.
Let's go to live meter mode first.
So we go to live meter mode.
Now we can get our dynamic graph here that is changing okay.
And based on this, again we're just in here in our studio, and we can see that our temperature
and our surface temperature are about the same.
Now if I put my hand in front of the unit here, so now we're measuring my outside temperature
of my hand, we can see that it's somewhere around 27 to 28 degrees Celsius.
And we can change that.
And the graph is going to change accordingly.
And you can see the sensor body is nearly identical.
I mean that's very small changes.
But obviously just being closer to that did increase that sensor body temperature a little
bit as well.
Now the important thing about these graphs are it is not logging.
This is just live data right now since we came in and pushed live.
If I go out of this and I go back here and then I go back to live meter it has reset
okay, and so now it is logging again just giving us our spot measurements at our current
location.
And again it will just dynamically change with that, and we can see those graphs.
Now if we want to record individual points, this comes down here, and we just hit record
current value.
Okay so I did a time date and then it gave us our surface temperature and then it gives
us our sensor body temperature.
And then if we want to record value here, we can see that surface temperature sensor
body temperature, and we just hit record in values.
Now if we want to export data we hit export.
It comes up with the line item of each one.
And then we just hit that familiar button up there, which is the share button, which
will allow us to just attach that straight to an email and email that to ourselves.
So this is live meter mode.
Perfect to verify that our coefficients are in and perfect to see spot measurements.
Okay so now currently it is updating that average — averaging every second.
Let's say we wanted to go 5 seconds.
So if we go back to home here, and then we click on settings.
And then we're gonna go through each one of these settings.
But first let's look at live data averaging, which is about the third one down here on
settings as we scroll down.
And this is averaging samples over one second.
So if we move this over to 5, and it can go as high as 30 seconds.
Okay so we go to 5 okay, and then we come back here to live meter.
So now it's doing 5-second averaging to get all the way up there to that 28.
So it was increasing because it was still doing, still takes the 5 seconds averaging
before it got up there to the 28.
And we'll see that slowly fall off as well just based on the 5-second averaging.
All right so that is live meter mode, and again it's giving us those same values that
we'd see in live meter right up here under current reading.
So let's go through settings now.
Now just in case you wonder if you entered your coefficients wrong because that was a
lot of numbers, they are always available right here under settings.
So you can pull up your sheet and double-check yourself anytime.
Now if for any reason you lose your cal sheet, just email us at techsupport@apogeeinstruments.com
and we can email this information over to you and you can re-enter it into your µCache.
So everything looks good there.
Logging enabled is turned off currently.
We'll come back to that and turn that on and set that up in a little while.
We talked about live data averaging.
Here's some points here.
The battery level says 100%.
This is not very accurate, so do not trust that level.
You can email us at tech support if you have any questions about your battery levels.
Okay hardware and firmware version okay.
And then match current time.
So what you want is you want the time on your phone to match the time on your logger, and
so you just hit match current time and then it goes through and it just makes sure that
those two sync up together.
Now down here is update sensor firmware.
Always a good idea when it's new to go ahead and click this.
Even if you have the latest it's not going to hurt anything.
So right now it says version on device is 5 — can update to version 5.
I know you can't see that because it's very light on that screen.
But you'll see that on your own.
So if I hit start, then down here you can see that it's going through some things.
It's gone red here.
So it's going through the bootloader.
It's uploading the current version of firmware here.
Okay and then it's going to come down here… and completed.
Now you'll notice it's not complete until the start button goes green because that means
it reconnected to it again after it reset itself.
So we are all set on the firmware.
So that's your basic rundown on settings.
Dark threshold — that doesn't affect IR readings.
And then notify when full — you can click on that so that once those 400,000 data points
have been filled and you login and connect to it, it will give you that notice.
So you can turn that on as you as you want.
Now logging enabled.
So we want to set this up so that it can log.
Now on the QuickStart instructions as we said we recommend 15 minute log times so you can
get your 6-9 month battery life out of the µCache.
If you do less than that then it's going to shorten it.
If you go as short as minutes, then you will reduce the life down to weeks.
If you go to 1 second, it may be 1 week long is all the battery will last on this.
So make sure as you're setting up your logging interval and your sampling intervals that
you're aware of that.
So again we just have this one set up.
I'm going to go out to to 1 minute and I'm going to go logging interval 15 minutes...
so get this on 1 minute get this down to 15 minutes.
All right so it's gonna average twelve samples to average and then it's going to log that
average every 15 minutes.
Okay now until I hit save it is not enabled.
And then once I hit save, it has now saved it and it is now logging internally in here.
Okay so our logging is all set up.
So if we come back here, it says zero for collection because it is waiting to do that
every minute.
Okay so then we deploy it, set it up wherever we want, and then let's come back in an hour
or two hours — whatever our plan is — and we want to collect the logs.
So we go right here to collect logs.
And we want to be on create new because this is the first time we're getting our logs.
Okay and we can set the date... okay… so we can set it.
So let's do June 2020.
Or you can set to the date.
Whatever you want.
Start time, okay, so if we set the start time to… okay... set time to the beginning.
And then if we collect logs up to today it will say
logs remaining 65,000 because from since this sensor’s been used there are 65,000 logs
on it okay.
So it's going to go through and download each one of those.
Now that's going to take quite a while.
And then it will graph it down here below... and then it will graph it down here below,
and you'll be able to see that.
Alright so we'll go ahead and we're going to set that one aside, and then we're going
to look at this one on how to append logs and what logged data would actually look like.
So right here we have it here in front of us, and we can see it's a road temp in the
front.
So what we want to do is we want to connect to it.
So we're going to push the button down until it blinks blue.
Wait for it.
And it said connected right up.
So we see right here, we have our two data points here, our target temperature, and our
sensor body temperature.
we go into it okay.
And it says logs available for collection is one.
But we actually... so if we go to collect logs... now I know that there is actually
a week's worth of data on this where we were measuring the temperature of just our walkway
out front here in the summertime.
So if I go start date.
And I go to create new.
And I can dataset 5.
So let's just say “studio demo” just to name it something.
Okay and then for the start time let's go back a week to Thursday, and then end time
today.
Okay and then I hit collect logs.
Okay I can see that the collect logs... clicked start time... create new… go back a week...
Thursday... let's do midnight...  to today... collect logs…
Okay so it is saying that the only data it has is 3 days.
So the data that I was looking for is no longer... was erased off before the presentation.
But, nevertheless, we have our data points from the last three days as well as the data
point that it had logged in here.
So anytime we want to get new data points, we just hit collect logs, make sure it's on
append to existing, and then we will collect logs.
It says there are currently zero available to log.
And then down here we can see our sensor body temperature.
And then if we want to export that data, we go to view data, we click here, and then we
can go ahead and get those data points.
Alright, well that concludes our Quickstart Guide for the IR sensor with the µCache.
If you have any questions just email us at techsupport@apogeeinstruments.com.
Thank you.