hi I'm mark Blanc with the scientists at
Apogee instruments and I'm here to talk
today about a relatively new product in
Apogee it's a new thermal pile pyrometer
the model number is SP 510 before I talk
about the specifics of the sensor I want
to talk a bit about the motivation for
creating a new thermal pile sensors
Apogee is traditionally manufactured and
marketed silicon cell pyrometers so I
have some data here three different
plots on the graph on the x-axis is
wavelength from about 300 to 2500
nanometers and on the y-axis is either
normalized irradiance or spectral
response the red data set is a clear sky
solar spectrum the blue data set is an
overcast sky solar spectrum both of
these data sets are normalized at 500
nanometers so you can see the shape
comparison how the spectrum changes from
overcast skies and clear skies the black
data set is the spectral sensitivity of
a silicon cell pyrometer and silicon is
sensitive from about 350 to 1100
nanometers so it captures much of the
radiation coming from the Sun but it's
not sensitive to the the wavelengths out
here beyond 1100 nanometers and when we
go from clear sky to overcast sky
conditions often that's where the
largest changes in the spectrum occur so
if a silicon cell sensor is calibrated
to measure accurately under clear skies
as the sky gets cloudier and cloudier
this can do introduce errors and so if
we have these three pieces of
information the clear sky spectrum an
overcast sky spectrum and the spectral
response of this sensor we can actually
predict what the error will be assuming
calibration to one of the conditions so
if we assume calibration to the clear
sky spectrum
the theoretical error prediction for the
overcast sky spectrum is about 10% so
what this means in practice is shown in
these data here and just have two
consecutive days from September of last
year
the black plot if you can see it
underneath the red one there our
measurements from a secondary standard
blackbody thermal pile pyrometer on the
rooftop of the apogee building then the
red plot is data from an Apogee SP 110
silicon cell pyrometer mounted next to
the secondary standard also on the
rooftop of the Apogee building so if we
calculate the error on a daily total
basis the silicon cell matched the
secondary standard no error on the clear
sky day on the cloudy day however there
was about an eight percent error and you
can see the the percent differences in
this lower plot here these are 15-minute
averages then compared relative to the
secondary standard to provide a error
measurement so these data as I mentioned
were collected with an Apogee SP 110
silicon cell pyranometers but you would
find similar results for any silicon
cell pyrometer and it's because the
limited spectral sensitivity of silicon
as we mentioned and showed on the
previous slide it's only silicon is only
sensitive from 350 to 1100 nanometers so
it's not capturing all the changes in
the solar spectrum silicon cell sensors
traditionally have been quite popular
because of their low cost they do work
relatively well as long as people
understand that these errors exist when
going from clear sky to cloudy
conditions silicon cells can be useful
they're often found in state Mesonet
networks for example or in plain of
array measurements for solar panels so
at Apogee we've often tried to to
maximize
formants and minimized price so our real
goal in building the new thermo-pile
pyranometers the SB 510 was to make
something that improved upon these
cloudy or overcast sky airs with silicon
cell centrists but still kept the price
similar to silicon so and I have one
here to display you can see it's small
compact and similarly shape to the
standard Apogee silicon self-censor to
show you how it performs we actually
have data for an Apogee SP 510 for the
exact same two days that we showed for
the silicon cell so again if we compare
daily total errors we get no error on
the clear day and minimal error on the
cloudy day only about 1% you can see
down here that the 15-minute periods the
errors are much smaller for the
thermo-pile sensor just to give you an
idea of some more of the the features
and performance of this particular model
we've had seven replicates of the SP 510
some prototype sensors that have been
deployed continuously on a rooftop for
three and a half years we've been
comparing them to secondary standard
Pyron ometer all of the seven replicates
have been stable none of them have
changed by more than one percent per
year some of the features it has a low
thermal offset less than five watts per
meter squared because it doesn't have
the traditional glass dome of a standard
thermal pile sensor has a diffuser more
like a silicon cell and we can better
thermally bond that to the thermal pile
detector itself and it reduces the
thermal offset all of the SP 510 s come
with internal heaters these can be
controlled by the user so the heater is
optional but the heater can certainly
reduce error caused by precipitation Dew
and frost
and also as I mentioned previously we've
targeted low-cost were offering the this
particular sensor and only 30 percent
more than the standard Apogee silicon
cell heated model the SP 230 so the the
new thermo-pile Perrin ometer from
Apogee instruments is really targeting
markets where silicon cell pyranometers
have been traditionally used but where
higher accuracy is required and also any
application where thermo-pile
pyranometers have been used in ISO
classification is not required
appreciate the opportunity to present
thanks for your time