i'm bruce bugbee president of apogee
instruments and in the next few minutes
i want to show you about
the latest product that we have just
released for
measuring
daily light integral this is it right
here tiny
very rugged
it has a microprocessor in it and
records so it measures the integral of
light through the day
and records it for 99 days really easy
to use you can download the data
we're excited about this project
this product this meter is one that i
have had running
in my conservatory at our house my wife
and i remodeled we built a conservatory
for all my exotic plants and oh god it's
been wonderful i just every day i go out
and check the data on this thing
so let's let me show you
what we have
so this is the meter we call it a dli
meter
daily light integral and i think most
people let me show you what what we mean
when we say that
if we make a little graph
up here let me get some
pen on here i'm going to show this in
yellow
if we make a little graph
and we do dawn to dusk
dusk
and if it's a sunny day
it looks like this
nice smooth curve on a sunny day
what determines plant growth is not the
light intensity to any given moment it's
the integral this whole thing in here
all this area under here
and to do that you need a microprocessor
now lots of apogee meters have that but
they're not as small and compact as
rugged as this new meter shown here
really big
and i'll walk you through this in just a
minute
what if it's a cloudy day that's that's
attempt showing a cloudy day
in green
now we get clouds like this
it still adds that all up day after day
gives you a different number for each
day that's the concept of daily light
integral and why this is so critical to
use
meters historically haven't had this
because you need a microprocessor that
can do integrals inside the meter
apogee's had this before but only in
more expensive meters this is lower cost
so let's take a look at this meter and
and i'll show you what it gives you
this first number right here and big let
me put this back to
um
let's let's go with
blue right here
this is dli daily light integral the
units for this are moles
of photons
per meter squared
per day
now remember
a standard meter gives you
micro moles
per meter squared
per
second
and this is good but you add all those
seconds up in a day
and you add all these micros up and you
get moles
and on a typical day
inside a greenhouse you might get 18.5
moles per meter squared per day of light
this is what determines plant growth
and
i'll show you some charts about how to
interpret that number it ranges in the
winter outside
this dli
might let's put this in an even
different color right here
the winter now i'm recording this in
winter
we might get
eight
moles
per meter squared per day pretty low
summer
we get
60.
huge difference
inside the greenhouse
we might get
four
in the winter and 30 in the summer
because a typical greenhouse blocks half
the light
so that's why you need this for
inside a greenhouse it's also valuable
for indoor agriculture
because it it uses as you can use it as
an immediate meter but also even making
sure you got the right daily light
integral in your greenhouse even though
the lights are on all the time
so there's the first number
and i'll show you in a minute how it
records that
in addition to this
it's also got timers in it and it gives
you photo period under here
in hours
to a tenth of an hour
this helps you understand flowering in
crops
i'm not going to go into short day and
long day plants in this video but
floater period is a big deal
you want to know
if if you have light pollution you want
to know how long your photo period was
especially for medical hemp growers this
is a very critical number to know photo
period
this is because it records it also shows
you days ago right here
so
there's the one of the screens in this
and we'll walk through some of these
screens in just a minute
this shows you the recorded data
but what if we take this
and we want to know what the light is
right now you know i can turn it on
right here one click of the button show
what the light is in the studio it's
plenty bright to shoot this video but
look we're only getting four
micro moles per meter squared per second
in here not enough to grow plants so
what's the next screen look like boom
this is instantaneous
i'm going to put inst for here and this
is dli
over here
you turn it on
there's there's our number 164.6
micro moles per meter squared per second
so this is a rugged portable
accurate
meter for measuring what we call ppfd
at all times and then it has this
additional functionality to record it
for daily like integral
notice in this screen
these these two meters are example of
the screen
notice one other thing this one's blue
this one's gray
this measures this is our classic high
end meter for doing par
photosynthetically active radiation 400
to 700
this meter
is calibrated for sunlight
so it's a way that we can offer you a
lower cost meter
that's perfectly accurate in sunlight
and then you can do calibrations of this
to get other things
this is the same detector as the apogee
original quantum sensor
we just say it's calibrated for sunlight
right here
this is the meter that has a square wave
a step up
to give you 400 to 700 nanometers
now there's one more option on here
if you've listened to other videos you
know that
we do
e
par
because of our research on
photosynthesis we do extended range
power
and we also call this eppf
we also have a version of this meter
that does epar and eppfd
to 750.
this is the emerging new standard for
this and for the best accuracy
this is the meter that
gives you the extended range
this one is 400
to
this is also 400 to 700
but
calibrated for sunlight so there's the
lineup there's the three optional meters
this this you probably can't see these
tiny numbers
this is the dli
and like things go when the number gets
higher it gets more sophisticated this
one is the 500 and this one is model 600
and if you had a microscope you could
see the model number right there in
these uh
meters and it
tells you what it does
let's take a look
and at one of these and how it works in
the screens and i think i can just
demonstrate this to you
chris wants to try and zoom in on this
thing let's see if we can show this
little tiny screen
as big as possible for our
users we get that oh beautiful beautiful
all right turn it on
all you do is push the button it's on
it's giving you
ppfd just like any other meter
now we push the button again
and it's showing days ago zero
what that means is the total so far
today
so it resets it automatically as a timer
resets at night
so it gives you the total so far today
and i just turned this one on so it only
shows a short photo period
if i push the button again or when i do
it goes to one day ago
and
that well this this one that is just
here let's look at this one
here
here's the one in my conservatory the
one they've actually been running
current dli
so far today now let me push it again
one day ago
here in logan utah in my conservatory i
got 9.1
moles a day of photons
now this is pretty good for winter i
have a little bit of supplemental
lighting in there it integrated the
whole thing
the photo period was 14.1
hours because these supplemental lights
ran
longer now let's push it again
there's two days ago
what happened keep going we got 14.4
hours 11.2 that was a nice sunny day
now 9.1 three days ago let me find a
cloudy day there we go
five days ago it was cloudy i only got
4.1 moles a day
because of the clouds in the
conservatory keep going go go go go 99
days of storage
so
do you need to sit there with a pencil
sure you can do that but
there's more
if you take this meter
the bottom has two screws
you can take these out
we send you a little tiny screwdriver
for this
now this is a very well sealed meter
this is an ip65 meter it's exceptionally
rugged
users tell us they're running this
underwater in their salt water aquariums
the reason it all over the place you can
spray it with hoses it's amazing so it
has really good seals
so you take this little post that's
supplied
you can screw it in like this
and pull the bottom out
now there's the batteries there's the
bottom but
right here
chris when we zoom in on this little
thing i think i got a slide of this too
but we'll show it live
there's a little usbc port and we give
you a cable
plug that in
boom
download the data to your computer
so you can download the past 99 days of
data with this cable as soon as you take
the bottom off
then when you've got it all downloaded
pop the bottom back in and you're and
you're good to go with the
screwdrivers now
let me
show you what else you can do with this
little cable
this is made to help mount it notice
at home
i have a little tiny tripod and i mount
it i can move it around nice
but it also comes with a little steak
so if you have
containers
just put her in a container there you go
you're good to go it's mounted
so
a lot of mounting options
let's let's go back to these slides now
and go into some more detail here
we have been testing this thing in many
greenhouses in many places for
both for ruggedness for examples of
mounting and that's what we want to show
you
here here's a nice poinsettia crop
on the top of a tripod in a growers
greenhouse
some lettuce on a tripod right here
another example of mounting here it's on
the end of a cross arm there's lots of
ways to mount this here's that little
stake in a pod and here it is on one of
our
platforms
this picture shows you a bunch of things
it's rugged we've done a lot of a lot of
testing on it
and a lot of mounting options
we have yet to have any failures and
we've been like i say it's
ip65 um
let me review that for a second let's
let's go
back to this slide
so i got room to write
and
i'm going to
attempt to
now i've just put it up here
i
p
is a rating of how resistant it is to
dust and water
we used to think ip50 was good and we
get better seals when we get to ip55
this is 65. this one stands for dust
any kind of dirt getting into it won't
get into it it's very sealed five stands
for water and
so it's two digits that um
the higher you go the better sealed
that's exceptionally well sealed all
right now let's get back to this
here it is here's it is with some
medical hemp in a greenhouse this has
been really helpful to
medical hemp growers let's take a close
look at the screen just to review
instantaneous
the screen goes up it measures
high numbers in micro moles again
micro moles per meter square per second
real simple that's just the standard
mode
if you go to the screen
that recording screen
gives you the dli in moles
photo period in hours to a tenth of an
hour and then how many days ago
you every time you push the button you
go back one day at the end of that you
just put a long push and it resets right
to zero
this meter once you put the batteries in
the meter turns on
and it automatically runs in the
background the meter is always on
the screen will go blank to save battery
power but it's always running that's a
unique feature of this batteries last
six months the two triple two triple a's
very quick to change the batteries every
it saves all the data when you change
batteries
but it's always running in the
background as soon as you put the
batteries in
here's what i just showed you only big
there's the usc cable there's the
batteries they're in the compartment
this is gasketed in the bottom
and then right in here it's hard to see
here is the usb for downloading the
data
this is what the screen looks like once
you download the data it's just a
standard excel file
i don't know if you can see this but
days ago is right here
dli on that day and photo period on that
day
so it tells you what's going on
now another feature that we put into
this
was
30 minute averages
for
light intensity for the past 10 days
because sometimes you want to know is it
clearly cloudy was it was it bright and
sunny
so here's days ago and a 30 minute
average let's do that in blue 30 minute
average of ppfd look at this data if we
graph this data
we get up to 500 so this is a nice sunny
day
if we graph that data to look like this
and we'd get up to 500 in the middle of
the day not a sunny summer day but still
still gives you the average for the day
dli let's let's let me walk you through
the interpretation of that
jim faust dr jim faust one of our great
colleagues
visited the lab has done a lot of work
helping people interpret dli numbers
this is just a generic chart on dli
in moles per day this is moles per meter
squared per day
they didn't put the dli in this chart
remember i showed you some numbers i was
getting about 10 in my greenhouse in the
winter at home
okay here's a list of crops these are
all
flowering ornamentals
white means too low can't grow it
yellow means just barely it's going to
struggle it's going to be floppy
green is better and red is excellent if
you got red you get plenty of light
so at 10 i could grow most of these
crops i would have some
trouble with crops down here not quite
enough light
if this was medical hemp the more the
better we would be we would want to be
up to 20 or even 30 and now we go off
scale we go even higher than 30 with
medical hemp
so some and lettuce we'd like to be up
in this region this doesn't have lettuce
we'd like to be up in this region here
for lettuce 16 to 20 moles a day
this meter tells us if we get there
if you search the internet for
james faust
dli
you will get a series of maps
for average dli for places in the united
states
on average and with the season this is
not inside a greenhouse this is just
outside
here's january dli and man these numbers
are purple i mean up in here this is
just not enough light to grow plants we
put supplemental lights in
down here it's still low
but you can
look at typical dli values on average
from a month at a time
from
this this website there's james faust
right there he's at clemson
and if you follow football you know
about the clemson um
i won't say any more than that but
they've had a good year
um
so
let me
close on this i think i've said
everything i want to
um
why is photo period important
some crops are short day
some crops are long day
and the short day crops need to be below
a threshold medical hemp is a short day
crop typically we want that to be less
than a 12 hour photo period if you're
getting photo periods
13 14 hours you're going to have trouble
getting hemp to flower
long day crops follow flower faster in
long days
and many of our crops are long day
plants wheat is a is a long day crop
so you want long photo periods for those
that's where the photo period comes in
now there's one key thing about this new
dli meter that i got to share with you
that's not so intuitively obvious but we
have come to this
as we look at crops
medical hemp and a lot of other crops in
the field
as you know apogee makes a light bar for
measuring
light penetration to the bottom of the
canopy and if light gets to the bottom
those photons are wasted so you want to
capture the light
but that light bar only works
per second
and you measure above and below the
canopy
but in a greenhouse the sun moves and
through the sky
so how are you going to introdu
integrate that light capture through the
day
well you can use the dli meter to do
that let me give you an example
here's a bunch of crops right we get
leaves all over the place here
um for a crop
if we put and and
we'll put this dli meter up here in
yellow one meter up here
for incoming light and it comes at all
angles through the day
like this
and then we take a second meter
and we put it down here
at the bottom of the crop
now this also integrates the light
through the day
at all angles
so the difference be this is in
this is out
and in minus out
oops that's a minus in minus out
equals absorbed
this is a really powerful technique to
tell how your canopy is doing how much
light capture did it get
and two sensors like this give you the
daily light integral for both of them in
a way that you can't get if you just
have a single meter once a second in
here you want to integrate all the light
so this is a creative use of this that's
been really useful for us in our
research
now following in this same principle
where we're doing capture
how about you have your greenhouse right
here your greenhouse roof
how much what's the
penetration of photons inside your
greenhouse
if you mount one out here
and you have one inside this doesn't
have to be straight above just above the
greenhouse
the ratio of these this is the same math
in minus out equals absorbed
and you'll be surprised at how much
greenhouses absorb a typical greenhouse
can absorb half of the photons and then
people go up and clean the glass and
they go oh my god you know we should
have done that years ago
this really helps to make sure your
greenhouse is
clean
it's the same thing with
even electric lights do you need to
clean electric lights getting a ratio of
in and out
integrated through the day so both of
these have been really useful for this
meter
so
i'm going to close on this slide
here's the three models the
400 the 500
and the 600
if you search for apogee dli meter
you'll come right to this page
this is an exciting development we've
been refining this for
some time
to get peak accuracy and peak
functionality we've had prototypes out
with a lot of people to give us feedback
on how to do this
for me this is one of the most exciting
things we've
introduced in a while
i think it's really going to help our
users
let me mention one final thing
if you want to know the level up from
this
the light oh during the night and more
detailed data
you still can buy our micro cache with
sensors and download that data to your
phone
this gives you more detailed data than
the dli meter
but it's it's
also more money too so there's still
multiple options for measuring this
thanks for listening we'll pick this up
in the next video
you