In the past when measuring air temperature and humidity in remote
locations,
researchers have always had to sacrifice accuracy to conserve power, using
naturally aspirated radiation shields that can produce temperature errors up to 3 degrees Celsius.
To solve this problem
Apogee Instruments proudly introduces the TS-100 low-power aspirated radiation
shield. Representing a breakthrough in design and performance by yielding the
same consistent and accurate measurements as the best aspirated
shields on the market, while drawing only 80 milliamps and as low as 28 milliamps on
low power mode. How is this possible? It's all about the design. The internal
variable speed fan uses pulse width modulation and can be configured to
reduce power usage at certain weather conditions, while the shield body
features a coanda inlet and venturi contour, to enhance airflow, allowing
accurate measurements in both strong winds and still air. Finally, the shield
is manufactured in high precision injection molding process using geloy
plastic, which offers low thermal conductivity, maximum weather durability,
and a glossy white finish for high reflectivity. The TS-100 is compact,
lightweight, and rugged allowing for easy and extended deployment in the harshest of
climates. For measurements right out of the box, every sheild comes standard with
a precision thermistor, and is designed to accommodate PRTs and humidity
probes if desired. To learn more about the Apogee TS-100 aspirated radiation
shield visit us on the web at www.apogeeinstruments.com.