hello my name is Skyler Smith I do
technical sales and support here at
Apogee instruments and we're here to do
another frequently asked questions video
today we're going to talk about the BTM
3000 update instructions the reason why
we have the BTM 3000 update is we have
switched the way we do the format on the
software and therefore and the firmware
and so because of that say for example
it did work on an old computer but then
you downloaded the latest BTM 3000 and
it's not working on your new computer
then you would need to do these firmware
instructions to get it to work
appropriately so here's a few reasons
why you might be interested in this
video did your sensor work on a
different computer and it's not working
now does your sensors show connected but
with no serial number and there's a few
other small things in there you may be
able to pick up if and figure out why
your sensors are not working and we'll
get it working for you so this is what
the original software looked like the
original format had your micro mul
reading right there said biotech marine
this is what it currently looks like if
this is what your screen shows with your
micro mol per meter squared per second
reading here and you're showing
connected here you're set you're all
done you don't need to worry about any
sort of firmware or software upgrade
you're you're there you're good to go
you can pause or turn off the video now
if however you like everyone else
you probably see something more like
this where you're reading 0.0 here and
you're showing device not connected here
or you're showing connected here but 0.0
will cover both of those issues by the
end of this video
before we go on though I do need to
stress this point the firmware update
has to happen on a PC and it can't
happen on a Mac now once we've updated
the firmware on your sensor on a PC
you'll you're good to go on a Mac it's
going to work great the new software
works great on a Mac but you just can't
upgrade the firmware on it that has to
happen on a PC so friends neighbor
whoever you need to borrow a PC from to
update it and then you'll be set to go
on your own Mac
now what I've done here is I've outlined
all the instructions this is the
all-inclusive troubleshooting
instructions for you to go through and
I've put these up here and you can see
I'm scrolling through them fast you can
just pause where if you want to see
something and go back to it we've also
listed these instructions on our website
under the technical support page so this
is just to give you something to refer
back to if for whatever reason the
situations I go through don't match up
with yours perfectly you can come back
to one of these steps and it will answer
for you alright so let's go ahead and
jump into our demonstration so here we
are blank screen well we need to get the
latest version of BTM 3000 we have here
an old sensor that has the old firmware
on it and it would work just fine on the
old software but that's not our example
our example is the latest software that
we need to upgrade the firmware on where
do we find it Apogee instruments comm
there we are we come across to the
support tab then we come down here to
where it says software downloads click
there and then we'll come over to
biotech marine click right there
and we have our manual and then our two
versions of course we're doing the
firmware update so we're on PC version
we'll click there a pretty basic way for
it to download files here down here in
the corner of our internet browser it's
going to take a few seconds for it to
get I think it's the file size is like
40 megabytes or thereabout
so once that gets loaded there then
we'll click on it and go through the
install instructions so there we go we
have our dot exe file open that up and
then our install shields is going to
show up right here in the middle pretty
basic instructions we'll just go through
this we hit next yes I accept the terms
in the license agreement next yes I want
to install up there
Program Files x86 BTM 3000 install yes
I'm okay
installing this so we click through
these alright now if you had a slightly
older version of the software it may not
have come up with this launch driver
installation we do want to make sure
that's checked for all the latest
version so looks like this we hit finish
yes we're okay with that so we will let
it do if we click right here we can see
device driver installation wizard all
right so we click Next
it's installing our drivers for us this
is excellent
we hit finish we're done that part is
done now we have the BTM 3000 software
so let's open that up and see what we
see pull this up there we go again this
is probably why you're watching the
video cuz you follow those steps and
you've landed here what do I do now
alright so first thing is let's just
close the software for now and we need
to pull up our device manager so there's
a couple ways to do this through control
panel
I like Windows 10 I just click down here
and type in device manager pops right up
I open it up here now we can see it says
BTM 3000 USB sensor so it's trying to
recognize it but it has a yellow dot
okay so in our example this is what
we're dealing with so what I'm going to
do is right-click on him and I am going
to uninstall and it's going to say are
you sure you want to delete the driver
software for the soft for this device
answer's yes
I make sure that's checked I click OK he
is gone alright he is out of there so if
we open BTM 3000 we can see it says
would you like to update your firmware
yes I would so we hit OK and it comes up
now if yours did not
come up the first time there have been
instances where you just have to close
out of the software and then disconnect
reconnect your sensor and then open the
software again for some reason some
computers take twice but once you get to
this screen where it after you says
would you like to do the firmware update
and you click yes then you click on USB
quantum version 2 the correct version is
version 2 this will work for you there
are a few instances who need version 3
but you'll want to contact us if you
think you're one of those cases everyone
else it's version 2 if once you have
your sensor reading if it's reading in
the 5,000 area it means you clicked
version 3 you need to just update your
firmware to version 2 and we can show
you a couple of those steps later on as
well so we click version 2 click open
let it do its firmware update all right
so it's asking us to reconnect the
device if we hit OK and pull it apart
and reconnect it the first thing we will
notice alright again
we're not showing any progress here
let's close it and reopen the software
would you like to do the update now I
said you might have to do it twice we're
going to have to do it twice do open let
this come up here let it do that
firmware update
now you'll notice that when it was done
correctly
he says USB serial device come three
over here in device manager that's why I
like to leave device manager running in
the background all right so if we hit
okay then it automatically comes up all
right please enter the serial number we
know our serial number is 11 66 we can
find that on the white tab right here
next to it it says BTM 3011 66 I hit OK
comes up device connected to serial
number 11 66 all right so now for those
of you who have 0.0 but your device is
connected this step is for you it's also
on those pages before it said important
last step number 11 so what we do is we
click here on the gear click on
calibration so under multiplier
we're in caps lock we're going to type
in factory and hit enter and then I'll
will allow us to overwrite permanent
calibration if we hit 0.0 you know
overwrite you also see it will allow you
to update firmware if for whatever
reason you tried other steps and you
couldn't update the firmware but you can
connect and it will allow you to update
the firmware here this is a way to do it
as well so I overwrite and then I click
Save we give it a few seconds to load
and then it will begin reading
there we go 5.6 so that's what we're
reading with our lights in here is six
so those are the steps to update the
firmware on your BTM 3000 and to get it
to work with the latest software if you
have any questions feel free to email us
or call us at tech support here thank
you very much