so today I want to share a talk with you
that I recently did at the annual
meeting of the American Society of
agronomy which was in Baltimore Maryland
I was asked by the society to give a
talk on Serendipity in science how that
occurs
how things how we
accidental discoveries in science and
how they impact our science
and of course my immediate thought when
they asked me to give a Talk about
serendipity and Sciences so what do you
would you think my whole career was just
based on log pad luck that's why
by here talking and but they said no no
no we don't think that but but you've
had some significant discoveries and
we'd like you to talk about how those
came about
so
I decided to title my talk Chance favors
the prepared mind and I've always loved
this quote I first read it when I was in
graduate school and I thought I want to
dedicate my career to having a prepared
mind so when those chances come along
they're a big deal
so this this seems to make pretty
intuitive sense but what's a prepared
mind really mean
you know an analogy that I thought of is
what if we said
Chance favors the prepared athlete
well that would make perfect sense
athletes spend a long time preparing
their minds and bodies for that one
catch in some great game
but that didn't that wasn't luck that
was a lot of skill honed by years of
practice the same principles relate to
this with Scientists
the prepared mind means learning all the
principles of your discipline the
equations that make up your discipline
the theory the models the literature in
your discipline it means really becoming
a true expert in your discipline that's
what prepared mind means
and then when you come along and see the
odd things you're prepared to say hmm
that could be something right there and
you follow it up lesser people might say
now that was bad day to just forget it
and move on
so this quote came from Louis Pasteur he
lived in the 1800s he was a great
philanthropist everybody knows about him
the germ theory of disease came from
pasture he was he was always working
with sterile systems it's amazing
stories of his life
um
but
when he wrote about this he got the
Nobel Prize when he wrote about this he
didn't have five succinct words to
describe this principle here's what he
wrote well even before I get to what he
wrote let's let's take a look and
what a prepared mind might be
here's some data right so this is an X
plot an input variable here's why a
plant response you get data like this
now we would normally
say the data like that this is this is a
common
principle for a lot of things so the
more you get vax this is non-linear you
make measurements you get this point
right here
the first inclination is that must be
bad just throw it out but you measured
it what what happened with that let's
see if I can get back to this you
measure it just throw it out we have
statistical principles that say this is
so far off the line just forget about it
you can we can throw it out but there's
an example of something that might be
real
let's take this out here for a second
that little line right here
and we're going to go back to this
now some people might take this and they
have a high speed computer
and they'll attempt to fit this
with a 10th order polynomial that looks
like that and now you got to come up
with the principle that says right here
there's a big inhibitory effect of X on
y so just that simple data set alone
gives you a lot of examples of the
challenges we go through and we make
good measurements very careful
measurements and we're sorting good data
from bad data and and looking for those
anomalies that lead to Great
breakthroughs
pasture didn't
say these five concise words
here's what he originally wrote for his
Nobel Prize
um
in fields of observation Chance favors
the prepared mind but look at this it's
this is true in all Fields not just an
observation so
we can edit that out Chance favors only
the prepared mind and not only that we
don't need the word only Reddit that out
too now we get to his quote so pasture
like a lot of people had good editors as
as if stuff to make the concise
statements and that's part of science
the conciseness that leads to new
breakthroughs
so
we often think scientists must say when
they have a grade through they say ah
Eureka I found it but that's really not
how science works you rarely get to
something you expected
the most common phrases that's funny and
that's this part that leads to these
great breakthroughs
this came from Isaac Asimov for this
quote and here's a book that I've had on
my shelf for years Serendipity
accidental discoveries in science and
this is loaded with examples of
and and happy accidents that occurred in
science it's a it's an interesting book
it's still in print so let's let's take
a deeper look at this
in 1963
Science magazine had an editorial and
the conclusion of the editorial was
Serendipity is not a substitute for hard
work and that's a gold standard in this
they were being criticized you should
just fund the scientists that are lucky
yeah there's not lucky scientists
there's ones that have hard work and
have prepared Minds so they were pushing
back on this
there's an old phrase the harder I work
the luckier I get yeah great but look
hard work is in here work is in here
work is something you don't like doing
and in order to do a lot of it and feel
good about it and be creative
you got to do the stuff you like doing
you have to like what you do so I always
say just this isn't work this is
something I enjoy and work is something
I don't enjoy
that's one of the keys to doing a lot of
something and then being able to find
the pick out the happy accidents that
occur
so
let's get rid of this
here's another big thing about
statistics statistics is not going to
lead us to Great breakthroughs it helps
us determine mathematical probabilities
but I love this quote if your experiment
needs statistics you ought to have done
a better experiment this came from
Ernest Rutherford Nobel Prize in
chemistry you can believe he wanted
clean experiments where we didn't need a
lot of reps and he didn't need a lot of
Statistics to sort out his results and
certainly in our research here we try to
do simple clean experiments so we don't
need a lot of replicates
so
the next section of this talk is about
this intersection between Theory and
measurement and we get to a point right
there
knowledge is really the extent to which
Theory agrees with measurements now
theory is another term for models and
models are equations and if models
predict something and that's what we
measure we get confident that we have it
right
this is in this room up here on a board
by our clock to keep people thinking
about this and really this quote in here
says never believe a measurement unless
it can be substantiated with Theory
and conversely the degree of confidence
we can have is the degree to which these
two things agree
so theory is what you learn in school
theory is what prepares your mind and
measurements what you do in the lab and
you look for when they converge now to
pick out these serendipitous
measurements we need wisdom so it's a
three-way interaction between all three
of those things that gets us there
so here's another quote
that's just striking
everybody believes a measurement except
the person that made it now the person
that made it knows how hard it was to
make that measurement and they not sure
they got it right but everybody else
thinks oh no no it's measured it's fine
it's it's the gold standard
the corollary to this is nobody believes
a model
except the person who made the model and
the modelers are always saying I have a
model I have a model look it's right and
people say no no so the bottom line of
this we should believe measurements less
and we should believe models more they
put equal weight on both of these to
guide us now the place where I think
what I think much of this came from is
Back to the Future where they're making
a lot of measurements to go into the
future and they make a lot of models
back and forth so it's a nice corollary
to this quote
so
let's see we'd get this off the slide
the analogy I
have used to emphasize this link between
Theory and measurement is getting to the
top of a house
with two ladders and the rules of
science say you can only have one foot
on each ladder and one ladder is
measurement One ladder is theory and you
get to the top of the house fastest when
you put one foot on one rung and back
and forth and back and forth and up you
go on the ladder
if you try to do only measurements you
maybe could get there hopping on one
foot on the ladder but it'd be awfully
hard and only Theory hopping on one foot
would be awfully hard now another part
of this is if you want to be really safe
you should tie your ladders together so
that you the whole thing is more safe
and that's a that's a good because we
want to link Theory and measurement
intimately back and forth here's some
examples of that
here's Theory there's measurement let's
take these off of here
um
back and forth back and forth and here
we go in up up up up
out
but boy they're far apart and this takes
a while to get up there what if we more
intimately link them now we have a
faster progress because they're closer
together back and forth and then finally
they become one and the same in the same
person Theory measurement evaluate that
makes for excellent progress I want to
further emphasize this with some
pictures
here's Theory Albert Einstein all he
ever needed to do research was a box of
chalk and and it's a wonderful I'd like
to be his department head just Bobby
needing another box of chalk this year
for my research budget
here's our Theory we do all kinds of
empirical replicates in the field that
look like this
Theory and measurement Excellence
emerges from continuous coupling we move
these together it's continuously coupled
and we make faster progress we sort out
the bad data from the good and we
improve our models by doing this
so often in research
we get this out of balance and we do a
lot of empirical measurements and we
have very inadequate Theory to explain
them
in some Labs the reverse is true
and we have a lot of theory but not very
much data this often happens in climate
science where we have a lot of models we
rely heavily on models and
just a little bit of data but in both of
these cases it's out of balance and it
doesn't lead to the fastest progress in
science
now let's switch to a little bit of data
that we have here in our lab
this is a graph of colors of light at
night and how they affect flowering in
cannabis
so we always say a green light is safe
if you want to work at night always use
green light because that has no effect
on plants
don't use red or blue
this is days after start and flower
diameter so the steeper the line
the faster the plants flowered so if
they were completely dark
they flowered fast if we gave them blue
light and I can show that in Blue on
here
they followed equally fast so in this
study blue light was safe no effect look
at red light red lights the opposite of
green flowering was inhibited by red
light
right here
and the flower diameters were smaller
because the plants perceived red light
at night here's the point they'll get
the green green in this study was just
effective as red so
it's not the case that green light is a
safe light plants perceive the green
light
how can that be if plants reflect green
light how can that be so potent that's
why we think it's safe because they just
reflect it
I'm going to put up here a diagram of
how well light penetrates plant leaves
green light is reflected but that also
means it penetrates deeper into leaves
this is a diagram of the cross section
of a leaf
here's the top of the leaf here's the
bottom of the leaf and this distance is
just like one millimeter it's way blown
up
blue and green
are absorbed very quickly in the surface
layer
the green photons hit
and they bounce around and they
penetrate the leaf and this means the
green photons get to the site of
perception
of the light which in this case is the
phytochrome molecule and even though
those photons don't have such a big
effect
they're not zero and they're getting to
the site of perception so
this only came from our understanding of
principles we said well this can't be
correct you know just throw the green
light data out no it led to a new
principle and here's the paper that
resulted from it improving the
predictive value of phytochrome
photoequilibrium in a consideration of
spectral Distortion in a leaf so this
data led to this paper
now having said this green light is
still the best light to use because our
eyes are really sensitive to Green Light
it's it's so use green light if you have
to work at night but try to use a
minimal amount of green light it is not
completely safe
let's take another example
this is weighing vysimeters
in our
Greenhouse
go back to this these are load cells we
weigh plants we measure transpiration
with this here's a growth chamber and
here's this is cotton on these and and
corn on these Chambers so we can make
very accurate measurements of how open
the stomates are and how much
transpiration there is let's look at the
data
this was day and night two days
transpiration rate which is right here
in purple now that is and let's see if I
can show this in purple right here
it's low at night not zero here's zero
right there
high in the day low at night high in the
day
this is our measurements just like that
it's the model conductance that's how
open the stomates are that's shown in
green
the stomates open in the day and close
at night but look they're not completely
closed at night
and this number right here is about 0.4
open and wide open and the day is about
0.9
so in this data the stomates are about
half as open at night as they are in the
day
the reason this is higher than this is
it's very humid at night uh and the and
the leaves are cooler so that that
transpiration should be much less
because there's not much of a driving
gradient
conductance is the ratio of driving
gradient to transpiration
but this is remarkable
now this data was collected some years
ago in Cotton but we know this also
happens in cannabis which is a very big
deal because we have a lot of flux of
water at night when the stomachs are
supposed to be closed and they're open
we have to run dehumidifiers or we get
plant disease all the textbooks say
stomates close at night and that
sentence in textbooks is just wrong
except
if we give the plants some water stress
a minor water stress
they quickly start to close their
stomachs at night in this same data had
we stressed these plants a little bit
with water now the conductance would be
down here
it looks like this
so
If plants like like many of our cannabis
if they're grown with no water stress
they don't close their stomates at night
it's a big big deal
look at this curve this was in electric
lights let's get rid of these lines here
this is in electric lights and I'm going
to have to do that there we go
um
the lights in this
were a square wave
they came on and looked like that this
is not sunlight it's an electric right
all of our principles say that
transpiration rate should follow the
light it should go up and high and come
down and instead it's a curve in here
and it happened every day it should have
been a square it's a curve in here our
models don't predict that there's some
measurements in here didn't match the
models when we got this data we very
quickly
went to multiple plants
let's go right here and looked at this
here's a square wave of light all plants
do this
in the afternoon it's like they get
tired and they and they this is
transpiration rate or this is stomodo
conductance they start to close their
stomates in the afternoon and they don't
even open them until about 11 o'clock in
the morning it's a just remarkable that
plants do this and it took controlled
environments to be able to study this
this has now look at this here's these
lines are close to zero down here
because the plant's got a little bit of
water stress
um this has big implications for
Designing air conditioning systems and
humidity and Disease Control these
stomachs are wide open in the middle one
third of the day but it takes them a few
hours to get there and a few and they
close their stomachs for a few hours in
the afternoon
now let's go back to another fascinating
thing about this
this is
a
well-watered cotton plant
and a two water stress cotton plants the
same thing happens in cannabis here's
the opening took a long time to open and
then they started to gradually close
there's night right there
but look at these drought stress plants
they also take a while to open they stay
open maybe about half this is a
measurement of how drought stressed they
are but look what happens here they go
nuts there's noise that is not noise the
whole plant is cycling for water it
opens its snowmates oh we overshot in
the closed them and open and closed open
and closed we've seen this repeatedly in
Plants this is anomalous data this is
the kind of data you go huh that's funny
and then you find out you can repeat it
this has big implications for design of
controlled environments where we spend a
lot of money taking the humidity out of
the air
um let's get rid of those these
and we'll do those lines are off
now let's move to another huge area for
us here in the crop physiology lab and
my colleagues this is far red photons
you can just barely see far red right
here
we call these the Forgotten photons
because they're on the edge of our
vision we can barely see them
we've done a lot of work with far red
photons and their photosynthetic value
this work was done with my long-term
colleague Mark Van ersol at the
University of Georgia he was here last
summer with us we recorded videos with
us he's just been a joy to work with
he's now got an endowed chair position
at the University of Georgia and Chu
young Jen who is a very talented
scientist she got her PhD with Mark then
she came to Utah to work with me for a
postdoc she is now an assistant
professor at Texas A M University
together the three of us have published
six six seven papers on this and I want
to review this evidence because it has
the potential to be
a profound implications for all of plant
biology
here's lettuce
no far red and 10 percent of the photons
is far red now you don't have to be a
rocket scientist to see those far red
photons they're doing amazing things to
this plant
some of this is due to what we call the
shade avoidance response they think
they're in shade so they just spread out
they spread their leaves bigger that's
not surprising we've known that forever
but with careful measurements of
photosynthesis we have shown that some
of this profound effect is also due to
far red photons
that is a big deal because for years and
years we've said far red photons do not
cause photosynthesis
so it's an amazing claim to say they do
when we have amazing claims
we should always fall back on this
mantra
extraordinary claims require
extraordinary proof now this was
popularized by Carl Sagan and Cosmos but
this is an old saying
so now what I want to do is show you the
extraordinary proof
for far red and photosynthesis
this is gonna it's a very concise
summary but this started in 2017 with
Journal of plant physiology Mark and Shu
young in Georgia studied the light
reactions of photosynthesis and very
clearly showed these far red photons had
a beneficial effect they followed it up
with laser diodes a year later published
another paper physiologic a plantarum
which showing that the wavelengths of
far red up to about 730 nanometers were
clearly helpful in the light reactions
then
after that Shu young came here to our
lab in Utah where we have a whole series
of whole plant gas exchange Chambers so
we can measure photosynthesis on whole
canopies
Shu young and I published a paper in
2020 in plant cell and environment one
of our top journals
far red photons have equivalent
efficiency to traditional photosynthetic
photons implications for redefining par
par is photosynthetically active
radiation
we kept working on this in longer term
whole plan studies published a paper on
Far red photons in Frontiers in plant
science so it more accumulating evidence
more papers and now our colleagues are
getting into this and there's other
papers from other Laboratories showing
far red photons have photosynthetic
value note that all these papers are
pretty recent papers
now there's one thing that's critical
here
and that's the mechanism for this
here's my diagram of how the light
reactions of photosynthesis work
the Stark Einstein loss is one Photon
excites one electron
this is how solar panels work this is
how photosynthesis work a photon comes
in
excites this guy this electron gets
excited and then it's passed down this
Mill this turns it makes ATP makes
energy another Photon hits this guy boom
and other electrons excited so it's a
two-stage process
for a photo system two comes first in
photosystem one comes second this is
because we discovered this first and
then we later found out there's two
um water gets split right here to oxygen
but here's the key we have known for a
long time that far red photons excite
this photoreceptor in photosystem one
and that is called the Emerson
enhancement effect it's been known for
50 years but it's been little studied
until now when we got far red LEDs we
can do more rigorous studies of this
um you can pause this and look at this
diagram but this is the this is electron
transport in photosynthesis but
simplified to show electrons getting
excited it takes four elect four four
photons here and four photons here
either
classic or far red and
it takes eight photons to get through
the whole thing and fix CO2
so
we have extended this now
to plants in sunlight
not just electric light sunlight and
very recently July 2022 we published a
paper
photosynthesis in Sun and shade
surprising importance of far red this
extends the work to sunlight and this is
a new phytologist is one of our top
journals
we
hope that this will help people
understand the value of far red light
which is a very big deal in the world of
cannabis because far red photons are
very efficient they're long wavelength
and they're very photosynthetically
efficient
here's the classic McCree curve for
photosynthetic efficiency
it the our definitions it cuts it off
here these photons are not very many and
this curve is pretty accurate they drop
pretty fast over here we got 700 there's
the classic definition now we add this
recent work this curve has a bulge over
here so it looks like this the and it
goes to 750. the old definition is
called par
photosynthetically active radiation the
new definition is called epar extended
photosynthetically active radiation
apogee makes a sensor to measure epar
and it's a better predictor of
photosynthesis than the old par
so on a close here this is a diagram
done by a Utah artist James Christensen
and I just love it this is what we do in
science to get serendipitous discoveries
we take our
equipment out and sometimes their Labs
look like a bad day in a Spaghetti
Factory around here we take it out for a
drive and test it and see what happens
and if you want to know how to get
Serendipity and science
build equipment homemade doesn't cost
much and take it out for a drive and see
what happens and be prepared for
anomalous findings
thanks for listening I hope this
inspires you to go on and make a lot of
measurements in science