well my name is Skyler Smith here at
Apogee instruments and today we're going
to talk about the MC 100 we're gonna do
a demonstration with it we're going to
talk about how to take measurements with
it how to save samples how to read the
different units the CCIE units the SPAD
units and the micro moles per meter
squared of chlorophyll depending on
specific species and then also a generic
species we have for that how to change
the meter to read for those and then how
to get all the save data off the meter
onto the computer and we're going to
briefly touch on if you want to add the
GPS module as an add-on feature so to do
that we do need the overhead camera so
we're just gonna change that
so that'll just take a second to come up
here as that comes up you can see right
here in front of us we have the MC 100
here's the full unit okay and we're
zoomed in tight so we can see the screen
because we're going to go through the
settings on it so first thing we're
gonna hit power it's going to beep and
that's how we know it is on we see three
things right off the bat we see run data
and save and then we see our time and
date stamp up here now if this is not
correct you want to change this then the
first thing you want to click on is
system and then you want to go to setup
and then it's going to tell us our time
date and the format it's in if we want
to edit that right there and then as a
note this is a 24 hour clock so we'll go
ahead and hit exit there now we first we
want to set this up we need to first set
up how we want to save the files and
then we want to set up how many averages
we're going to take and then we're going
to set up the units so first thing how
do we set up the files so we go to run
and then we go to setup and the first
thing that comes up is save data and
data file well let's go ahead and edit
that so we hit edit and then when yes is
highlighted so we want to save data yes
but maybe you want to rename that data
file or change it to something else or
understand why it came up with that so
if we hit over it comes up with the
file name manager now right now it says
use existing file well we don't want to
do that we don't have any files on here
next is enter a new name if we wanted to
just go ahead and type out a new name we
could do that there next is edit a
default name and then the last one is
used date as a name so for our example
we're going to go ahead and use the date
as the name so let's accept that and
then it comes up with this and we have
the year first followed by the month
followed by the day followed by the hour
and so this looks perfect it's how we
want to save for our demonstration day
so we're going to hit accept
all right so we have all of that set up
our file name the next thing is if we
want to do averaging so there are three
different test measurement ways you can
do it
you can do it in multi-point average as
it's showing right now you can do it in
one point no averaging and you can do
multi-point standard deviation so let's
start by talking about one point no
averaging this means that every time
that you take a measurement on a leaf
that it's just saving every measurement
every time you point is just taking your
measurement it's not doing any averaging
for you and so this average number of
points and recorded point data they do
not apply in that in that feature
multi-point standard deviation and this
one it will take your standard deviation
as an average of between 10 and 30
readings so you have to change this
number of a point to between 10 and 30
now on this last one record point data
if you have this in no right here then
it means that it is only going to save
your standard deviations your your
average standard standard deviation if
it's in yes it's going to save every
individual point as you measure and as
well as that it's going to save your
your average standard deviations now as
a note on that feature if for any reason
your measurements are different are
larger than two times the standard
deviation then the instrument itself is
going to throw
that outlier and cause you to take
another measurement asked you to take
another measurement so just be aware of
that if that happens to you so in our
example let's do multi-point averaging
okay so it's and it's going to do
multi-point averaging it's going to ask
you how many points to average and then
record point data on the record point
data if you put no it's only going to
record the averages for you and if you
put yes it's going to record every
single point when you take a measurement
as well as the averages so if we click
enter here and then if we click over it
will ask us the average number of points
we can push up or down here to get the
average number of points higher or lower
for our example today 3 is fine and then
record point data yes that is fine as
well
so we can just hit enter next on the
menu is this data echo output as off and
GPS data logging off so the data echo
output refers to the rs-232 which is the
port on the bottom of the sensor you can
see it right here and so if you had an
rs-232 to a serial cable and you wanted
it to be sending data out through that
as well as logging data on the unit
itself you would have that on and then
you'd have that set up if for more
details on that just contact us here at
tech support and then same on the second
one the GPS data logging you would also
plug in to that same q 32 port some sort
of GPS module and then you'd be and then
you'd click on on this menu and then
you'd have that set up so again for more
details on that just contact us here and
we'll tell you what we have found that
has worked for us next use custom
measurements so what it's asking us here
is what is the unit that we want to read
our chlorophyll in we talked about we
have CCI units we have Spade units and
then we have units of chlorophyll in
terms of micro moles per meter squared
so when it says use custom measurement
it says know right now that means saying
no means it is in CCI unit
so for our example let's go ahead and
start with doing it in terms of
chlorophyll of micro moles per meter
squared and for our example let us pull
up our heart leaf IV our little
philodendron core datum here and so we
want to do some chlorophyll readings off
of him and let's start by doing generic
readings first the generic chlorophyll
table so to change this we go to edit we
change that to yes and then when I push
the side button it's going to ask us
which one and these are all the custom
tables it comes loaded with but since
philodendron core datum is not listed in
here we just want the generic so we'll
go ahead and hit generic hit OK accept
and now it's saying use custom units yes
use generic all right
so we are all set we are ready to start
taking measurements so we click measure
and it says clear sample area and hold
down the arm so we will go ahead and
just hold down the arm all right he's
all set so now for our example we'll
just go ahead and come over here pick a
leaf and we can see that it says average
point and it gives us the reading for
one so we'll do that on the second one
and we can see what it reads after the
second one and then the third one and it
gives us a double beep saying it has
taken an average so here it is giving us
our average and then telling us it's in
that generic so for our data let's go
ahead and do three more
okay so we have our two averages using
the generic alright well I wonder how
our Hartley 5e also reads in span units
so let's change it to sped units and
save some averages so we hit exit here
we go into setup and then we hit up and
it has used custom measurement yes so we
hit edit and then if we hit over now we
just need to go down until we get this
bad so we just we will scroll through
all the different species we could click
on that we have coefficients saved in
for micro moles of chlorophyll per meter
squared so we'll come down till we get
to SPAD there it is right there we'll
accept so this is telling us custom
measurements yes Spade units so if we
hit exit now we hit measure and it's
going to say this this file already
exists do you want to overwrite it or do
you want to append it well we just want
to append it because we're just taking
the same we're measuring the same plant
same leaves we were just doing in a
different unit so we're going to hit a
pend we're going to come up here we're
going to take a reading and there we go
telling us the average point one it's
bad right here and if for some reason
there was a measurement error we could
just hit delete and then it would ask us
to take that average point two again so
three beeps tells us it did the average
and it's telling us across the top one
that it saved that one because we said
save every save a sample every three
and here we go so we have two of those
now now let's do it in CCI units so
because we've saved that our plant here
with the generic coefficients
we've saved them as bad units now let's
save them as CCI so go to exit we go to
setup we push up use custom units no so
we do push there enter when yes it's
highlighted we push up no enter it's now
saying use custom units no and when that
says no that means we are now reading in
CCI units so we hit exit we hit measure
it's gonna say you're on that same file
do you want to override our appendant
well in our example we just want to
append it so we'll just hit there and
then we are good to go
and that's our first reading our second
reading and our third reading in CCI and
again just for uniformity we will go
ahead and take three more ok so we now
have all these measurements saved on
here so now we want to get them onto the
computer so we get out of the test menu
here and we hit back and we see where it
says data so in our example we need to
just take the USB that's that's supplied
with it and plug it in to the usb on the
model right here on the side so we do
that and then we hit data and it says
USB link active so now we need to turn
on our computer here
and we can see in our example that it
comes up just like a flashdrive would
with the information here and so we see
all these tables come up on the file
these are all the save tables to the
unit and then right here is our file so
if I double click here my text documents
automatically open up as notepad however
you have your text documents and so we
can see the time date stamp across the
top and we can see that we're doing
averaging over here we can see these are
our generic coefficients for micro moles
of chlorophyll we see our three readings
here our average our three readings here
and our average and then we see our
spade units here the average sped units
an average and then we see our CCI units
and our CCI units and our average so you
can see that that comes in a CSV file so
that's really easy to drop into a
spreadsheet for more analysis as needed
with that that concludes our
demonstration of the MC 100 how to take
measurements if you have any questions
feel free to put them below in the video
in the comment section and don't forget
to subscribe to all of Apogee
instruments videos thank you
you