I'm Bruce Bugbee, president of Apogee instruments. Today I'd like to talk about
chlorophyll meters especially the non-destructive chlorophyll meters
that are vary widely used by a number of people. We'll go through a little bit of
the history of it how they work and then the advances that have been made over
the years. So in the 1980s Minolta came out with this
meter it was made by the scientific products analysis division at Minolta
a they use their acronym, they call it a SPAD meter. Sometime people
begun to think S.P.A.D. is synonymous with chlorophyll and it is not it's an
acronym for a company. That was the first meter. Then some years later Optisciences
came out with this meter.
It has some advantages over the Minolta meter, little bigger area to
average leaves and then recently Apogee instruments came out with this meter
which has some fundamental advances over the other types of research-grade meters
for chlorophyll. So let's take a look at what those differences are. The first
thing is if we draw a leaf it's full of cells and these cells are full of
chlorophyll. If we shine a light on this leaf and we put a detector down here we
can get the transmitted light through the leaf. This is pretty easy to do and
it gets us the amount of cellulose in the leaf and the amount of chlorophyll
in the leaf, both together. The chlorophyll is in here in little packets
inside these cells so to really be able to measure this we take another
wavelength of light and another detector down here
and this is red light and this is near infrared light (NIR). These are all on the
apogee website, the details of these. And now by subtraction we can get at the amount of
chlorophyll in this leaf. And it's the electrical output of these two detectors.
When we make a graph of this difference and we put transmission down here, the
ratio of these wavelengths and we put chlorophyll up here. And I'm going to
abbreviate that just CHL for chlorophyll. This would be lovely if we got a nice
straight line and the transmission was directly related to chlorophyll we would
have a meter that told us chlorophyll. Unfortunately the distribution of
chlorophyll in a leaf is so clumped up that the light goes in many directions.
It doesn't come straight through the leaf and when we make this graph
it's highly nonlinear. That's a fundamental characteristic of all of
these optical meters to get this non-linear relationship between
transmission and chlorophyll. So here, let me show you what happens with this, if we
put tick marks in this graph now and we have 12345, we make a measurement here
and we have that much chlorophyll, let's call that about one. now we make another
measurement out here at five,
and you would think the chlorophyll went up by a factor of two and a half and in
fact it doesn't. This only doubles so the transmission is not a direct
indicator of the chlorophyll in the leaf. This has led to lots of problems.
People write papers and they say "the SPAD number went from two to four
therefore my chlorophyll doubled." And that is wrong, the chlorophyll did not
double. This index doubled, so the SPAD Minolta meter that reads in SPAD units
only gives an index that's non-linearly related to chlorophyll. The Optisciences
meter also gives an index that's non-linearly related to chlorophyll. And
because of these problems and because of the need to really measure chlorophyll
Apogee instruments built on the research that developed characteristic lines like
this for each species of plant. There's one line for wheat, there's another line
for corn, there's a line for rice, they all take the same basic shape they just
have slightly different curvatures. With this equation you can convert transmission
into actual chlorophyll in the leaf and the result is a graph where we
have chlorophyll here,
actual chlorophyll measured by extracting the chlorophyll, and this unit
down here is now optical chlorophyll, or
optical CHL, and the relationship is a straight line. So we can very
accurately measure chlorophyll in the leaf with the appropriate software in
the meter to convert this family of curved lines into straight
lines. That's the beauty of the apogee meter in terms of what it does to get
chlorophyll. This took a lot of work, a lot of measurements of chlorophyll and
non-destructive chlorophyll. We have a video that shows the techniques to do
that. There's a family of curves in there for twenty two species and it's growing.
We're getting a curve in there for potatoes and other species now so we can
establish this linear relationship between what the optical meter measures
and the true chlorophyll in the leaf. So in a nutshell that's the advance in this,
and it's a sufficiently big advance that Apogee patented this meter, it has a
patent pending on this meter. It now allows researchers to get measurements
of chlorophyll without having to kill the leaf, without having to
extract a leaf and measure it in a spectrophotometer. So thanks for
listening. That's a nutshell of the advances in these measurements over the
last thirty years.