My name is Schuyler Smith here at Apogee Instruments
and today we're going to talk about choosing the right quantum/PAR sensor.
We're going to talk about what do quantum/PAR sensors measure,
our original versus full-spectrum sensors,
the difference between all the models we offer,
the output options available,
and then we're going to talk about our USB output options and how those are different.
First off quantum sensors measure PAR.
PAR is defined as photosynthetically active radiation,
and we measure PAR in units of micro moles per meter squared per second.
These are the five different series we offer. The 100, 200, 300, and 400 series are all in the black.
Now the black head have our original spectral response.
We have our full-spectrum over here that have the full spectral response.
We're just going to touch on that here in a minute but here are some references for you.
There's a great video from our CEO Bruce Bugbee,
and it's going to be an in-depth explanation of what PAR is.
You can click on all these links in the comment section below.
We have a great link here that talks about the spectral errors by light source.
Again you can click on that in the in the comments below.
But that's going to tell you based on which type of sensor you go with
whether, that's the original or the full spectrum,
based on what type of light you have what type of errors you would expect.
Of course with the full-spectrum, those are going to be pretty small errors compared to the electric or sun calibration.
Then we have a link here as well that just compares all of the sensors together.
We're going to show that table later in this video, but if you want you can just click right there to see that on the website.
Full-spectrum versus original spectral response.
Now first we need to define PAR as how the plant sees light.
We can see that is the dashed line here from 400 to 700 nm, right here.
Ideally that is the spectral response a PAR sensor would have.
We're not able to get that with our sensors.
Our original one you can see it cuts on right here, cuts out a little bit of the blue,
a little low on blue and then it completely cuts off some of that far red above 665 nm.
With that we calibrate according to sunlight or calibrate according the electric light sources
and we have those two different options available.
Then we came out with the full-spectrum sensor, which more closely matches that PAR response.
That one is going to give you much more accurate readings for all light sources.
The SQ-100 series. The SQ-110 is calibrated for sunlight. The SQ-120 is calibrated for electric lights.
Electric lights meaning your high pressure sodium, your metal halides, your T5 cool light fluorescents.
It's not great for red LEDs because of that spectral range we talked about on the graph before.
It's self powered, meaning you don't need to add an additional power supply.
You just need to hook it up to a single ended order differential reading on your logger.
It will give you an output from 0 to 800 millivolts (mV).
Tthat range is equal to 0 to 4,000 micro moles
so our factor for every sensor we send out, is 5 micro moles per meter squared per second per millivolt.
That's for the SQ-110 and -120.
Again that link right there, it's the same link as the page before.
Our SQ-200 series, this just takes that same sensor and amplifies them into a voltage that you can use on your logger.
The SQ-212 and -220: 0 to 2.5 volts (V).
SQ-215 and -225:  0 to 5 V. SQ-214 and-224: 4 to 20 milli amps (mA).
Then the same thing, the SQ-210s are for sunlight and the SQ-220s are for electric lights.
I do want to mention these all need to be powered in order to get that amplified output.
It needs between 5 and 24 V, whatever, you have in there.
If you have 12 V, great it will automatically regulate the sensor and then give the output accordingly.
These are just some of your applications that you might be using these for:
greenhouse, nursery, growth chambers, under canopies, aquariums,
freshwater and ocean underwater environments,
and any measurements with your traditional grow lights (metal halide T5, high-pressure sodium).
The SQ-300 has the same sensor as the SQ-100 and -200, we just put it in a light bar so you can get your spatial averages.
310 is for sunlight. The 320 is for electric.
Then you can kind of see the breakdown here. The SQ-313 and -323 is 3 sensors spaced over 50 cm.
The SQ-316 and -326 is 6 sensors over 50 cm,
and the SQ-311 and -321 is 10 sensors spaced over 70 cm.
You can see you can use it under canopy to see how much light is filtering through given that spatial average
or on a bench, pretty much anywhere if you want that spatial average.
Again we're just going to touch on that we've just been talking about the original sensors,  the black line for spectral response.
Now we're going to talk about the full-spectrum (SQ-500 series)
We actually have one sensor in this series, it's the SQ-500.
It has that wider spectral range.
The signal itself is much smaller. It's only 0 to 40 mV.
That puts a 100 micro moles per meter squared per second per millivolt,
so make sure your datalogger or whatever you're using to read this can read that small signal.
Then the output range is the same,
0 to 4000 micromoles per meter squared per second.
Accurate with all light sources including all LEDs to give you those accurate PAR readings.
Again you can see just a couple of applications.
Everything that was on there before but especially with all LED lights,
even those narrow bands, it's going to give you accurate PAR readings.
This is that table.
What this table shows you is how each sensor measures up to next one or compares with the one before.
Really let's just go across the output here for the sensitivity.
You can see 0.2 mV per micro mole per meter squared per second for the SQ-110 and -120.
1 mV per micro mole per meter squared per second for the SQ-212 and -222.
For the SQ-214 and -224, you can see this is milliamp per micro mole per meter squared per second and that's 0.0064.
Then the SQ-215 and -225 is 2 mV per micro mole per meter squared per second.
The SQ-300 is the same as the SQ-100, where it's 0.2 mV per micro mole per meter squared per second.
Then the SQ-500 that has a really small signal,
0.01 mV per micro mole per meter squared per second.
You can pull this up on the website and look at it yourself see if the specs meet what you're looking for.
The SQ-420 and SQ-520 both have a USB output.
The SQ-420 being the original series the SQ-520 being the full-spectrum series.
It does require a computer or tablet to display the output.
One of the really neat things here is you can set it up on the computer, sampling interval and logging interval,
unplug it from your computer and then take it and set it up in this type of application,
where you're just powering it and it's going to log those readings that you set up in the head, up to 10,000 measurements.
The next time you plug it into your computer you'll be able to take those readings in a CSV file and analyze it and look at it.
I also want to mention that this is written in an open software
so if you're some sort of system integrator or someone who would just like the command codes
to integrate it into your own software, just email us at tech support and we'll work with you on that.
This is just the example of what the ApogeeConnect software looks like.
You can see our instantaneous reading right here and then you can see our reading here.
We're just logging it right on the computer, doing 5 second increments.
Then we can see where it's being saved right here in a CSV file.
This is just a couple of applications, just going back through.
You can see our sensors here in a greenhouse, where you might use them.
The LEDs where they might be used, out in the field as far as a line quantum.
Well, thank you very much for watching.
Feel free to comment below with any questions you have and we'll get back to you.
Also, you can send us an email.
Don't forget to subscribe to our channel. Thank you very much!