I'm Bruce bugbee professor of crop
physiology here at Utah State University
and I'm thrilled today to be announcing
the fall 2022 edition of our well-known
course in
medical cannabis cultivation
we started with 54 lectures in the first
edition and we're going to build on that
in this new edition with about 40
additional lectures in this course
that's going to mean breeding you
lectures on plant breeding expanded
insects and diseases
cannabinoid extraction medical cannabis
we're thrilled to bringing you this
course I'm joined in this effort by Dr
Royal Hines a long-term colleague and
also Mitchell Westmoreland who is we are
the primary instructors and we're joined
by several other people helping us in
specialty areas
let me very quickly show you what we're
going to talking about nine Cardinal
parameters form the basis of cultivation
four in the root zone five in the shoot
Zone we especially focus on nutrients
water light as the light goes up the
water goes up everything it interacts
with everything else this is complex but
exciting in its complexity
we're not only going to give you
lectures in the principles and the
theory we're going to take you to our
greenhouses and our growth Chambers and
show you the research we're doing we're
actively conducting research on cannabis
cultivation and as we make new
discoveries we're going to share them
with you and we're going to show you how
we collect the data we have over 44
growth Chambers here at Utah State
University to do this kind of research
at the end of the course you can take an
exam and on successful completion of the
exam you'll get a certificate of
completion assigned by all of us uh
that's been a great thing for students
I might add that the tuition money that
you pay goes to support graduate
education doesn't pay my salary doesn't
pay for anything else it just supports
our graduate education in our research
we're excited to have you in the class
and we look forward to getting started