is your par meter accurate I have no
idea but I do know of a tool that can
help you decide whether or not your
meter is starting to drift the tool you
can use is called the clear sky
calculator and it can be found at Clear
Sky calculator.com can be used to
determine the accuracy of any brand of
parmeter first take the measurement with
your meter as close to solar noon with
non-polluted Skies minimal humidity and
the sensor perfectly level second enter
that information into the field and
voila it will compare your measurement
to what the ideal measurement should be
thereby giving you a baseline to
reference from and determine the
accuracy of your par meter keep in mind
it is a mathematical model so if you
have less than perfect conditions when
you take your measurement you'll have
less than perfect results but it should
help you notice any serious accuracy
problems before weeks or months worth of
data are lost if your AP meter is more
than 10% off a button will appear
inviting you to take advantage of the
recalibration services provided by apog
instruments click on the link below to
check out the clear sky calculator for
yourself and now you have an answer to
the question