well my name is Skyler Smith here at
Apogee instruments and today we're going
to talk about how to wire up the St 150
ambient air temperature sensor the CS
240 back of panel module temperature
sensor and the TS 100 aspirated
radiation shield to the SMA cluster
controller all these components are part
of our pv 100 monitoring package from
Apogee instruments which also includes
the pyrometer
the SP 214 which is part of a different
wiring video and so if you're looking
for wiring instructions on that just
click on the comments below and then you
can find that video so let's start with
the CS 240 and this is what the back of
module temperature sensor looks like
right there's got a little bit of
adhesive and then it will also come with
some captain tape to be able to mount
that on the back of your panel so the
wiring for this it comes with seven
conductors here to black to red to white
and a shield for our application
connecting to the SMA cluster controller
we'll just go ahead and bend down the
black conductors because we don't need
them so I mean if you want to trim them
off whatever your needs are so we'll
start with the shield and we're going to
be working on terminal x seven down here
we're going to start on row B which is
the bottom one and so the first terminal
here is going to be the shield and then
the next one is going to be the white
conductor and it actually doesn't matter
which white conductor you can choose
either and then the next one is going to
be a red conductor and again it doesn't
matter you can choose either then we can
choose the other white conductor that
goes in the fourth one and then the last
one is the other red now the way we can
check our self here is if our cluster
controller is powered up we can just
push down until we get to meteorology
and then we can see our second one says
module temperature and it's giving us a
reading right now and it is it looks
like an accurate reading so we know that
that is why
up correctly now we're going to talk
about the SP 150 and be an air
temperature sensor and this is what it
looks like you can see our class a PRT
so we'll just slide that back into the
TS 100 shield there if you do order the
pv 100 package it will come already pre
glued into the port that goes in the
side of the TS 100 shield so this one
comes with 5 conductors comes with a
shield a red a black a green and a white
and we'll just be using all five of
these conductors so we're now on x7 row
a so we're going to start right here and
we're going to put the shield in first
in the first terminal the second one is
going to be the white conductor
the next one is going to be the black
conductor
then we have the green conductor into
the fourth terminal there and then we
have the red conductor and again once
that's all connected we can just scroll
down here and we can see our ambient
temperature and it is giving us a
believable reading last thing we need to
do today is power the fan on our cs100
and it's really important to use an
active shield when you're taking you to
ambient air temperature measurements and
we have on our other video the pv 100
video some graphs that show the data we
collected on active radiation shields
versus those passive shields so to power
the fan on this it needs the 12 volt
power supply included in the pv 100 is
this little DC to DC converter that
takes 24 volts DC which is also already
available and converts it to 12 volts so
the conductors from the TS 100 there are
seven of them we can bend down all but
the red in the black we only need the
red and the black for our application
and then so connected already to the
converter is the 24 volts powered off
the 24 24 volt power supply so we will
go ahead and the middle one here we will
connect the black conductor to
and then the one on the end will be our
read to power up to 12 volts on the fan
and as we slide him in and tighten them
down we can hear the fan we can also
fill the air coming off the fan and we
know we're getting those accurate
ambient air temperature measurements
thank you very much for watching how to
wire up the st 150 ambient air
temperature sensor the CS 240 back of
panel module temperature sensor and then
powering the TS 100 aspirated radiation
shield if you have any questions feel
free to leave them in the comments below
thank you very much for watching
you