this little device could save you money
and keep your indoor plants looking nice
and
healthy it's called a DLI meter and it
tells you just how much of that sweet
sunshiny goodness your plants are
getting think of it as like a rain gauge
but for
sunlight every plant needs to have light
to grow too little and nothing will
happen too much and you run the risk of
stressing your crops now every plant is
different some need a little light while
some need a lot more luckily a lot of
really smart people have done a lot of
work in determining how much light
specific plants need a good place to
start is by searching DLI requirements
on the internet for the specific plant
that you're trying to grow odds are
you'll see a number like 18 moles per
meter squar per day and often they'll
say that that light needs to be over a
6-h hour period that 6-h hour number is
called the photo period this DLI
requirement is the amount of light that
a plant needs to thrive and be healthy
all right so we've got our DLI
requirements we know kind of what our
Target is there's two ways that I like
to measure DLI with this DLI meter the
first way is to take the DLI meter press
and hold the button and then it'll
change it into ppfd readings and you
take those ppfd readings by holding it
at the canopy of the
beans seeing what your ppfd is and then
using a calculator it'll tell you how
much time you need to have to reach that
18 moles the way that I like to do it
that's a little more simple and doesn't
require a calculator is to just kind of
take the DLI meter and leave it there
and then come back tomorrow and I can
scroll through the data from yesterday
and yesterday it says I had 20 moles
over the photo period of 13 hours so
check I've got it over 6 hours and check
I'm over 18 moles once we know that our
plants have got that DLI requirement
meant we know that they're happy unlike
the sun outside this light is not free
and depending on the size and the scale
of your operation these power
requirements can really start to add up
that's why this di meter is so important
this meter can tell you when your
lighting requirements have been met
here's a few more ways that monitoring
DLI can help your plants grow their best
sometimes plants need more or less light
at certain stages as they grow by being
able to closely monitor that amount of
light you can increase the quality and
the yield of your crops if you have a
greenhouse and you're not getting the
light that you need for your plants to
grow you can use a grow light to
supplement the light that they need so
that way your plants can grow their best
changes in data can act as a canary in
the coal mine for determining larger
problems such as fixture failure or
power outages in the end this meter is
about telling you how much light your
plants are getting and when your plants
get enough light you can turn the lights
off and that saves you
money to learn more about our DLI meter
click on the link below
[Music]