I'm Bruce Bugbee professor of crop
physiology at Utah State University and
also president of Apogee instruments I'm
here today at the apogee instrument
studio to talk about our recent research
on far-red photon effects on plant
growth and development this is a
emerging field that's red hot right now
companies are putting far red LEDs into
fixtures and it's based on our work and
that of some other laboratories that
have clearly shown some value of far red
so in this seminar
I'm calling this far red The Forgotten
photons we can't see them they're barely
visible to the human eye and yet they
have powerful effects on plant growth
that we're just discovering we missed
these effects for so many years because
the electric lights don't have far red
there's no reason to put them in there
sunlight is loaded with par red photons
but it wasn't until we got LEDs and
especially afar red LED that's very
efficient that can be added to electric
lights so this work is both fascinating
from the standpoint of fundamental photo
biology and also has immediate
significant commercial implications
because we can manipulate both
photosynthesis and plant shape with
these four red photons so I'd love to
show this prism breaking up the colors
of light those of you know Pink Floyd
you know order this came from so the far
red I likes to show this it's right on
this edge right here of just the edge of
visible light and that's what we're
gonna talk about in this I want to
acknowledge two of my colleagues that
have done this research they're in the
trenches day-to-day
making the measurements and every we
meet every single day discuss the data
what the next studies were gonna do the
first one is Xu Jung Jen who was a
started as a postdoc she's now a
research scientist in the lab she has
done the measurements on photosynthesis
and especially canopy photosynthesis and
then also Paul Kazuma who came to us
from the University of Florida
Kevin Voltas lab there he's done the
research on plant shape from far red
photons our work has been funded by
primarily by NASA they've funded the lab
for over 30 years for some very basic
studies and now more recently the USDA
has funded our research through what's
called the lamp project lighting
approaches to maximize profits basic
funding agency applied funding agency
and the interaction between those has
really helped us understand the value of
far-red photons let me show you another
graph of where the far red photons lie
here's the colors of light all the way
from blue to far red and you can see
let's put some dotted lines on here the
cut-offs
now our traditional definition of
photosynthesis doesn't start counting
photons until that's it's um black until
right here right at 400 we start
counting them we have evidence these
photons are useful too but for now we're
going to talk about just the far red so
right here on the edge of our vision
we're talking about these photons right
in this area right here what's the
effect on plant growth just to review we
typically break up light into three
categories blue green
and read and I'll be talking about the
effects of those it turns out this is
these are hundred nanometer increments
but it really works well to break them
up into this we're currently studying
different wavelengths of blue but the
green that could look at the green
includes yellow transitioning to orange
we call that whole thing green but it
turns out it works really well to break
the light up into this so what I'm going
to start with is a story and it's a
story of a study that you young did with
four growth chambers where we did canopy
photosynthesis on the plants and gave
them different colors of light so let's
go to that story here's the four
chambers two of them had white light
from white LEDs two of them had magenta
or purple light from red and blue LEDs
here is the input of photons to each 300
350 300 350 so if we looked at this
chart without prior knowledge of for red
photons how would you say the lettuce
grew this is a study with lettuce the
first thing you'd say let's see if we
control this in red is that these by
virtue of having higher light would have
higher yield and these would be less and
if you were a believer in red and blue
photons for photosynthesis you would say
that this would grow the best and this
would be second and these would be third
and fourth now let's look how that data
comes out for this these two were
exactly equal now I've normalized the
fresh weight and the dry weight to a
hundred for these to make the point
there was no difference in growth when
we went from purple or magenta light to
like that should not be a surprise
because now we know that green photons
are just as good as any other color for
photosynthesis and I'm going to discuss
that more in a bit let's take a look
just at those two chambers and and the
difference these two chambers grew even
better in this experiment so suddenly
look at the difference 27% better 35%
better this is just opposite of our
intuition where we thought this would be
the best and this would be the worst
it's completely flipped let's take a
look at what's going on here is there a
mechanism for why this should be the
best and that and grew better than that
what I didn't tell you is that these two
chambers had 50 micro moles per meter
squared per second of far-red photons
that's a big deal so 350 300 plus 50
this got 350 the total here is 350 all
four chambers had the exact same photon
flux if you count the far red photons so
what's up with that too far red photons
caused photosynthesis let's take a look
at this first let's take a look at these
two chambers is this right do white
lights grow plants equally well to
magenta lights with a long history of
now of people saying pink houses with
this blue people said this is a plant
growth light this is not efficient for
photosynthesis because the green photons
just bounce off let's take a look at
that this is a 2002 edition of the plant
physiology book that I use in class what
does this book say about red and blue
and green light 2002 that's 17 years ago
here's the graph here's what it says
this is a absorption of chlorophyll
really strong absorption and blue lessen
the green strong absorption in the red
says chlorophyll absorbs minimum green
light that's proof statement and that
resulted in people making lights with
just red and blue because of this
powerful absorption by chlorophyll but
sunlight is loaded with green light is
that really wasted that's jump ahead to
the 2015 version of this book which is
the current version this is Tyson's
Eiger now it's on the sixth edition now
we turn to the exact same page of
chlorophyll look at this graph there's
new pigments in here and then now it
says multiple pigments absorb radiation
from 400 to 700 now this is still a
little misleading because this pigment
fighter Ethan is only found in algae but
the chlorophyll absorption even though
it's low and here on this graph is
enough to penetrate the leaves and cause
excellent photosynthesis so what I'd
like to show you briefly is the effects
of these colors of light this summarizes
a big part of my career to categorize
these remember we have blue green red
and now far read summary of spectral
effects here's our Dark Side of the Moon
spectra blue photons inhibit cell
expansion that sounds terrible but when
it's stem elongation it's a good thing
more blue shorter plants and that's
tremendous now if it's smaller leaves
that's bad but that's the most
fundamental effect of blue photons is to
inhibit stem elongation but they also
inhibit leaf expansion green are far
more valuable than we once thought
because they are very effective for
photosynthesis and they facilitate human
vision let's go to this slide right here
this is cannabis grown under red and
blue LEDs and
white LEDs our experience working in the
lab is that these are tremendously
valuable for diagnosing the plants get
in there to see microscopic insects
subtle nutritional disorders they
penetrate deep in the canopy we can see
these dark areas this is very difficult
to understand the health of the plants
now you can turn those off and turn on
whites but you don't see surgeons
working under dim white light they have
bright white light in we have found that
really helps diagnose subtle disorders
on the plants this is still slightly
more efficient electrically and but the
difference is getting smaller this is
maybe 10% more of electrically efficient
than this but this has the clear
advantage for being able to diagnose the
plants this is a little sidebar from our
from our quest to understand far red
photons but it's an important sidebar
back to this inhibit cell expansion look
at far red photons Wow
they do the opposite of blue they
enhance cell expansion and that effect
is so powerful here sit Elliot lettuce
with white light with no far red and
with 10% far red now I just jumped ahead
of myself to show you what's going on in
our study with those far red photons but
this enhancement of cell expansion is a
very big thing it's a very powerful tool
look at how well photons penetrate
leaves this is a beautiful study by
Brodus inand Vogelman 2010 they looked
at a side view of a leaf here's blue
there's so much absorption by
chlorophyll it doesn't penetrate here's
green penetrates the whole leaf there's
the top of the leaf then we get a green
color here there's the top of the leaf
right there here's the bottom of the
leaf green beautifully penetrates the
leaf through the spongy mesophyll all
the way through the leaf that's a big
Valley
of green light red similar to blue
absorbed by chlorophyll absorbed in the
top layers look at far red that also
penetrates the leaf so these effects
only become apparent when we study whole
plants and especially plant communities
but this is a nice slide showing the
penetrating effects of these colors of
light back to our study better growth
here better growth here what caused that
better growth when we get a result like
this that's sort of unbelievable because
if these don't cause photosynthesis
what's going on we need to know the
mechanism and this by the way this is
fresh mass and dry mass both in this
study we very carefully measure this
we've done it more than once we get the
same result now let's go back to Carl
Sagan who popularized a phrase that I
think all of us would be good to
remember when we're doing these studies
extraordinary claims require
extraordinary proof with waar red
enhances lettuce growth we need
extraordinary proof to begin to
understand it so this comes from first
of all the Makri curve there's a picture
of Keith McCree he died five years ago
here's his famous curve here's 700 and
in the Makri curve he shows these
cutting off so fast that these photons
are of minimal value but as terrific as
a scientist as McCree was and I got to
know him personally early in my career I
he was a physicist that came across to
help biology is a great guy he only had
primitive tools to make this curve he
didn't have the LEDs we have now he had
prisms and filters so we had low light
levels
and he only could study one color at a
time and on a single leaf
it's a terrific piece of work and his
papers are a masterpiece of writing but
they're limited because he couldn't
study synergistic effects of multiple
colors of light at once on the leaf so
let's look at what happens
there's our far-red this is a diagram of
what happens with photons flowing
through the light reactions of
photosynthesis now usually this is shown
with a lot of biochemistry but I really
like physical diagrams so here's a
person it's a man wife team I guess
moving photons through what we call
photosystem 1 and photosystem 2 they
first come in it takes 4 photons to
excite this these four electrons to a
higher energy state this is where water
is split in photosynthesis now they get
this photon roll it down this platform
and this male turns and it makes ATP so
if that's that's a first step really
valuable now they get to with another
platform and we need four more photons
to excite four electrons up here to this
guy there's four electrons in a very
high state and now we put them in a
bucket and this makes NADPH so the
combination of ATP and NADPH very
high-energy compounds are what causes
photosynthesis interesting enough
because of the way we discover these
photosystem two comes first and then
photosystem one that's a trick question
for a students on plant physiology exams
2 comes first however we have known
since the 1950s and the time of Emerson
that far red vote
guns also are effective right here and
it in fact that work helped us
understand there's two photosystems so
the far red photons can substitute for
the traditionally photosynthetic photons
here but only if we have we'll call it
white light photons on this side far red
photons all by themselves are not
effective we know that they but it's
easy to give our red photon
synergistically with all the rest of the
photons so this is a nice easy to
remember diagram of how photons turn
into energy and then all this energy is
used to fix co2 into sucrose in plants
but the point is far bit photons now
there's a very fundamental law that
underlies all of this and this law
relates not only to photosynthesis but
it relates to solar panels and for that
matter it relates to human vision in our
the retina of our eyes and that law this
is the Emerson enhancement effect this
law is called the stark Einstein law
this stark helped explain Einstein's
work they both get credit for it and
here it is 1 photon excites one electron
a simple law we have forked photons here
we get four electrons here
four more photons here we get four more
electrons up there that's a remarkable
law and it links the photosynthetic
value of photons to human vision and to
solar cells and really all of biology
this is how the system works and this is
why far red photons can act
synergistically with white now let's
take a closer look at this is our
definition of photosynthetic photons
correct to do this work we put lettuce
and those gas exchange chambers that I
talked about and gave them supplemental
far red light
this is just exactly how we did this
study we're talking about here's their
traditional photons here's the far red
right there we normally wouldn't count
them for photosynthesis what happened
this is 400 to 700 there's the far red
when we gave them only white light we
get this kind of curve for
photosynthesis this is gross
photosynthesis as a curve that slightly
nonlinear because we're getting up to
high light levels now we start adding
far red photons to this what happens
well look at this they go up we're not
counting them but they made
photosynthesis go up and we're not we're
not counting them as photosynthetic how
do you explain that
we need another graph here is the graph
where we count photons all the way to
750 and now those photons fall perfectly
on the line
this is powerful evidence that our
definition of photosynthetic photons
needs revision to count for red photons
particularly in canopy photosynthesis
where they penetrate the canopy and they
have a bigger effect than they might
have in a single leaf let's take a look
now at does this happen in all species
remember we want convincing evidence we
want extraordinary proof may be that
only works in lettuce Xu yung Chen has
now done this in something like 20
species spinach basil kale different
kinds of lettuce c4 crops like corn
sunflower wheat it happens the same in
every species every single species those
far-red photons are equally valuable to
traditionally photosynthetic photons
here's the commercial implications we
did a paper last end of last year it got
published in the journal Nature most
people show that flux of photons like
this in an energy basis and here's
far-red right here not very good but
energy doesn't cause photosynthesis
energy doesn't cause plant shape
it's photons and these are low energy
photons so when we take this data and
rege RAF it for photon flux look at this
the far red photons are almost equal to
the Reds and the Blues these violets are
coming on fast - that's a subject of
another talk but the far red photons are
very effective so now we can use those
commercially not only can we use them
for photo biology but we can use them
commercially to manipulate plants back
to the study now this shows if they're
photosynthetic this shows why these
should all be equal because they cause
photosynthesis but they weren't equal
these two are even better than those two
this gets us in to plant shape this is
Paul kazuma's work now and this is the
responsive plants to shade when the
plants are in the bright Sun they have
plenty of visible photons blue green and
red they know they're in the Sun but
when they're in the shade over here
underneath this tree they have a lot of
far red photons this is the graph of the
shade they're very enriched when plants
perceive a high amount of far-red they
panic
we're under shade they need to do one of
two things get tall fast to get into the
light or get bigger to capture more
light so there's two types of plants
here they come once growing fast this is
called a shade avoider plant because
it's getting tall
this plant is called the shade tolerator
plant because it's getting big if we can
trick plants that are not in the shade
to think that we could make them like
this this is a traditional plant in the
Sun this is exactly what happens with
lettuce that the lettuce gets big like
this because of its being tricked by far
red photons let's take a look at this
shade avoidance shade tolerance there's
a big picture of that lettuce and the
value of far-red this was with just a
little bit more far-red we tricked this
lettuce plant into thinking it was in
the shade it got enormous this is a
powerful picture we're all anxious to
use far-red for indoor agriculture -
unless to get the plants bigger and many
people have said this is incredible
we're going to meet we need to be giving
far-red to everything but remember that
far-red also increases stem elongation
and some plants could be shade avoiders
let's look at what the results from
multiple species here's here's a top
view of these plants no far red far it's
the same slide as the last known only
shows you that the dramatic benefit of
red photons both because of
photosynthesis and because of expansion
but look the photosynthetic photons were
less so we needed those for
photosynthesis but they not only grew
equally they grew better here's the
problem we give the same amount of fire
red photons to Tomatoes look what
happens more stem elongation this is
very undesirable in tomatoes I know we
don't grow soybeans in controlled
environments but there are a great test
species
it made soybeans panic they get tall
this is not a good effect
cucumbers makes cucumbers tallest
not a good effect spinach we have some
evidence as leafy greens this can help
with leaf expansion in spinach too so
for leafy greens the addition of ferret
is great but it's a powerful tool
because we could use it a little bit
when the plants are young we can use it
at different times look at this flower
right there let me see if I can
highlight this we'll put that one in red
there's evidence that far red light can
help plants form flower sooner so I hope
this seminars helped explain from our
results the tremendous value of far red
photons so historically we have quantum
sensors to measure photosynthetic
photons but those quantum sensors don't
measure this far red in order to measure
it you need a spectral radiometer which
is terrific but that jumps up the price
and complexity considerably in making
those measurements because of this
Apogee has developed a sensor that has
both red and far-red detectors in the
same sensor so this helps us measure
Photosynth that traditional in
photosynthetic photons and in a separate
measurement for red photons that's it
thanks for listening we'll talk to you
again in another video