i'm bruce bugbee and i'm here in our
recording studio today
to talk about low-cost led fixtures for
home horticulture
now we do a lot of research on leds
color of leds efficiency of leds
but we use
high output leds that are expensive
hundreds of dollars
but there is a rapidly emerging market
of many options of lights that are
somewhere between twenty dollars and
forty dollars
and they work wonderfully for home
horticulture
at my house i have maybe a dozen of
these lights over plants
and if we cut away and went to my house
you'd see them but they're giant house
plants some there's a bird's eye fern
that's six feet tall under under these
lights and some peace lilies that are
big
they're fabulous for growing plants in
dark corners
they're also fabulous for growing leafy
greens on your kitchen counter
you do not have to spend hundreds of
dollars to
get very
useful effective lights so what i want
to do in the next few minutes is
review these lights
show you examples of the ones that i
have purchased and how they work the
advantages and disadvantage
of all these lights to help you make
better selections
so to start with that
we're going to go to
the amazon website which has lots of
lights you don't need to buy them from
amazon but there's many options and i
can quickly show you the options from
their site
and i can point out the pros and cons of
the lights and we'll start with a little
view of that and then we'll look at the
lights themselves
so here we are we just typed in led grow
light very generic search
and all of these lights come up look we
can scroll and scroll there's there's
dozens and dozens of lights on here
the first selection criteria is cost
look at these that are that are here
254 dollars 450 even this one's 159 you
do not need to pay that much
maybe if you're growing cannabis you
need highlight but we're talking about
growing leafy greens lettuce and basil
and spinach and all of your favorite
house plants under these you don't need
lights like that so you can screen down
here for price
under 25 25 to 50
that's a useful screening feature but
for now let's just
leave this there's no single brand
that's the best
these are all
they're made in china they're sometimes
they're hard to tell who makes them
here's the first point we scroll up a
little
many of these lights
are purple
rule number one
do not buy
purple lights
the reason they even exist is they're
slightly more electrically efficient
and you can save 10 cents a month on
your electric bill
but they're horrible to look work under
they're horrible to look they make the
plants look black
we don't we no longer use those at all
in our research and i don't recommend
them because they're
the
really difficult color
they are finally
going out of fashion there's many more
of the white leds than these
people say full spectrum well that's
fine these are these are full spectrum
lights but it's not because they make
the plants grow better it's because
they're much more pleasant to have in
your house the light quality is fine
most of these now
are a warm white color like the warm
white fluorescents you might have in a
bathroom
cool white means bright blue light and
sometimes that can be a little bit harsh
it's so blue in your house
so warm white is a really excellent
color most of these are warm white but
again
here's one that's not so bad eighty
dollars but i said we're going to look
at twenty to forty dollars so even this
one is getting up there in cost
they don't give you a lot of specs they
give you a lot of seaming specs in these
lights but most of them don't mean much
let's scroll down here
to we can probably just screen
um
um on that first page
doesn't even this first page doesn't
include any of the lights we've
purchased let's just try this
um
25 to 50 dollars
so we've edited this to
to be the 25 to 50 dollar lights
there there's many options you get rid
of the purple lights here's one it's
called the gray love sp 1000 let's take
a look at that
this is not a light that i have
purchased for analysis yet but i looked
at it before it looks promising
um
it's a it's a good-sized light and they
they show us the size in here 46 dollars
you get a lot of light from this might
be overkill for some things um
it it's dimmable you can you use high
medium and low this shows the uniformity
of the light oh i got to be careful to
touch this
let's go back to that
um
this shows the spectra it's it's warm
white it's got a lot of orange and red
not so much blue
and then after that it's uh
there's a dimmable
there's what else comes in the package
so this is a light worth considering in
this
but if you look closely at this
these are leds mounted on a board
and they're not focused they'll shoot
the light sideways so they kind of light
up your whole living room whether you
want it or not
it's possible to get lights with the
leds indented and then they're much more
focused
so
let's take a look
let me
take a look here
i'm not going to search through all
these lights let's skip to
this light right here
this one is a yes com
this was one of the early lights we
started buying this one
for research about
five or six years ago
it used to be about 22 dollars the
prices crept up a little bit
this is a fine light but it's a thin
panel and it's one of those lights that
shoots the light out sideways
so let me show you in a demonstration
the effect of a light that's focused and
one that's on a flat panel
and we've got lights set up right here
and i can wheel them in here
and plug them in
we lost our yellow cord
i guess i'll shoot the yellow cord went
away but i can plug them in here
these are very rigged up here just so we
can do this demo
and we'll get them
flat
see if we can get this flat
if you can see this
this light on the left
shoots the light sideways
let's let's do these one at a time
this one
is this light right here
shoots the light sideways
and i'm gonna unplug that a little bit
hard to see in the studio you can see
this is a
cool white light it's bright look at my
hand it looks it looks uh
white
not
flesh colored because this is a cool
white
and the light shoots sideways out and i
have found this light is undesirable
because
of the sideways light
so for a little bit more money
we
get this light
which i'm going to tilt it up so you can
see it
look at this it's still not bright
because the lights the leds are in set
and they're more focused
so this gives it more light right below
it and
this has less light pollution all over
your house than this one let's take a
look at the light output
to do this
you need a
light meter quantum sensor
these outputs are going to be similar
they take similar wattage
to do this we got to hold the
sensor
similar distance
these are not bright lights this one i'm
getting
31 micromoles per meter squared per
second
and this one
i'm getting
oop
sorry
we gotta get this back to the
like
i didn't have it on the right setting
let's do it again
this one i'm getting
below that light
and this one i am getting
460 below this light
so they're both a similar output
this light takes only 18 watts
this one takes 24 watts so by virtue of
being a little more focused it's a
little bit brighter right here
but the big difference is
side lighting and i have found these
inset lights to be
more
helpful for this
now let's wheel this
away for the moment and look at these
lights on the screen
keep our meter right there
yeah
we've got this set up
to
look at some other lights let me skip to
this nope skip to this one
this is the website for that focused
light you can see it's in depth you can
see the lights are inset nowhere do they
they show the picture of it but they
don't advertise that fixture here
this is a 21 light so this is a little
cheaper than the
previous light
again you just got to scroll and look
look through these to find the lights
with the features you you want because
there's no
clear identifying feature that would
tell you search just for this
light
let's go back to another light
right here
that's only it's 19.95 20.
here's this light
we've gotten a lot of these tested them
comes in a real nice box so if you want
to give it as a gift to someone this is
a great box now let's take a look at the
light
and i'm going to
plug this in
this light has a switch
so this is a combination
of reds
and i'm going to not point these right
at the camera
of reds and whites so it's somewhat of a
warm color
this is somewhat flexible you can put
the
the these together you can put them
apart there's two things you put them
under a shelf so that's a bit of an
advantage
note these are not in set so they give
you a lot of side lighting
um but this is called
a this is one that does have a name a
sepal led grow light
when these say 20 watts that doesn't
mean that's the power they take that's
some advertising thing similar to the
what the equivalent of an incandescent
would be
but in this case
this one is about a 20 watt light so
this is like worth considering
um
because of the flexibility and low cost
now let's look at um
we've that one that one this one
here's here's another warm white um one
in a box oop i don't want to
don't want to do that
here is one
that is purple it's got a few blues in
it but it's purple
when i hit the reorder on this light at
amazon
the the light i ordered did not come up
with the exact website a purple light
came up so apparently this manufacturer
has replaced their wonderful warm white
light with the purple light
so it's unfortunate but you got to be
careful to
screen these
and then finally this is the this is one
that we haven't tested um but it's
another possibility you can go in here
and count the leds
on the from their pictures
um
but this is
the 45 dollars roughly gets you twice
the amount of light as a 20 dollar light
but these are sort of overkill they have
more light than you really would need
for most plants
i think that's all i want to say about
these
buy them and use them i it will enrich
your life they put them you need them on
a time clock so you have to buy a little
some of them have timers
and you buy a time clock and keep them
on
one more thing i forgot to show you one
light
here's a box this is a light that comes
in tubes
and you open the box
and
the light
looks like this
and we've mounted those tubes
on a piece of styrofoam here plug it in
here i could plug this one in
this is also a fine light
this one's got a switch
this one's dimmable
so we can
do multiple levels
but this is a nice one because you can
put these in long linear strips this is
one of the defining characteristics but
you can see lots of lights now with
warm white leds that's a great thing for
options
so
let's take a look at what it costs to
run these lights per month on your
electric bill because people get
concerned and rightly so
so here's one
most of these lights
are about 20 watts
so it's the same as a 20 watt light bulb
so what does that cost
so if we have let's get our pin up here
if we have 20
watts times
we're going to run these for 16 hours hr
per day that's a typical time you don't
want to run at night keeps people up and
some plants don't like to have light all
the time so 20 times 16
is 320
watt
hours this is watt hours per day
and this is 0.32
kilo
watt
hours
this is how we pay for electricity
kilowatt hours
so it takes .32 kilowatt hours per day
and now let's take that times 10 cents
per kilowatt power this is a real
typical price for
residential electricity you can see the
math that cancels out
this equals 3.2
cents per day
or
30 days in a month
we're about one
dollar
per month
to run
a 20 watt
light
12 a year i submit that unless you're
really out of money
that's some of the best twelve dollars
in a year you're going to spend is
running these lights and growing great
plants they don't cost much
if you get a big one a bright one
this might go let's put that in a
different color here
red
they might get up to nah red's not a
good color
blue
they might get up
to 40
watts
but then everything doubles and if it's
a 40 watt
now you're looking at two dollars a
month
still still uh not expensive
big lights for leds now we're talking
much more now we're talking
100 times this easily to get bright
light to grow real high light crop
plants but none of the plants we're
talking about are highlight so there's
the math and the cost per month
so i would like to
walk over here and show you our
venus flytrap research that we have
going on
with
one of these lights
we've done a lot of research on
nutrition of venus fly traps here's a
few of them most of the research is done
now
but here's one of these lights warm
white mountain under the counter focused
you can see my hand looks flesh colored
under this light the plants grow great
this is just a little lid to keep them
healthy these are really healthy venus
flytrap plants and we've had them a long
time in here so it's a really good
example of what you can do with lights
venus flytraps are tricky to grow
but under this steady light they love it
keep them keep a lid on to keep a little
bit higher humidity you can see one of
them's flowering
in here
so there's an example of
these lights
thanks for listening i hope this video
inspires you to buy some of these lights
for home horticulture