hi my name is Skyler Smith I work with
the integrator and technical support
team here at Apogee instruments and
we're here to talk about connecting our
SP 214 pyrometer to the SMA cluster
controller very popular controller for
use in commercial solar applications the
SP 214 is an irradiance sensor in order
to see the watts per meter squared
available from the Sun so the first
thing to note is the SP 214 comes like
this with a four inch pigtail to connect
to so the sensor does need to be powered
24 volts power supply so you need to
know where your power supply is and then
how far away that is from your x8
terminal on the cluster controller
depending upon the distance you may need
to split the jacket like so and we have
the red and black over here that will
power the sensor and the green and white
which are the sensor output that will
connect into the controller so we'll go
ahead and right here in our example
we'll connect the red into the positive
on the power supply so we just slide
that down in there and this is just a
regular screw on terminal so we will
slide it in and tighten that down
and then the black will go in the
negative and same thing we will just
tighten the him there okay and then over
here on the controller itself we are on
x8 and the top row is a two so we're
going to go in a two for the white
connector a three for the green
conductor and these are just pushing
terminals so they just push in and then
our shield we will go into a four okay
so that's how you wire up the sensor
itself the next step is to change the
insulation curve and you do that through
the user interface for the SMA cluster
controller and so once you have that
interface pulled up on your computer
navigate to meteorology and then go to
environmental and then it go to a
radiant sensor and then go to
characteristic curve and when you're
there you just need to change it to zero
to twelve hundred and fifty watts per
meter square and as a reminder this is a
4 to 20 mili-amp sensor the other way
that you can look at this is on the
controller itself if you scroll down a
number of times then you get two analog
inputs analog current input number one
on the top there is showing us what the
data is reading from the center and in
our example here it's reading four point
zero 1 million which is correct for our
studio there is very little light and if
we hit down two more times we can see
the insulation converting that to 1
watts per meter squared it should be
correct
for normal applications you'll probably
be reading between 7 to 11 milliamps
depending on your time of day and
location
that concludes our SP 214 parinama tur
connecting to the SMA cluster controller
be sure to watch our other segment on
connecting our TS 100
aspirated radiation shield to the
cluster controller to get very accurate
ambient air temperature readings thank
you