i'm bruce bugbee president of apogee
instruments
and professor of crop physiology at utah
state university
in this short video we're going to talk
just about
uv photons and what they do to plants
apogee makes a couple different sensors
for
uv it makes a su-200 which is just for
uv
some of the extended range now start to
measure uv
and most importantly for uv
is a spectroradiometer and
they're more expensive but if you're
really doing uv research
you really need to buy the more
expensive instrument
now let's take a look at this because
it's very
confusing to people here's our what we
call the electromagnetic spectrum
and the two key points are 400
and 700 nanometers and this is visible
light
and it's been well discussed in previous
videos
so we'll just draw a box for this
now as everybody knows these colors have
different effects
on plants they're not all equal but for
photosynthesis
they're close to equal suddenly
right at 400 we call this uv light
but the wavelengths of uvv are very
different and so we give letters to them
and let's put uv in blue
so if we go to
320 now some people
say this is 315 nanometers
but the the transition right here
this is called uv
a and it's just a the letter a because
it's close
to the visible this
radiation is leds
can produce these this this uv radiation
pretty effectively but it is
much less powerful to a plant
than the next group of wavelengths and
now
i'll show these in blue there's a band
right here
this is b u v b radiation
and then finally we get a band down here
which is uvc so
this is pretty much review for people
that study
study uv a is fairly
benign b is a lot more powerful and
c is really powerful very damaging
let's take a look at two things how much
of these wavelengths are in
sunlight and how do those photons cause
sunburn because we know that sunburn in
people
is caused by these so let's take a look
at sunlight first i'll put that in
yellow
sunlight starts this this wavelength
right here
by the way is 280.
below 280 we get all of the
radiation from the sun is filtered by
our atmosphere
the sunlight starts here and if we're
going to make a curve for sunlight
it's vanishingly small
and get this in yellow here
and then right about 380
starts to go up and then there's a big
jump right at 400
and it curves starts to look like that
sunlight
so this light little tiny curve on
graph like this looks like there's
hardly anything there
but these photons are hundreds and
thousands of times
more powerful than these photons so the
trace of radiation here is a very big
deal
for light then it starts to jump up
how about sunburn we have waiting
factors
for sunburn and let's put those
and let's put those in white
the waiting factors for sunburn start
very high here and they
look like that this is
a
this is called the erythema response
curve
and a huge rating factors one photon
in uvb is equal to 100 of uva
it's tremendously powerful for causing
sunburn the glass in greenhouses
filters out pretty much all of the uvb
so if you worked all day inside a glass
greenhouse
the glass is kind of like spf 60
um in in terms of the sunscreen effect
you could get a sunburn inside a
greenhouse but you'd have to be working
a long long time to get it
so these photons are not at all the same
big weighting factors and you can see
why you need to know
are you on this curve are you
right here on the curve you're right
there are you right there
enormously different how does this look
for plants this is the erythema response
curve
when we graph this for plants the curves
look really similar to sunburn
curves there's a series of plant growth
curves depending on what we're
interested in
some are dna damage but they all
come down something like this and the
exact shape is
is important but they all exponentially
decrease uv
is so damaging down here
we want to use it very sparingly
but up here it can have some beneficial
effects
it can help make plants tougher
plants make their own sunscreen so you
give them some uv
they synthesize pigments in the leaves
and they protect themselves against
uv photons so that's a beneficial effect
but these photons in here
that are close to the visible light can
be beneficial to plants
and we can use them in various ways help
keep
plants short help keep them make the
cuticles thicker make the layers on the
plants thicker
the same thing happens here but when we
get into these
we we need to have extremely small doses
we have done research on uvc in our
laboratory
and oh my you only have turn that on for
seconds
per day and you hope you don't burn the
plants the bee
we've also studied and we've burned our
share of plants with uvb
by turning them on one hour two hours
three hours a day and then you start to
see
burned parts of leaves because the
plants couldn't
adapt to that much a is far
less powerful and we can give them a lot
more
uva so all three of these are
potentially beneficial
depending on the dose the rule of thumb
is
some uv is good for people
it's just the right amount and some uv
is good for plants
it's just the right amount
we get so concerned worldwide about
the skin cancer and sunburn we have
everyone's using
sunscreen guess what the incidence of
vitamin
d went up in the population because
people were blocking all the uv
and we need uv light uv photons to
synthesize vitamin d so it's a powerful
example of some ub is beneficial for
people it's just not too much same thing
for plants
the let's go to one
other screen can i get to another screen
there let's take another screen
and just to get a clean screen here's
here's 700 same graph uv
the apogee makes the
meter quantum
dot sorry this is not right
but i'm getting the wrong model number
on here um this is a visible
bit meter the sensor
uv 200
this is a just a uv sensor and its
response curve
looks something like this it gets mostly
uv a it doesn't get any visible
it cuts off in here this is a useful
sensor
but it's you got to couple it with what
types of uv
that it it measures to be
able to separately get uvb
uvc uva and all the weighting factors
then you need a spectroradiometer which
which is a powerful tool on this is just
more expensive
so the sensor is good but it but it
doesn't tell you the exact
wavelengths and of course the other epar
sensors now
get some of this in here because this is
beneficial radiation
right below 400 that causes
photosynthesis
so i hope this helps as a summary of uv
light in in plants
we really need to know the wavelengths
to be able to tell
whether we can have big doses of a
fairly safe wavelength or tiny doses of
a really powerful wavelength
but we have electric lights to give all
of these different
wavelengths and we are actively studying
these now
in my laboratory at the university these
effects of
uv i can tell you our early research
is it's tricky
to get the doses just right because
these are
damaging wavelengths but the goal
is to use them to improve product
quality one of the things plants do
when they get uv photons is make what we
call
secondary metabolites secondary
metabolites includes cannabinoids it
includes terpenes
it includes vitamins a lot of beneficial
things for people
so if we can get the doses of uv just
right we have a potential to
improve product quality thanks for
listening
we'll talk to you again in another video