hello and welcome to this video brought
to you by Apogee instruments my name is
Nick hold and I'm an engineer here at
Apogee and today I'm here to talk to you
about one of our most recently released
products the AL 120 and the AL 120 was
brought about to replace our old
leveling system consisting of the
mounting bracket MV leveling plate sold
as two separate items and the mounting
bracket consisted of a Swiss cheese
array of holes only six of which were
used for actual mounting
additionally the leveling plate
consisted of a combination of six screws
three being used for mounting and three
being used for leveling a very very
tedious tedious system and based off of
feedback that we've received over the
years we have immensely simplified this
design to consist of three holes for
mounting and a fixed wave spring as a
pivot point for easy leveling today I'm
going to talk to you about how to
assemble your AL 120 and how to mount it
to your weather station or your cross
arm so to begin for best practices we
encourage that you mount your sensor to
your leveling plate prior to assembling
your bracket and prior to mounting it to
your weather station however if you need
to remove your sensor for calibration or
for any other purpose you can always do
so by unscrewing two black nylon screw
through the bottom of your bracket so to
begin using the three hole pattern on
your leveling plate match it up with a
three hole pattern on your leveling
bracket fitting the wave spring into the
groove on the back of the Loveline plate
take your hex cap screws and fit them
through your leveling plate and begin to
thread them into your bracket once you
have loosely finger tighten these grab
your u-bolt and place it through the
Vblock on the bottom of your bracket and
begin installing the hardware beginning
with your washers followed by your lock
washers and then followed by your bronze
nuts
so once you've installed all this
hardware tighten down your bronze nuts
approximately to where your your cross
arm will fit between the u-bolt and the
V block then you can slide this right on
to your cross arm and finger tighten
your hardware until it fits loosely on
your cross arm and approximately
parallel to the ground then take a half
inch crescent wrench and further tighten
this down so that it fits firmly and
snugly to your cross arm after a few
turns should have it in place and there
you have it so now our al 120 is mounted
on a horizontal cross arm
additionally we do have a vertical
configuration all you need to do to
change it from horizontal to vertical is
remove the screw that holds the plastic
Vblock to the bracket and move it to
this back side using screwing in the
screws from the inside inner side of the
bracket now once you place that on you
follow the same steps to place in your
u-bolt in your hardware and mount it to
your vertical cross arm this has been a
video a tutorial of how to assemble your
AL 120 for any questions or concerns
concerning this product please cottagey
instruments thank you for watching
Oh
[Music]