hello my name is Skyler Smith and I do
technical sales and support here at
after the instrument and today we're
going to talk about choosing the right
infrared radiometer for you going
through all the options of infrared
radiometer that African Instruments has
to offer
so we're going to cover all the field of
view options we're going to cover the
difference between the SI 100 si 400 and
si f-series and then we're going to go
through a demonstration of using our
field of view calculators that we have
available as an app and on the
spreadsheet so first thing the SI 100
and si F 100 series are both analog so
that means that they both require two
channels in order to read them a
differential channel to read the
millivolt output from the thermo-pile
and then a single-ended channel in order
to read the sensor body temperature
which is the thermistor and so those
thermistors are usually measured with
half bridge measurements and so the
difference between the SI 100 and sis
100 is that the SI f 100 is a fast
response at the point two second
response time whereas the SI 100 has a
point six second response and then you
can see how that affects the signal size
it being a much smaller signal between 5
and 15 micro volts per degree C on the
SI f series whereas the SI 100 is
between 20 and 60 micro volts per degree
C so the SI 100 is ideal for static
stations on traditional data loggers
your si F 100 series is ideal if you're
on a moving platform of some sort doing
measurements connected to data loggers
that have that high resolution that can
read that small signal the SI 400 series
is all completely digital using the SDI
12 protocol so that's ideal for your
static stations require multiple sensors
with a logger that can read that digital
sdi-12 then in each one of those we have
the different field of view options for
the SI 100 s 5 400 series we have 4
field of view options from our narrowest
14 degree half angle field of view up to
our horizontal
field of view and then we report that in
half angles and if you want more
information you can click there on that
website unfortunately do the small
signal size we only have three of those
field of view options available so we've
put together this table to kind of
explain a little bit better but for the
largest field of view the 22 degree
field of view we have the SI 111 si 411
SI f 111 and mi 210 the mi referring to
the infrared radiometer connected to the
handheld meter that gives you that
temperature so you can look there to
find your corresponding field of view
for which model it corresponds with and
this is a great illustration showing
that same concept so the si 111 is equal
to the 22 degree field of view and you
can see in this particular application
where you're doing crop canopy the si
111 may not be ideal because it's seeing
much more than just a crop it's seeing
the trees and the mountains in the
behind it whereas the horizontal is
seeing the most amount of the crop and
just the crop without anything behind it
and we'll go through this next on the
field of view calculator demonstration
so the field of view calculator is
available as an app just search for
Apogee instruments in your app store and
you'll be able to find that and a few
other things we have to offer and then
it's also available on our website and
there's the link right there you can
click on that and we'll just go to the
website right now and go through that so
just come here to Apogee instruments
comm so here we're on the webpage on the
homepage we'll come over here to support
we will click there and then on the far
side over here is infrared radiometers
so we'll click here now there is a lot
of information on this page a lot of the
frequently asked questions so if you
have questions yourself if this is going
to fit for your application I would come
look through here and then a lot of
helpful articles and links on trying to
get that to work for you
first one there being filled of you
explained I mentioned that on an earlier
slide but that is the link that you want
to look through if you want to get more
information on that we're going to click
on the second one here fill the view and
canopy fraction calculators we just open
this up here and it's going to say
viewing angle and viewing height so
let's just take for an example let's say
we wanted to do a 10 meter by 10 meter
plot and we want to measure the crop
canopy inside this 10 meter by 10 meter
plot so we want to maximize our field of
view to get as much of that in there as
we can so let's start with the SN 111
which is equivalent to that 22 degree
field of view and let's just say that
our viewing angle is 65 and our viewing
height is 1.5 meters above the canopy so
if we calculate it gives over here and
says our field of view is seeing 122.8
meters squared well which is good
information it tells us the total
surface area at seeing but we don't
really know how that's allocated and so
to get those details we need to look at
the excel sheet and so that's right here
this link here excel sheet program to
calculate target area so download that
and then open it up so I've just I've
done that already so here's that excel
sheet what it looks like
and I've pre entered in these values so
I've chosen the SI 111 which is
equivalent to 22 degree field of view 65
degrees is our angle from the angle from
the surface and then 1.5 meters above
the crop and that gives us that same 120
2.82 if we scroll down then we'll see
those details so first off again we're
trying to look at a 10 meter by 10 meter
plot is our example so we want to know
how what eye length is from A to D what
our field of view is seeing so if we
come down here we see right here it says
27 point 2 so that's way too long we
need to cut that down to 10 so let's
come back up and let's adjust the
numbers and let's adjust this to 63 and
be one meter above the crop so we've
significantly lowered this
from 122 to 24.2 let's see how that
allocates so our a to D is right here
ten point five six so that's pretty
close so that's pretty close to our 10
meters and then our C to F or B would be
our widest part and we come down here
and it's one point four six so we need
to double that so we have the full width
and that would be three meters so
essentially we're at three meters wide
and just over ten meters long if we were
to use the SI 111 in that application
but let's look at what it would look
like with the horizontal so if we come
over here into the SI one h1 let's go
back to our original numbers of doing 65
and 1.5 that's 65 degrees with our
height being 1.5 meters above the crop
canopy and then if we come down here we
can get our details so we want to know
first what is our length that we're
looking at and so we need to know G 2 -
G 1 and that's equal to V right here and
it says it's five point one four so it's
less than our centimeter so that's good
we could possibly maximize s more but
that's that's less and then let's figure
out our widest part or G 2 to F times 2
is equivalent right here to eight point
zero five so that's not maximized either
that's less than our 10 meters so we can
come back up here and adjust them and
let's actually just adjust it to two
meters above the crop leaving the angle
the same so we've almost doubled our
surface area from 27 to 48 meter squared
and then we'll come down here and look
at V it is now six point eight five
meters along so we're closer we're still
within that ten meters but then our
width which is G 2 to F is here ten
point seven three so we're just over
that 10 meters but we're pretty close we
could obviously dial that in to maximize
it so you can see in this example of our
10 meter by 10 meter square plot the
horizontal does it does a lot better
covering more surface area and
maximizing that field of view now as you
can see in these examples
we're doing pretty specific angles so in
order to get those angles highly
recommend using some sort of angle
locator angle finder so you can get that
right on 62 degrees or 65 degrees we
resell these but you can of course buy
your own or find your own anywhere just
so you can get those angles exactly
where you want them so that concludes
our video today on the infrared
radiometer choosing the right one for
you
if you have any questions feel free to
comment below and we'll get right back
to you on those and then if you'd like
to also just click right here and you
can subscribe to all of our after the
instrument's videos thank you