Today we're excited to bring you the results of some new research we've done here in the Crop Physiology Lab.
We're going to talk about light pollution and how sensitive cannabis is to very low levels of light.
Now, right out of the gate, I can tell you that our research shows that it is extremely sensitive,
but it is not as sensitive as most people think.
We're going to show you how to measure the light and interpret the data.
One of the terms that we have use is reagent-grade darkness.
Our laboratories are full of reagent-grade chemicals, which means they're very pure.
But the contaminants aren't really zero, they're just extremely low contaminants.
That's what reagent-grade means.
In the case of darkness, how dark is dark? Can we really get to zero if we really count photons?
We're going to talk about that.
What are the tolerance limits for cannabis? Let's take a look at this.
The people who are doing the work on this are Paul Kusuma,
who has been in this lab for five years doing a PhD,
and we're proud to announce last week he finished and now he's a post-doctoral fellow at Wageningen University in the Netherlands.
He did a lot of this work. And also Mitchell Westmoreland, who you know because he's given you lots of lectures.
These two guys have been taking careful measurements of multiple species,
we're not just testing cannabis, but some other crop plants.
When we take a look at this, look at this title—no problem seeing this title against a black background.
But now, when the sun starts to come up, this is early dawn,
how many nanomoles of lights is this? It's getting brighter, the sun's getting brighter.
At what point do plants detect it's bright?
And this is still night, but this is light pollution, and now you can't even read the title because of the light pollution.
This is a big deal. Neighbors worldwide complain about our greenhouses polluting their neighborhoods with light.
But, this is a two-edged sword because their yard lights and security lights pollute our greenhouses with light.
We need to understand and be able to measure these low light levels, so we can see when we're getting into trouble with this.
There is a dark sky organization, darksky.org, that studies the effects of very low levels of light on a wide range of species.
Lots of stories of turtles getting confused by light pollution.
It turns out there's good evidence that many of the wildlife in our national parks are more sensitive to light than our plants are.
Some people can sleep with lights on, some people have to have it completely dark.
There's all kinds of interactions with reagent-grade darkness and biology.
Here's our license plate, Delicate Arch in Arches National Park. It's a source of great national pride here in Utah.
Now this is artificially lit up to get this photograph, but guess what?
See this aurora back here? That's the city of Moab in the background with light pollution to the sky.
These are common kinds of slides.
This would have been taken with a very long shutter speed, so we can see the starlight.
So our instruments now need the equivalent of a very long shutter speed to rigorously quantify these very trace levels of light.
You can go back in the literature to see what other studies have been done, and that's something we try to do. Good scholarship.
If you look for cannabis, you get to a book by Daphne Vince-Prue, 1975. The sensitivity of seven plants to light pollution.
Now threshold value for an inhibition of flowering. That's exactly what we're interesting in.
Here's the seven species. Even back then, they were studying cannabis.
Not because of anything of medicinal value. It was an interesting botanical species that was sensitive to low light.
These numbers are in lux, but they range from 0.1 to 21.5.
So that's a huge range and these are all species that are sensitive to light.
Here's the original references they came from.
This book is a great piece of research on this.
And I want to thank Royal Heins for doing some of the early scholarship on this to find this table.
Now, let's convert from lux to micromoles per meter squared per second of photons.
Because it's not lux that triggers this, it's numbers of photons.
And assuming this is reflected sunlight off the moon, we can make a conversion to units that we're more familiar with.
And here it is. Same species, but now micromoles per meter squared per second.
The first thing you see is all these numbers are below one.
Now remember full sun is like 2,000,
so this is low, low levels of light.
Most normal meters have trouble even measuring this low level.
Garden mums are real common commercial crop. We pull black cloth on garden mums to get them dark enough.
But kalenchoe and other floriculture species. Look at poinsettia.
We have long considered poinsettia to  be our most sensitive commercial species to light pollution.
And in fact, based on this data, it is. It's four times more sensitive than mums and kalanchoe for 0.1 micromoles.
Morning glory, not a commercial species.
Cannabis, wow. Based on this data, 1975, that's far more sensitive than even poinsettias to light pollution.
Soybeans are also really sensitive, but this gives me the chance to point out that we've studies soybeans a lot,
and over the decades of repeated breeding of soybeans, the sensitivity of soybeans to low light has been breed out of them.
Our modern cultivars of soybeans can tolerate a lot more light pollution than their early predecessors of 50 years ago or more.
So it shows you that you can use breeding to shift the sensitivity to light pollution.
But that's a lot of breeding and right now we deal with this.
How do these levels compare to what we get from a full moon?
A full moon is very bright. You walk outside with a full moon on a clear night and, wow, it seems really bright.
Let's take a look at what full moon is.
This is a study we did in 2018 with some precision sensors on the roof of Apogee Instruments.
Clear sky. Moon rise, we got to a peak, moon set.
The peak was 1.6 nanomoles.
Here's 0.16 nanomoles over here. Let's get the pen on here, dark blue.
0.16.
This would be 0.0016 micromoles per meter squared per second.
As we get into this business, we have to shift our thinking from micromoles to nanomoles because the light levels get so low.
So here's that graph, just against a dark sky.
That's a picture of the Apogee light pollution detector people are using now to detect these nanomoles of light pollution.
So let's go back with that 0.0016 to our original graph and now we can put that on there.
Now we round that up to 0.002. If it's a harvest moon, some things can make the moon extra bright.
So instead of 0.0016, rounded to 0.002.
But look. These levels are almost as high as that.
0.006 is three times as high as the full moon, but it's close to the full moon causing a problem.
This data is from these references reported in 1975. That means all these studies were in the 1950s and 1960s on these crops.
How good is this data?
Fortunately, Jim Faust at Clemson University has recently done very rigorous studies on the effect of light pollution in poinsettia.
So before we look at cannabis, let's see how good his data is for poinsettia.
Here's his studies. This is Professor Faust looking at his crop.
This is a light gradient study, so down here it was very dark. The poinsettia bracts turned red like they should.
But as you got to more light over here, there's light pollution.
And these are intermediate levels of light in his study.
So he repeated this several times on several cultivars.
Here's his data.
First of all, micromoles. And this is days to anthesis.
So, this line right here means they turned red quickly up to this point,
and then as the light pollution got worse, it took longer and longer.
Up at this point over here, it took over 100 days to turn red. This is a serious problem with light pollution.
If we put some data on here, 0.04. Now remember—let's put it up here—this is 40 nanomoles.
40 nanomoles, the poinsettias started to detect this.
These dots are two different poinsettia cultivars.
In his work he didn't see species variability in poinsettia.
So anything below that is dark. Anything below 40 nanomoles.
Now remember, full moon was 2 nanomoles, so full moon is way down here on this graph.
Up here, 0.4, so that is 400 nanomoles.
And that completely inhibited the crops.
So let's keep track of this number, this is where the line starts to change direction.
Go back to our screen.
1975, this number is 100 nanomoles.
Jim Faust found they started to detect light pollution at 40 nanomoles.
So what he found was they were even more sensitive than those early studies.
40 is a lower number than 100.
So how about cannabis?
That's coming in close to full moon. Could cannabis detect the full moon?
We set out to study that. We've done replicate studies now with cannabis, with precision levels of light pollution.
When we do these studies, we turn the light pollution on. It's tiny LEDs, and we run it continuously through the night.
Here's the data.
Nanomoles, here's 40.
Now this is the level that would start to affect poinsettias.
And that took more than that, but look at this.
This is flower diameter, so 100 means they got big flowers quickly.
As we increased the light pollution up to 10, no effect. Neither Trump nor Cherry, two cultivars.
Cherry was more sensitive than Trump. As we went to 20, we saw the flowers are just smaller.
Now the plants were fine, the flowers just developed more slowly.
And quite a bit more slowly, that's half of this and it only took 20 nanomoles.
Trump is a little more tolerant, that took a little bit longer to fill out.
But based on this data, we now conclude that 10 nanomoles or lower is dark enough so that we don't get an effect on flowering in cannabis.
Remember our reference? Full moon is 2? Here's our full moon reference here.
Even the full moon is not even close to bright enough to trigger an issue in flowering in cannabis.
That's a key thing.
Now, to help you get a sense of light levels and what full moon light really is,
we're going to do a little experiment here in the lab to show you light levels.
And let's start with—this is a standard light meter that we would use to measure light for crops.
Sunlight goes to 2,000. You probably can't read this here, but can we read that here if I put it out? 11.
This is a well lit office. We've got lights in here, so every things is well lit.
So what if we turn this to the floor like that?
I'm already getting zero turning it down here.
But again, we're talking nanomoles, which are below detectable limits on this meter.
So what we're going to do now is turn the lights out and show you what nanomoles look like.
Here's an important rule of thumb, and I hope you remember this.
If you take a book, even with large print,
out in the night on the full moon, the brightest full moon, the pie in the sky, very clear skies,
take it out and try and read the book.
And I brought "Charlotte's Web," a children's book, because it's got big print. Easy to read here.
On a night with full moon, even with a dark-adapted eye, you cannot read the print in a book.
So if your greenhouse is so dark you can't read a book with big print, you're still okay. It's not going to trigger the cannabis.
If you have one LED in the corner, it's not enough to read a book. It's not going to trigger the cannabis.
This is a nice rule of thumb for how dark you are in a greenhouse or dark room facility.
Now let's try some experiments here. Let's turn out these lights and measure nanomoles.
So here we are with all of our studio lights turned off, but with a dimmable LED in the back of the room.
When we took our standard light meter to do this, there's light enough to shoot this video.
It's zeroes, it's some number less than one. It's clearly not really zero, it's just too low to detect with the standard light meter.
So we go to our light pollution detector, which is a thousand times more sensitive and reads out in nanomoles.
This has Bluetooth, so it's reading on my phone right here.
If I hold this here, I'm getting 70 nanomoles.
Now this is plenty of light pollution to cause problems, at least with cannabis.
And if I take my "Charlotte's Web" book, I have no problem reading at all with this.
But now, what if we go darker?
And we're going to try to get this even less.
Now we've reduced this to 37 nanomoles.
This is still enough light pollution to cause problems, and I can still read my book without a problem.
I might have to wait now to let my eyes adapt, but I can still read the book.
Let's see if we can get it even darker.
Now we're down 17... 13...
9... 7.
Alright, now we're down at a light level that cannabis wouldn't detect.
And now I'm going to even turn this down. We're at 4 nanomoles.
Cannabis wouldn't detect this. I look at the book and if I let my eyes adapt,
I can just barely read this book in this light at 4 nanomoles of light.
In fact, I wouldn't want to read this. Oh wow.
I have to have dark-adapted eyes to see the print, but this is 4 nanomoles measured with this.
And this is pointed right at the light source.
This gives you a sense of how dark is dark.
Now, we'll bring the light up a little bit.
Look at this, 40 nanomoles.
70 nanomoles.
These are light levels that would trigger problems, but this is a lot of light.
Now you can read this thing, you can read this thing from your computer screen where you're sitting.
And all we're giving is—now we're going down, let's hold this up here.
There's 60 nanomoles, going down 40 nanomoles.
There's 20 nanomoles.
13 nanomoles.
10 nanomoles.
I can still read the book.
7.
This is the kind of light pollution we're talking about.
See that little red LED there? There's no way that's enough to cause a problem with cannabis flowering.
It needs to be brighter than it seems.
The bottom line is our eyes are exquisitely sensitive to low light.
Our irises open up, we can detect light pollution extremely well,
but you have to measure it to see if you have a problem with cannabis.
Now let's go back to full light.
So, we're back to full light in the studio.
All of these tests we were able to run the light all the way up to 50 and above and back down here.
But you can see, once again, this zone right here below 10 is what we consider safe for cannabis.
And again, our eyes are so sensitive, we can detect 1, 2, 3, 4 down here.
But you have to measure it. You can have light pollution in one spot and ten feet away is not enough to matter.
So one crack of light could affect one plant.
If you see strange things happening with a plant in the corner, it doesn't necessarily mean it was light pollution.
It could be temperature, it could be something else. Once again, you've got to measure the light.
So, back to this. Full moon.
Our data here suggests this would be 6 nanomoles from 1975.
Our data indicate that this number is closer to 10 for the most sensitive species detecting light.
So, one other thing we have done is interactions with temperature.
What we have found, I'm not going to go into this in detail, but this is nanomoles of light pollution.
The slope of the line is steeper for cool night temperatures.
That means there's an interaction with night temperature.
Plants appear to be more sensitive to light pollution when the nights are cooler than when they're warm.
This is an area of active study, and I don't think this is going to wildly shift the data,
but it might shift it from 10 down to 7 for detection limits, if the nights are cool.
Now the average cannabis is somewhere right in the middle here.
It's neither a warm night—the warm nights in this, I think, were 28 degrees and the cool nights were 20 Celsius.
So, somewhere in the 80s and the 60s at night.
This was a big range, but it might interact with temperature.
And finally, how does it interact with color?
All of our studies were done with pure red light, which is the most potent source of light
for phytochrome and for triggering light responses.
That's why we're comfortable saying 10 is a safe limit.
This is a study of the growth of the flowers with time after the start of short days.
We took a micrometer and measured the flowers.
Now the first thing you want to look at is the control. Completely dark.
And the flowers got big at this rate.
Look at blue light. Blue light, at the same intensity as all the others, had no effect on the plants.
It's remarkable. We know that red has an effect, but in this study, look at green light.
Green light was just as potent as red light for the plants.
We say green lights are safe lights for plants.
In this study, the green light was just as potent as red light. Why is that?
This is a picture of a cross section of a leaf.
Here's the top. Here's the bottom of that leaf.
Chlorophyll absorbs blue and red very efficiently, so those colors don't penetrate.
But chlorophyll reflects green, and the green hits and penetrates deep into the leaf,
and this is part of the reason that green light is not as safe as we might think.
Now, don't go out here running around saying, "Dr. Bugbee says that green light is not safe at all."
Our eyes are so sensitive to green, we can see plants with 1/100 the amount of green light as we can with blue or red.
If you've got to have a light, it's still the best color of light.
But, it is not completely safe.
Some outfits have green lights on at night. That's a bad idea. You shouldn't have any lights on at night.
It's still difficult.
So it interacts with color.
We're looking at what we call reciprocity.
What if we give the plants a bright flash versus a low steady level?
Are they the same thing? We're studying it.
In some other crops there is reciprocity. It is related to the cumulative dose of light at night.
Really, we talk about daily light integral, we should now be talking about night light integral for light pollution.
All of our studies were done with steady state light pollution.
And we're starting to study what happens if we give them bright light for a short period of time.
Lot of interesting stuff. It's a new frontier and cannabis is a wonderful botanical species for this,
because it is so sensitive to low levels of light at night.
This stuff, this work, led to this paper by Paul Kusuma, published in Frontiers in Plant Science.
"Improving the predictive value of phytochrome photoequilibrium: Consideration of spectral distortion within a leaf."
What we have found is our prediction of phytochrome needs to change too because,
again, green light penetrating leaves so effectively.
Phytochrome is the molecule that triggers plants to get tall and short. Triggers perception of shade.
And our understanding of how colors affect that has been inadequate in the past.
One important consideration in all this is, does light pollution cause hermaphrodites and hermaphroditic flowers?
There's a lot of observations suggesting that it does and there's certainly the potential for that.
It's a statistical thing, it's not black and white.
But again, if you're in the safe zone, we don't have any evidence that it causes hermaphroditic flowers.
That's a very interesting question, a lot of things affect hermaphrodism. Genetics is a big one.
We're actively studying that and we'll talk more about that in another episode.
One final thought.
This is human vision and how our perception of color changes as the light gets dimmer.
We talk about the photopic curve and that means how we see colors of light when an area is well lit.
And the peak here is right in the middle of the green light and look at green lights.
At least 10 times more sensitive than red and blue light, but look what happens when the lights dim.
Our rods and cones adjust and this is called the Purkinje Effect.
And this shifts and it's called the scotopic curve in low light.
And now we can see blues and greens better, but look at the reds. This is the reds here.
We can't see red colors in low light.
Here's a geranium flower. We can see it fine. Low light it's less red, and even lower light you see the flower, but it's gray.
That's just a function of shifting.
I put this slide in here because I think we're going to see something like this for plants.
They perceive colors differently in very low light than they do in high light.
This is some of the cutting edge research that we're doing on light pollution now.
So, stay tuned, we'll keep publishing papers and share the results with you.
But for now, measure the light so you're into the safe threshold when you're growing cannabis.
We'll talk to you in the next episode.