[Music]
we kind of introduced my topic at the
end of his last presentations and talk a
bit about spectral reflectance and I put
all of these pictures and the different
scales on my introductory slides because
there's lots of different scales that
you can consider when measuring
reflectance everywhere from a single
leaf measurement all the way up to
satellite measurements of the Earth's
surface so I think mostly what I'm going
to talk about is more reflectance
principles but we'll be down in more of
this range of scale but some of or most
of what I will say will apply to all of
the scales and again if you have any
questions feel free to ask while I'm
going through the slides reflectance is
a pretty simple concept we just divide
the reflected radiation so everything
that's bouncing off the surface and
coming back by the radiation that's
incident on the surface and it's
powerful simple but powerful because we
can learn a lot about surface properties
surface conditions based on how the
reflectance signal changes we've already
seen this plot more than one time today
so I won't spend too much time on it but
it shows the shortwave radiation
spectrum at Earth's surface and so in
most applications not all because we can
do this in the laboratory and we can
also do it on small leaf samples where
we often use artificial lights that
we're talking about the scales of plants
canopies and flux towers things like
that typically the light surface or the
lights or
is the Sun and so incident radiation is
these data that you see right here then
we have to invert our sensor and measure
the reflected signal and that goes in
the numerator of our equation when we do
that it looks like this for some
surfaces that we're all familiar with I
have water soil a plant canopy and snow
so you can see one thing that sticks out
immediately from this slide is we can
use reflectance to characterize what it
is at the surface I don't know that
that's necessarily a major application
because there's other ways as
characterizing what's going on at the
surface but the reflective signatures
are very very different when we move
from one surface to the next
so this gives you an idea of how much it
costs to measure the different
wavelength ranges so to get the the
visible spectrum and a little bit of the
near-infrared maybe 350 or 400
nanometers up to about a thousand
nanometers or so is this reasonable
price tag then to get that same
wavelength range plus more of the
near-infrared now we're talking about
maybe half of the solar spectrum we're
getting a bigger price tag and to get
the whole spectrum we're talking about a
lot more money so the price scales with
the amount of information that you're
measuring and I'm mostly going to talk
about this range of 350 or 400 up into
the a thousand range largely because
that's the more affordable range and
that's the type of instruments that we
typically deal with at least at Apogee
instruments so I want to focus on the
reflectance spectrum for a plant canopy
for a minute you can see there are a lot
of unique features here one that we
already talked about earlier is the
photosynthetically active radiation
range which is 400 to 700 nanometers the
reason that it's so much lower than a
lot of the other parts of the
reflectance spectrums because green
leaves have a lot of chlorophyll in them
and the chlorophyll is absorbing all of
the photosynthetic photons for
photosynthesis and so this whole portion
of the spectrum is depressed small
values because all of those photons are
being absorbed for photosynthesis
and within that range we have this
little green peak we're all familiar
with it you can see it applied plants or
green
there's the red edge so the point where
we transition from the
photosynthetically active range to the
near-infrared range it jumps up here
because everything beyond about 700 or
non-photosynthetic photons so a high
percentage of them are being reflected
and all these dips here are water
absorption bands so healthy plant leaves
tend to have a lot of water in them and
once you get out into the near infrared
range water is a pretty good absorber of
certain wavelength there's a water band
about 970 or 980 another one around 11
to 1200 another one about 1400 and then
another one about 1900 nanometers and so
we can learn something about potentially
about photosynthesis about water
different variables based on
measurements of plant reflectance
this slide illustrates how you would do
it for a single leaf so typically this
is done in the laboratory and it
requires an artificial light source
here's a fiber-optic cable that's going
to absorb the light take it back to a
spectral radiometer which actually makes
the measurement so when we start we have
to have a reflectance spectrum a
reference reflectance spectrum we use a
small highly reflective white surface to
give us a reference spectrum essentially
this would represent the denominator in
the equation when we make this
measurement this would represent all of
the incident radiation assuming our
reflectance panel has a high
reflectivity something near 100% and
then we after we make our measurement on
a reflectance panel and often this is
made out of spectra lawn or PTFE some
material that has really high
reflectivity near 100% once we get our
reference measurement the denominator of
the reflectance equation then we can put
the sample under the light source and
measure reflectance from the sample and
you'll notice we have to have some kind
of flat black background behind the
sample Bruce talked a little bit ago
about how reflectance and transmission
spectra look very similar they're kind
of analogues of each other well if you
have some photons that are being
transmitted through the leaf and you
have a highly reflective background like
if we flip the leaf over top of our
reflectance panel some of those
transmitted photons would reflect off
the white background we transmitted back
through the lease and actually get
measured as reflected photon rather than
photons that were transmitted all the
way through the leaf reflected off the
back and then transmitted back through
the leaf until you
when you measure your sample you put it
on top of some kind of flat black
background that has a very low
reflectivity so we can assume that all
the reflection comes from the sample
itself in this case a leaf and so this
measurement as I mentioned it represents
the denominator of our equation this
measurement over here represents the
numerator of the equation so this is how
you would make a laboratory measurement
of a single leaf sample and when we move
to the field to do it for a plant canopy
for example the actual method isn't that
much different I'll explain it when we
get there so just to give you an idea of
the kind of information that leaf
reflectance might indicate we have two
reflectance spectra here one where the
the peak in the green and then some of
this radiation in the red is more
reflective than the other the
reflectance is higher I should say this
would represent a well fertilized leaf
with a high nitrogen content this one
would represent potential of nitrogen
depth so you get changes in the spectrum
as a function of properties of the leaf
here it's related to nitrogen but there
could be other other properties that we
can we can measure by analyzing the
changes in the reflectance spectrum
and so when we move to the field the
reflectance for a plant canopy look
similar to the reflectance of a single
leaf so the previous data were for a
single leaf this is actually a
reflectance spectrum that we measured on
a plant canopy in times test we're
interested you know very specific
portions of the of the spectrum one that
everybody I think is familiar with is
the difference between red reflectance
and near-infrared reflectance so I
highlighted them here and for a long
time we've used reflectance measurements
of these two wavelengths somewhere in
the red and somewhere in the
near-infrared to quantify NDVI you've
probably heard this acronym before it's
the normalized difference vegetation
index where we take near-infrared
reflectance - red reflectance in the
numerator and then we take the sum of
the two in the denominator because we
have strong absorption of photons and
low reflection in the red and high
reflection in the near-infrared
essentially NDVI is a green index and we
can measure it it tells us about you
know how much leaf area is covering the
surface how green the surface is there
are small devices this is an instrument
from from decagon devices that we can
use to measure specific indices like
NDVI so this small sensor that I've
shown here is essentially a 2 channel or
a 2 band radiometer it has one sensor in
it that measures the red range and
another sensor in it that measures the
near-infrared range it makes those
measurements does this calculation
internally and outputs and NDVI values
so if we're only interested in in
you know specific indices like NDVI then
small low-cost radiometers like this can
be very useful I showed some prices
earlier of spectra radiometers and you
know 3000 to 6000 was a rough estimate
of an instrument that would give you
this reflectance spectrum this
two-channel radiometer is about an order
of magnitude lower this would be maybe a
300 dollar instrument somewhere in in
that ballpark but red and near-infrared
reflectance aren't the only wavelengths
of interest the red edge can be very
informative often we're interested in
blue reflectance and there's a another
index kind of like NDVI the mathematical
form is exactly the same you'll see in
just a second that uses reflectance at
531 nanometers our green wavelength and
reflectance at 570 nanometers out of a
yellow wavelength and it's called PRI
this means photochemical reflectance
index so we take the reflectance at 570
and minus the reflective at 531 and
divide that by the sum of the two and we
get this PRI and it's still being
studied there's a lot of work going on
to better understand what PRI is
actually measuring but it seems to be
closely related to light use efficiency
of plant and so PRI and NDVI we can
measure again with these these small
low-cost devices like this and I will
say that decagon also has a PRI
instrument in addition to the NDVI
instrument and there turns out there are
a whole host of fairly simple reflective
indices that have been published in the
literature here's a relatively recent
review paper this is actually a table
from that paper
we're 20 different
I think there's 20 of them on there
relatively simple reflective indices are
shown here that are all attempting to
quantify different things we've got
chlorophyll content photosynthetic
activity liquid water content
carotenoids and xanthophylls cycle
anthocyanins canopy water content
there's lots of different plant
properties that people have attempted to
estimate using reflectance indices or
learn about using reflectance indices
you actually got a list of from a
colleague one time its unpublished but
the list that she had compiled had 62
different reflectance indices in it so
there's a lot of these things out there
I guess the point that I want to make is
if again if you're interested in in one
index like just NDVI or just PRI these
relatively simple to band and sometimes
I've seen three or four band radiometers
are available to give you information on
a single index but it makes sense that
why not use the whole spectrum if we can
rather than trying to just build sensors
for specific indexes only and so that's
what a spectral radiometer gives you is
the measurement of the entire spectrum
and one of the reasons I think that
maybe this hasn't been more widely used
or is maybe just starting to be to be
more and more applied in in research and
especially in commercial operations in
the past spectra radiometers tended to
be expensive oftentimes they're large
and heavy and so
there and they require operator or
computer and so they're not necessarily
easy instruments to take from the
laboratory and use routinely in the
field it can be a little bit challenging
so hence there is a lot of use of these
small narrowband single or excuse me
dual or three Chandler radiometers so
the apogee spectroradiometer we tried to
design it to overcome some of these
these challenges and limitations and
make it more of a field instrument in
addition to a lab instrument if you
wanted to use it in the laboratory some
of the the features are highlighted here
but really we wanted to try to make
something low-cost small lightweight and
there it is compared to a couple quantum
sensors just so you can get an idea of
the size and so some applications and I
won't go into a ton of detail here this
is the kind of thing that you could do
with a unit like this continuous
automated measurement of plant canopies
who often were interested in plant
response to environmental change and
this might be one way to quantify that
measuring reflectance spectra another
potential application is precision
agriculture you know rapid field
phenotype of crop plant looking for
differences in genetic lines differences
in different treatments we can mount
them on mobile instruments and collect
high-frequency data for precision Eric
and so I said a few minutes ago when I
was explaining how to make the
reflectance measurement in the lab but
the procedure was relatively similar for
making measurements in the field well so
there's a couple of different approaches
that you can take one would be to mount
one instrument level and looking up and
another instrument pointing down at the
plant canopies so this gives you the
reflected spectrum this gives you the
incoming spectrum the ratio of the two
is a reflectance measurement the using
an approach like this you actually have
to match the spectral radiometer so in
essence it's a field calibration we want
we want the data for this one to match
this one when we have a hundred percent
reflectance so what that means is you
have to use a reflectance panel which is
a diffused reflector with reflectance
near 100% to match the spectral
radiometer zoom before you start it
essentially means you have to put your
reference panel your reflectance panel
underneath the downward looking
instrument and then calibrate this one
to match the output from that one and
then when you remove the reflectance
panel you can take the ratio directly
will be a measurement of reflectance so
there is some
you say requirements of users being in
the field to to make the system work
before you start we have to match the
spectra radiometers another option is
you could you could make measurements
with the single downward looking
instruments if we take this one away we
can make measurements with this one by
saving the measurement when we've got a
reflectance panel here this becomes the
denominator in our equation and then
when we remove the reflectance panel
subsequent measurements become the
numerator in the equation we just take
the ratio of the two the challenge with
doing it this way is every time the sky
conditions change we have to make a new
measurement of the background radiation
with the reflectance panel because the
if the sky conditions change that means
the denominator and the reflectance
equation changed we have to account for
that
so there's multiple ways to do it using
two instruments like this would be the
way to do it for long term unattended
measurement if you only had a single
measurement that'd be the way to do it
if it's more of an on-the-fly
mobile measurement where it's convenient
to make the reflectance measurement the
background measurement periodically as
the sky conditions change so we actually
we actually made some measurements we're
still in the process of beta testing and
this instrument we actually made some
measurements in the backyard of our
facility at Apogee instruments in Logan
Utah just over a grass surface so our
configuration essentially looks like
this we have a upward facing instrument
and a downward facing instrument we use
a spectral on panel to match the
downward instrument to the upward
instrument and this gives you some some
sample data as I mentioned this was over
turfgrass
to make it a bit more interesting we
intentionally stopped irrigating the the
turfgrass so this is the reflectance
measurement on the last day that the
irrigation system was on and then we
turned off the water about three days
later on August 24th the reflectance
spectrum was here five days later on
August 29 it was here and then four days
later on September 2nd
it was here so you can see there's some
pretty substantial changes in the
reflectance spectrum as the grass dries
out going from well-watered to water
stress this is the kind of the kind of
data that spectra radiometers yield the
changes in for plant responses to
environmental change
and we can potentially learn a lot about
plants without having to sample them and
take them back to the lab for analysis
because now we have a way to to measure
the light reflectance is the function of
changes in the environment