I'm Bruce Bugbee, president of Apogee Instruments. This is a series of
seminars on principles of environmental measurement. I'm not sure what number
we're on but today we're going to talk about photosynthetically active
radiation. To me every single component to this is critical to understanding
plant growth. This is one that I've been particularly involved with for a long
time in my career, and I want to give credit to Mark Blonquist who is
the chief scientist at Apogee. He and I have worked on this together for more
than 10 years refining this measurement and understanding its effects on plant
growth. So, let's get started with this, first thing we want to look at is what I
consider to be the eighth cardinal parameters for plant growth. So, what are
these eight parameters? So,
here we have a plant, and we always want to show the anatomically correct roots
of this plant. Well let's take the below ground parameters, first, of all we have
nutrients. That's one. Second, we have water. Third, we have
oxygen. Three parameters below ground that are critical to excellent plant
growth. How about the ones above ground. Well we have temperature and I'm going to
abbreviated that temp. We have humidity. So, 1 2 3 4 5 not necessarily an order of importance.
Carbon dioxide; critical parameter. 7- wind. We got eight, we're
missing one. The elephant in the room is radiation, and I'll put that in a giant box up here. We can
measure all of these parameters better than the plants can sense them but in the
case of radiation the plant is so exquisitely sensitive to that that our
best sensors are only equal to what the plant sees. So, I should put some
arrows here for radiation coming in and specifically today we're going to talk
about photosynthetic radiation, a subset of this, but I put this slide in here to
really emphasize how critical it is to do
radiation. All of these sensors, we can tell temperature by it's cold its
warm. We can feel the soil for water. we can tell if its high humidity. We think
we can tell temperature and we can tell radiation, but our eyes are a terrible
light meter. Our irides contract when we go out in bright sunlight and we don't
realize how bright it is. Then come back  inside they expand.
We have a very poor ability to tell the amount of light and the result of that
is, I'm going to draw another little figure here.Here's our plant outside, now
we get that same plant that looks like this, tiny leaves. People say oh your plant must be
low on potassium, it is low on light. And, anytime you have indoor plants you
really need to understand radiation. So, I can't emphasize more the importance
of really understanding that. So, let's take a look at this, multiple sources of
lights to measure plants. Right, we have the Sun. Here these are different types of
electric lights: high pressure sodium, ceramic metal halide,
compact fluorescent all with different colors of light, and there's a whole body
of studies about what's the right color of light for plants, and I'm not going to go
into that. But, our research says there's not as much difference as you might
think among colors of light. But, we're missing one key color on here and that is LEDs,
light emitting diodes. This is a picture of some plant growth chambers with different
colors of the LEDs. There's a tremendous amount of research going on with the
colors of LEDs and people are using them for plant growth. So now look, a sensor
has to integrate all these different types of light, and accurately predict
radiation for plant growth and that's the focus of this seminar. How do we do
that, what are the options for doing that, and making accurate measurements of this
so we can predict the rate of plant growth?
Alright, so a couple of definitions. First, and these confusing a lot of
people P-A-R is photosynthetically active radiation and that just means that
radiation that drives photosynthesis. UV light, that's radiation but
plants filter that out, it doesn't result in photosynthesis. Near-infrared light
doesn't have high enough
energy for photosynthesis this is the radiation for photosynthesis, and we'll
come back to this again, it's 400 to 700 nanometers. This is close to
the visible range as well what are eyes see that's the radiation that drives
photosynthesis. Alright second definition, photosynthetic photon flux or
photosynthetic photon flux density. Now these two things
refer to the same thing in the next slide I'll explain the use of
these two terms. This is the whole amount of radiation again between four and
seven hundred nanometers. So, really all of these terms refer to the same thing.
They're all this radiation that drives photosynthesis, these terms here are
technically a little more exact and PPF and PPFD. So we get then to
what's a quantum, and this gets back to Einstein and quantum physics. A quantum is
a mole of photons and this mole is Avogadro's number of photons so it's
these particles coming in and we know from the Stark Einstein Law
that one photon excites one electron and that's the first step in
photosynthesis so we're really interested in measuring, with these, moles
of photons and that's what the sensors measure, and we'll talk about that in the
next slide. But quantum sensor then, is a sensor to measure all this stuff
that's when we say quantum sensor we could say a PAR sensor, we could say a PPF sensor,
or PPFD, they're all the same thing, but that's where this word comes from
quantum sensor. Or, if the sensor is connected to a meter then it's a quantum
meter. Now I'll show you some examples of that.
In fact I'll show you an example right now. Here is a quantum meter, sensor plus
the meter, and reads out all by itself you can buy just the sensor and hook it
up to a data logger and then it's a quantum sensor. That's all it means
between the two of those definitions.
All right now, I want to talk about this issue of flux, and I've given myself a
nice white board to do this. Flux, if we are to talk to our physicist colleagues flux has
two definitions and you would think by this time in the evolution of science
read out this term all worked out. One definition is per time and in the case
of photosynthesis this would be moles M-O-L-E-S per second, that's one
definition of flux. Moles of photons per second, but equally valid is per
area and time. Together.  And this means moles per meter squared per second.
Even in physics
these two things are used interchangeably. If we use this
definition per time we would have PPF and then where's the area in here, we
better add D for density to this definition to make sure we've got the
area. If we use this definition
and we said PPFD
well wait a minute we've got per area and per area again, so this D could be
redundant. We wouldn't need it. If you look through the literature on this half
of the people say PPF and the other half say PPFD, the terms are used
interchangeably.
They mean the exact same thing, but it's been confusing to people
just as it's confusing to physicist. Is it flux only per unit time or does it
mean per unit area and time? There's the difference. For the purposes of this we
don't need to worry about it PPF and PPFD are equal. All right, now, let's go to what
we're looking at. Here's photosynthetically active, photosynthetic
photon flux,  photosynthetic photon flux density it means radiation between 400
and 700. Sharp cut offs. Now, remember that Stark Einstein Law that you're
remembering for the test,
equal weighting of all photons 1 photon excites 1 electron. Every photon
coming in up here gets equal weighting on this chart. These are blue in here,
this is ultraviolet, this is blue, this is green in the middle, and then red, and
then right after 700 its infrared, IR. Thermal radiation doesn't
cause photosynthesis its just this here with equal weighting of protons. T his is
what we're after a sensor that can get this sharp cut offs on the end so we can
predict photosynthesis and plant growth by measuring this. Right let's take a
look at how we do this. Here is our quantum sensor we just talked
about very simple. One detector, right here, one filter and one output if we ran it
over here to a meter. This is a quantum sensor,
but this has to be designed with filters to get all of these colors exactly right
and that's a tricky business, very hard to do. If we make the jump to lightspeed
now we have a spectroradiometer and a prism it breaks up the light and we have
lots of arrays down here and this goes off to a meter. This is more
accurate it's also more than ten times the cost. So, we're going to look at these
how accurate are these compared to a spectroradiometer and comparing back and
forth. This is two options to do this quantum sensor, spectroradiometer. Okay. Here
is what they look like these are quantum sensors one from Licor, one
from apogee, and the apogee spectroradiometer, little bigger a lot
more stuff going on in here.  If we did x-ray vision we'd
have a prism and here. The light comes in it breaks the light up into multiple
detectors down here, and these have a single filter. These are
the most widely sold in North America Licor and Apogee. Licor came out with
a new sensor, they have a better head. It sheds water better now, than this one
which tended to trap water.  It has a nicer cable, it has a cable like
this. But, I'll talk about the new sensor in the old sensor they're
both equally accurate. It's just how it sheds water and how rugged it is
for outside. So there's the comparison, about ten times the cost
for this. So if you need very accurate measurements, this is the instrument of
choice. But, let's talk about how close we can get with these. Alright here's our
box again
equal weighting of photons. Kipp &amp; Zonen is widely sold in Europe, and
here's the Licor. Look at how closely they match the curve now this is
really good
sharp cut offs because there is multiple colors of light. It's real important to
have a sharp cut off here. These are their two model numbers. There's the new
Licor looks a lot like the old Licor and it's equally accurate to this.
Now let's look at the original Apogee sensor, that Apogee is short for some
time
here's the curve. It comes up a little slow in the blue and look how it cuts off
here, at about six hundred and sixty so what misses this radiation. That's not
serious because it's calibrated to light sources, unless you get a light source
with a lot of radiation right here. Now let's take a look at an example of that.
LEDs may come into the picture, this is a red LED and its called
deep red cause it's very close to this cut off I'm going to put deep red here but
this is common in some LEDs. Of course this is a blue LED, but
look at the problem it cuts off before it can capture that deep red LED. So, this
is an excellent sensor for all types of light sources except when there's a deep
red LED in the light source. So what can we do about that? Let's take a look this
is the original Apogee that blue line that we just looked at. Apogee developed
a full spectrum quantum sensor
that's this gold line right here, that cuts off here. So you can see the gold the green and the
blue line are all very similar comes up better here. So if you need to measure
red LEDs or LED spectra this is better than the original, but the difference in
cost for this full spectrum is about two times as expensive, so all of
these are quite a bit more expensive than this. But, if you measure LEDs you
need them.
Let's take a look at this here is the original black sensor. Many people
have this. Here's the new one it's slightly taller slightly bigger head.
Because it's a higher end sensor it's a gold color instead of a black color,
that's what the two sensors look like. Original and full spectrum. Now let's go
back to that graph and here's the difference again, right here. Now let's
take a close look at the accuracy of all of these sensors and to do that we
need to use this fancy integrated method originally developed in 1966 where it
takes all the colors of light and it multiplies this by the accuracy of the
spectral accuracies of these. This is something that Mark Blonquist has done
in great detail for all these. This is the equation to do it. I'm not going to go
into that now except let's look at the results how close do we get. Kipp &amp; Zonnen,
Licor and this is also the 190 R, is very close to this, and then the original
Apogee and the new Apogee. Sunlight and cloudy,
these are all tiny errors, so you really don't need the full spectrum to be
accurate if you're just doing sun light measurements. Any errors less than
certainly 1% are very tiny, even 2% errors are fairly
small for these. All right, now we take cool white fluorescent lights. All these
errors, less than 2%. This is calibrated here. They are
calibrated to be 0. Small errors. Small errors. Now look at the original Apogee
here's LEDs. Red and blue LEDs. Remember it didn't capture that red peak? Big errors.
If you're not using it under there it's fine, but if you need these
you need for spectrum. We jump to full spectrum and everything gets better.
Metal halide a little better. High pressure sodium, better. But these errors
here in particular are small and you take a close look at this, and positive
video and study it. You can see that the errors between Kipp &amp; Zonnen, Licor, and
the full spectrum Apogee are all really small under all of these different types
of light sources. This one has an asterisk   because it has separate
calibrations for Sun and electric lights. That's explained on the Apogee website.
All right let's take a look at the next slide here.
Spectroradiometer,  remember the ten times, bigger, more expensive sensor? It nails every single
source. 0 errors, because its measuring every color individually. So if you
really need excellent accuracy you need to spectroradiometer to do this, but most
people if they have two or three percent accuracy that's good enough for their
applications. Okay, I'm going to conclude on this slide Apogee also makes a line
quantum sensor and it looks like this. When we want to measure radiation
underneath the canopy it's really variable,
there's bright light and shadows. This sensor averages the light over the whole
length of this. If you start to cover some of these
it gives you a proportionately reduced reading. This is something that is
helpful for people for transmitted light. Of course I have examples here
hooked up to meters.  I guess I should put them in the same order
as this, but the old and the new sensors. Again the new one is full spectrum and
more accurate under all the different colors of light. I hope this overview
of some terminology and some differences among meters is helpful to understand
and make more accurate measurements of photosynthetically active radiation. We
look forward to another session on other topics in environmental biophysics
thanks for listening.