Apogee Instruments Infrared Radiometer are excellent for measuring surface
temperatures in applications that require extreme accuracy and zero
interference to the target. Scientists use them in many ways such as: monitoring
plant canopy temperatures, to detect water stress;  taking road surface readings
in harsh climates; measuring water and snow temperatures in hydrological
studies; spot checking solar panel temperatures, to ensure efficiency; and
more. When it comes to precision and durability, Apogee sets the standard. Each
infrared radiometer has an industry-leading uncertainty of 0.2 degrees celsius at a
range of -30 to 65 celsius with aa response time of less than one second. To
eliminate water vapor errors the sensors unique germanium window, matches the
8 to 14 micron atmosphere window and any emissivity errors are eliminated by
applying a correction formula when measuring background temperature. Finally, each
sensor is housed in a sealed aluminum body to provide years of reliable
service in any environment, with a radiation shield to protect from rapid
temperature changes.  As the final step of production each unit is custom
calibrated and quality checked, using a state of the art temperature chamber
that puts each sensor through a fifteen hour performance cycle before it leaves the
factory. For added flexibility, Apogee features models with various
half angles field of view,
including 14 degrees, 18 degrees, 22 degrees, and our wide format, 32 by 30
degree model, for measuring surfaces at shallower angles. To maximize
compatibility with dataloggers each model is available in both an analogue
version, with a microvolt output, and a digital SDI-12 model, for
instantaneous readings. All sensors are available with an integrated handheld
meter. Tor more information about Apogee's line of infrared radiometers,
visit us on the web at www.apogeeinstruments.com.