I'm gonna talk about surface temperature
measurements using infrared radiometers. If you have any questions while I'm talking
feel free to raise your hand and ask and
I'll do my best to address it.
I have lots of slides unlike Bruce so
we're going to shift technologies just a
little bit, but surface temperature can
be a very important variable in lots of
environmental applications. I'm going
to talk about it more in relation to
plants today but bear in mind that you
can use infrared technology to measure
soil surface temperatures, snow surface
temperatures, roadways if you're
interested in road conditions for
example. The three key components to an
infrared radiometer listed here you have
to have a radiation detecto,r you have to
have an internal temperature sensor, then
you have to have a housing to contain
the two and be rugged so that its stable
in changing environmental
conditions. So the basic operation is as follows,
we all know from from physics that all
objects that have a temperature above
absolute zero emit infrared radiation. So,
whatever you point the sensor at is
going to be emitting infrared radiation
towards the sensor in this case its a
plant canopy and the sensor itself has a
temperature above absolute zero so its also
going to be emitting radiation back out
so to speak, and the signal that's
actually measured by the radiation
detector inside the radiometer is
proportional on this difference between
the absorbed radiation that's coming
from the surface that you're pointing it at
and the emitted radiation from the
detector itself and those signals can be
quite small example of a common infrared
radiometer output 60 microvolt that's
0.06 millivolts per degree C
difference between the target that
you're looking at and the temperature of
the sensor itself. What this means is
if you're making an analog measurement
of this, you're measuring the voltage
directly, you need a high-resolution
voltmeter in order to measure that small
signal and to get an accurate number
so I've listed here about 1 micro volt is required.
You have to have a high-end datalogger or
voltmeter to do this.
In the absorbed radiation, the amount
of radiation coming in is less than the
amount of radiation going out then the
radiation balance at the detector itself
is negative and you'll get a negative
voltage so the opposite is true when you
have more radiation coming in then what's
going out the radiation balance at the
detector is positive and you'll get a
positive voltage rather than a negative
voltage, and so in addition to needing a
voltmeter that can measure small signals
in the micro volt range
you also need one that can measure
polarity both positive and negative
voltages. Right and so I mentioned a
minute ago that we all remember from
physics radiation and temperature are
closely linked. All objects with a
temperature above absolute zero emit
radiation, and the actual equation that
quantifies the relationship between the
two is called the Stefan Boltzmann
equation, where the the energy emitted by
an object in this
case its the plant canopy is equal to a
constant, that's the sigma times the
fourth power of the absolute temperature.
So if we're able to to measure the
radiation being emitted or the energy
being emitted by an object then we can
calculate the temperature, and that's the
basic premise for how these infrared
sensors work. Right so another important
component of infrared sensors that I
didn't actually list on the previous
slide is the filter that goes in
front of the radiation detector, and so
radiation detectors tend to be black
bodies, meaning they're good
absorbers of all the wavelengths of
radiation that are incident on them.
Remember we only want to measure the
wavelengths that are related to the
temperature of the surface. In order
to  build a radiometer that measures
what we're interested in
we have to put a filter in front of it
to give us just the wavelengths of
radiation that
we're interested in. So the radiation
detector should include a filter that
blocks all of the long-wave radiation
that's outside of what we call the
atmospheric window. The atmospheric
window is the wavelength between 8
and 14 micron, and I have a graph here
that shows wavelength on the x-axis from
5 to 20 micron and then transmittance
of the atmosphere on the y-axis.
The reason we choose 8 to 14
micron is that's the wavelength range
is called the atmospheric window and
it's essentially the the wavelengths where
the atmosphere is transparent to
long-wave radiation meaning if you point
a sensor with the filter that has 8
to 14 micron window on it
that radiation is going to come through
the atmosphere rather than be absorbed
by the molecules, water vapor
and CO2, in the atmosphere. So it's just
the wavelength where the sensor sees
through the atmosphere, so to speak.
Below 8 micron there's the lots of
absorption by water vapor molecules and
above 14 micron there's lots of
absorption by carbon dioxide molecules.
We want to try to measure the
surface radiation and not the
atmospheric radiation, therefore, we need
a filter that matches the atmospheric window.
Just to give you an idea of
calibration, I've got a couple quick
pictures right here. This shows the
calibration system that we use at Apogee
Instruments to calibrate infrared
radiometers and there's lots of these
things commercially available and we're
going to let you play around with some
of these handheld devices later you can
get models like this really cheaply at
the hardware store, and you point them at
the surface that you, you pull the
trigger and it gives you a temperature.
I just measured the temperature of the
floor as 71 Fahrenheit or if we
convert it to Celsius about 22 Celsius.
These are fine especially
for demonstration purposes or just
spot-checks where high accuracy isn't
required, but the main difference between
something like this that you can buy at
the hardware store for a few dollars and
something like this that we manufactured
at Apogee Instruments is really the
calibration. Something like this the
accuracy is probably 1-2 Celcius. Here
I'm just showing the sensors, the
uncertainty of the the calibration is
about 0.2 Celsius. So there's an
order of magnitude difference between
the accuracy of something like this and
a research grade instrument, and what
you're looking at here is actually a
two-component system and it's kind of
hard to to see it but in the next slide
I think it will become clear. There's
this cap piece that fits on top of a
large piece of aluminum. The piece of
aluminum has a big hole in it shaped
like a cone and that's painted flat black.
We use that as the blackbody radiation
source that we can fine-tune the
temperatures and get specific values of
of temperature independent of the
sensor temperatures themselves. This
cap pieces another block of aluminum has
a bunch of holes in it that you can
slide the sensors into and then
independently control their temperature
what you have is a target or the
blackbody cone and a cap
that fit together, but we can
independently control the temperatures
of the two and set this temperature at
one value and the sensors at a different
value and derive a whole set of data
that allows us to get sensor specific
calibration coefficients for for all the
radiometers and we can fine tune it to
0.2 C uncertainty. Just to give you
an idea there's the actual calibration
device with the the cap piece pulled off
of it so you can see that it's a black
body. I have another one a small one that
will use for a really brief
demonstration later so this is
called a Leslie cube or if you look it
up on the internet sometimes it's called
professor Leslie's cube.
I don't know who professor Leslie is but
I'd like to meet him someday.
It's a really simple and powerful device
that will use in a few minutes to
illustrate the concept of emissivity but
essentially what you're looking at here
and what you're looking at here similar
devices that you can use to calibrate
the instruments.
Alright, so once you have a functional
sensor that's calibrated and you take it
to the field to make measurement it's
not just a simple matter of putting the
sensor out there recording the
temperature that it gives you and
accepting that as the the true value of
surface temperature. We actually have to
correct emissivity affects. Emissivity
is just a fraction of blackbody
emittance. Something like this
black body cone here the black-body cone
that I showed you on the previous slide,
they have very high emissivities well over
0.99, meaning they're almost black
bodies. A black-body is a a perfect
emitter meaning it emits all of the
theoretically possible radiation for its
temperature. Something that has an
emissivity less than one is often called
a gray body and it's basically it's not
a perfect emitter, meaning it emits some
fraction of radiation less than it
otherwise would if it were a black-body.
An emissivity is is how we quantify the
fraction of black-body emittance, so if
you have a surface with an emissivity of
one for example the only radiation
coming from the surface that arrives at
the sensor is radiation that was
emitted by the surface but if you have a
surface that is not a black-body for the emissivity is
less than one here will say 0.98, which is a pretty good estimate of
emissivity for a plant canopy. That means
most of the radiation incident on the
detector is coming from the surface of
interest but there's actually a small
fraction of radiation coming from the
background if it's outside the the
background is the sky. There willl be a small
fraction of radiation incident at the
surface that's coming from the sky. The reason
why is the long wave reflection at the
surface is 1 minus the emissivity, so
if our emissivity is 0.98 that means
our reflection of long way this
0.02. Essentially you have
98% of your radiation
is coming from the plants, which we're
trying to measure and 2% is
coming from the background or the sky
because being reflected off of the plant surface
sources towards the radiometer. You might
ask yourself why is that a big deal
well the plant temperature and sky
temperature might not be the same number,
if they are the same number if they're
close to the same number
it doesn't matter if you're reflecting a
small fraction of the sky radiation
towards the sensor it's similar to the
the plant canopy temperature, but if the
sky temperature significantly different
it can lead to errors.
We can correct for this effect with
a relatively simple equation and the
equations listed up here, I won't go
through the derivation, but the
information that you need to go into the
equation to correct for emissivity are
the actual measured temperature itself,
which we get from the sensor but then
you need some measurements or estimate
of the background temperature and then a
measurement or estimate of the surface
emissivity. You see once we have those
numbers they go in the equation here and
give us a estimate of the true surface
temperature. So just by way of example, on
a clear day the background temperature
and again if we're outdoors this is the
sky can be really cold in the
8 to 14 wavelength range that the
temperature sensor is measuring. We might
measure a surface temperature of the
plant canopy is 25 Celsius, a clear day
the sky temperatures negative 40 Celsius,
if our plant canopy emissivity is are actual surface temperature
0.98 is about a degree higher close to 26
Celsius than the measure temperature.
Emissivity can have a big impact on
temperature measurements and it's
important that we account for it if our
application requires accuracy better
than you know a degree Celsius or so.
Just to give you another example, on a
cloudy day with some again a measure
temperature of 25 Celsius, but on a
cloudy day the sky temperature isn't
nearly as cold as it is on a clear day,
15 Celsius is a much better estimate of
background temperature on a cloudy day.
Again assuming a plant canopy
temperature of 0.98, now the
surface temperature or the true surface
temperature is only about 0.2 Celsius
above what our sensor gave us. The
emissivity effect will vary with the sky conditions
clear sky is cold, cloudy skies warm
and when we get a break will actually walk outside
with some of these low-cost
handheld infrared sensors and you can
point them up and measure the
temperature of the sky and measure the
temperature of the surface and get a
feel for how big the differences are.
All right so this table just shows a
handful of emissivity values for
environmental surfaces and some man-made
surfaces, concrete and polished aluminum.
Fortunately most of the surfaces that
were interested in measuring things like
plant leaves and plant canopies, soil,
water they're close to black bodies not
quite because none of them have an
emissivity of 1. Deep plant canopies that
have a lot of leaves can be really close
to black bodies 0.99 in some cases.
The emissivity effect tends to be small
environmental applications but again it
can be quite important especially if we
have clear sky condition, and so this just
gives you an idea of background
temperature, clear sky will be very cold,
overcast sky will be near air
temperature, and this is a simple
equation that we derived in Logan, Utah that
you can use to estimate the
background temperature or the sky
temperature in the 8 to 14 micron range.
You take the the air temperature
and you add 50 times the fraction of clouds and then subtract 60.
The fraction of clouds is basically
what percentage of the the hemisphere of
sky is cloud cover and what percentage is clear.
Let's take a quick break, I'm
about maybe halfway through and we have
a break for tea time in just a few minutes.
I'm going to ask if James would go fill
our little Leslie cube full of hot water
and just show you the emissivity effect
in real time. Yeah, just hot water,
just put it in right there
fill it all the way. All we're
going to do is I have a a couple
infrared sensors here and when we take a
break your welcome to play around with
these so it's really simple power button
and then you point it at what you want to
measure and it outputs the
temperature on the screen in Celsius,
for example if I point it at the
ceiling and we get around 22 Celsius, I
point I at the floor we get about the
same number and that makes sense the
room here is essentially the same
temperature and so the surfaces in the
room should be about the same
temperature. All we're going to do is
measure the black-body surface of the
Leslie cube and then the side of the
Leslie cube and so take a look at these
numbers for a second and I can tell you
the side of the Leslie cube its polished
stainless steel so polished aluminum has
an emissivity of around point 0.3-0.5,
polished stainless steel will be
something similar, I don't know the
exact number but it will be something
similar. Now what we're going to do is
fill the the Leslie cube full of hot
water, right, and we know that the
blackbody cone of the Leslie cube is
close to a blackbody so it's emissivity
is very near one.
Any ideas what the temperature of the
black-body cone will be versus the
stainless steel side of the Leslie cube,
if we measure it with one of these
sensors. Let's just assume the water
temperature will be 50 or 60 Celsius.
What should be the black-body cone
surface temperature be?  It should be
close to the true temperature because
it's a black-body meaning it's it's even
emitting the maximum amount of radiation
it should emit for that temperature.
What about a if we point it at the side
of the Leslie cube and measures the
polished aluminum surface,
what should the temperature be?
Yeah 22 C, we should see a temperature
that's pretty close to the room
temperature, because remember 1 minus the emissivity
is the long-wave reflectivity
and so let's just assume that the
emissivity of this flat side is 0.05.
That means 95% of the radiation that were measuring
should be reflected from the room. We should see
something that may be about 22 Celsius
because the ceiling and the floor were
about 22 when we measure them. I'll
turn it on and I don't know how well you
can see the screen all yell out the
numbers for those of you can't see the
screen.
If we pointed at the the black-body surface,
and the unit actually does some averaging,
and so it's up to temperature now looks like it's about
38.6 Celsius.
Now if I pointed at the panel on the side,
we're getting about 26 Celsius. Not quite as
cold as the the 22 that I measured on
the floor and that might be because the
emissivity is actually a little bit
higher maybe the emissivity is like 0.1 or 0.2.
What were actually doing is getting an
average temperature somewhere between
the true temperature and the room
temperature because the emissivity is
somewhere between 0 and , and I
don't know exactly what it is.
Oh increase the distance, sure.
This is an excellent question because
you're actually jumping ahead in my
slides the next thing I'm going to talk
about in my slideshow is the field of
view, and so what happens if we put it
right up next to the blackbody we should
measure something around 38 and again we
are about 38.4. If I slowly start to move
it away, in the front row what's
happening?
It's getting colder and colder. Now
we're about probably 12 centimeters,
maybe 14 centimeters away, and we're
reading 30 instead of 38.
What's happening is we're moving it further and further from
the black-body, we're seeing more and
more within the footprint that this
thing measures. Now we're starting
to move it away and we're seeing the
sides or its polished aluminum in
addition to the black-body and that's
determined by the the field of view of
the sensor. I might actually be
able to do another demonstration let me see
if I have a light in my bag.
Bruce: Mark let me make a comment
while you're getting set up for that.
If you look on the internet, for
manufacturers of infrared radiometers
you will see some manufacturers that
sell an instrument with a dial on the back,
that is allegedly correct for emissivity.
They say this is a terrific feature,
our instruments are more accurate
because it dialed in emissivity, what they
do is take the reading and multiply it by the emissivity.
Mark: Actually, they divide by the emissivity.
Bruce: Yes, they divide. But, it often makes
the measurement worse instead of better
because they're not including
the reflected radiation that Mark's
talking about.
That confuses a lot of people.
They act like a simple dial you can just
correct for this and it drives
people that know what they're doing
crazy because it confuses the issue.
You can't just take a dial and correct for emissivity.
Mark: Good point Bruce.
If you have infrared radiometers that
have a dial on them and allow you to
tune it to the emissivity of the surface,
I would strongly recommend that you set
that dial to 1 so that it doesn't make that
correction, actually it will make the
correction will take the measurement and it will divide it by
1 so you get the actual measurement and
then use the equation that I gave you on
the previous slide makes the emissivity
corrections the right way.
If there's no more questions about emissivity...
Question: We've got real problems with emissivity down south in Anartica because our moss temperatures in
full Sun and it can get up to 20 degrees
Celsius and the air temperature is obviously much colder than that.
If we use infrared sensors down there, we are finding a lot of degree accuracy and
also the mosses, the emissivity can change according to
if they are dry, underwater, frozen, whatever. Is there any quick solution for
correcting for emissivity if the emissivity is changing over time.
Mark: I think the answer to that is you have to
actually characterize the emissivity.
You need to know what it is with within
whatever degrees of uncertainty you're
comfortable with in order to use the
equation that I've shown here.
There are ways to measure the emissivity
and if you want I can give you some
direction regarding the papers and literature that will
describe how to measure emissivity.
But yeah, in order to use the equation to
correct for emissivity you have to have a
pretty good handle on it, you need to know what it is.
Bruce:  You can get close by
looking it up, because you look at water
0.96-0.98, biological surfaces are
full of water and so there always in
0.96 to 0.98, like our skin is a
high emissivity because its hydrated, its full of water.
Sometimes it matters if its 0.96 or 0.98, but biological surfaces
that are full of water are always high emissivity
but still you can have significant errors if you don't do anything about it.
Question: I think it is because the moss temperature is
so different from the air temperature,
even a slight difference in emissivity
could drastically alter your measurements.
Mark: There's no doubt my examples only showed,
I had an example for a clear sky and a
cloudy sky but I could just as easily
have an example for clear sky with an
emissivity of 0.98 and clear sky
with an emissivity 0.95 and we could
look at the error there.
There will be an error as a function of emissivity
and so if you don't know the exact
emissivity you either have to live with that
uncertainty or you have to measure the
emissivity so you know it is.
Any other questions?
Let's talk about field-of-view for a second.
The actual area or the footprint that's being measured by the
radiometer will depend on three things
one of them is the field-of-view of the
radiometer, one of them is the mounting
height or the distance of the radiometer
from the surface that you're trying to
measure, and the other one is the angle
of the radiometer whether it's looking
straight down or at an angle.
The field-of-view of the radiometer is
defined as the angle or the half angle
of the cone apex where the cone base is
the area surface being measured in the
apex is right here. Just to illustrate
this particular model has a half-angle
field-of-view of 22 degrees or a full
angle field-of-view of 44 degrees, but
the best way that I like to think of
field-of-view and the best way that I
like to illustrate it is with a
flashlight. This is not necessarily a
flashlight it's just a pen with LED on
the end but I think I can make it work
for demonstration purposes.
We're all familiar if we go into a dark room
and we hold the flashlight close to the
wall and perpendicular to the wall we
get a small circle where it's pretty
high intensity light right
then if we start moving the flashlight
away from the wall the circle it gets bigger; it spreads out.
If we hold the flashlight back to
the wall and then we start to angle it's
no longer perpendicular to the wall, the
footprint or the spot on the wall it
now spreads out into an ellipse rather
than a circle and so the the field of
view of a radiometer is analogous to the
the spot or the light dot that a
flashlight makes on a wall.
If you're radiometer is perpendicular to the
surface that you're trying to measure,
its going to have a footprint of a
circle. If you're pretty close to the
surface you're trying to measure, that
footprint is going to be small. If you
move the radiometer further from the
surface, the footprint gets bigger and
bigger meaning you're averaging more and
more of the ground area into the
temperature measurement.
Just like when we moved the flashlight away from the
wall, not only does the circle get
bigger but it got less and less intense.
If you're radiometer is
perpendicular to the surface, you see a
circle as soon as you start to angle it
the footprint spreads out into an ellipse.
Here are the different field-of-view
options of infrared sensors that Apogee
builds and other companies that make
infrared radiometers are likely to have
different fields-of-view. There's three
of them that have a circular
field-of-view, just different angles that
make the footprint either a little bit
smaller or a little bit larger and then
this one has a horizontal field-of-view;
this one is actually designed to look at
row crops. The field-of-view is wide
in this dimension but narrow in this
dimension, so if you orient it
horizontally like this with row crops
looking that are running this way then
you can try to minimize the soil that is
in the field-of-view and maximize the plant
area that is in the field-of-view using a
horizontal field-of-view. What
often comes up is that's all well and
good I understand that putting it close
to the surface gives me a small
footprint and moving away from the
surface gives me a big footprint, but how
do I actually attach numbers to the
footprint? There is a tool that you can
find on the Apogee Instruments web page
that allows you to calculate in
dimensions of meter squared, how much
land area am I going to see if I have a
sensor with this field-of-view, for
example; this height above the surface,
and this angle from
perpendicular. We have two know three
numbers in order to to get a footprint
calculation. You have to know the
field-of-view of the radiometer, the
height above the surface that you've
mounted your radiometer, and then the
angle of the radiometer from
perpendicular.
Once you input those three numbers into
the calculator it will spit out meter
squared of ground area that
you're going to actually measure on the
ground. Another question that comes up
often in relation to field-of-view is,
what do I do in this situation where I
have partial canopy cover? Maybe it is
row crops or maybe it's a forest where the
trees are fairly sparse and you're
trying to measure the plant canopy
temperature but you have all of this
soil that you see in the background.
A couple techniques and I won't spend too
much time on these, one way that you can
deal with this is angle the radiometer
to try to maximize the canopy within the
field-of-view so you can see if it's
looking straight down you're going to
see something like you know half of the
area within the footprint is soil and
the other half is plants, but now if you
angle it, most of what you see is in the
in the area is plants you might still
have a little sliver of soil here that
you see, but
by angling it you can try to get more
plant area and less soil area in the
footprint. Another way that you can
deal with this as you can measure or
estimate the soil temperature and then
approximate the fractions of canopy and
fraction of soil that are within the
field-of-view and you can use a simple
equation to try to estimate the canopy
temperature if you know roughly what the
fraction of canopy is, the fraction
of soil is, and the soil temperature.
The input you need here are this
is the actual measured surface
temperature from the sensor, this would
be a measurement or estimate of the soil
temperature, this one is the fraction of
canopy in the field-of-view, and one minus
that number is the fraction of soil
within the field-of-view. So if you have
reasonable estimates of soil temperature
and then the fraction of field-of-view
that's occupied by canopy and soil, you can
try to estimate canopy temperature from
the data and eliminate the soil
temperature,if canopy temperature is
the number that you're you're looking
for. I have a few more slides that deal
with an application of infrared
measurements of surface temperature or
we can take time for tea.
You want to see the application, it won't take too much time?
Okay, I'll try to be brief.
Just a real quick summary of
infrared thermometery or infrared
radiometry, small signals require a
higher resolution voltmeter. That's if
you have an analog sensor nowadays a lot
of sensors have analog-to-digital
converters onboard the sensor and then
they output digital signals like SDI-12
or modbus and so ifyou want to
make surface temperature measurements
but you don't have a way to measure
these small voltages that doesn't mean
you can't make the measurement it just
means you need to buy a version that
outputs a digital signal like modbus or
SDI-12. Emissivity correction is required,
we spent quite a bit of time on that one.
Remember the radiometer averages
everything within the field-of-view, so
if you have things within the field-of-view
that you don't want to see you either
have to reposition the sensor to
eliminate them from the field-of-view or
if it's the case of plant canopies and
soil there's ways you can try to
estimate one temperature if you know the
other. We're going to move on to the
application really quick. In the past
we've often made the model conductance
measurement with these little handheld
devices or sometimes they're not little.
This is a full photosynthesis
system from Licor, some
of you may be familiar with this. This is
a pourameter from Decagon they
allow you to the clamp on to leave and
measure stomatal conductance and these
are great instruments but all you get is
the stomatal conductance of a single leaf
that you clamped on. It also
requires a person to be in the field
with the instrument to make the
measurement. So a few years ago myself
and Bruce in one of our colleagues set
out to use infrared radiometers to try
to measure plant canopy stomatal
conductance automatically. Basically
using weather data and with the addition
of an infrared measurement of the canopy
temperature to estimate stomatal conductance.
I won't spend too much time here but
you're looking at a picture of the
surface energy balance so the
equations over here are all the
equations necessary to describe the
surface energy balance and the number
that were interested in here is the
plant canopy stomatal conductance.
Without going into detail, we can
rearrange all over the equations that
are shown here for the the surface and
we can solve for for this number.
Everything is described in the paper on
this slide and if you're interested in
the paper i can easily send you a PDF of
it. When we do that it gives us an
equation that that calculates plant
canopy stomatal conductance if we
have these measurements or estimates and
so we have to have the canopy
temperature, air temperature, humidity
radiation, wind speed, and then some
information about the height of the
plants and the leaf area index.
In the previous slide I was showing a
picture of one of our weather stations
and so here's where we're getting all of
our weather data and all of these
things that you see here are the
infrared radiometer and these ones are
looking at a corn canopy. This was in
Nebraska I believe. I'll just show you
some data we actually calculated
stomatal conductance from the measurements
that we made.
What you're looking at here is
canopy stomatal conductance on the
y-axis and then x axis says day of year.
This is day of year 195 through day of
year 206 those would be roughly
mid-july or right in the middle of the
summer in the Northern Hemisphere.
There's two lines on this stomatal
conductance graph here green line and a
black line. The green line is actually a
model calculation of canopy stomatal
conductance and we're calling it
potential conductance, and so what it is
is an estimate of what we expect the the
canopy stomatal conductance to be if
the plants are well watered and not
stressed. Then the black line is our
actual data the canopy stomatal
conductance. We calculated from our
weather measurements and our measurement
of the canopy temperature from the
infrared sensor and you can see these
couple days here the black line matches
the green line pretty well indicating
the plants are well water because
the calculated values of the model
conductance for measure matching the
model values and again the model values
give us what we expect the theoretical
value to be for well-watered conditions
and then you can see for a few days in a
row the black line as well below the
green line, meaning the actual values are
well under the potential values
indicating the the plants are water
stressed. Over here it jumps back up
again and we have two or three days
where the actual matches the potential
pretty well before it starts to go down.
You can see the same thing in this graph
here, this is just the ratio of the two
so you take the the black line divided by  the
green line. If we're near one,
it means the two-match. If we're
below one, it means the black line is
lower than the green line. So any ideas
what happened right here where it jumps up?
Well you can see it declines there. Mother
nature irrigated; we got almost an inch
of rainfall the cornfield that I
showed was naturally irrigated and when
the rain fell it bumped back
up like we would expect it to do. This
is just one application that you could
potentially pursue with infrared
measurements they can give you
information about plant canopy water
status and plant response to their
environment. Here were looking at stomatal
response. One more graph; this just shows
a plot of the potential value, so a
reference value on this axis and the
actual value our calculated value on
this axis. This is from the exact same
experiment in Nebraska in the United
States and it was corn. All were
doing here is plotting the 24 the days
immediately after rainfall when we
expect that our actual value should
match our model value and indeed that's
what we get, as long as the plants are
watered the two numbers match. So it
indicates that our method of getting
actual is is working pretty well, the
outliers are possibly when the canopy
was wet. You'll get data that
don't necessarily match the model if the
leaf surfaces are wet.
That's all I have for stomatal
conductance for the application. Are there
any questions about any of the IR
measurement details that we covered? Any
questions about this specific
application?