my name is Skyler Smith and today we're
going to talk about the PV monitoring
package available from Apogee
instruments and this is a list of
everything included in the package
each of these sensors is available
separately for your own application we
designed this to go with an SMA cluster
controller so each of these are
compatible with that but for your
application you only need certain ones
feel free to contact us for availability
on that so the package includes the sp2
14 solar radiation sensor the SP 150 era
temperature sensor the TS 100 fan
aspirated shield and then the CS 240 vac
a panel temperature sensor and then
these smaller things are accessories to
help with the installation of those the
SP 214 measures your solar radiation in
watts per meter square and it comes with
a standard 5 meter cable it is a silicon
cell detector but we calibrate it to
match those higher-end blackbody
thermopiles secondary standards and so I
have a link here for the traceability
you can find that same link in the
comments below but what we mean by
calibrating to those secondary standards
is that our spectral response is from
360 to 1120 nanometers for the SP 214
but we calibrate it to match those
high-end secondary standards that have a
range of 285 to 2800 nanometers so that
means on a clear sky our SP 214 is going
to read the same as those high-end
secondary standards the SP 150 ambient
air temperature sensor it's a class a
PRT
ip67 rated come standard 5 meter cable
and it does meet that IEC standard for
air temperature accuracy now you can
just put that in a guild shield or we
recommend putting it into our active
radiation shield our TS 100 and you can
see in this picture over here on this
cross section how the SP 150 would just
slide right in there so the idea behind
this is it's got a fan in there to
circulate the air so you're getting the
highest accurate air temperature
possible
with that long rated fan comes with five
meter standard this particular 24 volt
step-down converter again is designed
for that SMA cluster controller that is
powered with 24 volts to step that down
to the 12 volts needed to run the fan
now as far as that argument between
guilt sealed and active radiation shield
we did some testing on our roofs to show
the difference and you can see the blue
across the top here is your passive
radiation shield your grill shield right
there and then the red is our TS 100
active radiation shield so if your goal
is to meet that IEC 6 172 4-1
specification the uncertainty says it
has to be plus or minus 1 degrees C and
that's in gray on our graph here and
each of these blue dots and red dots are
15-minute averages for measurements so
you can see when the Sun comes out and
gets between five and six hundred watts
per meter squared that we are actually
outside of that range with a Gil shield
that we're outside that 1 degree C
accuracy so if you want to stay within
that particular specification you really
need some sort of active shield that's
why we recommend the t s 100 C s 240
back panel temperature sensor class a
PRT
highly accurate comes in your standard
cable length 15 and 50 meters in length
and that it also includes that captain
tape for mounting so to recap our pv 100
monitoring package does include
everything on this list here the 214 the
solar mounting bracket with leveling
plate their temperature sensor the fan
aspirated shield the step-down converter
and then the back panel temperature
sensor with that captain tape so please
feel free to contact us by email by
phone for a price and availability we'll
love to get you a quote on that thank
you so much for watching any questions
feel free to email us give us a call and
don't forget to click below to subscribe
to our channel thank you
[Music]