[ ♪ Background music ♪ ]
Introducing the Apogee MS-100, the InSight,
a handheld spectroradiometer designed for photobiology.
Powered by a rechargeable lithium ion battery.
Small, fast, reliable measurements.
A powerful tool for researchers, consultants, and agronomists looking to spot check and log spectra data.
Configured with modern metrics used  by industry-leading researchers.
View the data on device or with the powerful InSight software available on desktop and mobile devices.
Optimize your lighting wherever you grow.
Now available at apogeeinstruments.com and authorized distributors.
[ ♪ Background music ♪ ]