I'm Bruce bugbee president of apogee
instruments and also professor of grub
physiology at Utah State University
and in this talk today I want to talk
about
modifications to our fundamental
understanding of photosynthetic
radiation
and I especially want to talk about the
two edges of the cutoffs at 400 and at
700. now this talk is a modified version
of an address I gave two weeks ago at a
controlled environments conference at
the in Tucson Arizona it was a big
conference and uh I was asked to talk
about this and an invited talk but that
that talk wasn't recorded so now we're
going to record it for you I love
starting this off with the Dark Side of
the Moon the prism divides up the colors
and we and we analyze them and now we
have LEDs is a very powerful tool to
study these effects photobiology
and but we did used to use prisms a long
time ago so it's a really amazing change
the tools we have to study this and of
course not only are they great tools for
fundamental research but they're great
tools for growing crops too so we're
simultaneously doing work on them and
studying their commercial effects
so to start with this I want to start
with sunlight and look at the ratios of
color in sunlight and make the point
that there's not a lot of photons down
around 400 so the cutoff down here is
less critical than the cutoff at 700
because there's a lot of photons at 700.
so let's take a look at sunlight here's
a classic curve of sunlight
worldwide close to solar new and this
changes just subtly with time of year
and time of day it changes a little but
not a lot
look at this three percent let me turn
on my pen here
and we can highlight some of this
there's only three percent of the
photons right in here that sunlight
because of atmospheric filtering drops a
lot right at 400.
so even if we change the definition down
here in sunlight this is a small effect
but we still want to look at this
because it's important for LEDs as well
as studies in sunlight but look at over
here 18 percent this cutoff makes a big
difference for our measurements of
photosynthetic radiation
let's take a look at this
for LEDs which is why we're so keenly
interested in this if this if all we
ever did was measure photosynthesis in
sunlight we wouldn't be so concerned
about this
but look at our collection of LEDs
this was a this beautiful slide showing
the peak wavelengths the classic things
that there's not efficient green they're
in the middle but look at right here
there's some very efficient Violet LEDs
right near the cut off and the same
thing up here we have a very efficient
far red LED and they are being used in
light fixtures to manipulate plant shape
so we really need to know if these
photons are also photosynthetic there's
the Violet there's the far red and
because these are being used we want to
know this graph was made by Paul kasuma
who was got his PhD with me in 2021 last
year he graduated he's now at waganingan
University so we've had a long
relationship with waganingan
sharing Talent back and forth and and
we've worked closely with Leo Marcellus
there
it's been a great relationship so what I
want to do now is oh first let me
emphasize two papers that Paul consumer
wrote These are not on the cutoffs but
they're on LEDs and they're if you want
to get state of the art where LEDs are
now and where they can go search for
kusuma and bugbee and you'll see our
referee Journal artists come up this
one's called from physics to fixtures to
food current and potential efficacy
where are they going to go in the next
five or ten years and also Photon
efficacy and Horticulture is a real
detailed analysis of all the colors
so let's take a look at the
what we know about first the short
wavelengths here the efficacy there's
there's the part we're going to zoom in
now on the next graph
now we got 250 to 500 and here's our
classic blue LED that's very widely used
this is the a very efficient LED it's
used as the base phosphor for white LEDs
but we also have a series of LEDs right
close to 400 nanometers
and it's real critical to know
how efficient these are they're being
used in fixtures because they can have
significant morphological effects on
Plants since triggering secondary
metabolism but are these do these
photons cause photosynthesis
so to look at this I want to go back and
look at the Historical studies on
Quantum yield from photosynthesis
this is a from a paper I published in
five years ago 2017 it's it's a book
chapter
but here's the very famous McCree curve
that hundreds more than hundreds
thousands of people cite this paper from
1971 but if we he wasn't the first to do
this
a scientist named Hoover did it in 1937.
Imagine the technology he had that's 90
years ago to do this where they got
similar curves not identical but similar
and then a Japanese scientist and not
have repeated this in 1976.
at first glance these are similar but
look at the area right here McCree shows
a big taper Hoover shows a sharp cut off
inada shows a relatively sharp cut off
right down here in the UV
you can ask why do we cite mccree's
paper so much when there's other
literature on this it is because his
paper is exceptionally well written and
as a series of two papers
and they're very comprehensive papers
it's a great example to graduate
students to read how clear his writing
is in these papers here's Keith McCree
and I as a young scientist I had the
opportunity spend time with him he came
to Utah State University to give us a
seminar and he spent an afternoon in my
lab there was it was a it was a great
thing to know him he died in 2014.
so let's take a look at his studies
right here and on UV light
we're going to blow this up
what McCree found was there was a large
species variability in response to these
UV photons he studied 21 species and
I've taken from his data
the one that was the most responsive to
UV and the species that was leased and
it turns out radishes is the most
responsive sunflower was the least and
if all crops were like radish you bet we
would move the goal posts we would count
these photons but if they're all like
sunflower you can start to argue we
should move it the other direction
but
crops vary a lot and when how fast this
drops off in the relative photosynthetic
efficiency now some flowers and radishes
are not big crops in controlled
environment but lettuce and cucumbers
are
here's lettuce and cucumber
they're intermediate they both drop
quite fast right here right close to 400
nanometers this is mccree's data now he
had to use prisms and filters to get
this data it's amazing what he did given
the equipment he had now fast forward
50 years to where we are today with
state-of-the-art LEDs so we set out in
my laboratory to see if we could
reproduce these curves using those
Violet LEDs that I showed you
state-of-the-art gas exchange equipment
state-of-the-art LEDs
and here's what we found
now this was done by Shu young Jen who
is a very talented young scientist she
was got her PhD she was a postdoc with
me she's now an assistant professor at
Texas A M University these are her data
in in my lab
remember that radish from mccree's data
was one of the best look at that radish
is one of the best remember that
sunflower was one of the worst we
repeated mccree's data using 50 years
better technology and cucumber was in
the middle Tomatoes up there with radish
uh
it's it's just quite remarkable that we
were able to repeat his data how about
lettuce
here's lettuce
these curves
um they go they down to maybe maybe 70
percent
um at 380 nanometers this is a good
point here Marshall is a purple lettuce
with a lot of anthocyanin and that does
not use UV photons well at all those
anthocyanins are pigments that block the
UV we think the species variability is
just blocking of the UV and the cuticle
which is for protective reasons
that take home message from this is
these curves drop off fast
and we don't see any reason to change
the definition of photosynthetic
radiation from 400 nanometers from what
we have today
unless you're doing work with some hot
species that can use them and in that
case you ought to buy a spectral
radiometer so you can precisely count
these photons
so now let's move to the other end of
the spectrum
boom look at this effect this is why
this is such a big deal this this has
been repeated Now by scores of other
scientists and Laboratories we know that
far red lettuce
makes the lettuce leaf expansion take
off and this is a picture of lettuce
without far red and 10 percent far red
this is a big deal lots of literature on
this
here's the question it's not
controversial to say that far red
triggers a shade avoidance response and
makes the plants get bigger because they
think they're in shade that we've known
for years we know that happens
but is all of this dramatic Improvement
caused by Photon capture and leaf
expansion
or is some of it caused by for Direct
effects on photosynthesis and that
finding is profound because remember
we've said for since McCree
400 to 700 is our range
but now do these far red photons
contribute to that that is a
extraordinary claim to say that we
should change our fundamental definition
of photosynthesis
now for this extraordinary claim
we require extraordinary proof
and I bring in Carl Sagan who in the
series of Cosmos said extraordinary
claims require extraordinary proof
so what I'm now going to show you is the
extraordinary proof that far red photons
cause photosynthesis in the next few
slides
for this we start with papers of Shu
yang zhen
who was a young PhD student with Mark
Van ersle who was
a distinguished professor at the
University of Georgia many years ago
Mark Van ersold was a postdoc with me
and then of course recently Shu young
was a postdoc Mark got his bachelor's
degree at wagoningan University and had
opportunities in the United States and
came across the ocean here although he
maintains his ties with wagoningan
Chu young and Mark first published a
paper in 2017. these are all very
reputable are highly high impact factor
reputable journals Journal of plant
physiology they and I'm not going to go
into all the details but they studied
the light reactions
of photosynthesis in this paper
and showed that the far red photons
clearly improve the light reactions of
photosynthesis we'll come back to that
in a minute in the second paper a year
later physiologica plantarum they use
laser LEDs at specific wavelengths to
show that that the photons at least up
to 730 nanometers were improving the
light reactions of photosynthesis
so after this work in Mark's lab
I recruited Shu young to come work with
me because we have a canopy gas exchange
system it's very sophisticated system
but it measures photosynthesis of the
whole plant communities continuously
over the whole life cycle there's 10
Chambers there's a few shown here using
this canopy gas exchange system and
precise measurements of canopy
photosynthesis we published a paper in
plant cell and environment and other
high impact Journal far red photons have
equivalent efficiency to Shorter
wavelength photons implications for
redefining par
this is now
two years old
we kept going because we were interested
in the long-term effects this was
short-term effects with and without far
red on canopy photosynthesis so we did a
study with long-term effects through the
whole life cycle and again showed these
far red photons where
it had equivalent efficiency to the the
shorter wavelength photons and this is
in Frontiers in plant science so
we get four
significant Journal articles now from
two different Laboratories showing the
value of these because of this work
most colleagues have now switched to
including photons up to 750 nanometers
as photosynthetic when they're doing
studies in controlled environments
it doesn't just stop with our papers
because two other research groups that
study this have now reported on this
Zhao at all 2019
terashima is a well-known scientist
plant and cell physiology well-known
Journal these are supporting papers so
the
technical studies on this are providing
that extraordinary proof that we need to
change our understanding of far red
photons
so
to
make a claim like this it's not
adequate to just say you have empirical
evidence that this occurs
you need a mechanism coupled with the
empirical evidence and as I say
our understanding of how the world Works
requires
a coupling of measurements and models
and data and Theory
so this is the theory that supports that
without the theory maybe 400 years ago
we said the moon is made of green cheese
well that must have been because of
reflected light you know that's a common
common myth and people said you're nuts
you know there's no mechanism behind
that and think of all the observations
we have without mechanisms
that usually means the observations have
something wrong about them or they're
incomplete
but in the case of far red photons I go
to my favorite Twin Towers diagram of
how the light reactions of
photosynthesis work
so we know from the Stark Einstein law
our body with the wild hair one Photon
excites one electron
that's why we count photons a photon
comes in
it hits the light reactions boom it
excites an electron that electron
Cascades down in energy and it makes ATP
another Photon comes in boom Another
electron goes up and this makes nadph
this is photosystem two this is
photosystem one water is split here and
the photosystems but this is a really
good example of the energy state of
photons exciting electrons in
photosynthesis here's the key
this guy over here can be excited with
far red photons we've known that for 50
years and that is called the Emerson
enhancement effect
that these photons can excite electrons
in photosystem one and in fact if you
don't have any far red photons these two
photosystems that run in closely
synchronized closely synchronized
process can get out of balance
so this is the
theory that underlies this there's other
many ways to show this but I I've liked
this Twin Towers
diagram which which I got out of a
photochemistry book to show where the
photons come in
so now let's take a closer look at this
back to the full sunlight Spectrum
so far we have only shown this under
electric lights where we add far red and
we take it away that's compelling
evidence
but if it works under electric lights it
should also work under sunlight the
effect should also be present under
sunlight
so now in the final series of studies
and this is with Shu youngjen Mark Van
ersel and myself
we undertook to make these measurements
in sunlight now there's 18 percent
photons out here
so that's what we're looking for is an
18 effect
to do this we filtered the light bought
special filters that cut this off
and there's our filter far red filter it
was a very nice filter Cuts this off
cleaning it 700 these photons are gone
this filter also cut out the UV now
remember we hypothesized that UV is not
going to have a big effect that does so
we added measurements with the third
filter that only filtered UV this is
blocked let this through
when we put the UV filter on leaves and
when I say weed that means true young
did the work making the measurements in
the trenches
less than one percent so these photons
as predicted had a small blocking them
had a very small effect on
photosynthesis that's part of the reason
we say 400 cut off at the bottom is is a
good cutoff we see no reason to change
that but what happened up here with the
far red filter
peanut decreased 12 percent
now remember there's 18 photons up here
and there's a number of issues up here
with how high was the light what was
saturating
this number doesn't precisely match this
but that's a big decrease in
photosynthesis
and if it's not caused by this you got
to hypothesize something else it does it
and it wasn't temperature we measured a
number of things with this research
this data shows that far red photons are
important in sunlight as well as
electric lights but now let's look at
one other case for plant ecology
understory crops we when we start
measuring Global photosynthesis what
happens to these plants down here that
get filtered light the far red light is
transmitted to these plants and if we
make a spectral curve of this
is filtered this is transmitted so
suddenly for these understory crops in
here
wow
more than half of their photons are far
red photons
this has huge implications are we only
going to count these photons and in here
green are we going to count all of those
photons
so we made measurements of understory
crops
filtered by leaves what did we find
here's the filter applying that filter
we block this let the green come through
peanut decreased 40 to 60 percent
this is a huge effect and it further
emphasizes the value of far red photons
in global climate change research our
global climate change models
this is a big finding
and throughout all of this work to
collect these data we knew it was a big
finding so we published this in a very
high impact Journal called new
phytologist this is an impact factor
above 10. it's reserved for
groundbreaking research look at the date
July 2022 this is a recent publication
photosynthesis in Sun and shade the
surprising importance of far red photons
so I refer you to this paper for the
details of how we did the work
we got a lot of excellent reviews from
some prestigious photobiologists and
this and they were very appreciative of
our work
so the collective
body of evidence indicates that we need
to be counting photons
from 700 to 750 so what does this look
like now back to the McCree curve the
classic McCree curve
once again we don't see evidence to move
the goal post here but up on this end
remember McCree did not do synergistic
effects this was one wavelength at a
time and had he done synergistic
wavelengths far red and shorter
wavelengths together
he the evidences that he would have seen
the same thing we did these are
synergistic with this
and so now the new definition adds this
out here to the curve so the old metric
there's 750
the old metric was called par
the new metric
we've been calling epar for extended par
and we're recommending people report
both of these in their studies but they
focus on epar as the fundamentally best
metric and multiple other Laboratories
are doing exactly that they're setting
they're counting these photons as
photosynthetic in their research
this is
has a number of implications and I want
to review those now
so the move from par to epar
number one efficiency of fixtures
are we going to count these photons in
LED fixtures and all the evidences we
should be counting them
asabe does standards for this and so far
their old standard is 400 to 700
nanometers
but they're meeting again to revise this
and people on this committee have told
us we need to change the standard in in
the light of all the evidence we now
have for uh epar as an improved metric
over par so this is one big implication
of this
second one is the design light
Consortium rates lamps and they becoming
a go-to standard for efficacy of LED
lights
if they do not count far red protons
they penalize the lighting manufacturers
that add far red to their lights
so they're looking at making this change
too and they probably will have two
metrics par and epar to help people
select the best
lighting fixtures and then finally
in portable photosynthesis systems which
we use a lot to measure photosynthesis
they use LEDs to light the leaves
but historically they've not had far red
LEDs in the heads of these portable
photosynthesis systems so that means
they get artifacts and they
underestimate true photosynthesis under
sunlight
and it also inhibits further studies on
this because the LEDs don't include far
red but there's one exception
PP systems have now come out with a new
gas exchange it's called the Cirrus 4
and that one has a far red LEDs in the
head so it's continuing evidence that
the world's changing to a new definition
many people use a lycor portable
photosynthesis system and we're told
that lycor is looking to add these far
red LEDs and the head of their meter as
well
this is the end of the story but
we need to help you make these
measurements and to do that we need a
new suite of sensors
so
apogee instruments
came out with first of all
they've come out with a e-par sensor now
let me draw here's the sensor silver
looks like this
let me draw this on the board
here is
we count the photons equally here's 400
700 par
just like the slide shows
this sensor goes to 750
and it's and it's called epar
extended photosynthetic Act of radiation
in sunlight this adds
about 18 percent to the to the total
photosynthetic radiation
under electric lights it may only add
three or four percent unless you're
using Farid LEDs and now that under
electric lights it can add 18 as well
because of this effect and because the
we have the traditional par and the new
epar apogee also made
this sensor it's a black sensor this is
a hooked up to a micro cache data logger
this sensor is called
the par
far
sensor
creative names for sensors and it has
two detectors in it so it gives a
reading for par and it gives a second
reading for just this radiation right
here and then of course you can add them
together so it gives you three numbers
this reading that reading and the sum of
both of those
this is a little bit more money because
it has two detectors but allows users to
separately measure both of these
and then finally
um
lots of people want integrated meters
for Daily Light integral this is a
relatively new meter that just it has a
microprocessor inside and it gives
instantaneous
epar and it also integrates the total of
the day you can it stores it in memory
you can get Daily Light integral for the
past hundred days with this sensor
which which comes in both of the old par
version and the new epar version of
course all of these sensors can be
hooked up to data acquisition systems
they don't have to be hooked up to
meters
this is an exciting time
think of people in greenhouses that have
mixes of supplemental light and this if
we don't include this
we're going to underestimate the
photosynthetic radiation in greenhouses
so not only do we feel like there is
solid empirical and theoretical evidence
to change to epar
but we've also provided the sensors to
facilitate making that change
thanks for listening we'll catch you
again in the next video