hi my name is john huber and in this
video we'll be going over a quick set of
instructions on how to set up a
laboratory spectroradiometer for
reflectance measurements
now for these reflectance measurements
you're going to need a few things you're
going to need obviously your
spectroradiometer the computer that
it'll interface with
a reflectance standard
a stable light source in my case i'm
going to use a reflectance probe with a
flashlight built into it
and the unit's fiber optic cable
now as far as reflectance standards go
i've got a sheet of spectral on here it
is the same material as our
as004 reflectance standard so
this material reflects
all light within the spectroradiometer's
sensitivity range and so it'll work very
well as a light reference
so the first step to setting up your
spectroradiometer will be
first to make sure you've got stellarnet
spectrois installed and working on your
computer
after that you're going to want to make
sure your spectroradiometer is plugged
in which mine is
and then after that the next step will
be to plug in the fiber optic cable
so you'll want to note the end that says
it plugs into the spectroradiometer it
has a little arrow pointing to where the
spectroradiometer should be
so i'm going to go ahead and plug that
end in first
and then if you're just using the fiber
optic cable for your reflectance
measurements you'll want to position it
in a fixed position
for
the duration of your measurements in my
case i'm going to put it into this
reflectance probe here
which will also serve as my light source
it's very important that you have a
stable light source throughout your
measurements
so once you've got everything hooked up
the next thing you'll want to do is
start up
spectro is
and to do that we do recommend that you
run it as an administrator so i'm going
to go ahead and navigate to its install
directory on the c drive
program files
stellarnet
spectrawiz
and then the executable is this swd file
i'm going to right click it and run it
as an administrator doing this makes
sure the program has the
privileges that it needs to function
properly otherwise windows is going to
create some false files in another
directory that you'll need to delete for
the program to work right
so once you've got stellarnet spectrawiz
running you're going to want to make
sure you're in scope mode so select view
and scope mode
and then once you've got that set up
you'll want to make sure your light
source is on so i'm going to turn
the little flashlight in my probe here
on
and then you're going to position your
fiber optic cable over your reflectant
standard target
now once you've got it positioned over
the target your next step is to optimize
the integration time
so
when you're optimizing the integration
time your goal is to make sure that this
graph here occupies as much of the
y-axis here as possible without cutting
off at the top
so right now the graph is too low i'm
going to show you what it looks like
when it's too high
so you go view
there you go setup detector integration
time
and to make the graph go higher you
simply increase this integration time
number to make it go lower you decrease
it so i'm going to increase it by too
much
just as an example
so as you can see
the graph is cutting off slightly at the
top here which means my integration time
is too high i need to bring it down
so i'll go set up detector integration
time
i'm going to bring it down a little bit
to 14.50 here now your integration time
is going to vary depending on the
brightness of your light source the
brighter the light source the lower your
integration time will be
so in this case this integration time
looks like it's good it's occupying a
good portion of the y-axis but it's not
being cut off at all
so we're gonna let it sit for a while to
make sure it's stable
which it looks like it is
so once it's stable your next step is to
obtain a dark scan
so the key to obtaining a good dark skin
is just to make sure that there's no
light getting into your
spectroradiometer so for this procedure
i'm going to unplug the fiber optic
cable
and then cover the opening port
and when you do this you should see a
nice flat line at the bottom it's okay
if there are some tiny bumps in it we're
going to flatten those out with the dark
skin
so
i prefer to release old dark skins first
this is optional but usually it leads to
better dark scans overall in my
experience
so to release an old dark skin you'll
want to right click
this button here
with the dark scan icon
and when you do that you'll notice that
a small square forms in the lower left
corner of the graph that means that the
old dark skin has been
erased and when you're ready to save a
new dark scan just left click the button
here
you'll notice the line is nice and flat
along the bottom and the value down here
is bouncing very close to zero it'll
vary by a bit but it should always
remain close to zero
so now that we've got a good dark scan
i'm going to plug the fiber optic cable
back in
and then i'm going to
replace
the probe over there standard
and then we're going to make sure that
our integration time still looks good
which
it still occupies most of the y-axis
here so that's still a good integration
time
so once you've got your dark skin and
your integration time set
the next thing you need to do is go into
transmission mode so you go view
transmission
and now the next step after that
is simply to click this light reference
button here
and that will establish your reflectance
standard as the standard for 100
reflectance
and at this point you are now ready to
start taking reflectance measurements so
i'm just going to take a quick
measurement off of the black tabletop
here
as you can see the black tabletop is
absorbing most of the visible spectrum
but is beginning to reflect the far red
spectrum beyond 700 nanometers which
we'd expect to see
so once you have a good spectrum and
you're satisfied with it and you want to
save it
you go up to file
save
sample
you'll pick a location to save your file
and give it a name i'm going to call
this one test
and now this window comes up it allows
you to define your starting wavelength
your ending wavelength and your
wavelength increments for this file i'm
going to just keep the starting and
ending wavelengths and then change the
wavelength increments to 1 nanometer
once you've done that you click ok
and your spectrum is saved
and now if you want to open your
spectrum up in a program like microsoft
excel all you need to do is open up
excel
click file
open
browse to the location where you saved
your file
and then you want to make sure that
excel is looking for all files and not
just excel files
find your file and open it
and then you want to make sure it's
delimited
by spaces
click finish
and there's our spectrum file
and that concludes the brief tutorial on
how to take a reflectance measurement
thank you for watching