So this is going to be different because this is a higher level class than
beginning
graduate students because most of you have already had exposure to some of
this stuff. We will try to solidify the basics and then go into more depth
as we come up on things.
I should introduce myself like I due to all the
students.  I'm Bruce Bugbee (and this is more for the video)
my title is professor of crop physiology.
Somewhere along the line I got much more interested in the physics of plant
growth then the physiology and that means energy and mass transfer into and
out of plants, and because of that my laboratory is done well with getting
funding because people want to quantify things. Many, many years ago that led
to a lot of instruments to rigorously quantify inputs and outputs. What I've
evolved to now is instrument intensive research on plant growth.
Some students have called this class, in the reviews, some students have called
this class crop physics. "You should just call it crop physics because
that's what it".
That's not strictly correct because there's a lot of biology in the class as
well.
What I'm going to focus on in approximately the next eight lectures is
this outline here, which I've handed out, which focuses on energy balance.
It's the first part of the class, and it's the fundamentals by which we get
evaporation from surfaces.
As a point of introduction and before I get way too far into this,
I thought it would give you a full copy of the whole class that I teach.
You can see we're pruning off these early lectures right here. I teach this
winter semesters up here. We're pruning off these this first section up
here on energy balance. This is the whole thing. This is also the front
page of the textbook I use, which is a bunch of readings of this and I love to
put all the key equations right on the front of the book so people can see
those and see what's coming up. Mostly the top half of these things are
the ones who are going to focus on in here.
The reason we do energy balance analysis in any field is to try
and determine that temperature of objects and anytime water is involved
now it gets way more complicated because water evaporates and changes the
temperature of objects, which is why agriculture focuses on energy
balance so much.
If we could get a low-cost sensor that could measure the evaporation of water
from a field, it would be a huge breakthrough.
Just put it out there and measure the flux of water, but there isn't any
low cost ways to do that so we do it with modeling and lots of modeling.
We measure all the parameters around this and what's left is this missing
water and this much water must have evaporated to balance the energy. That's
the most cost-effective way to do it and frankly that's a big reason
instrument companies are in business. They sell instruments to measure
everything. We can put plants on a lysimeter and weigh them, and that's an
accurate way to get water that evaporates.
Lysimeter are really expensive to install. They're expensive to operate,
and only people that use those as references. Refrences use lysimeters the rest of us
use calculations and and modeling. We use lysimeter as well but only for
reference instruments. We can do things like eddy covariance to get water
transfer and that's expensive and requires knowledgeable
people. It's still an indirect measurement of measuring water vapor.
So we keep coming back to energy balance principles to really understand where
the water is going.
If you type in water use in the world on the internet, you get
lots of things like this.
Agriculture is 70 % of our water in the United States and worldwide.
Its the massive user of water. I gave a TED talk on this a few years
ago, Turning Water Into Food, and the main point than that talk was people aren't
wasting water. The image says farmers are using seventy percent of our water,
they must be just wasting it, running it down into rivers and into the
groundwater.
It just takes that much water to grow food. This is one of many graphs of
that. The point is if we could improve water use efficiency in
agriculture by 1% it would be more than what you use at home.
Forget putting bricks in your toilet and turn the water off when
you brush your teeth.
Those are just miniscule compared to the amount of water that it takes to grow
our food, which is why it's so imperative to understand that and use every drop as
efficiently as we can. Ww call that more crop per drop, that effort.
It takes a lot of instruments to get that analyzed, and it takes a lot of
rigorous and careful
theoretical development to make sure we've got it right because so many cases
are different.
People need oxygen to run our respiration and you think what's a
person's water use efficiency. What its our personal water use efficiency?
You calculate how much water do we exhale and how much food we eat. It's the
reverse of plants. People have it easy because there's 21 %
oxygen in the air and we don't have to breathe very much and therefore we don't
lose much water. Plants have to work on 0.04% CO2 in the
air.
For plants to breathe,
they got to have their stomates wide open and the water diffuses out into the
world. I could start this by writing what I think is the most important
equation in the world.
Then you ask people what that is, maybe it's E=MC^2.
To me the most important equation in the world is
photosynthesis. Note they're subscripts on these C-6 H-12, but this is the basic the
simple stochiamitry. The plants in photosynthesis are taking this low
energy gas, that we used to put out fires, and turning it into carbohydrate, a
high-energy solid.
It's just amazing that they do that!
Again if this is a 20.95 % the oxygen and this is 0.04 %
the CO2,
not only are they taking a low energy gas but it's a trace gas,
it's minuscule. I've said it took the of molecules in here and turn
them colors. The nitrogen in the air if that was say black and
that oxygen was red.
Now try and see the CO2 molecules. You  probably wouldn't be able to see them
they are such a trace gas. This is four out of every ten thousand molecules is
CO2.
That's what the plants are having to work with. They got to keep their stomates
wide open to get that CO2. People can breathe with not having to
exhale much water vapor because there's plenty of oxygen. As my friend and
colleague Rick Allen says,"
It's a good thing plants don't have to go anywhere because as soon as they
start to move they get out of breath
there is not enough oxygen." Of course this is going the other way,
here's the photosynthesis, here's respiration.
But this low gas is really the fundamental reason we have to give so
much water to plants so they can make our food. So that puts it in
perspective of the stakes in this thing, trying to optimize every drop of that
massive amount of water. That's why
I was honored to be able to give a TED talk and talk about this issue of where
all the water is going in agriculture.
I think to start this,
I'm going to start with
another important equation, the energy balance equation. I think I said in
the outline the multiple components of this. Let's leave that
up here for a minute.
Let's even start before that, first law of thermodynamics: energy E in
equals E out.
This is easily the most widely known and the most to me by far the most profound
of the laws of thermodynamics.
There's really three laws of thermodynamics: energy has to balance; the
second one is the world tends to more entropy meaning more randomness in the
world,
the planets are moving apart and and the world's becoming more
random, lower energy; and the third one has to do with absolute zero, as you get
closer to absolute zero that the energy in the system approaches 0.
I don't know why that law just doesn't say at absolute zero everything stops,
but it doesn't. It says as you approach absolute zero you get less energy.
Some British chemist said about these three laws he said the first
one you could say there's no free lunch. That's another way to say
this, but he said you can't win because it's always balanced.
The second law is you can't even break even
because the world tends to lower entropy. The third law you can't even get
out of the game.
yYou can't quit the game. You're always at some temperature.  We're
going to focus on this, energy and energy out. Right away if we can measure
these components we can calculate the missing components. In the simplest
sense,
if this is radiation in (R in).
For now we'll do R for radiation. Over here we have transpiration plus
conduction and convection.
Different people use different symbols for these but I have typically
used C^2.
For conduction and convection, we consider simultaneously. Ones the heat
going to the molecules and the molecules blowing away but they're in one term.
This doesn't mathematically mean C x C. It just means there's C, C or C squared.
That's pretty simple
that's the essence of this whole energy balance equation.
These have to balance. Why do we have whole text books on this thing to
analyze this if it's this simple?
This is reduced to the simplest components. Any good plant person is going to
say wait a minute, wait a minute there's photosynthesis in this and some of the
energy goes into photosynthesis
and it's correct. Over here we have
P for photosynthesis and that's some of the energy.
Now we're getting a little more complicated and more detailed. Llet me
stop right here and make a mention about some of the principles for this. Many
books talk about this.
Let me start with a different book. Pretty much every University teaches
plant physiology whether they're a agriculture, land grant school, or
anything, they teach plant physiology. Every year new editions of new plant
physiology textbooks come out,
this is Tyson Zygier the one we use her, and you open up this fat tree it
gets thicker every year.
Try to find energy balance analysis in this textbook.
It's not in here. That is not a traditional part
of plant physiology. This deals with chemical principles and it deals with
single leaves and when it gets to calculating evapotranspiration
that's not a subject covered in this book. They do cover
what causes stomates to open and close, which is a key part of this but
that's it.
They do mention water use efficiency in here but they don't talk
about covering that. Lots of other books do. One of my favorites that I
learned this stuff from, fortunately it's now in the fourth
edition, this book by Park Nobel,
Physicochemical and Environmental Plant Physiology. The principles of what I'm
talking about are in this book in chapter 7. I use the same symbols as
he does in this book.
It's a great reference for looking at the principles.
I brought with me a few other key books that have been important to me and
also talk about these principles. One that many people are familiar with is
Galen Campbell's book and John Norman, An Introduction to Environmental Biophysics.
This has got a lot of great stuff in it.
It shows basic equations for this. This is also a good reference on these things.
Hamlin Jones, Plants in Microclimate: a Quantitative Qpproach to Environmental
Plant Physiology.
Any time somebody puts quantitative approach in the title some of the
students go eeee I'm going to try to avoid that class and the other students
go
wow this is cool I gotta sign up for that. So it depends on how good people
are with quantitative approaches. Here's a third one,
Environmental Physiology of Plants.
This subject matter is covered in many books it's just not
covered in traditional plant physiology textbooks.
Let's go back to our equation here
we're putting in photosynthesis
because some of the energy goes there. If we were doing energy balance
analysis of ourselves, which we do. We stand out in the Sun, we've got radiation
in. You gotta drink water
to stay hydrated. If you get hot, you lose heat by conduction and convection.
Photosynthesis
for most of us is approaching 0.
I'm still working on that chlorophyll gene so I can stand out in the sun and
then I don't have to eat.
Just have to get green skin. Our bodies are above room temperature
because of respiration.
Now we've got respiration in here and in the case of plants so do they have
respiration. When they respire, that's exothermic and that warms them up.
Because respiration is adding to the heat
we really have to do something like minus respiration
because it's it's giving off heat, it's not using it.
Any time we burn up heat. Those four components are the essence of this,
for this side.
What happens when something changes temperature? Energy in equals energy out.
This balances over long time periods but if you take a
black piece of metal and walk out in the sunlight out there and lay it out
it's going to get hotter. It's going to get hot fast and this won't balance
because it's heating up. Some of the energy is going in to change the
temperature. Then we bring that back into the room and it's cooling down;
we got all our hundred instruments around this thing
and energy doesn't balance.
It's cooling off because it doesn't balance. We have to have another term over here
and that's usually called G and that is storage.
Now storage is easy. That's either heating up and cooling off.
In the case of a leaf and my analysis is going to do a single leaf,
just one leaf out there in the Sun. How are we going to make the energy
balance for that? We get a leaf right and then we can go to bigger things canopies
and all kinds of bigger things.
How much goes into photosynthesis?
Let's just start with a rough estimate of the size of these parameters up here.
I'm going to ask you
how efficient is photosynthesis? Chris you ought to know this from some classes.
What's the efficiency of photosynthesis? You can
say in the test tube algae can be this good and in the field this good, but
about how efficient is photosynthesis? Do you have any idea?
Boston do you know? That's correct it's not very dang efficient.
What does that mean, less than fifty percent? Less than twenty percent?
Photosynthesis can be up to thirty percent efficient in a test tube with algea
in perfect conditions, but when we go to the field
we're talking more like five percent efficiency. It obviously varies.
How bright the light is, there's a whole bunch of factors. Let's
just go with five percent here.
That means ninety-five percent of the action is somewhere else in this equation.
If photosynthesis is five percent, how much energy comes out in respiration?
In people,  if its energy balance in people its food. You eat. That's how much energy you get.
This has to balance in food too. So if we ate 5 grams of food we had 5
grams of respiration.
In plants that are growing, respirations typically a third of
photosynthesis
because they're storing energy as they get bigger. Respiration might be two
percent. We're getting down to some terms that
are pretty small, here, and then storage in a single leaf, storage is
insignificant.
I'm going to see if I can draw a
that three-dimensional leaf here,  something like this. One of the
calculations in Park Nobel's book is how much a leaf could store?
How much energy a leaf could store given the magnitude of the radiation coming in
and he shows mathematically it's insignificant. A leaf is so thin
there's not much mass there and fifty percent of the leaf is air leaf. A leaf is just
a bunch of cells with air in between them and it's a fraction of a
millimeter thick. In a single leaf
we just ignore storage. This is absolutely not true as soon as soil
enters the equation. Soil now is huge but when we're talking about the leaves of
plants
storage is insignificant and both of these are tiny.
We can easily calculate this one too because... let me draw a graph of this.
Let's think about this efficiency of photosynthesis for a
minute. If I draw a graph,  of photosynthesis.
I love drawn XY plot so I get a lot of XY plots. Sometimes I think I dream
in XY plots. But here's radiation in and and here's 0 so it's dark and we
get up here to,
1000 watts per meter squared.
This would be typically full sunlight in a summer day.
Normally we do this graph with just photosynthetic radiation with photons
but for these purposes this is ok. We got energy coming in and over here we're
going to have
photosynthesis. Here's another thing that people understand the shape of this
graph at different levels.
If this was a high school class a correct answer to that question if
somebody said it looks like that,
they probably get full credit.
But what's wrong with this straight line?
Why is that not full credit for a more advanced class? What does it look like?
Yeah,  it can't keep going;
it tops out. So that part's wrong, so it tops out.
Now we're up to plant science 301 and that's the correct answer, but
it's not correct for plant science 501 or whatever number we are putting on
this.
What's still wrong about that?
What if we put a plant in the dark,
reagent grade darkness right here?
These are not plastic plants,
they are real plants. We put them in the dark,
they have respiration. So we put the plant in the dark and this is 0.
It has to go somewhere down here this line has to curve like that.
Now that line is correct at plant science 501.
We've got this dynamic down here at zero and we've got the flat line as a general
shape of this line. When we get these five percent numbers were usually
somewhere, I'll  put this in green,
we're usually somewhere on this part of the curve, early part of the curve where
we get higher photosynthesis.
By the time we get out to full Sun and we're out here. We're down to maybe
two percent efficient  in full Sun because it just tops out.
When we say five percent, yeah that's correct
if the sun's not too bright. This is the efficiency is like this and here's
five percent and that's that slope of that line is more like two percent.
Most of this transpiration is just what we ultimately after in this thing is
happening during the bright light parts of the day and the rest of this we
can ignore it for the for the first order estimates of transpiration and
conduction and convection. There are times when a refined analysis will
include photosynthesis but typically not. Typically we're just dealing with this
part right here, even though that's the full equation as it relates to plants.
We can put numbers on this, quickly put numbers on this and the sum of these two
fluxes has to equal this one.
Let's do a very quick calculation. I just love back-of-the-envelope
calculations. The goal of this classes to get everybody to were every time
somebody asks a question they go,
"mmm you got some paper" and you can calculate stuff. There's all kinds of
things you can calculate if you get started and get a little background.
Let's say we have radiation in, 1000 watts per meter squared.
Now this is a nice number to remember because right now that's about the
radiation outside this classroom
coming in. Let's say our leaf right here is evaporating, to be anatomically
correct
water always has to be shown in blue,
this leaf is evaporating enough water to stay exactly at the same temperature as
the air.
This happens all the time you put a wet dishrag on your clothesline, black
dishrag maybe to simulate a leaf, and measure the temperature of that it's
going to be pretty close to air temperature because it's evaporating
water at the same rate as that energy is coming in, and in fact a very wet dishrag
is pretty often below air temperature around here.
Then as soon as it starts to dry out,
now it's still evaporating water, but it goes above air temperature. Let's say
it's the same. So conduction and
convection is 0, and if it's the same at this leaf is 25 degrees C and the air
is 25 degrees C that exchange is 0. Now we have really simplified this energy
balance analysis to see where we're at.
We got 100 watts coming in zero is here,
how much water does it  evaporate?
What you find out in this analysis is a huge part of it is just
units conversion from getting one unit to the next getting all straightened out,
and once you get that then I tell people a monkey could do the last part
of it. Just the computer can do the last part of it  if you get the units right.
What we want to know is transpiration and what we know is energy coming in.
Let's start by looking up
a typical number.
I can  put this over here, I can even zoom in. Here we go, now too much zoom in. This
is out of this book right here, Utah Climate.
It's  published by the climate center and it's just a bunch of statistics of
climate. In this example here, I have pulled out the campus weather station.
This is this is 30-year data this is not our new environmental observatory, this
is a older station,
real old up by the place you buy ice cream up there, nutrition and food
science. Here's every month of the year,
evapotranspiration, inches per month.
Now we're going to take the highest transpiration month of the year 7.48
inches.
This is per month, and that is 0.24 inches per day
It's 0.6 centimeters a day.
This is measured by, I think this one
this is measured by pan evaporation Taking a pan with water in it and look
at how much water evaporates in that pan. It is a old time-honored, simple method
to do this. Pan evaporation, we get a number right here equals 0.6
centimeters per day.
This is supposed to balance but we don't have the units in the right order
yet. To put the units in the right order,
there's one key number that you could probably have tattooed on your arm so
you could always remember this number
LHE (Latent Heat of Evaporation) and I use this number enough I can remember it,
2.45 megajoules per liter.
This is close to a constant. If the water is almost boiling,
this is something like 2.41 and  if the water is freezing it's something like
2.49, but it's 2.45 megajoules per liter at 25 degrees C. Really this
temperature doesn't matter that much.
This is three significant digits all of them round off
to 2.45. Okay, great.
But neither liters nor megajoules is in this equation yet.
For this first lecture, I want to take some units and see if this is 0
if we do this conversion here.
1000 watts is coming in. This is a real simple physical principle but
it trips people up a lot.
A watt is a rate of energy flow. Most people could probably answer on a test
a watt is a Joule per second. We just have this happen so much rates of energy
we just have this nickname form called the Watt,
but it trips people up sometimes. I think the whole thing would be simpler if we
always just said joules per second but going back and forth and this is a is
really helpful.
One of the ways to help think about this is if we had a gallon of gas
sitting here and you said how many watts are in that gallon of gas ,and somebody
whips out their phone and they say, "Um watts in a gallon of gas" and they say, "I can't
find it".
If you said how much energy is in that gallon of gas,
it's easy you can find the energy in a gallon gas. It's six to the tenth
bajillion joules of energy in a gallon of gas.
If I light a match and I blow it up,
it is six brazilian watts of power because it grew up in one second.
A watt is a rate of energy like release or energy transfer and  jewels is the
fundamental unit of energy.
Let's put this down here, 1000 joules per meter squared per
second.
We're dealing with centimeters a day.
I can see a conversion I need to make right away.
This is the maximum rate of energy coming in, in the middle of the day.
This one is the total water for the whole day.
Over here we got seconds and over here we got days. I have to put
another curve here.
This is solar noon and up here
this is 1000 watts per meter squared, the brightest we get typically
in the middle of the day.
If we're going to compare all the energy coming in a day to all the water
we used in a day,
we have to have the area under that curve. When we do that we get 30 mega
joules per meter squared per day.
These are full Sun summer day,
30 mega joules integrated under the curve. For comparison,
over here I'm going to change my units instead of 1000
joule, 30 mega joules per day.
We at least have the time
on the same on both axes. 0.6 centimeters of water from a pan
evaporating to possibly keep this equal.
We have to get this meter squared equal on both sides. To do that we're
going to take a tray, a giant cookie sheet.
We should sell cookie sheets, one meter squared cookie sheets for teaching
purposes because you could lay them out you could put water in them.
This is 1 meter squared. Our reference sheet,
the radiation is coming in to that one meter squared. If we evaporate 0.6
centimeters of water,
how many liters is that? To put the liters equal,
so this is 100 centimeters,
this is 100 centimeters, so 1 meter squared is 10,000 centimeters squared (10
to the fourth). This trips people up a lot because so much stuff is 10 to the
third, 10 to the third, everything's multiples of ten to the third.
This one is not, this is 10 to the fourth because it's a hundred times a hundred.
Then remember another reason that the metric system is so far superior to any
other system 1 centimeter cubed, is one milliliter, is one gram,
Which everybody learns that in high school. Then I do a true/false test
and I say this and this is one milligram, and I put the milla really big and half
the class misses it.  It's a gram.
This is a milliliter but that's a gram. Okay we're getting close to getting our
units the same.
One liter is 10 x 10 to 10 a thousand cubic centimeters.
One centimeter deep, one centimeter of water times ten to the fourth
centimeters of area is is a 10 to the fourth centimeters cubed or 10,000
centimeters cubed or ten thousand grams and ten thousand milliliters.
One centimeter deep is 10 liters
when we do this evaporation.  0.6 centimeters centimeters per
day is 6 liters
per meter squared per day. I went over
this math pretty fast but it's not complicated. A centimeter deep on
on a liter tray. If we had a meter of water and we poured into a meter squared
tray,  it would be a millimeter deep.
If we had 10 meters of water and we poured it in it would be a centimeter deep in
the tray. Therefore, 0.6  centimeters a day in a meter squared area is 6 liters of
water. We have 30 mega joules coming in per meter squared per day,
now we finally got units the same, meter squared per day and we can cancel those out.
30 mega joules in 6 liters now we bring out our latent heat of evaporation
and 30 mega joules divided by 2.45 megajoules per liter, and I
think this comes out to about 12
liters per meter squared
per day.
This is how much water would have to evaporate to keep this thing at the
exact same same temperature as the air, and what happened in this calculation
when we measure this we only get 6 liters.
Now I'm going to wind up in this  principal because tomorrow will pick it
up from here, if this was all that was going on you would then right in your
notebooks well clearly the object got hot because it doesn't balance. It needed
to about evaporate 12 liters of water to keep itself at air temperature and
these plants only evaporated 6.
It doesn't balance, this cannot be 0.
It heats up. You would be correct in the analysis of this, but it's more
complicated than that.
This is only a short wave radiation in. This was a very simple analysis. This
assumed every watt of this was absorbed and some of this gets reflected, some
gets transmitted. This is only short wave radiation we have to calculate
long-wave radiation to do a comprehensive analysis.
I filled up the board but tomorrow we'll break down this radiation into its
component parts to see how much of that radiation actually got absorbed.
Here is a perfect example. We do pan evaporation right to get these numbers.
Just put a pan out measure the water evaporating, time-honored. What if the
tray is made out of aluminum foil and another tray is painted
flat black. Huge difference in evaporation from those two so
we got account for the different amounts of radiation absorbed in order to make
this balance.This is an empirical number 0.6 centimeters a day
during them
hottest month of the year around here. Once we get this number
analyzed then we can start to look at partitioning between how hot the object
gets and how much water  has to evaporate.
This is driven by just the temperature
difference.
We can measure the temperature difference of this and we start to zero
in on transpiration, which like I said we don't have any good instruments to
measure that directly but this is an example of some simple units to get to
this.
I  like to end sometimes with
a homework assignment, which i'll just tell you the homework assignments in
here and you can decide if you want to work them. So I said this whole
thing is units conversion.
Here is a homework assignment, I sometimes given this on the first day of class.
Einstein's, it's one of the one of the top five most important equations in the
world, E equals MC squared. How much energy is in one pea seed? If this is right, and how long could you live if you
just ate one pea seed and you could use all the energy and that pea seed? Of course c
squared, speed of light squared is a huge numbers so it's a lot of energy. This
is about the simplest equation you can get and now think about units conversion.
Get the energy in a pea seed from the typical weight of a pea and then this.
MC squared with SI units and SI unit conversion comes out to be joules
of energy in the pea seed. I'll show you the key for this tomorrow.
The key for this is setting it up with the units.
All of you know SI units.
Here's a nice symbol for the whole world and SI units are of course wonderfully
simple. Seven base units and these calculations get immensely easier
when you get them down to base units
so we can compare different things.
Now days you can
look these up on them internet, not just the base units but all the relationships.
Most of them are so simple like watt and joules per second you remember them,
but here's a little handout that I've found useful on this for some of the
relationships.
This is a two sided hand out and it it helps to understand the relationships.
When we talk about energy balance
we're only talking about a very small subset of all the units in here but it
helps too
be fluent in the in the simplest relationships of SI units. his is
something I found that is useful.
I got a second one that I found useful.
It just looks like this. The first ones that double-sided, it's got some units on
the back. This is just conversions among units. Every single beginning
chemistry book has these SI units in the front and sometimes I think people see
those in the go yeah good and then they can forget about them for years and years.
Then you get to an energy balance analysis and you have to remember them
and use them.
I'm going to stop here and pick this up tomorrow.
There's no two sides it's all,  it's just it's one side.
No I'm wrong
it does have two sides. It just takes a subset of the units. It does have two
sides. The first side is self-sufficient and the next side is a is a subset of these with
some of the more common ones. We can copy this and I can give you the second side
tomorrow.
Any questions on how to apply this? Mark
Point number two on and indicates the seven components of energy balance.
Are you splitting conduction and convection into two?
No for the purpose of this  class I'm going to introduce the seventh
term tomorrow.
In a nutshell it's splitting radiation into short and long wave.
I like to start with the simplest thing and then get more complex.
I mean to work this out in five or eight minutes and and
finally get it in the same units that's the essence of energy balance.
Then you get to where,
okay it doesn't balance now why not.
Are our instruments not calibrated
and the answer in this particular case is the model is not complex enough yet
to account for that.
The model needs to be more detailed to account for it. As a
rule of thumb well watered plants stay very close to air
temperature. This term for well watered plants is always small and if we
get all the radiation right and this is exactly air temperature
then we know transpiration. But we gotta do short and long wave both to get that
term right.
As soon as they run out of water,  imagine a cactus in the desert.
One of my students came back and he said it's a hundred..They were in Phoenix
last week and they said I can't see how people live there.
They go from one building as quick as a possible to the next
air-conditioned building.
It was a hundred and fifteen in the day but it cooled off  to 90 at night.
How far is my car, can I make it?
But imagine a cactus without water. The tissues of that cactus are
just astronomically hot and it just sits there.
We can run this the other way, what if T was zero?
We run this analysis for putting a metal hammer
outside in the Sun let it get to equilibrium, now trying to pick up the
hammer and it's so hot you can't pick it up. Because this is an enormous number
and this one's 0.  I'm thinking if we do every day this
week,
that's five lectures. I put eight lectures but when I look at what
I've done it
typically it's maybe more like six or seven lectures.
Usually I give a pretty long lecture in the beginning about how I'm going to grade
the class and stuff like that and we can just skip all that.
We could do this whole thing by the end of the week maybe.
Let's see how we're at, how we go. Particularly today I tried to do, I don't
know how long was that.
That was including the introductory stuff that we might edit out.
I'm going to try to one hour of stuff but ifIi did an hour and a
half where we did some and we stopped and took a little break
you know it could we could get done by the end of the week. If we get into
more details and there's more questions well then it will take longer
but that's good.
I'll try to weave into this
the instruments we use. Everything's a component of the of the whole thing.
There's no single instrument to measure what we want to know. We just surround it
with indirect instruments and basically calculated by subtraction, which is how
we do everything and if we can measure something easily then we just measure it.
There's a whole bunch of stuff that we can measure so we have to model it
and transpiration is one that's a subject of all kinds of models.
All right i'll stop there.