summarize this and I remember to get my
space blanket out of my car so now you
can all understand how I can get nice
and warm in here
everyone should carry one of these for
emergencies like in their back pocket
they might become more important than
your cell phone yeah but and I think
mostly you can buy these at camping
that's where people end up using them
but I think these are so good car
manufacturers should all have a be
required to have a little pocket in the
door and they're one of these comes with
the car in the pocket if you ever get
stranded in a cold place and you can use
it we ended the last lecture talking
about radiation for us on a gift some
examples of that here's a picture of a
radiation frost detector just a flat
black disc so you can see how nicely
that radiates to space doesn't work at
all in the day because it keeps way up
above air temperature but it's designed
to only do at night so here's an example
graph of what this looks like at night
and this was a few years ago air
temperature bud and leaf now bud
temperature is a single little sensor
about the size of a fruit bud and here's
a classic example of this there is
everybody's above the zero Celsius so
we're all happy but right here the air
temperature is +3 and the wind this is
there's wind speed the wind died oh can
I go back
I'm going backwards here let's see we
got it we got to get back to that page
we were close to there we get to start
now all the way back okay
it opened up as a damn page so we can
there we go
here we go thank you the wind dies and
the the temperatures separate and we
have the beginning of a leaf starting to
freeze because it's below air
temperature so now the wind picks up and
not enough it's still calm wind and then
the wind dies here and these separate
and now clear these leaf has been below
freezing for several hours and then
finally the little tiny bud even goes
below freezing so the blue line or at
least the red line is what a grower
ought to be after not just the black
line and historically they've used the
black line so now we can go back to our
our camera what a growers do to protect
against frost this is a huge industry
and it's common to have problems that's
why fruit orchards are located on this
tops of valleys on the edges because the
cold air drains to the middle and
they're somewhat protected by elevation
we don't have fruit orchards in the
middle of the valley they're up along
the benches took perked up for that
reason many years ago and I remember
this as a kid growing up in Minnesota
reading about the Florida fruit growers
oranges in Florida and they would get
these dross late spring Foster's tender
buds are out so here is a picture of
some fruit trees
somewhere don't have to be in Florida
the most common way to protect your
fruit trees was to light this thing
called the smudge pot and it was
designed to burn really inefficiently
and make a whole bunch of black smoke
and they never got all that hot but this
black smoke would go up like this
and guess what they've just blocked the
cold night sky and this was effective
for protecting trees against this
radiation Frost because that emissivity
was blocked and these were used for
decades by fruit growers and they'd have
them all over their orchards and they'd
go out and light the smudge pots and
well they really make bad air pollution
so they were banned and now what are the
growers gonna do to keep their fruit
crops alive well if they could increase
the wind that would help them so I don't
have a picture here but they're not hard
to find the smudge pots go away and
there are pictures on the internet of
huge towers they look like reverse
electric wind generators blow and wind
over their crops all through the orchard
to mix the air and these are cooling by
radiation but they're warming them back
up by wind
so they both prevent inversions because
the wind but they also mix the air so
that they the airflow over the leaves
warms them up and they don't have a
radiation for us they just have leaves
similar temperature the air so when is
is a solution but these wind generators
and I've talked to some of the fruit
growers in Utah
they tell me they cost $10,000 per hour
to run that these are big wind
generators and if they're super
expensive
and of course I'm going geez you know
wouldn't you like to just put a few
thousand into a lot of really careful
monitoring because if you could just not
run this for an hour you've paid for
your whole weather station so we're
getting there but better better
monitoring so they can pinpoint when
they have to turn these on but this they
pay for themselves the value of the
fruits so much but now there's the third
technique that's getting more and more
popular and you're gonna love this
picture this was the cover of the
American Society for horticultural
science a few years ago and this is a
fruit tree crop I think this was in
Florida Dorf fruit trees are in pots and
it's the first thing in the morning and
you would go oh a lot of bummer you know
his crop is ruined
but this grower is so happy and you see
that sprinkler right there this is using
latent heat of condensation to keep his
trees warm they go below freezing he
turns on the sprinkler and this is cold
water but when that water freezes it
releases heat and it warms the leaves
only once you start this you have to
keep going all night long because it
can't stop but he keeps running the
sprinklers the water keeps freezing
doesn't pollute the air doesn't cost ten
thousand dollars an hour he's just
running his sprinklers but it's using
physical principles to prevent frost in
his crops and this is now the most
widely used method of frost protection
it makes a mess there's mud everywhere
in a yacht uses water but it uses water
in the early spring there's usually more
water and it's way way cheaper than
running these vans so it depends on the
orchard this is harder to do of course
if the trees are big but it's a great
principle and when I saw this and
started thinking about this I think I've
a data logger in my
and I run the wire out and my yard at
the thermocouple and put it next to my
garden and I didn't want to automate
this because well I miss all the fun I
had to turn on a radio when the
temperature got below freezing so I get
up and put on my slippers and go turn on
my irrigation controller and this is a
picture of my garden in 82 Crockett
Avenue on one morning after a radiation
frost it's a little glarry but this
looks like those orchards all covered
with ice
nothing froze I had tomatoes that made
it through the night it was a great
achievement and of course I'm monitoring
how the temperature went with
thermocouples out in my garden so this
isn't just a theoretical thing you can
do this in your yard to keep your
Tomatoes going longer in the fall and
all you have to do is pay for the water
bill no it just it just sits there and
freezes it protects them it doesn't it
it could I suppose but it's if it if it
got a heavy and a branch broke off it
could damage the plant but but it
doesn't happen all at once it's just
little tiny freezing and it gradually
builds up so this our frost sort depends
exactly where you left when the Frost's
are there there later campus than they
are in the middle of the valley but in
the middle of Lu or sometime in
September and into early October but the
problem is you get one frost and then
you might get where you hold that Indian
summer two or three weeks of nice
weather you can take advantage of that
if you if your client didn't freeze yep
late September
yes so that so the question is what
happens in the day well now the Sun
comes up in the radiations more
favorable and the Sun shines on it and
it melts the ice and they're fine
yeah you could you could probably keep
irrigating and
melt it off or something but but if the
Sun melts enough and that's actually
kind of important that it doesn't throw
up immediately but it's typically a cold
clear night is followed by a sunny day
it's clear at night it's clear the next
morning so it warms up and you can melt
all the ice and the temperature swings
are big so and it just barely went below
freezing so the next day is it pretty
easily melts all the ice the next day so
this is one of those things you got to
try this at home
because it works and you just need a
little controller to tell when it to
turn the sprinklers on you need to know
when to turn them on because you make it
worse if you turn them on too early it's
not freezing no it's wet and now it
makes them colder it only makes a
mourner when there really are a below
freezing so you want to get the timing
just right and calculate the leaf
surface temperatures and when they're
freezing then you start and then they
have plants can take minus one below
freezing but they can't take minus 2 or
3 and this keeps them right close to
freezing so
a couple other follow-up things on
conduction and convection this is an
article from a few years ago a newspaper
article nice concise summary but many
people know and everybody knows about
wind chill and if you grow up in a
really cold place and it's windy and the
winter the wind chills way colder than
the air temperature and when I was a kid
growing up they closed schools because
the windchill got so cold that they just
closed the school well it turns out the
windchill factor was initially a really
crude factor by a guy in our Antarctica
put in a can of water out and then
looking at wind and how long it took the
water to freeze and he made this crude
index so much later people came along
with biophysical principles of heat
transfer and made a new wind chill
factor and what they found was this guy
overestimated it and so it's really not
as cold as it seems when we have the
corrected index and people were slow to
use the new one because everyone likes
to brag about how cold it is and really
not as bad as it seems but this is a
short summary of this and calculating
the the windchill we do that by the way
on campus we have a line for windchill
and the winter how cold it gets but it's
it's a great and now this is widely used
I mean now people when they do school
closings they don't use the embellished
windchill factor they use the real one
this is a nice summary of that
so I've had these beads up here for a
for a couple of days can you see those
Gris and this and this thing and I
forgot to show these to you the other
day I had occurred to me to make this a
couple years ago when I was asked to do
a TED talk on water and I wanted to find
ways to emphasize what's in the air and
so we went to El Sporting Goods and
bought a bunch of these little white
pellets and then we had to paint them
colors to get this but this big jar
represents the nitrogen in the air
twenty point nine five percent this is
the oxygen in the air this one is the
carbon dioxide there's 10,000 of these
bb's to every four and and the point is
wow the plants have to find those four
molecules - for photosynthesis that's
just remarkable and here's what we get
to work with we have twenty point nine
five percent for our breathing but
here's the other thing water you look at
what's in the air and nobody ever
mentions water because water is so
variable these are other ones are very
constants and now we had water to this
so if you counted these I made this
example three percent water which is a
typical day in the summer if this was
air in the winter
and if this was a real thing I could
take this and I would just pour a bunch
of these out so there's just a few left
winter air hardly has any water in it it
is so cold the water can't hold anything
so this jar would just have a few water
molecules in it if we made hot humid air
this could get could this could double
this amount of water vapor in the air
but I've always liked this because it's
a nice concise visual demonstration of
nitrogen oxygen water vapor and co2 and
all the other stuff like there's a
little argon and the other stuff we can
ignore but we certainly can't ignore
these four Co twos when I was a kid
there's a there would have been three in
this jar now you know how old I am
old enough to remember when there were
three in this jar and now we got this up
to four and we're working another twenty
thirty years we might get it up to five
in the jar that's that 400 parts per
million for in that jar but it's a great
visual demonstration of what's in them
air I suppose I could do this with some
leaf and have these inside the leaf and
in the air and then you could even have
them kind of falling out of the leaf to
show transpiration rate and there's
probably a lot you could do with bee
bees from else trophy or else boarding
goods it's a great thing now I want to
switch a bit ome another miscellaneous a
couple other miscellaneous things are
interesting this came up the other day a
little bit comfort box on a psychometric
table I'll look this up this here's the
same psychometric chart this is for the
space station humidity and temperature
interact so they say we try to get in
this box and then people are comfortable
and it varies a little bit with humidity
so when when you do building control you
try to arrange your humidity and
temperature to be in the comfort box or
the room it also came up the effective
pressure on this psychometric chart so I
thought of a way to show this this is a
psychometric chart for sea level I
probably can zoom in just slightly on
this and it looks exactly like the ones
we handed out now this has other factors
in here has enthalpy and things
but this is the chart for sea-level now
I made a transparency of the exact same
chart for our elevation I didn't make it
I looked it up and printed it so I'm
going to lay this on top of this and
trying to line up the zeros and they
look pretty close they're not exact but
they're pretty close so when you look at
these this shift is like this as you go
to high elevation this saturation curve
shifts up
and here's 1500 meters in here sea level
and I looked at the numbers for 28c and
the absolute humidity 100% at 28 C at
sea levels twenty four point six and in
in Logan it's 29 now that's a big
difference but after you divide for air
pressure this number is 86 percent of
that number and our pressure is 86
percent of sea level so when this chart
is per kilogram it's a different chart
everything shifted if this chart is
saturation vapor pressure and you divide
by pressure its then it's the same chart
you don't need charts for elevation they
only differ when you have amount of
water per weight of air not per volume
of air um you could see when the when
the pressure is less that that air
dilutes and it's the same amount of
water
so these that's why we simplified that
whole chart to just do that saturation
vapor pressure curve
now I want to talk about in in closing
implementation of all of these
principles we've been talking about in
what's called the pennmen Monteith
equation we use this two guys Penman and
Monteith we used this equation all the
time to calculate evapotranspiration and
i'm going to show you the equation and
say how do these principles go into this
equation to do this perhaps the best
book for this is this book called food
and agriculture organization fao 56 crop
evapotranspiration guidelines for
computing crop water requirements so
this is full of step by step
implementation of these principles I can
probably put this right here and it
occurs to me that with this thing I
could just open the pages in and show
the pages instead I made some I copied
some of the key graphs out of this yes
that this thank you and this the
question is there's a website for this
and you can get the whole book on the
web I think the book the paper copy cost
quite a bit but the website is free and
yeah so let's jump right here - mmm the
pennmen monte here it is I have to fold
this to make it fit
I'm gonna zoom in just a bit
so now we can I could probably soo-min
even more get this big so here's the
pennmen Monteith now this varies the
coefficients vary depending on the units
everything has units and in a rough
sense if we took all these energy
balance principles and rearranged the
equation they would have a lot of
coefficients like this but let's look at
the difference so first of all this is
with the units in here
reference evapotranspiration now what
this means is the maximum you could get
for the conditions in millimeters a day
so you could do that with this then look
at the next components net radiation -
soil heat flux now we didn't put soil
heat flux in here but it wouldn't be
hard we could just say sums disappearing
in the ground and sums coming back out
of the ground so there's net radiation
right front and center in this equation
then we go air temperature that's that's
jump to a saturation minus iere so
there's our leaf - air difference in
this equation the rest of these
coefficients without going into this in
detail are units conversion to get this
- net radiation and resistance to water
flow
here's another key thing that people
don't think about in this U is wind
speed that's the universal symbol for
wind speed this is in the numerator this
is in the numerator as these get bigger
transpiration gets bigger look at wind
speed it's in both the numerator and the
denominator of this now we have wind
speed is just up here house wind speed
in the numerator and denominator
if you ask the question does wind
increase transpiration this wind
increased transpiration true or false it
depends
there could be no change - that's a
tricky question and in fact it turns out
I heard this was a part of a law case
once with somebody suing somebody else
over water rights and the wind if the
leaf is already well watered and it's
close to air temperature the wind will
end it or if it's especially below air
temperature the wind will definitely
increase transpiration by a lot because
it's warm and the wind warms the leaf up
because it's below air temperature and
most of the time when we use this it's
for well watered crops and then when
does increase it but now imagine a
cactus or some plant that's water
stressed the leaves are 10 degrees C
above air temperature transpiration
minimal but the wind starts to blow the
leaves cool off there's a case where the
wind could decrease transpiration if the
plants water stressed and and the wind
helps cool the leaves down that's an
exception but it could happen and in
intermediate cases you can kind of see
that from here with a numerator and
denominator wind doesn't have as big of
an effect on transpiration as most
people think
yet it cools our skin
well we're benefiting from both of these
when when we're out and we're hot and
the wind breeze blows we cool off but in
the case of water we're only we're only
worried about this so this book
FAO 56 includes this nice graph here
figure 10 effective wind speed on this
and here's increasing wind speeds hot
and dry it's helping but as it gets more
humid that the effect here is effective
example of no effect of all and even
this effect is not all that great this
is not a real steep line so this is
because wind effects it can cool off the
leaves significantly this another useful
figure from this here is an example of
these components through the day we just
talked about to calculate examples right
here at noon but here's our
evapotranspiration and they shall lambda
for that symbol H is conduction and
convection H is a common symbol for that
and G is storage in the ground but
there's the total and it's partition
roughly equal into the two parts and
this particular example et was more than
this in the mornings when it's cool et
can equal net radiation and then find
the transpiration can't keep up and then
sense of then the leaves start to warm
up but you can imagine scenarios like
this where these the partitioning of
these changes all over the place
depending on water of the plants but
it's a nice diagram of how that changes
through the day so
we another important aspect of this that
is often overlooked this calculates ET
but now we have a coefficient with this
and as we've run these equations its ET
zero or uh or all eto and all you can
think about is optimum this is the
maximum that could run and everybody
runs this equation and they calculate
the maximum and I think that's what they
got to irrigate with and that's the
maximum not them not that typical so we
have all those components that we just
showed in this big honkin equation
measured with great precision with all
of our instruments to get the inputs
just right in this and then to estimate
actual we multiply this by K and a lot
of times its Jonas Casey that's a crop
coefficient and it changes with the
amount of ground cover when the plants
are little there's not much of a pore
transpiration they fail in this goes up
so this and this number varies from zero
and I've seen it as high as one point
two it actually can go above one which
says something about whether this is
really the optimal because the crop
coefficient is even higher than the
optimal this is a very coarse estimate
of the water so even if we get this to
three significant digits with the most
precise instruments ever we got to
multiply to this which at best is plus
or minus 10% maybe 20% so this and then
this equals DT of the C of the crop of
the actual crop
and not many people think about this we
take a number that we're trying to get
super precise and we multiply it by
really kind of a ballpark estimate and
that leads to a lot of people really
over irrigating in the implementation of
this this is mrs. F here's a diagram of
that in this book of the reference crop
ETO and then you multiply by this factor
to get 80 of them Crump and then because
plants aren't always well watered even
with all of this this is still for well
watered then we try you might show this
down here back out just a bit then we
try to put an adjustment factor in here
for how water stress they are so we have
to fudge factors on this precisely
measured et the crop coefficient and
then the whoa this is really a water
stress coefficient and we get the crop
coefficient adjusted oh boy by the time
we get to this one where it's kind of
like spray-and-pray you're hoping you
got it in the ballpark for irrigation
and meanwhile we're running out of water
so there's there's a lot of potential to
calculate water I want to talk about
another technique of calculating this
that well first of all there are at
least 20 equations in the literature for
calculating evapotranspiration from
weather variables all over the place and
they're in there in discussed in this
book Blaney Krita I forgotten all the
names but many many people have worked
on this this is becoming the standard
because our weather stations are getting
better and we have instruments to
measure all the parameters to do this
and it is the most biophysical it's
based on physical principles so we've
come to trust this but it lots of
people don't have all the instruments to
measure the inputs to this so what are
they going to do and what did they do
before the pennmen Monteith was was
usable here is a one-page handout we
keep two pages that I wrote this for
them there's some of the introduction to
this Utah climate book about ways to do
ET and I'm and hopefully easy to read
but it shows more than 20 equations have
been developed to do this here's the
potential it summarizes all the stuff
then we get to this the Hargreaves
equation George Hargreaves is on the
faculty here at Utah State University
and of the 20 equations I would say next
to the pennmen Monteith his is one of
the best it works the best and it is way
simpler than the pennmen Monteith to run
here's the equation and I've been told
this story by Rick Allen who was on the
faculty who has written much he has a
award-winning paper called the pennmen
for all seasons and it's about the use
of the pennmen Monteith equation in all
conditions all around the world and Rick
tells me even he and Hargreaves died
about two years ago he lived here in
Logan he said Hargreaves would come in
his office and that the models didn't
match the measurements and and he'd say
yeah and the two models wouldn't agree
that our graves in the pennmen monty
'then he'd say yeah well that's because
your models too complicated and you're
gonna get bad data in it and if you just
use my model it's simple and it works
and it does work for a wide range of
conditions that look at the inputs to
this min and max temperature Wow
this was from the days when there were
no data loggers we just had min max
thermometers that was it that's all we
had to go on
and his brilliance in developing this
was to empirically correlate min and Max
temperature with pan evaporation and
he's got mean right here but that was
the mean was in between men and Max so
he still had men and Max this is the
sport of the point oh five this is the
square root RA he said all he had to do
net radiation no he didn't he calculated
it based on radiation above the Earth's
atmosphere that was a completely a model
based on latitude he didn't have to
measure net radiation he calculated it
from the time of year and the Sun above
the atmosphere and then here's a
coefficient and this equation for ETO
works remarkably well and it's way
simpler but we we don't use it much
anymore because we've got lots of
instruments and we can use them far more
complex Penman Monteith when you get
into the literature on this and you turn
the page this is with my colleague Larry
hips talking about this this Hargreaves
tends to under predict under high wind
conditions and over predict in high
relative humidity so it's not perfect
and then when it gets to minus 17.8 C it
goes nuts because it values go negative
but you're not too worried about that
because those are super cold days it's
made for them summer but I show this
just because it's a it's a brilliant
empirical equation then does a pretty
good job match in the evapotranspiration
data
I'm gonna close with this picture as we
work and work and work to model this and
calculate it we keep going back to Lysa
meters a big container that we can weigh
water is heavy we can accurately measure
transpiration used by weight but you
have to contain the plants in something
you can weigh and all of a sudden you're
into ten twenty thousand dollars per
container in the field to set up a
system to weigh the plants so this is a
system in art and the research
greenhouses that my students and I build
and each one of these has a load cell
underneath it and here's some corn
plants in a bucket to get evaporation
low we covered them with tinfoil but we
can do various levels of water stress in
here using lysa meters and look at these
principles and see how well they apply
to different kinds of plants we can do
precision water stress with this because
we can bring them down to a low weight
and keep them there just water enough to
keep them there we can tell they well
how well water stress they are we can
determine obviously hourly transpiration
rates with this this is all hooked up to
multiplexers and Campbell scientific
data loggers too and we watch them
transpire on the screen this has been a
really useful technique of course it
constrains the roots so there's our big
interacting factor or what would they do
in the field if they had more roots and
we can get bigger lysimeter so we can
get bigger load cells but they don't
have the precision so it's all and then
you can't have as many replicates if you
have big load cells so mark question
we have a photosynthesis terming the
energy balance but because
photosynthesis is small this application
you have a higher precision instruments
to very accurately weigh the water you
know exactly what what water loss is but
there's going to be a mass gain because
of the carbon right yes yes now we're
into the details so the the question is
the way to this will change because the
plants are getting bigger and not just
the dry weight but the fresh weight of
the plants are getting bigger and we do
worry about that and in some cases we
calculate it out in most cases we
calculate it out but this brings up a
really interesting opportunity to make a
point you would think wow aren't you
using this to measure the size of the
plants and not know every the water in
the soil because the weight of the water
down here is several orders of magnitude
greater than the fresh way to the plants
and the water use efficiency of these
plants might be one gram of dry weight
per thousand grams of water transpired
so that says something about and it
might be 10 grams of fresh weight or
thousand grams of water but the water
transpiration and the water flux through
this is at least a hundred times bigger
than the fresh weight gain and we back
calculate the fresh rate gained by the
water lost if we've transpired a hundred
grams of water then 0.3 grams of fresh
weight is added to the system so it does
matter but it's small because of the
poor water use efficiency because of
waters fluxing through those and the
fresh weight gains tiny
if we just go buy this replacement that
you pull 10 grams of 10 grams water
that's 1% right yes we were saying maybe
2% of the radiation and one percent of
the water so very similar yes this so
one two hundred it might be fresh wait
but photosynthesis makes dry weight and
that's more like one to a thousand even
a thousand grams of water lost and one
gram of dry weight showing up which kind
of its small and depending on the model
it photosynthesis can be 5% and so now
if we're really tweaking this model we
can start to put coefficients in for
this but this leads to a larger issue
with models at least in my experience we
start putting more coefficients into
this thing and we forget about the
importance of the two big things I love
simple models you get the relationships
right in your head and you start to
think about it and then we start to add
more coefficients and the tendency is to
think we've made a better model because
we have 14 coefficients instead of two
and it gets in the way of people's
thinking to have extra coefficients and
they're in many cases they don't add
they don't fundamentally add to the
precision of the model this is obviously
a a big discussion among lots of people
as how many coefficients to put and how
many are useful I think it's analogous
to how many significant digits you show
in a spreadsheet
well great we can calculate a
spreadsheet in Excel put six six or
eight significant digits on every number
and now you're scanning that spreadsheet
looking for patterns in the data
and all those extra digits are just
noise and they they block our ability to
see the big picture of patterns these
are all sidebars related to your
question but but photosynthesis is in
some of the models and for sure when you
apply this to soils now the not yet have
storage we didn't talk about storage at
all but the book goes into storage
quite a bit and that's a whole nother
subject term getting that storage
component right which is why we have
heat flux sensors in the soil to try and
measure that and it's hard to measure
so we'd model back and forth measure and
model and hope we got that part of it
right
so I'll end there you've been a great
audience thank you for coming to these
lectures and hopefully you find places
to apply this stuff
[Applause]