series and I want to get some closure
Ryan today on this topic of energy
balance um but there's one little tidbit
I want to point out before I get into
the Earth's energy
balance this is a graph remember how we
said the radiation can go above a
thousand because of Reflection from
clouds and that causes all kinds of
people to panic about things this was
happens to be some data from the campus
environmental Observatory for last
January but it was a series of days that
were partly
cloudy so there's a black line on here
that is the calculated radiation for a
clear sky now this is winter so note it
only goes to about
450 watts per meter squared but that's
the value for the winter so here's three
different replicate radiometers in here
and this was partly cloudy this is
partly cloudy this was very cloudy then
look at this day right here the clouds
acted like a lens like we talked about
and even though the clear sky was about
450 we had readings of
650 on the instrument that wasn't bad
instruments it was reflection of light
by clouds so sometimes these can go way
above clear sky by uh radiation focusing
on
them and then we calculate Nat and
shortwave on here in addition but the
main point here was to show this but it
has been very useful for us to calculate
a clear sky
radiation so you can tell here's a day
when it was clear sky and the
instruments are close to the model they
came up with the sky came down with the
sky so because the clear sky model is so
useful we've there's a website that
shows this it's I can show it on the
magnet here's the magnet right
here and I
can many of you have this magnet boy you
got to they're really uh bonded
together this is the third mag third and
Fin
magnet that we're going to talk about
and this is that clear sky
calculator.com
and it for any time a day any point in
the world this calculates the clear sky
and it's particularly accurate at solar
noon and you can use it to tell if your
instruments need to be
re-calibrated we all of our tests with
this indicate in the summer at solar
noon this is within 2% of the True Value
um the coefficients you put in here
include humidity and temperature because
of atmospheric attenuation elevation
latitude of course time of year um
calculate radiation anywhere in the
world that's just a little tidbit that's
been really useful to help people make
better measurements for uh radiation and
it's fairly widely used think it could
be used a lot more widely um for people
to make better
measurements so now this is the outline
for today where we hope to get to
radiation balance of the earth I think
it's real interesting as soon as we get
these numbers and we can figure out
radiation for a leaf how's this look if
we do the whole planet
and this
is the I guess I need
to maybe not don't need to zoom in or
out there it is the whole planet there's
many diagrams like this but this is one
of my
favorites I stopped into pole Campbell's
office a year ago and he had this on the
wall of his office and it's I gave it to
him and he loved it so we put it on his
wall here's all the incoming solar
energy to the Earth so 6% boom right off
the bat reflected by the atmosphere
right back into
space clouds this is a variable if
there's more clouds more reflection but
some clouds and then finally Earth
surface pretty small
reflection
um absorbed by the atmosphere a tiny bit
but then finally here's the absorbed by
land and oceans and then this warms up
and it radiates into space as long wave
radiation so it's coming in as shortwave
and it's going out as long wave I love
these colors cuz the burner on a stove
is glows red and that's longwave
radiation so um all of these are small
numbers but you can see how this is a
delicate balance if this radiation
balance
changes
and for all the apparent controversy
about global warming
we know CO2 absorbs longwave radiation
we know CO2 is going up we can
mathematically calculate the absorption
of CO2 of radiation by CO2 in the air
and calculate the heating caused by that
so you could say how could this be
controversial these are known physical
principles and as we say the absorption
of longwave radiation of by CO2
is unassailable we we know exactly how
it
changes this cooling by longwave
radiation here's the amazing thing about
this remember we had well you could see
them on here n there's not numbers on
here but this is a th watts in the
middle of the day coming in these are
big numbers here's a
paper by a whole bunch of authors
one of the key authors is James Hansen
who was quite famous for in circles he's
a testified before Congress many times
on this and look at how many offers they
put in these papers um but look at this
our climate model driven by human-made
greenhouse gases aerosols calculates the
Earth is now
absorbing
0.85 watts per met squar more energy
than the sun then it's emitting to
space less than one watt is the energy
in balance of the earth now he puts a
plus or minus
0.15 that's those are some serious
models you're not saying oh this is less
than 5% we'll throw that out all that
stuff matters so even though these are
known physical principles the energy
imbalance is small but it's enough to
cause the temperature to rise um I think
the only controversy about global
warming is what's the effect of rising
temperature yes it's rising and yes it's
caused by CO2 and yes the CO2 is caused
by people so can Canadians have a
t-shirt that says I'm in favor of global
warming so so some people it's not a bad
thing to them and then people say well
look it's going to melt the ice caps
raise the ocean Miami will be flooded
so they can
move that's there's the controversy it's
not what's happening it's how serious is
the problem and that's where we get into
erratic weather if all that happened was
a slow steady increase in temperature a
few tents of a degree per decade we can
deal with that but if the weather goes
chaotic now we got a big problem and
there's the Cutting Edge of climate
science research is will global warming
cause erratic weather and there's lots
of evidence that it does but there
people disagree about how much erratic
weathers might happen if it changes
rainfall patterns that's a big deal that
can change agriculture it could it can
cause a lot famine for a lot of people
just by shifts and rainfall patterns so
to me
That's The Cutting Edge of climate
change research um not whether it's
happening but what are the long-term
consequences going to be but I when I
read this paper I it it was some years
ago but I just about fell out of my
chair I think of when you think of the
fluxes of these
numbers so I want to go into this a tiny
bit
more several years ago got to zoom out
on this NASA
got ready to launch a satellite called
glory and and this is a brochure on
Glory understanding the Earth's energy
budget now NASA has lots of satellites
doing this already but this one had
specialized instruments to get some of
the Lesser known parameters to measure
them more accurately and we were all so
excited about this
satellite it took years of work and had
really expensive in instruments it blew
up on launch
and it and now we're trying to get money
again to launch another version of it
but in this
brochure was a
two-page
analysis of the Earth's energy budget
that I thought was the best short
summary I had ever read of this so I'm
sharing it with
you the this
is I have two handouts one here's one is
the what I just showed which shows
percentages of all these arrows and now
you have a a sense of what those arrows
all look like on a single leaf apply the
same principles to the whole
planet this one shows absolute numbers
on this I might be able to focus this a
tiny bit
better um this one shows absolute
numbers you can't see them here but they
on this handout um and what's reflected
and absorbed and of course these numbers
change as the Earth rotates we're not
always measuring it right pointed at the
sun there's nighttime in there and we're
on the edges but it but in a nutshell
this shows these so here's another
reason another thing that helps you
understand some of the controversy in
this here's radiative
what's called radiative forcings which
is just another name for what's causing
this and I want to zoom in on this just
a little
bit radiative forcing components now
this is becoming more and more common
for people to express their data like
this but if you haven't seen this before
and people debate the size of the error
bars on these but it also helps you
understand the controversy about global
warning so if it that bar goes up that
means it's a factor causing the Earth to
get warmer if it goes down it's a factor
causing Earth to get colder so if
there's things on here that
reflected radiation the Earth would cool
and if they absorb it gets warmer here's
CO2 the biggest bar in this graph in the
end over here is the net of everything
here's CO2 that error bar is our that
difference among the models of what CO2
is doing and they're not all the same
and this is watts per met
squared so 1.5 1.6 watts per met squ
Plus or minus1 or02 that's not very
controversial we we understand this
methane nitrogen oxide gases and hoc
carbons are real powerful absorbers of
longwave radiation so just traces of
these have a big effect and cumulatively
these add about another Wat per meter
squared these have been going into the
atmosphere before they were people but
human activities have increased these
other gases as well there's a lot of
work on methane and nitrogen oxides and
other things now in addition to just
CO2 so then we go into ozone and there's
El tiny elements of cooling and heating
this is a much smaller bar but a bigger
error bar on that um Stratos pheric
water vapor tiny changes in atmospheric
water water absorbs long wave radiation
so if the humidity changes it it drives
warming but not very much then albo if
we painted the Earth white we'd cool it
off well land use changes can mean that
more radiation gets reflected into space
if we have big forests they absorb a lot
of radiation we cut them down we just
have bare ground
we reflect more radiation into space so
there's bigger error bars here but it's
plus or minus now we get to
aerosols droplets tiny droplets of
things in the air they're if we had a
microscope you could see them but
they're they're uh droplets of liquids
in the air they reflect radiation and
look at the size of these error bars
Cloud albo
effect those clouds that are caus cusing
us complications in our model if it's
cloudy all the time the Earth is going
to cool so that's one of the huge
variables in here is what the clouds do
because look at the size of that error
bar um clouds are aerosols after all so
they're in this category and then a
couple other tiny factors changes in
solar radiation people said the sun is
just putting out more
energy well yes it is there it is it's
above zero and and with a pretty big a
bar but this is not a big effect um we
would like to say it's all this party on
don't worry these things are minor
compared to the Sun but the data doesn't
support that hypothesis and here's the
net effect now this model shows about
1.6 watts per meter squared and the
paper I just showed had 85 watts per
meter squar so you can see where the
different models vary a little
but there are no models that say this is
zero and there are no models that say
it's a negative number they just vary in
the magnitude of the warming but this
helps explain why it's controversial
because some things make it cooler some
things make it warmer
um for years we've worked with NASA on
on long-term space missions growing Food
for People in space so one of the issues
is terraforming Mars can't we just start
making Mars more of a nicer Planet well
yeah but it's cold well we'll just fly
some stuff up there that turns it black
and makes a planet darker and then you
run the numbers and yeah that works you
can make Mars a darker color get the
absorption up it'll start to warm up
it'll melt the water into ice and pretty
soon we start to create an atmosphere up
there so they're literally as smart
people saying let's get Mars darker so
we can might take 50 100 years but let's
get it darker so we can go and live
there that's this is these application
of energy balance principles to whole
planets not just our
own whole universe has to follow the
first law of
thermodynamics far as we know we haven't
discovered a universe that doesn't have
to follow that so we take those
principles to other
places
so with all
the convers ation and debate about
global warming I think it's useful for
people to be a bit more educated
particularly when you get the principles
of shortwave and longwave radiation now
you can take those and apply them to
lots of
places
so I'm not sure where NASA is on another
satellite but but a big part of that one
was to do uh
aerosols this is following up now in my
order of my organization on a few little
things that we didn't get
into remember
when radiation
absorbed equals radiation
in Time 1 minus lbo
this is all fine and then we said for a
typical Leaf the albo is 1
minus
0.5 so
0.5
however here's shortwave radiation again
short and long here's the short wave
here's the long wave
l s over
here long wave is really pretty
consistent it doesn't matter what
wavelength it is for long wave as far as
absorption of materials matters a lot
for transmission through the atmosphere
but when we talk about longwave
radiation a number that's at
8,000 would behave similarly to 50,000
it's all those wavelengths are the same
this is not true for shortwave radiation
the the wavelengths matter a lot for
shortwave and when we say 50% Elbo or
25% when people talk about
albo they are talking about an average
of all the wavelengths and remember this
is about 280
nanom to 3,000 this whole thing is in
units of nanometers lots of times you
see this in
micrometers these wavings matter a
lot and
on now let me get get to this in a
second in the
textbook
[Music]
for right here figure
7.4 this shows for a typical
Leaf what's absorbed what's reflected
and what's transmitted and of course
this is very far from a flat line you
can see that 50% is an average so that's
okay we can use
50%
but here's photosynthetic radiation
micrometers point4 to 7 almost all
absorbed up this and remember this is
40% of the total almost all absorbed of
this this is what causes photosynthesis
so it's a good thing it's absorbed then
we get to 700 and there no the
chlorophyll molecule does not absorb
light past
700 it's just heat so I'm going to say
that plants are pretty
smart they let that thermal radiation go
right through or they reflect it and
this radiation is like 10% absorbed this
near INF red radiation and if we draw it
on our graph right
here we have
UV we have
4700 this
is
95%
absorbed this this radiation in here
then suddenly it gets just past that and
I control this and this part of it out
here is is
maybe 10% absorbed depends it depends on
the exact wavelength you can see this
bounces around out here a little
but it's so it's a little misleading it
simplifies the model a great deal to say
we just have one number for albo but
since we're dealing with plants and
and not
just parking lots and other surfaces
it's it's important to know that these
very a lot that's the diagram in the
book and lots of people diagram the same
thing in different
ways here's a diagram from another book
and I like this a little better cuz it's
not on a log scale so you can see it
better and now it has absorption here
photosynthetically active radiation 400
to 700 nanm this is green light so
little bit more green light bounces off
and little bit more is transmitted but
boom right at 700
nanm the reflection and transmission go
up and they're real low until we get out
here to 1.4
1.5 and then they become absorb more but
the amount of radiation is going down
like this so these are huge amounts here
and after we get out here there's just
much less
radiation this shows differential
absorption by the leaf of those
components
and I could tell you were worried about
this
because this is the handout from the
other day let me back off so you see the
whole thing
here this is the handout that talked
about typical values for Elbo
and emissivity of these and then if you
kept reading for being in advance you're
itchy to ask me what's going on with
these numbers down here and I think I
got to fold this to show it on the
bottom of this is what happens to this
radiation
there and I'll zoom in a bit but these
are typical numbers on the bottom of
this and it Segways into long wave too
photosynthetic now on here I put 90%
absorbed and over here I put 90% it's
High um it depends on how thick the leaf
is whether it's 90 or
95 roughly equal amounts of reflection
and transmission to to 100% so great
there's photosynthetic boom we draw our
line and it switches to to uh mostly
reflection and transmission
and this is a big reason leaves can stay
cool they're not having to absorb that
thermal radiation it's of no value to
them unless they're cold and they want
to try and get warmer but they got
plenty of light to keep them warm so
then we go in this to longwave
radiation
and 4,000 to
100,000 this says micrometers and this
should say nanometers right here these
are all
nanometers so
96% absorbed of long wave and we had
emissivity and absorptivity of of
96 okay what happens to the other
0.004 if it's
not absorbed by the leaf and the answer
is it's reflected there was a tiny bit
of longwave radiation that gets
reflected by
surfaces tin
foil
reflects
97% of longwave radiation so for thermal
radiation tin foil is just like a mirror
and if we put a piece of tin foil right
here and I put an infrared gun on it it
wouldn't tell us hardly anything about
the temperature of the tin foil it would
tell us the temperature of the people in
the class because it's reflecting all
the people in here so this is a tiny
number but when we get into rigorous
analysis of energy balance this 4%
matters and in a field it's just
reflected back into space but depending
on the situation it can get reabsorbed
somewhere
so does it do with
it if it's reflected
it so what does it do with the 4% if
it's reflected nothing the 96% it this
96% becomes heat it it's thermal
radiation and it makes the object get
hotter until it reaches a new
equilibrium it it
uh it it's it it's converted to heat
can't utilize it no it can't utilize it
um so it this is a as we said the other
day this is a big reason leaves are warm
but of course the good news is they can
also by radiation get rid of it too but
it's uh it's it's highly absorbed but
not not completely
100%
so this little example here about
emissivity and absorption of of
reflection leads
to the use of some instruments to uh
measure
radiation and the place that I have
found that's the most interesting about
this is in
buildings all buildings built in the
last 10 to 15 years have low E glass and
if you ever dealt with the building
you've heard of low E glass have you
heard of that Boston right so what's low
E glass it's all the rage oh yes we're
putting low E glass that is low
emissivity glass the glass looks like
tin foil for long wave
radiation now exactly the physics of how
they're doing that I'm a little fuzzy on
because we could certainly put tin foil
up and it would be very effective but
this glass right here this is a new
building this has lowy glass I've never
tested it
but here is let to do some research
right right now about the emissivity of
the glass so here's a little cheap
infrared gun and I we got several around
here and I've bought lots of these um
and you can get these things for under
$25 and it it gives you the surface
temperature in either Celsius or
Fahrenheit so um and and they're
remarkably accurate for what they cost
so let's see if I can get this in
Celsius so we understand the number so
let's do a test right here I'm getting
and I can't see this I'm getting 32
Celsius for this uh
glass and that's probably the
temperature of the ceiling up here in
this room um although the glass is
pretty warm because the Sun's shining on
it 3% of the signal if if this was low
that low E this is probably not the same
as tin foil the emissivity might be
let's say it's 10% the temperature I'm
measuring is 10% of the true surface
temperature and 90% of the ceiling so
it's warmer than than the ceiling but
it's certainly not the temperature of
that glass now most of the things in
here are I mean we could do it on I
don't know if this is lowy glass because
it's not an exterior wall but if if we
did it on this you can see this has a
little uh red LED so you can tell where
you're pointing um but if that was cold
and and this was warm it would reflect
and it' tell us the temperature in here
that's the concept of low
E and help me try and attempt to take
this one step farther one thing I know
for sure as soon as anybody learns the
principles of these stuff they want own
a lot of instruments to measure it cuz
then they understand what's going on so
this
is
a thermal imaging camera now these
things are 25 bucks and you can the more
accurate Ones cost few hundred dollars
but this thermal imaging camera these
have come down fast
and, bucks something like that for this
I mean they used to be a lot more than n
so now let's see if we can point now I
don't know if the camera can get this
but we point at this
window and it's telling us the glass is
warmer than the wall but mostly the
glass is it's reflecting the long wave
Off the Wall see your other gun oh yeah
I'm going to help your demo excellent
terrific oh you're going to get
a we're gonna we're going to test some
lowy anyway here you can see me in this
um what parts of me are hotter than
others um these are really useful for
refined measurements of different
temperatures they the absolute accuracy
of these is not the greatest but the
relative accuracy is really impressive
you can see Tiny changes in uh
temperature if I get out of the
way um we can start to see the windows
in this the board's much
cooler
um I could pass this around and you can
look through it a bit I just I just
charged it up so I hopefully it's got
enough charge to last for a little bit
but this if you spend a few minutes with
this pointing it at things it really
drives home the principles of longwave
radiation and the value of using
longwave emissivity to get temperature
of
things so I have one more demonstration
of uh low E glass I went down to
Bennett's
Glass and I said don't you guys have a
demo of this that helps people
understand low E and they got all
excited and they said yeah yeah yeah we
can order
one so this
is for people selling
lowy glass this side right here is
ordinary glass and this side over here
is low E glass and like I
said 15 years ago there was just only
primitive low E glass now I think it's
almost cold I think everyone has to use
low E because it keeps the heat in
you're not going to lose heat by
radiation and it works both ways the
cold radiation outside it doesn't
radiate inside anymore the cold is
reflected on the
outside so now let's start our
experiment got a
light and these little radiometers spin
in proportion to how much radiation is
hitting them
and you can see that the ordinary glass
is making this spin more than the low
eag oh can this see it too yeah yeah
so there's the principle of these are
real cool you put them in the window and
they spin like crazy so let's this
actually works pretty
good this is for people that really just
want to see a demo they don't understand
the physics they just want to see a demo
and the ordinary glass makes that spin
more thank you
so how would you calibrate one of these
you can
take this is called a lesli cube but
it's a cube full of water and a cone
inside painted as black as we can get it
special flat black paint so that
emissivity gets very 99 something for
the emissivity and if it's a cone shaped
the long wave bounces back and forth
sideways so the emissivity gets even
higher because it's a cone shape so my
assistant has filled this with hot
water and now we could put this right
here what are we saying it's I think it
holds
it 80
5050 MH now I want to get
close let's see if we
can what are we getting
there yeah okay now point at the silver
side
yep good so now let's go over
here what do we get
there 31 it's it's emissivity this is a
silver side it's not emitting the heat I
touch it and it feels hot and and they P
they're exactly the same temperature but
because this is Hut emissivity it gives
us a bigger number you can use these in
an instrument you can use these to
determine the field of view because
these all these instruments have a
cone-shaped field of view and you would
like to think that this little red dot
I'm only getting that red dot but it's
in fact averaging this one's probably
averaging a 2 or 3 m squared area up
there CU it's low cost if you want to
get just the Red Dot you got to pay more
for a more precise
instrument
um then you can take these and if I do
this and it's got a high temperature and
I start to move it back away quite
quickly it'll start to see the edges and
it's no longer measuring just that black
cone cuz it's averaging the cone plus
this and the higher some of the higher
quality instruments you can go far away
and it'll still just see the cone but
that's one of the reasons you pay more
for higher end instruments and you can
buy cheap ones like this plus these work
pretty good if the temperatures are all
within 5 C of the instrument but if you
try to measure a hot surface with this
they're just not very accurate so that's
another problem with with radiometers is
they always measure the delta T because
there's always an exchange of radiation
between the instrument and the surface
and it it measures says this is my
temperature that surface is 5 warmer so
it adds the two numbers
together so this
is emissivity on uh uh principles of it
and
and fortunately glass helps you to see
this we we could do all kinds of things
with tin foil in here too showing how it
reflects the radiation like a mirror and
shows the power and the importance of
the
emissivity two simple equations or laws
that relate to radiation that are
important one is Wan's law this is It's
pronounced wans this is a German
guy many years ago he's looking at the
relationship between longwave and
shortwave
radiation and he says as objects get
hotter they radiate at shorter
wavelengths cuz this is showing us a
dichotomy of short and long but wait a
minute isn't there stuff here in the
middle yes there could be so we's law
says now let's let's erase
[Music]
this the maximum wavelength and in this
case this would be this point right here
maximum equals no I'm going to be
simpler it's proportional to one over
temperature real simple inversely
proportional to
temperature so as the temperature of an
object gets hotter it radiates at
shorter and shorter wavelengths so this
is low temperature objects out
here this is the sun right here and the
peak number from the Sun is
550 I'm going to put nanometers or
micrometers that's pretty you could look
at the yellow magnet that's pretty close
to that Peak
wavelength yep thank
you now that I switched to micrometers
0.55 now let's put some numbers in this
and and and solve it and so now after we
get this the concept here now if we do
equal
sign first of all this is temperature in
Kelvin not in Celsius and this is the
maximum wavelength
in
micrometers so now we have units but
it's not one over this this is a
constant and this constant is 28
97 so there's the entire wngs
law roughly
3,000 divided by the temperature and
Kelvin of the object will give us the
peak
wavelength so if the
Sun is radiating at 0.5
micrometers now we're going to do some
math to make this
simple 0.5 micrometers
how hot is the
sun well we'll rearrange we's law
temperature and
Kelvin and I'm going to put
some we're going to round that to
300 and this is 0.5 micromet
rounding the sun is 6,000
Kelvin rounding to make the math easy
and that's pretty hot there we don't
have anything on the earth that's that
hot which is why this short wave is
coming from the sun because it has to be
that hot what if
we put
about the inside of a oven you're going
to bake the
turkey let's let's go
to
uh let's take this
off and now now we're going to say
maximum wavelength 3,000 now we're going
to put temperature in here and you bake
a turkey it's 400 or a pizza at 400
that's roughly 200 Kelvin
so the inside of an oven might be 273
plus a couple hundred 500 Kelvin to make
this math easy
so six
um now I got a mistake in here somewhere
this is coming out to
six micrometers yeah no it's not a
mistake so this is
0.5 and a hot oven is out
here at at uh the these are nanometers
so this is 8 micrometers so hot oven is
over
here 6
micrometers so this is why terrestrial
objects all radiate out in here
depending on their temperature and even
a hot oven doesn't get us to shortwave
radiation it's still longwave these are
all described by we's
law and there's another application of
this
here is
a
graph of doing this for a couple of
temperatures
so here's 5,500 Kelvin and as this gets
cooler it shifts out here to longer
wavelengths not by much but it shifts so
you see two things happening remember
Stefan boltzman equation the total
radiation is determined by the
temperature and as the temperature gets
cooler the area under this curve gets
less and as it gets hotter it becomes
more
blue and the more the hotter the object
the more blue the cooler the object the
more orange and
red so we use Wings law .1% of the
people in the world know this to
determine color temperatures of lights
and all kinds of things we say and film
this is a 4,000 Kelvin film and this
light has is some Kelvin temperature
none of them are smooth curves it's just
an an effective way to say the color
temperature of objects we talk about
color temperature but it's from wngs law
the bigger the number the more blue the
output blue lights have you could say um
cool white for fluorescent which is blue
is might be a 6,000 Kelvin light and a
warm white fluorescent which is more
orange might be a 3,000 Kelvin light and
that all comes from wngs law and there
shift from the maximum wavelength
so when you see those color temperatures
and you think through this and anytime
it's inversely
proportional you have to shift your
thinking a little um hot hot objects are
more blue
Plank's
equation I don't have my picture of
plank here um but he's one of the top 25
scientists of all time um and this
picture he has a tie on and little tiny
glasses and he just makes it look like
he was a very organized guy and he was
he he lived to be 82 years old which is
a real accomplishment in the in the
1800s when he lived so
we
have this refrigerator
magnet which everybody's uh got on their
filing cabinet
now and we're showing this both
in
photons and
energy and the shape of the
curve and the photon flux is all the
physiologists that are modeling and
predicting
photosynthesis and the energy flux is
all the meteorologist that are modeling
temperature and the differences in
temperature they're obviously both
important and they're different
shapes so is there any way to go back
and forth
between Jewels this is per meter squ per
second per nanometer this is me squ per
second nanomer is there any way to go
back and forth between jewels and moles
of
photons and the answer is thanks to Mox
plon and what I do with my black marker
here it
is thanks to MOX plon I'm going to erase
some of this to give give plon lots of
room for his for his
equation another very simple equation
energy per
photon is proportional
to one over the wavelength real similar
to this only this is temperature and
quality of the
light and this is helping us go back
allowing us to go back and forth between
Jewels or watts of energy and
photons so energy drives thermal
reactions and photons drive a whole
another set of reactions like
photosynthesis we know that one Photon
excites one
electron that's that's called the Stark
Einstein
law and that's what causes
photosynthesis that is exactly what
causes electricity in a solar
photovoltaic cell one Photon excites one
electron and we get electricity those
solar voltaic cells aren't running off a
thermal radiation they need shortwave
radiation and we need to count photons
to determine
electricity so we get Plank's equation
inversely proportional to wavelength
now if we change this to
equals this one becomes H and
C and C is the speed of
light H is Plank's
constant and I don't have these two
numbers memorized but it's but they're
big
numbers
and this is Jewels per photon here
um if we put numbers in this and this is
how I remember it cuz it's like a a lot
of things you work it out for one value
and then you can rate forever racial
things to that value but if we
do
HC over
nanometers now this is right in the
middle between 400 and 700 550 is the
average wavelength of light from the sun
it's green light it's average light
right in the middle
this comes out to
be
kles per mole of
photons putting these numbers in I'll
work out a page with the step-by-step
math worked out on this and all the
numbers in it but there's a
relationship so now if you say what
would the energy what would this number
be at 600 well you can easily ratio this
and you get this relationship here
um this so so Plank's equation allows us
to go back and forth between energy and
moles and you can keep going with this
equ like we have here to 800 900 1,000
here's the photon flux these
photons are longer associated with
longer wavelength
they have less
energy I like to think of the UV photons
are really high energy you know if this
was 3155 nanm this thing would be let me
see if we took half of this
275 this would be over 400 Kil 400 KJ
per mole that's ultraviolet light that's
high energy photons which is why
ultraviolet photons are so degrading to
everything they're super high energy
they're just I don't know they're like
third graders they just got a lot of
energy then you get out here to 900 and
it's the people with canes and there's
low energy there's still one person but
they're low energy
so these photons past 700 no longer have
enough energy to excite electrons for
photosynthesis so we don't count them um
and down
here they're too high of energy for
photosynthesis they're they're damaging
there's not that much down here either
so it's got to be just in this right
range
um but it leads to the shapes of these
curves
incidentally solar
photovoltaics are in the
laboratory similar efficiency to
photosynthesis and a good solar voltaics
and now you get up 30 40% efficiency
photosynthesis can be 30 40% too in the
lab and they're both going off of one
Photon excites one
electron one makes carbohydrates and the
other one makes electricity solar panels
can use these photons they they keep
absorbing out to a, even
1100 out here so solar panels can use
some of this longer wave radiation
photosynthesis can't and it's generally
why solar photovoltaics are more
efficient in photosynthesis they can
capture that bar you said something that
so
sunlight majority of sunlight or tends
towards the green Spectrum PL evolve not
using the
most yes though the question is how come
plants are green if there's so much
green light wouldn't they want to
capture that two answers one it's it's
not this is a fairly curve so it's it's
not U that much different green
light but still why don't they absorb
everything why do they have a dip at all
in green
light and they could if they could
capture that green light too they'd be
more efficient so you could say well
chlorophyll just doesn't absorb green
light that molecule well then it's a bad
molecule we should have got something
else and the way I like to think of it
is
animals came along and they eat
plants and our eyes can see green light
better than any other wavelength if we
drew our eyes on here I can put it on
here uh green put around here in black
blue here's our eyes this is a little
thing our eyes look like that we see
green really well we don't see blues and
reds very well so animals of evolved to
be able to see
plants they plants reflected the green
light and the animals that that could
see that green light got found the
plants better and got more food and I
don't know I never heard anyone else say
that but that's a good sounding
hypothesis it's interesting the
wavelengths of light reflected by plants
are the ones that we see the best and
so but you could also ask couldn't we
invent a better molecule for plants that
that captured all this
and now we know there's lots of pigments
in Plants besides chlorophyll if you
look at older plant physiology textbooks
they say well plants don't absorb much
green light look at
chlorophyll in
fact let me answer that let's see let's
put this right here we got this done
with
this here's our 400 to 700 blown up big
if you look at a plant physiology
textbook
chlorophyll looks like that it absorbs
Blues there's chlorophyll A and B but
they're they look like this they absorb
blues and reds but the chlorophyll
hardly absorbs any
green and all the plant physiology text
book said well chlorophyll doesn't
absorb much green so guess what when we
invented efficient LEDs that were blues
and reds a whole bunch of people going
wow these are perfect for plants cuz
they match the absorption of chlorophyll
there were no there still are no
efficient green LEDs the ones green we
have them but they're not efficient at
all so they said the LEDs are perfect
for plants they match the absorption of
chlorophyll and then we found out they
really don't work very well through 10
20 years of work and way how come well
now we know and if you take a modern
plant physiology textbook they have
Curves in here like this and like this
and they're all colors they're I'm out
of colors but you get the idea there's a
whole bunch of Curves in those now and
they say multiple pigments absorb all
the light um there's there's a new
pigment psychoan is discovered in
algae I don't know about discovered it
was clarified in algae just a few years
ago it's its peak absorptions in green
light so there's the potential to
genetically engineered to put more
psychoan in plants and then they will
get that green light they won't look
green anymore I guess they'll look I
don't know black but so it's that's a
long answer to that to an interesting
question how come they don't get
pigments to capture every spec of it and
what I would like to see is pigments so
they could use some of this there's a
lot of energy right in here and if we
could just get pigments to get to 800
wow we could feed the world but we don't
have them they chlorophyll ends at 700
and then nothing yes they would absorb
more heat too but will Precision
irrigate and save water and get more
yield um so there's why do pigments do
what they do how do they evolve um they
interesting questions Damon so is the
limiting factor on plant growth
capturing radi D
photosynthesis so the question is is the
limiting factor absorbing radiation for
yield and then if you got additional
pigments you'd be able to grow more but
I don't know if
that's yes it is the limiting factor if
if if we when you plant in the spring we
got beautiful light it's it's May and
early June there's a lot of light oh 90%
of it's wasted because it hits the
ground and here's the little nice green
plants but the 90% is wasted finally
they fill in and yield takes off um so
there's an example of absorbed radiation
but what we're talking about here is
after it fills in couldn't we get
it I mean here's one answer to to the
question kind of a smartass answer what
do you mean they already absorb 95% and
you're complaining couldn't we get this
to 9 8 and yeah that would be a 3% and
every little bit helps
so
okay I'm going to stop here and we'll
take a
break this is the end of radiation
lectures when we come back
in we will in a few minutes we will talk
about transpiration
all of this is we're going to get
transpiration by
subtraction well can't we just measure
it
directly and the answer is sort
of so let's take a break