clock and welcome everyone back to
lecture number three we're gonna talk
about long wave today and then hopefully
I made an outline here today of the
objective for the next 50 minutes or so
to get the total net radiation before I
start and then so we're somewhere in
here we get these to go I made a small
error and and people say there are no
small errors there there's no small
typos there's their typos yesterday when
I did this we have a thousand N and
fifty percent reflected so so fifty
percent was absorbed so the shortwave in
was five hundred that's correct
this reflection right here is a hundred
and I said irrelevantly you have a
hundred that means six hundred watts are
absorbed but some people correctly said
wait a minute this hundred is also x one
minus the albedo and so this really is
50 and the correct answers 500 not 600
550 thank you this is over here 500 plus
55 50 and
this 50 is quite a bit of energy so it's
not really a small error but it's also
it's important that this is correct
because sometimes this reflection is
huge if you get something on the south
side of a building this reflected energy
can be a lot more than 10% in some cases
in this example it's not so big but it's
depends on the case so we've got this
diagram up here with arrows in and
arrows out and this is a pretty messy
diagram but it's useful to have diagrams
like this because it helps you keep
track of the inputs and the outputs so
some years ago we made this diagram and
I have this as a handout the inputs and
the outputs I need to go up just
slightly to see the whole works there it
is and all this is a nicer diagram of
this I guess the sun's on the right-hand
side now but solar in with this arrow
we've talked about
oops sorry this is sky radiation coming
in here which we didn't talk about yet
here's solar in some bounces off here's
reflected same thing these big fat curvy
lines what want to talk about today long
wave radiation calculating these and
then of course we get outgoing
transpiration conduction convection and
here's some long wave components here
coming into the leaf long wave means the
wavelengths are long and so we draw
those with curvy lines and short wave is
the way with wavelengths are short so we
draw those with straight lines
and then finally here's soil heat flux
when we calculate that so a diagram to
keep the components straight and then
the goal then in a quantitative sense is
put numbers on the arrows and add them
up make sure it balanced
this issue of a diagram is something
that everybody that teaches this makes
some kind of the diagram of their own
and here is part nobles diagram of
exactly the same thing out of this
chapter that we're using it's slightly
different arrows and it's in some ways
these real fat arrows for infrared
radiation kind of overemphasize if you
scaled these to the rough size of their
numbers the biggest arrow in here would
be direct radiation right there coming
into the system that's ultimately what
drives the whole thing but these are
diagrams to help people see this so
here's the one I love so I've read this
stuff every time a new textbooks comes
out I read the chapter on radiation and
I think oh that's a nice diagram and
this explains it a little better and you
know I keep thinking of other ways to
teach it but one of my favorites is the
textbook that we use on campus animal
physiology the third edition so you turn
to chapter 16 animal energetics and
temperature relations and this is not
just metabolism because respirations big
in in animals much bigger than people
but so is all the fluxes of long-wave so
you turn the page to this authors
diagram this I just love this
hippopotamus with exact same arrows
reflected he's got a little tiny bit of
evaporation infrared thermal radiation
so that point that this is everybody's
got their diagram and once you get these
principles you start applying them to
everything a hot tool laid out in the
Sun and now how hot it gets you can even
calculate how fast your laundry will dry
on the clothesline went depending on the
wind speed and solar radiation from this
so where we left off oh I have one more
diagram I want to show you before we get
there couple from the book to link this
to the book here was my picture
yesterday of shortwave and all the
components and then this big clump of
thermal long wave so Park Nobel has that
diagram as well in the book only I like
my diagram a little better than his
because he shows the same thing but he
hasn't on a vlog scale and I'm not a big
fan of vlog scales for teaching because
they they distort things so look at his
infrared radiation by the leaf it looks
like this sharp peak and if this was not
a log scale it looks like this but it's
the same data direct solar and he has
some reflected skylight in here and he
also shows wave number wavelength is
simpler but it's still relative fluxes
and if you look at it long enough it's
the exact same diagram just log scale he
also has
this diagram which was on the bottom of
one of the handouts for this Stefan
Boltzmann equation radiation emitted in
watts per meter squared and surface
temperature an important thing about
this this is a nice big diagram but if
you put a pencil on here and you put a
ruler on here and you put 25 degrees
you're pretty close to 400 watts per
meter squared which is useful to
remember because we're talking about a
thousand here but we're talking about
fluxes of 400 and long-wave so they're
not trivial fluxes at room temperature
so this would all be terrific if we just
calculated temperature we've multiplied
it by this deffend Boltzmann constant
and we could get our long-wave radiation
but in the case of long wave radiation
not everything is a perfect black body
not everything is perfectly black and
radiates of black some shiny objects do
not emit long wave radiation very well
at all so we get an additional symbol in
here it's lowercase t called emissivity
emissivity is 1 for a perfect black body
and the opposite extreme is a piece of
tinfoil the best common thing I can
think of that has a low emissivity and
somewhere right here I have a piece of
tinfoil
to emphasize this point and here it is
and I'm enough now we have two things
that are confusing albedo which refers
to shortwave radiation reflectance of
shortwave and then this thing emissivity
which only refers to long wave radiation
and again long wave is warm objects all
objects that are neither less hot than
the Sun in our environment the only
thing that's any significant source of
shortwave is Sun and then all the
terrestrial objects are all
back-and-forth long wave so I'm going to
put this up here I'm gonna erase this
this is pretty straightforward
you've got it
three objects and I'm my goal is that
ten years from now you'll still remember
this little demonstration and it'll
stick in your head and you'll have it
forever pin foil a aluminum foil where's
my marker albedo
pretty reflective of shortwave radiation
so we might say and it depends on how
perfect the tinfoil is if it's got
crinkles but if it's pretty perfect it's
going to have an albedo of 0.9 then look
this up in a book to see exactly what
people claim for this but it's high now
let's do hell just doing lb toes for a
second
black paper albedo zero point one might
even be blacker net but 0.1 so now we do
white paper and instead of drawing a
square I'm putting actual white paper up
here this white paper and if this was a
test question hundred percent people
would get this right the albedo of this
is about 0.9 plus or minus 0.05 or
something for these okay now let's do
right below this giving ourselves plenty
of room to see it emissivity completely
different concept this is reflected this
is emitted from the surface so this as
the surface gets warm it's the ability
to give off long wave radiation a
blackbody this depending on how black it
is this might be 0.9 for the ability to
give off not white paper what do you
think white paper would be well hardy
can emit right it's the opposite of
black no white paper might be 0.85 maybe
even 0.9 a white surface is a fine
emitter similar to black but now let's
take a shiny surface any kind of
polished metal that shiny the emissivity
of aluminum foil 0.03 that's a clean
piece of aluminum foil shiny surfaces
are poor emitters so what does this mean
for energy balance
if this was hot and again let's imagine
we're on the moon where there's no air
because it simplifies it we put this on
a stove we get it hot we lay it out it
would take forever for this to cool off
by emitted radiation we heat this is a
block of metal now all right so we take
another block of metal that's black heat
it up exactly the same lay it out it
cools off right away
same thing with white they cool off
right away because they can emit that
radiation into space into other objects
on the ground and the moon simplifies it
because there's no transpiration
conduction and convection so this little
diagram helps to emphasize the
differences in emissivity and now we are
going to sacrifice part of this leaf
right here to science because the thing
we're after is leaves and that plant
just gave part of its life for science
typical albedo of a leaf and I'll put
this one in green 0.25 not intuitive
it's in dreams in between black and
white but has a much lower albedo than
white paper wood emissivity of a leaf
not completely intuitive from this but
at the typical value we used for leaf is
0.96 very very high leaves emit it's
effectively emit radiation which also
means they can effectively cool off when
they as soon as they get hot
it's worth putting on here one more
thing let's see can erase this this
water is blue right so now we're gonna
put mm a blue square right it's it's
full of water
all blue water has an emissivity of
about 0.9 six maybe even 0.98 it's and
this is why biological objects that are
full of water like our skin have very
high emissivity that things that are
hydrated and wet effectively emit long
wave radiation the albedo of water
depends up a lot on sun angle if it's
low Sun angle you get glare and a lot of
reflectance so and it it depends on how
clear the water is I'm not going to put
a number in here for albedo but the
point is water is a really effective
emitter of long wave so there's the
concept of emissivity and one of the
things that I think of when I'm thinking
about this is where for designing wood
stoves to heat the cabin somewhere we
would not want to build the wood stove
out of aluminum foil and be terrible it
had sit there and get hot and if you
walked into the room and tried to find
that wood stove you wouldn't tell where
it is but wood stoves are black and
they're effective emitters so as soon as
a wood stove it's hot it's giving off
its heat to the room so you would think
there's a lot of things in between here
between these two for emissivity and
there are but not as many as you might
think all polished metals have low
emissivity but most building materials
bricks white walls
stucco walls are all up in a higher
emissivity the only things that are
really low are shiny objects but they're
a nice example because they're really
low so why don't we just with G we you
just told us we can ignore
photosynthesis
why don't we round this off to one
significant digit and just call it one
yes we would if this was radiation
physics 101 but this is radiation
physics 501 and this number matters it's
multiplied by hundreds of watts per
meter squared so small changes in this
multiplier make a big difference for for
energy balance and it's worth putting
those numbers in by the way
snow is like this good emitter of long
wave and reflex short wave I've never
actually taught this with the live leaf
taped on the board before but in but it
helps drill de that concept so now that
we have this we can start to assemble
our energy balance model with all the
components of long wave radiation in
addition to shortwave because we just
ran our model and that
[Music]
we'll erase some of this and we will say
in red radiation shortwave , absorbed is
550 now we'd like to do radiation long
wave incident first incident on the leaf
how much is coming in this vine is
incident on the leaf how much long wave
is coming in there's two sources of our
long wave particularly since our leaf is
a flat leaf above the ground a nice
simple example there's our flat leaf
right here and I'm gonna even take that
part off so we have ground shown in
black long wait coming up to the leaf
from the ground so let's say the ground
now I've the handout that assimilates
these in the giving them and it want to
follow the same numbers
we have to assume a ground temperature
measure it or assume it and in this case
I assumed 27 degrees C for the ground so
now we plug that number in and if I'm
lucky I can find my chart of long-wave
chart from yesterday where'd that go
anybody have that handy that's the table
of yeah you can you can look it up but I
want everybody to thanks follow along
here we go the grounds 27 460 but so 464
this part right here 460 P to the fourth
Kelvin but we have to soon measure or
assume an emissivity of the ground then
we're gonna take mmm I don't have a lot
of room but you can see it here times
0.9 for the emissivity of the ground so
that radiation going up is 414 these all
these units are in watts per meter
squared so that leaf is absorbing or is
getting 4 and 14 from the ground now
it's a horizontal leaf so it's also
getting radiation from the sky so you
would think the sky temperature on the
warm day Mike the air temperature might
be 27 degrees C and you would think well
if not the same as the ground then if
the air molecules are 27 we could do the
same thing and be 414 here correct the
question is there is how much long wave
is from the Sun and the if the answer is
no if you take a Radiometer good
radiometer and point it right at the Sun
you get the same temperature is that
open sky yeah none it's just amazing and
you know it's so counterintuitive you
almost have to walk out with the
instrument so that's baloney I don't
believe that and they pointed at the Sun
so after class take an instrument and go
through that test and convince yourself
it's just it's just amazing all that Sun
is shortwave so but that's the shortwave
is
. in the sky and the whole rest of the
sky is emitting but even though the air
molecules might be 27 degree c radiation
the atmosphere is pretty transparent to
long-wave and if it was perfectly
transparent like say on the moon it
would be zero outer space is zero kelvin
that'd be zero but we don't get zero we
make careful measurements of this and we
get cold sky temperatures somewhere in
between room temperature and zero and we
call that the effective sky temperature
and it it depends somewhat on elevation
so it's colder skies and high elevation
because there's less air it depends on
relative humidity a bit because the
water vapor molecules affect it but
typically from a sky we'll get three
hundred watts per meter squared now
that's a clear sky so did we use this to
get the clear sky whale what's the
effect of emissivity of the air what's
the effect of temperature both of these
interact to give us this number so this
is generally a measured number it
doesn't depend on air temperature it
just depends on how clear the sky is
clouds let's take a case with clouds I'm
going to get rid of this zero clear sky
which is what we're doing this model for
right now and clear sky now we go over
here
[Music]
clouds and it doesn't have to be a black
thundercloud it can be a perfectly white
nice cloud in the sky
now we go out with our instruments and
pointed at the cloud
clouds are relatively close to the earth
they're full of water vapor so now we
are in fact reading the temperature of
the water vapor molecules in the cloud
and pretty often a cloud can it will
jump up to oh maybe four hundred watts
per meter squared because it's close to
the ground and the molecules in the
cloud are warm and we no longer see the
infinity of space so and if it's a real
heavy cloud this can get all the way up
to over 400 for a cloudy so there's a
big difference between cloudy skies and
sunny skies for long wave radiation so
everything else we do from the
emissivity of the surface and the
temperature but clouds and sky
temperature we just measure them now
2-pin measured many times and so we we
know approximately what they are so
let's start adding up these numbers now
for radiation and we get 550 absorbed
now this is oh let's see
414 plus 300 would be 714 watts per
meter squared radiation but there's one
other calculation 0.96 is the emissivity
of a surface but this is an important
thing I'm I'm going to put it right here
emissivity equals absorptivity
RP e equals 8 this means that if a
surface is 0.96 for emitting radiation
it's also 0.96 for absorbing that same
radiation
so if 714 is coming in let's put this
right over here 714 in we have to
multiply that by 0.96 for the leaf for
the absorptivity of the leaf and that
comes out to 685 and that number is the
energy absorbed by the leaf in long-wave
this is radiation long-wave absorbed it
in this example with now we som that 685
with 550 here our long-wave absorbed 685
so the staggering message is wow there
is more long-wave absorbed by that leaf
than shortwave the Sun is hot you go
outside and you think wow this is it how
can this be this is hot now what's the
sum twelve thank you
twelve thirty five so maybe in radiation
101 you would say wow they have to
evaporate enough water to get rid of
this energy but long wave works both
ways all this long wave is coming into
this leaf from the ground but wait a
minute
what's the leaf temperature and I
assumed a leaf temperature of 25 °c
now how much is leaving that leaf by
long-wave and we look up on our chart 25
448 I'm gonna let's see I'm gonna put
this over here here's a leaf 25 for 48
times 0.96
right so that's a little less than that
for 30 for 30
so you say well good we can subtract for
30 from this and the leaf doesn't have
to evaporate so much water but it gets
even better than this radiation doesn't
just go down radiation can go up to from
the leaf both up and down so the
downside is 4:30 and the up is also 4:30
so radiation long wave emitted is 860
watts per meter squared so then erase
some older stuff here
so we start to do a sum of this and we
have radiation absorbed total radiation
absorbed
12:35 radiation emitted 860 so and this
is out so we subtract it 300 Thank You
375 watts per meter squared and that's
the final answer no other add-ons this
is how much water that leaf has to
evaporate to stay at air temperature so
big numbers coming in because this is
shortwave and long wave but big numbers
going out too and if you think about
this this energy balance right here
between the leaf and the ground if
ground and the leaf might be close to
the same temperature so this is always
fairly tiny the net between the ground
but the sky is colder than the ground if
it's clear so we can lose energy by
long-lived radiation to the sky and that
helps on a clear day it helps keep leave
school because they're emitting to the
clear sky so these are the components
and what we calculated was but we didn't
explicitly do net long wave but we could
have
here's 685 N and 860 out for long wave
and so the net long wave is a negative
number and it is always a negative
number if the sky is clear we're losing
more long wave we're losing heat by long
wave so having worked through this
step-by-step using the same inputs as
this here's a worked out example and
thankfully with your help getting done
the math we got the same number as the
worked out example so it means either we
had corresponding errors or everything's
correct but this is these are the inputs
and outputs that you always use to
determine radiation balance for a any
object leaf and these numbers are all
big the stuff coming in and going out is
big
you would think maybe we would like to
have leaves kind of like tinfoil why
didn't they evolve like this well they
can't get rid of their once they get hot
they can't get rid of the heat that
would not be so good because they're
shiny it's better to have leaves
something like this and there they're
not absorbing the heat in the first
place
and then they're emitting long wave to
stay cool so there's a I'm thinking
about this and teaching it over the
years and I'm thinking about how do you
give examples to drive home the power of
long wave radiation and i'ma give you
I'm gonna let's see I'm gonna take these
down to there's more room up here what
if well here's that this is a well-known
thing from Boy Scouts if it's a cold
clear night in the mountains go sleep
under a tree you'll be warmer and the
Boy Scouts are coming you know but if
you went out there and did the net
radiation the tree is way warmer than
sleeping outside under the clear sky
because of the radiation I don't have
one with me bred it but I did it would
be a great example a space blanket you
know how can they nope yeah there's spin
while they help you ee because they're
shiny on both sides so your body heat
gets reflected back in and this does not
emit to the outside that's why space
blankets are so effective it's nothing
to do with conduction and convection
it's all radiation physics keeping the
warm temperature in people say yeah yeah
you know my grandmother always says put
the dull side out and potatoes in the
oven you can read on
we'll argue about that stuff online it
turns out it just doesn't matter the
dull side is really close to the outside
and you know they're they're both low
emissivity sides so if this is the case
why do you wrap potatoes in aluminum
foil because geez
I mean the radiation from the oven is
not contributing to heating up the
potato to keep the moisture in for the
potatoes this is very effective to keep
the moisture in even though it makes the
potatoes cook more slowly but that's all
radiation physics in the kitchen and it
can go on and on about all the cool
examples in a kitchen of cooking food
and radiation physics how fast is my
food going to cook in an oven what's the
walls of the temperature of the oven
there's no shortwave in an oven it's all
radiation physics and it's helped now
with convection ovens return a fan on so
we get some convection in there but
here's an example that drives home the
power of long wave radiation and I'll
draw a diagram of this and then you can
tell me what you think is going to
happen we're gonna build
a box or a cylinder and we'll make it
out of styrofoam something that's a very
effective insulator and yeah a couple
feet tall and in the bottom of this
we're gonna put a bowl with water in it
thin layer of water and by the way the
bowls painted flat black it's a surface
of the bowls playing flat black water in
it now we take this outside it's a
simple device take this outside like
tonight it's hot and but if my the
temperature might get down to 28 25 see
tonight we take it outside under a clear
sky and it's calm winds what's going to
happen to the temperature that water
the room temperature when brought it
outside
it's going to radiate to the infinity of
space and the whole inside of this is
going to radiate to the infinity of
space and it will get colder and colder
and conduction and convection can't
can't warm it back up because we have a
big insulated cylinder and if it's windy
we could put a piece of cellophane on
there real thin cellophane transmits
long wave but if it works good even
without this so now it gets colder and
colder and it's radiations coming in
from the sky right but it's a clear
night and the sky temperature
I put 300 as an average but around here
and I've got some examples of this this
sky temperature can be more like mmm I
don't know if I've seen 200 but 250
watts per meter squared mark do membered
low numbers from sky there it's so let's
let's say 250 for summer now radiation
entered we have to follow the thirst
first law of thermodynamics so energy in
equals energy out so this keeps going
until these two arrows are exactly the
same size and if 250 is coming in 250
has to be going out what's the
temperature of the water on a hot summer
night and Logan if 250 is the emitted
radiation
ooh I got put mine back to our table the
water freezes it easily freezes and this
is so counterintuitive it would freeze
even if the sky was three hundred it had
get below zero and the water would
freeze that is the power of long wave
radiation so this is so cool after I
thought of this I had to go do it and
this is my house my backyard patio we'll
Gazoo min on this we can get this really
big in here and I got some blue
styrofoam I did it once and it didn't
get super cold and I kept doing it and I
got bigger layers and I made this longer
you can see a fine net radiometer right
up here so I can see how this is coming
along and you can tell this is a long
time ago because this is like an old
8088 computer and this is my daughter
who is now 26 years old and little pump
to inflate the domes and that thing and
right in here is a Campbell scientific
data logger with thermocouples in the
water and thermocouples all over and I'm
watching a very primitive graph of the
temperature in this thing and my wife
came out and took a picture and it
wasn't dark yet it was you know the Sun
was just setting I never got that water
to freeze but I got it to like one
degree see it was pretty cold that's
that's radiation physics and in fact
this is such a powerful principle the
reason I thought of it is because people
make refrigerators in the tropics just
like this and they open them at night
and they have blocks of water in here
and if they get cool in the day and
they're cool at night and then they
close them in the day and you can keep
food cold just by radiational cooling in
fact you could run this in the days if
you kept pointing it away from the
sunlight because the
sky is clear in the night and the day I
have a couple of other examples of this
and since this particular audience is
instrument intensive now we'll show some
actual data and I guess oome out just a
bit there we go
this is some data I gave this is a test
question to students after I talked
about this principles
this is last winter January 1 11 January
11th it's one week to January 17th this
is on campus net radiation and first of
all its measured albedo because we have
radiation and radiation out so what you
need to know here is on these days the
snow had melted off and it was basically
grass mostly dead grasses January but it
wasn't snow so what did we say the
albedo of grass was maybe 0.25
hard to see on this scale but there's
about 0.25 for these days here then we
had these are night by the way in here
that's just zero zero and zero out then
we had this big spike that went to two
and if you weren't an instrumentation
person you're going to go Wow two times
as much shortwave radiation leaving as
coming in
so what could have caused that this this
giant spike right here now if you're
living in the area you would remember
what the weather was like but here is
why that thing spiked up this is peter
sinks at the same time and there's a
bunch of snow this is a Huck's a flux
net radiometer shortwave in long-wave
out guess what the shortwave in it's
blocked so of course it goes to two
because is it that bottom one is not
blocked so we get issues like this and
you just have to understand the things
that may give you a bad data and filter
them out of the data set so but that the
can I wish if eyes a little more
organized I'd show you the exact picture
of the campus station at the same time
because it happens every time it snow so
you get stuff in here for that reason we
put heaters in sensors whenever we can
two heaters are expensive so it's hard
to run them off a solar power and then
when it snows you get snow in your solar
panel and stuff but here is it one
little silicon pyrometer with the heater
that kept reading correctly during that
snowstorm so if we would have had two of
these in that system we would not have
had this artifact right here this L
Beatle of two but okay right here the
snow melted and it's a little not
completely melted now look at the albedo
of this surface no snow snows ha point
eight so the snow we did what it showed
this reflected shortwave radiation and
then we got some I think we got more
snow and but it but it better jump from
is a nice example of no snow and snow on
the ground here's some numbers for
incoming long wave so so mark said we
can get down to 200 in the winter well
there we go that was a very clear sky
the long-wave was 200 watts per meter
squared here's a cloudy sky and we're up
around 320 and when it gets whenever it
gets clear this guy gets cold outgoing
long-wave is just based on the
temperature of the ground and that's
this Purple Line and you can tell the
temperature of the ground because the
outgoing long-wave was 280 to 300 which
is right just slightly below zero the
surface of the snow up there was was
probably -3 degrees so this these graphs
are on the internet and I'm going to put
the location right here because as soon
as you know the principles you can watch
these graphs and say yeah that's why
this is working there at weather dot USU
dot e-d-u this is a whole series of
graphs of all these principles there's
many more but this is one of them
and I use these all the time as test
questions they say hey was the weather
last week here's what was going on
explain this graph why did this go up
why did this go down and you've got to
look at ratios of different graphs to
see what's going on but it's really
helpful that drive these this all this
radiation physics into your head to see
examples of it
[Music]
yeah this is the same same time period
it's a different graph but ground
temperature equivalent sky temperature
that's what we call it the sky
temperature up here is if the equivalent
of minus 22 C it's the combination of
effective emissivity in sky temperature
and we call that equivalent sky
temperature and then net is just the
difference and of course whenever the
net is a really low number that means
it's a clear sky and look at this zero
cloudy skies lots of clouds in this
period the net radiation was zero the
clouds were just as warm as the cold
surface and in the winter there in the
in in the heavy clouds
now let me here I don't have a handout
of this but I'm always looking for
teaching examples here is can move this
up a little a picture here to be to be
right I'm gonna I put that part off
there's a picture of the stone it's a
little bit Glary but this is all snow
this is in the middle of winter I'm not
this I'd like to tell you this was up
Logan Canyon but it wasn't a dark rock
and look at the melting of the snow
here's the shadow of the rock it's a
bright day here's the melting of the
snow now right around the rock what made
that snow melt reflected shortwave oh
wait a minute the rock is really dark
there's hardly any reflected shortwave
every day that rock absorbed the
shortwave like crazy and got warm above
the air temperature and all night long
is emitting long wave radiation and
melting the snow so this is long wave
radiation melting the snow from a warm
Rock not reflected shortwave radiation
that's what then I put that down here
long wave radiation emitted from a stone
and you can see it's it's not super warm
it's probably melting this a few
millimeters every day until it snows
again but it's warm enough to melt the
snow by the long-wave because net
radiation is such a big factor in
everything with energy balance and and
and because by the way now we have
simplified all this stuff feeds it into
one thing
and we'll put it up here it's just good
now our whole equation goes to our net
and this is absorbed equals T plus C
squared all those components that feed
into this give us one number and sort of
put numbers on this 375 equals T plus
the sum of T plus C squared so once this
is a tough number to get at because of
all the factors we talked about but once
we get it wow there's only two
components that can go into this so this
is the theory but not surprisingly
companies have built instruments to
measure this number to make this easy
and to help people understand those
instruments we made another refrigerator
maintenance and you can put it on your
filing cabinet and look at it and every
time things seem a little goofy and this
has got two sides I think this is I can
zoom in a hair two sides summer and
winter and it's great because these
fluxes are so different and it's got
shortwave and long ways all these
principles we've been talked about for
two days are all right here thousand in
now two hundred out so the albedo is
point two in this example nice round
number the net for this is 800 because
sums reflected here's long wave for 50
so this is roughly what would 450 be 24
C or something right around there sky
300 net minus 150 so net and net 650
watts per meters
weird for a fully vegetated surface so
in this case this is not a single leaf
we do not have transmitted radiation to
the ground because it's fully all those
leaf layers are all absorbing it we also
don't have two sides to radiate
radiation here it was radiating down but
here the ground and the leaves are the
same so we gotta get rid of 450 watts
per meter squared in the summer winter
much lower input you can see the Sun
anatomically-correct Sun sank in the sky
a little bit 400 in snow 350 out now the
Nets only 50 in the winter no wonder
it's cold in the winter long wave the
snow is cold so only 300 and a little
bit less long way from the sky net 50
our net plus 50 net minus 50 zero so
it's not warming up on days like this in
the winter largely because of the snow
cover then we finally get some warm air
to help melt the snow and then the hole
warming starts but this little
refrigerator magnet helps to understand
the magnitudes of the fluxes in in two
very different conditions so it's been
helpful
I'm gonna stop here and pick this up
tomorrow
when I think at this point the next
thing I want to do is apply this to the
whole planet Earth for energy balance on
the earth because we're an independent
or system orbiting through the vacuum of
space we are not losing heat by
conduction and convection the earth
isn't we're not losing or gaining heat
by transpiration the water we have stays
in the earth all we have is radiation
physics to the rest of the rest of the
universe so if that doesn't balance if
if this whole thing if our if net
radiation is a zero point zero zero for
the earth we're either going to cool off
or warm up so now that you have these
principles in place and how we can take
and look at the fluxes for the whole
earth and this in a nutshell is the
essence of global warming and I think I
can explain to you why that's complex
we're the smartest people in the world
are doing gold forming right now to try
and see is this number really zero you
know and how how far off of zero is it
and that's all radiation physics so I'll
stop here no that's not noise that's the
subject of many PhD theses it is and
yeah well you got to start with one
thing that we understand really well and
then you say okay here's that leaf now
we're going to tilt it and now what
happens so the first thing that happens
is multiple tilted leaves don't reflect
quite as much and and as we just said
here they the transmission of the ground
is much less but it doesn't affect it as
much as you might think because you
still have reflected shortwave and the
long wave is just from the surfaces it
doesn't matter that they're all vertical
surfaces and it's going like this
eventually it goes up so one flat leaf
has the same effective radiation as a
hundred vertical leaves as long as
they're covering the ground
that orientation doesn't matter for the
emission of long-wave same thing for
absorption it comes in the biggest thing
with tilting leaves is reflections of
shortwave where we're at bounces and
captures that better like it's any rough
surface would absorb better than a
smooth polished surface in fact that's
part of the reason that polished metal
is so such a low emissivity when
polished metal oxidizes my copper it
goes green all of a sudden polish copper
is 0.03 it oxidizes and goes green and
now it's 0.9 because that surface is
rough and it's so it's a similar thing
to leaves that it's the structure of the
surface affects the reflection of
shortwave
just part of it also
with with vertical leaves it yeah okay
let me add to this answered let me add
to this answer we said a thousand watts
per meter squared for this I actually
had never thought of this before that
only happens the fifth leaf is
perpendicular to the Sun and the Sun is
only perpendicular to the ground at the
equator at the right time of the year so
I probably should do this example with a
flat leaf in an angle because it
wouldn't be a thousand it'd be flattened
if it was really close to the Sun it'd
be a lot less so yes that angle
definitely matters being mean
perpendicular to the light source
thank you that's correct we yeah that's
right it and and this brings us to an
instrumentation tidbit that is not well
understood by people let me go right
here
when we build or use instruments here's
an instrument and here's up some white
discs up here I mean they're various
shapes of curved domes but we say these
are cosine corrected and everybody says
okay cosine corrected that's good what
does that mean it means that if you put
a reference light here you would get
let's say we did this and we got a
thousand watts per meter squared now we
took that same light and we put it at
some low angle if this sensor still
reads a thousand it's not cosine
corrected it has to read less by the
cosine of this angle so at a low angle
the correct number might be say a
hundred the correct number now if it
reads 200 it's not cosine corrected if
it reads 50 it's also not cosine
corrected has to be the right ratio of
tilted radiation so if we make a graph
of this there's one of these graphs on
the apogee website have to think this
goes like this and I think this graph is
let me see nope this is this is
radiation here and this is angle so
right here is 90 degrees and that sensor
should read zero because everything's
missing it and here's zero degrees and
and this might be a hundred or a
thousand depending on the units so this
is a theoretically perfect cosine
response that says at each lower angle
that reading of the instrument should
reach somewhat less and I used to think
many years ago that all the instruments
went like that and they were wrong
because they didn't capture the low
angle right and now we know it's this is
easy to make a sensor that goes like
that it's you can get too much low angle
light you can undo it
or overdo it and any instrument has to
have the right optics to follow this
line as closely as possible that the
theoretically perfect cosine not too low
not too high we calibrate our
instruments right here and then we hope
all those angles are correct and once
you get it right for an instrument it's
it's reproducible this in the summer
most of the sunlight is in this range
here it's in high angles and it's not
too hard to get an instrument to follow
this at these angles it gets really hard
to get the instrument to keep following
it right to zero and in fact none of our
instruments get this perfect the highest
end Kippen zone and instruments aren't
perfect none of them are but they get
close they they start to deviate right
down here from perfect and this isn't
too critical because this is low angle
light it's there just in you might be
off by
five percent but it's five percent of a
small number and over here you better be
right on because it's it's a big number
so this is this is cosine correction and
I think this speaks to your example of
angles in here and what happens when you
tilt things what what how does it change
it but our instruments measure it's by
definition what would the radiation be
on a flat surface and if you want to
calculate the radiation on a tilted
source you can you little trigonometry
in like like Mark just pointed out and
if you tilt that it goes above the
thousand but it's that's that's one way
to explain the effect of tilted surfaces
and this is for an instrument but you
can also use this for any surface but
what would it be tilted toward the Sun
if you made your measurement flat you
could predict them the increase in
radiation from tilting it
that's a good question yes yes there yes
really good question and the answer is
yes and now let me answer that question
I got a race and give myself a tiny bit
more room in a beef in particular here's
our leaf now we're going to bring in a
way giant microscope and leaves are half
air and this marker green marker yeah
it's good enough you get this is some
beginning plant physiology and then you
get stole mates in here like this and
every plant biology book has a diagram
like this there's full air and these
aren't as probably as quite as dense as
I drew them they're not they're not
touching now we have light coming right
through and it bounces around and it
bounces out and now we have light coming
at an angle and it bounces a lot more
and the transmission of light coming at
and angles way less the reflection is
more because it's a low angle but the
transmission is less so we study
penetration of light into leaves at
different angles and it the lower the
light the less the transmission so one
part of this goes down and another part
goes up which is partly why we get away
with saying point five because it's
there's some offsetting changes than
this but in general the transmission at
low angles goes down faster than this
goes up
in fact when we get to hole canopies you
can imagine how much math you can do to
try and analyze this with all the angles
and people have worked on that but
another way is just to put a net
radiometer out there and just measure it
and say the sum of all these is this and
that's there's a theoretical treatment
and then there's the measurements and if
your instruments good you're going to
nail these these fluxes on this this is
a great example of why net radiation is
so valuable but net radiometers are more
expensive instruments so few people use
them and when they don't use them
they're trying to model these fluxes all
of them and it can measure this big one
and then you try to model the rest and
some years ago Rick Allen who was now he
was here at the University for many
years now he's at Kimberly Idaho but he
broke part of a book chapter and after
testing at the time a bunch of
instruments from net radiation
he said these instruments have
sufficient problems that it's more
accurate to model the net radiation
fluxes than it is to measure them that's
a sentence in that it's a chapter in a
book I think it's FAO 56 since then
Blanc West at all
did a big study with the bunch of net
radiometers and as I recall nearly all
of the net radiometers were more
accurate than the models the only ones
that weren't were the very cheapest
models all even even the cheapest net
radiometers so that's the evolution of
instruments they're they're better and
cheaper and then yeah you can see if you
can get this number right with an
instrument wow you're really you're
getting there because now you just got a
couple other components but in my
experience if a user just puts the
instrument out there without any
understanding of all this stuff they
have no idea when they're klett
getting bad data and if you understand
the stuff you can look up these lines
and say this can't be right
right here and we'd better go check the
instrument and that's worth a lot to
have that background you you would think
they would have a huge effect on this if
you asked the to false the population
you know the ever and so what does they
have a huge effect on it if you go out
with our radiometers and measure this
there's hazy right so this is going to
be less wait a minute those inversions
are 1 to 300 meters thick when you look
sideways at the mountains you can see
the haze now go out an inversion and
look up and tell me if you can see the
haze it's not deep enough you can't that
sky looks fine you have to be looking
through an air mass of several two or
three or four to see the haze so this
incoming shortwave is actually hard to
measure during I mean hard to hard could
tell that there's an inversion based on
attenuation of shortwave we could if we
had 100 4 or 500 meters up and one at
the ground we could we could see it but
it's it's it's hard to see but this
tells you why we get cold inversions
snow on the ground and we can't heat the
ground up because there's snow on the
ground
yeah some because there's crap in the
air but here's an example so we all we
keep study in the website PM 2.5 and we
say wow this is a terrible day it's up
to 50 what are the units on that well
micrograms per cubic meter Wow
a microgram I mean a paperclip does a
gram and so this is a millionth of a
paperclip per meter it's the amount the
weight of the particles is tiny and even
though they're bad for our lungs there's
no doubt about that the optical effects
are smaller than you might think
so these fluxes don't change much from
those they change more with humidity
humidity can be 3 4 % of the well in the
winter it might be 1 or 2 percent but
humidity is many orders of magnitude
greater than the PM 2.5 and small
changes in humidity would have a bigger
effect than big changes in the
particulate matter but those are
examples of this stuff that you know how
would this apply to different things
okay
tomorrow we'll model planet Earth ah
I've promised a key for a equals MC
squared which I already showed you but
here it is and
that's it that's a good example of a
question where you can't rely on your
intuition to get the answer you have to
follow the rules and and get it
Megan taped this back