start this is day two of approximately
an eighth series lectures of the energy
balance principles and I want to review
today a little bit of where we got
yesterday just very quickly and that's
why I did not erase the board because we
can put it up here but the key take-home
message from yesterday is we're
measuring radiation and then through
this latent heat of evaporation we can
calculate how much water would have to
evaporate to balance this and we go to a
volume of water and then multiplied by
area depth of water which the depth of
water is typically the irrigation that
we tell people to put on how many
millimeters a day or how many inches a
day should you be putting on to balance
this equation so the key point we got to
is if we measure 30 mega joules a day
which yesterday we got 30 mega joules
today we're going to get 30 mega joules
it's a clear day it's summer if all of
that was absorbed we would have to
evaporate 12 liters of water per meter
squared every day 12 liters of water and
I always think about a meter squared
this tabletop is probably not it's close
to a meter squared but that is a lot of
water and it's worth remembering because
of these volume and depth things twelves
liters of water is one point two
centimeters of water per day than the
meters squared the depth cancels so it's
possible to get conditions where you
have to evaporate 1.2 centimeters of
water a day to balance this but this is
an extraordinary amount of water we as
we pointed out the other day we get more
like half of this so now we have a case
where something's wrong the typical
measured evaporation is only half of
what we calculated so either that model
is wrong or the measurements are wrong
and like all science when we start out
with this we don't know which one's
wrong so we go back and look at the
measurements we'll go back and look at
the model and in this case the model is
not sufficiently detailed to calculate
absorb radiation I did it purposely did
a very simple model yesterday and assume
if 30 comes in every speck of that is
absorbed and evaporates water and that
never happens not we never get a hundred
percent absorption so I want to start by
dividing this up now before I talk about
that yesterday we talked about Einsteins
P and how much energy you get from this
thing I don't think I made copies of
this but I will and you can have them
here's the math of this the key for this
thing and zoom out just a little bit
and the answer depending on exactly how
big you assumed that p is is 6,000 years
so in perfect SI units it's more like
six killer years using the right prefix
it's a good chance you're going to die
from something else before you run out
of energy and that p and it's it's a
pretty simple calculation and here's the
dimensional analysis of it showing
energy kilograms per meter second
squared times a meter is a jewel and a
Joule is a Newton per meter so when you
work through this you get a good sense
of these the units for energy and I'll
give you a copy of this this is a good
time to point out one of the reasons for
using SI units when students do this
calculation in class they frequently get
it wrong by a factor of a thousand
where's that where's the air where's the
air it's wrong by a factor of a thousand
it's hard to tell because you might you
might at such a long time anyway the
place that people make the error and now
I need to create a little bit of room
here it's I'm going to blame this on the
nutrition and food science people
because they got it they've got it all
screwed up what are they used for energy
how many calories should you eat per day
that's you should eat so many calories
per day they capitalize the word
calories and they say when it's
capitalized it means a thousand calories
that's nobody else does that you don't
capitalize words and multiply by a
thousand except they do and so a calorie
spelled with the capital C is equal to a
thousand calories spelled with a
lowercase C and that trips people up all
the time in this so we need 2400
kilocalories a day then if we should we
should get rid of this capitalized C but
this is a big problem it's on cereal
boxes and it's everywhere and you just
got to know that when you capitalize
that word it's thousand times worth a
thousand times more interestingly enough
when you do this math our energy
requirements 4.18 kilojoules per
kilowatt
we need about 10 mega joules a day for
energy for a typical person I just
that's an easy number to remember 10
mega joules and now you could start to
think about everything in mega joules
and stuff start stuff line up
so I'll give you a copy of this it's
system it's just a helpful introduction
to units and I also want to say one
other introductory thing I didn't
mention this yesterday but at the
University we have a requirement for
competency in writing for graduate
students and American students don't
have a problem with near-native fluency
but foreign students we ask them to
write an essay about something to show
that they have good command of English
they take this TOEFL test and other
things but this was an essay which I'm
gonna hand out you could take a copy of
it's a short essay it was written by a
woman from China and I was on her
committee I thought this is one of the
best written essays that I'd ever seen
by a by a foreign student and it's about
as you can see differences in the
educational system between the United
States and China and she talks about her
experiences in China where memorization
is prized if you can recite things and
memorize them
you're just promoted you're a genius
minimal effort to apply the knowledge in
creative ways and she said I was amazed
here if people gave me a page of notes
for exams I didn't have to memorize I
just had to learn how to apply the
information so that we aspire to help
people understand how to apply the
information rather than memorizing it
because you can look stuff up in a book
and memorization is not a goal of our of
our education except in some cases where
I guess in the third and fourth grade
don't memorize edition tables and I
don't know if you memorize those or
figure them out but kids kids have to
pass multiplication tables and
but beyond that we're always looking at
how to apply stuff so this is a it's a
nice essay it's shortened and I was I
was really touched by it and it's it's
part of the reason the world comes to
the United States to study because of
our approach to education trying to
apply the principles rather than just
memorizing the principles so
now let's get back to this radiation and
now I can start to erase the stuff from
yesterday we're gonna keep
so speaking of memorization this is a
good number you can have it on a card in
your pocket or something but this is a
good number to remember because you it's
quickly energy and volume of water and
go back and forth between those units
and it's worth mentioning let's see I'm
gonna keep going here
we don't always use leaders but of
course 2.45 kilojoules per milliliter
dividing numerator and denominator by a
thousand so once you get it one memorize
you can quickly switch and of course a
millimeter is a is a gram of water it's
a cubic centimeter of water so that's
just switching units quickly back and
forth and I've been my experience I've
found it useful I'm using this number so
much I can flip the units in my head
pretty fast to fit the question that's
being asked what volume water is
evaporated alright we get calories
figured out we're gonna leave our leaf
right there everyone's committed this to
memory now we get we got our units
conversion before I get into separating
this I thought of working this out be in
as a quantitative example of what how do
we calculate this 5% and I drew this and
I got an example for him and give you a
handout on this because everything is
quantitative and calculated here's the
energy in here's photosynthesis
abbreviated 0 0 and
my example goes up to full sunlight
thousand watts per meter squared and we
do our curve on here look something like
this
now we clamp on a leaf with a
photosynthesis system it's a I call them
clamp on chambers and you can measure
quickly measure the photosynthesis of
the leaf so we get points in this curve
what do we get out here
what's the photosynthesis and a typical
rate is 30 and this has units of micro
moles of carbon per meter squared per
second of leaf so down here we have a
thousand joules per meter squared per
second same thing so the meter squared
per second perfectly lines up now we can
calculate efficiency of photosynthesis
with appropriate units conversion in
this energy and energy out so efficiency
is output over input real simple we've
just got to get these in the same units
so we can make this calculation so if we
have let's go over here output out in
thousand watt I'm gonna skip right to
thousand joules per meter squared per
second 30 micro moles of what we measure
is co2
disappearing per meter squared per
second under a big line so obviously our
meter squirts and our seconds are gone
and the output is moles of co2 that have
gone into the leaf and the input is
joules of energy we can't do an
efficiency yet we've got to get this in
units of energy so from our equation
which I wrote up here co2 I'm gonna skip
here becomes C h2o
I'll put that put all of it up here
water plus oxygen this is elegant
because one mole of CO 2 becomes 1 mole
of carbohydrate over here so we're
measuring the uptake of co2 but we know
there's a one-to-one relationship with
moles of carbon that disappear and moles
of carbon that are fixed in sugar in the
leaf so now we can take this times the
joules of energy in a mole of carbon
I'm gonna just say a mole of ch2oh and
with this the numerator becomes joules
and the denominator becomes joules and
this number this is a number you can
look up in a book the energy in sucrose
and this is 480 kilojoules per mole of
ch2oh
I'm going to give you a handout here to
make sure I get the unit's right so this
is micro moles so now we're keeping
track of this 30 times 10 to the minus
sixth moles times this and now the moles
cancel 30 times 480
I couldn't write that down here 30 times
4 80 not going to keep track of the
prefix
this is 14.4 joules that the units come
from up here divided by a thousand
joules that of energy it took to fix
that amount of carbohydrate so
photosynthesis in full sunlight of the
healthy leaf everything going for it one
to two percent so that five percents
even a little high average for most
leaves it would only get to five percent
in lower light metals and most of these
calculations were doing high light
that's why we say we can we can ignore
photosynthesis and here's what I just
wrote on the board in a worked out
example with with this and there's the
efficiency and down here one point four
four now it's a right away I made a
mistake I tell people never to do this
model has really assumed inputs we're
assuming 30 and then I wrote the answer
to three significant digits you know I
should really say one to two or
something down here but we all do that
and it helps to show that
this implies you can make quite a
precise calculation and you can if you
have accurate if you knew this was
precisely a thousand and you knew that
was precisely 30 but the point of this
is you can it's not difficult to
calculate the energy going into
photosynthesis okay now let's focus on
this radiation component here and since
we all get the handout and it's up here
take this off take photosynthesis off
there's one other aspect of modeling
that's significant here you could say
and people do wait a minute we can
measure photosynthesis um I'll change
this now to two percent and and maybe
this is more like one percent for
respiration and people say well wait a
minute we can measure that we can put it
in the model
every time you add coefficients to the
model and add complexity you have a
greater chance of making errors on the
primary thing it's kind of like writing
down significant digits if you get too
worried about the third or fourth
significant digit in a model you can
make errors on the big picture thing and
in my experience it's a lot better to
get the big numbers correct and really
analyze them and don't worry about the
small stuff until you really need to
until you're really trying to get three
or four significant digits in the answer
so this little graph is worth really
remembering both the peak of the day and
the integrated total because we go back
and forth between a daily total for
transpiration and an instantaneous value
and when our instruments calculate this
we do this in one-hour time steps so we
do each number in here and it's also
possible to just integrate the whole day
but our data acquisition systems do
one-hour time steps so now I'm going to
focus on a thousand watts in of
shortwave radiation and we're going to
model like one hour near solar noon when
we have a thousand watts in so this
thousand watts
I think I can let's let's get rid of
this and come back to some of this stuff
I think I can model this to keep my same
leaf diagram up here here's the Sun and
we got to have some appropriate color
for the Sun and as every school kid
knows this is the appropriate Anatomy
for the Sun so the sun's coming in and
we have a thousand watts per meter
squared hitting that leaf and we'll say
this is a 1 meter squared leaf if you
hold the leaf to the Sun you can see
light coming through it so light goes
through leaves so it's not all absorbed
if you hold the leaf like this and look
at it you it you can see light bouncing
off it so lights reflected and
transmitted and we only have to
evaporate enough water to account for
what's absorbed by this leaf so we know
from lots of years of measurements on
leaves they're all very similar with the
exception of really thick leaves like
maybe a cactus but of that thousand
about 25% bounces off and about 25% is
transmitted
so suddenly remember our model and we
are off by a factor of 2 between the
actual evaporation of water and the
input just with this simple analysis if
only half is absorbed by the leaf
remember we had on one side we had one
point two centimeters a day and then
over here we had zero point six
centimeters a day this is the measured
from pan evaporation all of a sudden if
only half is absorbed our two sides of
our model line up
Wow but we're not done it gets bit more
but suddenly there's a big difference
and all we've done so far is account for
absorbed radiation so this term when I
just said radiation in in a generic
sense this has to be our radiation
absorbed by the leaf and no equals T
plus C squared so now our challenge is
to calculate the absorbed radiation by a
single leaf or by a community and this
is applied to anything I mean your car
parked in the Sun we're calculating
absorb radiation to do this but it's a
key first step because you can see from
this the absorb can be half of what's
incident and our it's not difficult to
measure the incident coming in these are
little harder we model them and we
measure them both depending on the
situation so
let's take this and erase this let's
take this 25% reflected when we
calculate energy balance for the planet
Earth for anything we're measuring
reflected radiation and you can look up
characteristic reflectances of surfaces
all kinds of surfaces you can look up
the piece of white paper you can look up
a piece of black paper and so because
this is so common in calculations we've
got a unique name for it albedo and
that's the fraction of reflected
radiation
so we've just said for a typical leaf
25% as a as a round number if we did
let's say what's the albedo of a black
piece of paper black paper if I drew a
little thing and colored it in all black
it's about I'm gonna get rid of my zero
it's about 10 percent albedo is a
expressed typically as a decimal
fraction not as a percent so black paper
0.1 white paper maybe 0.9 so there's
some pretty extremes and leaves are in
the middle somewhere around 25% so I
have
a handout showing typical values for
some common surfaces see if we can get
that on there nice and straight and this
is where we get into that's for here's
white paper and black paper and well
this is really black paper I put point
oh five this paper might be sort of
charcoal if it got up to 0.1 and in this
paper well I had super white paper here
and this was a little off light so it's
0.8 but you get the idea never mind this
column just yet we're going to get to
that here's a flat leaf 25 now plant
community if a leaf is 25% okay fine but
now a plant community we got leaves at
all kinds of angles and the light
bounces around so typically a plant
community is a little bit less than a
single leaf because of vertical leaves
and bouncing it absorbs the light
slightly better aluminum foil up there
pretty close to white paper they both
reflect light pretty well in fact I've
been in a lot of discussions with growth
chamber manufacturers what's the best
color for the inside of a growth chamber
should it be reflective mylar or should
it be white and there it's pretty
academic they're both about the same
human skin that's a good comparison 50%
reflectance from our skin which brings
me to an interesting sidebar
this little graph is an example out of
Campbell &amp; Norman's book biophysical
plant physiology I physically in
Antarctica and the energy balance of a
person in Antarctica how big of a coat
that they have to wear yellow here you
get to go out and it's a little chilly
I'll go change clothes I'll Antarctica
you have to know how cold is gonna be so
what color should the coat be what's the
energy balance of the person working
outside in a super cold condition and
here's this chest in the Sun and he's in
the shade and I won't go through all the
details but there's an application of
energy balance and now let's take that
to the limit I've had the wonderful
experience of working with NASA people
and listening to lots of seminars now
we're gonna have a person go into outer
space on a extra-vehicular trip and you
don't get to go say it's a little chilly
I'll come in and put on thicker gloves
they have to know how that person's
going to work and imagine getting every
single finger at just the right
temperature in this suit and the physics
are different there's no air so
conduction and convection is zero and
there's no transpiration they have to do
everything by radiation balance these
numbers are both zero so the radiation
in has to equal the radiation out for
this spacesuit
and and that's true of if you're on the
surface of the Moon there's no air so
this is all radiation balance and
there's it's just an interesting example
of applications of these principles
snow is a big deal look fresh clean snow
as soon as it gets little old it drops
off that has a lot to do with hydrology
and calculating how fast the snow is
going to melt in the spring and come
down
how car white is the snow doesn't take
much to drop that albedo of the snow and
this drops 10% more Energy's going into
the snow this also brings us to a
theoretically perfect black body which
is a black disc and that has an albedo
by definition of zero point zero zero
and if we ran if it's theoretically
perfect you could put ten zeros on this
would still be it's zero our radiometers
are designed to have a black disc that's
as close to theoretically perfect as
possible and you look at that little
black disc and it's supposed to look
like it's a hollow cavity like there's
nothing there you could put your finger
in the hole if we had a theoretically
perfect black body here it would look
like some giant tube that was like a
black hole and it looked like you could
put your hand right in it because
there's nothing there so it's rare we
ever get anything that good but we
aspire to make this albedo of those
black surfaces as close to zero as
possible so we're coming I'm going to
come to this and I'm going to come to
this in a minute but there's the concept
of albedo and it's easy to look up the
internet that albedo is for all kinds of
surfaces because this is such a big deal
here's a pyrometer measuring son-in and
if we take one like this we could
measure reflected out and this
instrument with one turned upside down
is called an albedo meter that's and you
can purchase these and characterize
surfaces so we for double the money you
can measure it and if you don't have a
lot of money you model it and your but
it's a critical parameter their fraction
of reflected radiation so
this before I know let me let me move
now from I'm gonna race this albedo
because we we've all got that nailed and
the albedo meter
so now let's break down radiation
absorbed equals radiation in times
albedo no let me take one more step here
radiation short wave SW that's that's in
times albedo this other marker is
slightly better times albedo is
radiation shortwave ABS absorbed let me
give you a handout that shows us all
worked out so we got one component of
this for absorbed radiation but in a
single leaf albedo is only this fraction
here so we need to put a number in here
that accounts for both absorbed and
transmitted so typically we have
radiation shortwave in or incident
radiation times and the number we're
going to put in here is 0.5 because it
accounts for both transmission and
incident arc
yes thank you well it's fraction
reflected yep yep abde Oh
so now we got 50% absorbed and if we're
going to assume this a thousand coming
in here if this one's a thousand times
0.5 now we have absorbed radiation and
500 watts per meter squared of shortwave
we have not yet done long wave radiation
but this is the powerhouse of the
shortwave coming in from the Sun at
solar noon
there's one thing that we typically add
to this to make the model a bit more
accurate you can you can ignore this but
almost always there is additional
radiation coming into that leaf from
reflection
it comes off of clouds and bounces on
the leaf and it comes off the ground and
bounces on the leaf so in this case if
we're assuming a leaf over ground
especially wet ground moist soil 10% so
if that a beater was ten percent if it's
moist soil now we have a thousand coming
in tens percent one hundred watts per
meter square so five hundred plus
radiation shortwave reflected so now we
have six hundred watts per meter squared
of radiation coming in on this leaf to
deal with that we're trying to either
see they're going to heat the leaf up or
evaporate water this is the end of the
shortwave radiation part
when yes as soon as these leaves cover
the ground this reflection goes to
virtually zero only that this this is a
still put this in as a component because
if there's clouds next to the Sun you
easily can get ten percent off the
clouds so that's you can it can come
from cloud to a another way I might have
drawn this different arrow but here's a
cloud over here I could have drawn it
like that and it's still reflection and
that would be the case for a full canopy
this goes to zero which allows me to
make a key point here
lots of people panic when they find
their radiation measurements go above a
thousand you just told me a thousand is
clear sun at solar noon and I've get in
1300 your instrument must be wrong is
that a partly cloudy date well yeah and
are the clouds on the size of the Sun
yeah okay we have seen 30 as high as 30
percent reflected off of clouds that's
really high but 10% off of clouds this
happens all the time so all of a sudden
their measurements spike and there's
nothing wrong with the instrument its
reflection off of clouds after we drill
people about a clear sky number we often
fail to tell them that it can be higher
than clear sky when the clouds are like
a lands and they and they focus it of
course that also has to do with people
setting a range of their data logger you
want to make sure your data logger is
capable of measuring
numbers higher than a thousand so this
is the story with shortwave radiation
from the measurement of incident in to
absorbed and in this particular example
we get a thousand in and six hundreds
absorb now obviously this can vary but
it it's an example and it's
roughly half to two-thirds of the total
coming in but this is only shortwave
radiation which is the energy coming
from the Sun when we look at let me draw
this up here if we put the blinds down
in this room so no shortwave came in we
would still have fluxes of long-wave
radiation and long wave radiation comes
from warm objects not not as hot as the
Sun but warm objects and it's
proportional to the temperature of the
objects so if you have two objects in
outer space no air no transpiration and
one's hotter than the other that energy
is going to move by long-wave radiation
from the hot one to the cold and these
are hundreds of watts per meter squared
of energy transfer by long-wave
radiation that we haven't yet accounted
for in this so we need to add that in
let's see what I have for
typically and in them in the book in the
chapter seven that I'm following from
this you can see graphs in there and
I'll put this graph over here and let me
let me erase this and put the graph
right here we're still at radiation
absorbed now we're going to do
electromagnetic spectrum and over here
is 400 and 700 this whole thing is in
nanometers of the wavelength in
nanometers
this is photosynthetic radiation which
we'll come to and if we make a curve of
the energy from the Sun it looks
something like this and this is
shortwave this looks like this above the
Earth's atmosphere there's no absorption
bands in this yet for water vapor and
and co2 out here we get a curve that
looks something like that less intensity
but a really long area and this is long
wave so this dividing line right here we
typically take as 3,000 nanometers or 3
micrometers the difference between short
wave and long wave now I've roughly
drawn this to scale because it's the
area under these curves that drives the
energy and the area under this curve is
roughly the same or maybe a little less
than the area under this curve so a long
wave transfer is a is a big deal
this yes this is only thermal radiation
this is happening in a darkroom you
would never get photosynthesis it only
it warms up the leaf but it absolutely
doesn't Drive photosynthesis well I'm on
this it's let's let's analyze shortwave
radiation for a minute if we take 400
and 700 nanometers right here this is
very close to the wavelengths that our
human eyes can see 400 is purple and 700
is deep red it's like the burner on a
stove you can tell it's light but you
wouldn't want to read a book by it it's
it's these are the wavelengths we can
see and this area under here is about 42
percent of the total depends on sky
conditions but there's a rule of thumb
about 42 percent drives photosynthesis
it's one of the reasons photosynthesis
is so inefficient it's all this thermal
radiation from the Sun out here that
doesn't drive photosynthesis but it
counts as heat and it warms the leaf up
this part here this tiny part of course
is ultraviolet and this is about 6% of
the total then I could show this part in
red this is infrared
INF infra-red this there we go this this
red markers better infrared out here and
generally this zone in here we called
near-infrared because it's close to the
visible so that's all this part in here
and it's 42 this is roughly half or like
52% of the total radiation so these are
three key components of shortwave and
all this analysis so far just took lump
them all together for them for the three
because the shape of this curve is
important and out here is where we get
dips black line showing absorption of
water vapor and co2 big dips in this
band this this is that there's a big
difference between the extraterrestrial
curve and what we measure on the surface
and of course our instruments measure
what's on the surface and because this
is a everybody many people here might
have seen this magnet oh I need one to
show not my things we've made this
magnet some years ago to help show the
shape of this curve and now with the
wonders of this technology I can make
this magnet like big and here's this
curve at the surface of the earth and
it's shown in two forms the units over
here are the energy flux joules per
meter squared per second and now they're
per nanometers so it just each
individual wavelength and that's the red
line here's the UV
is a big jump right here at 400 here's
the visible up to 700 which is
photosynthetic photon flux which is what
the plants can use separate instruments
to measure this and then the rest of it
out here now you can start to see bigger
energy bands this only goes to a
thousand and to complete the curve this
should go to 3000 and this this tapers
off there's less and less energy out
here but and you can see the tapering
but this doesn't drop right there it
keeps tapering out so this is a useful
magnet because it shows up both ways we
can calculate the photon flux from this
and that's a different shape of a curve
so the photon flux is what drives
photosynthesis in between here and the
energy flux is what drives transpiration
I see the Sun lots of people's filing
cabinets in their offices in different
places and that was measured here in
Logan at our elevation noon solar noon
on the summer solstice so it's slightly
different at different times of the year
but it gives a reference on the
brightest time of the year
while I'm on this we're not going to
talk about photosynthesis per se in this
class but our instruments measure both
of these and we go back and forth
between energy and photons with Planck's
equation energy is HC over the
wavelength speed of light Planck's
constant and the wavelength and the key
part of this is energy is inversely
proportional to the wavelength of light
I've got a handout with this worked out
and I don't have it with me today so
I'll come back to this but it helps us
go back and forth between energy and
photons calculating and in both units
and it's it's helpful to show a worked
out example of this and I'm I'll throw
it next time so there's our solar curve
with absorption bands for for some of
the factors in here
now let's do long wave radiation and
I've just got a few minutes left before
the hours up long wave is governed I
better leave that up here
hmm one other key handout I made for us
zoom out here it is this is shortwave
and long-wave radiation that I drew
right here above the Earth's atmosphere
and at sea level yeah this is 1.5 air
mass is the depth of air that the
sunlight comes through if the Sun was
perfectly overhead that'd be one but
it's rarely as it perfectly overhead
it's at some angle so 1.5 is a typical
amount of air for the Sun to shine
through and that's what 1.5 mm has is if
it's in the winter this can be really
low angles it can be three be heavily
filtered at really low angles so here's
these absorption bands and you can see
how tiny the radiation gets out here
it's mostly absorbed above 2.5 this is
long wave and there's lots of
atmospheric absorption of long wave
radiation a perfect black body curve and
then the absorption at different
wavelengths here so
we would like to know the amount of long
wave radiation hitting things we measure
this with the blackbody parameter or
some type of pyro na meter long wave we
can also measure with an instrument
called a per G ometer but we can also
calculate it from surface temperature
and to get that surface temperature
measurement
here we go
I love showing this picture of this guy
we go to Ludwig Boltzmann this is from a
book I have of the hundred most famous
scientists in the world
I think Einstein was number one i
boltzmann ate it that number 24 in this
list and I've really enjoyed reading
about some of these people because that
there lots of them are really eccentric
that Boltzmann was in and out of insane
asylums his whole life and he and he
made it to 62 years old and he he only
died in 1906 but what a what a crazy guy
and I'll I'll show you mocks plunk in
this book who was up one of the top
scientists mocks Blancas have a
perfectly ordered life I could imagine
him with the perfectly clean desk and
nothing out of order he was just a
complete opposite of of Boltzmann but
Boltzmann gave us what's called this day
and any later like a lot of things
paired with Stefan the Stefan Boltzmann
law and this is the widely used very
famous law for long wave radiation and
in principle it says energy is
proportional to I always put my fish
symbol in here it's proportional to
temperature so if the surface gets
hotter the energy is more so that's
pretty simple so if we know the surface
temperature we know the energy we use
this in Reverse we measure the energy
coming off a surface and we say that's
that's got to be the temperature of the
surface so we use this both direction
sometimes to measure an energy predict
temperature sometimes to measure
temperature predict energy has nothing
to do with air temperature it's all
about surface temperature
and to make this better than this simple
principle we've got energy equals this
Sigma Greek letter Sigma which is the
stefan-boltzmann constant and I've used
this enough I can remember this number
it's five point six seven times ten to
the minus eighth watts per meter squared
per Kelvin so here's the big
significance of this Wow 10 to the minus
eighth you know this has to be Kevin
it's a big number but this this is a
really small exponent and lots of these
constants in our equations have some
really tiny some really big exponents
but here's the amazing thing about this
all kinds of our equations have squared
something squared or the square root of
something this is the only equation I
know that has temperature this is by the
way temperature in Kelvin to make this
units cancel its temperature to the
fourth power so it's really a nonlinear
relationship with temperature but
because it's Kelvin it's we're going
from room temperatures three hundred
Kelvin so three hundred times to the
fourth power to maybe three hundred and
five to the fourth power but this is the
relationship
setup is this available energy we didn't
good question we didn't get into how
much of this is absorbed yet which we
need to this is the tonal energy
transmitted not all of this is absorbed
as if this is a key point but first
we'll talk about what's coming off I've
got one handout and then I'm gonna stop
and we're gonna pick this up next time
and here we go
always good when I can find my handouts
this is so there's enough exponents in
this here's a worked out example
stefan-boltzmann law of equation right
there 273.15 - Kevin so we put this to
make it easy to do in a surface
temperature in Celsius and then you put
it in an Excel spreadsheet and you run
it and here's the emitted radiation
coming off a surfaces from minus 40 to
plus 80 hot surface of a car might get
the plus 80 or something really hot in
the Sun look at the numbers now that's
this is just three columns radiation
emitted 25 degrees C 448 so as a rule of
thumb this leaf is 25 C so
448 watts per meter squared is being
given off by long wave radiation so all
of a sudden we had 600 watts of
shortwave absorbed Wow 448 is is given
off by long wave all of a sudden this
leaf doesn't have to evaporate that much
water because a long wave emission
now here's then here's the thing that
we'll pick up next time
long wave works both ways the leaf is
giving it off to the environment but
down here we have ground and let's say
the ground is 25 C now we have to count
+ 448 coming in so if the ground
temperature and the leaf are the same
this net long-wave radiation cancels out
and it's a small number that's the
simple basics next time we'll talk about
a little letter right here e which is
emissivity and what does different
surfaces emit at different rates it's
sort of like albedo only this is
emission not reflection so this is a
really key component and we'll pick it
up next time next time we should be able
to wrap up all the components of long
wave in this and so we have a total
absorbed radiation and how to calculate
it and then we could move on to these
next components
yeah you can see the two graphs down
here this is slightly nonlinear because
it's T to the fourth and this is the
slope of the line so if it could
estimate it between two points okay any
questions that make an answer about this
you did a good job stopping me and
especially when I had one minus albedo
you got to always be vigilant for for
those things okay we see it tomorrow