I'm Bruce Bugbee professor of crop
physiology at Utah State University and
we have been asked so often by home
growers what are the optimal conditions
to grow cannabis at home so in this
video I'm going to go through all of the
environmental all of the key
environmental parameters and the ways
that we measure them here in a research
laboratory and ways that you can measure
them at home to get optimal conditions
for cannabis we have a license to study
medical hemp at the here at Utah State
University so we're gonna take those
principles and now scale them down for
home use so one of the things that we
often talk about our the nine cardinal
parameters for plant growth and I drew a
little plant here to give you a sense of
this let me put the parameters on here
and then we'll talk about each of them
in turn let's start with temperature I'm
going to just put Tim over here then
we'll put humidity then we'll put wind
and inside we usually call that air
velocity co2 and we put brackets around
that to show co2 concentration how do we
measure it what are optimum levels and
now we go underground and to get this
just right we go to around so we have
temperature down here in the root zone
We certainly have water in the root zone
nutrients and then find the oxygen oops
Oh
so here's our parameters you can pretty
quickly see that's only eight parameters
I want to start with light light we put
up here l IG HT
it's enormous it's coming from all
directions it affects everything in here
when we turn up to light the water flux
or the plant goes up the optimum levels
of other things change so to optimize
growth we have to start by optimizing
light now this same diagram is over here
I've shown this many times in talks but
what I want to show you is a little bit
of data from our laboratory on a couple
of cultivars here we can zoom in on this
baby get it get it big a couple of
cultivars this is yield and this is a
input parameter called D Li daily light
integral and what I'm going to show you
right now is how to measure this because
the higher the number the higher the
yield this is a curved line but look if
these numbers are still going up as we
approach 60 now 60 is a sunny summer day
no clouds at all in the middle of summer
that's the brightest day of the year and
hip benefits from that you don't always
have to grow it here it'll grow fine
down around 30 but if you want to get
maximum yield we need to push it hard
with light and if we push it hard with
light we have to optimize everything
else so let's look at the calculations
for this when we measure light we take a
ordinary quantum sensor and measure it
and if you just have
a quantum sensor with a meter you're
going to get a unit of that one's done
you're going to get a unit of micro
moles of photons per meter squared of
area per second this is the standard
unit from quantum sensors and what the I
in integral means is a you have this up
over a whole day so if we take a quantum
sensor and we measure 1,000 now this is
bright bright light is of pushing the
plant hard just like to get to over here
we're going to get two moles per meter
squared per day and this is what's
called daily light integral and the way
we get there is just add up to seconds
there's 3,600 seconds per hour
and so we multiply those together and
you can see a thousand times three
thousand we get three point six times
ten to the sixth micro moles per meter
squared per second now 10 to the 6 micro
moles is one mole that micro is ten to
the minus six so this is three point six
sorry this is per hour right here read
the seconds canceled three point six
moles per meter squared per hour in the
world of cannabis
we need short days to get the plants to
flower and make good flower buds and to
do that I think most people know to be
safe we go with to have our photo period
so now we multiplied these two
twelve hours 12 times 3.6 is forty three
point two moles per meter squared per
day this is how you get the daily light
integral after you measure this now used
to be you had to do some math after you
did this to calculate this but because
this is so important companies have
developed instruments to add it up
continuously and here's one made by
Apogee instruments it's connected to
this device this is a quantum sensor -
and this adds up the measures the light
and adds it up and because it's
bluetooth shows it on your phone and
what this is showing is the daily light
integral each day and this was outside
recently so you can see we got up to 35
this is in the spring of year cloudy
days or five inside we'd have a constant
light it also does photo period now this
is really critical because we want 12
hours and at night we don't want any
light pollution a little bit of light
leaking in can cause cannabis to not
flower at all or flower poorly so this
instrument is it's like a silent
Sentinel it's watching all the time make
sure the light is correcting the day and
make sure it's off and dark at night so
this this shows a whole bunch of screens
I'm not going to go through them all but
it collects data and summarizes it for
you so this is in addition to this
instrument how hard can we push the
plants a thousand gave us 43 now that's
fine we can grow find cannabis
that but if we want to push it we're
gonna need to go up to 60 now look what
happens if we increase this to 1500
micromoles everything increases by 1.5
we take this times 1.5 and that's that's
see that's going to be 43 plus 22 it's
gonna be 60 to about 60 to micromoles
per meter squared per second now we're
up to where we're pushing it hard and we
get very high yields but boy the other
inputs also have to be optimal that's
why the rest of these parameters are so
important so I'm going to put near
maximum now we've done studies in the
laboratory at two thousand and healed
keeps going up at two thousand but
that's getting really high it's hard to
keep everything water so here's the
light level you want to pinpoint this to
make sure it's there it's the light
levels a lot like the speedometer in the
car if you're going to take this car out
for a fast ride you sure as heck want an
accurate speedometer in it to know
exactly how fast you're going of course
you got a lot of other gauges too but it
starts with getting the light exactly
right it's possible to measure light
with the foot-candle meter or a Lux
meter but those can lead to big errors
you need to calibrate them against a
good quantum sensor there's a lot of
stories of people having troubles with
lux meters and can lead to a difficulty
in the crop let's go through the other
parameters here if we're going to push
this crop part with a lot of light
temperature the temperature curve is
about I'm going to put 26 to 29 Celsius
and now I have to convert this this is
going to mm-hmm let me change this a
little bit here make it round numbers
let's do 25 to 30 degrees C and in
Fahrenheit that's 77 to 86 F this is a
broad top broad range and in this range
you're going to have pretty optimal
conditions when you have a lot of light
you got to have some cooling or you're
going to go hotter than 86 and that's
that's definitely not good now let's
look at humidity in these conditions
the plants produce a lot of humidity and
the key for the humidity is blowing the
humidity out so if we were to draw I
could probably put this up here but
here's a light box here's our plant down
here I'm going to put the plant on this
and green growing it's a big plant this
plant putting an enormous amount of
water into the air when the lights I'm
going to put h2o here h2o so you want to
have some kind of event like this to
have the air come in and blow out most
of the time the humidity is too high and
that leads to powdery mildew leads to
diseases so the optimal humidity is
really well exactly
optimum might be 60% but that's a pretty
broad optimal you can grow fine plants
from 40 to maybe 70% as long as you
don't get disease up at the high end
to this so that's humidity and we're
venting this tube loadout at the same
time we're venting this number one it's
cooling the plant by venting which is
important with all this light to have
lots of ventilation and one way to tell
the ventilation is put your plant in and
measure the temperature and keep enough
ventilation so you don't so you don't
get above 30 Celsius or 85 Fahrenheit
and humidity same thing get a humidity
meter put them by the vent
make sure you don't get too high
humidity wind is you can get anemometers
to measure wind but generally you just
want plenty of air flow if the leaves
are moving slightly that's a good air
flow that's around a meter a second wind
speed and that's what you want to
maintain for this co2 II we've known for
since photosynthesis was discovered that
co2 improves crop growth in the
laboratory we can enrich co2 and big
commercial operations we enrich co2 it's
complicated to enrich at home so we
rarely enrich at home but we're
breathing out a lot of co2 in the house
anyway and the pilot light in a water
heater gives out a lot of co2 I measure
co2 carbon dioxide of my house and some
years ago I found the house never went
down to ambient co2 and after a lot of
testing I finally found out it was my
pilot light in my water heater that was
enriching co2 in the entire house it's
beneficial to enrich with co2 but it's
certainly not necessary to grow a great
crop ambient co2 is now about 400 parts
per million
the challenge with co2 is to keep it
from going below 400 and again if the
ventilation is not adequate the co2 for
a plant is like oxygen for people so the
water vapors coming out that's putting
co2 us black and chemistry so we're
gonna put co2 carbon is black the co2 is
going in if you don't have enough
ventilation you deplete the co2 in the
plants basically suffocating so make
sure we get plenty of ventilation to
keep the humidity low that temperature
low and then the co2 will automatically
be close to 400 and that's adequate some
years ago I did a TED talk called
turning water into food and that TED
talk was about how much water plants
really need now TED talks are 15 minutes
long I had to take a lot of stuff out to
make it fit but I'm going to show you
something that got cut from that TED
talk this is back from high school or
beginning college chemistry these beads
represent the ratio of gases in our
atmosphere and if you know a little bit
about the atmosphere most of its
nitrogen so this one is 80% nitrogen
this is an inert gas at 79 80 % of our
atmosphere what's the next biggest gas
oxygen so 20% of the air is oxygen shown
here in red then we go let's take this
one out for a minute
these four beads and this one there's
10,000 beads here this is carbon dioxide
this is what the plants have to work
with to grow if these four beads go to
three beads the plant growth suffers you
want plenty of aeration going through
your your grow tent
make sure it's adequate this once water
vapor blue there's quite a bit more
water vapor than co2 but here's the key
point
humans need oxygen and we had a lot of
oxygen for us
plants need co2 and they hardly have an
E and that's the whole reason that good
supply of air is critical to that plant
it's almost like you can't have a fan
that's too big in here but yeah at some
point it's a waste of electricity I
would just measured temperature and
humidity and keep those down because
drawing a scale drawing here here's the
lights and in this box all day long
they're putting a lot of light in that's
driving the water driving the
temperature you want to blow those out
one key thing about light the plants
need to be dark at night now most people
line this with silver or mylar let the
light reflect in black on the outside
you want to make sure this is dark at
night if there's light pollution
somebody turns on a light and that leaks
in your plants could not they might not
flower properly or they might not have
good you for this reason another thing
Apogee developed it's this sensor here
was a light pollution detector and it's
really sensitive to low levels of light
it's the same as the other one only a
detects trace amounts of light
contamination that's to keep it good and
dark because here's 12 hours of light
that means 12 hours of dark now by the
way we're studying lines that might take
13 hours maybe 14 hours of light but for
now to be on the safe side to have hours
of light and dark to be to optimize
yield you want to decide you want to
make a good decision about when to go
from vegetative growth or what
called veg to reproductive growth and
typically this is 18 in up to 24 hours
24 hours doesn't hurt the plants it
might not be used quite as efficiently
but you want a long photo period till
you get a big plant and then you go into
reproductive and after that point it's
about not 12 weeks it's about 8 weeks
till harvest so I brought a couple of
plants in here to show you these are
some that we're doing research on here's
it there's a young plant
this is gets this big and depends on
again on the light level but it could
get this big two weeks
after depending on what you start from
but after you start from cut a rooted
cutting if we gave this plant 12 hours
right now it would start to flower and
it would never get very big it would
have a fine yield they just never get
very big so what we do is keep it on 18
hour long days and boom now it gets big
and now if we give it short days at this
point we're going to have a lot of yield
on one single plant the point here is
gauge when to switch to short days to
short to have our days make sure your
plants big enough to fill the space if
you switch too early you'll reduce yield
if you switch too late the plant just
gets too enormous bigger than you can
handle most plants increase in size
about 30 percent have to switch through
this one maybe even double in size this
one might get this big when it's done
this one would be enormous when it when
it flowers sorry
that's floatable period
this one we talked about light intensity
there's lots of choices for lights to
get the intensity high you absolutely
have to measure it to so you know what
you're dealing with we've already talked
about all the blue labels in the foliar
environment but if you do not have an
optimal root zone environment you're
gonna have yellow leaves discolored
leaves purple leaves and that's why I
want to focus a bit on the root zone
here temperature if the root zone about
the same as the top one it's it's really
26 to 30 degrees C for temperature
oxygen nutrients and water all have to
be optimal particularly if we're driving
the plant hard now let's go over here
and I'll show you the media that we use
in the research laboratory these are
some media components lots of people
sell media for cannabis and lots of
people claim they have a special media
we make our own from simple ingredients
and we have done whoo 30 years of study
on media components now this is the
media we use here in the research
laboratory and I'm going to put it up
here and then I'll talk about options
for that let's see we'll put that in
Brown it is 50% peat 50% vermiculite
so I think most people know what Pete
looks like not everybody knows what
vermiculite looks like there's some
other additives we'll get to those but
these are the primary ingredients here's
Pete same you could buy this at any
hardware store in North America it
almost always comes from Canada this is
a great media in the United Kingdom
they're really trying to crack down on
minimal use of peat and they've gone to
many other things but in North America
them
it grows typically start with pita in
the media some substitutes for peat are
ground-up wood this is a product called
Hydra fiber which is a shredded wood
product and this can be used as a
substitute from peat or as an additive
to Pete here's vermiculite here's the
container I could put this on a slope
this was and still is sometimes widely
used for building insulation but this is
mica that's mine and heated and puffed
up it's not widely used by commercial
growers of ornamental plants because
it's expensive um they used to use it
years ago but as it became expensive
they switched to perlite which is also
widely available in stores and you can
also use perlite but peaked is a little
better and when you're pushing plants
for optimal yields we'd like to use peat
and perlite let me put vermiculite or
perlite or shredded wood
shredded wood and the brand name that's
widely available is called Hydra fiber
we've done a lot of research on that in
this lab and it's a good good product
but again peat is the base and we've got
a lot of additives to it
I should mention it's not a tray coconut
choir just it's a strange name to spells
cocoa nut see all I are some people
pronounce it car some people announce it
choir just shredded coconuts and this
used to have a lot of problems 20 years
ago we did a lot of research on this the
companies that make it have really done
a good job cleaning it up and the
quality is much higher than it was so
coconut choir is a fine additive for a
media as well but we use peat and
vermiculite because we want the absolute
premium media vermiculite has
exceptionally good water holding
capacity it has exceptionally good
cation exchange capacity that means
ability to hold nutrients it provides
this is huge
for cannabis s I L I see a silica all
those little trichomes in cannabis are
full of silica on the leaves and more
than other crops cannabis benefits from
silica if you use vermiculite you
automatically get lots of silicon these
other products don't have any silica so
if you is one of these other products
you should find an additive of silica
and add it to the media or just use
vermiculite there's several sources of
silica products to add now let's talk
about what we add to this media of here
in our research lab and again this
results of lots of studies peak is comes
pretty acid the pH of peat is about it
depends on the peat but I'm going to put
3.8
that's pretty acid Pete another benefit
of vermiculite is it's alkaline and you
mix them together and this automatically
plus V erm vermiculite this goes to
about 4.5 it's it's still asset but it's
a lot better than straight peat
so to help get this in the optimal range
we add it's hard to see this lime this
is just a powder it's added east of the
Mississippi it's added two fields all
the time and in particular we had
dolomitic lime which which gives us some
magnesium I'm running out of room let's
let's put this plus lime and I'm going
to put comma dolomitic
and dolomitic is a unique kind of lime
that has both calcium and magnesium we
add that they get a look at this to make
sure I got my notes right at 40 grams
per cubic foot now I know this is mixed
units metric and feet but grams is easy
to measure I brought in my household
scale if you don't know on one of these
by one by two or three they're cheap
it's easy to measure the weight of your
fertilizer on this here's a little jar
one one that I brought from home of the
blue powder fertilizer you weigh
everything out Oh on this forty grams of
lime this brings the pH up to about 5.5
and that's near optimum and it adds
calcium and magnesium to the mix and
just mix it in into the media as you
make it there's one other thing we add
I'm running out of room I put it down
here gypsum
gypsum is a common agricultural product
and it is calcium sulfate caso4 if you
had chemistry
this adds additional calcium which is
good many places have inadequate calcium
in the tap water and it adds sulfur here
in Utah we have low sulfur in our water
so we put gypsum into the media and
again you can buy this in many places
and we use up talat eyes gypsum it looks
like this add that to the median it's
really slow release over a period of
many months and you don't need nearly as
much gypsum ten grams per cubic foot and
I think you can it doesn't these are not
precise you can be off 10% and it's just
fine
I think it can visualize a cubic foot if
we wanted to do this all metric a cubic
foot is twenty eight point three liters
per cubic foot and now you can convert
to all all metric so people there's a
lot of options the one we like the best
for an absolute premium media is peat
vermiculite with 40 grams per cubic foot
of line and 10 grams per cubic foot of
gypsum now we're ready to go we got our
container let's put the container down
here something like this you can see
these containers over here that we use
to grow the plants there's our here's
our container with our media in it
we keep this pretty fluffy to get plenty
of oxygen to be sure you have enough
oxygen you can buy an oxygen sensor
Apogee instruments sells an oxygen
sensor to put in here that helps you
make sure you got plenty of oxygen in
your growth medium this media is so
fluffy that it's hard to overwater it
the water will drain out you want to be
sure you have a tray under this because
we're gonna want to flush some of the
nutrient solution through this and now
let's put in red nutrients we're going
to put nutrients in here what do we use
for nutrients the many companies sell
special nutrients we have tested many
things over the years I teach a class in
principles of plant nutrition it uses
this big heavy textbook mineral
nutrition of higher plants so we've
analyzed nutrients a lot and we've done
many tests here we have found we use the
same fertilizer that we use for all of
our other plants wheat plants corn
plants tomato plants we can recommend a
general fertilizer that works well for
this and fertilizers come with three
numbers N and P and K and the one we use
is 20 - 10 - 20 has less phosphorous
plants need less phosphorous than
nitrogen and potassium so this ratio
gives us ample nutrients provided we're
slightly over watering and what it
really means is about 10% of the water
comes out the bottom and
want to catch it and put it on your lawn
put it somewhere else it's still fine
fertilizer but when this fertilizer is
running through it helps to ensure that
there's plenty of nutrients it's
possible to do this with no leaching it
just gets trickier so how much of this
do we put in to the mix here's another
instrument that you you really benefit
from this is an electrical conductivity
meter so this particular one sold by
Hana
we used Hana instruments we use these a
lot the more salt in the water
the higher the electrical conductivity
you can tell if your nutrient solution
is optimal by measuring this and let me
do a little demo for you turn it on I
made two beakers let's put them right in
the front in fact I want to put these on
a piece of white paper because we're
we're gonna make a little demo
see the difference in color this is tap
water and this is our nutrient solution
it has a blue dye in it so you can tell
when it's there it should be just
perceptible very light blue so we put
this in tap water it depends on what
part of the country what part of the
world you live in but tap water is about
0.4 tap water 0.4 and the units on this
are milli-siemens per meter now the
units are a little bit messy in this
because different meters have different
units but here's tap water now look what
happens with the fertilizer this is very
dilute fertilizer put this in here stir
the second I don't know if you can see
it on the screen 1.27 this is 0.4 this
is one point two seven and I'm going to
put about one point three nutrient
solution the reason this is important is
you can measure the electrical
conductivity of this water that you
collect and if this water is between one
and one and a half you know your plants
are doing well they're doing great if
you don't water enough this gets too
high and they have too many nutrients if
or if it's a big plant it could be too
low too so you want to you put one point
three in the top and water enough so
this is about about one point three
coming out the bottom then you measure
that with an electrical conductivity
meter this is
the the fertilizer ratio to get this I'm
running out of room I'm gonna I'm gonna
have to calculate it because I can't
remember the number off the top of my
head
this is 20% n and we're gonna want to
get about 120 ppm in this is the optimum
level of fertilizer so 120 ppm is 120
milligrams of n per liter a part per
million is exactly the same as a
milligram per liter if you do this
you're going to end up with an honorary
degree in horticulture that's it and
learn to do this math the fertilizer is
only 20% so this is 0.2 grams of n per 1
gram I'm going to call this blue because
it's the blue fertilizer so one hundreds
of 20 over 0.2 is 600 milligrams per
liter you can see there that take this
times five so I've know 600 milligrams
per liter equals six
he'll bond 120 ppm
this is this is 0.6 grams per liter this
is grams of blue powder ooh
fertilizer there's the optimum rate now
it doesn't have to be exact it's close
to this but when I did this study over
there with EC I put in 0.6 grams per
liter of blue powder you don't need to
know how to derive it just write down
that number but the instructions come
with that on the fertilizer let me show
you briefly the vast array of
fertilizers that commercial growers use
this is my folder now I know everybody
looks this stuff up on the internet but
I grew up at a time before the Internet
so I still use paper here's one of the
charts with all the fertilizers use
these are called Jack's fertilizers
there's Peters fertilizers these are all
specialty fertilizers for specialty
applications to my knowledge these guys
aren't marketing a special cannabis
fertilizer at the moment but if they did
they should be selling twenty ten twenty
because after a lot of analysis this is
what we've gone to here these these are
[Music]
sold by many companies Peters
fertilizers a famous brand name Jack's
is essentially the same thing there
they're available in stores you could
buy these in small packets we buy them
in twenty five pound bags a whole pallet
load up them because we're going through
a lot of them but this is the ratio of
fertilizer applied at this concentration
to get and you're gonna buy an EC meter
to make sure you didn't make a math
error to get about 1.2 to 1.3 of your EC
and a very slight blue color after a
while you get so good you can tell the
EC from looking at the color if you
don't want to fertilize daily it is
possible to put in a
release fertilizer here are some pellets
this is a product called nutria coat you
can put these in these come in various
release rates they're not as precise as
watering each day with fertilizer like
this but for some kinds of studies if
there's reasons you can't do a liquid
feed or a straight hydroponics you can
put slower these fertilizer in the
bucket water you got to learn to how
often you have to water if when the
plant gets big let's let's go back to
these plants it depends on the life the
higher the light the more you have to
water this plant at a thousand micro
moles per meter squared per second we
could probably water it once every three
days how often do you think we need to
water this plant if there's a thousand
micro moles twice a day that's a big
plant in a small pot that means you've
really benefit from heaven some kind of
automated system or a bigger container
and lots of people go to quite a large
container so they only have to water
once a day but it really depends on how
big the plant is and then you get to
develop the skill of lifting the pot
this pot feels heavy
that means it's full of water when it
runs out of water it'll feel light
that's a tremendous skill keep lifting
your pots and gauge how much water is in
them you can there's many products you
can poke in here to get water in my
experience yeah it all comes back to
calibrating yourself you can do much
better by lifting the pot so we've
covered all of these Cardinal parameters
for plants nutrients and media are big
and light is big you want to get these
correct you want to make sure you want
to do temperature and humidity in your
box if you have plenty of wind you're
going to be fine with ambient co2 i I
want to conclude on one thing
lots of cannabis gets yellow leave
purple leave discolored leaves burned
leaf edges in our research here most of
the time that's from too much fertilizer
people panic and they think they don't
have enough but it's often from too much
which is why that EC meter is so
important and why flushing it like this
keeps it from being either deficient or
toxic because you're flushing the pot a
little bit each time you water if you
get these parameters right your plants
look just like that to be healthy green
they and and it highlight you can you
can push them hard and get high growth
thanks for listening we'll join you
again on another video two more things
we already got two questions from the
audience that I want to make really
clear in this number one water with
nutrient solution every time you water
no different tap water it's very dilute
it's made to be watered every single
time no matter if you water once every
three days three times a day always
water with nutrient solution that's
thing one thing to color of light this
is a huge question and many people have
strong opinions about colors of light
we've done a lot of studies on this
here's what it comes down to for
homeowners white WH ite white light the
reason I recommend that is you can see
the plants you could diagnose subtle
differences in color of the plants you
can diagnose tiny insects in the plants
there it's aesthetically pleasing you
want to look at the plants there's this
old Chinese saying the best fertilizer
is the footsteps of the farmer well if
the plants are in white light you're
going to want to look at them and you're
gonna tell purple lights are slightly
more efficient but white lights have
come a long ways now they can be white
plus red
that's good but something that makes the
plants look green that's the key Thanks
you