I'm Bruce Bugee, president of Apogee Instruments, and today I'm going to
walk you through the research we did over several years to develop this new
chlorophyll meter. We had this idea quite some time ago, but it took a lot of R&amp;D
to get this and the work we did is published and publicly available in this
paper here I've got a copy of it here. We were really pleased that plant cell and
environment published this paper. It's one of our top journals because there's a lot
of detailed physiology in this paper. There is so much detail physiology that I
want to walk you through some of it in the next few minutes, with references to
the paper. Here's the meter on a leaf. It's an optical meter, you clamp it down.
Based on the transmission of two wavelengths of light, it converts this in
software to a unit of chlorophyll per unit area, and in this case its moles  of
chlorophyll per meter squared of leaf. No other meter optical meters in this
price range can do that. That's  the unique breakthrough of this meter, but it was not
trivial to get to that point. Let's walk through some of the graphs in this paper and
look at what we did. The first thing we did was a massive literature
review, and we found that there are over thirty studies on this relationship
between transmission of light and chlorophyll concentration. They started
back in 1986, there was a meter called this SPAD-501, and later in
1992 they came out with the SPAD-502. These are old meters. People are starting to
establish this relationship. Here's a critical paper a Moje and Bugbee,
1992. This was one of my graduate students Oscar Monje and I. This paper turns out to be
one of my top five most highly cited papers, in this list, because we discuss
the inherent limitations of doing this
back in 1992.Then about ten years later, the papers start to show up with an Opti
Sciences meter the CCM-200 getting what we call
the optical absolute relationship. In other words, the relationship between
what this meter can read and the true amount of chlorophyll in the
leaf. We know this relationship is nonlinear, which is one of the big
problems, but the first thing we looked at was how did these studies
agree. The studies are on all different species. Let's take a look at that. Here's curves for
the Minolta meter. This unit by the way,  is not a measurement of
chlorophyll. SPAD stands for special products analysis division. It's just the
name of the division in Minolta that developed it. It's not a unit of
chlorophyll concentration. It is a name of the group of people. You can see its
nonlinear going up. But, look at the scattering studies. Here's
our studies, the green line right here. Then when we did this
again using more modern techniques, 20 to 25 years later.
Modern spectrophotometer, more rigorous extraction techniques, gave us this black
line, which is close to the average of all these. Now some people have studied
the Opti Scienes meter and chlorophyll, and that's also nonlinear. It curves
the other direction. We did both of these in this paper, but
so far this is literature review, except for our study. All it does is show these
these papers don't agree. Well why don't they agree? Part of it is
because they're different
species. Different species have chlorophyll arranged in different packets, in
different ways so the light transmits differently. This means you really need a line
for each species. However,
several papers studied the same species, wheat, and they got different curves for wheat.
We went back and looked at these
studies and  not one of them use the right combination of techniques to
accurately convert an optical measurement to an absolute measurement.
This is always the absolute measurement, here. Chlorophyll,
which is always what we want to know. This unit down here is what the
meter gives us. You have to get several things right to do this: you have to have just
the right solvent extraction, you have to have the right equation, and you have
to have the right spectrophotometer. All three of those things have to match, and
when we looked at the literature it was very rare for these older papers to do
everything correct, to get the exact right chlorophyll. This includes our own
paper from 1992. We realized we didn't use the exact right techniques. When
we did it again, this study means, this plant cell and environment paper right
here, we got this curve. Fortunately the reviewers agreed these are all
the right techniques, that's the gold standard curve that replaces all these
previous curves, which are similar but not exactly right.
Let me make a point here about the problem with older meters. If you clamp
on a leaf and you get a reading of 20, you are on this point in the curve, and you have
about
a hundred units of chlorophyll, micromoles of chlorophyll per meter squared. Now you do
another leaf, and you get a reading of 40. You conclude the chlorophyll has
doubled because the number is twice as high. However, look what happens, we go up here and
across, the chlorophyll went up four-fold, between 100 and 400, and our meter only
doubled. There's the problem. We have a lot of bad data in the literature where
people are over-reliant on these SPAD units, when they should be reliant on
the actual chlorophyll. That's a pretty dramatic example of
the problem and the misinterpretation of data.  So, our goal in all of this was to
develop a meter where we could convert in the software of the meter to actual
chlorophyll units in the meter, not a relative index of chlorophyll but actual
chlorophyll. How do we do that? Let's take a look. This is a video, shot in the
laboratory, of making an optical measurement with the meter and then very
carefully marking where that measurement was. Underneath this, is the reading
of the amount of chlorophyll that you write down. Now, in order to get the gold
standard you have to take that disc out from the exact same spot on the leaf
where the measurement was made.. This is done with a cork borar. We put the disc
into a little vial of dimethylsulfoxide. There's different extraction solvents,
but this is the one of choice. Then mix it up. Looking here you can see
this tiny little leaf discs floating in this extraction solvent. Chlorophyll
doesn't come out right away.
To speed it up we put it at sixty-five degrees Celsius. Here we are walking over
to a drying oven, putting it into drying oven  with that extraction
solvent, and now we wait. It typically takes about three hours until all the
chlorophyll is gone from the leaf in solution. The oven is still sixty-five degrees.
There's the vile three hours later. Now the disc is white and all the
chlorophyll is in solution. So, step one, is extract the chlorophyll. This is one
measurement on one leaf.  The next step, is to bring it into the laboratory
and measure it.
Next, transfer it into a cuvette. Measure it in our spectrophotometer, which scans the
appropriate wavelengths and then reads them out on a computer. We will zoom in
here for you in just a minute, on these values, which show the absorbance of
those two wavelengths. With those two numbers in the correct equation,
that matches the instrument and the dimethylsulfoxide, we can calculate both
chlorophyll A and B. We add the two values together, and we have chlorophyll.
As long as your laboratory procedures are correct, this is how you get the gold
standard of chlorophyll, but it's obviously a lot of work compared to
getting a single digital number. One of our concerns was that you can't ever
have a single curve across a wide range of environments to do this because the
arrangement of chlorophyll molecules will change with environment. We tested
that in many ways we grew plants in many different environments, and our data
pretty clearly indicate environment has a minimal effect on the arrangement of
chlorophyll,
chloroplasts, in a leaf.
One of the tests of that was to compare our data for paper birch. This is a
widely distributed species. This was studied by Richardson, who is at
Yale, in 2002. He did everything right in his extractions. We also measured paper
birch, half a continent away, thirty years later, same species. There's a correction
in the equation. When we plotted this against Richardson's data, and we got
virtually the same line. That helped convince us that this procedure is
robust across time and space and  species. Once we get a curve for a species,
that is the curve for that species. That allowed us to take the curves we
developed and put them into the software of this meter. So, what are those curves
look like? Here's the  index from the meter and the chlorophyll here. You can
see all these nonlinear curves. Some species are similar; wheat rice and
barley are similar. Pepper and soy bean have
a remarkably high amount of chlorophyll in the leaves, scale change was double
these other curves. This is a graphical representation of the curves  for all of these.
This is a summary of the species and the numerical equation to linearize
the data and the R squared values.
The R squared values are mostly in the
0.9, here is a 0.97.
There's high correlation, coefficients of determination, for that fit with these
species, which allows us to
convert an optical reading to the absolute reading. This is all published
in the paper.
Here's all the curves for all the species, with the index and then for species
that we don't yet have a curve for here's a generic curve, and that's the
equation to convert the reading to absolute chlorophyll content over here.
Lots of species. Lots of lines. Only a few species had very dark, very high amounts
of chlorophyll. Most of this species are down here. Along the way we were able to
develop two very accurate curves for converting among optical units from
different meters. These special products analysis division units can now be
converted to chlorophyll content index which is what Opti Sciences uses
and vice versa. If you know the CCI you can convert that to SPAD units with these
equations, which are pre-programmed into this Apogee meter. So you can have this
meter read out in any of the units of the previous meters in addition to the
true chlorophyll units. These are very high correlations 0.98 and 0.99 for
these conversion equations. You would think you could do this mathematically
but Minolta has a confidential equation in their meter, and it's it's not known
what the coefficients are. So, we have to do it
empirically.  Now, if you likee logarithms in high school and
manipulating logarithms you'll be interested in this little section of
this paper, which is a series of five equations that takes us through the
percent transmission all the way down to chlorophyll. This is the mathematical
relationships that are going on because there's two wavelengths coming through
the leaf, and we've ratio of these wavelengths.
The reason this needs logarithms is the transmission of light is nonlinear. When
you double the pigment you do not cut the transmission in half and
you change the absorbance. I'm not going to go through the details right
now but this is a ratio of two transmissions, e raised to a power.
There's two wavelengths here. This is critical.
Tthis NIR wavelength, which is at about 930 nanometers measures
cellulose. This
measures just the cell wall. This red waving, which is at 653 nanometers
measures both chlorophyll and cell wall together. There
is no single wavelengths that only gives us chlorophyll; we have to ratio two
wavelengths. Now you can see how by subtraction we can get to chlorophyll,
but we have to deal with this nonlinear effect. So, we have e raised to these powers
This arranges to e (chlorophyll plus cell wall) minus e (cell wall); take the log of both sides, and slove
that for the logarithm. We get chlorophyll plus cell wall, minus cell wall, equals chlorophyll.
Mathematically this is what these meters read. SPAD should
theoretically equal chlorophyll, and the log of the CCI should equall chlorophyll. Know
this is all done in software in the meters. You don't need to know this its
just a fun math exercise, if you like following the math. It took us
awhile to work through this in the lab. But, it is very satisfying
once we showed it theoretically.
These are the species in the Apogee meter that we have equations for. We're
working on additional equations for this. There's generic equations in
here. The major annual crop species are in here. There's
a number of deciduous species, also in this.  So, that's a summary of what we had
to do, to make this meter read out in
moles of chlorophyll per meter squared,
which is what you get with a spectrophotometer, and it's now what you
get with this non-destructive optical meter. For details, I refer you to our paper in
Plant Cell and Environment. You can contact Apogee for a copy of the paper,
and it's also available on the Internet.
Thanks for listening. We look forward to another visit.