hello my name is Ben Crabbe I do
technical sales and support here at
Apogee instruments I'm here to talk
about our new micro cache Bluetooth
logger this is a little Bluetooth
enabled battery-powered device that
connects with your smartphone and
interfaces with any of our unamplified
analog sensors any of our sensors that
put out a little millivolt signal this
micro cache can log and so I'll just
briefly go over some of the features and
specs of the micro cache and then I'll
show off with the phone how to connect
it and some of its some of its
measurement capabilities so here's a
picture of it and an idea of the
dimensions there is a little four to 20
threaded hole in the back for mounting
so you can mount it to any of our
mounting brackets by default most of our
sensors come with this little cable it's
about 12 feet 12 inches long 1 foot long
30 centimeters and so that makes a nice
compact unit we also have for our par
censors we've got a 2 meter cable length
option for measurement underwater or for
corals let's see this app or this micro
cache connects with your phone with a
little smartphone app called Apogee
connect you can find it on the Apple App
Store or the Google Play Store just
search for it here is an overview of the
specs I'll point out a couple of the
major ones the IP rating is ip67 this
means that it is rugged for outdoor use
I've got a couple on the roof for the
apogee building and they've been snowed
on it's the end of January now they've
been up there for months and they're
doing fine let's see the weight is only
52 grams so this would be great for
mounting on a drone if you wanted to fly
it around and take aerial measurements
the data storage capacity is almost half
a million data points and the battery
life ought to be long one or two years
based on this 10 second sampling
interval or 60 second sampling interval
with an average of five minutes of daily
connected time that battery life will be
dependent on
amount of time that you're connected
with your phone the Bluetooth
communication requires more power than
just the logging let's see the last
thing on this so I'll point out is the
ADC the analog to digital converter
resolution this is 24 bits so that's 2
raise of the 24th power a number of
intervals across the two and a half volt
measurement range which is negative one
and a quarter volt one and a quarter
volt and so that's very fine resolution
measurements you can distinguish very
fine changes in the voltage value from
the sensors oh one more thing I'll point
out a 2/3 double-a is what it runs on so
there's a little unusual battery size
but you can find it online and battery
stores it's not too hard to find and it
just looks like a double-a battery but
it's a little bit a little bit shorter
so it is a great solution for spot
measurements we're talking about the in
particular the par application now spot
spot measurements logging ppfd values
this is photosynthetic photon flux
density that value that's expressed in
units of micro moles per meter squared
per second of light within the 400 to
700 nanometer wavelength for plants and
calculating D Li and photo periods D Li
is the daily light integral this is just
the the summation of all those ppfd
values over the course of a day and the
photo period is how many hours over the
last 24 has the light been above a
threshold and you can set a custom
threshold in here by default it chooses
half a micro mall which is quite dark
and then these two graphics just show
the concept of D Li across the across
the country per month so this is just
from from Sun but of course if you're
growing indoors electric lights will
also contribute to your D Li situation
and on the right this is a document that
you can link to on our website it came
through the univer to University's
Extension Office and it highlights the
the DOI values for a whole lot of
different species so with our device
with this might with this micro cache
logger you can
precisely measure your light levels for
optimum the optimum level for your
plants and the optimum photo period for
your plants okay here's an overview of
the screens in the app just briefly the
overview screen gives you a look at all
this all the micro caches you've been
connected to and so you can you can be
connected to as many micro caches as you
have with the app in this screenshot
just one of them is connected and you
can see it's got a value of eighteen
point four micromoles per meter squared
per second the other ones aren't
connected but if they were you'd also
see live readings from those the logging
setup screen you get to this by clicking
on a little gear icon this will allow
you to set up your logging and family
sampling intervals and the fastest
sampling you can do is one second
sampling of course that'll drain your
battery a little faster in this case
looks like we have it set to 10-second
sampling in one minute logging in this
screenshot one minute logging is still
quite fast you could log every 10
minutes or 15 minutes still get a real
good idea of your light levels through
the course of the day let's see this
live meter display you can go to live
meter mode and then this graph will
update every second with new values as
you you can walk around and put it under
this light under that light and and be
able to see precisely the light levels
on this mode you can also do a manual
data collection so there's a button a
little lower on this screenshot where
you can push the button and it'll time
stamp give a date and time in your micro
molar value and those will be there the
next time you open the app as well then
over here on the far right side of the
screen this is after you've downloaded
log data you can take a look at what's
been going on over the course of the
previous days or weeks that you haven't
been attending to your sensor perhaps
and in this case I've pulled a fast one
a little bit this graph is not just from
an SQ 500 which is what this blue-headed
sensor is but this one's from a new
sensor that we have the par 4 sensor so
this has two diodes one measures the
and the other diode measures far red
light which is also important for plant
photosynthesis and morphology or shape
and so on this graph you can see there's
there's the green curves each day that
is the par level and then the far red
light is is expressed with the red line
and those are smaller values but anyway
you can get both values from this new
par forest sensor on the far right
screengrab you see the daily light
integral and so this is the value I was
talking about previously that's just the
summation of all those ppfd values over
the course of the day it's expressed in
moles per meter squared per day and then
you can also see your photo period which
is a number of hours over whatever dark
threshold you've set and so those are
the kind of summaries you can get from
collecting log data off of your par
sensor with the micro cache or from your
par far sensor with your micro cache I
think I mentioned this before but we do
have two cable links the approximately
one foot or 30 centimeter length which
is the default length from for all of
our sensors before it gets to that
little connector but for coral
enthusiasts or underwater users we do
have a two meter cable length that you
can order and I could just give you a
little bit more leeway to put the sensor
down in the water
I wouldn't go dunk in the micro cache in
water but it'd probably be fine for a
brief dunk but I wouldn't put it down
under for long and then this just shows
how it connects to our brackets it's got
that quarter twenty threaded hole in the
back and so it's it's pretty easy to
mount it's got some grooves on here you
could use zip ties to connect it to
things oh and then our web page our
product web page you can go to our web
site Apogee instruments comm you click
on products up here and you'll be able
to quickly see micro cache Bluetooth
logger and you get to this webpage and
there's more information and and and
things you can see and there's the URL
for you I think that's the end of the
slides that I have and so now I'll
switch over to HDMI to
get this phone connected so we can show
off the the sensor or the functionality
of the app let's see screen mirroring
here we go okay Apogee connect is this
app with the logo kind of looks like a
planet green colored and so we click on
that here's the Apogee connect kind of
general screen so on this phone there's
been a lot of sensors have been
connected in the past a lot of different
micro caches each micro cache is
uniquely identified by its serial number
here in this screen that makes it a
little easier to know which one you're
connected to the one I've got here is
surround lumber ten ten eighty five and
I don't think that's connected yet and
so to connect we just push the big green
button on here for two seconds or so
three seconds and this little LED will
start flashing that means it's
advertising now we click on this plus
button up here to add a new device it
searches for the device it quickly finds
it's called micro cache 1085 this is the
default name it gets at the factory so
you just tap on that and it gets
connected in this case this SQ 500 is
the correct sensor but if it wasn't you
could just click on choose model and you
can scroll through and choose the model
that you want I'll hit cancel because it
was correct you could enter a custom
calibration but of course this one just
has a standard factory calibration so
we'll leave it alone but if you wanted
to you could enter a new calibration
number then in there to multiply your
millivolt value and get a a calibrated
value so we'll just we could rename it
here or whatever we want but we'll just
leave it micro cached n85 for now now
this thing that we just added should be
at the bottom of the list here it is
with the current micro mold reading so
tap on that and now we get to kind of
the more well this the micro cache
specific display and we get a we get an
instantaneous update of the make of the
micro molar volume if we cover this
sensor up should drop to zero a little
bit of noise around zero
but that's what it's at and if we
uncovered it comes back to that
approximately 5 micro more value in here
let's see I will show off let's see the
loot the live meter Mon let's click on
that and this will give a graph it's
updated every second and so right now
it's just gonna Bop around approximately
5 micro moles if we were to cover this
up I'll drop down to zero uncover it
will go back to approximately 5 we would
have pointed at the lights in here it'll
go up a little bit if we were to get it
closer to lights it'll go up even more
and if we were outside in the Sun of
course it would be much higher than what
we're seeing in him here but you can see
they can get instantaneous live meter
mode graphical results right there if
you click on View data there's your data
every second for what we've been doing
let's go back down here these are the
manual data collection values I'll clear
this table it must have been from before
but if we hit record current value you
get a timestamp date/time micromo value
and so you can walk around and take
values by clicking this record current
value button and the next time you open
the app those will still be in there you
can you can export the data well you can
look at the data and then you click this
little sharing icon up in the top right
and you can select the app you want to
email it to yourself or send it to your
computer in some other way
and I'll give you a CSV VAT a CSV file
oh I think it's a semicolon separated
file but a tabular data file that you
can use okay so that's the light meter
mode let's see I think we already went
over settings I went over it on the on
the static screenshot but here's the
settings you can adjust logging and
sampling intervals you could turn
logging on and off if it's on its using
up the battery so if you want to save
your battery just make sure you turn log
off in the settings even if you unscrew
this even if you unscrew this the micro
cash is still logging it's just logging
noise it's not logging anything good and
so it'll eventually eat up its battery
so you want to turn logging off if
you're gonna store this for an extended
period of time
to reconnect it there's a little notch
on this and so you just kind of well you
just kind of twist it until it falls
into place and then you you know finger
tighten it you don't have to tighten it
too much and then it's good to go
okay what else water correction you turn
this on when you take measurements under
water the light kind of bounces off the
sensor and so the scent more than it
does in the air and so the sensor reads
inaccurately low but we've characterized
that on this model it reads thirty-two
percent low and so if you put this
correction on here it'll boost the
values back up to the correct values for
underwater measurements but we're not
doing that so I'll leave that off some
other settings in here including this
dark threshold that'll help define the
photo period down at the bottom you get
some information about the serial number
of your micro cache and the hardware and
firmware versions and the current time
your time on the micro cache over the
course of weeks and months might be off
by a couple seconds and so you can
always go match current time in this
case I think I matched it very recently
so it's still very accurate let's see
now let's show you how to collect some
logs currently there's just two logs
available for connect collection so it
was about 20 minutes ago my last
collected that logs off this device but
we could do that and so we'll just
create a new data set it's called new
data set for it's not going to be very
interesting but we'll hit collect logs
boom we got them I don't even know if
they display if there's only two of them
but more interesting more interestingly
if there were more than two in there
we'd see a graph but let's go collect
logs will get create new and now it'll
be new data set five and what you can do
I know this one has been logging data
for about since early December and so on
this start time
going to hit start time and I'm gonna
kind of roll back the clock by about
four days to January 26th and I'm gonna
set that as my start time here's my end
time right now
January 30th from the late afternoon so
I hit collect logs oh there's my two
data points they finally showed up it's
very exciting data set
regardless here's our new logs coming in
there were about 500 of them and now
they're all collected and now our
display updates now we're looking at new
data set five if we wanted to go back we
could hit switch data set and we could
look at new data set four which was our
boring data set of two data points we
don't want that we'll switch back to new
data set five which we just collected
which is these four days of data and you
can see that there's a diurnal pattern
as the as the lights come on the Sun
comes up and then everything's dark at
night in this case we had an electric
light this was sitting in a window
inside but there was an electric light
on it that was on a timer and so at
night the electric light went off and
the day it was on and then the Sun came
up and so on and I guess I guess the
electric light must not have been on
this day in this day no it wasn't
I remember we disconnected it but anyway
you can view this data you can click on
View data and you'll see each timestamp
date/time micromo value over the every
10 minutes so 10:30 p.m. 10:40 p.m. and
so on and so on over the course of time
that you had data collected and if you
grab this thing on the side and scroll
all the way to the bottom here's the
most recent one that was collected at
4:20 today next graph on this log data
summary is the daily light integral
again this is the the summary of all the
PFD values over a 24-hour period and you
can see that it was inside so we didn't
get real high moles per day but it was
around 3 and a half this day and around
2 Mol's on those days and you can hit
view data and you can see that and if
you wanted to share it you can click on
that share button up in the up in the
top right corner again and finally we
got the photo period now this is a
little fishy because there's
here three bars here that are all around
24 hours per day and we saw that it was
dark on these on these graphs it looks
like it's it's dark at night well I
think there was a little light on over
the course of the night that they kept
the micro more values at around 3:00
where usually they would go down to zero
so what we can do is we hit this setting
gear click on that we go back down to
our dark threshold I'm gonna put in a
value of five this is kind of an
unusually big value but just to show off
this photo period of capability if you
set the the dark threshold to five now
this at this photo period summary
updates rather than 24 hours a day now
it says it's around 12 hours a day
which makes more sense in line with our
our graph here let's see what else do we
have we got through settings live meter
switching data sets I think I think
that's about all of the major
functionalities of the micro kashish
again this little device will interface
with a single Apogee sensor any of our
unamplified analog sensors that produce
little millivolt outputs it's small it's
rugged and and weatherproof and we hope
that a lot of people find a lot of use
out of this so thank you very much for
watching and see you next time
you