I'm Bruce Bugbee, president of Apogee
Instruments and I'd like to in this
next couple minutes introduce Apogee's
new four-component net radiometer to you.
Now this, here it is, this is something
we've been thinking about for 20 years
my whole career I've been thinking
about ways to more accurately measure
and model net radiation and then four
years ago we started a project to build
and improve net radiometer. It's not been
a trivial task but we're excited to
introduce this to the world. So I'm going
to give you about a 30 second review of
how we got to this point. We started
seven or eight years ago
testing all of the net radiometers
available on the market at the time in
the field.
This is a picture of Mark Blonquist the
chief scientist at Apogee out precision
leveling these radiometers cleaning them
all to make sure we have good data to be
sure we had it right we bought
triplicates of each of five types of
instruments to evaluate their accuracy
in the field.
What we found from this was the two
types of net radiometers that could
separately measure the four components
of net radiation were by far the most
accurate and in this picture
they're shown here as the Kipp and Zonen
this is a CNR 1 this is now been
upgraded to the CNR 4 and the Hukseflux,
which is here, and if we look hard
and here you can see triplicates of all
these sensors on this mess. We ran this
all summer long, collected enormous body
of research and concluded if we're going
to do a good job at net radiation we need a
four-component instrument. Now this work was
published here and you can pause this
and get the paper you can get it on the
Apogee website, Accuracy of Net
Radiometers. So what is our instrument
look like?
Here's a picture of it and you might
think this is life-size because these
instruments have historically been big
and after a lot of work we were able to
reduce the size and weight of this
instrument so we're quite proud of being
able to do this because it makes it far
easier to mount and to use. Let's take a
look at what the four components really
mean. In this big picture this little
dome here is for short wave radiation,
which apogee is spent the whole 20 years
of the company precisely measuring
shortwave. So we start with the Sun,
always smiling,
this is short wave in, you also need to
measure shortwave reflected and that's what
this bottom is. These are the two
components of the four. Then we have long
wave radiation from the sky coming in
here, measured here, and long-wave
radiation from the soil here. That's a
four-component net radiometer, four
separate measurements coming out to the
instrument.
Let's take a look at the state-of-the-art
for net radiation, and this is
exemplified by two instruments.
The first one is the Kipp and Zonen CNR 4.
Now it has the same component
shortwave in and out, long wave in and
out and the Hukseflux NRO1
out. These instruments are bigger, heavier,
and more expensive than the newer Apogee
net radiometer. There's two other very
significant differences between the
Hukseflux and the Kipp and Zonen and
the Apogee, because net radiometers have
a lot of outputs they take up a lot of
channels on a data logger. Here's a
classic
CR 1000 data logger, made by Campbell
scientific, if we hook either one of
these instruments up to it we have  a bunch
of wires that look like this. Now
let's look at these wires and where they
go on this this diagram.
These are the analog channels. We have
shortwave radiation that comes into one.
We have shortwave radiation out, this is
incoming this is out, these are two more
channels. Long-wave in two channels,
long-wave out two more channels, now we're
out of channels on the top and we
haven't measured the reference
temperature yet. That is a platinum
resistance thermometer for the reference,
and to make accurate measurements of
that we need to differential channels so
we've consumed most of the analog
channels on this instrument and we still
haven't run
the heater for this to make accurate
measurements that need to be heated. So
now we have h for the heater and that's
two more down here, and 12 volts, and
ground. That's what it takes to connect
one of these instruments to the CR 1000.
Because of that extensive network of
wires and the complexity of users
getting all those hooked up right and
all the calibration factors Apogee went
to an SDI-12 output for this sensor in
which all of the A to D conversion is done
here in the center in the head
what does that look like? One wire with
three subcomponents. Let's take a look at
what where those go. Oops
I'm going the wrong way.
Here's a new version of this, the Apogee
takes up one comport, one
12 volt, and one ground, that's it.
All the calculations are done here and
it still has individual outputs for the
four components. That's a big advance. It
makes the wiring simpler and greatly
enhances the user interface. Now, doesn't
stop there because for precise
measurements you want heated sensors
Apogee has tiny heaters because it's
small the heaters only need to be tiny
to keep frost off of this to keep dew off
of this in the summer accurate
measurements night and day. How's that
look? You already got a little preview of
this when I showed this, but look at this.
There is the heated apogee sensor on one
of our typical winter days, clear as a bell,
excellent measurements.
Oh great, it's a heater doesn't that take
a lot of power?
Let's take a look at the power. The CNR 4,
which requires, here's the CNR 4
here is the heaters and the fans for the
CNR 4 this fits on like this,
how much power does this take, this
combined unit? 6 watts to keep the CNR 4
clear. How about the Hukseflux? This
doesn't have fans but it has heaters in
here to keep frost from forming. The Hukseflux,
which is the NR01 that
comes in at 1.5 watts (roughly drawn to
scale here). What's the Apogee take, this
small thing? 0.74 watts this can easily
be run from a solar panel in the dead
of winter these cannot, without
having an enormous battery and a
big solar panel. So that was another
breakthrough tiny heaters to keep this
free.
Here's another picture of it, frost all
over. This does not have to be heated
that's why this insulating
plastic is in here to heat
just the part that needs to be. So we
worked hard at minimizing that power
consumption of this. So the big advantages
are simpler to use, fewer wires to hook
up, less consumption of all the wires on
your data logger then you can use those other channels
to measure other things with this, much
lower power requirements and a small
footprint so it's easier to mount, and
then finally all of these are four
way net radiometers to get the best
accuracy possible. In our longer video we
talk about measurements and models of
net radiation many people try to model
net radiation from a single measurement
of shortwave, we show in that video and
in the manuscripts that we've published
on that, that the measurements are far
superior to the models. The
best models with the best inputs are
still plus or minus ten percent for the
accuracy and in the world of saving
water plus and minus ten percent is a big
deal. You don't want to overwater
10-percent you don't want to underwater
10-percent. So we've done all this work
to make make this small and
low-power, how's the accuracy compared to
the larger models let's take a look at
that? We ran this instrument for 15
months summer, winter, summer on a weather
station over alpha, you can tell this is
Utah because of all the mountains in
the background, here is the rolls-royce
instruments at CNR 4 mounted right
there on the panel and if you squint you
can see three Apogees on here,
they're small so they had some bird
spikes on here to keep this clean. How's
the data come out after 15 months of
work?
Here's the reference CNR 4, here's the
three replicate Apogees, we were
thrilled to see this tight line here.
If you look closely at this you can see
some scatter the CNR 4 was not heated
and ventilated so there was days with dew,
which caused that to read low so some of
these data in here are caused by
problems with the reference not by the
Apogees. These high radiation days where
there was no dew all three
replicate instruments lined up
beautifully.
That's what we've done to make this
accurate for the user is refine and
refine and refine not only is it good
out-of-the-box it's stable over many
years.
Thanks for listening we are excited to
get this in your hands for future
measurements help you make more accurate
measurements.
We've already had numerous instruments
out with with users in many places and
all the reports are terrific, and people
have been excited to know when became
available.
We hope you can purchase one soon.