I'm going to talk about net radiation specifically the four components and
then selection among sensors. Bruce will talk a bit about radiation frost and
non-destructive measurements of leaf chlorophyll, and then I'll talk about
hyper spectral reflectance. If we get that far and if people are interested, we
can speak a bit about soil oxygen and barometric pressure. We'll just see
where we're at after we get to the end of the reflectance stuff. As
long as interest is still there, people's eyes are open at that point. Alright so
as before if you have any questions please feel free to ask, I don't have
that many slides this time I might make use of the of the board. A lot of
what we've covered already when we talked about pyrometers and infrared
radiometers relates directly to net radiometers, the instruments that we use
to measure net radiation. We won't talk maybe as much about principles of
sensors in the in the net radiation section.
Net radiation is just the difference between incoming radiation at the
surface and outgoing radiation at the surface. There are both short wave
and long ways components that we have to consider. I passed out a magnet if you
don't have one there's more down here and you're free to take one. It has the
exact same picture that you that you see right here. These are typical values of
the four different components that make up net radiation this would be
representative of a clear summer day over vegetation near solar noon so when
the Sun is in the middle of the sky.  The largest component of net radiation
is the incoming shortwave component, 1000 watts per meter squared is a reasonable
value for midday in the summertime. Then the vegetation or soil whatever is at
the surface in the summertime usually its vegetation, is a good absorber of
shortwave radiation so a much smaller amount is being reflected about 200
watts per meter squared is a good estimate for vegetation. The
difference between these two the incoming shortwave minus the outgoing
shortwave is net shortwave so we have a positive value of 800 watts per meter
squared, net shortwave at the surface. A term that you're probably all familiar
with is albedo. That's the the broadband shortwave reflectivity.
Essentially it's just the ratio of these two numbers in our example would be 200
divided by 1000. It's the reflected shortwave divided by the incoming shortwave that would be
0.2 or 20 %. That's a really reasonable value for for green
vegetation when the Sun is in the middle of the sky.
Now we switch over to the long-wave slide. We also have an incoming longwave
component and an emitted longwave component. If the sky is cloud free,
and a lot of you are just outside with me pointing infrared sensors up and
measuring the sky was quite cold, but we found that the clouds were a bit warmer
than the blue sky. The sky is emitting longwave radiation towards the
surface and the surface is emitting longwave radiation back towards the sky.
The reason the incoming radiation from the sky is lower than the emitted
radiation from the surface is the sky is colder than the ground surface. At least it
typically always is in them in the summertime especially if the sky is
clear. If it's cloudy, they can be pretty close and these numbers can be a lot
closer. If we were to actually take the measurements that we are making
outside, I think a lot of us were seeing like -20 or -30 Celsius for
the sky temperature that we were measuring with those infrared sensors,
and we put that temperature in the Stefan Boltzmann equation, let me just
write that over here on the board it was in an earlier slide but just to remind
everyone.
Energy is equal to a constant that we use is sigma multiplied by the absolute temperature
raised to the fourth power. If we were to take one of our measurements outside,
we'll just say the blue sky was negative 30 Celsius and we were to plug it into this
equation we would get a number that's a lot lower than 300 watts per meter
squared. The reason why is those infrared radiometers we were using outside
they're only measuring the wavelengths between 8 and 14 micron. You remember
from the infrared presentation that I gave this morning when we're trying to
measure temperature we have to have sensors to have a filter over them that
only gives us 8 to 14 micron because that's the atmospheric window where the
sensor can effectively see through the atmosphere to the surface that we're
trying to measure the temperature of. When we're trying to measure net
radiation we don't want the 8 to 14 micron filter on our longwave
radiation sensors because we're trying to measure all of the radiation
coming from either the atmosphere or the land surface. We're not that interested
in the temperature in other words and we  we don't want to see
through the atmosphere and measure the cold temperature we want to actually
capture the radiation coming from the air molecules and the clouds and
everything in in the air. Longwave sensors don't have an 8 to 14
micron sensor on them like the infrared temperature sensor does. That's why
if we were to plug in - 30 Celsius here we wouldn't get 300 watts
per meter squared. I can't remember what -30 Celsius is when we plug into
the Stefan Boltzmann equation, but it's a lot closer to like 150 or 200 watts per
meter squared. With that being said, the sky we're
talking about all of the long-wave wavelengths, the sky is still colder than
the ground surface and so there's less longwave coming in from the sky
than what's being emitted from the surface. In this example, the net longwave
radiation is - 150 watts per meter squared. Net radiation then
is just the sum of these two numbers net shortwave plus net longwave gives
us net radiation that's 650 watts per meter squared. Essentially that's
what our equation here says. The symbol we use for shortwave is shortwave (SW)
and then subscript "I" for incoming subscript "O" for outgoing. The symbol for longwave
is LW same subscript. Any ideas of what these values will look like for
the winter over snow? Everybody has the magnet but don't cheat.
Exactly right so you're going to get a lot greater reflectance here because
it's snow on the surface instead of vegetation. The albedo of snow is often
around 0.7 or 0.8 if the snow is kind of old and dirty or like
0.8 to even 0.9 if the snow is fresh, it's really
reflective. How does this one change? We know there's going to be greater
reflected radiation but how does this one change in the winter?
Yeah but you're cheating you've got the magnet. No I'm kidding. It's okay.
We all know that the seasons change right and the reason the seasons change
is because the sun angles get much lower in the winter versus summer.  This
number gets a lot lower just because the Sun is at a much lower angle, it's winter.
If this guy is lower, we have less overall shortwave coming in, but we have
a much larger reflected component because they have snow on the surface.
What about these two how does a change in wintertime? Remember these ones are
dependent on temperatures. Exactly it's colder in the winter than it is in
the summer. The sky gets a little bit colder and this number gets smaller
but not a lot. The surface actually gets a lot colder so this number gets quite a
bit smaller. Now if we look at, and everybody has has the magnet, reasonable
values for the middle of the winter in the middle of the day over a
snow-covered surface incoming shortwave is only about 40 % of what it
is in the summer, 400 watts per meter squared. The reflected component is a lot
bigger because the the snow has a high albedo. Somebody that can do math in
their head what's 350 divided by 400. That's about 0.85 roughly, I think. Yeah,
0.875 is right. The albedo in this example is almost ninety percent that's
a high reflectivity then you can see the incoming longwave from the sky does go
down a little bit but not as much as the outgoing longwave from the surface.
Essentially in the wintertime the sky temperature and the surface temperature
are closer to the same value and they're both cold. Our net shortwave here is
positive 50 our net longwave there is negative 50 and so the net radiation is
actually 0 in this example. This is
true of the middle of the winter. What about at night, what happens?
Essentially the yellow arrows and the yellow numbers go away and we only have
longwave at night. If we only have longwave at night, that means net
radiation is a negative number at night, and that's why it cools off a lot at
night. The surface is now losing energy to the atmosphere rather than gaining
energy as in the day.
The reason that we are interested in measuring net radiation is it's a
major driver of surface processes. I kind of have just explained one heating and
cooling but another one is evapotranspiration. In many cases net
radiation is the biggest driver or the biggest contributor to
evapotranspiration. Vapor pressure deficit, which Bruce talked about a lot
this morning is another one of the major drivers of evapotranspiration.
There's lots of reasons that net radiation could be applicable especially
in environmental and ecological studies Here's a slide showing the
surface energy balance and here's a simple surface energy balance equation.
Net radiation is a major component. We won't consider the radiation terms in
too much detail; they were on the previous slide. You've got incoming
shortwave streams and then outgoing, the reflected shortwave stream, and longwave
radiation coming from clouds and sky whatever is in the sky that has a
temperature is going to be admitting long wave radiation towards the surface
and then plants and soil whatever's at the surface is going to be emitting
radiation back towards the sky. The G term is the soil heat flux; the
flux of energy into the ground. The H term is the sensible heat flux; the heat
gain or loss due to conduction convection. It usually is heat loss
during the day because often the surface is warmer than the air but not always
the surface can be colder than the air so there can be a sensible heat flux
towards the surface. Then the LE term is the latent heat loss, which is the
combination of evaporation and transpiration. There are other terms
like photosynthesis would be a small contributor and there can be heat
storage in the plants themselves typically heat storage doesn't happen in
crops but can in forests. We just defined those.
Here's the real point the available energy and we call the difference
between net radiation and soil heat flux as available energy because that's
everything that's available to do things like evaporate water or heat the surface
for example. We often find when we make measurements of all of these terms like
at eddy covariance sites for example when we can measure sensible heat flux
and latent heat flux with gas analyzers and sonic anemometers we often find that
the available energy is not balanced by the heat fluxes, at many measurements
sites.  It should be the energy coming in should equal the energy going
out. The the real point is net radiation measurements have to be
accurate for surface energy balance studies. O'll talk a
bit about net radiometers and I'll also talk a little bit about net radiation
modeling. Earlier we were talking about how many routine weather stations that we
have like weather networks. They're going to have a pyrometer on there to measure
the incoming shortwave radiation, but a lot of times they don't have any other
radiometers. When we are talking about photosynthetic radiation earlier
weather stations typically don't have PAR sensors on them
to measure the photosynthetically active radiation. They often don't have a
net radiometer on there to measure net radiation. You can model net
radiation from incoming shortwave radiation and I'll talk about that in
addition to measurements of net radiation with net radiometers.
There are four kinds of net radiometers and I'll start with the most
complex and then I'll move to the simplest. Most of the time you don't
see too many of the intermediate types of net radiometers. Usually there's four
component instruments, which are the most complex and they're quite common, or
there's single component instruments which are the simplest and they're quite
common. A four-component net radiometer has an individual sensor for measuring
the four components that we just described. You've got an upward
looking pyranometer that measures the incoming shortwave. You've got a downward
looking pyranometer that measures the reflected shortwave. You've got an upward
looking pyrgeometer that measures the incoming longwave. You've got a
downwards looking pyrgeometer that measures that emitted longwave.
Pyranometer is the name of the sensor for shortwave radiation measurements; pyrgeometer,
kind of a funny word, is the name of the sensor for measuring the
longwave radiation. They're very similar instruments. Both of them consist
of a thermopile detector. Bruce talked about thermopile pyranometers
earlier today, essentially it's a device that measures the heat difference
across the top surface and the bottom
surface of the plate. Then over top of the thermopile
there's a blackbody absorber. The blackbody is just used to absorb all of
the incident radiation on it. Then pyranometers have a glass dome over top of
the thermopile and blackbody detector. The reason for the glass dome is two-fold:
one is to give it accurate cosine or angular response, and the other is to
block all of the longwave radiation. For a pyranometer, we're only interested in
the shortwave wavelengths. The glass is only transmissive to shortwave radiation
so we have to put a glass dome over top of the blackbody so that it blocks the
longwave, lets the shortwave through; therefore, the blackbody will only
absorb the short wave and the thermopile will only measure the
shortwave radiation. The downward looking pyrometer is the same thing it's
just inverted. It is one of them that's mounted upside down. The pyrgeometer is very similar
the only difference is instead of having a glass dome it has a silicon dome over
top of the blackbody. I know what I've drawn here doesn't look like a dome
shape, sometimes the pyrgeometers will have a small dome shape other times
it'll just be a flat surface so it's actually a silicon window rather than a
dome. The reason that we use a silicon dome is because it blocks the shortwave
radiation and transmits the longwave radiation. A pyrgeometer is
designed to measure  longwave. We have to block the shortwave and allow only
the longwave through so that the blackbody absorber can absorb it and the
thermopile can measure it. Here again you've got one up, one down to
measure the short and longwave. Examples of this type of net radiometer
are the Hukseflux that's a Dutch company and Kipp and Zonen, also a
Dutch company. They both build four component instruments that work very
well. I'll show you some pictures in a minute. Apogee Instruments also builds
one. I don't really have a good demo to show you but I will pass this around so
you can see what an instrument actually looks like. This sensor here with the
the white diffuser on the top is the upward looking pyranometer. I know I just
said they typically have glass domes, this one doesn't have a glass dome it
has an acrylic diffuser, which is also transmissive to the shortwave wavelengths.
The bottom pyranometer is a glass window that's this one. Then the two pyrgeometers
have black, flat black, windows that are made of silicon. They look the same up
and down. You're welcome to have a look.
Question: What is the price of these?
Mark: The Hukseflux
is probably, these numbers are going to be in US dollars I don't
know what they would be an Australian dollars.
I  gues Ican say the price. Peter is the one who sells it in Australia but the US list
price is about $2,500, but you will also have to
pay for importation and stuff like that. This Kipp and Zonen us is about
$6000 I think, maybe a little higher because it comes with a
heater and ventilator on it.  The Hukselfux  unit is closer to $5000. I think
it's between 4500 and 5000 US dollars that gives you an
idea of the price tag of these sensors. In a minute I will compare in a
relative sense, I'll compare the price of all of the above because we're going to
put four more or three more pictures like this one on the slide here.
The next type is a net all wave radiometer and this one is the simplest version. You
basically have one thermopile and it's sandwiched between two blackbody
absorbers, one on top and one on bottom, and there's two polyethylene domes over
top of the absorbers. What you have is a thermo-pile that's just outputting
a signal that's proportional to the temperature difference between the top
surface and the bottom surface. That temperature difference between the top
surface and the bottom surface is dependent on the radiation incident on
the top and the radiation incident on the bottom. The reason this is called a
net all wave radiometer is that it's measuring each surface, the upward
looking surface and the downward looking surface, are measuring all of the
wavelengths at the same time. It is sensitive to shortwave and longwave
together. Polyethylene actually transmits shortwave
and longwave. The reason for the polyethylene domes is just to
basically be a weather barrier and keep rain and moisture and dust and dirt off
of the blackbody surface. Not all of them have, not all of these net all wave
radiometers, have polyethylene domes. Probably the most common one at
least historically is this Rebs. Rebs stands for radiation and energy balance
system model Q*7.1. That's an american-made instrument from the state
of Washington. They were used a lot especially in past decades. Now it seems
like the Kipp and Zonen NR Lite 2 is the most common type of these net all
wave radiometers. The Rebs has the polyethylene domes the Kipp and Zonen
NR Lite 2 does not. The real challenge of polyethylene domes
is they are flimsy and you have to keep them pressurized often in order for
them to not collapse. At the same time polyethylene is better at transmitting
shortwave than it is at transmitting longwave and so when you get different
proportions of longwave and shortwave say clear sky versus cloudy sky for
example or over vegetation versus over snow it can really influence the
accuracy. The polyethylene domes all they can keep it clean and free of water
they also have their challenges. They have to be replaced quite often
because their flimsy, birds like to peck holes in them. The Kipp and Zonen
NR Lite in doing away with the polyethylene domes they get around at
least part of the problem of the domes but at the same time
when the surfaces get wet the radiation balance goes way out of whack and they
don't yield accurate measurements until they're dry. These ones while they're
the simplest and the cheapest also are the most prone to errors. We just talked
about prices for all of these. These guys are probably 1500 to 2000 dollars US,
somewhere in that range. I won't spend nearly as much time on these two
intermediate types just because this is the only example of this type of
two component instrument that I'm aware of and it's no longer available.
Essentially it worked a lot like this one where you have a single
thermopile that is measuring the net difference between what's coming in and
what's coming out. It's just that we separate shortwave and longwave.  We
actually have two components one of them is measuring net shortwave the other
ones measuring net longwave. This was a nice instrument when it was available
but it didn't last very long on the market. The other type is also kind of
like that one but rather than being a net device that only gives you one
signal that's proportional to the difference between all of the incoming
radiation and all of the outgoing radiation is that they separate the
pirradiometer so you've got two of them. You've got an upward looking one that's
sensitive to both the incoming shortwave and the incoming longwave, and then
a downward looking one that's sensitive to both the outgoing shortwave and the
outgoing longwave. So a good example of this one
is the Phillip Shane model 8111 it is a European instrument I believe it comes from
Germany maybe Switzerland, I can't remember for sure. This one is
not a very widely used instrument predominantly you'll see this or that
one. I said I had some pictures here's what they all look like the Hukseflux and
the Kipp and Zonen and the Apogee that I passed around the room is in the middle.
The major advantages of a four-component net radiometer is that
you get an individual measurement of each one of the four components.
That's a major advantage because typically that gives you higher accuracy.
I say potentially here because four individual sensors also means you've got
four components that might cause problems, like if one of them isn't
calibrated correctly that can be a problem or you've got four of them that
might get dirty for example. Then we already talked about price, these tend to
be higher cost. Just one design feature that I will mention with regards
to the Apogee is that it has an SDI-12 output. We get around this need
for all of those datalogger channels. What this means is in the center
box here on the Apogee unit, there's a circuit board in there; all the outputs
from the individual radiometers are being measured by the analog to digital
converter on that internal circuit board and then we're just digitizing those
signals and outputting an SDI-12 measurements. You can plug it
into a digital, one single digital channel, on your dataloggerr and not
have to tie up all of the analog channels to get a measurement.
If we look at the net all wave radiometers here's the two examples that
I listed in the previous slide, there's the polyethylene domes and that one is the
domeless model. Again these domes, they're better transmitting shortwave
than they are a longwave, which can lead to errors. They don't always stay
inflated. If they get a hole in them, they will get water condensing on the inside causes problems.
The domes need to be replaced periodically. This one because they're domeless
they're exposed to the environment to get wet and dirty.
The main advantages here are it only requires one datalogger channel to make
a measurment. Remember it is a single detector where the signal it is outputting is
proportional to the differences of everything thing that is comming in and everything that is
going out so it requires one analog measurement. These do tend to be smaller and
lighter weight so they can be easier to mount level. Again we already
talked about price; they tend to be lower cost. The major disadvantages
they have fragile domes and they're domeless. This domeless guy requires a
wind speed correction because if the winds blowing over top of it it can
change the energy balance. If you have mismatched detectors that can be a big
problem, essentially what that means is you only have a single sensor and you've
got one detector surface on the top side of that sensor or thermopile and one
detector surface on the bottom side of that thermopile. They have to have the
same sensitivity to shortwave and longwave, and they have to have the same
sensitivity to each other. Otherwise they're only accurate for the conditions
that they're calibrated to, if the conditions are changing like they do in
a dynamic environment then the mismatch detectors so the upward sensitivity
doesn't match the downward sensitivity can lead to errors. They tend to be
higher maintenance for example you have to replace the domes and all of the
above combined lead to lower accuracy. This was just a summary slide and I'll
mention that a few years ago before Apogee started building net radiometers
we were interested in potentially selling net radiometers from other
companies and we did a extensive field study where we compared several
different models of net radiometers for part of the growing season over a
uniform turf grass field in Logan Utah. The citation to our work is here if
you're interested in getting the paper again shoot me an email and I will send
you a PDF. The major findings were that the four component net radiometers
did indeed provide the most accurate measurements but I put an if in here you
have to make sure that the radiometer is level and you want to make sure that the
individual sensors are clean. The net all wave radiometers were the simplest but
they did have lower accuracy and it was due to lower sensitivity to longwave
radiation. The last line I think is important; we found that net radiometers
were capable of measuring radiation with better accuracy than what is often reported
in the literature. There's quite a few studies out there like energy balance
studies especially at flux tower sites that indicate net radiation uncertainty is
like 10 or 20 %. I think if you're measuring it with a
four-component net radiometer that's well leveled and clean then the
uncertainty is probably lower than what's usually reported in the
literature for net radiation measurements. Any questions about measuring net
radiation? I'll just take a minute I don't have any slides for this but I
think I can make use of the board. I might not even need to make use of the
board. I think I can just explain it. Tor those of you that are interested in
modeling net radiation, again we can talk afterwards or you can send me a
follow-up email and I can give you more detail but for those cases when you
have weather data and you need net radiation but the weather data did
not include a net radiometer to measure the net radiation you can model it. The
most important component that you need is a measurement of the incoming
shortwave radiation from a pyranometer. If you're looking at your fridge magnet or
if you remember my first slide, usually the largest
component of net radiation is the incoming shortwave component from the
Sun so if you have that measurement you have at least a reasonable idea of net
radiation and you can model the other components. Typically how it's done is
then to take a published value of albedo for the surface that you're measuring.
If it's vegetation it's going to be pretty low around 0.2 to 0.25,
if it's snow it's going to be quite a bit higher. Published values of
albedo are fairly accurate if the surface conditions don't change
dramatically. If you're trying to do this when the vegetation is always green,
just estimating or taking a published value of the albedo and calculating the
reflected shortwave component that way works pretty well. The challenge is if
you're trying to do this over the course of say a whole year when you might have
you know snow or bare soil in the  winter time and then the crops start to
come up and you have green vegetation and soil mixture and then the crops fill
in and you only have green vegetation for most of the growing season and
then the crops nest and they turn yellow and then you harvest them. I mean
the surface can be quite dynamic over the course of a whole year. You can
only use values of albedo if you know what it is for the surface or have a
good estimate of it and if it's not changing significantly. If the
surface is changing a lot then you have to change the albedo in your model.
Tthe way that longwave is often estimated is from measurements of air
temperature and relative humidity and then we we can predict longwave pretty
well from equations like this. This is the Stefan Boltzmann equation and emitted
energy is proportional to a constant times the fourth power of
temperature. If we know reasonably well what the the fourth
power of temperature is for the surface, then we can estimate a longwave
relatively well, the components being emitted because we know that most
surfaces are blackbodies, most land surfaces are blackbodies. If we are working
with plant canopies or soil or snow, the emissivity right there in the equation
this number is going to be close to one. If we have a reasonable estimate of
the surface temperature, we can estimate the emitted longwave components so the
part that's going from the ground to the atmosphere from this equation. To
estimate the incoming longwave component we use the exact same equation
and oftentimes we use the air temperature as a proxy for
the sky temperature. The challenge with doing incoming longwave radiation
estimates is this number is the hard one and you were asking about that earlier.
There are ways to estimate the emissivity for the atmosphere and that's
where the humidity measurement comes in. It's usually empirical equations that
estimate atmospheric emissivity based on sometimes  theare temperature but
typically the vapor pressure of the atmosphere. The error can be
kind of high because atmospheric emissivity is not always that dependent
on the vapor pressure near the surface. The vapor pressure that we
measure at the surface typically comes from a relative humidity probe that
might be two meters off the ground but the longwave radiation coming from the
sky is coming from the whole depth of atmosphere from two meters above the
ground till way up in the atmosphere. If the near-surface vapor pressure is a
reasonable tstament of the whole column of water in the atmosphere, then
empirically estimating atmospheric emissivity from near surface vapor
pressure works okay. If the near-surface vapor pressure is not a good estimator
of the whole column of water in the atmosphere, then the empirical equations
don't work that well. There are ways to model net radiation if it's not
available, but I would recommend measuring it if you have the equipment
to do so. Iif you're interested in learning more about how to model
net radiation please send me an email I can help with that. There's quite a bit
of information in the literature that's been published. There's a really good
study from about 2007 I think, maybe 2009, where some folks at USDA in the United
States compared a whole bunch of different incoming longwave radiation
models and assessed the accuracy relative to measurements. Any questions? I believe
that's all I have for net radiation.