[Music]
are you responsible for a Weather
Network a big Network a really big
Network we know you have citizens
agencies farmers and scientists that
depend on you and your precipitation
Network for Reliable accurate data are
you looking to upgrade your
precipitation gauges to a gauge that can
more accurately monitor solid
precipitation like snow and hail but
worry about the high prices of weighing
precipitation gauges are you looking for
a more cap a more accurate more robust
but also cost effective former
precipitation measurement then we have
something for you introducing the apogee
Cloud burst the cloud burst is a
weighing precipitation gauge designed to
measure all forms of precipitation
including Rain snow hail and grapple the
cloud burst features are rugged
all-weather housing with a black ionized
Inlet that naturally sheds snow and
resists capping the inlet comes in two
sizes both with optional heating
elements there are no moving parts to
get overwhelmed clogged or seized the
cloud burst provides you with both
filtered and raw data assembled and
shipped from the US the cloud burst has
been designed to be cost-effective in
both implementation and maintenance the
cloud burst maintenance is quick simple
and toolfree with a large capacity
system maintenance intervals are reduced
meaning less hassle and less labor in
the field after 8 years of development
with several beta testers the Cloud
burst has been designed to meet your
needs and has proven to meet the highest
of
Standards this is the ape Cloud burst an
excellent solution for your
precipitation monitoring needs no matter
what weather to learn more about the
cloudburst visit apog instruments.com
the cloudburst is assembled and shipped
from the
[Music]
USA