[Music]
because now we're talking about not
radiation or wind or reflectance but a
measurement of gases in the air and
particularly oxygen and this is so
powerful because gases are used to
measure metabolic rates of bacteria of
plants of people and particularly of
course oxygen and co2 we measure
photosynthesis with by measuring co2
changes but oxygen also changes and
oxygen sensors are far cheaper than co2
sensors so we have four sometimes sold
this oxygen sensor and this is a picture
of what it looks like buried in soils
one of the common applications putting
it in soil to measure soil gas
concentration obviously if a plant is
growing and it's healthy and it's
consuming oxygen in the soil the oxygen
goes down in the soil so number one we
want to understand how low that is but
number two the rate at which it goes
down helps us tell the respiration rate
of the root system of the plant which
tells us something about health of the
plant so it's both to monitor oxygen and
to do metabolic rate studies this sensor
fundamentally it's a galvanic cell
sensor so it causes a chemical reaction
with the oxygen gas which creates a tiny
voltage and it's measured by a data
logger so that's the general physics of
the signal transduction of this
changing of the gas it has a screen on
the end I don't know if we have a oxygen
sensor here Peter do you know if we have
an oxygen sensor here we could pass one
around that's a and it that helps keep
the water away from the sensing tip but
also to measure a bigger volume of soil
these are a few hundred dollars I mean I
can't remember the exact price but
they're not thousands so that means
they're much more accessible to many
more people to have multiple sensors I
think I have a couple example pictures
of this and then I want to talk about
how they work here's one application in
the lab we've used this quite a bit in
my lab there's a petri dish sealed the
tip drill it drill a tiny hole put the
sensor in there and we're measuring the
change in oxygen in this petri dish
which is an indication of the metabolic
rate of these seats at real sensitive of
this there's another one in a jar drill
a hole put the sensor in the top now in
this jar there's no respiration going on
it's clear water it's not it's
metabolically inert but if we run the
temperature up and down we would like to
get zeros in that jar and all kinds of
things are changing that humidity in the
jar is changing which dilutes the oxygen
but we want to make the appropriate
correction factors so we can get a clean
zero in a jar where the really isn't any
respiration so this is a laboratory use
of this but it also has a similar uses
in the field just a review I'd love to
show this equation this is the health
students this is the most important
equation in the world to a biologist
this is respiration going this way and
photosynthesis going this way and if we
can measure the rate of oxygen depletion
or the rate of co2 build-up we know the
metabolic rate and that's as simple as
that
one mole of oxygen disappearing
one mole of carbon has been metabolized
in respiration so we can precisely
calculate metabolism and you can do that
with either oxygen or co2 first up
background of oxygen is much higher
there's a this is a picture of it with
the meter and the sensor on the end so
now to come full circle and the very
first talk I talked about relative and
absolute humidity that's a water vapor
in air that same principle applies to
all the gases in air we have relative
measurements which are listed here and
we have absolute units listed on the
other side relative not surprisingly its
percent the same is exact concept is
relative humidity we can call that mole
fraction the pressure of oxygen divided
by total pressure parts per million
another measure the same thing but in
this case in the case of humidity the
sensors measure relative units and we
calculated absolute units in this case
the sensor is measuring the absolute
units and we convert to relative units
but these Conte's units are exactly the
same the moles or mass of the gas per
unit volume so let me go through a
couple of examples of how this affects
us now this all comes from what we all
learned in even high school chemistry PV
equals NRT pressure and volume equals
the moles times ideal gas constant times
absolute temperature and if you're
making these measurements you get good
at making those conversions so you can
calculate metabolic rate here's the
sensors respond to absolute and
recalibrate and
two parametric pressure affects the
concentration of gas in the air it's
easy to measure pressure and easy to
measure it electronically I'm not going
to talk about her sensor but it easy to
measure it if the pressure changes and
gets higher pressure that gas gets more
dense and you conclude that there's
respiration but there's not it's it's a
change in pressure here's a great way to
show it
elevation barometric pressure is the red
line as we go up the top of Mount
Everest and the unit over here is
concentration of gas now there's another
test question so we know virtually
everybody needs compressed oxygen to
climb Mount Everest what's the percent
the percent oxygen at sea level is
twenty point nine five percent what's
the percent oxygen on the top of Mount
Everest it's exactly the same so if it's
just twenty point nine percent why we
need oxygen well low pressure the
density of oxygen molecules is way less
and that's an example of the correction
for pressure so when we're measuring
this we often measure pressure with it
so we can correct for differences in
pressure and sort out metabolism from
everything else pressure doesn't change
that much high pressure front slow
pressure fronts this is a high altitude
pressure but still pressure from highs
to lows only changes the density of gas
air about one percent and maybe two
percent on extreme events so our our
pressures even though they have a huge
effect on our weather only have a small
effect on the density of gas but we
measure and correct for that so now we
put this sensor in soil and we want to
measure the changes in oxygen and soil
soil is very close to a hundred percent
humidity all the time because it's all
these wet surfaces all
in equilibrium with the gas what happens
if you put a sensor in soil like this
it's got it it's a tiny gore-tex
membrane that's gas permeable but it
doesn't let water into the sensor if you
put that in soil and you just leave it
sooner or later it gets condensation on
the membrane because 100 percent
humidity and the soil temperature is
cycling well the sensor stops working
that's the membrane is got water on it
gas can't come in so we heat the sensor
just a little bit just 1 degree C above
background and that prevents
condensation it's not enough to change
the metabolism but it is enough to keep
the condensation off the sensor the
other factors recent water vapors a big
deal is water vapor is maybe three
percent of the molecules in the air but
as the humidity and temperature go up
and down the oxygen gets diluted these
water vapor molecules come in and again
it's apparent respiration only because
of dilution of the gas and I won't go
through all the details of this but it
you have to correct for the temperature
of the soil to get the absolute oxygen
concentration and this is happening in
the background in software the of the
sensor to sort out what fraction of the
change in signal is true metabolism by
plant roots and what fraction is just a
parent caused by changes in the gas
composition obviously if this thing in
air and it gave us a 21% and then we put
it in a hundred percent humidity it
starts to read lower because of all the
oxygen and all the water vapor molecules
diluting the oxygen molecules
there it is same thing and that's how we
do this test and the corrections for it
and finally the third thing is
temperature PV NRT this is absolute
Kelvin temperature but as the
temperature goes up and down and also
changes the density of the air and the
oxygen in the air that's then there's a
temperature effect on electronics of the
sensor we had a correct floor and then
gas liquid partitioning the amount of
gas and solution and the mount in the
air and here's enough the temperature
and the parent change in reading this is
at 19 to 22 degrees it's a big effect of
temperature and this is also the this
written red line is the effect on the
electronics and fortunately it's pretty
flat in here from about 15 to 35 C but a
hot and cold temperatures we need to
correct for temperature temperature
affects almost every single sensor we
have that there's hardly any sensor that
doesn't have some temperature
interaction and we're always measuring
those and correcting for them and
software or trying to build sensors that
are so robust they have a minimal
temperature effect
and now couple slides since the final
slides I'm going to close with it people
have suggested sensors we might build
and as a company we're constantly
thinking of what's our next sensor we're
gonna work on and what how do we decide
what kind of sensors to work on well
I'll tell you it's no it's not brain
surgery how many we gonna sell how many
people would buy a sensor like this if
we build it if it's 10 we probably won't
build the sensor if it's a hundred then
we decide how much R&amp;D will it take to
make the first one and it's a ratio of
investment costs for Rd to the number
sold and when that gets favorable we
decide to work on the sensor but it's
also how much Rd will it take that I
don't know mark come along we've been
working on that net radiometer I mean we
we got it yeah we got a lot of money
invested in making the first one and so
we're just now getting them on the on
the market so you hold your breath as a
company and hope people will buy the
stuff that you build otherwise you're
gonna be out of business
here's here's a sensor that we're
looking at we've done some preliminary
testing and I could make a joke and say
don't tell our competitors about this
but even if you told them they'd say
well that's a hard sensor to build we're
not going to make it because it's too
much of a risk they there's a lot of R&amp;D
if we can make a sensor in soil that
both measures carbon dioxide and oxygen
together we can get what's called
respiratory quotient and that tells us
what materials are being metabolized by
the bacteria in the soils and I'll give
you some examples of respiratory
quotient but here's an example of a
bucket and some oxygen sensors and a co2
sensor so remember that equation that I
might have that yeah there's our
equation
this is when this goes that way this is
one that's one that means the
respiratory quotient is one but what if
the bacteria were metabolizing lignin
and now lignin is ch2 with hardly any
oxygen or fats fats hardly have any
oxygen substrates change in the ratio of
C h2o and that changes the ratio of co2
and oxygen and with such a sensor we can
tell what's being metabolized in the
soil here's a couple there's a
background this is the advantage of
measuring co2 they're so little in the
background it's easy to measure a change
I mean this is just point oh four
percent co2 in the air we can easily
measure change this is a huge background
so it's hard to measure tiny changes in
oxygen it's easy to measure tiny changes
in co2 anytime we do these metabolic
measurements we have bicarbonate effects
and that's a whole other lecture which
I'm not going to talk about but co2 goes
in and out of solution and it's not
metabolism and we've got it correct for
that and then oxygen is also the sensors
much lower cost although we're working
with some co2 sensors now that are we
think they're going to be done around
300 dollars back to do this or cost us
co2 sensors is coming down so this would
normally be one-to-one but look at this
this is this respiratory quotient
carbohydrates one proteins point eight
fat's point six and lignin point two so
we could begin to start to see what's
being degraded what type of material is
being degraded if we can develop this
sensor so we we think this would sell a
lot and
it's it's one we're slowly working
toward to develop there so there's
people that there's that windy windy
silver every year how does that sensor
coming along she's really anxious to buy
him as soon as you announce it here's
another huge deal we know that we put
ammonium on and even in an ecosystem the
degradation makes ammonium and the
bacteria gradually oxidized this to
nitrate this respiratory quotient uses
two oxygen it doesn't make any oxygen
it's zero so we can begin to tell what
forms of nitrogen the bacteria are
utilizing in a soil so sometimes we
don't like to say what we're working on
people get so excited they want to
happen in next year and it's way down
the road and we have a big problem as
our company and others of wouldn't you
say when a sensor is going to be ready
because people get anxious to buy it and
it sometimes it you think it's going to
be ready next month and it still takes
six more months it you keep you keep
working on refining the technologies but
this is this is one that's in the early
idea stages so that's one of my favorite
slides but I'm gonna conclude with that
I hope this gets you excited about
making more measurements with more kinds
of sensors it's it's a it's a joy to
collect data and and you get you know
how the world is supposed to work and
then you try and measure it and see if
it really works like that and linking
back to those very first quotes I showed
if theory and measurement don't agree
you've got a red light and eat that but
an amazing thing is the theory is wrong
sometimes and your measurements are
rock-solid and and you can get a Nobel
Prize for turnover turning some things
we thought we knew that we really don't
know so well and after all that's what
re
search is re searching take stuff we
thought we knew and see if we really
know it and a lot of that's a huge
danger of if we think we know something
and we're pretty sure we know it and
we're wrong that's one of the worst
problems of all of science and with
measurements getting better and better
and better we can revisit some things
that we thought we knew so hope you get
an opportunity to use these instruments
and and in your research and hear all
your endeavors and we look forward to
the potential of working for you
[Music]