This is the Apogee Instruments Oxygen sensor
and unlike most of our sensors
this sensor is user calibrated.
We don't know exactly where
you plan on using your sensor
so in order to get the most accurate results
we have you the customer calibrate this sensor.
But don't worry I'll walk you through the steps.
Now calibrating the oxygen sensor can be as simple
or a little more involved
depending on the level of accuracy that you need.
I'm gonna show you how to get good
better and best results with your oxygen sensor
and if you stick to the end
I'm gonna show
you a tip for getting high humidity measurements
like in soil.
Now there are two key steps to getting accurate
oxygen measurements.
First we're gonna talk about calibrating the sensor,
both the standalone sensor and an handheld meter,
and then we'll talk about correcting those test measurements
to get your final measurement.
This is where things can get a little more complicated
depending on your level of need.
All these instructions and formulas
can be found in the Apogee Instruments
Oxygen Sensor user manual.
Alright, let's get started.
For the stand alone sensor
you're gonna need a few things.
You'll need your oxygen sensor.
A multimeter or a data logger.
A calibration spreadsheet.
Which is available at ApogeeInstruments.com
or by clicking the description below
or there should be a link right here.
Lastly you're gonna need your calibration locations
altitude or pressure, humidity and temperature.
These are
typically available from your local weather station.
Your calibration should be performed outdoors
in an open air environment near your test site.
It needs to be calibrated outside.
Whether you're at sea level or on top of Mount Everest
the oxygen concentration will be the same.
It's always gonna be 20.95%.
As soon as you go inside
that oxygen concentration number can begin to vary.
Make sure that as you're calibrating the sensor
you also do an environment that doesn't have wind.
Wind running across the port
can cause different pressure changes
making your calibration off.
So make sure you're outside
in a location that's not windy.
Okay, now we're gonna calibrate our standalone sensor.
First we'll make sure that the sensor is upright
or that the measuring port is pointing down.
By pointing the sensor down
it gives us the strongest signal
the least amount of noise.
Then we'll take our multimeter
and measured the black and the white wires.
We wanna make sure that the black
and the wires don't touch,
because as the oxygen sensor is taking measurements
it produces a signal
which could cause problems and short things out
if they were to touch.
We'll clip on it both of these wires
and after a couple seconds
you should see that
the voltage will start to level out.
As we wait for a second
you'll see it's kind of hovering around
45.1, 45.0  even. This is the number that we wanna remember.
We're gonna use that and plug it into the spreadsheet.
But before we do,
we're gonna calibrate the handheld meter.
To calibrate the handheld meter
we want to do the same thing.
Make sure that it's pointing down.
We'll turn on the meter.
We'll press the mode button twice.
You'll see "Run" start to flash
and then we'll press the sample
and the mode button at the same time.
You'll then see the screen flash "CAL" as it's calibrating.
Then it'll be done and it's ready to go.
You can calibrate the meter as often as necessary.
Just make sure that you're outside when you do it.
That's the most important part.
Alright now,
let's go back inside
and plug that mill of volt number into the spreadsheet
and get our calibration factor.
Now that we have that value
let's open up the spreadsheet.
As always
you can check in description below for that link.
First, we'll select our sensor model.
If you notice that things aren't working
make sure you enable editing.
Enter that recorded voltage.
Then enter the calibration locations temperature
humidity and elevation.
Then at the bottom
it will give you that multiplier and the offset.
You can use this sample info
section to make environmental corrections
to data points that you had previously taken.
Your sensor is now calibrated
and now you have a basic linear equation
to begin taking measurement
of relative oxygen concentration.
This will provide good
relative oxygen concentration data.
Now for better data. If you
take the sensor outside and measure the oxygen outside
you should see a straight line
because it's always gonna be 20.95.
The problem is if you actually did that
you start to see these waves start to occur.
That's gonna come from the barometric pressure.
The concentration is still 20.95%
the difference is the amount of air is changing.
So we need to account for the barometric pressure.
If you use equation like this,
it's going to include the barometric pressure
and then it's gonna calibrate it
so that way you don't have these swings.
Humidity and temperature
are going to put some noise into your readings
so if you want the best data
then in your measurements
you need to include these equations
so that way you can offset the temperature
the humidity and the meriometric pressure
if you account for those and barometric pressure
then you're gonna have the best data
if you plan on taking measurements in a high humidity
environment such as soil
then it's ideal to calibrate the sensor
in a location where the relative humidity is also 100%
a simple way to do this is by mounting the sensor
in a sealed chamber over water
with ambient air filling the headspace
first we're gonna create my little chamber here
let's go inside I'll show you how to make that chamber
we're gonna make a high humidity
calibration chamber for our oxygen sensor
in the end the sensor is gonna mount to the top
of the container
and kind of be mounted and oriented vertically
where we will fill this with some sort of humid
material and then we will do the calibration
so we'll do is we'll just take the lid off this guy
we'll take a little ceiling lock nut
that goes with that oxygen sensor
we'll trace the inside of it
and we'll know that we just need to make the hole
slightly larger than that
so very carefully we'll cut this hole out
make sure you don't hurt yourself
cause that would be bad as always
let's get start together
we wanna make sure this hole is as close to round as we
can because we don't want air pressure to get out
or humidity to get out or air pressure
I guess air pressure getting in isn't too bad if we're outside
but really
we just wanna keep that humidity as high as we can
get it so we will cut this center part out
and there's always a chance that we might have to go
and make it a little bit bigger test fit the sensor
yeah that'll work so it's nice
it's tight but we want to be tight so take that
put our sealing ring above that
then we'll screw
the nut on top of that
so really we should have a good
a good connection between the oxygen sensor
and our high humidity
chamber
now you've made that chamber
we just need to create that humid environment
so what I'm gonna do is
I'm gonna put some warm water in this container
I put some tip paper towels in it
so that it doesn't swash around so much
you don't want water coming in contact
with the sensor itself so I used paper towels
you can use a sponge
and then I've gotten some warm water
you can also just leave water out in the sun
it just has to be a warm environment
and then
we just wanna make sure that the air pressure is
equalized between the sky and our container
we'll close this on top
and then we'll wait for just a few minutes
for the humidity to build up in it
once the humidity has built up
we're gonna do the same thing as we did before
we're gonna connect our voltage meter
and read that voltage between the white and the black
wait for a few seconds for that voltage to settle
we're gonna do the same thing as we did before
but this is gonna be the number that we're gonna use
just wanna make sure that you calibrate it
in environment that's high humidity
as close to 100% as you can get
just make sure that as you're sealing it
that you're outside when you seal it that way
the air pressures are equal
and it has that 20.95% in the container
when you close it
there you have it
you should have all the information that you
need to take high quality
oxygen concentration measurements
for any more questions
please refer to the sensors user manual
or contact the support team at Apogee Instruments
also leave any questions that you might have
in the comment section below
thank you so much for watching and happy measuring