At Apogee we sell a lot of PAR meters
and finding the right one
can feel a little bit overwhelming.
Stick around
and we'll help you find the perfect PAR meter
for your needs.
A quick refresher for those who might not know,
quantum meters measure light.
To make it simple,
imagine that the light coming from the sun is like rain
falling from the clouds.
Our meters are like uncovering a sheet of paper
out in the rain for 1 second
and then counting the number of drops.
Counting drops is essentially what a quantum meter does
but instead of rain they count photons of light.
A PAR meter measures the amount of light
but only in the light spectrum
that promotes photosynthesis.
The light in this range
is called photosynthetically active radiation
this PAR wavelength spectrum
is between 400 and 700 nanometers.
Knowing this PAR information
can be vital in growing and studying plants.
It's similar to how we use calories
when studying the growth of humans.
Using other measurements like Lux or foot candles
fall short because
Lux and foot candles determine the amount of light
that the human eye can see
and the human eye
see some color of lights better than others.
The human eye is more sensitive to colors like green
than we are to red this is because our eyes use a rod
and cone vision system.
Unlike humans plants see all the colors  in that spectrum evenly.
So if you graph the
photosynthetic response of plants to light
it would look something like this.
So if we want to measure light
according to a plant sensitivity
a perfect meter would produce a response curve
that would look identical to that PAR curve.
With that understanding,
you have the knowledge that you need
to understand the variation
in the sensors that we offer.
At Apogee we produce three versions of quantum
or specifically PAR sensors.
The first is the Original X
then the Full Spectrum and last the ePAR sensor.
The Original X is the least expensive sensor we make
and it features a response curve that looks like this.
As you can see this response curve is not ideal
in that it overestimates the blues and the greens
while underestimating the reds.
It also captures a significant amount of UV light.
At first glance
it might not seem like a close match to this
PAR spectrum but with the over
and the under estimations being accounted for
it's not bad in terms of accuracy.
At Apogee Instruments we take pride in being a low cost
high science provider of measurement tools.
The high science PARt refers to the fact that
although the
inexpensive sensors might not be the most accurate,
we know exactly where and why they're not accurate
and with those shortcomings
we can use calculations to correct the data
and make that sensor sufficiently accurate
for a much lower price point.
Because the sensor tends to overestimate the blues
and the greens while underestimating the reds
it does not work so well for LEDs.
But we do have two broad spectrum calibration options.
One of those options is for sunlight
and the other is for electric lights,
like a T5 or a high pressure sodium.
This is a great lower cost option
if you're specifically measuring either sunlight
or these electric lights.
Our next sensor is the Full Spectrum sensor
and this is the response curve of the Full Spectrum sensor
as you can see
the response curve on the Full Spectrum
much more closely follows the PAR curve.
It also catches a little bit of UV
and kind of under response
a little bit on the blue but overall it's really good.
A sensor that can obtain a perfect PAR response
is impossible to achieve.
And you can spend significantly more amount of effort
and time
which equals money chasing marginal accuracy returns.
This sensor is an excellent balance
between accuracy and cost.
Another benefit of this level response curve
is that the sensor is accurate
under all lighting conditions.
From sunlight to LEDs
to high pressure sodiums or T5s.
However,
the accuracy of this sensor does come at a higher price
than the original X.
All right one more type of sensor.
In recent years
there has been increasing evidence that far red light
found in the 700 to 750 range of the light spectrum
can contribute to plant growth
especially in plant leaf size and general
plant morphology.
This extended range has been given the term ePAR
or extended PAR and we have a Full Spectrum sensor
that includes this additional portion of the spectrum.
This is what the response curve looks like.
Alright, now
we've gone over
the quantum sensors that we have available
let me show you what formats we have these sensors in.
We have the handheld.
We have the DLI.
And then we have sensor only options.
Let's look at the handheld meters first.
The handheld meters are perfect for spot checking
and automatic logging of data.
It's a complete solution
that requires no additional hardware
or other components to operate.
The handheld meter allows for a sensor
that can be submerged, not the meter but the head can
and we have several underwater models
that have correction factors applied
for taking measurements underwater.
Like in an aquarium.
With all handheld quantum meters
you have the ability to access the DLI data
using the optional AC100 communication cable.
Using the Apogee Connect software
you can access all the saved data
in addition to the DLI measurements.
The next meter format we have is the DLI meter.
If a handheld meter is like
counting drops on a piece of paper,
DLI is like a bucket.
Rather than measuring light as specific moment
the DLI is collecting data
through the course of the day.
In math an intergal is a term
referring to the area under a curve.
So the Daily Light Intergal
is the amount of light during a 24 hour period
and is expressed in a term called moles
per meter squared per day.
In addition to the DLI reading
the DLI meter gives you instant PAR readings
and the previous days photo period.
Photo period is the amount of time the light was on
in the last 24 hours.
When the DLI is connected to computer,
with the included USB C cable,
you can access the data set
with 99 days of DLI and photoperiod data
as well as the last seven days of PAR data
with averages over 30 minute intervals.
In summary the DLI meter is perfect for collecting
DLI measurements,
photo period measurements, and doing spot checks of PAR.
It's perfect for outdoor use.
The sensor is resistant to falling rain
but you don't wanna submerge it.
The last sensor format
we have is the sensor only option.
This is ideal
for situations where you already have a system
or a method of collecting data.
We have a lot of options to match
whatever protocol your system uses.
So on our sensors we have various outputs.
We have analog and we have digital.
In our analog options
we have a 0 to 40 milah volt option,
which is our unappplified option
and it's capable of connecting with an Apogee Microcache.
The Apogee Microcache
enables app connectivity with Bluetooth connections
from your phone using the app that's available.
From the app
you can view data and adjust logging intervals.
We also have a 0 to 2.5 volt,
A 0 to 5 volts,
and a 4 to 20 million amp option available as well.
In our digital outputs we have an SDI 12 output,
a Modbus output, and a USB connection output.
The USB option
allows you to connect the sensor to a desktop computer
using the Apogee Connect app.
You can view and collect the data
and adjust your logging Parameters.
The sensor then can be disconnected from the computer
and then powered by a USB charger
where it can then collect data on its own.
If you're looking for the least expensive option
this is your best choice,
but it does require a computer
and takes a bit more time
and it's not quite as convenient.
With the various sensor output options
we have several cable lengths including no cable,
30 centimeter, and 2 meter.
We can even do custom lengths upon request.
In addition to our standard range of sensors
we have several specialized sensors,
like the light pollution sensor
which has a higher sensitivity
to a wider spectrum range
but will overrange around 200 micro moles
per meter squared. We also have an array sensor
that will take an average reading of multiple sensors.
Along with the various types of sensors
we have lots of mounts leveling plates
and other accessories for all of our sensors.
Hopefully now
you should have a better understanding
of what types of PAR
sensors we offer.
If you still feel a little lost or have more questions
feel free to call in
and talk to our amazing customer support team.
They can help you answer your questions
and help you find the best sensor for your project.
Do you wanna learn more about ePAR
and how the additional range of light effect plant growth?
Consider watching this video by
our founder Bruce Bugby.
As always,
thank you so much for watching and have a great day.