we teach all our students hybrid vigor
and this if this was some kind of
comprehensive exam we would ask you to
define exactly what it is that's hybrid
vigor and we like to think that by
merging plants and soils and climate we
get hybrid vigor in our department and
as you learn in plant science 101 that
is hybrid vigor is just diversity of
genes mixed all together where the
outcome is better than you would ever
expect from the sum of the component
parts and with that idea we are
fortunate to have funds for invited
speakers in our department and when they
come from another place they bring us
hybrid vigor and insights to things that
we might not have come up with by
ourselves
so today we are honored to have mark van
ear sole talk about his work he was at
that University and the Netherlands that
people spend their whole careers trying
to pronounce the University tonight vaga
ningún and that was the subject of a
National Geographic cover story I think
not long ago the Netherlands feed the
world and Mark is a product of that
University he came here for PhD with a
guy named Eric rooster house who was a
personal friend of mine and he did such
an outstanding job that we were able to
get him here as a postdoc and it's about
18 years ago or something a long time
ago and he then went to the University
of Georgia and he recently got an
endowed chair at Georgia which gives him
more money to work with he's brought a
lot of diverse expertise to the study of
plant physiology and particularly plant
physiology and controlled environments
using them to study
things that are much broader than the
controlled environment themselves so you
can see what he's gonna talk to us about
today
professor hips is pretty excited to hear
about cannabis research with this then
so please welcome mark the nurse'll
[Applause]
thank you Bruce and I'll pleb on this
mic and so Bruce talks about hybrid Vega
I might refer to it slightly as
inbreeding given that I'm coming back to
the University where I did my postdoc I
had a great time here slightly longer
than 18 years ago and I my former PhD
student Shu young in the back is the new
postdoc in Bruce's lab so more not so
much hybrid vigorous not just selecting
elite lines at this point so I've worked
in controlled environment agriculture
for a long time and really focus now on
specifically lighting and controlled
environment agriculture is a vague term
so when I talk about that I'm basically
talking about greenhouses and vertical
farms and when I started on this project
about five years ago I was initially
really focused more on vertical farms
than on greenhouses because in vertical
farms all of the light that you need to
grow your crop has to be provided from
some kind of an electrical light and why
does that matter why is that such a big
deal well and this is a really dense
engineering report developed by the
German Aerospace Center and so they did
a hypothetical design of what it would
take to build a massive vertical farm 37
floors high and probably given that a
determine engineer sway over engineered
in many aspects but it would probably
run flawlessly they didn't get the money
to actually build this but they looked
at what it would take to build this land
they looked at construction cost as well
as operating cost and when they did
analysis of what it would take to
operate this it turned out that power to
run this building was 60% of annual cost
and of that power about half of that so
30% of the overall operating cost is
needed to just run the lights those
lights are going to produce heat and so
the over 30% is pretty much all air
conditioning and that air conditioning
is needed to remove the heat that you
get from the lights and it is needed to
remove water vapor from the air because
all of these plants are producing water
so it's a massive amount of money so can
we reduce how much energy it actually
takes to grow these plants but as I was
thinking about this more and more I came
to realize greenhouses are actually a
much more interesting of challenging
system to burger Bergin so this is a
greenhouse just outside of Charlotte
North Carolina and look at the light
environment that these plants are
growing under it's a mess right so how
do you manage light in a greenhouse well
things are constantly changing they are
spatially clearly highly variable in
this case largely because of the very
large amount of hanging baskets that are
growing but so it's actually much more
complicated to manage lighting in
greenhouse compared to a vertical form
any greenhouse you obviously have
temporal variability to so this is just
light data from one day in the winter in
our greenhouse and even on a sunny day
like we have here at some point during
the day like here and here
you got shading just from the overhead
structure of your greenhouse so things
are highly dynamic in a greenhouse which
makes it really different from vertical
forms and so in the greenhouse industry
we typically just integrate the total
amount of light that you get over the
course of a day we call that the daily
light integral and so for growing
different crops we typically make
recommendations that are based on the
daily light integral this crop needs a
integral of Y and so this is 14 years
worth of data from Canal University
where a monitor daily line integral
every single day and you can see that
recessional differences in daily line
integral but even in the middle of
summer in Canal you can have a daily
light integral as low as maybe six moles
per square meter per day and this high
as 70 most the square meter per day so
again lots of variability so how do you
manage that how do you grow a crop when
you don't know what the light is going
to be and so can now focus a lot on
lettuce research for many years they've
worked on that and after years of
studies what they found out is that the
one cultivar of lettuce that I actually
studied it does best if you give it a
daily line integral of 717 Moore's
prescribed meter per day and what that
means is that for every dot that you see
below this red line you need to provide
supplemental lighting anytime you get
above that red line you need to provide
shading and I'm not that interested in
shading I'm more interested in the
lighting part which you can see on how
many days you actually would need to
provide supplemental light to reach that
target of 17 moles so why does this
matter in the greenhouse industry so if
you look at a typical greenhouse that is
using supplemental lighting they might
have 500 400 watt high pressure sodium
lights per hectare of greenhouse and
they may run them for 14 hours a day
let's just assume that they paid 10
cents a kilowatt hour it turns out that
they pay two hundred and eighty dollars
per hectare for they just an electricity
to run their lights now if they run the
lights for half the year they spent
$50,000 per hectare just on electricity
so that's a good amount of money then in
a recent Department of Energy report
they estimated the total cost of
providing lighting in controlled
environment
culture and that 600 million dollars a
year in the United States so that's a
lot of money if we can reduce that by 10
percent that's 60 million dollars right
that's almost real money so this is a
map that shows the daily lighter
integral in different parts of the
United States and different times of the
year
developed by Jim fast it was now at
Clemson University not surprisingly you
have big changes over the course of the
year and how much light you can expect
to get and this map was initially
developed to try to get some idea of how
much of what crops cook can you grow
where what time of the year
how much supplemental light might you
need to provide but this makes it spell
pretty difficult to actually figure out
for a particular crop how much light do
I need to get in addition to sunlight so
in the last two months I worked with two
colleagues at Cornell to develop a
different kind of a map and so what we
did let's let's assume that we are going
to grow lettuce and we want to make sure
that every single day of the year we
have a daily line integral of 17 moles
of photons per square meter per day we
have a supplemental lighting system that
can provide an instantaneous for the
synthetic photon flux of 200 micro moles
per square meter per second and so using
typical weather data from around the U
as we calculated the number of hours on
the y-axis here of supplemental light
that you need to provide to grow in this
example lattice and we can easily run
this for for whatever crop you're
interested in and not surprisingly in
the southwest you don't need a lot of
supplemental light
likewise in florid I'm not much but
there are big differences in how much
light you need in different parts of the
country and it makes it difficult to
come up with general guidelines for is
it actually cost-effective to install a
supplemental lighting system so along
with an agricultural economist at the
University of Georgia we try to estimate
the return on investment of installing a
lighting system and we did that for two
locations so we use Athens Georgia
because that's where we live and then we
use Seattle Washington and you can
probably guess why we picked Seattle as
the other place it is
well if supplemental lighting is going
to pay anywhere it is probably going to
be in Seattle and they don't get much
light so in Seattle if you provide
supplemental lighting to lettuce you can
expect to get an additional five point
three crops a year by by providing that
light and on a per hectare basis that
means and that you are going to gross
two hundred and eighty three thousand
dollars per year extra now of course the
lighting isn't free so it will take you
about two hundred and twenty thousand
dollars per hectare per year to actually
pay for the lighting and that includes
both installation and operating cost of
the lighting system but so net you have
an additional sixty three thousand
dollars per hectare per year and profits
so that's a pretty nice amount so in the
place like Seattle yes this is probably
going to be a really good investment
when you look at Georgia Athens Georgia
the situation is different so you may
get two point three extra crops a year
which grosses you another one hundred
and twenty three thousand dollars but
it's going to cost one hundred and
twenty thousand
dollars so you might expect $3,000 an
extra profit from installing a lighting
system and that is probably not going to
be worth the investment and so what we
are really interested in is trying to
help growers make these decisions based
on the local climatic conditions of
whether one or the discussed effective
for them to actually install that
lighting but so I'm a physiologist not
an economist I know nothing about
economics other than that I know that
growers make decisions based on expected
return on investment but so my part of
this is to try to make sure that we
provide supplemental lighting in the
most efficient way that we can and so
then we start out with a simple question
how do we actually quantify how
efficiently light is being used and so
for that well hopefully we all know that
plants need light for photosynthesis and
it's not exactly new so we have just a
very simplistic diagram where we have
sunlight providing life for the light
reactions creating ATP and nadph the
Calvin cycle then uses that ATP and
NADPH to fix co2 to make carbohydrates
which the plant can then use for growth
and maintenance processes so initially
the light is used right here in the
light reactions of photosynthesis so if
we really want to study that a
physiological level how efficiently
plants use light then this may be a good
starting point and so when light reaches
the chloroplast it is absorbed by
pigment molecules it bounces from one
pigment molecule the energy ultimately
is funneled towards the reaction center
where that light energy is used to
transfer an electron you're essentially
creating a current from light energy and
so this diagram shows the entire light
reactions of photosynthesis where we
have a pretty happy Sun on the top left
and it's going to provide us with a
photon
there it goes and with the energy from
that photon an electron from water
starts moving through the electron
transport chain
they've spots right here because that's
the rate limiting step in the whole
process of the light reactions of
photosynthesis and so as long as this
electron is right here inside of
photosystem 2 for the system to cannot
accept additional light energy so if
there is an order photon that now gets
towards photosystem 2 for the system to
cannot use it from there the electron
moves on and with the help of a second
photon ultimately the electron goes to
NADPH so we are really interested in
this process right here in photosystem 2
and how efficiently photosystem 2 is
using light energy to move electrons so
not all of the light that reaches leaves
is actually used for for the chemistry
or electron transport a lot of the light
energy is actually just converted into
heat and essentially lost that actually
is something that is actively controlled
by plants and a pretty crucial way for
plants to dissipate excess light energy
and then a very small one to two percent
of the absorbed photons are actually
re-emitted in the form of chlorophyll
fluorescence so a plant that you see
anywhere if it is getting light it is
actually giving off light as well you
can't see it because it is so little
light so it's if you have a green laser
pointer and you shine it on a leaf you
can actually see a red glow coming from
the leaf it's pretty neat we're going to
see that so it turns out that
chlorophyll fluorescence is something
that is really easy to measure you just
clamp the sensor here on a leaf of sweet
potato right here and you can measure
how much fluorescence is coming from
that leave and I'm not going to go
through the theory behind fluorescence
but you can calculate lots of things
from chlorophyll fluorescence
measurements and one thing that you can
calculate as the dark adapted or maximum
quantum efficiency of
system - so you do that in plants that
have been in the dark for fifteen to
thirty minutes you can take a
measurement and it gives you an
indication whether or not for the system
- its healthy if for the system - is
damaged that maximum quantum efficiency
the photosystem two decreases and it
indicates that the plans are some kind
of stress what is more interesting is
that you can also measure the intrinsic
quantum efficiency in the light how
efficiently is that leaf using the light
that it is absorbing and so from that we
calculate something that we call Phi ps2
or the quantum yield a photosystem two
and it is the fraction of absorbed light
that is used for photo chemistry and so
when you think about supplemental
lighting we would of course like that to
be high we want plants to use the light
that we give them to use that light for
photo chemistry if we measure the
quantum yield of photosystem two we can
actually calculate the rate of electron
transport through photosystem two using
a pretty simple equation we look at the
efficiency of photosystem two we
multiply that by the amount of light
that is absorbed by the leaf and we
assume typically that leaves absorb
about eighty four percent of the light
that hits them and then we divide that
by two because we need two photons to
move one electron all the way from water
ultimately to NADPH so we can calculate
the electron transport rate pretty
easily and so my graduate student Jeff
Weaver did a relatively simple but
pretty interesting study well about two
years ago now well he just monitored the
photochemical efficiency of ladders
grown in the greenhouse so for 30 days
he was growing lettuce from seedlings to
full-size plants and every 15 minutes he
measured the quantum yield of
photosystem 2 calculated the electron
transport from that and so when he took
all of those data points plotted them
together we see that with an increasing
photosynthetic photon flux the quantum
yield of photosystem 2 decreases so the
more light you give a plant the
as efficiently it's being used there's
nothing new about this this is well
known I think we may be the first ones
who have monitored this over such a long
period so frequently this is not really
what we were after but an important
take-home message here is that the more
light a plant gets the less efficiently
it uses that light we can use these data
to calculate the electron transport rate
and we see an asymptotic increase in
electron transport rate with an increase
in photosynthetic photon flux with an
asymptote of about 130 micro moles of
electrons per square meter per second
and overall I'm actually surprised that
every day we measured a different plant
that when we measure all of these
different plans it still follows that
overall trend pretty nicely so what we
were really interested in was death
graph so on the y-axis we have the daily
photochemical integral that's a term
you've never heard of because we made it
up but what we did very similar to the
daily lighter integral is over the
course of an entire day we integrated
all of the electron transport rates to
get to this daily photochemical integral
how many electrons are moved through
photosystem 2 in one single day and then
we plotted that against the daily light
integral and once again we get this
asymptotic increase and daily for the
chemical integral with an increase in
daily light integral and what was
interesting when we looked at these data
is that when we look at 90% of the
asymptote which is about 3 moles of
electron transport per day and we look
at the daily light integral that we need
Gladys we get a daily light integral of
18 moles per square meter per day so
that's took us 30 days to do come Nell
using four or five years of data on
growing lettuce drew the conclusion that
for lettuce you need 17 moles per square
meter per day so pretty much the same
light level so this correlates really
well with what canal fund so we think
that a daily photochemical integral of
three is a really good target for
growing lettuce plants and different
crops are differently so we did similar
studies using impatience which is a
plant that typically grows in the shade
and so you see the same general decrease
right here with increasing
photosynthetic photon flux and then we
did geraniums which is a high light plan
that you can see that with geraniums the
quantum efficiency or quantum yield the
photosystem 2 is much higher it has a
plant that is adapted to hide light
levels and it can use like more
efficiently in itself not that shocking
when we use the same data to calculate
the electron transport rates you see
that the Sun adapted geraniums can
achieve much higher electron transport
rates than the shade species impatience
so it's just important to keep in mind
that draw big differences among species
this also has some interesting
implications for how you're going to
manage supplemental lighting so let's
say you're a grower and you have lights
and you want to make sure that the light
that you provide to your crop is going
to use it's going to be used with at
least a 60% efficiency well for
impatience that efficiency drops below
60% at a light level of about 150
microvolts per square meter per level a
per second for geranium that efficiency
doesn't drop below 60% or 0.6 till you
get to a light level of about 530 micro
most
square meter per second so that means
that you're white might want to manage
supplemental lighting for these two
different species very differently based
on the physiology of those plants to
show it at a different way for
impatience you wouldn't want to provide
more supplemental light than to reach
this level right here 150 micro moles
per square meter per day well for
geranium you can go up to much higher
light levels and the geraniums can still
use that light that you're giving them
efficiently for the light reactions of
photosynthesis so in conclusion for this
part there are big differences among
species so you should take that into
account when you develop lighting
strategies but the main take-home
message that I want you to remember is
that light is used most efficiently when
PPF or light intensity is low and that
means that you want to provide your
supplemental lighting when there is
little ambient light available and to
illustrate that so this is a light
response curve for electron transport
grade of lattice and so if you add 200
micro moles of supplemental light the
lattice plans that are in the dark right
here you can increase the electron
transport rate by about 60 micro moles
per square meter per second if you have
200 micro moles of sunlight and you add
200 micro moles of supplemental light
you only get an additional 40 micro
moles per square meter per second of
additional electron transport for the
same amount of light that you're giving
and the higher the ambient light level
is less efficiently the crop is going to
be able to use that and so because we
know that plants use light more
efficiently when you provide it at low
light levels we wanted to look at the
effect of photo period on electron
transport and lattice so Claudia Elkins
a new master student in my lab just
finished up a study where what she did
was she provided a certain total amount
of light at certain daily light integral
over a range of different photo periods
ranging from
seven to twenty two hours and she tested
this with two daily light integrals of
15 and 20 moles per square meter per day
so this was known in growth chambers
there is a picture in a minute but we
had a data logger that made sure that we
maintained the light level at a
perfectly stable level over the entire
photo period and then Gloria collected
chlorophyll fluorescence measurements
every 15 minutes over the entire photo
period so this is an example of what
that looked like inside of the growth
chamber with the sensing out of the
chlorophyll for Amida right here and so
when you look at one day worth of data
there is average for a few replications
it looks something like this where
typically early in the day when the
lights just come on the electron
transport rate tends to be pretty low
and then it reaches a steady level after
about 20 minutes or so and there was
actually not a whole lot of change after
that it becomes pretty boring when you
measure this for hours in a row and the
values come out the same every single
time so with these data and what we
could do then once again is calculated
daily for the chemical integral the area
underneath this curve as well but when
we look at them instantaneous quantum
yield and this is actually averaged over
the entire photo period and we plot that
against the photosynthetic photon flux
we see once again just like in the green
eyes that we get a decrease in the
quantum yield of photosystem ii with
higher light levels and so higher light
levels are associated with shorter photo
periods because we had less time to
provide these plants with the same
amount of light and they don't matter
for this relationship right here
if the daily light integral that we
achieved over the entire photo period
was 15 or 20 moles per square meter per
day really big change here in quantum
yield from about 0.68 to about 0.28 at
high light levels so life had a
tremendous effect on the quantity of the
photosystem 2 and so much less efficient
at higher light levels and so we
calculated electron transport rates and
just like we saw in the greenhouse we
got this asymptotic increase in electron
transport rate with increasing
photosynthetic photon flux but what
we've more were more interested in than
the instantaneous values of quantum
yield or electron transport is how do
these treatments affect the daily
photochemical integral how much total
electron transport can we get with a
certain amount of of light that we
provide them so here we have the daily
for the chemical integral as a function
of photo period and so you can think of
for the period here as we go towards
longer photo periods the instantaneous
light level is lower right so all of
these treatments over the course of the
photo period got the same amount of
light and DLI of 15 and keep in mind
this is what we use in the greenhouse
industry to make recommendations for
light levels how much light a crop needs
when we look at the daily for the
chemical integral it goes from about 2.6
to maybe 5.2 with the same amount of
light we get about twice as much
electron transport if we provide that
light over a longer period so what that
means is that not all photons are the
same the longer periods you spread those
photons out over the more efficiently
the plants news lit and the more
electron transport you get and
presumably the more for the synthesis
and the more growth you can get out of
that and the daily light integral of 20
moles per square meter per day the
effect was even more pronounced so the
plants have much more electron transport
with longer photo periods without giving
a more light so the question after we
found this is this is actually matter
from a practical perspective do you get
better growth if you provide the same
amount of light over a longer photo
period because ultimately the growers
that I work with don't seem to care very
much about electron transport through
photosystem 2 I try to avoid that term
and I talk to them
they want to see what impact that has on
growth so in order new graduate student
in my lab Shane Palmer he just finished
up a study looking at the effects of
photo period on the growth and some
physiology of leafy greens produced
inside of a vertical farm like system
and so his basic hypothesis was that
longer photo periods where the lower
photosynthetic photon flux will result
in more biomass faster growth than
shorter photo periods with high
photosynthetic photon flux because
plants can use lower light levels more
efficiently so he worked with mizuna
which is a Brassica is an interesting
plan because it grows unbelievably fast
and he suggested that that we use that
crop it worked previously at Kennedy
Space Center growing mizuna and then we
have lettuce here he also worked with
basil but we don't have those data yet
but we grew to his inside of a
controlled environment chamber walk-in
chamber 20 degrees C co2 enrichment we
used white LEDs and all plants received
a daily light integral of 16 moles per
square meter per day but provided over 6
different photo periods ranging from 10
to 20 hours and so to summarize the
treatments so we have the photo periods
here so we go from 10 to 20 hours and
that meant that the photon
photosynthetic photon flux range from
220 to 444 micromoles per square meter
per day per second to make sure that all
of these plants received the same
mount of light and this graph doesn't
look very good but I haven't had a
chance yet to get my hands on the raw
data but the measured light and
perception by the mizuna over the course
of this study and I just want to draw
your attention to the middle part of
this graph where you can see right here
this teal greenish colored line are the
plants grown under the longest photo
period and the red and blue right here
are the plants grown in the two shortest
photo period so we saw halfway through
the study that the plants grown and the
longer photo periods were intercepting
more of the light and that may suggest
that the plants were bigger it was also
interesting to see that the morphology
of the plants was really different
depending on the photo period because
the plants that were grown in the long
photo period and low instantaneous light
levels they were spreading the leaves
out and they look like solar panels that
were deployed to try to capture as much
light as possible well the plans that
were grown with the short photo periods
and high instantaneous light level they
were like this they didn't want light
they did seem to be avoiding light and
that's not just reflected in the
morphology of the plants when we looked
at chlorophyll levels in this plant and
we just used the non-destructive meter
we didn't do a true quantification but
we have the chlorophyll content index as
a function of photo period so the plants
grown with short for the period
highlight intensity at much less
chlorophyll then plants grown with long
photo periods low light intensity so
that's consistent with the idea that
these plants were trying to capture as
much light energy as they possibly could
and then we measured the quantum yield
of photosystem 2 and we see that with
high light intensity short for the
period the quantum yield is
significantly lower than it is with long
photo periods and low light intensities
but when you look at the differences
between treatment
here and here these differences are much
much smaller than they were in the
previous 30 that was done by Claudia
Elkins that I showed she's so much
bigger effects and that is probably
because these plants were grown
constantly under these different light
levels and they had a chance to
acclimate to the specific light levels
Claudia grew all of her plants on the
wine light level and then exposed them
to a different light level so those
plans weren't a collimated to the
conditions so much smaller effect here
and then he collected driveway data and
we see a general trend towards increased
dry weight and mizuna with longer photo
periods 28% increase that's actually
pretty substantial but it was
unfortunately a lot of variability so it
wasn't quite specifically significant
and so when I was working on this
presentation early last week I looked at
this and I thought well that's a bummer
and so last Friday
Shane weighed the lattice plants for me
so that I could look at those data and
for lettuce we see a smaller absolute
increase but for lettuce we do see a
significant increase in the dry weight
of the plants as we grow them with
longer photo periods and again just want
to be emphasized all of these plans got
the same amount of light so that
suggests that daily light integral in
itself may not be all that useful
there's a predictor of crop growth so
longer photo period resulted in a more
light interception higher quantum yield
the photosystem 2 so combined that means
a lot more electron transport a lot more
light energy harvested and four letters
are significant the fact for mizuna and
closely significant effect on the
biomass of the plant so I actually think
that looks very promising and hopefully
next week we'll have to base the basal
data as well to go with this so this was
indoors and I mentioned earlier I'm
actually getting more and more
interested in greenhouses right because
greenhouses have this dynamic light
environment so Jeff Weaver who I
mentioned previously this spring did a
study where he looked at the effect of
photo
on the growth of greenhouse ground
lettuce and so in history too we wanted
to make sure that all of these plants
got the same daily light integral that
is really easy to do when going in an
indoor environment and you don't have to
worry about the Sun it becomes a lot
more difficult in a greenhouse where you
don't know how much sunlight you're
going to get over the course of the day
so how do we actually make sure that all
of these plants get the same amount of
light by the end of the day with a
highly variable background from minute
to minute and day to day in the amount
of sunlight so we have developed a
lighting control system that can do that
for us in my spare time I like to
pretend that I'm an engineer and I like
to put things together this actually
came out of a class project where I told
the previous graduate student in the lab
David Jeannine oh this is your project
for this class you go build it and so
what we do is we measure the
photosynthetic photon flux density at
the canopy level using a data logger and
then we want to control the amount of
light that we provide using LEDs based
on how much light the crop is actually
receiving so we can use the system to
either make sure that the plans get a
completely stable photosynthetic photon
flux density all day long or we can use
this to make sure that by the end of the
photo period the plants have received a
specific daily light integral and I'll
show you in a few minutes how we
actually do that but the principle is
actually pretty simple so we have a
light and LED light right here we have
the Sun a quantum sensor a data logger
and the dimmable driver and this right
here is the beauty of LEDs you can dim
LEDs very very accurately and
instantaneously and it doesn't affect
the longevity of the LED so in a matter
of microseconds if you want you can
completely change the light output from
LED lights and it is really easy to do I
probably shouldn't tell people that it
is easy I should pretend things is
really difficult but in reality
actually pretty simple so when you have
a certain amount of sunlight the quantum
sensor measures that signal goes to the
data logger and then the data logger
calculates how much supplemental I do we
need to provide from the LED and that
allows us to give a specific amount of
light to the crop so when the Sun there
gets brighter the LEDs automatically dim
and so in this particular study
Jeff grew lettuce green towers and
regular greenhouse trays one week after
the seedlings germinated he spouted two
lighting treatments and grew the plants
for 22 days under supplemental light all
treatments received a daily light
integral of 17 moles per square meter
per day based on the canal
recommendations but they got that light
and for the periods that range from 12
to 21 hours we had a control treatment
that on average received about 8 moles
per square meter per day and I could
have put standard deviations with these
treatments but so the plants in these
treatments that received 17 moles per
square meter today the standard
deviation on 17 moles was I believe 50
micro moles or something like that the
inaccurate that we have in this control
system are much more related to any
inaccuracy that we may have in the light
sensor itself than in our control we
can't control the light perfectly so we
measure the light level every two
seconds because that's the fastest the
data logger can do everything it needs
to do and so every two seconds the data
logger calculates a new lighting
threshold that we want to maintain so by
the end of the day we want to have 17
million micro moles we subtract from
that how much light the crop had already
received so now we know how much more
light needs to be provided over the rest
of the photo period and we divide that
by the amount of time that is left in
the photo period and so now the data
logger need a nose
how much light the crop needs to receive
and it can control the LEDs to make sure
that that happens so this is just a
picture of what that looks like in the
greenness so we have the light sensor
right here light bars donated by fluence
bioengineering this is a picture of the
whole setup at night no plans in this
case Jeff just took this picture to show
that you can see the different amounts
of light that are provided by the LEDs
and the different treatments so this is
a picture near the end of the study of
plants that were grown with 12 and 15
hour photo period so the light level
here in general was higher than here and
I hope you can see that but here too we
saw that the chlorophyll content in
these plants grown under shorter photo
peers and higher light levels were
actually lower than in plants grown with
longer photo peers very similar to what
we saw indoors and so I don't have all
of the data from the study yet but jeff
has the driveway data for this so the
plants that were grown without any
supplemental lighting they looked
absolutely horrible and that drive dry
weight was really really low we weren't
really interested in that treatment it's
just a reference for everything else but
so with supplemental lighting and again
all the same daily light integral we can
see that with longer photo periods there
was an increase in the biomass of this
of these plants and in this case we saw
a 43% increase in biomass just by
providing the supplemental light over
longer photo periods so I'm pretty
about this because that's a very large
growth increase and it has lots of
practical applications for managing
supplemental light so if you have a crop
that is for a period and sensitive you
really should be spreading out the
supplemental light over as long a period
as you can and in some cases you can go
up in many cases you can actually
provide light over 24 hour periods if
you choose to do so the advantage
another advantage of providing lower
instantaneous light levels over longer
periods is that you can install a
smaller lighting system because you
don't need the same power to provide
high levels of instantaneous
light so it actually makes the whole
installation of a lighting system
cheaper if you can spread your light out
over longer photo periods so it's not
just the physiology that makes sense
that actually I think has direct
business implications as well and so I'm
a big believer in this company so
shameless self-promotion I recently
started a company with a friend of mine
and we just got a USDA grant to actually
develop a lighting controller that can
automatically implement these kind of
lighting strategies for you so this is
our prototype control system there is a
light sensor I believe right here and
then I have no idea what the rest of
that stuff is but it works so with this
what you can do using your phone and
bluetooth you can tell the controller
I want this daily light and to grow I
want this photo period and then you walk
away from it and the controller will
actually then take care of managing the
lights for you so overall conclusions of
this longer photo periods have
interesting physiological effects higher
quantum yield greater electron transport
rate over the course of the entire day
so we grade on daily photochemical index
increased light interception because of
morphological responses at least partly
morphological responses to low light but
from a practical perspective that also
results in faster growth so what
were able to do in this series of
studies they're starting with basic
physiological measurements trying to
understand how plants use light in the
light reactions of photosynthesis but
subsequently actually then come up with
practical recommendations and even a
commercial product that came out of this
and that can now implement or take
advantage of the physiological knowledge
in a production setting and with that
I'm going to wrap it up I would like to
thank the companies and agencies that
have funded this mug and I would be glad
to take any questions
[Applause]