I'm  Bruce Bugbee, welcome to the next installment of a series of talks on
principles of environmental measurement. Today we're going to talk about
measurement of surface temperature. It is a very powerful and yet very challenging
measurement. Many people make errors in this measurement. Our goal is to help you
eliminate the errors. I'm joined in this effort by Mark Blonquist, he and I have
worked together for more than 10 years trying to make accurate measurements of
surface temperature. So, you would think you could just take a sensor and put it
on a surface and measure the surface temperature, but lets draw a little diagram
to show the problems with that. Here's the surface, now we take a sensor and put
it on the surface right against it, and this sensor has some wires coming out to
go to a datalogger, but as you can see this part of the sensor is touching the
surface and measuring that.  Over here we have air temperature touching all the rest of
the sensor. So anytime you do this it's a combination of air temperature and
surface temperature. Now this measurement gets better if you can get a very tiny
sensor, it's better, but it's still not the true surface temperature. It's always
an average and then people dig holes and puncture and put sensors in here and do
things like that. Now you're measuring the surface, plus the
temperature behind the surface, so anytime you try and do this with a
physical sensor you can never get the true surface temperature. That's why we
use infrared sensors, and on this diagram I can draw a sensor like this which
measure all only the true radiation coming right from the surface, whether
it's a soil surface, leaf surface, or a road surface it's the true
surface temperature. Let's take a look at some of the applications of this. The
biggest use of Apogee sensors has been in agriculture for canopy stomatal
conductance or irrigation scheduling of plants here's a couple of examples in
the field. Here's the sensor pointing at a corn canopy. Here's one sensor over a
small plant. This has allowed us to precision irrigate crops and determined
the water status of plants, precision water stressed plants, by measuring the
canopy surface this principle is real simple anything thats out of water heats up
if there's plenty of water
you stay cool. We've joked about having a headband and a little
infrared sensor pointed at your forehead for runners to tell when they need
to drink more water, if
their foreheads heating up they need more water. It's the same thing with plants, so this
is a huge application. Another application is predicting snow melt.
Here's high in the mountains the surface temperature changes rapidly, we want to
know how fast that snow is melting and running down for agriculture this is a
huge area of research worldwide because tiny changes in global temperature mean
that the snow melts a lot faster and we get the water earlier and we run out at the
end of the summer. We really need to predict snow melt, and there's many
scientists around the world engaged in this. A third application is transportation,
icy road analysis. This is in Italy here's an Apogee sensor off the corner
of their truck, telling them when to put salt down. It's a real-time response telling
them to put salt down. You can also use these on a bridge. Danger ice on
bridge, and that's determined by the temperature of the bridge. So just a couple
of applications. Now let's start looking at some of the key things, emissivity
this is one of the most
challenging things to understand. This is the fraction of radiation from a surface
that gets to the sensor. Now lets back up and go to the fundamental equation that
starts all this this is,  E is for energy
equals a constant called Sigma. This is the Stefan Boltzmann constant, you can look it up. This is
multiplied by temperature so this is pretty simple. If this is a constant
energy is proportional to temperature. If the temperature goes up, the energy goes
up this is fundamentally how we tell radiation from a surface is the energy
emitted from it. Here's where it gets complicated this is temperature in
Kelvin so a 1
Kelvin temperature is about 300 in a room. A 1 degree C change is only one
part in 300 parts so it's a small change in energy, but this is one of the few
things in science that is raised to the fourth power. Kelvin temperature raised to
the fourth power is energy so obviously this is a very non linear thing we've
got graphs on the website that shows this exact relationship. It gets more
challenging, this is only true for an object that is
infinitely black and it radiates all of its energy to the surface.
A third parameter is emissivity. This
is a number
that ranges from 0 to 1, and it's a multiplier times this whole thing. So we
need to know
emissivity the surface, that's characteristic of the surface, then we put
this constant in, this Sigma, and then we solve based on the energy. We solve
temperature at the surface. This is called this Stefan Boltzmann law.
Boltzmann
came up with that Stefan added to it, it's fundamental to all radiation
physics. You don't need to know this law to use them, but it helps to understand
the principles, particularly this idea
emissivity. So let's take a look at emissivity. To get accuracy we
custom calibrate every sensor this is twelve sensors in a complex oven that
controls temperature and they're further controlled here. The sensor bodies are
controlled at one temperature, the targets controlled at another
temperature. Every single sensor is custom calibrated, using this device.
So if we know temperature we can get radiation, but when we point these at
something we need to know that their point to get something very black.
Let's take a look at how black that is. This is the errors by the way.
They're specified at plus and minus 0.2 degrees. This is a typical 12 sensors.
This two times the standard deviation is only 0.12, so it's a generous spec to
say there plus and minus 2. And, look at the temperature range from min -30 to 65 or 70
out here. They're calibrated over a wide temperature range, this is replica
sensors on top of each other.
So now lets take a look at that blackbody we take the top off. This looks like a hole
right? This is not a whole this is a cavity, that's painted very flat black,
it's a cone shape
cavity and it looks like its a whole, you could put your hand in it and that's what's
called the blackbody. A blackbody has an emissivity very close to 1.0.
In fact nothing really can theoretically get to 1.0, so this
blackbody is more like 0.999, and that's how we calibrate the sensors against
this blackbody keeping it purely black. Let's go back to this concept of
emissivity.
Here's a typical surface and I'm going to  show you some emissivities in a minute.
A plant canopy can have an emissivity very close to 1.0. Wow, that's so close to
1.0 lets just call it 1.0,and call it good, but 98% of the radiation comes from
the surface. And now, let's look at where the rest of the radiation comes from. The
other part comes from the sky, and this part right here, this tiny arrow, is 0.02 or 2%
from the sky. This sensor is averaging, in some cases of very cold sky
temperature with the temperature of the canopy and it's important to correct for
this in the software of the sensor. This is well characterized, we know the typical
emissivities of canopies so we can use this to pinpoint measurements. There's
the equation fraction reflected is 1 minus the emissivity so its 0.2. Okay this is the
correction factor,
this is the equation, but it's more important to know the inputs:
measured temperature of the sensor, that's this temperature right here;
background temperature, up here as the sky temperature in degrees C; and then we
need to know this. Now we typically look this number up, we measure this, we
measure this, and we can solve for the canopy temperature. I'm not going to go
into the details of this equation right here, but suffice it to say that this is
well described on the Apogee website and we've described it in manuscript we have
written. The take-home message is all objects measure the object plus averaging
and sum of the background temperature. If you keep that in mind you realize the
errors you can get into.Let's take an example clear day, 25 degrees
measured, the background is -40, that's a typical background of the
very clear sky, the infinity of outer space is 0 Kelvin so that tells you
why we get such cold sky temperatures. Emissivity 0.98.
What we measured was 25, and the actual surface temperature was 25.95 almost a 1
degrees C error if we don't account for emissivity, even though this is very high.
Let's take a cloudy day on here.
25 now the sky is much warmer and this error is much smaller on a cloudy day, so
again these are examples of why it's so important to correct for emissivity.
Okay, let's look at the field of
view. All sensors have a cone shape field of view here is the target,
and it's critical to understand what you're looking at.
So to do the trigonometry of this, we've got  this angle here and this angle
here, and now we've got a right angle.  This is the half angle here, so this
describes how big the target is. Apogee describes us in two ways: the ratio of
the distance to the target to the target diameter, so this ratio you don't need to
know trigonometry to understand that ratio; we also describe it as a half
angle right here, this distance here.
Apogee sells a series of sensors at different fields of view, but it's
imperative to know what you're looking at because you do not want to be
averaging the sky, the sidewalks, other things off in the sides. It's important
that this be small, but it's even more important that we know what we're
looking at. This is described in two ways distance to target divided by
target diameter and then angle. Let's take a look and the area that is
measured with this. Depends on three things: this field of view that we just
talked about; obviously mounting height, the higher up if the sensor is up here
same field if you were going to see a much larger circle, so that's the second
parameter; and then the angle. We don't always point these down sometimes and often
we point them like this, and now its sees an oval shape out here. These
three parameters determine what we're looking at.
The next slide walks you through this,
on what we see with these. This is example, here's one that was 22 degrees
field of view. This is one of the Apogee sensors. Let's look at the
field of view options.
These are 1 2 3 4 options that Apogee offers for fields of view, and this is an
example over a target. Narrow, medium, wider, and then rectangular. The
rectangular you don't want to see any sky, we don't want to see any ground. Because this
is important
Apogee has a field of view tool.
You can find this on the Apogee website. You put in the type of sensor you have, the model
number, it'll take the angles, and then it tells you the area that's integrated. It does this by
doing a bunch of trigonometry calculations. It's just a worksheet you type
in the inputs and it tells you the area. All of these are really to help you
fully understand what you're looking at, what's in the field of view what's not.
It's important to be sufficiently narrow, but it's important not to see bad things.
These are the four options, pictures of them, here's that rectangular,
narrow, medium, wide. These are on the website, but  lots of options to
pinpoint what you're looking. Next critical thing, is the infrared spectral
response sensors can cover a wide range, but it's important not to measure water
vapor in the air. We want to see right through the atmosphere right to the
surface. Lower quality sensors measure much of this radiation
and this slide shows us some of the interferences from these things.
Water vapor interferes right here. This is water vapor in the air. We do not want
to measure the water vapor in the air. We want to see right through it, and I think
we've got over here
carbon dioxide. Carbon dioxide in the air has bands down here that absorb, but there's this
atmospheric window as it's called. 8 to 14 microns in which neither water
vapor nor carbon dioxide interfere with the infrared signal. Apogee sensors
are calibrated just to measure this wavelength, which means they can see
through many kilometres of atmosphere because it's very transparent. This is
something that defines the sensor, defines how its calibrated. Once
it's done all you need to know is it's calibrated to utilize the
atmospheric window. It's not something you need to know on a
day-to-day basis when you're using it,  except when you're correct for the
emissivity. It is important to know that it does atmospheric window. So what do we
do when we're trying to measure a canopy and it doesn't cover all the ground? This
is a common problem, you can't just pointed at the plant. If we put it
right here we could get only the plant, but plants move
around we want to average bigger areas. It's not possible to always have it
right above a plant.  In this scenario this fraction of the radiation is from the
ground and this fraction is from the plant. So we have a case of partial canopy cover.
What this is measuring
is both of these together. To solve that, we put it on an angle, and now the
same field of view, look at this, all plants. It doesn't see the ground. This is
only possible with a narrow field of view so you can see over the top of the field.
This is a common application to mounted it at an angle so we only see the
plants. There are still cases with young plants where you see some of the
ground, and the next slide shows that.  To separate the ground from the
plants, we measure the soil temperature, I'll put degrees C right here and this degrees C
plant, and then what we measure up here. We mathematically separate out the
plant temperature from the signal here and the measured soil temperature.
This is the approach fraction of canopy, fraction of ground. It's possible to
calculate these fractions, and we have some manuscripts that explain doing this.
It's a common problem. Here's the equation, temperature of the canopy, this is all
to the fourth power, all done in software in the datalogger, temperature of the
surface, temperature the soil calculating canopy temperature. Let's start
using these to calculate what we call canopy stomatal conductance. If we
put a sensor right here, and we pointed at this leaf, seeing the leaf.
Let's say the leaf is slightly above air temperature, 2 degrees above air
temperature, we write in our notebooks this leaf is water stressed
because the leaves are hotter than the air and that would be correct, but now the
wind comes up. Here's conduction and convection. The wind comes up, the leaf
cools off
well we write in our notebooks, oh, the water stress went away. It didn't go away
the wind started blowing so we have to measure and correct for the effect of
wind. The Sun goes under a cloud we have to measure and correct for the effect of
wind speed. We also have to measure the relative humidity of the air that
determines the driving gradient. If the air is humid the plants are going to
warm up. They're not out of water. They just can't cool from transporation as
fast. All of these parameters in here are necessary to pinpoint water stress
for plants over a wide range of environments.
This is a example slide that we used to show this, and the overriding equation
for this is Rn, which is net radiation. That's the sum of this
outgoing shortwave, incoming shortwave, incoming long wave, and over here leaf
radiation. These four all go into net radiation. That equals
transportation, and I'll put Tr for transportation, + conduction
and convection, and usually that's called H. This is
a simple equation, and by measuring all these we pinpoint the water status of
the plant. Let's take another look at this in another diagram. This is a lot of
equations, a lot of math, but this is where this comes from. This is from this
manuscript by Mark Blonquist, our colleague John Norman, at the University
of Wisconsin, and myself, from 2009. It's a paper that works through all of this, and
I refer you to this paper for details, but here's that equation
I just drew.  Net radiation, H is for conduction and convection, and delta E is
for transpiration, and this is photosynthesis some of the energy goes
into photosynthesis in this equation and we account for that. This H  is further
broken down into the canopy to air temperatures multiplied by conductance that
gives us H. It  is further broken down into transportation, this difference here is
saturation vapor pressure. We measure these parameters calculate transporation
and this canopy and stomatal conductance to get gT, canopy and stomatal
conductance. These are all the parameters necessary to measure that. It is  a lot of
parameters, but the information is extremely valuable. So, we take theses
equations and substitute them all in this. This is part of Mark's excellence
in advanced algebra, and we get an equation that integrates all of them
here. This is canopy stomatal conductance mathematically.
This equation is all done in datalogger
with these inputs, and we've done this now over many fields to
pinpoint water status. I'd like to show you some of that data. The next
slide shows that. The advantage of this it's a physiological variables related
to stomatal conductance and everything's in here. It can work anywhere in the world
as long as you have these inputs to it. Let's take a look at some of these
examples. This was at Nebraska a couple summers ago that we measured. We'd have a
model that gives us the potential stomal conductance. If the plant is well
watered
it should transpire at the potential rate. You can see here's day and night
and day, in the night stomates are closed. Some of these aren't smooth because
there was clouds  and other parameters. This is our measured
parameters. So, what we calculate is the ratio of these two. How
open were the stomates? This is canopy stomatal conductance in moles per meter
squared per second, a fundamental measurement, the ratio of actual to
potential. That's what this is, the potential
should always be 1.0. Now here are some cases where it got above 1.0, and we think this was wet
leaves that made this go above 1.0. Because obviously you  should never get above the
potential. But look what happens after a rainfall. Here
it gets less. Now look at what happens in the day, it also went down during the
course of the day. There were more open in the morning than the evening, further down
as they dried out.  This is the slope of this.
Now let's look at what happens right here, another rainfall, 20 millimetres of
rainfall, happen right here. The stomates to  jump back up to their potential
and even slightly above, and then they started that downward march again.
This is the power of using infrared thermometry to sort out the water
potential and the stomatal conductance of the plants. This is the average
conductance of all of the leaves in the field of view of the plant, and it's an
automated measurement. It can be made day after day.
Let's look at our next parameter. This is a graph of potential
canopy stomatal conductance and actual. Here's our 1.0 to 1.0 line. If
they're always near the potential they'll fall on that line. They're close to this.
The other environmental parameters affect this; humidity, wind, solar
radiation, but each case they're close to their potential. What happened up here?
This we think is wet leaves. When the leaves are wet we get numbers that are
above 1.0. There are just a few values, but this shows the power of this technique for
pinpointing water stress in plants.
Conclusion. Canopy temperatures can be used to determine plant canopy water
stress and in this example canopy stomatal conductance. There are simple
methods to do this, and complex methods are the ones I've described here, where
we measure all the parameters and account for all of them. The complex
measurements work over a wider range of conditions than the simple measurements.
Emissivity, the correction for that can be significant.
So we measure sky temperature and mathematically correct or that. Then
field of view, we talked about that. Partial canopy cover we need to sort
that out. This is the reference to the paper we're talking about. Apogee can
give you copies of this. It is on the website. This shows the details of
making this measurement. One more slide I want to talk about. Maintenance of
these sensors. It's one thing to get a new sensor and get accurate data, but how
about week after week, month after month getting accurate data.
Three things cause problems: one optical path interferences, this is true of
all radiation measurement instruments. Spiders
can make a nest inside this window. Some places never see this, other places
have a lot of spiders. There's a spider nest inside that window. When that
happens the sensor suddenly flat lines it just starts raining its own
temperature. You can tell when it happens, and you get in there with the q-tip.
This is so important that Apogee sells scientific q-tips with this. Put it
right in the sensor and you can clean that right out.
You can also use methanol to further clean this, sometimes it can be helpful, or
just water.  But, you gotta keep that sensor clean. Second thing, is calcium
deposits.
Sprinkler irrigation blasts this thing day after day. If it is being hit by
moisture it  doesn't hurt the sensor, this is very waterproof, but it evaporates and
it leaves a little film. A hard water film on the inside window of the sensor. This only
happens when you have water shooting up on it, that evaporates get this film.
People sometimes use things like Windex to get that off, that doesn't help.
You have to clean calcium with a dilute acid, and in fact it doesn't have to be that
dilute because the sensor is very rugged. And again, take the q-tips
dip them, vinegar can work or a dilute acid. You can clean it with acid, it comes right off.
Don't try things like acetone to clean it. That doesn't clean up salt deposits.
Third, is dust and dirt. This happens in all windows, it happens in the
windows  of your house. This you can clean with window cleaning products, like
ammonium, methanol, even acetone in here. The key don't
push too hard because you scratch the window.
Let the chemistry clean the window, not mechanically. Here's the Apogee
website that talks about caring for this Apogee radiometer. So, that's the
summary of the principles to make this measurement. The things you need to watch
out for. You can spend your life getting better and better at this, but you can
see I think that this is a very powerful measurement. We're excited to work with
you, to help you collect better data. Thanks for listening.