I'm Bruce Bugbee president of Apogee
instruments and in today's video we'd
like to talk about net radiation and I
want to talk about the evolution of
measurements and models to get to this
key parameter and particularly the
evolution of instruments and I'm going
to show you in a few minutes some of the
instruments that we've used to measure
this here's why it's so important we
talk about it all the time but not to
pretty has a good understanding of it
what we really want to know is how much
to irrigate crops and there's no sensor
to measure the flux of water vapor
coming out of a crop directly we always
use in direct measurements one of the
most time-honoured and classic
measurements is to measure all the
parameters is it called the energy
balance model and measure all the
parameters around it and then by
subtraction get at transpiration here's
what the model looks like so we have our
n which is the thing we're talking about
equals lambda e T evapotranspiration
plus h the sensible heat flux plus G is
soil heat flux now these are classic
symbols Gedo need to know them to
understand net radiation except we can
do a reasonable job of measuring this
and this and if we can measure net
radiation by subtraction we can
calculate the irrigation needs of a crop
now this exact same simple model is used
to determine global warming as well so
net radiation is a key driver so we
really need accurate measurements of
that both for global warming issues and
for crop irrigation needs so let's take
a look at the state of the art of this
about 10 years ago
2005 the American Society for civil
engineers came out with this book
drop evapotranspiration and this whole
book is about the details of calculating
that equation I just drew up there and
in the beginning of the book it makes
this statement net radiation is
difficult to measure so we recommend
this is a whole society we recommend
modeling net radiation from shortwave
radiation vapor pressure and air
temperature this prediction is highly
accurate so we measure we model a lot of
things in science we modeled the things
we have trouble measuring but we
co-evolved measurements and models to
get the most accurate analysis of
everything we do I want to look in a
minute at where we've come since this
statement was written in terms of
instruments to measure net radiation
now it's worth talking about the person
that was the editor of this book this is
my friend and colleague Rick Talon who
was at Utah State University when this
he did all this work and he felt
strongly about this because he saw a lot
of people making bad measurements and he
said it should you should model it the
model for this is not all that trivial
here it is four components some
assumptions for these things are not
going to get into this model but you can
you can easily look at it in the book
read can pause on this slide and see all
the components so the models got plenty
of challenges as well now let's switch
to measurements from the model and for
this we fast forward four years to 2009
we did a massive field study of all the
state-of-the-art net radiometers at the
time and ran them for all summer long
carefully cleaned the domes on a daily
basis level them here's all the
instruments on our on our rig one two
three four five different types of
instruments three replicates of the
here's the models and the the number of
outputs of each now let's before we get
into the number of nachos let's take a
look at these
now before I even show you these we were
studying net radiation well before this
with state-of-the-art instruments at the
time and let me show you a very classic
instrument this one is in our museum now
we didn't use it in the study but
instruments precision instruments used
to come in wood boxes and this is a
Swiss take o-net radiometer made by a
swiss company that was state-of-the-art
for many years had to have a pump and
inflate the domes but it better de
tempted to do short wave and long wave
measurements and it's a it's a gorgeous
instrument it's since been replaced by
several other instruments let's start at
the low end one of our instruments was
this one this is a radiation in energy
balance systems model q 7.1 it attempts
to get at radiation by on all of these
Arnette so they have an incoming and an
outgoing just by one simple blackbody
that attempts to balance short and long
wave radiation this is the lowest cost
of these instruments in this study and
we're going to look at how this did the
next one up is a tip and Sonnen in our
light you can see these fine plates on
here this again is similar doing net and
long wave radiation with one single
output from this this is sensitive to
wind wind cools it so there's a wind
correction for this which we used in
this study then we keep going up this is
the Hux of flux that you can see these
on the screen but now look at this
instrument four separate sensors
shortwave in shortwave out long wave in
long wave out four outputs this is a
considerable step up from
these other instruments and then finally
the most expensive instrument of all is
this Kip and zonin CNR one which is
shown in our pictures oh we've got the
CNR one in this study the CNR one is the
predecessor to this that's a big uns
heavy instrument right here this came
out after this study it's a similar
instrument same company it's a slight
upgrade from that again it has four
outputs two on the bottom two on the top
so how'd this come out well these are
ranked by from the bottom to the top in
increasing order of price and not
terribly surprisingly the accuracy went
up with the increasing price so it's
sort of like you get what you pay for
but one of the absolutely clear things
we found out about this was these
instruments that had four outputs were
fundamentally more accurate than the
ones that only had one or two
remember these instruments that just
have two sides I guess they just give
you one number and they attempt to
separate short wave fluxes and long wave
fluxes and that's very challenging to do
it's easier to measure them separately
so on a put on this a green box around
this because the two most expensive ones
with four outputs we're also the most
accurate in this study so this was a lot
of data it very carefully analyzed with
multiple outputs this is Mark blonde
twist who was the apogee chief scientist
that I've worked with for a long time on
this out here polishing and leveling
these instruments in the field and at
the end of the summer we published this
in agriculture and forest meteorology so
you can go to this paper and see all the
details of this study and the
separate pros and cons but in a nutshell
the thing we came away from this was
with from this was four-way instruments
are better than doesn't look lesser
instruments now I said models might be
better than measurements let's take a
look at what we found from that all of
the instruments in this study were more
accurate than the model so we
fundamentally disproved that statement
that if the instruments are level and
clean they're more accurate than the
model we ought to be measuring radiation
the more expensive instruments were a
lot more accurate and how far off were
they there's a simple graph out of many
that we did the model was 10 percent
high compared to measurements there's
the measurements so 10 percent height
means I have you know that's not that
much you're going to overwater 10
percent waist 10 percent to the water
water is a really precious resource I
consider a 10 percent error in this
model to be pretty significant and since
this paper came out we have seen an
enormous number of people switch to
measuring this from modeling it this was
also published in another paper in
agricultural water management that
really made the point that this the
measurements are better than the model
so our colleague Rick Allen was on
record saying the model is the best so
guess what Rick Allen he became a
co-author with us on this paper to make
a very clear statement that the
instruments are better so that led to
using instruments now we fast forward a
few more years and because Apogee
instruments has a long history of
measuring these parameters Apogee
started working on a new design for a
net radiometer
that incorporated four components into a
single instrument and has an
intermediate price this is the design
that Apogee has just recently released
after four years of refinement and
testing it's a 4 component radiometer
short wave in short wave out long within
long wave out this would take up all of
these instruments take up a lot of
channels on a data acquisition system
and which are precious channels that can
be used for other
things so when this we made the output
sdi-12 and it only takes up an SDI 12
channel you can have multiple sensors in
the same channel so we consider this a
pretty fundamental breakthrough in the
world of measuring radiation it's small
easy to level and has I'm going to show
you a minute has very comparable
accuracy to the highest end instruments
that cost considerably more one of the
challenges of measuring radiation is
condensation on sensors and snow on
sensors for that reason the Hux of flux
has a heater in it
it's a one-and-a-half watt heater so
it's very significant you have to have a
big solar panel to run the seeder the
Kip and zonin also for extra money has
this shield it's both of these high end
instruments have heaters to try and keep
the instrument cleaned so you make
accurate measurements in all weather the
apogee because it's smaller has tiny
heaters and each of these four sensors
to keep the domes clean let's look at
what that looks like when we put these
heaters in here's a winter day few years
ago frost in the morning it didn't even
snow is just frost is covering
everything the heaters are clean and
this is just a fraction of the power
this can easily be run from solar
powered weather stations we got a lot of
pictures this thing here's the same
sensor different angle showing the frost
this part doesn't need to be heated here
but these are nice and clean so that was
another advanced being able to heat this
thing how accurate is it well we have
deployed this in the field you can tell
this is Utah cuz we have mountains in
the background over a big alfalfa field
over 15 months
over a year we compared them to the
high-end Kip and zonin this is the most
expensive of all the instruments and we
had three triplicate Apogee net
radiometers on this tower so through the
winter through the summer
comparing the accuracy here's the data
here's the Kip and zonin here's the
apogee 15 months in the field all of
them track the Kip and zonin very
accurately there's a few scattered
points in here and this is because
something got on the sensor sometimes it
got on the reference sensor and caused
problems this was not heated this didn't
have the heated shield so there are
times when this had an error but the
point of this is we're very pleased with
this accuracy it's been over a year
since we've done that so the take-home
messages from all of this now are its
cost effective to measure net radiation
and as opposed to modeling it on all
stations and in the world of
cost-effectiveness we feel that this
Apogee net radiometer really fits a
niche for very high accuracy and yet
moderate cost thanks for listening we'll
talk to you again in another session
you