[Music]
I'm Banga molly i'm an application
scientist ICT international i'm excited
to meet professor Bruce Bugbee and chief
scientist mark Blancas we've been using
Apogee instruments for a long time now
being able to meet them and learn more
about their instrument is really
exciting I'm Bruce Bugbee professor of
crop physiology at Utah State University
and president of Apogee instruments we
are here at the Hawkesbury Institute for
the environment and Western Sydney
University to do an all-day workshop on
principles of environmental measurements
we've done some workshops together
before but this is the first in
Australia and we're thrilled to be here
this country is coming into spring as
part of that we want to talk about a
couple instruments that we have been
working on for several years and we're
introducing these instruments in this
workshop one of them is a spectral
radiometer and it's small compact rugged
it's made for continuous monitoring
outside and like any spectroradiometer
it can be mounted this way and a second
one can be mounted up to down so you get
reflectance signatures from plant
canopies this is small and lightweight
it can be flown on a drone
we've been working on this for several
years and we're excited to be
introducing it at this workshop and
tomorrow the videos will show in detail
the characteristics of this sensor and
what it can do and applications I'm
holding a net radiometer like the
spectroradiometer we've been developing
this one for quite some time the design
goal is when we started were to build a
small compact lightweight instruments to
facilitate mounting the same time we
wanted to build a 4 component instrument
that was lower cost but still performed
or its regards to accuracy compared well
and favorably to the four component
instruments already on the market a
couple of the design features all of the
signals come into a central analog to
digital converter and all of the signals
are output as sdi-12 so it doesn't use a
number of data logger channels in order
to make the measurement also each
individual sensor has a heater to try to
keep doing frost off of the detectors
and facilitate accurate measurements in
all conditions like Bruce said we're
happy to be here in Australia to teach
the workshop and discuss these new
instruments as part of our time so what
a fuses participants in this workshop
are PhD candidates so this is a workshop
for scientists and looking for new
technologies and emerging
instrumentation
my name is dr. Peter Cole I'm the
director of ICT international we are
proud to be the distributors of Apogee
instruments in Australia in regard to
the principles of environmental
measurement this is truly exciting
because these principles are really very
important things to understand because
they enable you to deploy the
instruments in the right way
collect the right data and provide the
correct in data interpretation and this
is really very important