Today we'll be talking about the proper installation and maintenance of your Apogee pyranometer
to ensure its performance for as many years as
possible. Apogee's parameters are built tough, but they are precision instrument
so following these steps will ensure the best measurements. First, when choosing a
location to mount your pyranometer. Make sure it's in a spot that has a
full unobstructed view of the sun throughout the entire day and even
throughout the entire year for long-term deployment. Periodic shading of the
sensor from nearby objects will affect the accuracy of the measurement. If you are
mounting the sensor on a weather station, it's best to mount it to the highest point
on the tower or at least on the south side of the tower in the northern
hemisphere or on the north side of the tower if you are in the southern
hemisphere. For global horizontal irradiance measurements, be sure to mount the
sensor perfectly level. To make mounting easier Apogee carries a line of
mounting hardware that is designed to fit perfectly with our sensors. The
Apogee AL-100 leveling plate is a stable platform for the sensor and has three
adjustment screws and an integrated bubble level. The sensor is mounted directly to the
plate by threading the included nylon mounting screw through the center hole.
To mount the leveling plate to a cross arm, we recommend the Apogee AM-110
sensor mounting bracket. It is pre-drilled to mate with the leveling plate and
comes with all the hardware needed to mount it firmly to master pipes up to
two inches in diameter. When using our pyranometer to monitor solar panel
performance, you may opt for a plane of array configuration where the
sensor is on the same plane as the panel. Again. they AL-100 leveling plate and the
AM-110 mounting bracket can be used to mount the sensors securely, however, you
can use your own hardware as well. After you mount your sensor you'll need to wire
it to the datalogger or controler. For this demonstration we'll be using a CR 1000
datalogger from Campbell Scientific, but wiring should be similar for most dataloggers.
There are a few different configurations that you will need to use
depending on which model of pyranometer you have. The output of the SP-110 and SP-230 are
considered self-powered and can be monitored using a differential or single
ended channel measurement. When wiring to a differential channel simply wire the
sensors red wire to the high and the black wire to the low. The sensors clear
shield wire should be wired to the dataloggers analog ground for cable
screening of electromagnetic interference. For single-ended
measurements, wire the sensors red wire to the single-ended channel and then the
black and clear wire should be wired to the analog ground.
Wiring the heater circuit of the SP-230 will require a 12 V DC power
supply. Connect the white wire of the  +12 V DC signal and the green wire to the
negative or ground. The SP-212 and SP-215 provide an amplified voltage output and
therefore require an input voltage in order to operate correctly. Make sure to check
the sensor manual for the proper input voltage range for each model. Cconnect the
sensors white wire to the positive voltage signal and the clear wire to the
negative or ground of the power source. The sensors green wire is the output and
should be wired to the single-ended channel or the voltage input to a
controller. The SP-214 provides a 4 to 20 mA output and requires an
input voltage range of 5 to 36 V DC. To power the sensor
connect the red wire to the positive voltage signal and the black wire to the
negative or ground of the power source. The clear shield wire should be connected to an
analog ground. Next, wire the white wire to the controllers 4 to 20 mA input and the
green wire to the input ground. Maintaining your Apogee Instrument pyranometer
is a two-part process of making sure the optical path remains clean and
occasionally checking that you pyranometers calibration is still accurate. Because of
the dome shape of our pyranometers, keeping this sensor head clean is a
relatively easy job. If the sensor does become dirty the next rain should
automatically clean the sensor or you can simply rinse the sensor with water
or even a little window cleaner. If the sensor becomes encrusted with mineral
deposits, we recommend that you clean it  with vinegar and a soft cloth. The lens is
made from acrylic, so avoid using cleaners or tools that are abrasive and
can scratch the lens.
The next step in your maintenance routine, is to occasionally checking that
your sensor is calibrated properly. Apogee pyranometers have a
long-term drift rate of less than 3% per year. For many applications
this light yearly drift is insignificant, however, accuracy is
important. So, in general we recommend that you send your pyranometer to us
for recalibration every two to three years. However, most pyranometers will drift
much less than the 3% a year so you may be able to forego calibration for a
longer period of time. If you are curious and don't have access to a reference
pyranometer, Apogee instruments  has developed a website called the clear sky calculator
that can provide you with an estimated amount of solar radiation falling on a
horizontal surface, at any time a day in any location of the world. You can go
to clearskycalculator.com and enter your exact coordinates and a few other
parameters to get an accurate reference measurement. If your pyranometer reads
too far off it may be time to send in the sense for recalibration. That's about
all there is to mounting in maintaining a pyranometer, however, here are a few more
little tips and troubleshooting issues you might find useful. One of the simplest
problems we see is people failing to remove the green protective cap from the
pyranometer. The green cap is designed for protection of the lens when you are
transporting or storing your pyranometer but needs to be removed when
you're taking readings. A quick and easy check of sensor functionality can be
determined using a voltmeter with millivolt resolution. Connect the
positive lead of the voltmeter to the red wire from the sensor and the
negative lead or common to the black wire from the sensor. Direct the sensor's diffuser
toward a light source and verify this sensor provides a signal. Blocking all
radiation from the sensor should force the sensor signal to read 0. Finally, if you have
any questions about your Apogee pyranometer, you can find a lot of information
on a website or feel free to contact our tech support department.
All of the technicians are highly trained and willing to help answer any questions.