[Music]
some organisms like plants corals algae
and certain bacteria need light to live
but not just any type of light will do
most photosynthetic organisms require
light specifically from the spectral
range between 400 and 700 nanometers
apogee instruments line of quantum
sensors offer a cost-effective and
reliable way to measure the
photosynthetically active radiation or
par that reaches any target from a
specific light source
monitoring par is critical to optimizing
specimen health and is strongly
correlated to plant growth
apogee instruments quantum sensors are
trusted for use all over the world in
many different applications such as
monitoring the output of electric lights
in growth chambers and greenhouses
oceanographers limnologists and
biologists use them to measure different
conditions affecting aquatic
productivity aquarists measure the par
of lights used for growing coral reefs
in artificial conditions
ecologists mount them on flux towers to
monitor factors affecting various
ecosystems and plant scientists use them
to measure par above and below plant
canopies when calculating transmissivity
apogee's quantum sensors provide
excellent quality for the price
each sensor comes fitted with our unique
blue diffuser that reduces spectral
errors to less than five percent for
sunlight and common electric lights and
to less than 10 percent for most leds
single sensor models feature our
dome-shaped self-cleaning head while all
models are milled from 60-61 aluminum
alloy and then potted solid making them
waterproof and ideal for long-term use
in the harshest conditions
models are available in single sensor or
multi-sensor line quantum configurations
that can be used to measure spatial par
averages in conditions such as under
plant canopies
sensor only models are available with
pigtail leads for data loggers and come
pre-calibrated for either electric or
natural sunlight for instantaneous
readings in the field models are
available with an attached handheld
meter that features both sunlight and
electric modes
for more information about apogee's line
of quantum sensors visit us on the web
at apogeeinstruments.com