this is the quick start guide for the
ape Cloud
[Music]
burst today we're going to show you how
to set up the cloud burst the first
thing is choosing a location make sure
when you choose a location that free
from obstructions that might prevent
precipitation from coming into the gauge
things like trees or buildings this
location is a great location now that
You' decided where to put your gauge you
need to put it in the ground when you're
setting your post make sure that you use
concrete so that during the operation of
the precipitation gauge it won't shift
or move or go out of level the cloud
burst has two mounting options either a
4in diameter Pole or a 6x6 in wooden
post if you're going to mount using
wooden post you can directly screw the
base plate into the top of the post
using lag screws make sure that as you
set the plate that you level it using
the Bubble Level on the base
plate if you're going to use a 4-in pole
make sure that you get the adapter the
adapter will allow the base plate to fit
to a 4in pipe I'm going to show you how
you set it up using the 4-in pipe with
the adapter screwed into the base plate
set the base plate on top of the
pipe Orient it so that the Bubble Level
is pointing
North and with it set level you use the
screws to secure it in place with the
base plate leveled and the bubble
pointing North is if you're in the
Northern Hemisphere or South if you're
in the southern hemisphere you're now
ready to add the load cell on the load
cell find where the cable is coming out
of the load cell and you want that to
align with the Bubble Level pointing
North if you're in the northern
hemisphere the holes on the bottom of
the plate should align
perfectly with the load cell centered
and in place you're ready to add the
cable run the cable through the access
port
up screw in the cord
grip and run the cable around to the
load cell connector and screw it
in make sure the cable doesn't come in
contact with the outside housing secure
the cord grip so the cord doesn't move
now you're ready to add the
sstn place a sistern on top of the load
cell it should Center and line up with
the indentation on the bottom of the
sstn
now you're ready to add fluid it's a
little bit of a process so we're going
to show you how to do that in the studio
when recharging your precipitation gauge
we recommend that you do it sometime
usually in September October or late
fall that way the minimal amount of
antifreeze is required for the winter we
recommend using an antifreeze that has a
ratio of 50/50 propylene glycol and
ethanol something like the Campbell
scientific
cs75 we recommend using this kind of
antifreeze because it's non-toxic and
has a lower impact on on the environment
when disposing of the antifreeze mixture
make sure you do so in accordance to
local state and federal guidelines now
for the calculations the purpose of this
equation is to determine the minimal
amount of anif freeze that is required
to go in the sstn for your situation
first you need to determine what is the
coldest temperature that you expect your
gauge to be in in Northern Utah the
coldest temperature that we could expect
would be- 25° C we can also determine
that between September and January when
we expect our coldest temperature we'll
receive somewhere between 7 to 8 in of
precipitation so we go to our chart we
take our minus 25° C and we see that
it's a one part antifreeze to 1.5 Parts
precipitation to determine how much
anifree we need to put inside the sstn
we're going to use the following
equation for National Weather Service
Inlet it's going to be this equation so
we're going to take
0528908075 Ed precipitation then we're
going to divide that by the parts per
water ratio so we take
42312 divide that by 1.5 so we can see
that we're going to need about 2.8 in of
antifreeze in our bucket in order to
prevent freezing at the coldest point
next year keep in mind you can always
add more antifreeze if you need more
protection it just costs more money this
just gives you the minimal amount you'll
need to avoid freezing the last thing
you need to do is add 400 milliliters of
mineral oil on top this will give you a
quar inch layer of mineral oil that will
prevent evaporation from occurring now
that you have your sistern full of
antifreeze and mineral oil you're ready
to finish the install now the sister's
full ready to go it's time to remove the
clips from the load
cell squeeze the
ends and pull them off if you're going
to move or transport the load cell it's
a good idea to hold on to these now
you're ready to add the outside
housing
the outside housing will
slide around the outside over the top
make sure you align the inlet with a
sstn on the
inside use the clips to secure it in
place hook up the cable to a data loger
and you're ready for another years's
worth of precipitation
recording we recommend servicing your
gauge in the fall by servicing the gauge
in the fall you minimize the amount of
antifreeze that is required to prevent
freezing to service the cloud burst
remove the outside
housing with the housing removed look
around and make sure that everything is
in working order the sistern is probably
to be quite full there's two handles on
the side of sister to help you lift it
off so another great option is to use a
siphon put the siphon in the sistern and
the few squeezes it'll begin to
automatically drain fill up the sstn
with fluid antifreeze and then the oil
on top now the sn's full ready to go put
the outside housing back
on with the outside housing back on
you're ready for another Year's worth
precipitation monitoring if you have any
questions feel free to leave them in the
comment section below thank you so very
much for watching and have a great
[Music]
day