A high quality silicon-cell pyranometer can be a cost effective alternative to a
thermopile sensor for measuring solar radiation. Apogee pyranometers are
widely used in agriculture and solar energy applications. In clear sky conditions
Apogee pyranometers compare favorably to secondary standard reference pyranometers,
but at a fraction of the cost. In 1996 we introduced a silicon-cell pyrometer
that provided a low-cost alternative to more expensive sensors.
Through continuous innovation and improvements to the design our pyranometers
are now known for quality and durability. As an industry leader Apogee's
pyranometes have been included on systems from some of the biggest
names in environmental monitoring, such as Campbell Scientific, Columbia
Weather Systems, Torro, Rain Bird, and many more.
Why did these top companies trust Apogee? As a research-driven company Apogee has
carefully refined our pyranometer design and manufacturing processes. All
of our pyrometer are built at our headquarters in Logan, Utah. Each
sensor body is milled from high quality aluminum, and is then coupled with
custom optics and precision electronics by our skilled technicians in carefully
controlled conditions. As a final step all pyranometers are thoroughly
inspected and tested to ensure their quality and accuracy before we ship them
to you. Apogee pyranometers feature a dome shaped head that
allows it to quickly shed water, dust, and other debris. Pyranometers with a
flat or even recessed top, can trap rainfall and debris, which block the optical
path. Our self-cleaning design allows you to collect accurate data without
worrying about keeping it clean. Apogee pyranometers are filled with a resin to
create a barrier against water and humidity. Hollow pyranometers
can have significant errors if water gets inside. With our design
moisture is completely taken out of the equation. Accuracy is a key property of
any sensor. Under clear sky conditions Apogee pyranometers have a calibration
uncertainly of plus or minus five percent when compared to a reference thermopile
pyranometer. A key pyranometer characteristic is cosine response or
the relative error as a function of solar zenith angle. Apogee has achieved
excellent cosine correction through optimization of the diffuser material
and shape. Testing by the National Renewable Energy Laboratory in Golden,
Colorado has shown that Apogee pyranometers are comparable to the best
thermopile pyranometer on the market.
A sensor is only as good as its calibration. To ensure accuracy each
pyranometer is calibrated in tightly controlled laboratory conditions
traceable to ISO reference standards. To maintain traceability to the world
radiometric reference, every spring we send our reference pyranometers to the National
Renewable Energy Laboratory for pre-calibration. Finally each Apogee sensor
is calibrated with a standard output to make them interchangeable in the field.
Apogee features a full line of parameters to fit our customers needs
our sensors come with standard pigtail lead for easy integration with most
dataloggers. Models include our flagship SP-110, which is a basic self-powered sensor
with a full-scale output of  200 mV. For customers needing an even
larger signal we offer three amplified models: the SP-212 with 0 to 2.5 V output, the SP-215
with 0 to 5 V output, and the SP-214 with a 4 to 20 mA output. To improve year-round accuracy we
developed the SP-230 all season pyranometer, which has a raised stand and a tiny 0.18 watt internal heater that
keeps the sensor clear of dew, frost, and snow. For mobile measurements Apogee offers two
pyranoeter options that includes a handheld meter with a digital display.
The MP-100
features an integrated sensor in the top of the meter, while the MP-200
features a separate sensor connected with two meters of cable.
Custom lead lengths are available on request. The handheld meter displays instantaneous
readings or can be set in logging mode that can store up to 99 individual
measurements. For OEMs and system integrators Apogee offers customizable
options such as different multipliers, output, cable length, and a variety of
pre-installed connectors. With Apogee you're dealing directly with the
manufacturer, and we can work with you to provide pyranometers to fit your
specific need, no matter how big or small. For more information on our line
of pyranometers, please contact one of our representatives, or visit us on the
web at www.apogeeinstruments.com.