One of the other very key measurements is solar radiation, to any
input. For decades the only instruments available were expensive
blackbody pyranometers, then silicon-cell pyranometers became available and I
think we have some here. They are in the catalogs. Let's see if we got one
sitting here. Well this is close. This  is actually a quantum sensor but
but they're this size, they're tiny. Now siliconcell pyranometers are almost an
order of magnitude cheaper than black-body pyranometers, so all of us use
silicon-cell pyranometers on weather stations to get solar radiation, for our
Penman-Monteith models and everything else. We just say great we've just
saved a lot of money, but what I want to show you is the differences and the
errors that you get with silicon-cell pyranometers. These are not
widely appreciated. It's only our work comparing them rigorously back and forth
that we've seen these things. This comes from the fact that
black-body pyranometers, and you look at them and there's a glass dome and a
black disk, record all of the wavelength, all of the radiation over this whole
solar spectrum. This is the entire solar spectrum and on a typical sunny day. They
measure all of this these are all giant bands of absorption of water vapor and
the spectrum. Outside the atmosphere it's a smooth curve, but silicon-cells
pyranometers subsample this spectra and predict the rest. We do that all the
time in science we subsample things and then we predict the whole and
that's fine, but subsampling changes the perspective changes with atmospheric
humidity. What I'll show you is the data on how does atmospheric humidity
effect this spectra and how does it affect the accuracy of our silicon-cell
pyranometers. I don't know how many of these I need, but this curve
will relate to the next talk and photosynthetic radiation. There's so many
things you can see from this curve and we made a refrigerator magnet, nowadays
not everybody put these on refrigerators but I'm pleased I go around and people have
these on their filing cabinets so they can see the curve but here's a magnet.
You could pass around and take one, and don't put it but a disk it might
de-magnetize it or it might change it. This is just a curve showing this in
a couple different units. Here's watts per meter squared, but what happens on
cloudy days? Here's the whole spectrum as an introduction to radiation
measurements and radiation was what Apogee has cut its teeth on, our quantum
sensors and we're known as a radiation sensor company.
That's the whole curve. Now we get photosynthetically active, which is most
people in this room we've got 400 and 700 nm memorized, that's the range of
wavelengths that cause photosynthesis. It's also really close to the range of
wavelengths for human vision then finally down here UV. There's times and
we just want to measure this, but with pyranometers were measuring the whole
thing. It's all thermal radiation, that's what drives the change of state of water
from liquid to gas. Here's black-body and silicon-cells. Now look at how this
curve changes on a cloudy day, atmospheric water vapor not only takes
out these bands but it greatly reduces these bands of radiation. If you measure
the whole thing with the black-body pyranometer, you accurately measure this but
if you're only subsampling it, just look at this spectra is hardly changed
in the short wavelengths on a cloudy day it selectively shifts the wavelengths
this direction and this is the spectral response of a silicon-cell, these smaller
silicon cell parameters that we all use. It selectively measures this;
it doesn't measure this. What happens is they over measure on cloudy days
because they're sub sampling the part that's transmitted more. How bad is
this effect of oversampling? Almost ten percent, depending on how much cloudy sky
there is but that's a big error on cloudy days. Let's take a look at a
couple of cloudy days in here. Here happens to be three days when we had
full Sun, which is what these sensors are calibrated to and then partly cloudy and
then significantly cloudy here. If you
just look at this, it looks like the curves are really pretty close the black-body
and silicon-cell but when you calculate the errors almost none here
and that just gets bigger here. Here's where we're nine, ten, even eleven times
it's greater than a ten percent error.
You can of course correct for this if you know the effect and you know
the fraction of clouds, but rarely do people do this they just assume the
silicon-cell is correct at all times. There's a  humidity
effect on this on this measurement;  here's the magnitude of the
effect here. Again they're accurate in full sun because they're calibrated to
full sun. This is the same thing, data ratio of clear sky to actual and error
always goes high in these conditions. This is also probably a pretty good
example of models. This is an average of these but this should
taper down to zero and there's just a few data points and if you fit this with the
model that red line is really not very representative up here because we don't
have enough data to make that. But, it's an example of how we take data and make
a model out of it, but on severely cloudy days or significantly cloudy days it's
a pretty big error from silicon-cell pyranometers. The good news about this is
the cost of black-body pyranometers continues to come down and because of
these errors, we've sold a silicon-cell pyranometer for a long, long time and
we just help people about these errors, but because of this and because of the
need to make accurate solar radiation measurements on all the days, Apogee has
now developed a black-body pyranometer that looks like this and it doesn't
have these kinds of errors because of the spectra that it measures.
The second source of error among instruments is called cosine error, and
that refers to how accurately does the sensor measure all the angles of
radiation. You can put any light sensor out there and get some relative
indication of light but it is really difficult to calibrate it for light
coming right straight down and have it also be accurate when the light comes in
at a low angle. Or same thing on a cloudy day, where there's equal radiation from
all angles, the sensor has to accurately integrate all those angles. Here's an
example of low angle radiation
coming into this, and that's why we call this cosine correction because if it's
coming at this angle the sensor should read 500. It's not supposed to read a
thousand, that's cosine correction. Does it really read 500 if it's at that
angle? You have to get that correction with the optics of the sensor
and all radiation manufacturers work hard to get cosine correction, at least
the ones selling what we call research grade instruments. There's plenty of
pyranometers out there that are really cheap and boy they do a terrible job of
this. I worry about people selling cheap instruments and
getting the cosine really wrong and  if you know what you're doing you
can test this compared to a better instrument, but this cosine is one of the
things that some lower-cost manufacturers sometimes
forget. Here's all the angles coming into this thing. This is a graph of the
angle and error. In this case, this is a bunch of parameters and the standard
deviations. The morning and evening are slightly different. They're really
close until we get out to 75 degrees then the errors get bigger. This means
they're not as accurate at dawn and dusk for those measurements, but there's not
very much radiation out here either. It's low light, so a five percent error in low
light is not that big of an error in absolute terms. But you would like these
instruments, to be accurate all day long, and summer and winter. How about changing
Sun angles. We get summer angles in here and then we get winter angles over here.
If it's not cosine corrected, it can have a big seasonal error because they're
typically calibrated for summer sunlight angles. We specify these often by the
error out here at 75 degrees and this is an example of how companies right
specifications to how accurate are they out there. You can't just test one sensor
you got to take your entire pool of sensors with replicates and you want to
make sure your specification matches all your instruments not just your best
sensor. We specify 5% at 75 degrees and this is two times the standard
deviation, which is ninety-six percent of the tested sensors. Stability, this is
characteristic of all instruments, how stable are they long term. Humidity
companies have said everybody can build a humidity sensor and it's accurate on
day one now check it two years later three years later. All sensors drift
but companies work hard to minimize that drift. This is some test of silicon-cell
pyranometers for long-term drift compared to high-end black-body. Now, Kip and Zonen
sells very expensive high-end black-bodies. This is on the roof of our
building in Logan Utah. Multiple replicate  high-end instruments to get a very
accurate reference point. You can see there's two glass domes inside of these
to make a primary standard instrument. Here's data, now we don't show the
hundred pyrometers next to these but it's a big table that's checking them and
this is some data that were compared. the mean change was only point one percent
per year. On average these are very stable. I mean it's a very hard number to even
measure, point you have to go ten years before you even see a one-percent drift.
But there's some variability in these, so we had some that drifted as much as one
point eight percent. Now oddly enough, some went up too. They don't always drift
down. There's tiny changes in the optics that affect the stability of the
instruments. Because of this we write our specification at two percent a year drift.
That's all of the sensors should drift less than that even though the mean
is less than a tenth of a percent a year. Again I talked about this
accelerated aging before but to really be sure you've got quality
instruments you need to check long-term stability. It's one of the troubles with
new instruments. Everybody gets excited with new instruments. How much did the
manufacturer test those for long-term stability? You can't put them in an
environment for ten years you're depriving people of that new technology
but you can run accelerated aging tests to try and make them fail to get better
confidence that they're going to work in a range of environmentsm the tropics and
the cold places, warm places. That's a critical thing with research grade
instruments. Another little point on these, here's some frost.
Here we are in Sydney you don't get frost here right but but you get dew, you
get condensation here. Here was a morning, where we had cold warning, we had
frost and actually this might be a radiation frost, which we'll talk about
in a little bit, but these two sensors right here are clear. They're clear
because they're heated and with this little sensor we can put a tiny little
resistance heater in this and warm it up just slightly to keep condensation off
the sensor and to keep dew off the sensor, which we call that occlusion of the
optical path. If there's anything on that sensor, it's going to read incorrectly
and frost is huge. I got some pictures in here of snow on sensors. That's also
huge. It blocks, it sits on the sensor. You can buy heaters for those
primary standard pyranometers but now we're talking five to ten thousand
dollars for one instrument that's heated and ventilated to make an
accurate measurement versus a few hundred dollars for a tiny sensor that
has a heater in it. Those heaters have helped quite a bit to help people make
more accurate measurements in places that get condensation or in places that
get snow and frost. Here's an example of snow, buried under snow here and and
above the snow here. The sensor is also on a pedestal to keep it above so snow can't
stick to it.
Temperature affects radiation sensors. This is an example of comparative tests
that we've done with Li-Cor silicon-cell pyranometers and ours. There's a tiny
temperature effect in here. Most research grade sensors, this is a small effect
look at this goes from minus ten to plus 40 and the effect is only one percent.
Again for precision measurements, this is repeatable so you can measure
and correct for the temperature effect on the sensor. That depends on how
accurate you need the solar radiation.
This I think might be my last slide in this and I think we can talk
about net radiation next. Okay this relates to that.
Remember how we subsampled the solar radiation? We often want to know, turn
them upside down, and know reflected radiation from the ground. That's net
shortwave radiation. We take a carefully calibrated silicon-cell sensor
and it's turn it upside down and we say great now we know incoming and we'll
subtract outgoing, and we have net shortwave radiation. That would be wrong
because this sub-samples you turn it upside down and the reflected radiation
is different. You can get significant errors if you turn this upside down to
do reflected radiation and here's the magnitude of the errors fourteen percent
error over a grass canopy. You can see almost twenty percent errors. You
should never use a silicon-cell pyranometer upside down to get reflected
radiation. They are not calibrated for that. You have to go to a black-body
pyranometer, which doesn't have this source of
radiation. These are so inexpensive
everybody gets tempted to do this and  if you know this and you're
confident you could correct for it in software, butyou get really nervous
about all these fudge factors. Sometimes they can make measurements
worse. Question: "What about if you use it in the vertical position, not horizontal,
90 degrees?"
Okay, yes there is same thing because now you're not
measuring the sky it's reflected. These errors would be similar to this
because we're subsampling and the spectral changes.
Same thing as cloudes.  Yeah, we spent some time in this because lots of people
use these this way and you tell them not to and they still do and
people don't read the owners manual. They just think I like this sensor and I'm going to
use it. Tdone a bunch of work on
to characterize these errors and try and make people aware of them through workshops
like this, through videos online. If you know what you're doing as a research
scientist, you can often get away with a lower cost sensor because you know its
limitations. Pretty often it's people that don't know what they're doing that
get tempted to buy low cost sensors and then they misuse them and they can have
big errors. It's sad because you see it all too often. Part of what we
want to help you do is evaluate specifications of instruments you don't
need to over by expensive instruments but if you understand the specs
sometimes you can get away with less expensive. Often you can get away with less than
the highest cost instruments if you really know what you're doing and  the
limitations of the sensors.
Leveling is a big source of error. Sensors become
unlevel or people don't check that often enough. What if the sensor
starts to tilt very slightly to the Sun or away from the Sun you can quickly get
big errors from leveling. We spend a lot of time making really rigorous
leveling mounts and they all have a bubble-level, but now you got to climb in
your tower and look at that bubble-level to see that it's staying level.
Occlusion of the sensor, of the dome is a problem. Some sensors that are flat trap
debris. They trap water, the trap dew. That's an error, and of course you can
clean the sensors but how many of us do. We don't and now they read
ten percent low maybe until you get a a rain
storm and it flushes the sensor clean. Sensors that have a dome top help, a
lot. The water, their self-cleaning and the water tends to run off. Those
dome tops help keep the sensor clean, also helps keep it dry. That's
another nemesis of all instrument manufacturers is moisture getting in
their sensors causing drift or even the sensor to fail.
Let me go back to this.
If you look at high-end sensors and now
unfortunately we can't quite see them in this picture because these all have a
shield and aspirated to get peak accuracy but you see a little side port
with desiccant in the port. It often changes color, it is designed to change color.
If water vapor gets inside the sensor, you change that. We go to a
conference in Brussels each year, a
World Meteorological conference;  Kipp and Zonnen doesn't have that little disk with
dessicant on their sensors, and doesn't that keep your sensor dry
internally, keep this perfectly dry so you never had condensation. They said
the biggest source of leaks in our sensor was that port, that little
desiccant port. So we just took it out and now we have a better sea;omg and
it's dry when it's manufactured and we hopeit's going to stay dry for many
years. It's an interesting change in the development of sensors. They felt
like taking that out helped people make better measurements than leaving it in
and making them go and change the desiccant in the sensor.
We pot our sensors solid so there's no, in the pyranometers,
there's not air space. Moisture can't get in and cause problems with the measurement.
Question:
A couple things. The fundamental physics
of the detector change. Solar panels degrade over time and this is basically
a solar panel on a silicon cell that that's becoming less efficient at taking
sunlight and making the voltage. Changes in the optical path, tiny changes in
deterioration of the diffusing material over it that can become less transparent.
Those are the both of the biggest fundamental things. In black-body
pyranometers it's changes in this black surface. Nark just talked about
emissivity, boy they work hard to make that emissivity as close to 1.00 as
possible but as that ages it starts to turn gray. If it gets from 1.00 to
0.99 well there's a one percent error. It's not fully absorbing the
radiation. Really all sensors have that, just the fundamental physics
of aging of the object detector and solar radiation sensors are particularly
subject to drift, aging caused drift.
Question: "What happens with artifical light? Do you get any over samples?"
You bet you do. These are calibrated for sunlight based on that frist slide so now if you
wanted and lots of people do this. They put them under electric lights, which
have a very different spectra than sunlight so silicon pyranometers can be
way off with maybe fifty percent errors under electric lights because of the
change in the spectra.
Question: "What about ones specifically calibrated for the lights?" Yes, exactly it's possible to calibrate them and they're fine.
As long as you don't have a mix of sunlight and electric, but yes they
just need to be calibrated against a black-body pyrometer for that light
source and then they're fine because you know the spectra and you can sub sample
and predict all of it. I'm going to say one other thing that not on the list but
I'll use this sensor is an example. The cable leading to sensors, different
companies use different cables. You've got to get the signal from the sensor to
the datalogger and higher quality sensors have higher quality cables
coming out of them. So usually people write specifications for the
cable and the first dead obvious one is you want this thing to be as waterproof
as possible. Moisture starts to get in this, the signal even though this is
perfect it's not getting accurately to the datalogger. The other specification
that's good to look for in sensors is shielding for electromagnetic radiation
and that's just wrapped with tin foil and grounded at the other end so that
you don't get electrical interference and inside in greenhouses this can be a
particular problem. If they're near fluorescent lights, if they're near equipment,
you get electromagnetic noise picked up by the cable so we shield them.
That further minimizes any antenna effect of the sensor and so the
signal gets cleanly and clearly back to the detector so it's shielded twisted
pair cable is the highest quality cable so you can get the signal back
to the detector. Not in the recent past we used analog sensors they took an
environmental change they make a voltage you measure the voltage at the data
logger and you convert it to our units that we want. Wensors are rapidly
changing to digital sensors with micro processors in the sensors. The
measurement is made right in the head of the sensor and a digital signal is sent
back to the datalogger. All companies are moving to more digital sensors it
changes the nature of the datalogger that you measure it with, changes this
whole thing because of the digital signal. That's generally a good thing and
the cost of that technology is coming down with digital sensors. The three big
signals are SDI-12 (serial digital interface 12) is common in sensors,
Modbus is a second common one and now USB. This one happens to be a USB port. No
datalogger needed. You buy the sensors and plug it into your laptop then you
use the software and control the results on the screen.
The interface is changing fast in sensors and the nature of the
meter that you use to the sensor is changing because of that. It used to be
digital sensors were quite a bit more expensive but now that's much less true.
In general digital sensors are better because of this signal effect,
it's easier to send a digital signal
over, not easier it's more accurate to send a digital signal over a wire than
an analog signal, and puts the puts the burden of measurement right in the
sensor head. I don't know if you can have seen these options in sensors.
It's really just in the last few years that more digital sensors have become
available. They're the same sensor, same optics it's just a little microprocessor
in the head.