if I'm Bruce Bugbee and this is a
continuing series of seminars on
principles of environmental measurement
in this next mini seminar we're going to
talk about radiation shields how do you
protect a sensor from solar radiation to
shade it to get it to more accurately
measure true air temperature now this is
something like many things that we
thought we knew how to do 10 years ago
and we start to do more rigorous tests
and then we start to find out the things
we don't know so we're going to talk
about the past eight years of research
on radiation shields and how we've
modified shields and come up with a new
type of shield that uses less power and
is more accurate than the traditional
things I'm joined in this effort by Mark
Blanc was the chief scientist at Apogee
he and I have been doing tests on this
in many places over a lot of time to get
this data so let's take a look at the
types of shields now here's a great
picture of these shields against the sky
and it summarizes the five types of
shields I'm going to talk about in here
this is at an angle so there's a little
bit of wide angle distortion here but
let's go through them here's the
shield's that everybody is familiar with
we called these multi plate shields
they're also called passive shields or
static shields there's no moving parts
they rely on the wind to cool it off the
winds supposed to go through them and
it's supposed to shade the Sun they've
been used on hundreds of thousands of
weather stations over many decades now
let's look at how accurate they are
compared to improvements there's one
type this is one made by Met spec in in
England there's a second type right here
which is made by our M young these are
come in multiple Heights we used ones
that are tall so the very best of this
technology but we compared it to three
active shields that have a fan in them
and it's pretty simple if you have a fan
blowing over something it doesn't heat
up in the Sun the way a static shield
does so as you can imagine if the Sun is
bright and the wind is not blowing these
heat up above air temperature and with
the fan the problem is greatly
diminished so in this series of tests
I'm going to show you we looked at the
meant one shield which is a long tube
it's actually the biggest of the three
shields and the inlet to the air comes
in the bottom right there and then the
outlet of the air comes out the top up
here the second shield we looked at is
the RM young shield again the air is
coming in the bottom blowing out the top
and the third shield we looked at is an
Apogee fan aspirated shield same thing
airs coming in the bottom and out the
top so we'll look at the data and then
we'll look at some of the physical
principles that result in air
temperature so after years of work and
refining that design the next step is
field testing and we've tested these now
in multiple locations so before I show
you the data let's look at the locations
one of the first test sites is at
Campbell scientific here in Logan Utah
and here's the multiple replicates
shields you can see in this screen net
spec shields small multi plates big
multi plates here's the Apogee shield
right there here's an RM young shield
there compared to all these other ship
and look at it and here's the anemometer
for wind speed so this is one of the
test sites run over an extended period
of time to look at differences in
measurement accuracy caused by shields
now these all have accurate temperature
sensors inside them to make this a fair
comparison next site is Apogee 's
backyard which is a
more extensive tests you can see all
these along a plane
here's replica Apogee shields there's
many of them here's the net one shield
here's the arm young shield
there's many replica shields in this
this is in a line but we filtered the
data for only when it was crosswinds
to get more precise data out of this
test all run off a single weather
station this example of some of the
testing we've done third site is
Campbell scientific England same thing
here's the RM young here's the Apogee
whole bunch of static shields in this
test all hooked up to a common data
logger run over a long period of time to
test for differences among shields
another site is the Utah State
University campus environmental
Observatory which is a solar powered
station right in the middle of campus
and here's a static shield and here's an
Apogee shield in comparison in that
typically we have the inlets of these at
the exact same height they're not quite
that way here because the ground is warm
and the higher you go the cooler it is
so this test would slightly favor the
static shield over this because this is
lower and this is higher but typically
and all the other tests the inlets were
at the exact same height now let's look
at some of the data from these tests
we're going to summarize a lot of data
in a few slides here's the raw data
these two slides here's the summarized
data so let's look at the summarized
data first with all all these data
points in it this is the temperature
rise above the active radiation shield
now all three of the active shields were
very close to each other so they very
close to zero and if the wind is blowing
nuts look at two things
here's a small thermistor right here the
blue line here is a larger humidity
probe
how do people measure temperature in
these a humidity probe so if you have a
larger humidity probe you can have one
degree see errors in still win if the
Sun is out if the wind is three meters a
second a gentle breeze you still have
you can see about 0.3 degrees C error
all the way up to a rigorous breeze
flags would be standing straight out at
wind speeds like this it still didn't
the humidity probe still didn't get
quite to zero
so the small thermistor was better and
let's see here if we can erase some of
this this is our new board it's just
like the blackboard and only no chalk so
now we go to this get back to green now
let's look at this small thermistor much
better because it's small this is a tiny
yellow bead thermistor made by Apogee
instruments very tiny look at this at
three meters a second now the air gets
less than a tenth of degree C but it's a
pretty big air below that and finally
this gets very close to zero out here
but at high wind speeds this is just the
raw data because these are short time
intervals there's little puffs of wind
but the key is that summary they're
small thermistors are more accurate than
larger humidity sensors and we'll get
back to that but that's a key
distinction because people often just
use the humidity sensor to measure these
and they use it in a static shield so
what's the next data look like this is
differences in the static shields this
is the RM young shield which is a very
widely used shield on weather stations
that had the greatest temperature
increases in our tests
compared greater increases compared to
the Mets Beck shields Mets Beck has two
models here's the one shown in green
here's the two shown in blue that mk1
was slightly better but still they
didn't get down to zero until there was
a reasonable breeze blowing to cool it
off these three showed the raw data all
feeding into this summary so shields
vary a little bit but even the best
shields had errors in temperature so
what happens in the winter this of
winter is a killer there's snow in the
ground there's low angle light
reflecting up on these shields so the
radiation intensity is focused on the
shield they're not designed to block low
angled radiation remember the shield's
have a design that looks like this yeah
what happens when the Sun comes in like
that it heats it up gets right inside
here's the data for no snow in the
ground this is over vegetative surface
and once the Sun comes out the errors
start to approach two degrees C with no
wind and they don't go to zero until we
get a very stiff breeze blowing on these
so the errors are much worse over snow
let's take a look now at the small
differences between these three types of
aspirated shields these are the RM young
shield and the Apogee shield compared to
the Met one shield now in our tests the
Met one shield read slightly cooler so
we use that as the reference here there
is no official reference for this at
zero things heat up as the radiation
gets bigger
so here's temperature errors in the
and they're less than 0.05 degrees see
the apogee shield was slightly better
than the RM young shield for accuracy
and in these tests but now look at the
winter much worse but remember the
static shields were more than 1 degree C
above air temperature now we've reduced
that error to less than 0.1 degrees C
even in the winter with the reflected
light and of course when it's dark
there's there's no error at all so these
are all close the apogee shield in these
tests performed the RM young shield and
was very close to the Met one shield so
how does this Apogee shield work one of
the design goals of this was to
dramatically reduce the power to the
shield and let's take a side view look
at this thing because if you're gonna
run these from a solar powered system
you either need an enormous solar panel
or a more efficient design this is the
Apogee design right here inside view
filled with foam sensor port adapter
right here going to the sensor now this
is what's called a Kawana Inlet and it
looks like a jet engine Inlet so that
when the wind is blowing sideways it can
more easily change direction and go up
here in the fan and blow out the top of
the shield if this was a square edge
like it was in all of our early tests
anytime there was a crosswind we had
problems so we had to go to this
specialized Coanda Inlet coupled with a
small sensor in just the right place
notice the taper here that's a rocket
nozzle contour to get the wind going
faster and faster over this shield right
here these are all critical to the
design and critical to the use of a
small pen here's the whole thing
sealed up yours gee Lloyd plastic
venturi contour Inlet I mean I mean now
that we're here let me show you some of
the component parts here's the fan this
is an IP 55 rated fan that's custom
built for Apogee ip55 is a measure of
the resistance to water and dust you can
spray this van with water and it doesn't
hurt it and we have yet to have in spite
of now having several hundred of these
in the field and very rugged
environments we have yet to ever have a
fan fail and some of them meant up for
four years now there it's rated for at
least 50,000 hours so this is an
exceptionally rugged small low-power fan
this cuándo radius we got up right here
here it is
there's the quandary radius so the air
can come right up in here and fan sits
right in here and blow out now this this
whole thing is covered by hat so that we
can shield it from the Sun and water and
it's a it's a simple yet elegant design
so let's take a look at some performance
data here's the quondam one of the you
could see the difference in fan size RM
Young 400 milli amp Apogee 80 milliamp
this is a five fold reduction in power
for the fan so much smaller battery much
smaller solar panel it gets better at
night you don't need to run the fan full
blast
so Apogee is put in a variable speed fan
which I'm going to talk about in the
next slide but this is the difference in
the quandary radius when the wind is
blowing sideways the RM young got worse
and because of that radius the apogee
gets better with slightly better with
high wind
in spite of a fivefold reduction in
speed now let's look at the variable
speed fan here it is running full blast
80 milliamps with the ratio of 1 at
night or on cloudy days with a PWM
command we can slow the fan down all the
way to 25 milli amps and now the wind
speed is less but the power consumption
is much less so it's already a small fan
and we can further optimize it by
slowing it down at night and on cloudy
days or on days when the wind is already
high don't need a fan here's the IP 55
rating tachometer output so this is a
separate wire to the data logger telling
the RPMs of this fan if anything gets in
there and the fans not working right
will slow it it'll show up and raise a
red flag this is how we save power pulse
width modulation from the data
acquisition system so there's a top view
with a fan right there how do you get
the sensors in this other shields are
there big to put them in from the top
you clamp them in after lots of testing
we found the best way is put them in the
side here's the picture here's the
shield the sensors go right in the side
like this it's simple its elegant you
can change take out sensors and change
them you can put in multiple sensors
here's a bunch of pictures of what we
call sensor port adapters so if you need
one thermistor this is the sensor of
choice if you want to have replicas
there's two replicas three replicates
full replicas thermistors for super
precision work it's easy to do these are
cheap and easy to make now what if you
want a humidity probe with it like
everybody does here we go
you buy the model with a humidity probe
adapter and that looks like this here's
a picture of that adapter clips writing
here quarter-turn snaps into place
Oh
to hold the humidity probe in place so
these come in all shapes and sizes to
hold a wide range of sensors here is a
picture of one in action it would sit
like this in the shield the air is
coming up like this we accurately
measure the temperature there and then
the humidity here this is a if I say the
HMP 110 shown with how this would go
right into the adapter so this is easy
to do for a wide range of sensors and
they're easy to take out and clean
that's another thing these eventually
get dirty and other shields that take a
whole shield apart here you just pop the
sensors out wipe them clean put them
right back in that was another design
feature that we put into this there's a
picture of that in the in the field so
these are the air temperature options
for this the Apogee st 110 is that
yellow bead thermistor now many places
call for more precise data with the
Platinum resistance thermometer and here
is an example of that with a four wire
PRT in that sensor port adapter four
places that require PRT that receive
measurements this is another probe that
works fine with it the Campbell
scientific 109 a wide range of
temperature sensors work fine by Sayla
Campbell scientific wrote Ronix EE
electronics we it works fine with a wide
range of sensors just with the right
sensor port adapter of course many
people buy more than one sensor port
adapter for future expansion here's a
couple case studies in the field where
this has been used this is the what's
called the eye Utah project and they use
a lowercase I to be high-tech there's a
many of these stations in the mountains
of Utah monitoring snowmelt where
accuracy of air
temperature is everything how fast is
the snowmelt on the spring how fast is
the water run down in the valley if
we're off a tenth of a degree C the
models are wrong we have to have
accuracy
there's the apogee seal this by the way
is Apogee heated parinama tur which
they've selected for use on this for
extreme winter conditions this is just
example up in the mountains the snow
gets deep so this stuff has to be high
up one more example is the greenhouse
environment this one happens to be
Roberto Lopez's greenhouse at Purdue
University
he ordered multiple Apogee sensors for
precision air temperature measurement
over his experimental plots so here they
are with the precision thermistor coming
out and the shield's multiple replica
shields hanging in a greenhouse so in
summary the apogee shield has been
optimized for accuracy and low power and
low cost those three things we think
make it a very favorable choice for
weather stations when precision air
temperature measurements are important
this can replace the old static shields
for precision air temperature
measurement and I'll stop there that's
the final slide had in the shield
measurement series we hope to see again
another measurement seminar thank you