I'm Bruce bugbee president of apogee
instruments and professor of crop
physiology at Utah State University so
today I want to talk about our latest
spectral radiometer the features it
gives you for plant photobiology and on
the screen itself of the instrument
[Music]
we have other videos that are like
owner's manuals of this I'm going to
focus on interpreting the data from this
this instrument has got a tiny screen
right here so you make a measurement
like this
and
instantaneously or within seconds it
gives you the calculated values in here
and that's what I'm going to go through
there are five screens in this and I'm
going to go through each of them and
what the values represent here's the
instrument big it's a model
MS 100.
minutes ago I walked outside and took a
measurement in sunlight that sunlight's
a wonderful reference Spectra so it's
close to solar noon here in Logan Utah
so let's take a look at what these
values look like with sunlight
there's a sunlight Spectra and this
shows up immediately in the screen if
this was an LED we'd get a spike of blue
and fluorescence it it's a immediate
spectral trace of the light you're
looking at which is really helpful
immediately you can interpret a lot of
stuff just from this screen no
downloading of data just just click the
shutter speed in the instrument and
collect this so a lot we can do with
this screen and let me put some units on
this right away if you're less familiar
with this first of all
this tells you something
let's get a color in here let's put this
in green
we've got one two three
four tick marks in here
if you're familiar with the sunlight
Spectrum this is UV
this part right here so it this
instrument detects down to 350
nanometers which is most of the photons
but the majority of the photons
from even from sunlight
this then and then the first tick marked
is 400 nanometers
then 500
and then out here
is 750.
so
this it the subsequent screens tell us
the amount the number of photons in each
of these categories but first of all
four to five hundred
is B for blue photons
five to six is G for green photons six
to seven is red for red photons and then
this critically important part out here
700 to 750 is fr
red
so
UV put that on here one two three four
five categories of radiation now it
downloads the Spectras you can fine tune
this as much as you want but for quick
analyzes the fractions of photons in
each of these categories are
particularly important this axis is of
course
Photon flux
foreign
that's an F
and it's micro moles of photons per
meter squared of area per second
and now because this is all these little
tiny bins it's per second per nanometer
is as a specter radiometer gives you
when you download the Spectra to a
laptop or to a cell phone it gives you
more data than this this is just the
screen it shows
that's the opening screen make sure you
got the correct Spectra in there save
the Spectra now let's go to this so this
is screen number one
now let's go
to screen number two and we're starting
to parse out these ratios
ppfd as we've talked about in previous
videos
is PFD is the photon flux density
and P is the photosynthetic Photon flux
density
and this means 400
to 700 nanometers
and this is the classic definition of
photon flux density that we've used for
over 50 years
sunlight we always say goes up to 2 000
micro moles the units over here for
these are all micro moles
per meter squared
per second
so this serves with this metric as a
regular Quantum sensor of high
resolution Quantum sensor and we always
say sunlight goes to 2000 well right now
in Utah was
1948. maybe there was slightly overcast
or it's not exactly solar noon but it's
close to two thousand now e this
lowercase e stands for extended
photosynthetic Photon flux density and
what this means is
to 750
that's a seven
nanometers
same units here
but it adds the far red photons to this
that based on lots of research have
photosynthetic value so it gives us both
numbers now look
1923 this is adding some Far red photons
in the difference would be the far red
photons here
those are actually shown on another
screen but this ought to be slightly
higher if you measure this under
red and blue LEDs there's virtually no
far red these numbers would be almost
the same but if you measure under white
LEDs they have a tail so the eppfd is
almost always a little bit higher and
sometimes much higher if you're
measuring lights that have a lot of far
red photons in them
so these are pretty straightforward
we've covered these in previous videos I
won't go into the I won't write out the
full acronym right here
but now there's a third metric in here
why
PFD proton flux density the same as
these
the y stands for yield
and this is the metric we've had for 50
years
and it does not weight all the photons
equally these do a blue Photon counts
just as much as a green and red they're
all equal that's our definition of these
but we know that particularly blue and
green photons
aren't absorbed as well by
photosynthetic pigments as red photons
so this metric weights the photons makes
which the red photons more than the blue
and more than the green
and because of that this is always a
number slightly smaller than this
many researchers report all of these in
their papers to make sure you've got all
the metrics in theory why PFD is a more
accurate predictor of photosynthetic
photons than ppfd
um and I and we don't have it yet but in
theory you can have an eyppfd I'm making
that up just now because that that
doesn't exist yet but this is this
weighted so I'm going to cross that out
this is a weighted flux of photons and
it's always about 90 percent of these
because it discounts blue photons for
photosynthesis
finally to round it out t
stands for total Photon flux density see
how this number is higher
this is everything the instrument
measures and it's 380
to
780 nanometers
this is all the photons
at the edges of this accounts the UV
photons in this counts all the far red
photons and it's a and it's a bigger
number
each of these metrics is valuable in
photobiology depending on the study
depending what you've used but the
beauty of this is you click the shutter
you take a measurement and you have
these numbers immediately right there
they're stored in memory but you have
them right there to to Analyze This
is screen two we have five screens
screen three puts the these Photon
fluxes in categories remember UV is 380
to 400
so there's the flux there's only 38
round this number to 39
all of these units are micro moles again
per meter squared
per second
so this is sunlight 39 micro moles of UV
photons
B is for blue
400 to 500
500 for blue
and you can see in sunlight it's a
little more green and even a little more
red that curve goes up here's the green
photons here's the red now if we sum
these up we would get the total Photon
flux if we just added these together
we would get the ppfd but this breaks it
down into categories of photons this is
screen three and depending on what
you're doing this is really useful to be
able to immediately see
the number of photons in each of these
categories
screen four
this focuses on Far red photons they are
such powerful photons there's four
critical metrics for far red photons and
remember the far red
is where am I going to put that is 700
to 7 50.
nanometers this Edge we can barely see
it but it's very very powerful for plant
growth
this is the photon Flux Of Far red now
this could be on the previous screen but
there's four numbers on each screen
so there was
357.5 Far red photons
um in sunlight right now when we made
this measurement
f r f stands for
far
red
fraction
so this is
far red photons
over
total photons p p f d and in this case
it's e ppfd
so you can see this is a number that
goes from zero to one the fraction if it
was pure far red light the numerator
denominator be the same maybe one this
is a very convenient we look for ratios
that are zero to one in all of our
science so it's because it's a fraction
it's 0.15 if this was a percent
we would have 15
.5
percent
and that's pretty close to the typical
far red fraction in sunlight
it's a real useful number because we get
so so intuitive was there five percent
far red photons was there 20 far red
photons we've used this in manuscripts
Polk assume and I have a manuscript on
the importance of far red fraction it's
becoming very widely used in
photobiology to describe the amount of
far red
PPE is a different metric that's I can
leave this other one up here this one is
for phytochrome
phytochrome photo equilibria
it's also called I'll put this here
let's see that's even
let's switch to Yellow
this is also known
as PSS they're exactly the same thing
this stands for phytochrome photo
stationary State phytochrome
photoequilibria same number this is a
number that also goes from zero to one
depending on the amount of far red light
and I'm going to show you a few slides
to explain that in a minute
this was 0.69 which means there's quite
a few quite a bit of far red
photons in sunlight but this weights all
the photons over the entire Spectrum for
whether they contribute to um stem
elongation or not and stem elongation is
largely controlled by phytochrome
so we have a final metric on this screen
i p p e and i stands for internal
what this means is the predicted
phytochrome effects inside the leaf not
above the leaf but inside the leaf
internal to the leaf this is a new
metric ippe
and our data indicate it more accurately
predicts stem elongation under a range
of colors of light then the old metric
which was PPE
now we show both metrics you can compare
and my colleagues have been putting both
metrics in their papers to predict
things like Leaf expansion and stem
elongation but this predicts both now
look this is 69 and this one's only 39
so there's a big difference in these two
metrics
and I what I'd like to do is take a
little sidebar right now and show you
some slides that I showed a few weeks
ago at a big NASA conference
to explain the significance of these
metrics for plant biology so let's go to
those slides and we'll come back to this
one right at the end
this is improved metrics for
photobiology this year just slides from
that talk
this is a picture of the phytochrome
molecule it's a big organic molecule
with with a lot of proteins in it but it
switches back and forth between two
forms depending on the colors of light
mostly red and far red so it's great to
think of this as Nature's light switch
because it's it's either on or off
telling the plants you're in the shade
get tall you're in the stun stay short
but it just switches back and forth
between these two and you need a
spectroradiometer to calculate which
form it's in and that's interesting
because there's thousands of these
molecules and plants and the plant is
integrating all of these light switches
to decide whether it should get tall or
whether it should stay short
here's sunlight this is the significance
of this in it simply in shade
plants have a choice they can avoid
shade and get tall or they can tolerate
shade and grow more Leaf area now here's
a plant in sunlight over here it's short
with small leaves what we can do with
photobiology and lights is Trick these
plants into thinking they're in the
shade so they get more leaves and that's
a wonderful thing it trick them to think
they're in the shade some species get
tall and this is very undesirable
but this is that curve we were just
looking at for sunlight measured Under
the Sun here's our Classic 300 to 400
506 700 now look what happens in the
shape underneath the tree all of these
wavelengths are filtered out and this
far red we better put that in a
darker
darker color
this far red right here
is transmitted and it flips that
phytochrome molecule to the on position
and it says change shape chain shape
we're in the shade even whether they're
in the shade or not we could trick them
but in nature this is how it works
there's the far red at the critical in
shade
this is the classic ratio of colors that
leads to this metric phytochrome
photoequilibria
and it's a ratio of far red
let's get another
it's really a ratio of
far red over total
foreign
photons and it heavily weights blue
photons and less of red
so with this we've known about this
curve for bow 60 70 years
in studies there's I picked one here
from 1976.
this is this PPE as the number gets
higher
stems get shorter
and actually this this is not quite
correct pfr
is response to the red
photons
not the far red
so as this number gets higher more red
light plants get shorter and that's a
pretty good predictor of this so you
measure it and you know the potential of
your light source to make tall plants or
to make Leaves expand okay this was work
great
but the phytochrome molecules not just
on the surface of leaves it's inside the
leaves
and here's these blue photons where keep
coming back to these same wavelengths
here
blue photons are absorbed by chlorophyll
and other pigments and they don't
penetrate the leaf this is a cross
section of a leaf top and bottom blown
up green photons penetrate into the leaf
and this is the transmission here red
photons don't they're absorbed far red
really penetrate into the leaf
so what does the phytochrome molecule
actually see it sees the penetrating
photons into the leaf
so
when we did tests
on the old this is the old PPE right
here
this wonderfully predicts this is a
knife linear relationship stem
elongation
when we did that test with
different ratios of colors in the
background blue green and red the lines
got all mixed up the the predictive
value of PPE was not very good so we
have a problem with the PPE under LED
lights where there's a mixture of colors
so let's look at the what we did
here's the old curve this by the way is
done with Paul kasuma a PhD student with
me he's now an assistant professor at
waganingan University in the Netherlands
this is the paper this came from
here's the original PPE right here
put that in yellow
with the weighting factors that we've
used
here's the screening of chlorophyll the
classic screening more green gets
through a lot more far red if we take
this
times this
we get this function and this function
is
ippe which your new spectradiometer
measures calculates instantaneously and
look at the difference this heavily
rates red this heavily weights far red
how well does this newer metric predict
stem elongation under a range of light
sources
very well
here's
I
this is the PPE once again same curve
I've been showing you
this is PPE with colors and this is i p
p e
the new metric with a big background of
colors and the lines converge
um so this coupled with other people's
studies now indicates internal PPE is
just an improved metric more precise for
measuring phytochrome effects
considering What's called the spectral
Distortion of the leaf the filtering of
chlorophyll into the leaf
that's a lot of slides to derive why
ippe is important let's go back to the
spectradiometer here's PPE
and ippe one last time
we show them both the older metric and
the newer metric and this is more
sensitive to as on a range of zero to
one this is a more sensitive these
numbers tend to be all very high on 0.7
to 0.9 whereas these numbers are 0.3 to
0.9
this is screen four
we have one final screen
this is screen five
and these are metrics for human lighting
color rendering index which most people
are aware of it's a number of zero to a
hundred the
um closer to 100 the better the light
source renders colors for the human eye
the Reds and the greens and the blues
now
zero to a hundred this is sunlight and
that's the reference so the color
rendering index
foreign
which is an index
um
it usually means that number to zero to
one or zero to a hundred
sunlight's a reference
what's CFI this is the color Fidelity
index
this has been called by some people
tm30
for technical memo 30. it's also called
RG but it's an index 0 to 100 so we call
it the color fidelity
index
and look under sunlight a hundred it's
it's as good as it gets for color
rendering Index this is very close
under LEDs this number gives bizarre
values it gives negative values it's an
old index the CFI is a much improved
newer index and people say oh the
calculations are more complex for CFI
for one this is based on six reference
colors
this is based on 99 reference colors
that tells you something about how
Superior it is and people say oh the
calculations are so complex oh yes well
it takes about a five microseconds to do
those calculations in a computer
um
so this CFI is replacing CRI and in fact
I would say it's largely replaced it but
this has been around a long time
finally and let's let's see if we can
erase these
um
give ourselves a little bit more room
right here
and we'll put this in yellow
color correlated temperature
is a number between about 2
000 and about seven thousand depending
on
really the blueness versus the
orangeness of the light
now the higher the number
the more blue the light this is sunlight
so it's five thousand so sunlight's very
blue light if this was an incandescent
light this number might be about two
thousand
and you go to the store and you buy LEDs
and you can buy you can pick whether you
want attempt to simulate an old
incandescent light incandescent lights
about
2500 it's a warm orangish glow
we say you put warm colors in your
bathroom to make it look like you have a
good tan and cool colors in the kitchen
to to be more like sunlight in the
kitchen
so this gives a number from
two to eight thousand depending on the
blueness of the light and finally the
old classic Luxe
which is the human outweighted human eye
response for uh
um
lumens of light Lux the definition is
a lumen
per meter squared
is a is a lux some lights about ten
thousand
foot candles by the way FC we used to
use those is a lumen
per foot squared
but this is the metric equivalent of
foot candles and we put this in here
just because it tells the brightness of
the light for the human eye it does
nothing directly to do with plants
these turns out have quite a bit to do
with plants because we want to
accurately diagnose subtle differences
in color of plants and the higher this
color Fidelity index the better we can
see the plants so
there you have it five screens first one
is a graph
screens 2 3 4 and 5 are summary metrics
of the light
we hope you love this instrument we've
been using it in my laboratory at the
University The Graduate students and I
and this is the go-to instrument because
it's so fast and easy to use and it
gives you these ratios right on the
instrument itself
thanks for listening
[Music]
thank you