I'm Bruce Bugbee, president of Apogee Instruments  and professor of Crop Physiology at Utah State
University. Today we're going to talk about  new sensors from Apogee and particularly
an extended range quantum sensor. We call that  an ePAR sensor. I'm first going to show you
the sensors and the model numbers,  and then I'm going to go through
why Apogee developed these sensors. It  comes from new research on the effects
of spectra on photosynthesis. So let's  take a look at these sensors here.
These are extended photon flux density,  and the new one we call ePAR. Now these are
similar price, but look what happens. Let's take  this... let's put the pen on green here... First
of all, photosynthesis, we say it starts at  400 nm, it stops at 700 nm, and it's equal
in between. So this area right in here is classic  photosynthetic radiation. We've used that for a
half a century since the days of Keith McCree's  pioneering work. This is called PPFD. I know I
just wrote over that but photosynthetic photon  flux density. Okay and this is the classic Apogee
sensor. This sensor is a big seller for Apogee.  And this one... let me put it under here... model
SQ-500. That's the classic sensor that  measures this radiation that I just
drew in here. So why do we have other  sensors if that's the classic sensor?
There are emerging definitions of photosynthetic  radiation that I'm going to talk about.
First of all, as most people know, here it  is right here — UV radiation right here.
This has some photosynthetic effects. Not  many but some. I'll talk about them. This
radiation out here is far-red. After 700 nm.  This has significant photosynthetic effects.
And I'm going to talk about those  in detail in the next few minutes,
which is why we've developed sensors  to do this. Now this radiation out here
is called extended PFD and Apogee has sold that  sensor now for about a year. It goes all the way
out to 1000 nanometers, and LED lights don't  have any radiation out here, so it doesn't
measure them. Sunlight has lots of radiation  so you can't use that sensor in sunlight. The
breakthrough is Apogee developed a cutoff filter  to cut this off right here, about 750 nanometers,
so that it now gets... and now we've got to show  that in red because it's far red... it now gets
this amount of radiation in here. This is a big  deal because there is a far-red LED that many
manufacturers — most even — are adding to their  lights, and the classic sensor doesn't catch those
photons. It doesn't show them at all, and they  cause photosynthesis. So with this new sensor,
which you know we're working on catchy titles.  So this is extended, lowercase "e", extended PAR
model, SQ-610. That's the one that  captures this extra radiation out here.
There is another Apogee sensor... I'll show  this first... that we call the PAR — for
photosynthetic radiation right here — and the  FAR — for the far-red radiation right here.
This sensor has two detectors in it, and it  measures these separately. It measures the classic
PPFD... I'm going to write that up  here... classic photosynthetic photon
flux density... and it also measures the far-red.  Now this sensor of course can add those two
numbers together to give you a total, but it  does them separately. This is a terrific sensor.
Way cheaper than a spectroradiometer, and it  separately measures these two types of radiation.
It is about 25% more money than the other  sensors. So save up. You could buy the classic or
right now... we'll go back... you could buy either  of these for a little bit more. And they're simple
to use — a single number. Now these are the  sensors. What we call an instrument means a
sensor connected to a meter. And now I'm going to  review the two types of meters that Apogee sells
because it's a package. For many many years,  Apogee has sold this classic meter. There's the
on bottom right there. Couldn't be simpler  to use. You grab it. You push "on" button.
This one does record, but it's  not very elegant for recording.
It's mostly people use it for instantaneous  measurements. And MQ means meter quantum. So
there's the meter quantum with 610, and the meter  quantum with 620. That's the classic package.
To make the jump to light speed with this,  about a year ago Apogee introduced a µCache with
Bluetooth. So now the same sensors plug into this  and it records data for a long time, over a year,
but it also displays the data  to your phone with the Apogee
app that comes with it. When we go to the lab, I'm  old school right? We're just going to make a quick
measurement. I grab this meter because it has one  "on" button. My students laugh at me. They say
"Get with the program. Just get your phone out,  and look at all the data you can collect so fast."
All the students, if this meter is sitting on the  counter they say, "Where's the µCache? That's the
one I want to use. That has more data." They can  put that in a growth chamber, close the door,
and measure what's going on inside. For me, I  could run the cable through the door, and it's
a mess. So this is an up-and-coming instrument  because of the ability to record. It shows both
instantaneous and long-term. There's the picture.  I have one here. A little µCache. I didn't plan to
show it with my phone, but there's some of  the histograms. Here's the PAR-FAR sensor. And
here's the new UV-A sensor in a silver housing.  You can tell the sensors apart because of their
distinctive colors. All right. This is the end of  the section on the new sensors. Let's just review
this because now I'm going to go into why it's  important to measure these. So just to review,
the old classic is extended. It gets this  radiation out in here. The improvement that really
is this ePAR sensor, model 610. Then we go to the  next one. The PAR-FAR sensor. So red and far-red
separately. If you can afford it, this is a great  sensor. But this one doesn't work with a meter by
the way. It's got two outputs. So a single  meter, you have to use this with the µCache.
And then there's the options for the  meters. Okay now we want to talk about
why we want to measure these different types of  radiation. This is a much longer part of this
talk, but you can skip around in  the video to the parts you want.
I like to call this “Towards an optimal spectral  quality for plant growth and development.”
And this is the name of textbooks. But when we  say plant growth, we really mean direct effects on
photosynthesis. The dry weight of the plant gets  bigger. When we say development, we mean plant
shape. The plant: tall, spindly, short, fat.  We can manipulate shape with quality of light,
and we want to know how the quality of light  affects photosynthesis. Plants sometimes get big
because we change their leaf shape. If we  can make a bigger leaf with light quality,
it captures more light, and the photosynthesis  per unit leaf area is really the same.
So this is a tricky thing — and I keep coming  back to this — plant growth and development,
photosynthesis and shape  or morphology of the plant.
This is very significant because in my laboratory  at Utah State University, we have been working on
these two parameters full time to get them right.  Shuyang Zhen and I have published two papers
just in the last year on this exact topic. And  this is primarily on the effects of wavelengths
of light on photosynthesis. They're in these two  papers... we'll put these in green... they're in
“Plant Cell and Environment” and “Frontiers in  Plant Science.” Two of our most prestigious,
high-impact journals. They have long titles. You  can pause this and look at the titles or just
search on Shuyang and Bugbee and you'll find the  papers will come right up in Google Scholar. Both
of them are on the effects of photosynthesis.  This science is what led to the ePAR
sensor. We could see the need for a sensor based  on this work. Here's Shuyang Zhen, and I'm very
pleased to announce that she has now accepted  a position as an Assistant Professor at Texas
A and M University. She's going to be continuing  this work there. It's very exciting work because
it fundamentally changes the definition  of what we call photosynthetic radiation.
We couldn't have done this work without funding  from both NASA and the USDA, and I want to
acknowledge their help. For NASA, we're growing  plants on Mars and a colony on Mars. And for USDA,
back to earth. This is the LAMP project:  Lighting Approaches to Maximize Profit. So it's
a very applied focus project for greenhouses and  growth chambers on earth. We're very grateful to
have this funding to be able to do this work. All  right, let's take a closer look at this. If we're
going to change the definition of photosynthetic  radiation, which has been for years and years
400 to 700 nm. We make students memorize  those numbers over and over again. Those
are the wavelengths of photosynthesis. Now  we're going to... I'll put this in yellow…
400 to 750 nm — another 50 nm. I love  this quote from Carl Sagan in Cosmos,
“Extraordinary claims require extraordinary  proof.” This is an extraordinary claim.
We're going to change this definition. The old  sensors aren't going to capture that radiation.
So here's the extraordinary proof. These are  two slides into the weeds on the biochemistry of
photosynthesis. This isn't just an experimental  measurement, it's supplemented with a lot of
detailed theoretical considerations. And I'll walk  you through this. This is a gorgeous slide made by
my colleague, Marc van Iersel, who is a professor  at the University of Georgia. Shuyang Zhen by the
way got her PhD with Marc working on this stuff.  And then she came to my lab as a postdoc, and
now she's a professor. This is out of “Molecular  Cell Biology, Sixth Edition.” This is a textbook,
but Marc has annotated this with what happens to a  photon. And this is a wonderful little animation.
Here comes a photon. Boom! It hits. It's  absorbed. It's a reaction center. This right here,
electron. Boom! That excites the electron.  It moves up to a higher excitation level.
Then more photons come, hits an absorption site  over here, and that then moves that electron.
Boom! All the way up to there. All the way from  the sun to here, to here, to here, to here,
out. That's called the light reactions  of photosynthesis. And those reactions
make adenosine triphosphate (ATP) and NADPH.  That's the light reactions of photosynthesis. And
if you can answer that on a test, you're ready to  graduate. This is a detailed light reaction. Now
that is a lot of biochemistry, and I  really like physics more than chemistry.
So I made a different diagram. And you can be  the judge of which one's easier to understand.
We know from Albert Einstein and the  Stark-Einstein Law: one photon excites
one electron. That's what Marc’s diagram just  showed us. But now I've got workers on towers
more than the biochemistry of this. Here's the  sun right? So we're going to show the sun here...
same as the other one. The sun is always smiling.  Photons come in. Boom! This guy hits this
platform with the hammer. The electron goes up  here. Another worker catches it. Note that there's
male workers here and female workers doing the  skilled positions at the top. They put it in here.
It turns a mill, and it makes ATP. The energy  for photosynthesis. Another photon comes in.
This one's coming in this way. Boom! Sends it  up here. Another worker puts it in a bucket,
and we get NADPH. This is called Photosystem  II and Photosystem I. We knew one first. That's
why they're backwards. Two happens before  one. But it takes photons from both sides
to do this to fully excite all the electrons  for photosynthesis. Now we have known for over
50 years that this worker right here can be  excited with far-red photons above 700 nm.
But you can see if this guy was the only one that  was excited, this system wouldn't work because
you got to have this side. You’ve got to have him  going up here, and then he does the second jump.
This is synergism. And we've tried with far-red  light and it does nothing, and we say well that's
no good. We've got to have visible light. When we  apply them both at the same time together, this
guy is excited, this one is excited, and the whole  system is more synergistic. Now Shuyang worked
on this in Georgia and showed that there was less  heat produced when she gave plants far-red light.
When she came to Utah we started — this is called  the Emerson enhancement effect because it was
shown by Emerson. Amazingly enough in the 1950s is  when Emerson's… then he was tragically killed in a
crash of a small plane, and no one ever followed  up his work. It's an amazing story in science. So
Shuyang comes along, and we start doing canopy  photosynthesis. Whole canopies of plants in a
closed box. You can measure photosynthesis. And  we get this classic curve with 400 to 700 nm. This
was with lettuce now. And it starts here at zero.  Goes up like this. Three points in this curve.
When we gave them far-red  light, photosynthesis went up.
But right here, this is 400 to 700  nm. We weren't counting it right.
You don't count those photons. Whoa! But it made  photosynthesis go up. These are different levels
went up. So what Shuyang did — graph this  400 to 750 nm. She counted it. Here it is.
And look, all the data follows one nice smooth  curve because we're counting all the photons.
When we got these experimental results  we went, “Wow! This is beautiful.
But so far we've only shown it in lettuce. What  about other crops?” Shuyang did 17 crops: spinach,
basil, kale, sunflower, corn. You can see them  all on here. And this is a picture of the plants
in the chambers one at a time. To make a long  story short, every crop did the exact same thing.
So this effect of far-red photons is universal for  many kinds of crops. This led to what I'd like to
say is going to become a landmark publication  in Plant Cell and Environment from this work.
But we kept going. We kept working on this.  The second paper, which is now published in
Frontiers and Plant Science, looked at what  we call quantum yield over the long term.
So this was like several weeks of a lettuce crop.  And quantum yield is... we have it right here...
moles of carbon fixed per mole of photons  absorbed. It's a very precise measurement of
photosynthetic efficiency and here's 350. This  is µmols... I'll put it over here... µmol m⁻²
s⁻¹. That's PPFD. Note that this one had 350. This  one only had 300. So this one should have been
much less, but we added 50 of far-red. So the sum  of these two is the same, and the quantum yield
is the same. Down here this was with RB as  a red-blue background — like purple light.
And it was the same with purple light. Then  we also did the same thing with white light,
350 and 300 + 50. And the lines are the same.  That's compelling evidence that far-red photons
are equally good to traditional photosynthetic  photons. And that's the underlying reason we need
a sensor that includes them, particularly  for LEDs. Because all those LEDs have
far-red photons now, and we need to measure  them. So that ePAR sensor includes these.
So there's the classic. There's the new 750  nm. The ePAR sensor, if you look at this,
includes some photons here. Those are UV photons.  And now I want to briefly talk about what UV does,
and I'm going to base it both on McCree's  data and our data. Remember? Keith McCree,
he's a wonderful guy, and as a young scientist  I had a chance to meet him. And he said, "Bruce,
what are you working on?" And I told  him. And oh first he’d said, "Bruce,
what's the most important question in your  discipline?" And I thought oh yeah it's
probably this. And he said, "What are you working  on?" And I told him. And he says, "Why aren't you
working on the most important thing in your  discipline? Get back to the lab. Get to work."
It was really inspiring. So he gave us this. Now  we're adding on this. What about right here? Is
this a sharp cut off right at 400 nm? This is  particularly important because now we have LEDs
right in this region right here. I'm going  to show you these LEDs and show you why this
end is also important. Here's four colors  of LEDs... and I'll put this one in blue…
This one, we call violet. We don't have the names  on here. But violet is really quite an efficient
LED, and it's right on the edge right  here. We call it UV. And look at this,
a big part of that sensor is really UV radiation.  Do these cause photosynthesis? Let's take a look.
Are these efficient over here? This sensor is just  inside of UV radiation but 2.22 µmol/J — that's
an efficient LED. If this does unique things, we  need to be putting this in fixtures. These three
are primarily UV. This one though has a tail  in the visible. So this is why we need to know
exactly what's going on right here with  photosynthesis. Look what happens, 65% efficient.
Excellent. 58%. 57%. 49%. These become less  efficient, but if they have unique effects
we need to be using them. This one is becoming  increasingly used. These three are still emerging
possibilities. But if we can show they  help, fixture manufacturers will use them.
Here's the same graph just shown on a bigger  scale. This is UV-C down here, which we're also
studying. This is very damaging, but  you give trace amounts and it has the
potential to do good things. So here's the  same thing. The peak heights are proportional
to their efficiencies or their efficacies.  This is the standard blue right here 450
nm. White LEDs start from this. This is very  common in all fixtures. Here's the violet right
here. We'll put “V” for violet. And then the three  wavelengths of UV. What do they do to plants?
Here's McCree's curve. Everybody shows this,  and we look at it over and over again. What we
just talked about... shown in red... is this curve  right here. We've now got compelling evidence that
we need to shift this. What about this end? Look  at the tail on this end, and compare it to those
three LED curves. What does this look like? Let's  take a deeper dive into McCree's original papers
on this to look at what the photosynthesis looked  like. This is a graph we made from McCree's data.
And here is 400 nm right there. These are plants  from the field, and they sparingly use that UV
light. Growth chamber plants. Wow! Look at this.  The growth chamber plants use the UV light.
I used to think this was because they weren't  used to UV, and they didn't filter it out,
and they used it all the time. But on closer  inspection of his data coupled with our own
data of measurements of plants, now we know this  was just chance. They have used different species
here in the growth chamber and the field. It  isn't because they were grown in the growth
chamber. You just use different species.  Let's take a look at this. There's the UV
that we're talking about. Look at the big error  bars in here. This is a fascinating area of study.
Here's an example: lettuce and cucumber.  Both two high-value common species.
Here's 400 nm right there. Cucumber minimally  uses UV light. Lettuce uses a lot of UV light. It
much more effectively uses those UV photons. Now I  could show you all the other crops we've studied,
but... sunflowers are actually pretty bad.  Sunflowers you'd think they were good. Some
species are even more out here. But there's a  big range of curves in the UV among species. So
for this reason, and I'll stop... We've got  one more summary slide... for this reason
we have made... this is this is the old  data from McCree where it cuts off here.
The new sensor comes out here, comes across at  1.0 all the way across, and then it doesn't have
a sharp cutoff. It counts some of these UV  photons as a tapering response. So the big
advantage is a little bit of UV right here and a  bunch of far-red there. That's the ePAR sensor.
Now I'm going to close with a slide that  summarizes all the types of light on plants.
Blue photons inhibit cell expansion. They make  plants small and compact. Green photons are fine
for photosynthesis, but they're really important  for human vision. If we have green photons,
you can see the plants. Red photons are terrific —  efficient photosynthesis. Our fixtures have a lot
of red photons. Far-red photons do the opposite of  blue. This inhibits cell expansion. These promote
it. So as we go into the future, we're going  to be going back and forth between inhibiting
and enhancing cell expansion with these colors  of light to shape the plant with photobiology.
Here's an example. This happens to be cannabis:  5% blue, 20% blue. We shrunk the plant. Everything
else was identical here. And generally a nice  compact plant is a good thing. But this plant
is also a little bit wider than that plant, and  it captures more light. So you can see how...
now we could put far-red... if I do that in red...  if we put far-red in here, this is going to look
just like that with more blue. It's a  fascinating ability to manipulate plant shape.
Human vision, you can see the green. This is white  LEDs. You can see the plants. There you can’t.
That's significant. Here's far-red  light and lettuce. It's tremendously
valuable. Look at that: 10% far-red = leaf  expansion. It's really valuable for lettuce.
Unfortunately, the far-red light makes most  plants significantly taller. So we have to
be very careful how we use it because it can  easily make tall skinny plants instead of
short compact plants. This is all in front of  us: manipulating far-red, putting it on at the
right place and the right time and the right crop.  But it's a very powerful tool, and that new ePAR
sensor now measures it. Thanks for listening.  We'll talk to you again in another video.