[Music]
This is Death Valley
the hottest place on Earth
at least for now.
For a brief 90 year span, from 1922 to 2013
the title of the hottest place on Earth
actually belonged to Aziziya Libya,
for an air temperature reading of 136° F.
But, no longer.
So how does a location loose the title as hottest place on Earth?
Well, by cheating, intentionally
or more likely unintentionally.
There are many factors that contribute to accurate
recording of air temperature.
Of the 681 page Guide to Meteorological Instruments and Methods and Observation,
produced by the WMO,
pages 43 - 63 provide guidance on proper measurement of air temperature.
Yes it's extremely detailed, but it needs to be
because of all the variables that come into play when recording air temperature.
So let's take a moment and see how Aiziziya lost their world record.
[Music]
Before 1919 the weather station in Aziziya was placed in town.
But in 1919 they moved the station to a hilltop fort
where it was placed on top of black tarmac.
Surface temperature are typically higher than  air temperatures because of solar radiation.
The rays of the sun go down and are absorbed into the surface.
The color of that surface can dramatically change how much heat is absorbed.
Because the weather station was placed above black tarmac
the air above becomes superheated  and artificially high.
Also, the original thermometer had been damaged
and replaced by an uncalibrated thermometer
typically used in a greenhouse or environment not intended for this kind of measurement.
A classic case of using the the wrong tool at the wrong time.
Finally, the usual record keeper was replaced by an inexperienced or untrained observer
who the WHO believes incorrectly read the thermometer
due to that thermometer particular style.
This is assumed due to the change in the handwriting shortly
before the historical measurement.
When you look at the list of evidence and see how the trends changed over time
you can see why the validity of the Aziziya temperature was called into question.
After reviewing the evidence the WMO decertified the 1922 reading
and gave the title of hottest place on earth to Furnace Creek in Death Valley California
for a measurement in July of 1913 for a measurement of 134°F.
(Cough) Did you say 1913?
Since the Aziziya desertification,
The 1913 record in Death Valley has also raised significant accuracy questions.
So could Death Valley loose its title as hottest place on Earth?
Potentially but probably not.
Randy Cerveny a geography professor at
Arizona State University and  member of the WHO stated,
"We accept the Death Valley temperature extreme record."
"Obviously if any new material on it surfaces, We will be prepared to open an investigation,"
"but at this time all available  evidence points to its legitimacy."
If the Death Valley record were decertified
then it's a tie for the third place
with a temperature of 129.2 degrees between Mitribah Kuwait in July of 2016,
and also Furnace Creek in Death Valley of June 2013.
A number that's going to stick.
On a side note there are two recorded measures of 129.9
in August of 2020 and July of 2021
both in Furnace Creek that are currently pending certification.
So how do you increase your measurements accuracy and prevent false readings?
We recommend using a shield that protects the sensor from solar radiation.
A shield like the TS100.
In addition to a shield that protects the sensor from solar radiation
the TS100 also uses a low power fan,
a fan that allows air to circulate and prevent errors caused by stagnant air
sitting inside the sensor body.
Also, being white and reflective reduces the shield's thermal conductivity.
Because of these factors, the TS100 is an excellent solution
if you're wanting a low-cost, high accuracy measurement shield
much like this station in Death Valley.
This station is set up as a collaboration
between Campbell Scientific and the NWS.
So the next time you're going for a world record or looking to get higher quality data
consider using the TS100 a low power,
fan aspirated, temperature  shield from Apogee Instruments.
Thank you so much for  watching and have a great day.