I'm Bruce Bugbee and in this video I
want to talk about our research over
especially over the last 10 years and
even over the last 20 years of the
effects of colors of light on
photosynthesis and plant shape and I'm
calling this towards an optimal spectral
quality for plant growth and development
now what do we mean by plant growth and
development when we say plant growth we
mean an increase in dry weight of the
plants and that directly comes from
photosynthesis when we say development
we mostly mean plant shape is it a tall
skinny plant the short fat plant you can
see you could have the same sized plant
with very different shapes spectral
quality has an effect on photosynthesis
but it has a much bigger effect on plant
shape and most of the time when we're
changing ratios of colors were doing it
to affect plant shape and I'll walk
through this both plant growth and
development plant shape varies among
species different species have different
responses to spectral quality
photosynthesis does not vary among
species much at all but you will see
there's evidence that our historic
definition of photosynthetic photons is
now coming in to questioning so I first
want to acknowledge NASA they have
funded my laboratory now for over 30
years and that has allowed us to do some
very basic research on spectral quality
on photosynthesis and development we
also recently got a grant from the USDA
it's through the University of Georgia
it is called the lamp project lighting
approaches to maximize profits this is a
more applied project to look at
quality and plant shape big implications
for supplemental lighting in greenhouses
big implications for indoor agriculture
and vertical farming so let's get
started let's look at this I want to
acknowledge two people that in the
trenches that did the work
Shu Jung Jin a postdoctoral fellow and
now a research scientist in my lab and
Paul kusuma a PhD candidate he came from
the University of Florida the work I'm
showing you is largely done by these two
young scientist so we talked about what
things affect plant growth and we talked
about nine cardinal parameters and here
they are temperature humidity roots on
temperature nutrients oxygen wind co2
and light the parameter right here on
the top most of the time we're working
to optimize these to use the given light
that that we have and for generations we
haven't been able to change the light we
just optimized what we get from the Sun
now that we can change the light boom it
this is a huge parameter this we change
and then we re optimize everything
depending on the light think about it
when you increase the light it increases
the flux of water through the plant and
that automatically changes everything
changes the nutrient solution ratio to
it that makes more respiration and need
more oxygen they need a lot more water
it means that co2 becomes cost effective
to elevate temperature and humidity are
higher so we need more wind changes to
everything so lights a big deal this
slide summarizes something like 30 years
of photo biology for me personally we
have four categories of light in this
blue photons inhibit cell expansion now
that sounds terrible but if it's stem
elongation blue photons are terrific
they keep plants
shorter there's some variability among
plants but this inhibition of stell SEM
elongation means shorter plants and
that's a huge factor
it also means reduced leaf expansion
which is bad here's an example of blue
photons this is 5% blue right here
let's go back to pin there we go
this is 5% blue right here look at how
tall that is and we increased the blue
to 20 and the height of the plant
decreased so there's the power of blue
fault runs those two plants by the way
our young cannabis plants their medical
hemp we're one of the few universities
in the United States with the license to
study medical him so we're doing
research on hemp along with the many
many food crops green photons facilitate
human vision they're primarily important
so we can diagnose subtle nutritional
disorders insects and disease there's an
old Chinese phrase that says the best
fertilizer is the footsteps of the
farmer and green photons are like
fertilizer because we concede the plants
and diagnose problems in the early days
of LEDs there was a misperception that
green photons were not used efficiently
and we made LEDs with blue and red
photons and that led to lots of problems
we have purple plants you couldn't see
them fortunately those types of LEDs are
diminishing or putting a lot more white
LEDs in our fixtures to get the green
photons so we can see the plants red
photons are terrific they're efficient
photosynthesis they're efficient LEDs
they're like the potatoes of the diet we
want a lot of red photons to drive
photosynthesis even though all of these
drive photosynthesis red photons are
better they're about 15
better than blue photons for
photosynthesis and finally new kid on
the block far red photons enhance cell
division so they counteract the blue in
the same way that blue photons make them
shorter we can bring in the Reds to make
them tall again so the middle categories
here green and red are doing their job
they're the background light the
biologically active colors are blues and
far reds because we can shrink and
switch swell
stems in this business let's take a look
at green photons you can see here's
green lettuce under blue LEDs it looks
purple and this is that's everybody's
scene graphs like this these are not
these are not really these are magenta
colored LEDs but very hard to see the
plants in those alright let's take a
closer look at all of these now here's
far red now this is a little bit of a
small picture but this is white light
and we added in this study Paul kusuma
added 10% of the photons as far red
they're like magic to lettuce they
dramatically improve cell expansion and
we got a much bigger lettuce plant so
for lettuce production for our red is
very powerful color of lake
unfortunately it stops with lettuce most
other species we add far red and we get
tall plants and that's unfortunate but
that's the the nature of far ready but
is still a powerful tool to manipulate
plant growth so there's a summary of
these colors of light now let's take a
look at how much they penetrate leaves
blue is absorbed heavily by chlorophyll
a and B so here's a leaf right here the
top and bottom of a leaf and it's
absorbed in the top layer
compare that to green look at green it
penetrates the leaf all the way to the
bottom
lights up the spongy mesophyll it's it's
terrific for its penetrating power red
is just like blue absorbed in the very
top layer of the leaf it's doesn't
penetrate nearly as well as green and
finally far-red penetrates even better
than green it goes deep into the leaf
and that's a good thing for the cases of
leaf so this is a this is from this
paper right here Broder son and Vogelman
it's a beautiful paper these the nice
images I added the far read they didn't
study far read but but these are nice
side views of a leaf with penetration of
light let's look at efficiency of LEDs
here's our primary colors that we get if
we do efficiency which is watts of
photosynthetic photon out per watt of
electric energy in that's efficiency
because the units in the denominator and
the in the numerator and the denominator
exactly the same Wow blue chips not
fixtures yet just the chips 88%
efficient that's incredible how far boos
have come white LEDs are a phosphor
converted blue and we can get pretty
good phosphorus but white is a little
bit less than the blues 80% and then the
Reds and the far Reds are slightly less
efficient so this is efficiency but we
know that watts of energy doesn't cause
photosynthesis photons cause
photosynthesis so
this column is micromoles of photons per
Joule of the energy and these are the
peak numbers we get up these are
staggeringly high most high pressure
sodium on this comes in at about I'm
gonna put it down here high pressure
sodium comes in at one point seven maybe
one point eight LEDs are approaching
twice the efficiency LED chips not the
fixtures yet let's review this a second
because this is a very confusing to
people what this is it is micro moles of
photons per second divided by joules of
electricity per second and you can see
how this simplifies to micro moles per
Joule a Joule per second is a watt so we
can say micromoles per second per watt
that's the same thing here but it's the
note the key here is that the numerator
is moles of photons the denominator is
electric energy or electric power this
is power to power now this is good news
for the future because eventually these
LEDs make their way into fixtures and we
can do great things with them we don't
want more column what's in that third
column how about the price of these
what's it cost to buy these the cool
lights are mass-produced because of
human lighting in large quantities so
their prices drop significantly compared
to these other colors here's the
relative price 1x for white LEDs 10x for
the Reds and the blues and the far reds
are still the VX this is not an inherent
problem it's just economy of scale as we
make more and more and more of these by
the
Millions these prices will keep coming
down and LEDs will get more
cost-effective let's look at a few
spectral effects these are cannabis
plants close to harvest we did a study
with blue fraction on cannabis this is
4% now for those of you that know blue
fractions this was high pressure sodium
lights these are LEDs all of these
they're all white LEDs with different
fractions of blue and we ramped it all
the way from 4% all the way up to 20%
now in this case there was no difference
on height because we grew in
vegetatively in the same environment and
moved them into this at flowering
what about yield here's the flower yield
no difference it looks like there's a
trend and it goes back down look at the
standard deviations there is no
difference in yield at all among these
treatments it's indicating that the
photosynthesis was similar and all these
treatments and the partitioning to
flowers was similar this is an amazing
slide because there is a lot of people
that really feel that colors of light
are just magic to cannabis yield they
need just the right colors this doesn't
prove they'll never be a difference it's
just in this carefully done study where
all the plants are in one big room and
had the same air the same humidity the
same co2 we didn't see a difference in
yield what about the cannabinoids in the
plants surely this bust of blue must
have done something the next slide is
cannabinoids here's the flowers at
harvest same thing 4 to 20 percent
these were medical hemp so we have
mostly CBD
but some THC look at the THC point six
point six point six
exactly the same there was no effect of
colors of light and ratios of colors and
especially blue on THC production and
there was no effect on CBD either so the
choice of lamp through lighting cannabis
should be based on the economics of the
lights not on the proposed hypothesized
differences in cannabinoid synthesis and
yield of the flowers at least according
to this study we're replicating the
study now but it's a significant finding
for this and I'm still not recommending
any particular lights I'm just saying
the LEDs were no better than the HBS
there were no worse than HBS however if
we did yield per kilowatt-hour
these LEDs would win they're more
efficient than the high pressure sodium
because the light intensity that
photosynthetic photon flux was kept
exactly equal in the study and it took
more energy to make the photons for high
pressure sodium in this treatment I'll
draw it right here here's a high
pressure sodium lamp that has a lot of
thermal radiation it's concentrated a
thousand watts in a small area so to
make the thermal radiation the same we
put a piece of tempered glass below the
light and that blocked even even more of
the light but it made the thermal
radiation more similar among these
treatments because we didn't want to get
differences in this treatment by thermal
radiation we're also studying the edges
of forests synthetic radiation and these
are a couple final slides on that here's
our classic curve this is 400 to 700
which we always say is photosynthetic
radiation this in here is we call it PA
our photosynthetic radiation and
precisely P P F D now look at that sharp
cutoff right at 700 reading a photon at
699 is a valuable and one at 700 one is
not we know it's not sharp
we've just approximated it for years
because it tilts like this but we now
have a very efficient far red LED and it
peaks at seven-thirty looks like this we
have studied that LED for far red and
those photons are photosynthetically
active so we need to rethink our
definition of photosynthesis with this
in mind they're not directly
photosynthetic they're synergistic with
these shorter wavelengths in here and
when they're coupled together they're
synergistic this was discovered in the
1950s by Emerson and it's called the
Emerson enhancement effect but it sat
there for half a century and not we
didn't study an Intel now that we have
far red LEDs were taken a close look at
the value of far-red on the other end of
the spectrum UV photons is this a sharp
cutoff how well are these UV photons
used the next two slides show some of
our work on UV photons here's why those
edges are so important when we look at
the photon flux of these colors we have
a violet LED that Peaks right at 400 can
we effectively use that for
photosynthesis and get a lot of the
value of UV blue LEDs and here's the one
at 7:30 here's 700 right there that's
the 730 LED can we use that one turns
out we can for photosynthesis what about
this one then what about wavelengths in
here you often see pictures of LEDs
showing the energy flux at an energy
basis these are lower than these the
most efficient is blue but that's not
what drives for
synthesis its photon flux when we graph
this same data by photons the Reds and
the blues are virtually identical that's
a tremendous thing this is from a paper
that we recently got published in the
journal Nature LEDs for photons
physiology and food and it analyzes in
this paper that economics of LEDs this
is the very famous McCree curve here's a
picture of Keith McCree as a young
scientist he died just a few years ago
he had a long and distinguished career
he was a physicist that came across the
biology he said well my these biologists
need help and he brought the excellent
physics background with them he this is
his curve laughter how the colors of
light caused photosynthesis it's called
the Makri curve now and he said let's
call it good we'll cut this off at 400
and 700 but our data indicates that this
curve should shift over here some like
this it doesn't it when the because of
the synergist 'm synergism of far-red it
shifts that curve this curve also tilts
and these photons just below 400 are
pretty good but when you carefully read
macri's papers they're 700 there's 400
you see this graph now this graph this
is this this is exactly the same as this
it's just graphed a little bit
differently
these are and here's 400 and 700 these
bars right here were the range of
species
from his paper my students and I made
this graph from his data there was very
little variability among species in his
data but what people forget is that he
also in addition to taking plants from
the field
he took plants from a growth chamber he
grew him in a growth chamber look at the
difference some of these photons right
here are almost as good as red and
they're close to UV photons there was an
enormous range of variability among
species in Makris trials so we're
examining this part of the curve right
now particularly with violet LEDs which
are just right here on the edge our
hypothesis is that the field growing
plants synthesize compounds to block UV
to protect themselves and once they
synthesize those the UV photons were not
effective in photosynthesis those
companies are made in the cuticle but
the growth chamber plants that didn't
see UV didn't make the compounds and now
the UV photons are valuable so this is a
cutting edge of the research we're doing
on photo biology and I'm going to stop
here and I will pick this up in another
video thanks for listening