This is the user guide for the Apogee Guardian.
[Music]
The Apogee Guardian is an all-in-one  Greenhouse monitor.
The Guardian features five different sensors providing nine different metrics,
and gives you the option to access them using one app.
The Apogee Guardian comes in two different  models the SM-500, which features a PAR sensor,
and the SM-600, which features an ePAR sensor.
The entire shroud is an aspirated shield for the  temperature sensor which you can see at the bottom.
The Guardian will take air and pull it up through the housing past the temperature sensor.
and then disperse that air out the top the top.
The bottom of the Guardian is held on by magnets and when  removed we'll give you access to the humidity,
the CO2, and the pressure sensors.
To put the bottom back on, line it up, and should snap right back on because it's held on by magnets.
Keep in mind the Guardian is waterproof from falling rain.
You don't want to spray water up into the unit,
because it could damage the components of the Guardian.
Inside the Guardian case it comes with a wire hanging kit.
and a power adapter.
To power on the Guardian,  pull the connector from the housing.
Line up the pins.
Connect the connector,
and finger tighten the metal rings.
Then, add power.
Make sure that when you power on the Guardian the  bottom is free and clear from any obstructions.
That way the air can freely flow through  the device and it won't over stress the fan .
The Guardian is powered on  but is not collecting any data.
To take data, you need to either use the Modbus protocol,
or use the Bluetooth Apogee Connect app.
To use the wire hanging kit,  first locate the wire kit hanging connection points .
There are three of them.
Take the clip, line it up from the bottom,
and push up.
It'll make a popping sound as it connects into place.
Do that for all three sides.
It should look something like this when you're done.
You can hang it from the hook,
or loop and then connect to the hanging kit itself.
To remove the hanging kit, pull the clips outward.
They should pop right off.
Available for the Guardian is the multi-position mast mount.
The mast mount features a u-bolt that allows  you to mount to various sizes of mast.
First,
Tighten the u-bolt onto the mast mount.
Orient the clip so that the Bubble Level is facing up.
Rotate the knob clockwise to increase tension.
When you found the appropriate tension,  pull the connector away from the Guardian,
and hook on the mount.
Push the top clip down to lock it into place.
Use the bubble level on top to orient  the Guardian in a horizontal position.
Simply connect power and you're ready to go.
To remove the Guardian from the mast mount,
take the clip on the back side,  push towards the Guardian and up.
The retaining clip on the top should lift. At this point you can lift and pull away the Guardian.
With the Guardian mounted and powered on you're  ready to begin taking measurements.
To use the Modbus protocol look at the user manual below  in the description for details on how to set  up using Modbus.
Right now I'm going to show you  how to use the Apogee Connect app.
First, you need to install The Apogee Connect app.
You can get the Connect app at the iTunes Store  or at the Google Play Store.
When you open the software it'll look similar to this.
Mine has several sensors already connected.
Yours will probably be blank.
To add a sensor go to the plus sign up in the top left corner.
It will begin searching for devices .
Find the device and click on it.
When it's connected you can  then change the name of that device.
We're going to change this to "SM 500 demo."
Then hit add.
When it's added you can scroll down  and see that it's connected.
If you want disconnect the device press and hold and swipe from the right .
It'll give the option to forget or to disconnect.
If you want to realign where your sensors are on the list,
Press and hold and you can slide them up and down.
On the home screen it'll give you a quick overview  of the device's measurements.
Let's look at those measurements in detail.
Click on the device.
From here it'll show you the readings as  well as what logs are available to collect .
If this is your first time setting up the device  click on the settings icon to set up your device.
From here you can either set up custom  calibrations dark offsets and enable logging.
We want to make sure we  do that so click on little toggle.
From here you can set how often you want to take  your samples and how often you want them to be logged.
We're going to change our sampling interval  to every 10 seconds and then log them every minute.
When you're done press the save button.
The device is now logging data.
Below you'll see the notify when full option.
Enable this if you'd like to receive a notification when  the memory on the Guardian is almost full.
After some time there'll be some data available.
To collect that data press the collect logs button.
From here you have the option to create a  new data set or to add to an old data set.
We're going to create a new data set.
We're going to call it "data set demo."
Click in the bottom right corner under collect logs.
It will begin to download that data.
Depending on how much data you have to collect  it may take a minute.
Once you've collected that data you can scroll down  to see those metrics displayed in graph form.
You can see things like: the DLI photoperiods,
PAR, temperature, all the metrics that the  Guardian measures will be there in displayed form.
On the icons below you have the option to switch your data set  export your data set  and delete data sets.
This also has the option  for a live meter mode.
Click on the live meter.
It will instantly begin to show you real-time  data of what the Guardian is collecting.
As it takes samples it will begin  to display in graph form.
With that you should have what you need  to get started with a Guardian.
If you have  any questions please feel free to leave a comment  in the comment section below,
or refer to the user manual found in the description below.
Thank you so much for watching  and have a wonderful day.
Thank you.