Is your PAR meter no longer giving you  readings that you can trust?
Are you seeing less than reliable results than when you  first set up your meter several months ago?
Before you replace your meter try these few steps.
First, make sure that your meter is clean.
Blocking the optical  path between the source and the sensor can cause low readings.
Dust, dirt and other debris can be cleaned from the sensor.
Using a non-abrasive cloth or cotton swab
sprinkled with deionized water or window cleaner.
Calcium deposits from irrigation water can leave a thin white film on the surface
that can be removed using a  diluted acid such as vinegar.
So make sure that you are cleaning your sensor regularly.
All right you cleaned your sensor,
but the measurements still  don't seem quite right.
Let's find out what they should be.
The team at Apogee has created a tool
that allows you to see what PAR, ePAR, UV and shortwave radiation
measurements should be
under ideal conditions.
That way you can see just how far off  your meter is.
It's called the clear sky calculator.
This tool is found at  ClearSkycalculator.com
and it works with all power meters  not just Apogee meters.
Ideally the measurements on your meter  should be taken as close to solar noon,
at summer solstice,
in non-polluted Skies, minimal humidity
and the sensor perfectly level.
Be aware this calculator will  give you an ideal number.
So if you have less  than ideal conditions,
be aware that your numbers  may be a little bit off.
This tool is not to be  used for calibration
Its purpose is to identify if meter readings  are drastically out of spec.
To use the calculator take a measurement from your meter
and enter that measurement  into the PPFD field.
Enter your ZIP code, country, date and time
and then hit calculate.
The calculator will show you how far off your meter is measuring.
If it's "off" by more than 10%  a button will appear
with a contact Apogee for recalibration button.
Keep in mind, it's a mathematical model with limitations.
But if you still feel that your  meter is out of spec
then you can send it in for recalibration.
After recalibration you can get back  to confident data acquisition.
[Somber Music]
Unfortunately, over time all  PAR meters will begin to drift.
Don't worry, it's not your fault.
Factors such as age, usage,  and environmental conditions
can all affect the accuracy  of every PAR meter.
[Music]
Being familiar with a sensor specifications, operation and measurements
will help you recognize errors  before days or weeks
worth of data become unreliable and unusable.
Apogee Instruments has built a reputation  of not just creating accurate PAR meters
but of PAR meters that stay accurate.
That's why we offer an  industry-leading 4-year warranty
on all of our PAR products.
But at some point every part meter  is past its expected life.
[Music]
So how bad is it?  Give it to me straight doctor.
[Doctor] "time of death"
[Doctor] "4:20"
Luckily, if the unfortunate does  occur,
Apogee will provide a discount  on a replacement meter.
If you have anyquestions feel free to leave them in the comment section below.
Thank you so much for watching  and have a good day.
[Music]