I'm Bruce Bugbee, professor of crop physiology here at Utah State University. And in this
short video, we're gonna give you an overview of the medical hemp research we're doing in
the crop physiology laboratory here at Utah State University. We've had numerous questions
from many people: What kind of research do you do? How do you do the research? What are
you finding? And today I just want to show you some of the techniques that we use. I
think I’d like to start with this plaque right here. We were told when we started that
the university had a huge research program in hemp in the 1930s. So we went to the University
Library in Special Collections, and here's a picture of people from 1931 showing the
hemp in the fields. Back then they were growing it for rope and the fibers. And the work was,
grow hemp. The Navy needs the rope. Now we have synthetic fibers. The value for rope
is much less. We still grow it for textiles, and we still grow it for seed for eating.
But our research here is focused on botanical medicines. And medical hemp allows us to study
botanical medicines. When you think about it, we have a lot of people with many problems
with prescription drugs － opioids. Botanical medicines are far safer. We know that. We
just have to understand how their use is in pharmacology. We've had conversations with
the medical school at the University of Utah to study the pharmacological uses. And so
what we're doing here is optimizing yield and quality of the flower buds, which are
then extracted for CBD oil primarily. All of our work is low THC lines of cannabis,
but it's still cannabis sativa. So there's many people in Utah, there's eight or ten
growers, that have licenses to grow high THC cannabis. And we're working with them to optimize
their work as well. But I want to say our license here is just to grow hemp. But after
doing many studies, we know that we can extrapolate most things from hemp to marijuana because
it’s the same genus and species. So this is from a lecture from yesterday in crop physiology.
This is the laboratory, the teaching laboratory, where we work. And we wanted to start here
and then walk around the greenhouse and the growth chambers to give you a sense of how
we do this work. The types of studies that we do at a world-class laboratory for controlled
environment research. We have been funded in this laboratory for almost 40 years by
NASA. And all of the work for NASA has been to grow plants in closed environments for
feeding people in space. Whether it's a colony on the moon, our current project is a colony
on Mars, feeding people on the space station. We've worked with NASA to fly plants in space.
We bred a unique line of wheat called Apogee wheat for use in space. So we've had a long
close partnership with NASA. About four years ago, a consortium of large greenhouse growers
in North America came to me and the lab and said, “Could we fund you to study hemp?
We're growing it. We need to understand it. This is a complex crop.” At the time, we
had to tell them no you cannot fund us. It's not legal federally. About 15 months ago,
it became legal federally, and we immediately got the green light. We got licenses from
the state of Utah to study hemp. So we switched part of our research capability from studying
food crops in controlled environments for NASA to studying the quality of medical hemp
for use in pharmaceuticals. That's what we want to give you a sense of how we do the
research and where we publish the results. Let's go to the greenhouse and take a look.
Follow me. We'll walk out from the growth chamber to the greenhouse. Let's stop right
here. We recently got funded by NASA to make an improved system to grow plants on the space
station. And this is the press release from NASA, and this is a picture of the system
we're proposing. It looks pretty high-tech. It looks pretty complicated. But it is not
easy to water plants in space. It's easy to overwater them because the water doesn't drain
out of the pot. So we've had flooded plants in space. We've had drought stress plants
in space. Our new system is loaded with sensors to keep the light exactly right. Keep the
oxygen in the root zone exactly right. So we're excited to be working with NASA to make
a high-tech system for the space station. So now we go. This is the graduate room here.
Graduate students have offices. This is some of our recent publications. There's some pictures
of people that work in the lab. Here's a cosmonaut on the International Space Station holding
the wheat that we developed for space. They become real psychologically attached to the
wheat as you can see, and sometimes they don't want to harvest if. They want to keep looking
at it. Here's our work on medical and industrial hemp right here. And some of our recent publications.
Here's one on far-red photons and their photosynthetic value. Precision water stress. Plant breeding.
We do a lot of work on hydroponics in this lab, and a lot of work on photobiology. So
let's walk and talk. Keep coming with me. Now we're going out in the greenhouse. There's
multiple research scientists in here that do a lot of work, and they're all different
sections. This is one where we're studying types of media. Can we use sawdust in media
to reduce cost? This section is for our student organic farm. They're getting ready for spring
scale up. But the section that I want to show you is this one right here. You can see this
is a secure section. Here's our certificate to study medical hemp － medical and industrial
hemp. This is where we keep our genetics. And these are all mother plants that are under
long days with high pressure sodium light to keep them vegetative. And we take cuttings
from these and propagate them over there. We're working right now with about 12 lines.
The growers around the nation send us their genetics, and say here to test my new line.
So we're continuously getting new lines of cannabis in here, and I should specifically
say medical hemp, to grow. That's why some of these are taller and shorter. We enrich
out here with high pressure sodium lights to keep them vigorously growing. So we're
getting about 600 µmol of photons. This is an averaging bar for the light. This keeps
the plants growing vigorously all throughout the winter. So we monitor the light in here
carefully. This section is CO₂ enriched. So here's an aspirated shield in which we
carefully measure temperature and humidity. And this is a CO₂ sensor. And that's connected
over here. Now the fans just came on. This is our system for monitoring CO₂ in here.
So it's another thing we monitor and control for optimal growth. You can grow cannabis
without CO₂, but it grows better with it. Over here we're studying oxygen nanobubbles.
This is a special system. This happens to be made by the Moly A company. It puts microscopic
bubbles of oxygen in the water to improve aeration of the root zone. And we’re working
with them to optimize aeration. We're also working with them for plants on the space
station. So this is one of our mother plant greenhouses where it starts where we take
cuttings and grow uniformed plants that we move into the growth chambers. So now let's
move into the growth chamber room and take a look at
what we're doing in there. So here's our growth chamber room... we have about 40 growth chambers
in this lab for testing various things. Some are big. Some are little. And we're remodeling
all the time to keep them updated for the research. Let's start over here. All of our
work is basically hydroponics because we make concentrated nutrient solutions and inject
them into the water. So what comes out is the plants are getting watered with nutrient
solution every time they’re watered. And it's all on drip irrigation. So let's take
a look at one of the chambers right now. You can look at the plants through the window.
But for this video, we're going to open the door. Take a closer look at the plants. These
plants are, I'd have to look at the door, but they're about 21 days after what we call
the inductive photoperiod － short days. They’re all starting to flower. This is
part of a temperature study. So we want to optimize the temperature for these, but temperature
interacts with light. So we're forever in here measuring the light to make sure the
light’s exactly the same in all the chambers. The chamber comes with a light sensor in the
middle. This particular chamber... I have to look... this is at 29 degrees Celsius.
So this is one of our warmer treatments. But the plants are growing real well in here.
Everything we do is by Julian date. Starts with day one. Goes to day 365. To keep track
of all the studies starting and stopping at different times. So let's walk and look at
these. A second chamber. This one's 26 Celsius. 26 Celsius 79 Fahrenheit. This is intermediate.
The plants still look good. Now all of these are continuously monitored for temperature,
humidity, and light by a Campbell scientific datalogger hooked up to computer screens so
we can make sure that controls are working all the time. This chamber is at 23 Celsius.
And what you can see is it's a little on the cool side. It's not doing as well as those
chambers at warmer temperatures. It'll be okay, but 23 is a little on the cool side
for cannabis. So far. This has still got a ways to go till harvest. There's one other
study I'd like to show you. It's over here. These four chambers
are four different treatments. What we're studying in here is the effect of light pollution
on cannabis. We know it needs to be dark at night. But exactly how dark? We coined the
term reagent grade darkness to mean really dark. Is the full moon bright enough to trigger
anything? The answer to that is no. But how much light can they take? So let's take a
look. All four of these are the same. These are LEDs. And it's going to be real hard to
see, but right up in here is a little tiny red LED that gives them a tiny bit of red
light at night. And you can see some of the plants are flowering. It depends on how bright
the lights are. All of these chambers look the same. They just have different amounts
of red. So we're trying to zero in on how much light the plants can take. For these
studies, Apogee has developed a special sensor. We call it the nano mol sensor. It detects
trace amounts of light. So we can extrapolate the results from here to all grower’s operations.
Cannabis is one of the most sensitive plants to light pollution. So far our data indicate
it's about the same as poinsettias. And they're quite a sensitive crop. But the data is not
all in. We do studies. We create different treatments. We do more studies. This is how
they work. Let me show you this. All the plants get drip irrigation with the nutrient solution.
And for this, it’s a pretty big container, to make sure they're not at all stressed in
the root zone. So this is our special medium. It’s a peat vermiculite media that we make
ourselves to get optimal plant growth. I think this is a good place to stop for this growth
chamber room. Now let's take a look at one other room where we're doing studies on light
quality. This is the laboratory right outside my office. And these are award plaques from
previous students over the years that when they've graduated we give them an honorary
degree in something unique. I've been doing this for coming up on 40 years. So we’ve
got a lot of students over the years. These are small chambers that we use. The size and
shape of the chamber on the space station. And we're in between studies right now here.
But here's where we create our own light and precisely study qualities on young plants.
What we really want to take a look at is this chamber right here. And you can see this one's
pretty heavily instrumented. So in this chamber we're studying light quality. And you so can
see right from here we've got three types of lights. These are about two and a half
weeks from harvest. They're high pressure sodium lights, LEDs, different ratios of colors.
We can do five treatments at once. We take our Apogee spectroradiometer and characterize
the ratios of colors. Here's another side here. High-pressure sodium, which makes the
plants look orange or gold. And then LEDs in this one, which has a much better color
rendering index. This is one of the things we're finding is we can diagnose plants much
better under LEDs because the colors are more true. It's hard to tell subtle nutritional
effects under high-pressure sodium light. So now we're in the hallway to wrap up. We're
thrilled that we finally have funding to do some serious science on medical hemp and cannabis.
The universities of the world really have had limited ability to study this until the
last year or two. And in our case, we were able to transition part of our work with NASA
to immediately get a jumpstart on the studies with hemp. I think what we'll do is just walk
down the hallway here. But we have years and years of students that have done studies.
And I can show you a few posters. This is Curtis Adams who is now an assistant professor
at Texas A&amp;M. He studied polymer coated, slow-release fertilizers. Polyon Nutricote and Osmocote
for his work. Nutricote’s the most expensive, but it was the highest quality that we tested.
Because of this work, which was funded by NASA, NASA switched from Osmocote to Nutricote
for studies in the space station. So walk down here. This poster is turning yellow because
it's so old. This is some of our early work with nutrient management in closed hydroponic
systems. Here's a picture of our wheat. And we have written several papers on this. Every
one of these posters turns into refereed journal articles. Here's high pressure sodium technology
advances with double-ended lamps. This is Jacob Nelson. He is now a PhD student at the
Max Planck Institute in Germany. He’s a terrific student highly recruited by them.
Did some nice work. This is lysimeters － weighing of plants to precisely measure transpiration
rates. Mark Van Iersel is now an assistant professor at the University of Georgia. And
Julie Chard was our research associate that did all this work. We can track transpiration
and stomatal conductance over time on these computerized lysimeters. We've done a lot
of work on chlorophyll, and it's led to some commercial meters. Chris Perry is now a research
scientist for Pioneer Seed Company. This was his work on measuring chlorophyll in leaves
using optical meters. And that led to, well it led to the Apogee chlorophyll meter (MC-100).
Take one more minute to show you a few more posters. Paul Kusuma is a current PhD student,
and this poster showed our interest in light quality and plant growth. And you can see
the title. Because of this we coined this term: the
FAR-PAR index. And what that is is a ratio of far-red light to traditionally photosynthetic
light. And it's just a number from zero to one. And this work showed that our old approach
of measuring phytochrome photo equilibria was not as good at predicting stem elongation
as this new FAR-PAR index. Since we're here, this is phytochrome photo equilibria. It requires
a spectroradiometer. And you can see, depending on the background of light, these lights aren't
together. This is R-FR ratio. The lines still aren't together. This is the FAR-PAR index.
Look, the lines converge. So this is why we've gone to reporting this in our studies because
regardless of background colors of light we get consistent results from far-red. Another
paper by Jacob Nelson. We've done dozens of studies of light quality in this lab. This
went all the way back to fluorescent lights. This was some of the early
days of LEDs. Characterizing them. Here's vegetative propagation of cannabis. And when
we were working out procedures to get it to root quickly, all that work was done here
and presented at national conferences. Some cannabis in the field is grown from seed,
but the absolute highest quality is grown from rooted cuttings. And you want to be able
to get a hundred percent rooting from those cuttings. This is my colleague Larry Rupp
who has since retired. And Sabrina Sage who is an outstanding undergraduate student that
did this work. Here's a little bit of the work that we've done for NASA. Food production
on Mars. Ultra-violet and far-red. The ultraviolets here. The far-reds here. Both of them affect
plant growth, so we manipulate them in different ratios. We just got a paper accepted for publication
in the journal, Nature. Horticulture research on this topic right here. It's called “Current
and Potential Efficacy of LEDs.” So it peers into the future and analyzes how good can
LEDs get within the next five years. Here's another poster in the hallway. This one's
been up here a while. We've done a lot of breeding of super dwarf plants. Extremely
short because they work very well for NASA in the space station research. It turns out
they work well for lots of people around the world doing
research in controlled environments because they're so compact. Some of these we developed.
Some of them we got from breeders in other places. But they're so short that they are
not commercially available. So we maintain the seed stocks here for research scientists
and other places and provide seed for them. So we're back in the classroom to conclude.
And I want to make the point that we don't just study hemp in this lab. Even though we
did look at hemp plants just now. But the NASA funding, none of that is for hemp. All
of that is for food crops, leafy greens, to provide fresh vegetables for astronauts. Tomatoes.
All kinds of fresh crops. Over the years we've studied a lot of agronomic crops, too. Particularly
wheat. So we're doing multiple things. And it really is because of sustained funding
for a long time. We've been able to attract some of the best talent from around the nation
in terms of graduate students because they're the lifeblood of this whole operation. The
work that they are doing is just terrific. I think something like eight of my former
students are now assistant professors at other universities. So it's been a great thing because
after they graduate and leave we continue to work with them. Thanks for listening. Talk
to you again in a future video.