what's up this is Gabby Staten Island
here on the craft Growers Network and I
wanted to take this opportunity to share
a little bit of my story and thoughts
for the new year this is something until
now only friends of mine knew about in
2017 Soma County was ravaged by a
terrible fire at the time my daughter
Lily was 3 weeks old my fianceé Leah had
postpartum preclampsia which is quite
dangerous the police pounded on our door
at 2 a.m. telling us we needed to leave
we left with nothing but a diaper bag we
left cash pounds of flour my entire
collection of seeds I had made and saved
and all of our belongings I left with
slippers no shoes I even left my wallet
we thought we were leaving as a
precaution but we didn't believe our
house would burn down and we would lose
everything which we did we got a hotel
with a help from someone in line at a
hotel because we had no cash or a wallet
that morning we awoke to the reality
that we had lost everything I'll never
forget that day Ben from IC Collective
sent someone over to our hotel with a
giant bag of weed rosin a dab rig and a
torch our landlord put us up in his home
and he moved out into his mother's so we
could have a place to live and all of
our friends and family showed love and
support they brought us food and so much
clothes was donated to us since we
literally left with the clothes on our
back is one of the worst things that
ever happened to me but in this terrible
time I saw how much we were really loved
by our friends and family and it
continued to give us strength to
continue on 2 years later tragedy hit us
again my grow shop burned to the ground
because of a faulty plug that had
nothing plugged into it besides a Wi-Fi
router fires got us again then Co hit
the accumulation of all these events
spun me into a deep depression it was a
very dark time for me I remember
sleeping in my Dusty dirty van one night
because Le and I were fighting W ing it
was really cold I had no blankets and I
was truly wishing I was dead but I knew
I couldn't leave my family like this I
pushed on started working at commercial
Farms as cultivation director and it was
the first time I had a job in a while
but I was just lucky to have an income
so I could support my family I was still
suffering from depression and did not
know how to relieve it I think it was
2021 that LE and I went to a concert at
the Mystic Theater in Petaluma that
concert saved my life from a life of
depression the artist was Mike love his
music was beautiful and his message was
so powerful there was this one song
titled be thankful and I'd like to read
to you a little bit of the lyrics right
now be thankful for whatever you got cuz
you better be sure that you're not
ungrateful cuz this life is a gift and
the more you receive should be the more
that you give so many contemplating
whether their cup is half empty or the
cup is half full it's just a bunch of
[ __ ] be thankful be thankful hey my
brother why you wearing that frown has
the system been cheating you beating you
and holding you down you've lost sight
of everything that you stood for and now
you're caught up in the Glamour and they
got you wanting more more of their
Illusionist hypnotist politrix they got
you on a puppet string dangling it makes
me sick just to see how long it's been
we been held captive as prisoners in our
very own skin but listen up my brethren
because my friend just when you think
that it that things couldn't get no
worse remember that the last shall be
the first be thankful for whatever you
got cuz You' got to be sure that you're
not
ungrateful and there's much more I'm
going to put a
link in the description and I hope you
guys will listen to the rest of that
this song and Mike Love's music changed
my life it changed my complete Outlook
it made me realized how lucky and how
blessed I am to have the most beautiful
family I have the most amazing friends
and I live in Northern California so I
make an effort to remind myself every
day how lucky I am I tell my family and
my friends how much I love and
appreciate them
so now to more current times I was
invited to a group on Reddit by Cosmic
who's now a regular co-host on the
channel I made some friends there
including wolf who's also a co-host on
the channel I'm so grateful for these
guys and I try to tell them every time
we talk Cosmic he's the one that
encouraged me to just make the first
podcast he offered to help and he he
recorded it for me on Zoom he also
taught himself to do meisam tissue
culture and has inspired me to restart
my tissue culture education you can find
him at Cosmic strains official on
Instagram wolf he reminds me of NATO dog
in all the best ways he's softs spoken
and so intelligent he's been growing for
four years but has been so immersed in
education I believe he's more
knowledgeable than many people growing
for decades I'm learning from him every
day but most important he's been a great
friend that I can lean on and ask advice
and get honest responses from you can
find him on Instagram at mrwolf grows
Sasha I met Sasha I think about 8 weeks
ago he messaged me on Instagram telling
me he enjoyed one of the podcasts we
started talking and I was not only
immediately intrigued by his nursery and
what growing in Australia and Slovenia
was like but I was also Amazed by how
similar our lives were we made an
immediate connection and we talk almost
every day for extended periods of
time I would tell you how to find Sasha
on Instagram but his Instagram handle
this crazy something like quality Grow
shops I bertics we need to work on that
we got to get him the uh Slovenian
Hobbit uh Instagram but for now I'll
just tell you I'll put his um Instagram
contact in the um
description I'm so grateful for these
guys and I wanted to put that out there
for everyone to
hear our guests we have had some amazing
guests from old friends like NATO dog
the weasel Mike klopp Michael wolf
seagull and Dell whose episode hasn't
been released yet to Mark Gallow Kevin
jrey Chad Westport and Boston Rob whose
episode I also haven't released yet I'm
so grateful for all of them they have
not only helped our show take off on a
traj trajectory I'm struggling to
believe but they've taught me things and
I believe I will have longlasting
friendships with them I can only assume
you can tell how much my friendships
mean to me finally our
viewers when I made this podcast I told
people I didn't care if anyone enjoyed
the podcast I told them I was doing it
for myself but I never thought about how
much I'd appreciate it if it was enjoyed
by viewers finally our viewers when I
made this podcast I told people I didn't
care if anyone enjoyed this podcast I
told them I was doing it for myself but
I never thought about how much I'd
appreciate it if it was enjoyed by
viewers
if you told me two months ago when we
started this that all of our videos
would get thousands of views right out
of the gate and there would be no hate
in the comments and nothing but
positivity and love I wouldn't believe
you I'm grateful for you all the
positive responses encouraged me to
continue to build this network into the
best we can I know I've gone on for a
long time but hey my name is Gabby I
just want to end it by saying if you're
listening to this I'm grateful for you
and I look forward to making better and
better content for you in the near
future Happy New Year