this episode of gabbing with Gabby is
brought to you by the Breeders direct
Seed Company in my opinion the Breeders
direct seed company is your Premier
Source for clones and seeds and they are
the only place that you can get the
Gabby Staten Island collection so visit
breeders direct for all your seed and
clone needs
[Music]
what's up everybody this is Gabby Staten
Island and this is the craft Growers
Network and we have um an exciting
interview today with Mark Gallow say
hello Mark hey howdy everybody happy
holidays uh it's a pleasure to be here
and uh chop it up you know um
I'm Marcus ailith 95 on Instagram Golden
Road seed company and I work with uh the
grateful Head LLC which uh we'll be
delving into a little bit during the
show great and these are my co-hosts my
Slovenian Hobbit
brother also known as Sasha hey
everybody go ahead and Sasha tell
everybody a little bit about yourself
before we get started yeah we I met
Gabby like what what is it now 20 days
ago over Instagram and uh we've been
connecting like you don't connect
normally like this every day to to
somebody so I instantly also knew that
he's a brother you know from another
mother and uh yeah you know this Our
Generation I think is one of these
Generations that lived through sometimes
that if you know somebody you don't need
to hear a lot and then you it's just
natural it happens it's like this
chemistry right
um and actually the after these two
podcast now uh I'm really I mean it's
it's normalized now for me that we we
are we are communicating so much
actually because like you know I want to
to to maintain this all the way through
and I'm really happy that you invite me
all the time to this podcast because I
think I represent a lot of the Europeans
uh Growers and craft uh people in kabes
that maybe um should also have a voice
and uh in the future I think there will
be others that will join the
conversation yeah that's beautiful in
international connectivity through the
plant we l is a beautiful thing yes and
exactly we we also have Nick wolf here
joining us and I met Nick through um the
craft marijuana Reddit and we started
communicating and it was similar to my
relationship with my my Slovenian Hobbit
brother I you know when we started
talking I just I wanted to know more
about him and he helped me with our
first podcasts I'm super grateful for
him I think he really
contributes um to what we're doing here
he's got a wealth of knowledge and uh
I'll let you tell a little bit about
what you're doing as well Nick while I
lower my
heat yeah yeah I'm uh I'm Nick wolf or
Mr Wolf grows on Instagram and Reddit
and I'm a you I'm a moderator for the
the craft marijuana subreddit and I also
I'm a a manager or one of the
cultivation managers for uh ta
cultivators in Oregon that's a small um
indoor with a two acre outdoor that we
do and uh yeah I'm a hobbyist Enthusiast
for the
plant we might have one more person
joining us is name is Cosmic he's got a
company called Cosmic strains and he's
kind of our producer here
um none of us are getting paid for doing
this podcast so he has other
responsibilities he has to tend to but
hopefully he will join us he helped me
record my first podcast um we did it on
zoom and and he just recorded me and I'm
so grateful for him because he helped
break the seal you know like or the way
Sasha says you know he helped me turn
over the Rock and once it's turned over
it's hard to hard to close it you know
it's like opening up the box you can't
close it um he's a great guy he's doing
marem tissue culture at home you know
which I think is pretty interesting you
know there's a lot of people doing Nal
tissue culture you know as a hobby and
as a home thing but he's actually doing
marem tissue culture at home so I think
that uh he has a lot to offer people on
this network as well so we're going to
get started and the first thing I want
to do is um tell Mark what we're trying
to do is give you an opportunity to tell
your story okay and we don't want The
Abridged version we want you to you know
tell us your whole story let's start
let's start from you know how you were
originally exposed to cannabis and you
know move your way through what you're
doing
today I originally was exposed to weed
at around the age of 12 and I lived in
Lower bux Town EPA north of Philly and
it was um I'd say a reasonably affluent
community and directly across the street
my best friend lived and it was housing
projects but I got along with everybody
and I would hang out there I would play
basketball that's where all my friends
were and back then nobody really cared
there wasn't as much as a sigtigma it
seemed so I would be across the street
playing basketball and my best friend
lived there and he called me over one
day his um brother-in-law was a weed
dealer and he had managed to to snag a
handful of roaches from the ashtray so
the very first time from uh the the the
sister husband was a dealer so he lifted
some right from the ashtray and uh I
remember clear's day um we had a ball
field near the highway where we' play
baseball and there was a malberry tree
there and he rolled this big pregnant
duber out of all the roaches and I can
remember just sitting under the tree
like oh my God my whole world just
exploded and I was like wow that's what
this is and uh it lasted forever and I
remember it it lasted long enough that I
was uh wary of headed right home to let
let my my parents see I was definitely
not trying to get caught then at the
early age and uh that sparked to the in
that got the ball rolling and uh
eventually a few years later after that
happened um my family decided it would
be better to move me from the city into
a more rural situation and they bought a
bunch of horses and a farm and uh that's
where where it really ramped up so
having compost as a kid you know it's
the last place you want to have to do
weed whacking and in gardening and we
had a huge Manor pile and I always took
notice how big all the weeds got in the
pile so my family inadvertently hired
dead heads as Farm hands not knowing see
where I'm going with this what a dead
head was and I was I was in M Glory I'm
like I work with these guys so long
story short they were getting really
high-end Imports back then we're going
back to
1982 83 as a 13-year-old I'm I'm on this
farm
so I would I would buy 50 $50 ounces of
high-end Imports that came from like the
Le Mexico there were some ties back then
and it wasn't bricked the way we know it
fully it was compacted and it was just
very lightly feeded so uh I remember
getting the out I'd pay them and they'd
hide it in the mailbox after the mail
people already came my parents wouldn't
find it so when I'd pay them I'd walk
down to the mailbox you know at 12:00
and uh grab my out in this particular
bag that uh was B I believe it came from
B I really love so I already knew where
I was going to put it because I had a
man nor pile so the first feed that I
grew was was a very young teenager and
uh I got a pound off that one plant and
it was better than the weed that it came
from and then man that was Off to the
Races but you never found it in the
compost pile yeah I got a pound plant as
a teenager not knowing
anything how how did you get away with
it how did your parents not find
it they knew I was getting ston by then
and um my dad dad colorated it Dad was
cool and I found out later he might have
been a closet smoker and he hid it from
me that came out a little later so he he
Let It Rock out no there were times
believe me it's a teenager when I'd piss
him off that he would get the weed
whacker and just stand there in slow
motion and go from the top of the bottom
of the plant while making eye contact
with
me so I learned the hard way but after
that you know High Times became a thing
and I started collecting those and um
that was when the first knowledge of
Amsterdam and genetics and all that you
know really came into my mind and I
think then after that I started uh I
bought marijuana botney I bought the
marijuana growers Bible and
uh I I think I first started growing
with chemicals not knowing any better
because there wasn't a lot out there on
organic and the only things we had
available in the 80s '90s were like
rapid grow Peter 2020 Miracle Grow so
that was my next
Advance was like maybe it's not a good
idea to put it in the manor pile dad May
chop it down so then it it mve to um
digging big holes like I read about in
some of the books and then putting I
just put straight compost in the hole
and it work PL plants would have new
deficiencies when they were G but I was
just excited I'm making Bud
yearly and it it kept going then with uh
those commercial indoors and uh some of
them wouldn't finished obviously because
they were equatorial but the ones that
did were and um I kept doing that for a
while until after graduating high school
1989 uh the next year there had been a
local guy that was a legend that was a
year ahead of me that had already
graduated that had the best weed around
and he was trying to stand office but I
I grew some balls one day and I I went
to his house unannounced and that's
where he handed me a brown paper bag I
can still see it with these plants that
had really fat leaves I never I look
like cabbage I never thought or been
exposed cannabis indicia other than the
ads and uh that's when my first breeding
started as a team and to this day I
think that may be M Grail
Afghan I'm the opposite of him he never
took notes so when I inquired about what
this is he said I would think it was
some Afghan i' had gotten from Vermont
so I drew that out and was just blown
away I mean that the was growing was
great but this stuff is narcotic it had
family bigger than my hand tight inner
nodes and it didn't mold so ran that
through um the end of the 80s through
the 90s but I really even though I read
books I didn't have the real-time
breeding chop and I remember each
successive cross maybe I didn't do the
best selection but it didn't resemble
what I first started with so out of
frustration in we're getting to the mid
90s once the punch was lost I realized I
I needed to go to
Amsterdam so I saved money and it took a
while as a kid you know and young man
then uh to get the money together and
the first year I went there was
1999 and it was for money I saved for my
my outdoor escapades you know so that
was the first year and I went over there
and
amazingly I ended up meeting Neville
inadvertently and this is a crazy story
um it was with my ACT Rec recently
deceased from cancer and um anyhow we
walked off the beaten path off of Dam
Square into a very small I I believe the
name of it was the Emerald Triangle
Trading Company where I met an American
who owned the place and we had mentioned
Neville and he said well speak of the
devil I believe I have an appointment
with him if you want to hang out and
meet him and that's when he walked in in
proper business attire leather atach
case and I bought super silver hay seeds
from him that he sucked out of the weed
there um I have an old CS of the whole
trip including parts of that Ali from
the old Cam corters that I need to get
converted converted to D which I plan on
plan on sharing that in the near future
we did the uh the the marijuana hatch
Museum um where I met Eagle Bill there I
met Mila the half Queen where she show
us pollinator we went to the STX Museum
the van go Museum so a lot of it's on
there to Crazy Stoned Out white people
from the US not knowing anything uh can
I ask you can I ask you which month in
the year were you there in in the in the
winter time or in the spring or
summertime unfortunately I believe it
was in the winter and I can't remember M
but it's listed on the top of the
camcorder tap okay so unfortunately I
didn't get to see the Tulips out on full
display along the single canal and all
that stuff but I learned not to bring
try to bring tulips through customs
that's a whole another
story The First Time
welcome what's that Cosmic has joined us
was the case oh cool so uh that first
year I believe I bought most of the
centy Seedbank
Library
um I had met Adam done there at TH seeds
we we recently did a um an anniversary
issue which was pretty cool chop it up
um but from what I remember I got Durban
Poison the first year I got Sia Gunk I
got Early Skunk from them I got juicy
fruit from
them and maybe a few others I forget
because that was a very long time ago
but I can remember what I got from Adam
dun because he had shared something he
wasn't sharing with the public as well
uh from chds headquarters I got um Puna
butter which is no longer on the menu
um chocolate something or other
chocolate trip maybe no longer on his
menu um and I got the sage which made a
huge impact on me we'll we'll get into a
little bit more of that later and um
then I remember oh yeah MK Ultra that's
another one I brought back that first
trick but then I remember thinking maybe
it's best to ask Adam if he has
something that's not released to the
public that he would come come up off of
um Adam gave me poana which I believe is
a Robert canel Clark
heirloom uh sativa which was the early
building block of early Pearl and um
silver Pearl so I managed to to get that
from him and um some of the others were
yumol from Sager Matha which was just
absolutely amazing I don't think that's
even in circulation anymore
um his bubbleberry which was absolutely
incredible uh what else did I get from
him that really made an impression on
me um the Western Winds which is a CI
myth knockoff that was also amazing did
you get the sage or the sage and sour I
got the
shade that was one that wasn't one that
he gave out no he us sage and sour but I
I don't remember him releasing the sage
he did the sage was a regular release
and then it became feminized later in
time the seed was definitely released to
the general public because the seeds I
bought were in the thcs packaging and I
ended up running a cut commercially that
we kept around for years that really did
good in PA I eventually ended up uh
naming my band stage that made such an
impact and we we band it pretty well for
good many years
so yeah it all dat it all dates back to
that faithful trip and then
um 99 I went
back or no I'm sorry 99 was first year I
went back 2001 and that's when I started
noticing a discernable difference in the
Fenty seed stock and that's when I as
Adam dun coined term I got dutched
because I went to my tri and TRS and
that it makes sense that that
holdovers that were still good after the
raids but some of the stock took the hit
hit early on because I remember bringing
the same Durban back from the same
vendor I went to the last time and all
of it was hey it was like
unrecognizable that was the the last
trip I took there but I think one of the
things I want to delve into is pre9 8
seems to be the the desired stock but a
lot of the dut vendors had leftover
stock that extended into the 2000s of
those trains so a lot of people think
after 2000 um it was undesirable it all
depends on if it was hold over or not
because they had both that lasted
probably I think into 2001 and maybe
even beyond that was when I first
started noticing their pack weren't good
you
know well Al others not only Sensi sits
I will tell you now you know there is
other big big producers that are still
on the scene from The Dutch scene and
the same team you know maybe maybe Simon
fius stayed the same uh I I I met him a
few times but he he always kept his few
strains you know what I mean and then he
bought up the MOs genetics uh when when
MOS was closed right so that was the
only
yeah Garrett the breeder I that brings
back memories because his his warlock
was insanity and that a shout out to my
boy Johnny Bones a grateful heads um
he's he's got a warlock cut that's a
banger and that's maget genetic jerett
was the breeder if I recall from memory
yes and uh you know I don't know the
story why uh the the the MOs genetics
stopped working but I know that Simon
took over the genetics we had a double
dutch uh cut in Austria circulating for
many years I think it's still alive uh
circulating still uh it was also still a
really really strong plant you know
branchy stocky uh has particular uh
attributes you know that everybody wants
so yeah these genetics are still alive
uh in some little you know in in little
even the Earth Bly you know before we
record you talk about the Swiss genetics
right you you remember the the arly and
the the the the old the uh old seeds you
know uh Al production and Felix MTH
producing beautiful flowers in F
Switzerland of course I would never
forget that yeah that is it's a big and
very little known part of cannabis
history over there yes all uh his name
was uh Felix Couts and I think he really
was a so you know this real cannabis
Soldier you know the one like like you
know some sometimes people say that the
hippies that came you know the the trail
the hippie trail that was before the
Pioneers that got the the genetics from
these far lands you know that came to
the west then you know for us to to
enjoy like you said before you know you
you got the the land races let me say
and then it watered down in time and
then you went to Amsterdam in the right
time right so please continue because
it's really interesting what you're
telling oh yeah yeah so so we were
dependent on the the train and after the
Dutch bank fell off because I was lost a
lot of them paid for mortgages for us
and
uh aware of cannabis Canada Cannabis
culture and whole thing going on up
there thank you to hot Times magazine so
the D St fell off and I I blew a lot of
money on my last trip to Amsterdam
unfortunately um I started using um Mark
emry Heaven Stairway um Hemp Depot DC
Seed Company
um British Columbia seed company and I
was amazed and it wasn't like when you
sent seeds to someone in Amsterdam where
you wait a month you don't get any back
then there wasn't tracking and you might
get them you would check the mailbox if
you like maybe show up in two months
Canada was closer and it was quicker and
uh that was the next thing because we I
really panicked and uh I really wasn't
doing a ton of dedicated breeding there
just some chucks at home because the
genetics I knew would work and I needed
them to keep you know keep the lights
going so uh then I started running um
off the top of my head
um Dutch tree times purple skunk from a
probably now defun breeder that did
really well for us um I sweet skunk from
feder and that's the other one I forgot
did great for us in our climate um
and what else did I find some there that
was a staple
um GTC company I believe it was White
Widow times nl5 and I can't remember the
name it might have been called white
lightning or the lightning or something
like that so ran out for a while and
kind of the same thing started happening
with those Banks quality went down some
of them just went completely defun and
uh this might have
been cir
2002 three through four I think it
started to fall off and that's when um
on itm I discovered you know brers that
were local like bog oh yeah B seats yes
Bubble Gum my life that ched my life
from then on um I got his first feed
going back to his first drop and that
was a game changer for me and not only
were they cheaper they were domestic I I
could get them shipped and it would take
a month before you got them you'd know
you get them and uh yeah I I kept
running with that and that's when um I
really started doing my first successful
Chucks and then going back line breeding
stuff uh I think not shortly after that
if I recall from memory was also you old
your felt forarm was up and that's where
I got some um from Guy the uh 88 G13
half plant that was going around on
treating yourself for him which I still
have I managed to keep CA skunk from
that first trip which I'm about to F4 I
have those in SE stock Early Skunk I
still have which needs to have an
increase done in the the super skunk
pack it just came into my hands I will
not get there but that's that's a whole
another topic because Blown Away
somebody randomly who I had a few
Communications with out of nowhere sh
you know I feel like these would do good
in your hands and that's kind of how
that came to fruition
nice have have you um like what what
what do you getting off of the super
skunk I know that you just put it into
flower but um like are does it bring
back any any memories of perhaps running
it from a you know decades earlier
or yeah the plant are poot on man and I
I have a pecul overactive whole Factory
fence pallet it's it's weird where I can
a smell from a decade ago will register
with me and then I'll put that memory
together so they they are spoton as I
remember them same length morpholog and
very uniform for an F1 cross that's what
they were when they made them
um I got only eight feed and they're all
going there were a total of five male
and three females and um there's
basically two main phenotypes I'm seeing
and the one is probably the U the maple
leaf aan leaner and I'd like to call
that a totem structure with minimal side
breaching they all have non Hollow stems
and that's the other indicator that I
know
um um and I think the St Rubes that I'm
getting from them the one phenotype is
like haate thinner turpentine where with
an almost sulfuric smell with skunk
mixed in there and the other phenotype
is chunky GD Afghan type with maybe the
back end of I'm very good at describing
Tarpin the creamy sweetness almost
defies description I would say maybe
maybe Citrus but we're not talking
anything fruity at all here we're
talking maybe
grapefruit and uh that's exactly how I
remember them so the ttail shine will be
the orange pistols because that was a
signature tra that when I grew Out
outdoors from 90 stock that they they
had and they were also bulletproof I
remember them getting rained on and
having no mold whatsoever so very
cool yeah you know one thing that I
remember about the super skunk when we
used to grow it is every single crop I
would hold the censi Seed Catalog up
against my flowers and it looked
identical and to this day it's the only
seeds that I've ever ever purchased that
looked exactly like the photo that they
were advertised with you know they good
well I mean the thing is that even
cultural practices could change the way
flowers look you know like if I grow the
same flowers as you or as Nick they're
going to come out looking a little bit
different but with the super skunk it
was unbelievable that it looked
identical to the catalog was the most
uniform strain I've ever seen that a
great way to valid for sure and uh
that's another interesting we should get
into later how the them cut grown by
three different people will always look
different I've even had things I've
given to somebody that was completely
different and I'm not going to lie
sometimes my own cut somebody was able
to maximize the genetic potential better
than I could and I'm like damn dude what
did you do you know and I don't get mad
about it I pick his brain so there's
something to be said about uh the plant
being an accumulator sympathetic
vibration from the person that it's
around and the energy that it gives off
and that's not some hippie [ __ ] no I
mean it can be hippie [ __ ] and be
real at the same point
right that's true
too yeah I mean some some plants yeah or
because like the the phenotypic
difference I've always heard like um you
know you have to take environment into
account because like if even if you're
like like a a cultivar let's say is like
the same cut but then the phenotype is
the production you know it's uh it's the
chemotype of like what is actually
produced based on the environmental
factors and the grow factors and yeah
the interactions with the grower
themselves and so I it I think that it's
super valid and maybe there's there's
also just a little bit of slight um Mis
terminology sometimes in the Cannabis
Community um just when it comes to how
we've used words in the past when it
wasn't something that we could openly
talk about with those who are educated
botanists or horticulturalists um but
yeah I think I think you're spot on like
it's it's going to change no matter
where you're growing it but if but if
something is super uh similar across
different growth environments and grow
Styles that's something that's that's
great because then you can actually have
something for someone in in like a you
know like in slovania uh right that they
can have like oh they want like the Cali
cookies uh or you know the Cali genetics
or whatnot but if you have something
that can grow the same across different
environments then that's how you can get
that into other people's
hands that's a very good point and uh I
think even even going further how a
plant will genetically acclimate to its
um to the to the outdoor environment and
become more resistant to things in your
own environment
there's needs to be more studies done on
that that aren't just Bro Science but
some real umol
group picture this this is it yeah I I
my opinion about this is let's go a
little bit deeper you know uh from from
the start you know Canabis behaves like
that it is a Survivor plant right it
would be it have to survive also without
uh the help of humans that's how it is
so the phenotypic expressions in a gin
pool are basically because if it grows
in a area where there is for example the
winter comes a little bit earlier some
years or the rainy season starts a
little bit earlier in the fall uh some
phenotypes Will Survive and because of
the cross pollination between the you
know it let's say it's inbr line it's in
not inbre but it's it's again wild
cannabis if we would put all these Kong
snow outside somewhere without the help
of humans something would happen and
what would happen in one year some
phenotypes would survive because there
was a dry season and they perform better
in dry seasons but they would be
pollinated but by males that would also
give them the genetics from others so
next year when there would be a wet
season the and the other phenotypes
would survive they will also carry the
genetics from the plants that would
survive the other Seasons you know what
I mean it's always in a gy pool because
it wants to survive That's the basis of
Canabis it's so hard it's so wants to
survive in in nature and like even even
going back to what we had talked about
last week too that so that's like over
over a period of time within a genetic
population like that where they're
picking up traits that are advantageous
to their survival that's the genetic
drift that uh I was talking about and
and we use genetic drift differently in
cannabis um but that that Within
population is the genetic drift and it's
a it's a positive change like almost
like a
microevolution that's why some people
get weird about things with tissue
culture because some of them think it's
unnatural and all but they don't realize
the chimeric and truncated Expressions
can occur
naturally the same things that happen
that's how we get mutations in nature
yep I've been waiting to use Eric in in
the fent by the way that was my time I'm
glad you I'm glad you were able to slip
that
in trunk mutations too so what so like
what what then happened next on on your
cannabis Journey Mark so you
um it it sounds like you like once you
were out of Pennsylvania or like um
where where were you where did you go to
from there well we can back up for that
part of the story and part of it I'm
going to intertwine what I did what I
did musically because it's all it's all
congruent with the whole story
so as this was happening and I got
better at breeding and I I had a
production cut that we you know we did
really well with um I walked into a head
shop in newo Pennsylvania called the now
and then shop and the clerk behind the
desk you know I talked to him and I said
uh you know I'm a guitar player nice to
meet you and from Good Buds let's go
smoke to Sage and that's how the band
Sage was started in early
2000s so in my in my Township I had
supported myself basically by by
cannabis in a non-legal state which is
had a trials and tribulations um we
started the band and the band started to
get bigger so I started to
do music festivals on the property
because my parents had a farm and it was
also for being honest a good way for me
to clean money because as the van got
bigger and the the population of the
event exceeded the town that it was in
so contractors could get a tax right off
if I put their name on our Banner um and
it got big and it was also a way that
kept me to continue the other operation
because that nobody had any any idea of
knowing how many people came in at the
gate or how much money was being
generated or not so I was able to do
that and incorporate it into a blur and
nobody messed with me I pretty much had
a symbiotic relationship with the corn
Farmers I would put thousands of plants
in their corn field we had no overhead
surveillance there and I would hand them
a paycheck every November and they were
making more money off doing that with me
than they were off their milk or their
feed corn so I'm like Johnny apple seed
in this very rural community in
Pennsylvania so enter
2005 how many do you think you had
gone it was ARS all multip
proper well I would plant double what I
needed because half would always get
taken by Hunters by rippers um I rate
Farm owners so it was a game a cat and
mouse with them it really was I mean
I've been shot I've been bitten by dogs
I've gotten cut by barbwire I mean it
went on and on until 2005 and it was all
local police though we didn't have State
Police or overhead
surveillance
but 2005 state police came and
unbeknownst to me they had Choppers and
they had Fleer
infrared so 2005's the first year I got
paid a visit and um it scared me good
but because I I didn't really H have any
priers at all um I got a slap on the
wrist and me being me you know and
somebody anti Authority and I feel it's
my god-given right to grow weed so it it
didn't stop me yeah I just mooved to
different locations I'd go out of the
County North or and uh I got to say it
was a different era back then because it
took a lot of people to pull this off it
took a lot of people not to tell it
would take me telling people to meet me
in the middle of a cornfield at midnight
with a truck or a trailer and there's a
lot of that going on I managed to do
that unath till
2015 by then um the band had started
having kids and we were no longer a band
but we still stay friendly so I just
kept my weed hustle going without the
guys of the music festival anymore so
long story short 2015 I caught the last
slick and uh that was on multiple
properties and they got me good there
was some seizure involved then and it
was the second so I caught I caught a
Fed case in 2015 and uh I did over a
year for that one and uh they gave me an
ankle monitor but me being me I devised
the system where I knew I couldn't go
far enough to maintain plants because
they kept me to my driveway with the
monitor so me being me I got skid
pallets I put cures on them I joined two
together and I had a bamboo poles and
then there was um an ihawk that was that
big so thre a pulley s them I could put
and pull the skid pallets that had
buckets on them into heavy brass and
then I could pull them to me to maintain
them and that's how I had to grow and I
never got caught but I will tell you the
thing you're just like pulling them in
and out of the
garage no not the garage high high
brush oh my God High brush where the
driveway ended I put them in pulled them
out yep so it got it got pretty bad at
one point because they could visit
without any
notification and I remember that year I
had the horse dolls where my meter crop
was was drying to be harvested and uh it
also happened that two very large
vultures made a nest in
there so when the probation officer came
to visit he wanted to check all the out
buildings I let him check all but the
one and it must have been a blessing
from God because I said I'm not sure if
you want to go in there but you can but
there are two very big vultures in there
that are n which there were and it I
mean I couldn't have planned it any
better because as I said it they flew
from One Flew from the roof and he's
like yeah we're not doing that dude I'm
like splitting sausage links I'm sure my
kateed already was doing it and uh I got
away with it but
um it got too hot there so while still
on parole and probation for this I did
the baly move I contacted the probation
officer I said said look I'm going to
sell the Family Farm they left it to me
and uh I'm going to I'm going to head
out of here to Oklahoma where I can do
what I can
legally and uh he said yeah that
shouldn't be a problem um I'll run it
past probation and whatnot so famous
this H I've been here four years so it's
2024 now going on five so this was this
was just five years ago that you were
growing
illegally and had the ankle monitor yeah
cuz that story sounded like something
you were telling from a long time ago
well that's you
know no no no so what happened then then
got even crazier because
um I didn't anticipate it taking any
length of time to to leave to transfer
the probation or any any of that so this
is dur in the peak of covid and thank
God that probation wasn't even coming to
visit then
so I sold the property and had
everything in new halls and we're
staying in a hotel in the proban says uh
well have to go through what's called
interstate compact they need to transfer
it to Oklahoma and us not knowing that
uh it was going to take that long we
were trapped in a hotel for close to
four months at the peak of Co we were
terrified because nobody knew what was
going on then and we had a dog in toe so
uh we burned through 30 grand just
staying there paying the hotel and there
was nothing we could do about it and I
was told if we contact Oklahoma to see
if they accept us to move there um that
they would violate my probation so in
the last hour I risked it all and I
found out who the director of Interstate
Compact was and I was able to call and
we were able to get through and and move
but uh wow that's how it happened and I
was shocked that Oklahoma let me get a
commercial license while fill on
paper I me that's pretty great I agree
and even more remarkable was the
outpouring of genetics from people that
I did not even ask because in order to
keep my sanity I kind of made a little
blog on Instagram while we were stuck in
the hotel and everybody was caring for
us waiting for us to get there because
we were losing our [ __ ] I'll be honest
pardon my French we were we were losing
our mind during that that procedure not
knowing
uh if we could leave or not it's being
you know rendered lost in that hotel so
there was a big outpouring from the
community which I I still can't thank
anyone enough with all kinds of genetics
and love and wellwith is and all so we
finally made it did you lose a lot of
genetics in the
transition that's a good story yeah not
all of them um I had to go through
hospice with my mother before we did the
transition and move and sell the
property and um he might have known I
was in trouble and meant well but there
was there was a vault that I had in the
CER band that she definitely threw out
and I don't hold it against her she was
looking out for me probably thinking I
shouldn't have them there and all that
so yeah there was there was a lot in
there sure um what's what's the longest
uh like mother you've been able to keep
around through all your different uh
travels and excursions and
police interactions police interventions
police police
interactions um that's a good question
probably oh an air fell out
um the dg4 is one of them it's not super
old but I was able to keep that since
getting it from from I mag that's one um
the ndn guy G13 hack plant um I've had
around probably since um
early 2000s those would be my oldest um
some of them people have copied them for
me that I trust so I I couldn't get them
here so I was able to get some of those
back so that really doesn't count that
counts that's what the communities for
yeah yeah yes in a non-legal state it
really took having someone you could
trust to have backups for then and
that's how I think prohibition a lot of
the Legacy cuts for law during then
because a friend means as well and then
you know what it's like when you
sometimes let your friends watch your
garden when you get when you go away
when you're Sil small scale never ends
good sure we've all had a horror story
like
that
so yeah those would be the oldest but
some of them were were older that have
been held by people that have gotten
back to me and uh I have a crap memory I
can't even remember off the top of my
head I know I have a list of uh what
clones were introducing to Grateful
heads
okay and one of
them yeah one of them is um the lavender
cut which came from 90s s seed stock
that's that's a great one we're excited
to get some of those to the Mass's szo
gen Cuts nice so one thing I wanted to
say is part of the reason why I'm trying
to get people to document their stories
is because we're all forgetting you know
so you know stories from 30 years ago
are hard to you know to tell people we
didn't have notes you know I mean you
have a VHS
tape I'm like at the edge of my seat I
really want to see that you know
because but uh yeah the whole purpose of
of telling your story is so that it's
documented for eternity you know
and so I'm glad that you're telling you
a story yeah I'm I'm pretty certain with
today's technology that can be um
converted to disc I should look into
that I think I'm going to make that a
priority you really do it soon because
tape loses quality it's not
digital I didn't even think of that well
even if I have to pay out to have
somebody do forensic retrieval I don't
think it's a stretch because we have
that technology today at worst worst
possible
scenario that's I mean I know a little
something about this you know when the
tape is damaged
there's no recovering it oh okay because
this is like if you have a painting and
you chip off some of the paint you know
like maybe somebody else could paint up
you know so really you just need to go
do that right away is have that video
digitized and then you know once it's
digitized it lasts forever but when you
have actual tape up like I'll give you
an example and I I know you're a dead
head and a fish head but like old
cassette tapes after a while they're no
good anymore and and VHS is kind of the
same thing for for video so it's a MAG
you know I'm I'm eight track
old I had eight tracks
too yeah yeah parents did you know
that's going to be a priority that'll be
uh real cool to share and get that done
so that's definitely going to happen and
uh it'll validate some of this stuff too
in video format you can only say so much
in words and then that way that's locked
Forever at a frozen moment in time like
you had
said yeah so so you get out to Oklahoma
in uh what 2020 and uh like what uh
what's your first moves once you get to
Oklahoma do you have a property or like
a you get your you said you get a
license tell us moreart the first the
first move was
um getting the license which happened
seamlessly um I was able to have
somebody who already had a license put
me on there or um om really CRA down and
everything we had minimal visits from
omma um we weren't huge as a 30 by2
shop with um a 40 lighter and five acres
of outdoor was what we first started at
and boy I get an education in a new
climate because I thought I had done my
breeding on the humid East Coast until I
came to a river bottom in
Oklahoma and uh for being completely
honest and I people should share their
failures too my first uh outdoor crop I
would say was 80% loss if I'm being
honest and
because there was all different kinds of
viroids and fungus here that I never
encountered on the E Coast so it was a
learning curve um we got set up right
away and I think my first legal fail um
was Indiana Indiana bubble gum in fact
it was our first legal sale we were
really proud of it but what did I do
when I first got there you and I
decompressed from the trauma that
happened man we
were nobody knew what was going on with
covid we were seeing people outside in
in Hazmat who tting testing the septic
for the hotel wow and uh it it was a
scary time because and I'm by no means
politicizing this people do they get
weird about Co but that's not what we're
doing we didn't know what it was so it
added that Fear Factor and uh there was
nothing we could do about it so there
was that anxiety because we were told by
Pennsylvania probation if we contact to
see the status of our transferral that
they would violate me and I did it
anyway so it took a long time I think
I'm just now getting decompressed over
that trauma to be if for being honest
that took a while um but so good to be
out of the sh it was weird for me
because we know wectors weed was on a
Polaroid you didn't share that [ __ ] with
anybody now everyone like duck face
selfie look at yeah here's the crop so
that that was weird and there was even
when in when legal some paranoia from
path uh posting stuff it was alien to
me yeah abely man the place that that I
live man it's not it's still like you
said nobody takes selfies with those
things you oh my god daddy was telling
me you can grow a plant of flower but
you can't yeah yeah it's like you know
um the facility where I have my library
yeah it's in Austria and Austria has a
law that is uh written like this you
know the Delta 9 THC is the drug which
is forbidden of course right it's it's
the drug right so but cannabis is not a
drug it's a plant and they uh have in
law they have written down that the the
plant itself is not a drug until it not
producing the substance you know you
know what I mean yeah so after and the
action of cutting a bot from the from
the plant is producing drugs not growing
it you know so actually if you don't uh
if you would not have anything uh no no
dry flowers at home and they will have a
police raate you will have uh flowering
plant outside your house nobody would
actually I mean the the judge would uh
free you in the end actually because you
are not producing
drugs it's aroma therapy you would claim
you know it's very very different right
I mean the system works like this the
the government has taxes from that uh
they you can sell it as a producer as an
ornamental plant uh cannabis ornamental
plants which I as a producer sell to
other shops too and to many businesses
and for example I've been contacted by
Swiss uh pharmaceutical company just few
weeks ago who who have a license to
produce high THC potent
flowers uh and also there is uh in
Germany this kind of uh companies for
years already which I contacted me uh
but now in Germany is a legal Market you
can sell to a private grower so you know
but still it is only opening up right
now you know you talk about something
that will be here in 10 years maybe you
know always the always the hurdles and
bureaucratic red tape I think it's time
time to free the weed and anyone being
persecuted for it it's a victim of crime
it's just yeah it's tragic and it still
feels like and it sounds like it it's
still prohibition era for Austria it's
so that sounds so convoluted yeah yeah
it is like um it is like a little bit of
taboo everybody knows about it and
nobody's really giving a [ __ ] about it
in that sense like until you're caught
and when they are caught you know like I
a producer when somebody comes to me and
buys five plants and he goes out of my
shop and I give him the bill that means
I I sold you the car yeah so I'm a I'm a
car seller so you have to be 18 years
old you have to have a li permit uh for
for driving and so you buy this car and
you drive away you make a you uh make an
accident and who is now you know I mean
you're the one who is responsible not me
you know I just sold you the plan and on
the bill is written that you have to
keep it on 18 hour of lights that means
that is in you keep it under vegetation
that it's not producing drugs you know
that that is written on the bill yeah
it's ornamental you know yeah and so in
essence that's a waiver of releas yeah a
waiver of release of responsibility yeah
wow well at least it's a glimmer of hope
head in the right direction um
unfortunately my only experience with
gentleman that was an austri
looked like this we got all the bells
and whistles for a very large seed order
we did the insurance we did the uh the
the expedited delivery and I think that
was counterproductive because it drew
more attention and it was flagged in
Austria and it didn't get through but it
was never any any official thing from
them other than they could do nothing
for us so it was it it was a huge order
what I did in good faith was
I took the loss on it just to get them
there he had a friend in Chicago who was
receiving the seeds and then however he
was getting them to Austria ended up
happening but yeah that's reinforcing
how tight it is there because it was
listed as art
supplies and they they allowed us to
have another claim again to try to get
it back and we haven't heard anything
about it so I'm hoping they got them
there because we were super pumped about
getting some some of our strains to
Austria yeah actually it's the system is
there and I think I already talk about
it in the last podcast how the system
here works and uh it will be uh from
year to year uh easier to do it because
uh um many many other countries will
will now decriminalize if I say Germany
legalized it's wrong actually they
decriminalized it right now thecriminal
yeah it's not legalization it's it's
it's just like you know it's really
still really strict you know but they
can grow now at home which they couldn't
before and you know that's a really big
difference right I mean it's a ray of
light anyway it's headed in the right
direction you know the fact you can
shipped to Germany is is amazing yeah
for example it is crazy for me when
Gabby told me that you cannot ship
between States you know in America the
Clones that is crazy well you can ship
we issue cultures worldwide if they're
under a certain height because it's
considered H considered .3 just saying
that if it doesn't flow it's it has no
drugs yeah so there's a a loophole in
the farm bill here where if it doesn't
contain THC it's considered hemp and so
clones can be shipped every everywhere
through the country what I was telling
you was it was something about a
licensed cannabis Nursery is not allowed
to sell clones to the public it only
allows to sell clones
to um a cultivator or a distributor that
then grows it or to a dispensary which
then can sell to the public but if for
example the generation zero zero clones
that uh uh you're producing right uh
with with a grateful Head LCC company
now this will be certified for example
for my facility I have a passport also
I'm under under uh watch of the food and
Rock administ
to do an import of that because you
already have it from from tissue culture
meric you have you have it from it's a
gene zero it's little bit acclim
acclimatized as I think you know uh but
it still needs care but it can be
shipped in one day you know this can go
through it's like this is also a signal
to all Europe now for for this you know
that generation zero is the next big
thing and also because we can trust you
know can you describe generation
zero I am not claiming to be super
well-versed I I know enough to be
dangerous but um I think probably Sasha
could describe exactly in proper context
what n zero is I think I don't claim to
be an expert in tissue culture Protocol
no it's I'm not an expert too maybe
Cosmic would tell the story now if it's
here uh I don't think he I mean
basically gen zero means it's the first
gener ation has come out of invit the
mar stem culture that's Mar stem culture
has to be there for a long time right I
mean I heard some podcast that the
maryem should be uh like at least two
years in in
maryem um no marem noal again marem noal
in this form and then after these two
years it should be introduced all
because viruses or this kind of
pathogens they cannot survive that that
kind long time as a as a parasitic uh uh
element in the plant right I mean uh if
you have it for 2 years in the chamber
and repeat the process and have it in
and then introducing it as first time
you know from uh Mar stem to noal from
noal to to rooting and from rooting to
to to a hardening phase where the Gen
zero becomes the Gen zeroc clone it
starts to grow a little bit you
acclimatize it first you need hoods then
you need without hoods I mean Gabby says
you need don't need hoods but it's like
just the as you would do traditional
mother plant cuttings you know you start
with the hoods and then you acclimatize
it you know and then you put it under
the stronger lights and then after weeks
and from these plants you know from
generation zero plants if somebody has a
little uh lap you know can do uh mother
plants quick and make no Cuts so you
have noal already from those kind of
plants and you you still keep it in your
Li Library you know that is my the big
thing my the idea that for me would be
so interesting I would definitely buy
this kind of genetics in the future from
yeah
y hom grower will make a mom and will
keep it uh really clean and he will
never get any diseases then you know
never let me say it's it's a good start
you know it's one of it's better start
than we have now you know and the the
the other thing um is I have a personal
relationship my very best friend
designed Ed one of the first modular TC
Labs that that he's making available and
he's working out of the University of
Tennessee tissue culture
program um so there's any Synergy there
that that's going to be a worldwide
operation um
modular
lab I need his phone number
bro well let's we we can make this
happen um he's my ve he's my very best
friend he co-signed for the people he's
working with and he's working with two
phds in the in their lab um at the
University of Tennessee they got they
got some grant money they're very very
gifted staff and they're giving me a
craft education in it I don't I claim to
have a rudimentary knowledge of what it
does but I think the important thing
about the f clones to mention is there
will be restored Vigor with the older
cuts it will do away with a lot of the
genetic drift that will do away with the
full panel of pathogens and viroids and
that's something really important
because hlvd fusarium moso tobacco are
starting to run rampant in our industry
and that being said I think mother rooms
are going to be obsolete within 5 to8
years and I think the thing that we're
going to start seeing next is cryogenic
storage where we can store millions of
plantlets at scale in a very small area
I think that that's going to eventually
make mother rooms obsolete because as we
know has your company been able to take
um like meristematic tissue culture or
other tissue culture out of cryogenic
freeze um the company that I'm working
with grateful heads I can't speak on
because I I just have introdu
um to the the uh Their scientist who's
doing it that the other company where my
friend is building labs for them has
they also can and haven't delve into
another controversial topic which is
crisper editing because there's another
misconception about that technology I'm
not an advocate of it nor am I opposed
to it it's still Discovery for me
there's a common
misconception that it's GMO and it's not
because if you understand the simple
concept of GMO it's introducing a
foreign entity to an already existing
cellular structure so we're talking
about crisper crisper is in essence the
giant pair of molecular scissors that's
adding the same organical plant material
from within the plant source that it was
derived from so they're they're doing
stuff there um I I haven't done anything
with my cannabis genetics there I'm a
I'm a brand ambassador for their CBD
product but uh any other Lab Services
there are offered to me you know so and
uh there's not really a conflict of
interest because my genetics are going
to Grateful heads that's a separate
entity in
itself yeah talk about grateful
heads super excited to be on there man
and I'll be totally honest a lot of the
guys that are on the board legal they're
like this and superheroes to me that
you'd see and be like wow that's so
awesome they're doing that so like my
are still getting they're getting flued
just talking about it because I I'm
blown away and honored to be part of
them um Kevin jod skun Craft medical
everyone on the staff is great and I
think it's uh Steve at craft medical did
a great job picking the team because
there's people that may not have a lot
of followers that don't get the exposure
but have a certain Talent he liked he he
he kind of handpicked a really good a
good group and we get the together for
Google Zoom meets try to get together a
couple times a month and just get our
heads together so um I like the fact
they're not all high-profile people I
think that means a lot because we're
we're going to build each other you know
on that
platform uh awesome and regarding my own
genetic
material um I'm going to be introducing
them probably January 15th and I I can't
believe I can't remember my my brain is
over inundated with information right
now list this morning you saw what I
posted yeah you can run through that
without without getting off the phone
um that's just the start of what I'm
going to incorporate I have a good bit
of other things and it's also important
to mention we were on the topic of Dutch
genetics um over the years and being in
Amsterdam I was able to forward some
friendships with some of the Breeders
there some old seed stock from some
people that are retired and that leads
me into the next conversation where I
think um embryo rescue protocol will be
will be a thing as well and to get some
of these um you know long lost cultivars
back back to where they should be um jop
from homegrown fantas seeds retired
recently and he gifted me all his
remaining
stock um we have the original myy which
is one of my all-time favorites we have
um his cheese which one won the Cannabis
Cup the H the Homegrown fantasies
te's um they're super Crystal
and a few others I can't oh white
widow um we have those I'm not sure the
viability but I think I'm going to save
those and also
um from Flying Dutchmen I got a lot of
their old old remaining stock um yes I
have a rora
Bor have
um God why can't I remember it now pot
of gold which I have is a mother mother
plant and Seed line separate from the
older
stock The Real McCoy that's the one I'm
most excited about we we have that and
uh a lot of people the early breeders
used that same Hawaiian cut for a lot of
successful things I think stelma was one
of them off the top of my head um and I
think sensey may have used that Hawaiian
IND in some of their crosses that makes
up the Real McCoy so I'm excited to see
what we can do because you got to
remember if the sea doesn't pop it
doesn't mean the cell embryo is dead and
you know you can run them through that
that uh protocol to regen to regenerate
them some little primitive way would be
using gibberelic acid right
with exactly yeah I think Dave Dave uh
Dave Pope AK Bean brains gave me the
recipe for that that I've been afraid to
do it you have to have the right PPM you
know in the water you soak the sea
yeah yeah if you uh if it's too high the
PPM of of it then I think there is one
guy called Vader on YouTube uh he has
this uh
um this seed company he's like having a
know a YouTube channel for years already
Vader OG is his name of the channel and
he's uh said it few years ago that and
he made an experiment also and you have
it in YouTube uh he has the right PPM he
has three cops with old seats like 20
years old seats and uh first cup second
cup third cup are with different ppms uh
the third cup is without gilic acid and
it's also the lowest uh uh rate of
sprouting and the first two were
sprouting really good actually 20y old
seeds and he has gibberelic acid in form
of crystals which he adds I have it at
home in the form of liquid
uh you can go I I don't know from the
head you know if I will say something
now it will be wrong but I it's Vader OG
and uh Vader he's named of the breeder
and he's uh having Ocean Grown uh is his
company Ocean Grown yeah I very good
information I'll keep that on the back
burner and for some reason it struck me
that great Dallas D I'm not sure if
you're friendly with him online he's
doing some home TC stuff like you are
and him being from Spain um you all
might have some connectivity
connectivity if you're not following him
I think I know
him you
get dude he's very informative about a
lot of things and he's like us in the
fact that he's doing Resurrection with
old seeds from um old dut vendors you
know he's a friend of my very good
friend from Barcelona the old school
genetics guys and actually
that's the one yeah he's one of the crew
members of old school genetics you know
uh and he's really into sativas you know
uh he's really I'm about to break in the
verse of
it's real it is really man I see him
yeah every year you know in March we go
to Barcelona and old school has a boot
where they sell Karma genetics old
school genetics and locky dog seats you
know from SK VA the gear you know that's
where I get my gear from luy VA from SK
VA you
know yeah you know it's like he's
grateful heads I can't believeing with
that guy actually the world is so small
you know but the the guy great dllas
like you told you know this is a guy man
it's like he's really really like into
it you know you meet these kind of
people like we are now on the podcast
like who are so into it but that's why
Barcelona for me is like the only place
where I can go that I meet like-minded
people in person
because otherwise you cannot meet in
person you we can meet overline online
now like we do but you know the world is
so small but actually we have points
where we can meet you know like yeah
it's it's crazy you know I'm I'm you
know I I camaraderie the camaraderie I
feel is what's needed again instead of
people concerned with what everybody
else is doing and all that stuff I feel
like if you're honest and you grind hard
and you're consistent everybody has
their own Lane there shouldn't be a
competitive Vibe if you're talented
there's enough for everybody to eat out
there yes and it's so much easier I I
get so mad I don't engage in public
drama it hurts my heart even some
high-profile people you'll see engaging
in online drama about a strainer about
this and that and even if you're right
that's going to be offputting to a
potential friend or an end user so I
just stay away from it man yeah the best
thing is to be quiet about it and you
know you don't need the drama uh for and
you don't have you don't have the time
in life for this drama because you have
so much work right with the plans man I
mean there is so much work to do even
now that we are on the postcast man it
is in the night now here but actually we
do in the day like your time now I would
have to go to the facility man I would
be like guys I still have five 10
minutes you know I have to go you know
because you know what I mean this is my
life this is like my babies everybody of
us feel like this I hope so I mean I see
it you know
it's all day man and the one thing that
struck me that I think is is helping our
business model work out is a lot of
these top readers you know you may grow
their St for years and they're not
really accessible and by all means
everybody operates differently it's by
means a knock on everybody and it's TR
me if I'm ever gonna do this I'm gonna
answer my phone I'm gonna answer every
single message I can it's a redundant
question from a noob who's just starting
out that could be the most important
question you're asked all day and you
bet you're ass if I can get back to
everybody even if I'm ready to pull my
hair out I'm going to do that because I
I think the the human interactive part
is really good and I think actually
giving a [ __ ] enough to take the time
goes a long way as a successful business
model it's pretty much business
yeah I'm trying to I'm trying to do just
that you know when I get a message on
Instagram or on YouTube I try to respond
to it respond to it quickly but I also
do understand you know like um NATO dog
you know I was talking to someone about
natso dog yesterday and they were like
well you know he used to answer my
messages and now he doesn't I don't know
if there's something wrong and I said
you know how many messages this guy gets
yeah oh no F if anybody anybody like he
has he has he has other responsibilities
it's not like take it personal or
something it's it's
just you know re realistically after a
while it becomes overwhelming so for now
while I can do it I try to do it I try
to and you know what's great is that's
how I met Sasha you know that's how I'm
meeting other great people you know and
you know one another great thing for me
of about this podcast is I feel like I'm
making
friends you know
and you know that's priceless that's
super important I can't emphasize the
the importance of that enough because
it's kind of lost out there everyone
thinks they're competing yeah and I just
see people competing with themselves and
their own egos there's really and the
way I perceive life and I always have is
there is no competition competition's a
a mental limitation because check it out
there's always somebody that's going to
be bigger better and faster than you so
learn from the best and make it your own
that's the old always the way I live my
life pretty much well you want with
yourself say that go ahead you want you
want to compete with yourself exactly
you know with your mind you can't do it
yeah with your mind saying that you
can't do it um my my lady she you know
she works out a lot she tries to go to
the gym every day I'm wearing gym rats
for Life dude every day I'm trying I'm
too busy this is this is my lady's uh
gym and they had like a competition
first of all so I I'm going to change
the subject for a minute just for some
light-hearted stuff but um do it so my
lady goes to the gym every day I try to
go I can't go as often and this gym is
kind of geared towards women okay it's
like you know mostly women that go there
but you know guys are allowed
and uh so I go there with them and they
have this competition like it's like an
actual weightlifting competition with it
doing all this different stuff and uh
you know they asked me if I want to do
it and the first answer is there's no
way I want to do it because these women
at this gym are [ __ ] badasses they're
all
like you know like so like it would just
be and the other thing is the only
person that I want to compete with is
myself right you know like I I just want
to do better and I want to lose some
weight you know may p on a little bit of
muscle um but mostly lose my gut you
know so I'm competing with myself when I
go to the gym I'm not looking at like
what the max weight that somebody else
can bench presses or or anything like
that what I'm looking at is you know how
much more can I do this time you know to
push myself to be better and so that's
why I said like I like competing with
myself yeah well real real quick on that
topic um
I being sedentary and being on probation
and not having a license because they
take their license when I moved to
Oklahoma I'd always stay lean you know
and just from being active so everyone
fact on Co dude dude I went I walked
around at 199 I'm 6'4 and 3 years later
in Oklahoma I got up to uh
254 I put much weight and uh this year I
lost it all and I got muscular again I
didn't think it was possible my blood
pressure went up I got scared I think
that's what made me do it and I I
dropped 54 lbs and the the main thing
that made the weight shut off and lose
my stomach and I I have a four pack I
can't believe it I'm not going to show
anybody that's to attack you but
anyway I'm doing it now I'm doing it now
which is the reason I'm bringing it up
is uh I fast every Monday I I go to bed
you know very early I go to bed at 8:
every night I'm up at 4:00 with the
plant and uh every Monday I fast I don't
eat until 7:00 on Monday and that's you
know over 24 hours and uh then my meal
is usually something very light it's
fruit or something and that helped if
you really want to get into it it's
super hard because you're going to get
irritable when you do it you might even
have cramps or anything but we we
consume as humans far more calories than
we need and I really didn't figure it
out until I I got into fat think so we
we'll end on that note and I applaud you
for your health Journey because our trip
is
short yeah you're you're right actually
you know uh the older you get the more
you feel the the body needs something
else you know I mean the the culture
here in my country is we eat quite a lot
of meat right I mean also a lot of
vegetables because we grow our own food
the quality of that food is quite High
you know but in the last you know 20
years of course there is a lot of
supermarkets and you know the food gets
lower quality so people lost it is also
cheaper so now people lost the feeling
that you need to buy from a
farmer you know somebody that is local
here the food is not being D driven from
Far places to your table right I mean
the best thing is if you have all the
food if you can from your local
environment which is like radius of 100
kilm you know that is great because it
means people people who do that you know
also we with people I say conab people
when we do our end product the thing
that is for us still here illegal to do
but when I do my
clones I want to be them the a quality a
AA quality you know as I can do it you
know I will not send them to Germany to
a hom grower if there is no not really
the best clone I can send to him I
rather you know if I have older clones
that is you know not the higher score I
rather say hey I wait for the next round
of the cut you know just to have the the
best quality you know because the word
spreads around if you if you uh
spreading uh your company will rise if
you uh uh advertise through your product
product not through advertisement naked
woman or uh you know what I mean you
know that is not the way you should
advertise wheat you know because fob KOB
people like the truth you know we like
the truth so there's so much truth to
that and presentations everything and if
you care about yourself and you run a
clean show that'll be felt and
appreciated by the end
users yeah something else I can add to
that is I remember when I opened up uh
the garden spout my my grow shop and
within days of opening up my store we
got a visit
from the only other place in town that
you could buy any gross stuff okay so I
I opened up the first indoor grow shop
but there was a store and still exists
called Spare Time Supply and Spare Time
Supply they saw sold soil and pots and
fertilizer all kinds of fertilizer okay
and then in a ocean container in the
back it had grow lights so it was like a
regular Nursery but it was in mesino
County right so the clients there wanted
to buy stuff to grow weed in but they
tried to keep it like lowkey right when
I opened up my store and it my store was
based for the indoor grower I had grow
lights in the window shining up the
highway like you couldn't drive through
Willets without seeing high pressure
sodium
lights so I quickly got a visit from the
son of the store owner and at first I
didn't know who he was and he's just
asking me some questions and I'm all
excited I got my store open and he says
well my name is Mike I'm from Sparetime
Supply and we're going to put you out of
business oh fighting words right he felt
he felt very threatened by it but you
know he didn't put me out of
business and you know they had a
wholesale company too and eventually
they started selling me stuff like
selling me the soil cuz I could buy it
from someone else but they were local
and it was easy I could just pick it up
instead of having pallets of soil
delivered so it was
cheaper
and you know I think eventually they
realized yeah you know he's taking some
of our business but he's also bringing
me some business and you know what what
they realized is they had to step up
their
game okay like if they wanted to Market
to the indoor Growers they had to take
the [ __ ] out of the ocean container in
the back and they did you know at that
point they had the grow lights right up
front center and they even grew some
plants and so like I feel like I had a
positive
influence even on them right and then
other stores started to pop up
and honestly a few of them were like my
former clients the two bigger stores
that opened up these guys used to be my
clients but you know I
remembered the spare time thing them
coming to my store and and threatening
me right and you know when they told me
they were doing it I was like well
congratulations you know like like let's
go into this as friendly
competition okay let's both try to make
each other do a better job we don't want
the bad type of competition where the
customer can work us against each
other right you know so like he would
call me up and say hey this guy says
you're selling him the lights for 400
bucks is that true and I'd say yeah and
he'd say okay I'm just going to match
the price that's what we would do like
we wouldn't beat the other guy's price
we'd match the price and so if you want
to shop with me because you appreciate
the service that I'm doing then you shop
with me if you want to shop with him you
can shop with him but it's not going to
be about price and you know well good
there's something to be said for good
but the whole idea I think what I was
trying to get at is when we were talking
about
competition okay competition can make
you elevate your game and not be lazy
you you know so
competition can be a good thing if
you're not
lazy now that's that's a good point yeah
I do want to say that there can be bad
competition to okay eventually what
happened here was there was some big
corporate owned Grow shops that owned
like tons of Grow shops throughout the
country and what they did was they
started targeting areas
and they sold products for like cheaper
than I could get it for certainly
cheaper than what I could sell it for
and you know they put basically all the
independently owned Grow shops out of
business
so what I want to say is there's good
competition and there's bad competition
you know but overall you should always
try to make the competition make you
elevate your game Fact you know y so and
it's good you had a healthy camaraderie
amid the uh the competitive nature
that's good you turned it around you
know that's what I love about the
grateful Head project you know the
you're your that so many great heads
came together you know that's that's you
know that's the thing I think this is
the game changer now globally because
you have to understand not only for you
this is a new thing because you are a to
it now but in Europe and all around the
world people know about it you know like
in South Africa is a legal Market in
Uruguay is a legal Market in you know
many parts of the world already there is
legal market and they will want to have
these genetics you know for somebody to
have like a true cut of KD you know from
Europe or South Africa this is like wo
you know this is for us cuz I don't know
anybody that would have a true Kim de
cot you know we have hybrids you know
you have yeah because I I s's lavender I
can tell you the back story on those
that came from a gentleman in Yuba City
California who got 90 Selma stock and he
did a pheno hunt and he selected that
cut from the best 23 females that he got
from that
stock and that's what I know about the
backstory of that I can tell you a
little bit
about I can tell you a a little bit
about the plant the lavender cut
has floral lavender turps with a back a
back end that's not unlike real opium if
you've ever experienced it so the first
the first initial um hit to the palette
would be like lavender aroma therapy and
then that gives way to something a
little more complex which is a spice not
unlike
opium and that plant is finished and no
later than 53 days I've grown two three
foot long Louisville Sluggers in really
bad Seasons outside without a spe of
mold outcross is like a champ the
branches on it it's a very tight to
itself plant so it's it needs topping
but the branches on it are like Lumber
it's absolutely insane prehistoric fans
very tight internodal growth and um it's
more potent than the named purple cuts
that I've encountered which would be a
berry um granddaddy purple purple Urkel
none of them are slouches in the potency
department but I think there's higher
LOLOL count in my lavender cut and
that's the other thing about it um that
and the alcross is are my wife and I
goto for anxiety and for sleep and not
to be too graphic but I've heard reports
that it's good for women's monthly woes
as well yeah this sounds a lot like this
sounds a lot like the lavender that mad
uses is it the same
cut no I have a lot of respect for him
it looks along the same lines but it's
definitely not the same cut different
sources shout out to mad family good
people in Oklahoma now oh awesome yeah
so that's a little about that um let's
see how bad my memory is so the next one
I
have pot of gold mother from feed pop of
Old Stock which would make it an F3 I
have that mother and then I have a 90 St
clone that uh somebody was kind enough
to gift to me so there's two different
things there I'll go down them and when
I my memory doesn't serve me how about
you ad lib I'll go down the ones I
remember all right I thought so pot of
gold is from um 90 stock Flying Dutchman
it's skunk one times Hindu C and that's
a plant that finishes in about 63 days
and it makes uh dense golf ball type
structure of the plant and the turps I
would describe as a skunk family and an
apple orchard it's got very mated notes
to it it's almost like the first toke
off off a bowl is um almost like a thin
mint I'm not going to stay cookies but
it has that that mtila mouth feel to it
and then as you exhale it's like burnt
rubber intermingling with skunk with
with the back note of Apple on it that's
the best way I can describe it and uh
it's funny I bet a lot of these that
they were COA would not test very high
but as far as potency you know threo
potency I put the pipe down I think it's
definitely comparable to some of these
high Tac test test things so that's the
other one um the GT4 cut came from an i
mag thread it came directly from Josie
May he rest in peace um I'm not sure we
we're on the fence introducing so if it
Steve you see this and uh I spoke out of
line my apologies because we're still
figuring out exactly what we're running
but I know most of that list is going to
be available soon uh the sugar P came
from my favorite sourer cut in the
industry I know it's a Hot Topic uh that
cut came from Mr Bob
henel and the cookies in that lineage
I'm not a huge cookies fan but it I like
them in outcrosses and I kind of
validate them by hitting them with old
school stuff I have a a few exceptions I
make for that nothing against them at
all it's just personal preference but
there's there's some goodness there is a
as a Chassy for me I look at as kind of
like a blank canvas so the sugar puss
that's on there Mr Bob hemple sourer cut
times bag seed mail that was found in an
official cookies draw a while back so
that's pretty much that one and uh
that's a great plant because it's got
the gas hour turp with the Fresh Bakery
stuff in there and it's a banger it
yields heavy checks all the boxes like I
said I I was looking at your list of of
of your strains not the grateful Head
one well I have a question um about like
the Grateful heads so I am ignorant
actually what so is this a gen uh like a
a clone uh like you're you're providing
genetics and are planning on doing it
globally or uh I'm I'm actually bit not
not
informed oh oh I'm sorry man I should
have done the intro um The Grateful head
is a collective of breeders and
geneticists who have access to a lab we
are offering fzero gen clones on a
global platform um Steve at craft
medical the CEO along with Kevin JRE as
as a majority shareholder Dutch blooms
in Skunk VA
and then the minority shareholders or
breeders and geneticists such as such as
myself um I can't remember them all
massm on IG um fire in the whole
genetics um Allstar clone from uh
Southern California's in there and I
can't remember there's 16 of them so God
help me I definitely it will be a global
Library yeah a real library for Global
Repository the main point about them is
Providence pain of custody is asstight
so if you're wanting to get the real
chem 91 or the real lavender they don't
play around obviously so any genetic
material that's introduced we have to go
through a very very vigorous background
you know to the 's degree before it's
even contemplated so it's exciting for
worry getting one or a hybrid of
something that isn't there when you know
that you're you're getting that through
us you know you're getting the real
chm91 from the man himself or the real
chamd or the real pot of gold the real
lavender and that that's exciting to me
because nothing against anyone I I see
so many knockoffs I see s1s I see fake
cuts I just don't even comment anymore
it's not worth it and and is this
already available to the community or is
this something that's coming
available um regarding my genetic
material I will be introducing it to to
the lab and for testing um January 15th
or before so sometime however long the
TC protocol takes mine will be
introduced but we already have live
drops going and uh you could find out
more about that on the Grateful heads or
Dutch Bloom's page where I think there's
a sticky thread with everybody mentioned
on
there
okay very
cool and uh so do you still have a
cultivation facility uh of your your own
in Oklahoma or have you like kind of
dedicated that space to these other
projects
or uh that's a really good question we
moved and downsized a little bit only
because I didn't need acreage and our
business model is only set up for my
wife and I which shout out to my lovely
wife because she my mother room on sleek
and she is the my queen of logistics
without her it'd probably be messy so
thank God for her so for sure uh we
downsized a little bit I have a half an
acre for outdoor which is all I need for
my purposes and I have a 30X 20 40
lighter here as well and then the rest
of of my home in garage is set up um as
a drawing room and testing area where we
keep the mother room and where I test
everything before I I let it out cool
but uh I I think because of the way
things are headed that commercial flour
that's a race to the bottom I'm focusing
on feed increases and and maintaining my
mother's stock and testing my new drop
because uh there needs to be more
transparency I think from in general
with testing so I I like to post the
mails I like to post the testing The
Good the Bad and the Ugly and get it out
there so uh you get what I what I would
think is a product I can put my name on
pretty much for sure and so so are you
using that 40 lighter to do all the um
you know the the feno hunting and
whatnot yes and no right right now I'm
using my home which has an ample enough
setup but um I don't think it's going to
justify not having a commercial license
firing that up with the overhead and
everything at least not not for now but
that's always there I do things
backwards from a lot of breeders because
my thing is who wants a plant that does
Great Indoors commercially produces for
somebody but falls apart when it's
outside so we have no plant count here
so I'm I'm the opposite I do my testing
outside for first I make my selections
based on the most vigorous plants that
don't show sep sep Foria powdery Miler
or btis then I bring them inside and
test them which is probably the opposite
of what a lot of people do I think isn't
Oklahoma Hurricane Alley or Tornado
Alley um it's shifted in the past three
years if you follow any of and we're not
in the area that's dry Barren and Dusty
that gets that we're actually in a group
little place that zone
7B and we are in the foothills of the
Ozarks in southeast Oklahoma near the
Arkansas border it's just such a great
outdoor growing climate that I I can't
even believe that we can produce the
quality of the outdoor flower because it
never rains here in the fall it's dry so
we get a lot of the outdoor you know
that looks like indoor
wow not even
Greenhouse no Li the
no aome just full time full sun full
full sun and that that does require
Vigilant IPM but it like I said I it
took a lot of learning curve to get the
climate down and to know what works and
and what doesn't work and uh I'm really
happy to say that we might have had
maximum of the outdoor Harvest um less
than 8%
loss even if it yes even even it uh rain
here you're still going to get btis with
certain super thick cultivars and
especially if you get uh Bud worms I
mean even even Without Rain that'll
that'll cause mold so the very few
little bits were from the budw worms
that's a whole that's a big battle here
and that requires uh they get immune to
bailus th gensis here so I alternate
with uh other things like theel that are
all all safe organic from the same
company and whatnot it takes that and
uh getting underneath the plants looking
under it's time consuming but it's what
it takes to make good flower here in the
state and it's funny some of the
cultivars I've had coas done from indoor
of the same screen and outdoor it's
always a higher not that I'm a huge
advocate of judging weed on CHC content
but tpine content in TC always seem p
with sungrown then the COA from the the
same strain run into
doors it's the full spectrum I mean full
spectrum we always say this term but
it's the absolute light you know what I
mean it's the planet Sun you know it's
it's not the planet it's a sun all the
other planets are are around it you know
like we are circulating around the sun
right so it's like this is this is it
the base of life you know is every every
every plant you see you know you've been
growing up in a in a in a Countryside
right you know cuz you talk about the
Farm as you you were a kid right you
know you know plant from beginning this
is something you observe they are around
you all the all your life in the
beginning you don't really realize this
you don't really cuz you are interested
in other stuff first and then actually
it comes behind you and then if you
catch the flow you do it because with
wheat actually what you told the story
is very similar to mine also like not
the the other drama you told but because
I live in another place but uh you know
from the perspective how you look to the
plant uh and now from breeding
perspective would be I uh I think that
after I read the mandle mandle you know
from the 19th C mandle you know the
first and the second and the third rule
of mandle you know uh he actually did it
on tulps and fish and you know he breed
with other stuff not Canabis right but
he actually uh was like a guy that could
see the code in the living organism how
it behaves the F1 generation from
through two very far away parents will
be a very good hybrid yeah and then from
that hybrid if you go to F2 in the
filial line you will have like the whole
picture of colors now choose one color
that you like right you know and go that
way because then in the F3 you will end
up with more of the that color you know
what I mean yeah that is with tomato and
any other vegetables right real quick on
F2 that is where a lot of the gems are
to be found and a prime example as
you're going through line breeding is
there are some jewels that can be
unlocked I look at it kind of like
opening up the Final Phase in the video
game for
example I have Super Lemon Haze times A5
Thai and I'm running through the F the
f2s to make my increase which I'm going
to have soon and um I found a recessive
trate Broad Leaf that looked like none
of them and it smelled like lemon
gasoline my mind was so blown and I I
thank God I cloned it and I ended up
pollinating it and because it's so far
away from the goal Target of what I want
with my release which is Jagged salus
seras thae looking plant that I'm not
releasing it but I'm keeping that clone
for R&amp;D so my point being is a lot of
end users like feed buyers Sky away from
the f2s I think there's always the
potential to unlock a recessive trait
that you might not see to the F6
generation which would bu in turn be a
pure breeding line or an IBL for sure
yes yeah yeah I I did a little or I did
a little breeding with a a great apape
sensey star mother and a um or a great
APAP sensey star father and a and a
Run's mother and then um when I got that
to the F2 generation I was getting these
uh two major different uh like
structural phenotypes of like one being
super short and squat like the Grape Ape
and then one being really tall and
stretchy and um the tall and stretchy
one I found one where it was just uh
like all grape uh and it was it was
really Pleasant to find that because all
the small ones were very grapy but then
all the tall ones had that sort of uh
spicy earthy um earthiness of like uh
kind of some of the older purples and
and a little bit of what I I remember
sensey star being but um yeah it was it
was really
cool I hope you cloned or did you clone
the unusual I did and then I I did and
then I moved and I lost everything but I
still have probably like couple thousand
of the F2 seeds so I I can hunt through
those
whenever yeah the everybody has The One
That Got Away story but this year
because there's so many times when I've
grown it out and was like God I can't
rev it why didn't I clone that and uh
yeah this year I got two that I think
I'm really really really happy that I
saved and the one was a volunteer that
came out of my compost pile and it R and
veg and I'm like what the hell is that I
didn't even and I had to backtrack to
what soil I put in a from run to get a
rough assimilation of what the parents
were I remember I ran lemon lemon tree
and gorilla four and the plant that came
out of it I grew it outside you can see
it back on my Instagram feed is louder
than the lemon tree and it's so resinous
it's insane it was a very skimpy
producer but then again I started it
late outside so I'm running that indoors
for R&amp;D too but uh people if you get an
ankling and you have a plant even if
it's an early veg and you can house it
trust your gut instinct cuz a lot of
yall are watching this have been around
plants long enough that you can learn to
trust your gut instinct even when the
plant at it's Fourth node that it's
going to be special so what I'm saying
is uh don't have regrets like all of us
have and quone it if you think you're on
to something and don't throw the runs
away either because those always end up
being the
best OG KB has entered a conversation
yeah right exactly it's like the the
weirdest you know curliest Leaf looking
[ __ ] and then it's just not
growing like anything else and then it's
turns out to be just like the best smoke
dude I'm the worst at calling everything
when I see people a lot of times be like
well we had all these mut and I got rid
of them and I like I'm crying on the
inside because some of some of those
mutants are worth the wait and they'll
grow out of their stunted trait or
whatever's wrong with them and develop
into amazing plants man I'm just
thinking like wish I could keep them all
yeah even like Mac one you know
like is just terrible because it it
takes forever to get a good clone mother
off of it and then it's like being
overgrown by anything else that's around
it and I always hates pollen hates
pollen yeah I thought I was able to get
some seeds off of that
uh that military chocolate dad and uh I
have to run those I have them sitting
somewhere I have the Caps Frozen lemons
which is similar to that like it grows
and you know it's so you talk about the
back one and this is another capulator
strain um it grows so slow in veg it
takes a really long time till you know
it becomes a plant with decent enough
structure that you want to flower it but
what's cool about it is that then when
you flower it it doesn't really
stretch and you know like for indoor
cultivators see baby or multi-tier
Gardens it's nice to be able to have a
plant that does doesn't want to have a
big stretch and it's it's super unique
weed it has a like Jacky T profile not
exactly Jack more like citrus than Jack
but um to me it's a sativa that grows
very much like an Indica you know so
like nowadays when people are wanting to
grow sativas you know you just can't do
it you know a plant that takes 14 or 16
weeks to flower you know and gets 10 ft
tall um yeah so the Caps Frozen lemons
it's culator put out some good stuff I I
think the Caps Frozen lemons I prefer to
the Mac 1 I'm not a big fan of the tur
profile of the Mac 1 and the Caps Frozen
lemons I think is it's really that one
sounds really good I'll have to get you
yeah I I respect Cap's work I remember
him I remember him on THC farmer posting
back in the day before his his fit blew
off he stuck with it and I think that's
a testament because a lot of people out
there in probably any Walk of Life or
trade if you keep doing what you're
doing and really have passion in it you
you push forward and you accept the
failures eventually something good going
to happen like us sitting here talking
together if I would have gave up I
wouldn't even be here and we you know
never even expected to be mildly
successful I'm not saying we're taking
over the world but uh it's really built
and I think that comes with taking the
lumps and just never stopping I think
that's the best thing and that goes to
like beginner people that are starting
out beginning hobby Growers tent Growers
you're going to mess up share the
mistakes and you you just keep doing it
and if you never stop and you're around
for long enough people are going to get
tired of seeing the and you're going to
be successful I think and also I think
you know all the Breeders uh the small
scale or or even the big scale for
example I will tell about Shanti again
Shanti Baba is one of those guys that
still uh communicating with his uh not
only customers you don't need to be be a
customer to ask him something you know
on his Forum but he's communicating with
you on his Forum on the Mr Nice seats
Forum he has a forum and cap cap coule
does the same thing he has some basement
some basement B you know I love this you
know these guys really are true breeders
through the caregivers you know you can
talk to them you know SK VA has uh this
uh how is it uh you know Reddit not
Reddit uh it's Discord yeah Discord and
uh Duke Diamond has the Discord and you
can reach those guys if you want to you
know I can only accessibility
accessibility yeah that is great and
then you know that these guys actually
really care for the what they do because
uh they they are accessible they you
know it's not like always no of course
you can't fake the funk you can't fake
the funk man no many others they are you
know maybe DJ Short is was a long time
ago also accessible not in that way
because but today he's little older I
think and I respect his work so much
also you know from a European
perspective uh because he's so his
genetics are not Dutch you know he took
his own genetics and Bre them together
and still has this you know uh I don't
know much about him rather than I've
been waiting from the '90s to know who
this guy is and then in 2000 something a
YouTube video appeared with a interview
with him and I was like wow man this a
professor you know like i' been I've
been around long enough to know that the
dut banks that got his blueberry never
paid him properly Unfortunately they
never paid him properly it is like they
took his work and they never let him
even select with them you know and then
they advertised it in the beginning as
it we were working with DJ Short and
after that they put his name out today
you can just read about blue lines you
know uh we will not talk about people
can Google it who it is and everything
but I'm actually every time I see this
you know that people [ __ ] somebody
like so directly like that you know I
will always cherish the real one you
know now that we're on that topic I'm
not going to get into the who the how
but um people out there if you're a
budding breeder or anything you have to
be really really careful careful who you
trust things with because uh we're not
going to delve on it but I think there's
some validity to this um recently a
friend that had gained trust that asked
me to acquire some some genetics that
were very rare and dear to me which was
pre98 Calli myth Neville Taz and uh
original Hayes the non AG stuff that was
sourced in Amsterdam by my friend two
Tree Farm who uh used to own the Great
area shout out the two trees on
IG and he got them for me and I
reluctantly told the friend the terms he
had wanted some Haze genetics and I said
look uh I know you're threat out in and
I doubled down I want to make sure that
you can do the increase and do the
selections for me and very recently uh
this happened in fact the day before
Thanksgiving 6 months later I didn't see
a picture of them no update no selection
done and the guy just got really nasty
said they're dead F you so people be
careful get everything in writing
document anything if it's larger scale
get a lawyer to draw up some contents we
don't like necessarily the plant
patenting thing but it's still someone's
intellectual property that meant
something to them and just be really
really wary of people because a lot of
people have this hippie moniker that
they adapt and then they use that as as
a math to gain Trust and I I think
that's all I'm going to delve on that
topic today is just to uh be careful man
it's my first nature to trust and some
people see that as as a weakness and uh
there's a less and learn in in that yeah
capitalists are going to
capitalize I I I want to say something
to that because you reminded me of an
old story that isn't just
cannabis or it's not about cannabis at
all actually um so first of all you have
to be careful right but what happens to
a lot of people is they get burned and
they don't trust people at all right so
you should be careful but don't give up
on the human race and don't give up on
people right my story and I I I'll tell
it quickly I used to go eat at this
Chinese
restaurant like couple times a week and
this is when I lived in the country I
lived in
cazadero and the restaurant was in Santa
Rosa it was like from near there go
ahead yeah so it's like 40 40 minutes
away from where I live
and one day um and this is like pre cell
phones I think you know this is in the
9s and uh I left home and I left without
my
wallet but I eat at this restaurant all
the time yeah I know the
owner and so I show up to the restaurant
and I tell the guy like hey you know
what I ordered food to go
but I left my wallet at home I said can
I pay you tomorrow and he says
no I say why and he says because I've
been burned too many
times and so I asked him I said what are
you going to do with this food says I'm
going to throw it
away and I'm thinking to
myself man oh no way and I told him I
said I feel so bad for you that you lost
trust in humanity to the point where you
would rather throw it away than trust
that someone is going
to you know come back tomorrow and pay
for the
food you know and what I want to say is
you know I believe you got to be careful
right you know I mean but and it sucks
that you got burned you told me a little
bit of the story yesterday I been burned
I mean I have a situation where I've
been burned by the same person
twice you know because I wanted to
believe
that they would do better because I
maybe I believe in people too much but I
think you got to find the balance right
don't there's a fine line between being
cautious and being cynical and I'm not
the type of person to be wired to be
cynical I'm very outgoing and I I love
people so I think it's just basically
never gambling what you can't afford to
lose while still being open to having
trusting relationships that's key and uh
and if you make some gambles you ain't
going to get the big reward too you just
got to gamble with a small percentage of
what of you know of what your net worth
whether it's in cannabis or or anything
else you know it's like friendship
requires trust and Trust requires
vulnerability so you gota you gota
like there's so much to what he he just
said too yeah because I've gotten to
where I am today which I'm not quite
sure where that is other than
Oklahoma by not being by not being
afraid to be rejected like some of the
higher profile people higher status
people whether it be in music or theater
or movies um you're never going to land
the Hail Mary that you don't throw and
i' I've ended up in some places that I
didn't think I would and that's from
being able to accept rejection and it's
kind of like a a really weak analogy and
by no means misogynistic if a guy hits
on 10 beautiful girls one of them is
going to go out with them you know what
I mean so you got to gamble sometimes in
life because you're never going to land
that Hil Mary if you don't throw it Val
what you said I want Nick to repeat what
he said because I feel like we're
talking over him and it was it was a a
nugget that that should go ahead ni that
you think I talked over him no I mean it
was off the cuff and and I've been
smoking so you're not going to get it
out of me again you're going to have to
back to
that all righty I think that's one
second speaking to smoking I'm gonna
yell to my uh my beautiful wife to bring
me a bowl because it's not near
me okay
uh i i s well I remember what I I had
said before so it's uh friendship
requires trust and Trust requires
vulnerability so that's true you have to
open up to be
vulnerable it's true like so true
s you know my what I can add to it now
is like I've been traveling a lot which
I told in the last two podcast a lot
little bit about it and you then when
you travel through different countries
different cultures really really far
away from your your uh home you know
where you used to be in your culture
then normally it's also you have to
accept the the the the difference you
know it's really also uh and then you
develop a sense of somebody that you
look in the eye directly and can sense
if he wants something bad or not I mean
I will have traveling through all of
Asia almost uh in the night in Jakarta
for example which is a place like you
it's not it's actually not dangerous if
you know how to behave you know what I
mean it's like uh of course if you're
stupid you're going to go in uh
different places of the world you're
going to go in the wrong Street for
example in Amsterdam we've been attacked
one day you know uh by by some guys but
uh my friend who was with me is also
from the Balon area and he said a swear
word in Serbian to them and they leave
they let us in the moment and they went
away uh and we were asking in Amsterdam
at that time why you know why was it
like that because he was swearing you
know in Serbian and they said to to us
yeah because Serbian Mafia is having the
place now you know in this time I don't
know what who is having it now you know
at that time but at those times also the
Balon Mafia was there you know I mean
people on the street the the the bad
guys you know uh you can avoid them if
you have the feeli you don't need to ENC
encounter them you you you you avoid
them all the time you know even in
conversation you you a short and you
always when they invite you somewhere
you don't go and you know you you have
to sense it it's a little bit of a of a
third feeling you know in the God I mean
that's how we survive right you know but
also with the business it's like that
you know I've been burned too maybe one
day I will talk about it in the podcast
but really in the business you know you
get burnt and you have to accept it then
you go on you have to learn something
from it and you go on you know that's it
you have to go on right you
know I want to say something um first of
all L that's such a like
what a proper thing to say that
friendship is you know being being able
to be vulnerable and open with somebody
and like that's why um Sasha and I have
become
friends is because you know over the
last few weeks we've been talking to
each other and we've been willing to be
vulnerable and tell each other things
like this and that's when we realized
that we're so much alike that if we
don't if we're not willing to be
vulnerable we don't get an opportunity
to have these moments and and make these
friendships if not it's
like you're just like one of those
plastic girls that are really fake you
know you don't you know like fine
they're pretty but you have no idea who
they really are they probably don't know
who they are either
but but yeah I mean you know I'm say
this me and Sasha have become super good
friends
because we did this podcast together and
I I hope we we get to make a friendship
too Mark I'm coming back youall ain't
GNA get rid of
me soon we're gonna have like 30 uh
co-hosts because everyone that we do a
show with I fall in love with you know I
mean a really good idea on that time man
so my friend is a Pioneer he started um
cerebral feeds with Tony from Saga with
sond from Sirus he the gray area and
Amsterdam and he's so damn that he's
good at self-promotion he was there when
all these legendary crosses happen with
Adam done we should get on here because
uh he just parted ways with a grow that
he was really contingent on that for his
income and I sparked an idea yesterday
said with
all with you
pioneering you start a seed company and
he's like dude why didn't I even think
of that I'm like dude what do you mean
I'm like get it going and I will help
you get it out there that's needs to get
some AirPlay man he was there with the
pioneers and he won't tell you this but
I think he met he met the stones in
Amsterdam and was their weed dealer for
a little bit he did security for the
whole steel wheel tour over there like
that so if you'd ever be open to get him
on there that would not only be doing me
at solid what make it happen two cre
Farm on Instagram I'm saying can make
you said you said you said he doesn't
like to
brag can you make it happen that he does
an episode with us we'll do it together
yeah okay yeah I get off the podcast
well one thing about one thing about
what we're doing I think I think I owe
him money for whenever I'm upset it's
like an hour long dude I'm like what are
you going to give
me well um you know we want to be a
place where people tell their story and
you know Mark he's never he's been on
the Adam dun show and I love Adam and me
and Adam go back to Amsterdam nothing
against you bro if you're watching it
you talk a lot and we got to we got to
get by's word out there to the
world in the most respectful way Adam if
you ever see
this oh I love Adam I've been friends
with him for a long time too um you know
like well what I what I want to do with
this podcast is I want to give people a
platform to tell their story and what I
was going to say is you know a lot of
people may look at the title and they
see Mark Gallow and they're going to say
well who's this guy but you have a
compelling story you have a really comp
telling story and and so that's what I
want to do so if he wants to do the show
it sounds like you know he's got a
compelling story we would be honored to
have him do it and the other thing that
I want to add love to man it he yeah he
was there when this all happened man he
so damn understated I think once he got
into it we would let spark a fire and
his story needs to be heard
um and his his gen is some of the the
rarest most thought after colars that
are out there I mean he's he's got quite
a lineup I'll let him tell you and we'll
save it for the the story uh let's say
let's save this for the show the one
other thing that I want to add and I I
know I've talked to you about it is
something else that we're trying to do
here on this channel is make a place for
smaller Growers to tell their stories
hom growers okay and the thing about it
is you know a lot of people they hear
these stories and it seems like a
fantasy like man you know I could never
do that or when they see uh pictures or
videos of a commercial grow it doesn't
Inspire them to grow and so I want to
make a place where closet gardeners can
be proud of their garden and they can
tell their story about how they were
first exposed to cannabis like you did
like when you told us when you were you
know planted your first plants in your
compost pile I think people want to hear
those stories and also when you see a
nice closet Garden or a little tent
Garden I think that inspires more people
to grow their own than when they see the
jungle boys with a massive you know
multi-tier uh grow room right Gabby I I
gotta say I gotta say something I said
it to you before but I want this to get
out there the dankest weed I have ever
seen in my life was grown in someone's
basement grown in someone's truck grow
with a creaky HPS
light all right or in a t and that's
where these people under Every Little
Rock like you had said earlier in Cris
are and to this day the dankest wheed
I've ever seen did not come from a
commercial row so that's validating what
you're saying they have a voice it's
just on a smaller scale some people with
I love you some people scream I love
you yes well I think I think the thing
is is and
like I don't know if it's if it's
humility or like you know when I talk to
these people they say well who wants to
hear my story why would somebody want to
hear my story when they
he well exactly and and there's more
people like them than there are people
that was that are um drawing on a large
scale you know know and so like I said I
want to encourage hom Growers now so
with hom Growers it's a little bit
different right um I we can't bring
every hom grower onto the show okay but
what we're doing is we're trying to
encourage them to send us submissions
like make a video at home it doesn't
have to be professional you know I our
podcast does not look professional I
have a fancy Studio I got the light
shining in my in the window making a a
huge shine on my bald head
which I know is uh you know terrible for
everyone but um you know I I like I said
I really want this place to be a place
where anyone can tell their story now
having said that I want to give you guys
a little insight on the interview that
we're doing
tomorrow cuz I'm literally freaking out
okay this guy um
he G made strains for the
cartels okay like but but the cartels
were uh I'm trying to remember what the
guy's name like when you watched the
Netflix special narcos the guy who Chapo
well it wasn't El Chapo the Mexican one
okaya right but like the guy that
invented
sensia trying to remember what his name
is um but yeah the guy that invented
selia he got the genetics from this
guy and I've known him for 30 years and
he told me these stories a long time
ago and then uh he actually saw the
craft YouTube
channel and he made a comment and I I
asked if he wanted to tell his story no
one he's never told his story before
publicly and I'm ping in man that's
insane I cannot wait to see I I I've
been up all night thinking about like
how ridiculous this podcast is going to
be and it's probably going to have to be
like multiple episodes cuz he has the
craziest stories
like I would never do it justice and I
don't want to be a spoiler but I'm glad
you did did your podcast first because
like holy I'm like I don't know how I'm
ever going to live up to this podcast
that we're going to do tomorrow like I'm
never GNA be get this get this for
synergy
very close friend of mine lived with
them too and they might know each other
it would be just insanity and we talk
about it on the daily he said that's why
he doesn't like Edibles because he
dreams a lot about some of the things
that happened down there I could
possibly get him on there and I'm not
even it's crazy that that's actually
happening because I speak to this person
on the daily and he's legit he's got
pictures of down there and he he grew
weed for
them so
uh I I probably shouldn't but I'm going
to read I want to read some of this that
he sent me I can't wait to hear it dude
do it do it oh my God it's crazy Le
stuff I'm gonna be honest if you were to
look at my history on what we watch when
we're streaming it's either cartel
related stuff True
Crime you know reality I I have it over
here so I asked him to give me like a
short
uh like description he said I brought
Advanced genetics to cartel marijuana
operations that business that
proposition took me into Mexico to the
highest levels of the guadalahara cartel
and he
says yeah I I supplied genetics for
Rancho Buffalo their giant cannabis farm
in chichua and then he
said uh I parted in San Francisco and
many other venues with Rafael Caro
quento who invented s Samilia and Miguel
Felix cardo head of the guadalahara
cartel so like this is the the show
narcos that was on Netflix this guy
lived the life I said to
him um I love it did they represent you
on the show Naros and he says in Naros
Mexico season 2 the first episode
depicts a party at gallardo's estate in
Mexico City where Al Chapo gave gardo a
Bengal T tiger as a gift he says I was
the only Gringo at that
party you gotta save the rest man oh
dude I love I love that gangster stuff
definitely yeah I'm just like and you
know I asked him and he's like I've
never told this story publicly before
you know he tells friends he told me 30
years ago like you know when I met him
all this [ __ ] that he used to be into
and um oh my God yeah the ne the next
show is going to be
ridiculous I'm all in man I can't wait
to see it well I I will totally listen
I'll totally share it on my Instagram
that that's happening you just copy and
paste the language you like me to use
preempted I got you I'll put it on all
kinds of platforms well I really want
you
know if there are people that you know
that would like to tell their story
please connect us and and so far the
couple of people that you mentioned I
think they would be great for our show
and and and it would be
great itive there's a
mys do you have any other genetics you
want to talk to us about like your
current stuff um the current menu um
there's a lot of new outcrosses on there
I got lucky and OG Rascal did a discret
auction that was only in his story never
win anything I felt like I won the
lottery was able to and the others were
donated by someone who else who won the
lottery shout out the Philly Roger I was
able to get OG Rascals legit WiFi 3 OG
Rascals Wii
43 um Skywalker OG and OG Rascal lemons
so the one new yeah the one new outcross
doing really well I'm calling Jedi
Master and that is Skywalker OG times 04
bog sour bubble bc2 F2 from bogs first
drop and arguably the best iteration
from Boe heads so uh Jed Master Jedi
Master is one the other is um Violet
buard which is 90 Soma lavender crossed
to the same sour bubble male and uh big
buds of floral lavender with the back
end of uh coffee from the Bubba cush
influence from the sourer bubbles it's
Del
nutrius turpy and pasty to the Head
we're going down the list U Miracle
bubble mints capulator that was the cap
donkey Cross by the same sour bubble
mail and gandi garden shud from 707 made
the cross was shared by gandal or um
farm so an IG taken to F3 by me so
basically a match up of the best to I
found with the best SF OG and Seed form
um commercial yields bread outside very
resistant
um I got the sour gasoline tur for the
OG C on the back end Sable resonance all
boox check moving on what's the next one
H let me go back uh you said the John
already I didn't go into what the the
the nomenclature was of the John Wi-Fi
so the John is Wi-Fi 3 cut the I got
from um OG Rascal cross to the same sour
bubble mail um the skinny on that is
that's for Indica overload lovers
massive prehistoric fans like to be to
twice to really put out longer veg time
and you'll be rewarded with uh your
wheelchair weed where you can sit and
watch yento and not get bored with that
St
recommended yent of the weed but the
movie for for the that's for the day
Ender people that don't have a love plan
that's totally IND overloan and think
the The Violet B Burger guard is the one
that I'm drooling over the most on your
list that's a great one too and uh
during our test runs uh I think that
might have been my my wife's favorite
flower and she's very particular she's
from Northern California so he doesn't
get excited about flower much and uh is
that
it uh uh I'm not sure you have a you
have an extensive list but people should
just check you out on your Instagram
Marcus marus
aelius great
name thank you he he was a stoic and
some of my all-time favorite quotes came
from him and I got the
nickname from my aunt who was a a school
teacher she used to call me Marcus
aurelios and it's St is a
nickname nice it's easy to remember but
you know what also I want to ask you
Gallow are you related to the Gallow
family the wine
makers I'm related to the other Gallow
family the New York one the
gangsters
yeah oh sounds like stories for another
podcast there's so many I haven't even I
haven't even scratched the surface well
also related to the The Gallows and and
um Tulsa Oklahoma who had the first
pizza shop in the 1950
has done two podcasts with us and we're
probably going to have to do and I mean
like when we talk about his story we're
probably going to have to do about four
or five more till we even scratch the
surface so we're gonna invite you to do
more as well um it was super nice
meeting you Sasha and I I really want to
hear your story because um it it's all
valid to what's going on currently in
your area and all over Europe and I
think uh we're going to see more Synergy
between the states and Europe as
cannabis legalizes more expansion and
hopefully we can all build long-term
relationships with one another and keep
keep some synergistic flow moving
forward I think so the it will
definitely uh the the true people you
know like the true people will always
find a way to communicate and connect on
the end you know it doesn't matter where
you're from no you know what I mean like
people I think globally also watch this
now not only Europe and America and USA
I mean uh it will spread and this kind
of uh it's the biggest Community
actually you can have because you
spitting spitting truth all the time
here you know I have I have never let an
invisible fent get in the way of me
making friends or anyone's ethnicity
religion or political inclination at the
end of the day it's Tey and it's cliche
we we are all one and we are closer
closely related than we think and there
should be more camaraderie especially in
the Cannabis industry because we're here
for the love you know Absol ex I'm
certainly not here to get rich ask my
wife it wouldn't suck if it happened by
Co happen sense well the the the good
way to look at it money procured through
cannabis is it's not the motivation the
monetary it's it's a perk it's not the
primary motivate the perk is comes from
the passion I think that's a good way to
look at it yeah I think that's a great
way to leave this too so I'm going to
just thank you once again Mark I'm going
to tell you we're going to have to have
you come back on for at least one more
podcast to keep telling us stories yes
um but yeah yeah I'm going to close on
this everyone that I've super every
podcast I've super enjoyed go so fast
because there's so much good content and
anyone needs
share this episode of gabbing with Gabby
is brought to you by the Breeders direct
seed company in my opinion the Breeders
direct seed company is your Premier
Source for clones and seeds and they are
the only place that you can get the
Gabby satin Island collection so visit
breeders direct for all your seed and
clone needs
[Music]
oh