this episode of gabbing with Gabby is
brought to you by the Breeders direct
Seed Company in my opinion the Breeders
direct seed company is your Premier
Source for clones and seeds and they are
the only place that you can get the
Gabby Statin Island collection so visit
breeders direct for all your seed and
clone needs
[Music]
what's up everybody this is Gabby Staten
Island doing the gabbing with Gabby
podcast with my
co-hosts Nick wolf and Cosmic Charlie
we're also joined today by NATO dog
who's helping us out with this interview
also NATO dog just um watch your
positioning on the screen cuz you're
cutting off your face a little bit you
might want to put the camera back a
little bit and Center yourself a little
bit that way yeah that's better and then
we got my good friend Mike who's also
known as the weasel or Klo we're going
to ask him why and how he got that
nickname but one of the main
focuses of this podcast for me is to
tell my story and Mike is a big part of
the story we're going to get into it and
and also he's the guy that created the
sour diesel so let's get started one
more time not so dog you're cutting off
your face I am yeah it's hard to see
sometimes like you're not centered I
know I I'm I'm hunched now I'm like a
hunchback over here just Center yourself
a little bit that way no you have plenty
of head room but you just need to move
over that way a little bit this way
right that's yeah that's better all
right fine all righty so let me start by
saying the weasel Mike he's a longtime
friend of mine and I'm super excited to
have him on this podcast and lots of
people have been asking for it so here
we go so Mike I I want to start by us
telling the story about how we
met I know we we've discussed it a
little bit in the past but
uh you want to you want to just start
off and tell a story about how we met it
was I believe fall of
92 right after the Dead shows at Madison
was
91 okay 91 that's not a big deal I was
just already in California in
'92 okay but you were going back and
forth but let's wait a minute all right
so it doesn't matter that doesn't
matter uh I was sitting on my back steps
we'll put it this way and just I I was
spun from the show last night how about
that and
some hippie walking by and he shoots me
a PE sign hit him back with
one and uh he comes turns around comes
walking
over and asked me you know if I needed
any buds anything
else I was like yeah you know I'll smoke
some weed with this guy you know and um
cuz hey I had two friends that are
around the
corner I said all right he says is it
all right if they come over I said can I
go meet him and he's like yeah I'm like
all right we walking we're in the town
eltville on Richmond Avenue and the
train station and there's this guy he's
got long black hair he's got one single
dreadlock lot of purple
[Music]
on and he with a girl and they're
sitting by the edge of the street you
know and they introduced me to them next
thing we know we're up at my house these
guys are camping out for a
week I had a great time you know and we
hooked up and uh we started talking
about weed and growing and you know we
ideas the wheels were rolling right then
let's put it that way so the way I
remember it is that
we showed you some indoor weed and you
had never seen indoor weed before you
had grown Outdoors like for over a over
a decade but that was the first time you
ever saw some like indoor kind bud and I
remember you saying you can grow this
inside you were just you were just
shocked and amazed yeah and I was
shocked and amazed
um but I wasn't like really growing a
lot like you know I'd grow one or two
plants outside so for saying to Growing
for 10 years it's kind of it's you know
and you're only doing it a little bit
here and
there but uh so yes you s you put the
the wheels were rolling right there I'm
telling you the wheels were rolling
upstairs and I went and I got a book I
all my friends laughed at me I started
growing in the closet
but you before the closet it was the
fish tank remember that I don't remember
okay so let me let me remind you because
that's what that's what's great about
having multiple people here is that so
what I remember is you planted your
first seeds in a fish tank okay like you
just put some soil on the bottom of a
fish tank and you put some seeds in
there and your cat kept digging it up oh
my God you're
right
right cuz he thought it was a
lot funny you're right so that that's
what I was telling NATO dog and everyone
like I love having these conversations
with people cuz we all remember
different stuff yeah you know and so I
will never forget how mad you were at
that cat cuz like you and he he did it
twice not just once he did it twice but
the thing is is like I think seeds were
hard to come by like good seeds yeah
sure any and and and the cat was the
disrupted them and then I think even
when I put them in the containers or
whatever else I started to to learn how
to do you know he was still digging them
out you know what I'm saying and the cat
had to go eventually I mean in in the
cat's defense there's probably
significant overlap between like you
know like an you know an indoor litter
box and a nice you know smoothed out
bunch of soil in the bottom of a of a
fish tank you know yeah
yeah smelling clean the
soil definitely yeah so what what I tell
people is that you know I inspired you
to plant those seeds and to grow your
original uh plants in the closet but
after that you were the one that
inspired me to grow so like we we
inspired each other like I had you know
seen indoor weed but I had actually at
that point never seen it grown
okay and and I'll never forget you had
that closet that you emptied out it was
like 6 feet by two feet and maybe you
put like four four foot fluoresence in
there I did I had eight of them eight of
them I I didn't even think it was that
many yeah I had four on each end it was
like eight feet eight feet by two foot
you're like you're you're right and then
I used to have them on strings like we
this is you know this is years
ago and uh it it was really primitive
now that I think about it it's kind of
embarrassing I I don't think that's I
don't think that's embarrassing dude I
mean I think that it it just goes to
show like how rudimentary knowledge was
right is before the internet you
couldn't just hop on I mean a lot of
times like in my crew like learning how
to grow weed was like secret knowledge
like you almost had to like become an
indentured servant to someone to teach
you
what was up you know and when I first
started growing I didn't know anything
about
electricity you know I had to like I
plugged in a th000 watt light and the
circuit blew and I had to be like well
why did that happen you know like you
it's like now the stuff that just seems
on like easy and basic and is easily
available to discover and you have all
kinds of people to teach you this is
prior to that where you're just you're
just trying to figure out how to maybe
you could buy a book or two books but I
did buy a book actually you know I think
it was around
Halloween all my Staten Island Buddies
besides Gabby at the time we went into
the village for the parade and we were
like hey I want to go over to Union
Square first and get a book I told them
what it was about they laughed at me how
to grow marijuana was that Sam by any
chance that laugh at you y Sam Kevin
Johnny Wheels Jerry Johnny
Wheels okay all these guys laughed at me
soon as that first crop came in they
were all knocking on the door where do
we get this stuff how do we do it and I
was like at that point I was like just
like not so dog said not so
fast I have
to I'm the one that you guys laughed at
you
know but then you know what matters is
who laughs last we're all laughing still
yeah so what I wanted to what I wanted
to say is um when I met Nick and Cosmic
it was in this group group on Reddit
craft uh craft
marijuana and the group is basically all
about you know showing photos of what
they consider craft flower and sometimes
in the group you know if it's a homeg
grower and the stuff doesn't look
perfect they'll say oh you know we we
can't include that cuz it's not craft
and if it's um a much bigger Garden you
know like hundreds of lights or
something they're like oh that's too big
it can't be craft and I made the
argument that what makes cannabis craft
is how it's grown if it's grown with
love and the intention to grow the
highest quality product um then I
consider that craft
I use you and your first Garden as an
example because I remember that weed and
and so first of all if you remember weed
30 years later that [ __ ] must have been
good right
and we could it
up like the one in the little closet or
Clos no the first stuff you grew in the
kitchen no the
closet okay with under those fluorescent
lights
yeah okay because you could hold those
buds up to the light and see straight
through
them okay but when you smoked
it that [ __ ] tasted really good and got
us super baked and you grew that with
love and the intention of producing the
best flower that you could and so I I
think that's the greatest example of
craft cannabis cannabis that's grown
with love and and you did that and the
proof is that you inspired me Sam Johnny
wheels and all those guys they wanted to
grow too because of what you did like
you inspired a tremendous amount of
people and so you know not to kiss ass
too much but thank you partner I really
appreciate that you know what I remember
out of that first round the most that I
learned about bugs instantly had a crash
course because I took soil from straight
outside
no had no clue cuz you couldn't like you
could go to the store and buy it but I
didn't have we didn't know about Ross
yet we didn't even know about him yet
exactly we knew about
Kmart okay they sold soil could have
gone there but I didn't want anybody
know that I'm buying soil and you didn't
even know that you that it wasn't a good
idea to dig up the soil from outside we
just we didn't thing I know
is battling spidermites
from like day not like one month in I'm
battling spidermites and I'm like and I
I fought them off but it all right so we
got that round in I think there was
maybe one round in that room that's it
and then it was moved to the kitchen and
that's that's where the RFK seeds went
in the tell us about the RFK so June
Gabby and I and RFK with with the Future
orany Crew That's
there and we're searching a lot for bud
this is
my perspective of this the of the show
that day okay hot really hot nobody can
find any bud who comes back with Bud
Gabby Gabby's got a quarter
ounce of looks like Greenhouse F like
kind of moist still kind of rolled up
looked like a cigar almost but in that
shape you know but like just all right
so in that bag there were I think maybe
five seeds something or right or maybe
there was seven seeds you got some I got
some I don't remember I didn't get none
you didn't give me any of those I got
all I know we fought over him I was like
I'm taking them
so I remember I had these three distinct
different
skunks that came out of the bag the one
two and three first one we say the RFK
one was very much like a hash
plant the number two was kind of sweet
smelling really nice buds but it it had
a it was skunk plants and then the third
one was fruity I don't know we lost that
one right away but the other two
survived for a few years they were they
were nice plants that we had for
starting you know like an indoor stuff
again I can still taste that weed today
you know I have a hard time remembering
like conversations and certain events
but I can I remember what that [ __ ]
tasted like and it was amazing and the
reason why I just wanted to mention it
quickly is you grew that [ __ ] for years
you know and maybe like five years I
grew
it yeah so until I got
seeds from
Amsterdam and and once I came back I
ditched it I mean may may you go ahead
dude you speak I I just have a question
I want to know how you kept plants
around for five years back then I'm I'm
just curious what your process was
learned to clone just like everybody
else I learned to cut clones I was
reading books you know what I'm saying
taking every bit of knowledge that I
could get out of a
book and then uh I was hoping to get
into uh the horiculture system at the
Bronx Community College and I got in but
I didn't stay in that I because it was
really hard to commute like two hours
from the other side of the city so I cut
that out but so like I just learned and
and read everything I could on my
own do you mind like do you remember
like what process you used for cloning
uh when you were first doing it like
were you using any sort of like hormones
for the roots or were you were you you
like had you like discovered
like Oasis right Roth was already in our
life at this time I wanted to bring that
up I wanted to get into Ross but I'll
quickly answer the question is we used
Oasis cubes and dip and grow okay exact
right same same thing as
now some technology advances some
doesn't too much you know you know I was
not around then so it's it's just I'm
just curious It's very fascinating to me
I mean one thing one thing that people
should know I think is like these
stories are I mean at least for me and I
I'm pretty sure it's the same for these
guys too is when we started smoking like
the two kinds of easily available weed
were Brown Mexican and green Mexican and
there could be various levels of
compression or various levels of quality
or seed but that was kind of it so
stumbling upon better weed or stumbling
upon bag seed right like I
think back then the only two places I
knew how to get good weed were literally
Grateful Dead shows and if you wanted to
go to
Amsterdam and most of my friends went to
Amsterdam first because it was the
literally the only source of seed that
anyone had any idea how to get that
wasn't Mexican because in the 90s right
then it was sort of like I don't know
about New York I I know Gabby had some
like you know Jamaican experience but
like in Chicago it was like there wasn't
any Thai or Colombian or panaman like
all that stuff was from a different era
there was Mexican and so kind bud was
basically anything of any quality that
was better than the
Mexican I mean that was pretty like it
was a there was a huge
range of you know so yeah you would go
like what he just said you would go
before shows and you would scour the lot
the parking lot trying to find somebody
selling better weed than you had so
that's thear of the century right there
kind bud was anything that wasn't
Mexican yeah 100% that sh It quotes
right there anything that wasn't Mexican
I'm like even like Gabby said like it's
homegrown kind bud was like like grown
in in the states I want 55 for this a
and you hold it up and you can see
through it like Gabby said and you would
still take it because it was beg
for exactly you had to pay to pay out
the nose for it yeah and like and this
this is this is obviously five or six
years before the start of the internet
or overgrow or any of like the ways that
people could get online and learn there
was maybe two or three or four books and
High Times that was pretty much the
start and if you were blessed enough to
have one friend that was doing it and
you could like watch what they were
doing and see and get some tips however
horrific those tips might be it was sort
of like a entry way to get in because
the knowledge level was so
rudimentary you know yeah it really was
it took a while press to find any swag
anywhere remember that was I was I wish
I had all those seeds from my childhood
oh my God that I used to throw out the
window because used to I used to have to
like my oldest daughter um I had to like
go on the internet did you get muted
Francis I can't hear you can you hear me
I can hear you I hear you I hear you I
hear everybody I don't hear anything oh
everybody can hear me but
you so check out the show
later sounds like you guys hear
everything but I don't yeah I uh um we
used I used to I had to Google what
brick looked like right so I brick weed
so I could show like I have an adopted
daughter who's 26 and she grew up in
mesino County so she just never seen
it and I had to show her like because
when I was trying to explain to her that
like when you got a sack you had to
break it up and you had to take out all
the stem and all the seed and all the
funky bits so you could get a pile that
you could roll into a joint she was like
looking at me all
weird yeah because she grew up in the
era of like seedless and like everybody
knew what they were doing you know and
that's the point I wanted to make is
that like in the very in the very
beginning nobody knew what they were
doing even the most rudimentary
knowledge made you seem like a
wizard right and you just had to like I
mean I would get like Jorge cervantes's
like indoor marijuana gardening or Mel
Frank's book and I would just
read um this you know like I learned
everything I know about electricity just
from trying to like figure out how can I
plug in this dehumidifier and this
light and not have my circuit pop so
that I just went like like stuff that
seems basic now it was not basic then in
my opinion everybody had to like start
on this thing and then figure it out and
then figure out a few more things and
then figure out a few more things you
know and so yeah B like he was just
saying I'll shut up after this but bag
seed found in a sack of weed on the
Grateful Dead lot that came out of kind
bud
super valuable yeah not Mexican better
weed those seeds that um that we got
from
RFK led to getting the chem dog from
Greg event really lucky to get at the
time I mean I don't remember the story
like that but that that's again okay we
should maybe just fast forward really
far since you're talking about this and
then go back cuz I know Noto dog is only
able to stay for a little while and he's
going to want to be part of this
conversation but the way I remember the
story is I gave him the the skunk that I
acquired by trading the Francine I never
gave him the RFK as a matter of fact I
never even had the RFK I know but I I
traded him oh so that's how you got
it I gave it to you we went to the F
show yeah fish yeah fish it was fish at
the rosand ballroom right okay after
that I went up to see him in the
Hampton okay and I traded him for a cut
with I went up with there with Sam and I
we drove
up I gave him an RFK cut and the skunk
cut or another cut and I got the chem I
gave him two cuts and I got the chem I
got I'm glad we're talking because the
way I remember the story and honestly
you you're probably right okay I'm
always the first to admit that I'm wrong
is that I traded him and then I thought
I gave you the chem dog but you probably
had it already you know because I had I
was already in in
California gave me the super skunk see I
think I gave you the if that's the case
that I gave you the skunk and the chem
dog because here here here's the quick
end of the story there was a guy from
Virginia that I met at the Warfield and
I smoked the France scene with him and
he wanted the
Francine okay so I drove the Francine
across country and I traded him for a
few clones including the VA
skunk okay it wasn't the super skunk it
was the skunk from Virginia and that was
the plant that I ended up trading with
um k dog for the chem dog I traded him
and you know hope maybe we can get him
on the show too I I think his memory is
probably as bad as all of ours will have
a different story yeah so and I thought
you know I gave you the chem dog but
maybe I did or I didn't I don't know
like you could have traded him the RFK
for yeah exactly I you might have
actually gotten it before me because you
lived out there and you know like I'm
thinking about it what happened was you
were responsible for me making the deal
with him for the chem dog CU like I was
out east for that brief period of time
we went to that fish show but like you
you became friends with him more than I
did and and but I okay but I I think at
the time was like I didn't have a cut
available I had it but it was flowering
and I was waiting I don't know if I was
waiting for them to root or you didn't
want them that they weren't rooted
or something because I remember you
asking me about it and I said I hope
he's not mad at me I'm like about the
RFK
noem because I didn't have one rooted
yeah and I oh yeah I remember yeah you
can ask Greg if if he's got one you know
because or I don't remember exactly I
think that's I think that's the way it
went down because I remember asking so
you did have it that's the deal you had
it you had it before I did and I asked
you for it and you weren't able to give
me a cut but you encouraged me to make
the trade with Greg and and then that's
what I did because so I see I've been
taking the credit for giving you the
chem dog for Years bro yeah I mean the
the funny part about weed history like
this really is that most of it starts
with just small groups of friends doing
things that nobody has any idea will be
important or anyone will care about
later exactly and then a long time later
people start asking for very specific
details and people's memories are
different you know it's nice to
reminisce you know
yeah I mean I you know this is this is
like way fast forwarding but like when I
met
Gabby he gave me uh the he gave me a
skunk and um and the dog and the chem
dog and uh I thought for years and years
and
years because that's how we talked about
it that it was that it was the skunk
from
Virginia and then like a year or two ago
uh I I almost said his name but skunk VA
was like no I think that was a different
Super Skunk maybe he would have given
him because I think we lost it right
before Gabby met me and so you can hear
stuff and you can have like you can have
stuff that just seems normal because
your buddy told it to you yeah right
yeah so there was the skunk from
Virginia okay which got lost before I
met you and then I had gotten seeds from
Sensei so those were the the super skunk
and I I want to throw something else out
there uh for Klo too is that so there's
this we can we we'll fast forward or
whatnot but there everyone wants to talk
about the sour but the sour I mean
essentially the sour story right is that
there was these there was these
gentlemen that were that were getting
sacks off of weasel right over the
course of probably like an entire year
and they would they would anytime they
found seeds right they would they would
hoard the seeds and it seemed pretty
clear for a long time that weasel you
were growing the chem dog and the Vos
skunk and then all of a sudden it comes
up that like you're like no I was
actually growing the RFK 1 and the RFK 2
and I might have had this other super
skunk and I had the Vos Gunk and I had
the chem dog and if do you I mean do you
even remember what were you growing in
1994 I had probably 10 different strains
going yeah see easily more let me I mean
h let me see I so all those ones that I
mentioned you had right you had couple
yeah he had all of those big I had NL
and no wait what year you talking which
year
94 yeah okay so I'm already back
right back from I'm already back from
amdam okay and I've got big butt Oasis
nl5 Nigerian [ __ ] n and the NL I've
got the super skunk yeah the super
skunk okay the rfks are now they're be
they're deleted okay as soon as I came
back from Amsterdam those are gone but
before that I was growing RFK 1 and two
and with the chem cuz I got the chem
from great and I had the sister the
sister plant the sister plant whatever
he had and I I didn't have that for long
I let that go now
also at this time I had a
room
with right after coming back from
Amsterdam after the first round so now I
make my seeds and stuff now I got a room
of a 100 going of the 10 times the
Northern Lights because what I don't
know if this is true or not but what the
story that I was told uh I mean I think
I can say their like by by vondo and
swell is that they were getting sacks of
weed off you all 199 all
1994 and then anytime they got a sack
off you that they found a seed they
would just put it in like a little B
like everybody did in the 90s or
whatever they would just had their
little stack of like seeds I found in
hes or whatever right or good nuggets in
a film canister whatever yeah little box
little this top of the sock drawer
everybody did it you know it was like
the most standard thing and nobody
labeled them carefully it was just like
good weed for later right and they said
they gathered like 12 or 18
seeds just over the course of a whole
year of buying butt off
you they did yeah so it wasn't they got
more than that okay and fact Mike and I
had a conversation not but a text back
and forth about like he reminded me and
this is how we were talking like hey you
see one side of the story and I see
another side and he had to point out to
me and I had to sit there and think
about it for like two [ __ ] days and
I'm like you know what he's right that's
exactly why we're talking that I have
that moment
nonstop I was like because it was wasn't
important to me that I gave him the bag
of seeds but it was so important to him
so it would it left an impression on
them I was just like I got [ __ ] 100
seeds already and these seeds I don't
want to grow because they have
Tendencies to be Mite we all struggling
at this point of like uh these rfks are
causing problems you know like they her
me get [ __ ] seeds you don't want to
[ __ ] up the thing is I don't want to
[ __ ] up the genetic pool you know I'm
reading in the books how bad it is you
know so I was trying to like no I don't
want that for a breeding program you
know because that [ __ ] was on my mind
about breeding already so uh NATO dog
that's the way Bondo tells the story I
recently listened to a podcast from AJ
and he tells he tells the story a little
bit differently and he gives um weasel
here more credit and I believe that this
story is more accurate but you know then
we'll see what what uh Mike says what he
says is that he was buying the uh the
sour diesel from
Mike okay or whatever the you know I
think maybe AJ actually named it that I
don't know what Mike was actually
selling him at the time but AJ was
saying that um Mike was selling him the
sour diesel and that um down the line
they found those seeds and that they
planted those seeds because Mike
wouldn't come off of a
cut you know so I mean that both all
those things could be true I mean really
but the point my point is is that the
original Sour
Diesel was from Mike and vondo takes
credit for it because you know he found
the seeds it's like I mean the story
that I was told and everybody and you
know and obviously we got Klo on so he
can he can differentiate is that these
guys were buying seeds or buying buying
sacks of weed and they would get sacks
of weed they were getting sacks of weed
and that they would pick out they would
find some seeds in it because whatever
he was whatever Klo was growing had
would throw beans on every now and again
and then they had this sack of beans
that they had collected over the whole
course of the year they planted
them and I guess they kept a couple that
they called diesel one and Diesel 2 and
I guess they called it diesel because
that was like the slang for really good
weed in that area yeah right and so then
apparently they took a sack of diesel 2
and they gave it to this dude called
Manny right and to differentiate it from
other people's diesel cuz diesel wasn't
like a strain diesel at the time was
just a name for fire Weed really they
wrote Our Diesel and Manny thought that
our had an s in front front of it and
apparently that's where the sour came
from so it's kind of like what they told
me was the sour came was bag seed from
weed that was bag seed from you
basically sorry guys still there yeah um
you know like there was a lot you know
for at this time there was a lot of sour
being sold to these guys much as I could
get rid of you know they want pounds and
some had occasional seed but I don't
think it was that was the they they
weren't buying the sour they were
buying the number two in RFK is what
they were buying they didn't say they
were buying this I think here's the
thing now so now I
had the super skunk too and they were
buying
that
okay and I crossed the Northern Lights
into the Super Skunk and I
had some weed half a pound that I didn't
want because it had a whole bunch of
seeds in I didn't [ __ ] realize so at
the time you know what I'm saying like
[ __ ] what am I going to do with a
half a pound of [ __ ] of [ __ ] whole
bunch of seeds I took out what I want
jar like this right I [ __ ] sold those
guys back a qu pound of weed or half
pound of weed only people that I could
think got that bag of seeds and they got
so many somebody got so many seeds I
don't know if it was JJ actually tell
the truth or [ __ ]
vond JJ or AJ the sour seeds got out
right
there JJ or AJ oh
JJ he really didn't buy too much he
bought weed for me but he didn't he
didn't get too much we would meet at the
wetlands but I more dealt with JJ
because it was just easier so I think
that I think I mean I think it's obvious
when you look at sour that it has skunk
Heritage in it right absolutely but it
turns out that uh you know you had
Neville super skunk and you had the
Virginia skunk and you had RFK one and
two and may like you had you had a lot
more of like you had a plethora of
skunk okay at different times but you
have to also realize when as soon as I
was growing seeds from Amsterdam there
was no RFK one and two in the room
because I didn't want any it wasn't
worthy what's that it wasn't
worthy
yeah like I don't want this anymore I
mean there's there's a bunch of families
of weed that exist only because they had
a tendency to Herm and throw accidental
bag seed yeah I mean accidental bag seed
is like you know like as much history as
I've done you trace it back and you
trace it back and then it turns out that
it's some accidental bag
seed there's a lot for all the intention
we put into breeding at times accidental
bag seed in the 90s is how like 70% of
cannabis stories begin in my opinion you
know it's it's a big component and we
used to think they're so bad and now I
think of them as like the biggest gem
ever because they gave us all this stuff
on accident that we didn't realize you
can make them you know if you want to do
that you know
not a problem stress out your plants
yeah I guess depends on what's throwing
the pollen you know if it's an actual
Herm or if it's you know nanners from
stress or something yeah because as as
far as I know um you know when you
create your own femin seeds and you're
searching out the plants you know
whether it's chemically or what you know
it's very similar to you know a plant
getting stress out and throwing nanners
I mean one thing that should be
mentioned is that I think that like
Herms and I I'm maybe like on a on a
tiny percentage on this level but I
think
Herms like we hate we a lot of people
despise them because they want to grow
seedless but that was like a very
effective like like breeding method for
cannabis
forever right like if a male died if
something happened a lot of genetics
harmed because it was another way for
the for like to make seed and we only
decided like sometime in the 80s or
whatever that we wanted
seedless so all of a sudden we started
trying to breed out this trait that had
been in cannabis for God knows how long
could be thousands of years and when
everyone grew seated right or you're
importing seeded weed Herms didn't
matter because seeds were
normal it was only when we started
growing seedless for ourselves that we
decided that this is a pain in the
ass can we grow can we breed away from I
always would think that the farmer
yanked the male plant out and when he
collectively bread I mean I actually
think like for a long time too like the
story of American weed right is that all
this seated sativa work came in as Bud
whether it was Panamanian or Colombian
or Mexican or Thai and that like the
Afghan stuff came in as hash if you even
saw it so in the beginning it was all
sativa stuff because that was the only
stuff that you had buds that you were
going to pull seeds out of yeah
you
know cuz the rest was turned into hash
yeah and just didn't and just wasn't
shipped over you know like what like in
import import weed had free seeds that
came along with it I never got any
seedless weed from import like sometimes
I'd get Mexican that was green and only
lightly pressed and it would have few
seeds but it still had them yeah you
know
as far as as far as they were concerned
they were still getting the money for
the weight yeah I just you I mean most
matter that seeds in it I mean most of
my high it's like you know Green wheat
green Mexican was the nice stuff like
super compressed Brown Mexican was the
norm at least for us so that was like I
don't even know if I would have been
able to get good weed regularly would I
have even started growing I think most
of my friends and this is probably true
for Gabby and klopp or whatever you
started growing weed because you wanted
access to better weed than you could
find you're right because like
occasionally I would come across some
like Florida Citrus you know it was
nice but I couldn't find it all yeah so
and I was and when I did pay it I had to
pay you know back then like $40 for a
quarter like what you're like what now
you pay $40 for a
qu hey not dog I I know you have to
leave soon and I want to uh get one
topic out before you do so it's it might
sound like it's a little off subject but
you gave me the nickname Staten Island
yeah I I'm I I got to let you know I
don't know if you've heard I'm not very
happy about
that well I mean Staten Island's a
[ __ ] [ __ ] hole yeah it really is you
it's your [ __ ] hole uh and for I was
born in Brooklyn
and I spent my last year hold on wait
the first time I ever grew weed was in
Brooklyn okay okay let just let's just
rewind a second when you're telling can
of stories because I do a lot right it
becomes difficult to tell the whole
truth and nothing but the truth right
because not that you want to lie but
you're talking essentially about illegal
[ __ ] you you might
not how do I put this the right way a
lot of people do not want to be public
figures right you don't they don't want
their name out there right you don't
want to out your friend if they want to
have privacy they might have moved on
they might have a different job I don't
blame you for giving me a nickname but
Staten
Island you know I is it like the first
thing that came to your head at the
moment when you were talking I actually
if you really want to blame oh almost
said his name if you really want to
blame it who I got it from was when
skunk VA was talking to the podcast
about his story and he kept saying my
buddy from Staten Island oh really all
right I'm going to blame him and then I
mean we can mutually him and I can
mutually share blame for
popularizing you know uh and all that
but it's kind of like yeah it's uh it
you know I you're just trying to talk
about people and a lot of times like you
know you stop because you're so used to
saying someone's name and you want to
protect someone's privacy maybe they
don't want their real name out there or
whatever you know so they um you know
they uh uh so
yeah my point in bringing this up my
point in bringing this up is the weasel
first of all we'll have to talk about
how he got that nickname because that
that might I that's pretty shitty too
but he's the real Staten
Island he was first on S Island he lived
there before I lived there he lived
there after I lived there he was the he
was the man on Staten Island like let me
ask these other two guys a question hold
on let me ask these other two dudes a
question Cosmic and do you guys know
what AJ's real nickname was no I don't
[ __ ] Joe [ __ ] Joe that's AJ
[ __ ] Joe Joe you know the thing about
the thing about nicknames is that most
of the time you don't pick them yourself
they are put on You by people in your
circle or your friend group that's what
I'm talking about bro you put this
nickname on me I thought we were good
now you're calling me like Staten Island
at the time at Le you're not [ __ ] Joe
at least you're not [ __ ] Joe I mean
Lu AEL a common enough nickname that
people probably don't think it means
[ __ ] Joe but it does it means [ __ ]
Joe right so in my defense Gabby right
when I was starting to talk about you
you had been retired from growing for
some time you were a legitimate business
store business store owner you know what
I'm saying and like this stuff was long
in your past and I didn't call you up
and be like do you mind if I out you on
the internet for doing a whole bunch of
like shady ass illegal [ __ ] a long time
ago right and so I just avoided all that
by like talking about you with a name
that wasn't traced back to you and now
that you've decided to say your name and
show your face you're stuck with it but
um you know that's kind of that's kind
of how it went I'm sure for dude I keep
wanting to say his real name I'm sure
skunk VA thought the same thing when he
was trying to figure out how to talk
about you five six years ago on the
podcast right without just saying you
know oh you know and that you know I I
don't mind I don't I don't mind that I
got a nickname I just mind the nickname
like what it actually is and the fact
that like now I feel pretty stuck with
it
you know like those
are so tell us about yours I why do
people call you weasel [ __ ] Joe
[ __ ] gave
it see it's all shared pain this is all
is it's all Shar the reason he gave it
to me was because I was like a hoorde
with all the [ __ ] sour bro it's so
funny like he he like brags on the on
his podcast that like he sold the [ __ ]
for like a million dollars a pound you
know that he used to get like $1,200 a
pound or not $1,200 $112,000 a pound
what something just ridiculous off the
chain you know and he calls you a
weasel yeah well that's actually you
know he's he's on my way from where I I
live in another state to come to this
house and I I told him last week I was
coming by
he didn't pick up this
morning I didn't get to see him I was
going to make a
stop I mean yeah he used to sell um you
know he used to sell tops for $1,000 an
ounce and bottoms for 500 an ounce yeah
and the weasel here wasn't getting paid
a fraction of that no right no I was no
how much do you think you were getting
for it back then oh what an ounce
whatever
or both for an ounce straight up I was
getting 400 fo the all the way up if I
had 10 pounds of it I was getting 400 an
ounce all the way
up I was that's why like I didn't cut
they but then they would turn around
double it or whatever Joe says he's I'm
selling it for 800 I'm like whatever I
don't have to deal with it
okay that people might should know is
that like back then weed like this was
gold because it was so it was so rare it
was so hard to find it was like I mean
growing up in in Chicago and stuff like
uh he's uh he's pass now but like one of
Gabby and I's mutual friends that I grew
up with um he used Sean he used to like
you could go up to a spot and you could
offer a d man a hundred bucks and he'd
be like [ __ ] off and then you could pull
out a small nug of really nice indoor
and handed to him and he'd be like oh
man you're getting in right because it
was like currency it was rare it wasn't
easy to get it wasn't you it wasn't easy
to even if you knew someone right like
uh I'll tell a story from my past this
is how valuable stuff was right I might
have only been three or four people away
from a grower okay and I knew who they
were but that grower would sell their
herb to a friend and that friend would
go through and like pick out nug by ug
the nicest half pound that they wanted
out of that herb and then they'd sell it
to you're not going to out him here you
did before
huh you've already outed him on your
podcast oh man and then and then they
would pick out they would pick out and
they the next person to get it would
pick it out would pick out all the
nicest pieces they wanted for theirs so
when I would get it it would be like you
know a $50 bag of
Smalls but it was still better than
Mexicans so like every every nug was
gold didn't matter the size it didn't
matter where it was from the fact that
you could get it like that you had
access before it ran out was just part
of it you know now it's like we're
drowning and it's like a sea of boof
everywhere we're just drowning in like
enormous waves of weed but like back
then it was like it was currency it was
hard to get you said it was like gold
but gold wasn't worth 400 bucks an ounce
back then no it you know like we were
like it way more than if you had the
money you could get
gold where if if you had the money it
was not guaranteed you could get kind
butt I mean part of the reason why like
that story in the beginning of like
Gabby and weasel walking around the lot
looking for her before the show was
because Dead shows used to be one of the
most reliable places you could stumble
upon someone selling a sack I got them
excited now coming from all across the
country Gathering somebody across the
country was growing weed some from
somewhere most people on dead tour were
pretty poor and they needed a they
needed a way to get from show to
show um you know and they needed to make
money somehow and so one of the
traditional ways people would do it is
like they're like oh if I bring x amount
of herb with me I can sell eigh and
quarters and half ounces and fund my
whole
run absolutely and so there was people
that were going to do that and you're
walking around the lot trying to find
someone that was like
that and then once people figured out
who they were that person could sell as
much as they wanted that day because it
was so rare Mike I have a question for
you how much do you think it uh affected
your decision in letting us stay at your
house that couple of days that we had
good
weed we had no money but we had we had
good weed right it was like changing you
know you know like it put me back on
the on on the on the deadlock I me just
just to tie it in right chem dog okay he
the whole chem story starts with him
buying a sack of weed at a dead lot in
Indiana in
91 and that same summer Gabby Colorado
oh no it was IND theana was it was at
Deer Creek and Gabby and that same 91
tour that same summer Gabby and weasel
walking around you know the RFK which is
obviously in you know on the East Coast
or whatnot you know uh RFK Stadium
looking for weed um and they found a
sack of weed that bag seed came out of
and that was like on the same summer
tour so that was like that was the
standard was people from all over
America would go go on dead tour and you
could bump into Florida people Colorado
people California people Montana people
New York people and it was sort of like
a
cross-section and it was also anonymous
because you didn't know if you were
going to see that person ever again you
know um but in all in all honesty I mean
like just just real quick weasel like if
you could have bought seeds in
America would you would have flown to
Amsterdam like I literally left the
country to go to Holland you know so I
could find seeds I might have gone
anyway because like for the culture I
like to travel a lot and I've been to a
lot of
places so yeah at that time I already
been to Europe in my life a couple times
so but you wouldn't have brought seed
backs you wouldn't you wouldn't have
taped the seeds to your package no okay
you told that story on on another
podcast you taped the SC to your podcast
package yeah I mean package that's the
thing is that that was where you know I
mean when when Gabby and I first became
friends it's like we used to pour over
those old
cataloges of Neville seed bank and we
look at them too I would with him I
would look at them we'd look like look
at that look at that you me you'd
memorize garli yeah you'd have different
favorites you'd have different dreams
about going over there and which ones
you'd grab when you were there because
there was just no access so you were
just trying to you're just trying to
figure out a way that you could get some
and I only knew how to get it in Holland
and Dead
shows that was pretty much it Dead shows
were like the Open Air
Market but see
Holland like we like be before Holland
though like say like like seven or eight
years prior to that though I think it
was actually 88 or
89 uh there was Operation green Merchant
yep and there was a bunch of Growers out
in California in fact all the top
Growers were out in California growing
these skunks and stuff and when that
went
down uh they all went over to Amsterdam
and setup business so there were strains
here in this country that were being
nicely picked over you know they weren't
being distributed it wasn't as like not
just anybody could go and get them like
I said before the internet it was
literally like the best way to find
better weed I would say probably the
best way in America to find better weed
at that point was to go to a Grateful
Dead show and wander around and make
friends and hope somebody you backed
into Gabby just left but like when I
first met him I'll tell him I'll tell a
story real quick before I got to go
there was this weed uh that he called
the Big Sir holy weed and there was
these guys on dead tour that sold Big
Sir holy skunk and Big Sir holy Haze
right and Gabby said the smell was so
distinctive that like if you walked by
someone in the lot that had Big Sir holy
in their fanny pack not only could you
tell that they had good weed but you
were pretty sure it was the big Are Holy
because of how it smelled and there was
a and Gabby would always say they were
connected they know they know somebody
from the dead
family but yeah that was kind of like
that that was I used to get that weed
from him and it was in little plastic
not plastic wax paper bags you remember
that yeah they gave them to me in wax
paper bags like like sandwich bags for
lunches yeah yeah that's what it was
yeah sandwich bag that's why it smelled
so bad
it that's why everyone knew you had it
because you were [ __ ]
wreaking they gave you these stupid
sandwich bags yeah I apologize I I got
to take my daughter to she's she has a l
start today I got to take but it was it
was it's good to see your guys's faces
you know nice to see you too very much
so and uh I will we'll do we'll do it
again soon I
promise all right okay first of all
let's start off is isn't that that guy
NATO dog an [ __ ] I'm only kidding I'm
only kidding he's my bro
um he's good he's good so one thing I
wanted to talk to you about we had
skipped over it because I knew that NATO
dog was going to want to talk to you
about the
hour was when we used to go to Ross's
East Coast
Hydroponics and the first thing I want
to say is I'm trying to get um Ross to
do the podcast
and he tells me that nobody wants to
hear his
story and that he doesn't like the way
he sounds when he
talks I can agree with one of those
things you
know I'm only kidding people want to
hear his story you know
is I'm here I'm not far from him if he
don't his house I can Ambush him would
be funny yeah Ambush him and and we'll
get him to talk come here while I'm here
this week hey come hang out and if I get
him here oh
[ __ ] put a secret camera up and just
live stream him without his
permission it's just he doesn't he you
know he was such a huge influence to so
many
people remember what naso dog said
a lot of people don't want the publicity
they don't want hammer on them and he's
always been that way if you can remember
how freaky it was like yeah
going are the cops are the cops you know
and that was because of you know maybe
green operation green Merchant yeah you
know like they came to his store you
know they I don't nothing happened but
you know like some of his friends in
operation business there they they got
arrested at that time for thr
equipment I think that's why I want him
to tell his story is
because he had that history of going
through operation green Merchant and he
survived you know he continued you know
for many years
afterwards and he sold
me
um he sold me what's up buddy he sold me
my first light
that that like you know like when when I
tell so one of the things Mike I want to
tell you the purpose of me doing this
podcast is that I want to document my
story more for me than for anybody else
because I'm forgetting it and you see
like when we talk we remind each other
of stuff and you know the stuff happen
so long ago so I want to record this
yeah I think I do
I mean I mean I don't know if you call
it Kidd like you know we all forget but
listen my memory is not what it used to
be for sure nobody's is you nobody's is
but it's nice that you you want
everybody to know and then you ask
people about it to help
everybody like it it it jogs my memory
when you ask me questions because I
wouldn't think about it all the time
either like and be like yeah that's 30
years ago and I'm like and you have to
sit and you think about it but if you
think about this stuff it'll come back
this like what like that's why I'm doing
this Mike said about the bag seat
because it took me a while like we did
we came out of Ross's store and I handed
him those seats and it took and I can
remember now you know just think about
it yeah I mean
so what I was saying is is part of my
story you know East Coast Hydroponics
that's part of my story and he's our
friend you know by the way he doesn't
have to be on screen he can just do
audio you know like and you know as far
as I'm concerned he's a pretty famous
dude you know like he might want to like
you know try to be private but it's
already too late for that too many
people already know him you know and
people know yeah and you
know at the time you think oh my God
this guy's such a pain in the ass like
you know he would leave a sign on his
door saying be back in 15 minutes and
you'd come back in an hour and he still
wasn't there and you know going to the
grow store back then on Staten Island
was shady as [ __ ] right so like we
didn't want to have to like go there you
know nine times you know to get our [ __ ]
and meanwhile he was hanging out in the
back with somebody else smoking weed the
entire time while he has his sign saying
back in 15
minutes but like now I mean I honestly
love the guy you back then it was like
[ __ ] this guy and remember he didn't
even go by his real name he went by
Bill you know like he was so paranoid
that anybody would know his name was
Ross that he would call himself
bill or is Bill his [ __ ] name do I
have it backwards I don't even know it
took me years I'm I'm I probably would
say 10 years before I knew his first
name and the reason is because he used
my my kids grandparents the father was a
lawyer and he used him as a lawyer and
so I was referring to him in a
conversation and
and my kid's grandfather corrected me on
his name I was like who so are you
saying that I don't know what his real
name is or is there no comment right you
do but yeah you know I I think he's uh
he's an interesting part of both of our
stories right yeah you know so he's very
interesting character I mean I remember
getting like Oasis over there and we
would buy all the down toe guos and [ __ ]
from
him you know
so at that time when he had that small
shop we were into the guos like
everything we were doing was it was back
guano D bird
guano and the Maxi
crop powder and
promix was that was state of the
art so getting those bals of promix
getting those bals of promix was shady
as
[ __ ] you know and and that's why it was
like and he's not here you know like we
borrow a friend's car you know to go
over there and have this window in our
day to get and we're all like got our
heart racing that we're going to the
hydro store to go buy dirt and then the
guy wouldn't be there everybody sees you
bring it into your house like oh yeah
what are you doing with that how do you
how do you hide that we should we didn't
you know yeah it's like this giant bell
four it's you know like a 4 cubic foot
Bell 3.3 cubic feet you know those bells
were giant yeah you know you got to like
have a little vegetable garden or
something out front where you're just
like oh no this is for my
vegetables at at Mike's first place
there was no grass there was no Earth I
don't he must have like he must have
like gone like to a neighboring Woods to
go get the soil that he grew in you know
because it was
C it did
actually Pond remember the
pond went over to Jack's Pond and got it
and uh brought it back along with uh
spiderm for your first crowd everything
every other bug too probably it was I
think they were
wor hey like I said I still remember
that weed as being the best you know
like no no one on Staten Island at that
point had better
weed right you
know I think I didn't it was different
like I like it was definitely different
it was I would think like the seeds were
probably
highgrade commercial
Mexican that's what I think it was but
it was kept short and flowered really
you know quick and then but when we got
the RFK se's that was the best weed on
the island by far at the time like I
couldn't find anything better I was
happy well um yeah the RFK weed that was
super nice I remember that weed still
too and it sounds like like you were uh
you're proud of it you you bring it up a
lot I mean you know it's like the start
like an indoor like doing really indoor
and it you know like changed my life
like completely like I realized not only
you you can make a living at this this
was when I was like wow like that was
the first time you realized that that it
was more than just personal smoke I
don't have to go out there and swing a
hammer anymore if I don't wna I don't
have to go in the cold
freeze when when was the last time you
you grew a a crop this summer I did the
sour and I did the
chem
91 nice I should let you guys ask some
questions since me and NATO dog
dominated the dominated the show one is
that the Chim that you guys remember
from uh like the early
90s that's that's the what I did this
summer the chem 91 is the original chem
dog from the 91 it's the same cut that's
been going down the line they call it
the 91 now to differentiate it from the
chem D and the chem sis and the chem 4
you know so but back then it was just
the chem dog and I actually just called
it the dog because we grew it organic
and I refused to call the chem dog cam
oh because I was growing organic at the
time okay I I
it actually probably indor does better
with Kim with Sals you know what I'm
saying yeah that's I think why he was he
he uh he called it that because he
couldn't do anything with it you know
like he was struggling on him and to get
it to grow correctly he hit it with
Miracle Grow that's what he told me if I
can remember but story I'm sure you know
oh yeah no no no so I I'll tell the
story too since it's a part of both of
our stories when I went and picked up
the cut of the chem dog he was growing
it
hydroponically um in I'll never forget
it was called the Emily's garden and it
was like a 2X two tray that had a wick
that went to the reservoir
below and that was the first time I ever
saw a hydroponic system was with him and
he insisted that um you had to grow the
chem dog with
Hydroponics because it just wouldn't
make it if you didn't it wouldn't
survive it just such a hard plant to
feed and so that was the first time I
ever saw a hydroponic system I refused
to accept it when he said that you can't
grow the chem dog organic and I just
called it the dog and I tried to grow it
organic and I did get
flower that people thought was the best
[ __ ] they had ever seen in their life
but that was because of the
genetic okay that genetic was so awesome
even if you didn't do it right you got
something really good okay now when I
learned about using mineral salts and
became open to it and then grew the chem
dog then it was like oh my God now I
really got to see what the potential of
this plant was what what the genetic
potential of this plant was um it was a
very difficult plant to feed even with
Hydroponics you know it didn't have much
foliage on it or doesn't have much
foliage on it and by by difficult to
feed with Hydroponics with the knowledge
and products that we had at the
time you know so the plant would want to
yellow and lose all of its leaves before
it finished you know and if it didn't
finish it wouldn't have anywhere near
the to Pro Prof to profile it would have
as when it did so when we fed it with
hydroponic nutrients it would stay
Greener longer and the plant could
finish and you know to me it's night and
day like and so now I don't object to
calling it the chem dog anymore because
on top of everything it's it's something
that encouraged me to be open to Growing
With mineral salts where you know there
was a period of time where I was like
nope you know it's got to be organic
so I find the plant uh is very hard to
feed also me got to have the pH just
right but like I do it in soil outside
and if I just go
with straight nitrogen and bat guano and
and you know the mixes that they have
you know in the
bags uh the plant will struggle to get
the proper nutrients out of even out of
the ground even if I've enriched it and
everything but once I add a few salts to
the ground outside I never had a problem
with this plant so you're growing them
actually in the ground in the ground
always I don't put them in containers
anymore it's a seasonal crop my soil is
beautiful you know and I can go away
which is the main key not worried have a
sprinkler come on once in a
while I'm going to Italy I see you in
two
weeks I come back and everything looks
good you got a trim that's it you know
what I'm saying cut things
back really low
maintenance this year is really nice was
really nice I had a nice I have a 30x30
plot and I I pretty good on it sweet
yeah um you know who I've been thinking
about a lot as well and I don't know if
he would do the podcast but uh a good
buddy Keith you know yeah have to ask
him he's uh very mysteriously he's I
don't know how often you talk to him I
don't really talk to him that often like
maybe like not even once a year but just
to tell everybody else about him Keith
was or is a good friend of ours he was
part of the group that was
growing and oh I'm getting some weird
sunlight behind me hope it's not too
difficult but uh
anyway on
you like his dad was a pastor right y or
a priest a and he had some like conflict
within him about
growing okay because you know it wasn't
the holy thing to do right and so
so I'll never forget I want to tell a
story about Keith and if you remember
any stories and I say this with all I
love the guy immensely right but so you
know sometimes I would want to buy weed
from him and he would sell me these bags
they'd be really small like like really
small buds and one day I go yeah he was
growing but you know and I thought
that's just the way it was turning out
just small bugs right
so one day I go to his house and we go
to his basement to
smoke and he breaks out this [ __ ]
Cola it's like this okay I'm like holy
[ __ ] I was like I I couldn't believe
Keith finally [ __ ] pulled off
something just ridiculous
right and he's like yeah what do you
think and I so I smell it I'm like
drooling I don't remember what weed it
was I you know he's got to be on the
show to ask him it was just fu
amazing right but it was really dry it's
like Keith why is this [ __ ] so dry it's
like oh cuz I just you know have it
sitting there so he takes a lighter and
he's like going like this like close to
the butt I'm like dude what are you
doing he's like watch goes like this and
when that flame touches the bud the bud
was so dry it [ __ ] ignites like a
[ __ ] like a candle go goes right
up and he [ __ ] takes the end and he
goes and he blows out the flame so now
it's no longer on fire it's just like
smoking like a cigar and he's going like
this with
it and I'm like dude what the [ __ ] are
you
doing like I mean I I'm
like like we were talking before weed
no you know what he
said he was sacrificing it to the god to
to because his dad taught him that you
should always give a certain amount of
money from what you earn so so he tying
to the church
he so he he
couldn't he couldn't like just take the
weed and give it to the church and if he
gave the money to the church cuz he was
making good money he would be like where
the [ __ ] are you getting thousands of
dollars from it was just totally Shady
so his way of giving it back to the
Earth was to light that weed on fire and
just let it [ __ ]
smoke I was so pissed that's that's
funny you have you have any keyth
stories or stories you want to tell
about anybody else or anything else you
want to talk about Keith Keith I I
remember you know like people want to
know is like like my first round with
Keith was
amazing and last
round
because I went over the house one time
and he yelled at me because I went over
early in the morning and I'm an early
bird he sleeps to 12 but um this is
where
like the first batch of seeds that I
did uh was with Keith when I came back
from Amsterdam we did 100 seeds in a
room and his
apartment it was a pretty interesting uh
Journey with Keith and occasionally I
see you know him and Ross and I we used
to go to a music festival all the time
but that hasn't happened the last two
years yeah the best story is the one
that Gabby told definitely I can't I
feel like we've kind of uh we've kind of
played around with u the story with sour
diesel we we told you know a little bits
and pieces but um I I personally don't
feel like I have a clear view of you
know the actual creation of of the of
the sour diesel is that um it was with
super skunk and with chem dog right yeah
but it the chem dog had already been
bred to the Northern Lights that's where
that round the seeds with teeth I think
you're muted Gabby can you guys hear me
now now I can I was running my water
bottle so people have been saying it's
the chem dog crossed with the um super
skunk that's not true
it okay to a certain extent it is but
this so let's play this out so that's
where so when I I've come back from
Amsterdam and I have the
seeds so you know I'm Growing Seeds and
and I like the Northern Lights through
the structure and everything the size of
the colar you know and uh I like the
taste and
everything so I took a male of that
plant crossed it with the chem this room
that I did with Keith is the 100
seeds Okay so it's the first batch from
that batch I tell Keith oh I like this
seed right here and we put the number
one we put it into the cup we grew it 99
plants okay that's it most of them got
weeded out because they were males we
were looking
uh kept kept the female but out of those
other seeds that I had out of 100 seeds
I grew another
batch and I got a male from that same
bad and I crossed it with the super
skunk so that's chem
lights times or chem times Northern
Lights times stup skunk and that's where
that bag of seeds that eventually got
out that I said earlier oh yeah it was a
whole half pound or qu pound of weed
that got out that had seeds in it we're
talking about seeds so it's it's nl5
chem to or nl5 super skunk to chem is
that is that right or nl5 times chem one
no it's the short NL just
lights Northern number one and thatn
lights that you grew out it wasn't like
um you know from got what I got from
sensey seed in Amsterdam
mhm so it was like your own feno that
you had hunted yourself that you know
you used to breed with right I right but
that Northern Lights was Brad to the
chem and then from the chem took the the
first generation of seeds found the male
crossed it with and it was your friend
that bought the weed um that had the
seed in it that actually grew it
out well I don't you know like I
wouldn't say that like he's got his
seeds I have mine I'm growing the same
seeds Okay this is how I feel like what
happened they got dis I got my own te I
can remember going to the cast Guild and
[ __ ]
Joe moved in to the
house uh across from where vondo had at
the time so they had two houses side by
side and Joe moved in and I gave him a
house Waring plant for his house and
that was my cut
of my sour that I had grown out seeds
and I like this plant right bondle says
or whatever Mike well says they did the
same thing so it's like that's where I
have my story at like I don't really
care like if they say they want to claim
it they can claim it I know the SE no I
I thought AJ actually gave you the
credit um like in this podcast that I
was listening to he said that it was
your weed and and that it was being
called The Sour Diesel and that and that
you wouldn't give up the cut and
eventually they found seeds and planted
those and you know but you know he said
that yours was the original one and then
you know then
afterwards you know they they grew some
seeds and and so right you know I I felt
like he was I felt like he was giving
you the credit so when I went back to
New York with that um
I saw the weasel shortly thereafter uh
in sheep's Meadow in Central Park and I
I showed it to him and he was so
impressed with it that within two days
he caught a flight to
Amsterdam and uh and took his first trip
there and when he came back he had seeds
with him and those would be the seeds
that would eventually potentially
uh father the genetics that that uh bore
the sour all of a sudden it was it was
just diesel but now uh we're getting all
these different things and now
everyone's like dude please just grow
the diesel like [ __ ] all this other
stuff please we just want the diesel you
know if you're a grower like you know
like every time you try to show people
something different there's like one
particular thing they want from you and
it's like you can't you can show them
the most the best thing in the world
they don't care so he did uh uh
eventually start growing diesel again
and uh but this time when it came
out uh there were some seeds and uh by
now these guys who uh who I had first
introduced to the diesel had had poached
out uh the weasel and found him because
it was you know it was a small scene you
know so those guys were from Albany so
those guys got weed with some seeds in
it I got weed I found one seed in it and
uh and and so that's kind of like where
it all began with like I don't listen to
his podast I didn't it was he did for
someone else yeah
um but I I I would have tried to stop by
to see him this morning need didn't
answer it's nice to have him on [ __ ]
[ __ ] yeah I'm gonna see if he wants
to come on too I never really interacted
with him much at the time you know I was
already out here and he was out there
you know I had you know I knew about him
from you so yeah I
like um kind of floating around now uh
Gabby you got you got to cut Sour Diesel
is that yeah so are you doing you doing
tissue culture Gabby so the the Clones
that I have the original Sour Diesel had
come from had been tissue cultured from
someone that I know that had been
growing it for a long time and then I
got the AJ sour was it but was it the
sour like was it the sour like you know
s s yeah I mean to be honest with you I
don't really know what you grew you know
because we're living on different um
different coast different sides of the
yeah exactly and um I'm gonna talk to
you about this after the show it's
interesting with um you know you
obviously we got the the original Sour
Diesel here we got you know something
that came from you know the other seed
and everything like that you know I
wonder which which sour was the one that
you know became super popular with
everyone that everyone had experienced I
mean like we we already know that even
back then there was a few different ones
right it sounds like there were two main
ones that that ended up into like the
hands of people who were calling it Sour
Diesel and it it could have it could
have been either one either from it
could very likely yeah it very likely
was more than two for sure and then how
does East Coast Sour Diesel fit into
this um I don't know too much about the
history on that strain but you know this
what we're talking about it's already
originating on the East Coast
you know so the West Coast I believe is
the
headband but I don't have I don't have
as much you know like Francis or NATO
dog would have been a better person to
talk to about that because he researches
all that stuff and he's probably already
done you know a few talks about it if
you look it back up but um yeah and it's
kind of weird you know it's actually
more proof
that you know it's kind of like Lemon
Cherry gelato today a lot of people just
start to add their [ __ ] to the name you
know um the when they started calling
the headband Sour Diesel it's like just
because that you know that was more
popular than headband you know so but
and you know I I will talk to not so dog
about it the Clone that I have um I
believe to be the original Sour Diesel
and then I have the AJ sour which is
actually something that he you know he
agreed to put his name on you know they
call it the Philly cut you know he's put
his name on a on a bunch of cuts
um so but you know and now he has you
know his whole AJ sour line you know so
now he has his own sour I mean do you
get royalties I wonder is like somebody
put the weasel on that jar should I get
royalties for that unfortunately I don't
think
he this person I swear to God like I
someone does that this's this guy I like
someone doing that he nice nice man and
he's got this sour that he says sour
it's
not the the sour I say it right now it's
not the sour okay but he's selling it as
the sour and grown by the weasel and I'm
like and he comes to me look I says I
did this for you and I'm like I I I
don't know what to say to the guy wait
hold on I did this for you so where's my
money yeah you know I'm like
I no you're using you're using my
reputation to sell your weed and it's
like all lie so I'm going to meet with
him soon again I just don't have time
right this minute I'm G to tell him well
first of all it shouldn't say groan by
the weasel because now he's taking
credit for like I'm not I'm not Happ
product at all I'm like this this can't
this can't be this can't be I don't know
how to break it to him though wow I'm
just too kindhearted in a way cuz you
like the guy until he did this I think
he's doing it he says it goes to a lot
of cancer patients so I don't you know
like
it I think it's going to a good cause if
he's doing that well cancer cancer
patients don't care that you grew it you
know like that's marketing calling it
you know saying groan by the weasel cuz
cancer patients just want medicine that
makes them feel better true right like
it doesn't matter to them if it's sour
easel grown by the weasel I think I
think the same cut of sour uh ever since
you you know originally created it yeah
so uh my buddy
here in the cat skills has it also and
he's from Stan Island crew like it's
kind of funny like the GU from orany
lived here for a while and then we came
here you know into the cat skills and uh
it's it's really nice but like
so this is kind of like Humble County in
a way that's the what we say Green
county is like the humble of the East
County in the East Eastern United States
like this area a lot of fine Bud coming
out of here now it's really nice it
always was like for the New York weed
that's where with all the good [ __ ] was
always coming from so my friend you know
like I just asked him in the spring can
I get a cut and I get it you know I get
the cut I want or or I do see Cosmo
Cosmic you
know what about you so your your friend
currently he's uh kind of like the
caregiver of your strain right now right
so like you don't perpetually have a
mother he's the one who's taking care of
yeah he's got it yeah um what about you
you dra anything I got uh quite a few
things um I have something that's
supposed to be Sour Diesel that I'd
gotten back in 2020 um from this breeder
Collective I'm over here uh in
California um it was this breeder
collective in San berino that just kind
of disappeared um so I can't really
Trace the history back on what it is the
turps are extremely sour um I mean as
far as what I understand what a sour
diesel should be um it seems pretty
close to it but um you know who knows if
it's if it's the real deal you know that
you know um but yeah I mean I have I
have quite the collection I've been
learning a lot about tissue culture
about Mary stem tissue culture so my
focus right now is getting better at
that and you know hopefully creating a
library of strains that I can kind of
play around with whenever I'm ready for
my next uh breeding project and you have
both of the sour that I that I have uh
currently Mar stem right yeah so I have
um the two sours I got from you and then
I have the one still that I had um from
2020 um and yeah I mean the Mary stem
process is it's very very long it's
going to take a long time for me and you
know I'm I'm still in the process of
figuring everything out you know um I I
know it was a different you know show
that we did but um I've successfully
done the
micropropagation um I've successfully at
right now at this point um have
extracted you know a lot of Merry stems
um and I have them currently growing
getting to the point where they're
almost um at the height where I would be
able to kind of do the same techniques
that I use with micropropagation on on
those plants so um right now my my
current you know process is is
connecting those two techniques together
to be able to you know eventually have a
plant that you can grow in a garden you
know so um but yeah my collection is is
vast I think I'm around uh 90 or so and
and about half of those if not more are
already just purely tissue cultured um
speaking of the chem 91 I have that
supposed to be on the way too so uh
that's pretty cool um I love sour I love
chems um any kind of those strains where
you're just like it's not it's not so
friendly to to you know to sniff it
there um the TPS um
but yeah I mean it's been so so awesome
to be able to talk to you and you know
here here where one of my favorite
strains came from you know because I
know everyone's a little bit different
you know with uh what they prefer you
know and um I feel like it has to do
with everyone's you know biology and
like the chemical composition of their
brains and you know what what campono
and tpin that they react to um but I
know personally Sour Diesel is um one of
my favorites for just putting me in the
best mood such a great mood enhancer
find uh I like smoking it better in the
day when I'm working than the chem dog
because chem dog would just couch couch
potato me out I'll be like I got sit
down not soon enough I haven't had any
actual it's funny it's funny
because it's funny because I feel the
same way like people and you know Cosmic
and wolf you can tell me your feelings
on the subject but people would always
tell me how the sour diesel would wreck
them and for me it was just never that
potent even when done properly the
comparison of the potency not THC but
just overall potency to your brain like
the difference between
smoking um the sour or the chem
dog it's like it's night and day you
know and maybe maybe it could also have
something to do with
uh you know if there was some more
sativa in it versus I think that's what
it is more sativa it
you know are you growing too Nick yeah I
I um so I have like a little tiny home
grow and then uh just because where we
moved but I I um I helped manage a uh a
farm as well um so we got like four
different flowering rooms and we have a
I think we have like 108 or 116
different cultivars that we keep on on
hand now but um we're we're also moving
to get some tissue cultur uh set up so
that we can get all of all of those on
cult because keeping 108 strains on on
hand is uh it's difficult it is um we
got uh we we have like two acres of
outdoor that we do so we we try to like
split up all those two acres between
about 102 or 105 different strains per
year and when you doing
Outdoors how you doing them Outdoors uh
we do uh row crops with uh um drip
irrigation oh nice yeah there's no
protection
we do um like tsts and uh and trellising
you know we we're doing out like uh up
here uh there was we had like 35 of them
this Summer over on a
farm and uh we put them on skids and
then on big bags and then we just keep
the brush back and we bring water lines
drip lines to them but I find a d no you
have to be outdoors and your bringing
the water from
afar you got like we have a reservoir
it's a spring so it's it's kind of hard
really to run the drip line so we just
we feed it with a hose most of the time
we don't use trellises so much cuz like
we're I don't know like far apart and we
use large staks and just kind of tie
them up you know the trellises like a
lot of people like them in green houses
but I just find it sometimes it's not
not the ideal thing for me for sure do
either of you guys do anything to what
was that Gabby well so I mean we have
like 3500 plants in the two acres so
it's like putting teap or putting steaks
for each one of those would just be a
little bit too laborious I like I don't
use a lot of stakes I just use like one
maybe this year I didn't have to use hly
any but we get enough wi I feel like it
they strengthens them and I don't have a
problem with them falling over you know
like this the buds they kind of just
stay up the strong the stems you know
what were you asking Gabby though about
like protection yeah do you guys do
anything to protect them from the
weather no um or like is it just grown
straight outside just straight out or
something some people do right we we use
like uh we use an electric stat
electrostatic sprayer on the back of a
tractor um and spray like Biologicals
and stuff to help prevent like petritis
and powder m do and we it's we're in
Oregon so like the hemp russet mites are
everywhere so we got to battle those
throughout the whole season to and um
this year we didn't have much like
thrips or spider mites or anything like
that it was just like the the hemp
russet mites and a little bit of powdery
mdeo towards the end I was thinking
protection from the wind and
rain that trellising um we we get some
pretty intense winds uh in the valley
that we're in so will um we have like
probably three three layers of trellis
per row and the rows are like um it's
like two rows down um straight uh
planted at like a 5 foot centers per
plant then you have the tpost just
running along the outside and then we'll
just pull the trellis along the whole
thing yeah you guys it's a the weather
is a lot different out there than here I
mean it snows where you at yeah but not
far from you too though we get snow here
right but far it's far it's it's far
enough from where I live that I don't
have to worry about it's snowing on my
plants you know like you guys are that's
a big business that you guys you're in
there you know we're just like small
craft farmer here that's
it well that's funny that you say that
cuz we had that discussion about what is
craft cannabis could I could never like
you know once you get once you get like
above 40 plants for a single person to
work it's a lot how do you how do you do
that like it's becomes a full-time job
like it is and you already have one of
those you know you already have one of
those right I have two of those familyes
another fulltime job okay so it's like
you're working a lot of hours trying to
take care of this
plant and you're not getting as much as
you used to get for it so like I'm only
going to grow like a small amount
compared to what I used to sometimes
grow I don't like I don't care about
selling it you know it's more about
personal butd and giving giving it to
some people that don't have itas is
use we have to use a lot of uh
Automation and uh irrigation because
it's only two of us pretty much uh that
are full-time there taking care
of four different rooms of flower and a
few different veg spaces cuz of all the
bombs that we have to keep around and
clone room and that's but I I think it's
pretty fun I like it actually and you
were in a facility too right Gabby you
were working in one I'm not anymore but
you were though what do you think of
like the large facilities so what I
believe and I said this before and I
I'll repeat it is that I believe it's
possible to grow on a large scale and
grow craft quality cannabis
now it's
probably less
profitable right because if it was more
profitable then more people would be
trying to do it but if what you're
trying to do is and we're talking about
large scale right if you're trying to
create a brand known for the highest
quality then you can't cut those corners
and you got to accept that like at least
at
first it might not be as profitable
right but I think if you go in there
with the proper intention and love for
the plant in a commercial facility you
can grow the highest quality product and
you know one thing that that I would say
about this is in a commercial
facility they regularly have tools
available to them that the
average you know craft farmer does not
you know like the amount of
monitoring and controls that are
available to these larger facilities
it's an advantage now I think a lot of a
lot of these facilities are
overusing this technology and and trying
to push the plants too hard and that's
causing other problems I think a
commercial facility can grow as good of
weed as anyone else can if they put the
proper love and and it's it's a
attention so when you have a commercial
facility you got to have enough people
working there if you don't have enough
people working there then all of a
sudden Corners get
cut but you know if you if you can have
enough people working there they can put
more attention into it than in a
situation where it's just like one or
two people working you know four
flowering
rooms so some of the flowering rooms are
huge you
know oh yeah I mean the last place I was
at the flowering rooms um each of them
had like 130 liks I think it 117 lights
something it was like 1,200 plants in
every room and there was eight rooms
plus the veg yeah we we only have 12
lights per room and around 108 plants
per room I just wanted
to uh just wrap it up and you you know
is there anything else that you wanted
to say Mike I'm good you got anything
you want to ask yeah any any well I'm
going to talk to you for the rest of my
life so I can ask more questions I'll
give Nick and Cosmic a
chance you guys have anything you want
to talk about I mean I think I've asked
every question that came to mind right
now it's probably just going to be a
matter of um just digesting you know
everything that we've learned today you
know it's um a lot of really cool
cannabis history you know especially
strains that you know that we all love
you know um so what's your favorite
today I mean besides the sour the diesel
like something else that you like
honestly yeah I mean Sour Diesel it's so
hard to beat um Sour Diesel I love
sfog um that's one I this is a story for
another day um actually my my buddy that
I did this with um about 15 years ago uh
was at my house this weekend and I asked
him if he wanted to jump on this podcast
so that's maybe maybe down the line we
can hear the story from his perspective
but back in the day him and his mom were
uh this about 2011 or so
2012 um they started a uh canvas Club
you know so like a medical dispensary
they had all the paperwork done
everything we were legal to grow in his
house we had a single room that we were
taking care of and um I at the time I
was delivering pizzas you know I put all
the extra money I had uh you know
because he still wanted to get money
from that room so we had to pay rent for
the room that we were growing in so I
paid all the extra money I had for you
know rent every month on that and then
all the equipment that we needed um but
long story short he ended up getting rid
it was a a whole deal um very
interesting story too again I just we
were talking about on Friday so I'm
hoping that we can get him on and uh get
him to tell his end of that but um back
to kind of what we were we were talking
about sfog was one of the strains that
we grew back in the days so I have that
personal connection from you know
basically the the first time of me
really you know learning how to grow and
then you know taking on um you know a
room with my friend
um San Fernando has always just been one
of my favorite
ogs um and then as far as like kind of
modern weed goes uh another favorite uh
actually I'll do a shout out for two
more strains uh one is uh blueberry
muffin from Humble um an amazingly
fruity almost too sweet uh when when
you're trimming up the plant it's it's
almost sickeningly sweet um but it it's
a really good nighttime smoke uh that
blueberry muffin and um I've used it for
several of my breing projects um with
some really interesting results um and
then another one that I uh that I've
been growing again since 2020 is a sugar
cane from in-house genetics uh really
really good hash plant you know lots of
uh lots of frost on it so perfect for
making bubble hash or any kind of
extracts and everything like that so I'd
say those are some of my top uh strains
nice nice and you Nick oh man I I'm just
because of like the volume of different
strains that I've been exposed to um
over the past couple years like it they
start to get muddled but one that always
that I really like because of like U the
medicinal qualities of it for my uh
specific usage would be like uh Miracle
alien cookies or the Mac one cut um that
one and then uh there's a cross of it
where it was crossed to uh the in-house
genetic slur cane and that one's either
called like mac slurry or Mac flurry or
Mac Daddy um but uh that that one also
is it's a just a huge yielder and it's
really potent so those are always good
for me but then I do remember like Tahoe
OG or san foral like sfv OG um or even
just like OG Kush like any OG uh is I'm
I'm downless yeah hey you know that
alien cookies uh I used that in the in
breeding I like the it uh it's nice I
actually back bread it into uh my
Underdog and Ed it to get a man we got
to end this pretty quickly I just want
to add to what you just said I have a
clone called the p855 it's the Pluto
times the E85 and I'm going to send you
a cut Mike um to thank or I could send
it to your buddy that that's holding on
to your genetics till spring but uh it's
an amazing plant for growing indoors or
outside um to me it checks all the boxes
and I'll send you a cut I love you buddy
and I I appreciate you doing this nice
Mee you guys all right super nice
meeting you yeah great meeting you Gabby
you want your work too by way listen you
guys than I ever did you got how many
strains each one of you got on [ __ ]
and so much today you guys are so much
more advanced than I ever was and and
still are we're standing on the
shoulders of giants you know
like you guys went to school for it
right you guys took courses I did
reading
reading learn anything pretty much by
reading and just hands on man as long as
you can get something to to show you
something you know in it and that's
really what it is it's somebody to guide
you do don't forget to leave the brown
browser window open when we hang up so
that this thing fully records and I love
you Mike I'll talk to you soon yeah just
hit leave see you guys yep see you see
you later bye
[Music]