this episode of gabbing with Gabby is
brought to you by the Breeders direct
Seed Company in my opinion the Breeders
direct seed company is your Premier
Source for clones and seeds and they are
the only place that you can get the
Gabby Staten Island collection so visit
breeders direct for all your seed and
clone needs
[Music]
what's up everybody this is Gabby from
the craft Growers Network joined with my
co-host Nick wolf and my good and my
good friends NATO dog and
Sasha Sasha is my Hobbit brother from
Slovenia is how he likes me to address
him so um
yeah super excited about this show today
we're going to do part two of our
interview with Sasha and because we were
talking a lot of strain history I
decided to invite NATO dog who is a
specialist at conversing about these
topics so we're just going to get
started right away and uh I'll let you
continue saying what you were saying
before we started recording NATO dog oh
I mean I I was just saying like on the
on the other podcasts and stuff that I
do like the whole goal of it was really
to justy try to like bring like a
conversational element to it you know
because you know when you get into when
you get into weed or cannabis or
whatever you want to call it it's not
like you know anything it's like you
know what your friend group knows and
then you start getting little bits and
pieces of information you don't know how
correct it is or not maybe you start
reading some like High Times or you know
you get a hold of some stuff and in the
beginning you don't really know what's
right and what's wrong right and so like
for instance going back to like olden
times Gabby and I used to sit around his
house and smoke joints and read every
entry in every Seed Catalog that
existed like knowing nothing about those
breeders really or anything like that we
used to drool over oh my God this
thing's going to be done in six weeks
it's going to be this we used to think
that like you know breeding was like
every line was like well done and well
thought out and you would almost
memorize that stuff you would dream
about going to
Amsterdam you know and a lot of the
early strains that we got there's no
evidence behind any of it you're just
hearing the story from your buddy and
that could be like as accurate or wildly
inaccurate as imaginable because it's
just some random Stoner telling you
something so you know later I mean I
used to think when I used to read High
Times that every month I was gaining new
knowledge and now I'm like horrified
because because there's so much in there
that would like send you in the wrong
direction you know but you just don't
know it's like Wikipedia anyone can post
that's actually kind of the thing now
where it's like even with all the
internet and even with all the
information out there it's you still
need a little bit of experience to
navigate what like is really true and
amazing and what is like oh man that is
not what you want to do you know and it
makes me think of how like when you're
like a a beginner at almost anything
you're just like trying to vacuum up as
as much knowledge as possible but then
you get to a certain point where you
have like a good standard of knowledge
and you start to feel like you know even
less than than you should because of how
much you've absorbed and so you start
looking at everything skeptically and
start to be like I know that this other
thing wasn't true so how how can I look
at this with a skeptical lens
in America people talk about Bro Science
right you know the science of of weed
but like without like the scientific
method but that's kind of like all we
had but that's all we had we had
observations it wasn't so much like we
were wrong it's just that like we
couldn't go Gabby and I couldn't go in
1998 or 9 or whatever and be like what's
wrong with the chem dog like like go to
a university and be like Oh analyze this
and see how we need to it different yeah
yeah we couldn't do any of that so we
didn't have any of like the tools that
you other people could use and so it
ended up just being observation and
stories example of that is uh nutrient
deficiencies oh dude you want to hear
the the classic example I used to take
the nicest nug out of the sack and I
when I was in high school and put it in
this resin chamber in my pipe so that
every time I smoked it I was getting
hash and then that nice nug would be
coated in hash so when I finally smoked
it it would be better because it' been
infused and this was like this was the
top secret Tech like you'd buy a special
pipe with a chamber that you could fit
it in there and everyone thought you
were cool you know and like later on
obviously we realized that's garbage but
that was like that was well known that
was told to you they had whole pipes
built for that reason you had a resin
chamber with a resin chamber yeah yeah
you had a think the uh it makes me think
of the like Millennium blunts or
whatever people would call them where
they would take the roaches from all
their joints or Blunts and then roll
them up and like it gets me higher
because it's got all the res in it very
much so and that that kind of that kind
of thing it's like you don't realize I
mean that's the crazy part for me too is
like if you go back all the way like the
first books I bought like Rob Clark
marijuana botne or something like
that I give mad respect to that guy
because nobody nobody even knew the
information he put in there like how do
you get a plant to flower what does it
take like what do the different parts of
the plant do how do they respond to
stuff and so when it's something's
illegal and you can't just go read about
it you have to sort of like you know you
have to figure it out you really do yeah
can I ask you the a question not so like
where did you get your first conab seats
from oh so that is interesting because a
gabby will laugh at this when I was in
high school the only import that I was
aware of in the middle of the country
cuz I'm I was from Chicago right which
is like smack dab in the middle I got
green colored Mexican and brown colored
Mexican right and so I don't I don't
tell this story too much but like
my I used to when I was in high school I
used to sit in my room at my parents
house and like pick all the seeds and
stems out of the weed that I had bought
and throw it out the window so I could
clean it up before you used it because
it all came with seeds and stems and my
very first grow I actually took a
picture cuz my parents just moved out of
their house this last spring so I my
very first grow was I was mowing my
parents lawn in Spring and I came around
the corner and lo and behold underneath
my window where I've been throwing all
these all this all the seeds and stems
there was was three or four Mexican
cannabis plants about 2 feet tall
growing out of the
bushes right and they lived about before
you noticed they yeah they I mean it was
just they lived about 15 seconds after I
discovered them I took that lawn mower
dude and I hammered him as hard as I
could because I had know where to put
them I had know what to do I just knew
that like if my mom or dad saw it I
would be grounded for a long time and so
yeah my first huh how old were you must
have been a sophomore or a junior in
high school at best what me I wanted so
14 huh 15 14
15 16 right in there and then um to
actually answer your question though is
like I Gabby and I used to go to Dead
shows right and at the Grateful Dead
shows there would be people would bring
their nice weed to the parking lot or to
the concert and you could bump into
those people sometimes so I pumped into
someone and I got what we now call as
kind bud and it was very expensive and I
didn't know how to get it everybody that
I knew that knew how to get it was at
Grateful Dead shows and all my friends
that I had back in Chicago they knew how
to get Mexican so actually dude when it
comes to First cannabis seeds I went out
to Amsterdam pretty
early because I didn't know anywhere
else to get good weed besides literally
wanding around a Grateful Dead parking
lot and trying to make friends and going
to
Holland mhm right so when I first went
Amsterdam which was I believe when the
summer I turned 18 which would have been
like 1994 or something like that I knew
nothing about
Amsterdam I mean nothing right so I went
there I knew enough because the high
times I knew that that you could buy
weed and you could buy
seeds I I didn't know there was a red
light district I didn't know there was
smart shops that you could buy and when
I walked in as like dude as a Grateful
Dead hippie kid walking into a shop
where they had legally growing living
psychedelic mushrooms like in a case MH
I was like oh my God they have they
banned you know they banned it of you
know because people went crazy a little
bit you know they they a touristic place
the same thing what you tell me now me
happened to me in 9 5 or 96 before that
time we were planting back seats all the
time like you did yeah back seats from
all the weed that you could back you
know from from wheat you have seeds and
then you make a you know my cousin he
was like a really like he was a Hendrick
fan and Jenny Joplin fan and you know
like he marked it with with Hendrick and
Joplin and you know some remark about
some party or I don't know you know just
to have a to have a breach that you
remember it remember
yeah yeah yeah yeah that was the wheat
you know on that party it was so good we
feel so good you know it has this this
smell or particular taste or you know
that's how it went and we got so many
different phenotypes man every seed that
you were putting in it turned out
different but then but then in 1995 or 6
I went to a pizzeria here in my town
which was the first stone Oven Pizzeria
guy from Sicilia came to make that
Pizzeria you know the oven and
everything to make this Italian style
calabres pizza you know and the guy that
was the cook was a guy that traveled all
around the world and he came back to
Slovenia he was Slovenian but he was a
cook on a on a cruise ship you know so
he went every he went everywhere you
know like in the 70s ' 80s he was you
know on ship well traveled so he saw a
lot of wheat so he came back you know he
was the first guy that put a catalog on
the table when I was there for a pizza
and he said hey little one you want to
see this and he put the catalog of sany
seeds catalog of 1994 or 93 I don't know
the catalog was there sany seeds and it
had all of these you know weed strains
with [ __ ] all the data and you know
like the were like all we know it and uh
the next year this guy had already uh
was it in it was was in in German
because he got it in German he went to
to somewhere in Austria or Germany maybe
at that time because seeds were allowed
at that time in Germany and also there
was a very big wheat scene in
Switzerland at that time you could buy
there was so much wheat in Switzerland
until 2001 2001 it stopped in
Switzerland they were growing High
potent THC flowers putting them into
bags like like like like uh you had
pillows they called them pillows and
they said it's aroma
therapy so it's like yeah they were
selling them in few you know Switzerland
is in three conton you know you have the
French speaking contone the German
speaking contone and the old Roman
speaking Italian and Roman yeah so it's
like and in few they have this law that
you could actually sell the the the
wheat the the the Bots for aroma therapy
so if you get into this little shop they
have buckets of kilo of wheat inside and
you said if you ask them what is the
best to smoke they were not selling you
nothing they throw you out yeah this is
not for smoking they say it's just for
you know because aroma therapy they sell
you the pillows but of course behind of
this was was a really big weed scene you
know so like in in America we used to
have it used to be really hard to get
stuff to smoke with I grew up in Chicago
so like in in that era it was really
hard to find the crappiest papers you
could imagine at a gas station we had to
drive to a different state Wisconsin to
even get pipes right and if you because
it was all illegal and if you went in
like everybody everybody in America of a
certain age if you went in you were
buying the pipe to smoke
tobacco right and if you so you had to
call it a water pipe if you called it a
bong like for smoking weed you could be
an undercover cop trying to get the
store in trouble for selling gear that
was used for drugs so they would throw
you out so they would have big signs on
the wall right only ask for water pipes
we do not sell anything but for tobacco
use only water pipe so like even just
saying the word bong would get you
tossed out right for us this is totally
on you know it's ridiculous that would
never happen ridiculous for us too they
would never they would never arrest
somebody for selling bongs or something
because you have shops here that sell
cannabis plants in Austria but you also
have shops that are not selling Canabis
plant but they sell all the other stuff
for par how you say it
paria you know what I mean all this you
know they sell only for consuming but
for example in my shop we don't sell
anything not even papers nothing to
consume we are a gardening shop we don't
sell you know we have you have soils
fertilizers we have seeds we have you
know pots we have uh you know all kind
of stimulants everything micro rasal
fungi everything blah blah blah but we
don't sell you bongs papers something
that you would consume wheat because
this is not our we are a library of you
know connection of makes a connection
yeah that yeah and actually we
specialized on the library you know to
to keeping genetics keeping good
genetics in a very good form but also
the old ones which everybody threw away
in Austria in the last 10 years you know
all the shops got R of the old cuts
which I was like crying for me was like
what are you doing guys you know you
forgot about the
Codex the C you know yeah I mean they
what I didn't realize as a kid and I
think this is like true of almost any
thing is that I thought that the weed
scene would stay relatively
static I didn't realize that like every
5 years there was going to be a sea
change in what you could get what was
available what would be common and easy
would become rare you know or impossible
or even legendary as time went on now
that I understand weed people and I've
spent my adult life in it I get why
things happen the way that they do and
the various things that get lost I mean
I can say from my
experience people laugh at me dude
because they'll be like how did you
collect all these amazing genetics right
and I'll be like it's really easy you
just hold on to things for years when
nobody else wants
them right like that's the thing is it's
like in all cannabis scenes I've seen
everyone wants what's popular and what's
easy to sell or move or grow at the
moment but what happens when something
goes through a period perod where people
don't want it for a while it might not
have anything to do about its quality or
whether you like it but it might go
through a period where like it's just
not popular and most people will dump
whatever it is if it's not popular and
they just want to hold on to the things
that are currently in the moment and so
that's what you were just saying where
it's like there's it's almost like a I
don't know what when you want to call it
a disease or whatever but Nostalgia it's
well I just I just laugh that it's like
I mean I literally because I live in
meno and I had the ability to I just
started holding on to things that I
personally
enjoyed right because I we I'd grow
whatever it was that needed for the
market but then we'd have a section like
for instance Gabby and I were talking
about it the other day the thing that
he's really famous for bringing the chem
dog West to California we never cropped
a ton of chem dog because it was really
ugly and most Brokers didn't want it it
so we would grow it for ourselves mhm we
would grow a few pounds for like us and
our friends and everything like that but
we were typically growing something else
to make the market happy you know and
then later on people were like oh my God
you had this legendary thing and I was
like dude it was so legendary nobody
wanted
it you know like that's not it's not
100% true like people that had smoked it
yeah people that wanted to smoke they
wanted it but people that wanted to buy
weed to sell it was a little bit risky
because it wasn't as and just like today
it's it wasn't as pretty it's ugly it's
legitimately it's I mean it's like like
I have bulldogs and they're like so ugly
they're cute you know that's kind of you
know like they are but that's kind of
like the that's kind of like the chem
dog like it but to me it's like all weed
looks the same when you roll a joint of
course that is my point too
same thing I believe in this Gabby last
time told me another theory like you
know but it's like we are all the same
actually you enjoy it even if you have
sex with a woman that is not physically
attractive to other guys maybe to me it
is you know what I mean I have my own
taste you know what I mean but generally
that that's a funny analogy dude because
I actually say there's I think there's
like there's there's weed out here right
now that's really gorgeous and doesn't
do anything for me and so all joke to my
friends it's like having a super hot
girlfriend that's really mean to you you
know like everybody else is impressed
and like they're all like so pumped that
you pulled this girl and you're like no
she actually isn't she doesn't treat me
very well you know like she might be
real pretty to look brother brother you
suffer you suffer right you know when
you with her you're actually suffering
but everybody thinks you are enjoying it
it's like no it's not like say you know
like when it comes to humans
80% of like our nerve end like there's
so much connectivity between our eyes
and our brain like our eyes for people
are way better than our nose or our
sense of taste or our hearing we're
basically like our species is really
about here you know and so like visually
things are really important and when you
see social media you can't see you can't
see like uh you can't sniff it you can't
taste it you can't squeeze it you can't
smoke it but you can see it you know and
I even think talking about those
cataloges High Times went in the early
90s late 80s from like very poor
pictures to probably by like the mids
when you and I were talking about it
full glossy pictures in the center of
the magazine of White Widow and great
white shark and cie mist and all these
things and you would drool over those
you would look at these pictures of
these buds you know just be entranced by
like could I get that you know brother
it is like also yeah we didn't have
internet at that time we didn't have
cell phones you know we have to tell
people also this in mind that there was
no internet there was no phones so you
basically was on your own experience you
saw what you saw from year to year and
then you made a picture and then
everything else you know overgrow.com
when that [ __ ] came you know yeah we
were all there you were there also I
think too Gabby you were there
overgrow.com before it dropped I don't
know 2006 it dropped right it was over
so in 2006 there was the four I think
maybe there was this there was this seed
seller in Canada called Heaven Stairway
yeah stairways to Heaven that was the SE
which is a play on Le lead Zeppelin song
or whatever yeah and they got raided by
the by the government for selling tons
of seed because the big Market is always
America right so all these seed
companies they all get in trouble for
sending tons of seed to America so they
got rid and it turns out that overgrow
and cannabis world were both tied into
that company so when they got busted
like the two forums that everybody was
on and communicating fell off because
the parent company that owned it all of
a sudden was in trouble you know and
there was I mean Mark Emery used to have
like Mar who used to have a cannabis
Culture magazine and the back of the
magazine would be like a two or three
page um you know catalog of everything
he was selling but that was where I mean
we had to uh you know that that was
where you got seed I mean I feel dumb
like I wish that all of the stuff that
like we had done when we were younger I
had like put a pack or two of everything
I bought in in the freezer for later me
because I blew through so much stuff
picking choosing killing males getting
rid of anything I didn't want and I
didn't realize that like I wouldn't be
able to go back later on and get that
same stuff it would just disappear right
same thing the same thing you know the
stuff that I you know when I was talking
about the catalog that the guy showed us
you know at that time we started to buy
seeds never bought seeds before from a
from a catalog and those genetics not
only we bought it and we have the same
thing like you we lost things and but
other people like like luy when I was
telling you from the last podcast you
know he was also having some of these
trains you know the skunk number one for
example he bought in those times in the
'90s and my guys had like a selection
they have the number 11 and the number
16 it was very popular in in the Clone
form in the underground scene when it
was grown but people tell me now it was
all skunk number one but they were very
different from each other and there was
another one which was actually very
recessive it has the stripes like you
see on Dr greenspoon pictures today you
know uhhuh this kind of you know when
you have the plant you just have this
sack underneath you know where the one
seat should be but the whole BT was
consisting only from these little sacks
like you know it was stripes we called
them the they called it the some Jerry
some some with Jerry you know but you
know the genetics that came from those
three years I think you told in another
podcast that those was those was nville
stock stock that was still from nille
because it was yeah after since seed
bought the the seed bank they have still
his stock which they directly sold
actually yeah so I I didn't realize that
for the longest time but from basically
from when they bought his stock in 1991
till about
1995 they literally just sold seeds that
Neville had already
made so for the first four years that
Sensei was selling all that they weren't
even making any new stuff they were just
selling like what Neville had already
made and then when they ran when they
started running low they hired him again
and he came in and that's where like the
the Jack herrer and the Black Domina and
some of those other things that they
started adding new stuff to the catalog
but if you get a 91 92 93 94 addition
sensey catalog it's literally the exact
same listing of strains no change one
question if if you would have somebody
in the world now that is listening if he
has a pack from 91 till 95 for example
of sensey seeds in his fridge or even
not I mean you know
probably they are not going to sprout
but the question for you Noto would it
Sprout with the help of gibberelic
acid and I will say that if it was if it
was stored well there is a chance that
it will Sprout so if it's stored poorly
or something happens to it like
physically that's kind yeah that's kind
of a tangent but like Gabby and I did
all this work all this breeding work for
a long time together and uh I lost my in
an unfortunate event and I think he was
on vacation in Jamaica or something and
he had all of his stuff in a fridge or
freezer and the breaker popped if I
remember right and it was just the seeds
got hot in a garage for X number of
weeks you know but I've taken 20 30 year
old seeds and I've gotten some of them
to pop so it just depends on how they're
stored temperature that is not
fluctuating too much from plus to minus
right that is
some yeah I'll tell a story and I mean I
told it a little while ago but I'll tell
a different version of it so when I
first moved out to California my ex my
ex lady with the reason why we moved is
she had cancer and so I we moved out to
mesino County because it was like the
most California passed the first laws in
America where if you were sick you could
have access to cannabis right and they
had just done that the year before in
and so we ended up planning in '97 to
move and we moved in '98 and I had a
friend that blew glass right and he
realized that like blowing glass like
spraying all that oh yeah spraying all
that gold and silver on your pipes was
unhealthy so we hired this old H this
old like HVAC heating and air
conditioning guy to help us build like a
hood and like all that right get a
little bit more professional well he
ended up being sick with cancer and I
felt really bad for him he was old he
was kind of poor to be perfectly honest
and he was kind of struggling and so I
was going through it with my ex and so I
gave him a quarter pound of weed or
something and some hash and I told him
you know don't even worry about it dude
just just hopefully it makes you feel
better right and so he felt so he wanted
to do something for me but he didn't
have anything really so the next time I
saw him he brought me a couple of seeds
in a in in a medicine thing right and he
was like man he's like I these just been
in my closet I used to grow weed a
million years ago I don't even know what
you'll find of them okay but but try
okay so I Sprout these things I grow
them up all right and one of them comes
out the most the only the only one that
lived came out the most beautiful purple
color and it ends up being called what
now what we call the Mendo perss right
and so I brought it back to him and he
was like oh my God this is the point of
the story I brought it back to him and
he was like oh man I only grew purple
weed once and that was in the summer of
77 in Koval which is this Podunk little
town in
Mendo and so really like the moral to
that is that those seeds when he gave
them to
me I was 22 or something and the seeds
were
21 oh so I had 21-year-old seeds and he
had just tossed them in like a cool
closet yeah in on his mountain house and
he lived on like the when you live on
like the Northeast side of a mountain up
in the hills you don't get very much sun
no you know it's like you really don't
like and he lived in the woods kind of
cuz he was a logger and some trees or
whatever so it was like we yeah I took
21y old seeds at the time do you think
it's from from Afghan origin I think
it's nepes but I I'm just guessing and
the only reason why I say that is
because once I met like real collectors
in Holland I started getting taken back
to their flats or their apartments or
whatever and they would like smoke weed
with me and we would chat and the nicest
hash they had was they were all trading
these nepes Temple balls they felt like
that was the best and when I smoked that
it tasted to me like the Mendo PE mhm
but I have no idea what it is to be
honest I mean um I do think I do think
it's that old too because it's really
low
THC so it kind of fits that era of
Canabis you know in the sense that like
most cannabis in the 70s was between 7
and
12% yes you know like and so it tests
kind of like between eight and 12 you
know really T amazing yeah but it tastes
amazing I mean Gabby and I actually
became friends and and when like when we
first started becoming good friends me
and my friend Sean who's passed we left
a couple joints uh of the meno on like
Gabby's window I can't remember like on
his my wind I we on his windshield or
something like that and left our number
and like yeah that's literally how we we
that's that's literally how we became
friends is we talked all this stuff and
we wanted to leave him a little gift and
so we left him a joint and so yeah you
can improperly store seeds and then you
might need like embryonic recovery or
something that's beyond my paygrade to
figure out how to do it but do it
through like tissue culture and uh you
can pull the embryo out of the shell we
need to find somebody to help us get
this a long process this is this is this
is it the end howo dog got his name
right there oh my God yeah I mean I I um
we Gabby and I did a ton of breeding
together and through A Series of
Unfortunate Events a bunch of it got
lost and then what got survived at
Gabby's went through a heat treatment
and I lost the rest in a fire in a fire
yeah yeah hey uh I want to change
direction real fast but before I do I
wanted to say that uh I thought the
question that Sasha was going to ask was
if you could go back in time and get any
one pack of seeds that you could from
back in the
day and for me the answer would be
sensey Seed Super
Skunk like it's like not even a I mean
there's other ones like that I'd really
want but if I it's like if you had to be
on a desert island and you could only
bring one thing the Sensei Seed Super
Skunk that's the one that got away I
might have two or three but but yeah
that would be one I got to choose
one I thought that's what Sasha was
asking oh yeah no I mean there's a I
mean what's funny about it too is the
way seeds are is like you could go buy a
bunch of legendary seed and get all crap
or you know buy one pack and find a gem
you know I mean the super skunk from
Neville was so consistent we used to
hold the magazine up against our flower
every crop and be like holy [ __ ] looks
just like the that is actually true Abby
and I we had I think it was the 1990 uh
seed bank catalog uh had a nice big
picture of super skunk butt in it was
the first year it was released and you
could take a side nug off the super
skunk that Gabby gave me and you could
hold it up to that picture and it looked
like you had picked the bud that he had
used to take that picture I mean it was
like it was it was a we used to joke it
was like a perfect example but it was
also it was also a bust because Gabby
has a different memory than me I don't
remember having carbon filters back then
there was and so I them I would have I
mean I don't know that I didn't buy
maybe I remember like those like ozone
generators I remember having an ozone
generator in and then venting and then
having like it go through 25 or 30 feet
of ducting before it went out the
house right because when that that super
skunk was a bust that turp that
everybody's after right now yeah that
exact back picture that turp that
everybody is after right now it was
stank up your whole house it stank your
stank outside your house so I would like
pull up to my house remember when I
lived in that red house outside of
Willets Gabby I would pull up to my
house yeah I would pull out of I would
pull into my driveway with my windows
down and be like oh my God I can smell
it right and it and like it wasn't that
chill to have that happening so hey
what's up
it was yeah I didn't even
see I got to like choose Cosmic joined
us welcome going welcome thank you all
right so I do
wna um I want to make it a little bit
more of a Sasha story time where we ask
questions because I've been talking to
him you know you missed last week when
he was talking about the Santa Maria
Plank and then um also the Shiva that he
has and I I want you to be involved in
that conversation also in the last few
days he's been telling me stories about
traveling to
Mongolia and finding weed there and then
also um carrying his uh ice waterer hash
bags throughout Spain and and making
hash there so um I you know the purpose
of this is to let Sasha tell some of his
story and
wait the short version of Mongolia for
example you know uh started to study in
lublana I had a really good friend which
is still a very good friend today of
mine a brother uh we you know having
like a night where we were getting drunk
and you know then we have this idea
where are we going to travel together
right now you know we you going to
travel this summer because we have like
you know between the studies you have
time you know he said let's go somewhere
there is
nothing and to Mongolia by uh plane
ticket and we have invitation letter
from a guy that lived in ulam B this is
the the the capital of Mongolia and this
was in 2001 that I was in Amsterdam I
was a wiad before that already you know
in the '90s but you know this was just
like uh if traveling you know like do
some [ __ ] you know some crazy [ __ ] in
your life that then you will never
forget it was Unforgettable experience
you know we were 2 months in Mongolia we
were hitchhiking horses you know no you
know you have you have like the capital
then you have you wrote on the back with
somebody else uh you know it's like they
don't have like public transportation
there it's like you have it but it's not
there is no roads like there are there
are uh them on the stars and on you know
it's crazy it's there is so vast it's
like three time of France is Mongolia
and it 2 million people like
Slovenia you understand it's like it's
like I mean and 1 million of people live
live at that time in UL in the capital
so it was like uh the only land world
that did not have possession of land
because there are nomadic people the
bers hang hang around you know like
where the G is then the cattle will be
fed and you know continue so it's a very
harsh environment to live in really
harsh but you have
me about how old were you uh when I was
traveling there 18 years 18 years old 19
19 19 years 18 to 19 yeah yeah 19 at
that time all right for example we were
many places in Mongolia like in the
South in goby desert and then in the
capital of course in First and traving
North and North is uh go uh to the of uh
elevation and you have SE uh which is
drinkable water this is you know in
Russia there is this Bal lake is one of
the biggest lakes in the world M so
south of Bal lake is a lake called hovor
Hol n it's called Hol and it's like 40
kilomet in or 30 km uh and 50 60 km Long
Lake and it's 1% of all the drinkable
Water Supplies on Earth there in this
Lake and I was there so on the way to
this Lake there is a town called
eret and in this town you know we were
walking you know this was 2001 I and my
body and another friend were traveling
you know together and we were like
walking through you know this little
town the white guys you know and because
we are slovenians we stand a little bit
of Russian because it's like I don't
speak Russian but it's a Slavic language
my language is a Slavic language group
so I understand Russian because I don't
know to speak Mongolian man it's like
Mongolian is a really difficult language
you know it's hungarians have a Mongol
uh root of language like near me where I
live so it's a really it's a un finish
group of languages so you know to go to
wheat you know I'm too long wheat is
grown in Mongolia to the border to
Russia from that Lake on there is wild
feral which is actually aof
flowering is the basis of actually outof
flow this is a Siberian type of cannabis
it grows there in abundance you cannot
even know I mean this is white trees you
know how how you call them in English
there is this white trees with white you
know they have this white skin
and yeah and then it's only Canabis
underneath and you have this Aspen uh
forest in siia which are like you can
drive with the train through the Trans
Siberian uh you drive days through these
forests so much of that wood is there
you have to understand how big this area
is it's vast it's you know Mongolia and
then it's Kazakhstan next to it and
Kazakhstan is really huge also you know
it's and these areas are so un
inhabitated people that live if there
they don't know about conies or even if
they do it's a total different approach
would that be ruderalis this is
absolutely rudis yes yes and this is
like it never grows more than 40 cm you
know it knees maybe and then it's
flowering because it has no flowering
time because of the short winter times
the short yeah the short it has to get
it has to do it quick yeah and THC
levels are really low I mean that is we
that is maybe I don't know 5% 4%
something like that you know you just
get to smoke
more extract it it's growing wild it's
you know like it's everywhere you have
access you know you can do that spli in
your mou day of course it's right
everybody talks about land races right
which that obviously would be just like
wild feral populations but I don't think
most people realize how much work it
would be to like take a land hand race
and bring it into something that like
modern style we would consider be happy
with like it's a lot of work you know
yeah and a lot of times we're just
taking work that's already been done for
decades prior with different people and
adding our own little flavor to it you
know but you know you want to take like
you were talking about earlier like some
Haze weed that had just like one little
KX two little KX three little KX know
just big enough for one seed yeah that's
not what Growers want to see so you'd
have to take that and like breed it into
something and over time so it's like
hard to reinvent the wheel because the
wheel takes a lot of
work you know but so did you was there
people selling weed in Mongolia no no
one they give it to us you know we were
smoking joints in newspaper no smoking
papers there you man it's like even
cigarettes were rolled in newspaper
oh my God sources at that time I mean of
course now it's
2024 and it's a different story to also
know that at that time 80% of the
population was under 20 years old when I
was there this is it because they
di% 80% of the population was under 20
years and 20 2 million and 400,000
people was in all
Mongolia that's the land is like three
times
France so just huge grass lands going
off every direction and you know 27
million uh in the land you know they
have 2 million people but they have 27
million horses because this is the land
of the horse you know they live with
horses they survive with horses
everything is with Hors all the culture
is about horses and the history is about
jingis con and the Conquering and
everything you
know so this is one of the stories you
know in Indonesia where I was uh the
wheat is there is absolutely illegal
it's really hard I mean I didn't smoke
wheat there for a year that I was living
there I didn't smoke wheat I didn't even
search for it you know because it's so
dangerous and there is vat there in uh
in north of Sumatra is feral Cannabis
sativa M high in THC and they use it uh
thing is that in in Indonesia
they use it also in kitchen for food as
a medicine a as a herb they put into the
food as a traditional food in North
Sumatra called band AEK the
region it's a very
Orthodox country Indonesia but in Bacha
they are the most
Orthodox and they have uh fasting of
jungle therea is there you know it's
kind of sativa that is there feral you
know but it's so forbidden in Indonesia
to consume kabes even or something it's
like you know if you don't like your
life then you have deal you then you
deal some Canabis in Indonesia because
get killed yeah you get killed yeah it's
it's death penalty death penalty yes
yeah even T tourists you know uh that
smuggled canab is through you know there
was cases we won't talk about this now
but there is cases that is is so
hardcore penalties that is like you
don't you do don't you know and I the
land you know I travel there I'm not
traveling you know then I need wheat you
know all the time when I was traveling
you know the when weat we it was great
it was no wheat there was just no wheat
you know you live your life you know
it's also a great experience because
you're not at home so we're not so
alike but of course I like it when there
is wheat right so for example in the
'90s you also been there we for us is
the same thing you go there you know it
from the cataloges you know it from the
seat Banks you know it's like wow I've
been waiting for this moment so long and
then I buy Bubble Bags there in 2005 or
something when I was second time there
and then you know bubble bags from from
bubble man you know for the Ice Water HH
technique so I okay so I have a question
yeah um because we're talking about like
your your worldly travel Sasha where is
the craziest place that you found weed
and were able to smoke
it oh yeah Mongolia yeah the Mongolia
that is the craziest place I saw it but
I mean that it even exists I guess like
where was it like something where
because it sounds like in Mongolia it
wasn't but but for people to have to use
it it was just like wildly growing like
was there any place where you didn't
expect to find weed that you found it
other than Mongolia and and and and but
like found it in like a smokable not
just growing out there in the wild
everywhere I travel there was kabes
everywhere go to antarc you know
Antarctica it does not have wheat you
know like you know but
allic you know but weed is every
everywhere weed is All Around the Globe
I mean it's so spread now because wheat
actually controls us the people you know
what I mean we die we become the food
for those plants then actually they eat
us sometimes people are like this in
romantic fashion that like you like have
you are the Whisperer of the plant or
something you know like yeah yeah yeah
you can be the Whisperer but she will
eat you on I mean you know there's this
uh there's this cool book if you're
lucky cool book it's old now but it's
called the botney of desire right it's
by this guy Michael Pan and it's a
plant's eye view of the world right yeah
and so instead of like focusing on us it
focuses on like which plants used us to
spread all over the place right and
cannabis is one of his main examples one
of the other ones is Apples because
apples just come from Kazakhstan like
you just mentioned yeah joh right yeah
and they and used humans to go
everywhere and now they exist everywhere
where they used to exist just in this
one zone right and um it's really
interesting to like think about it from
like well what does the plant want from
us and that's what cannabis gets from us
is we have spread it all over the place
yes and like when people were growing
hemp hemp was one of the main things
that sailors use to make rope and
sails so I read that
most sailing Expeditions would have hemp
seed in case they got Shipwrecked they
could grow a crop and turn the hemp into
fiber so they could make sails or they
could make ropes and they could try to
get the hell out of there they could
make rafts whatever and so hemp seed and
taking cannabis with them was important
to Sailors it was probably also useful
as a trade yeah and so you know yeah you
you can trade you can make you can grow
this thing and you can make ropes with
it you can do this I'll show you how to
do it it was valuable and so they
brought it everywhere and so that's kind
of like it seems like it went everywhere
based on you know as soon as wherever
Sailors went it went too yes that's how
it was spread actually right yeah that's
pretty much you know yeah yeah
definitely and you know the first seats
that we got here you know before we went
to amster and the Cals it was actually
land races because our guys you know
here from Yugoslavia they could travel
we were not under Russian uh
Administration Yugoslavia was its own
land we were the independent you know
the the ones that you know I told in
last podcast already about this a little
bit but we could travel all Africa all
Asia almost because we we were you know
Tito is the leader of Yugoslavia at that
time he was like a superstar you know
like a god
he was a really really good friend of
highis eloi the first oh
wow yeah yeah he was pal and Tito was
like that you know in Tito's uh funeral
all Hollywood came you know all all
everybody from all the the leaders of
the world came for his funeral because
Yugoslavia was at that time everybody
knew what would happen because it do you
know and then when I was young there was
one car in America from you oslavia the
Yugo Yugo the Yugo yeah they sold the
Yugo over here and yeah yeah cheap and
efficient it was the only car I've ever
seen in my life where the back seat was
an
option like you could get one without a
back seat it could just be you know like
it was there but you yeah it could just
be you know so yeah but um you know it
was affordable and you could get from a
to be you know the story of Yugo but
actually here it's a national it's like
a Yugo was the only car you know that we
so then I I have a question for you then
right which is kind of related to that
so with the whole when I first went
there was before the euro where
everybody all the countries had like
their own currencies and stuff like that
like there'd be Deutsch marks in Germany
or there'd be gilders in in Holland or
Fran in France or whatever MH
you know like when I first started
going like the Iron Curtain had just
fallen and like eastern and western
Europe had been sort of
separated by politics you know or
governments for decades like once that
started opening
up you know like what were you
restricted when you were young from like
going to like Western Europe no never
never you could go wherever you wanted
yes that was the difference between
Yugoslavia and other countries that was
under Russian
Administration most of for
example Poland Czech and uh Republic
Czechoslovakia at that time countries
were under Russian Administration they
could not travel to the west but me but
you could I could because West was here
like few meters away from my house no
yeah I get it and so did that was there
as far as weed goes when that opened
up yeah there like a lot of exchange and
different things going on because all of
a sudden Europe was like more integrated
you know uh interesting thing you know
we never exported wheat to to you know
like you know I mean some people did but
it's like more or less we wheat from
Albania that was your Mexican for us oh
wow yeah that's what I was kind of
getting
at was your weed like where where where
was weed being able to be grown like
when things opened up because it is you
know Alia it's in a place called you can
Google YouTube it it's a it's a place in
Albania that was really growing amounts
of cannabis under also you know the
government knew for that Albania was
like you know they you know this this
place was so
poor before it grew with that they
became the most uh place in in Albania
they were growing so much the whole
village grew the whole surrounding all
the village grew wheat and the
neighboring Villages also did it then
politics uh pressure on them and of
course it was shut down after some time
but of course if amarat was shut down
that does not mean you know that other
places are still operating but it pops
up yeah the problem is only that these
people you know they have genetics Maybe
that were good there to grow and
everything but the problem is for the
transport to to you know to get to
certain places in Europe they were using
like fuel tanks of trucks and you know
and then the wheat was like you know
that's you could smell the the the fuel
you the fuel in it yeah you could it was
totally see that I never consumed this
in my life because I was always
Enthusiast you know in the '90s already
I was H grower you know who and in the
forest also I have my patch as a gorilla
grower you know I uh me was like
medicine you know you cannot do this
with medicine it's over all right so let
me ask let me ask you a question then
when you were growing in the woods you
know and all that like early on like um
when did the weed need to finish before
your weather got so bad that it was like
cuz you know it varies obviously
depending on where you live in America
yeah you know some places it's really
hard to like get weed to finish yes in
other places it's a lot warmer and a
little bit nicer and all that but yes
but yeah when did when did weed finish
for you what kind of weed were you
growing were you getting Amsterdam Seed
were you getting Holland seed were you
trying to grow local stuff that would be
cool to talk about yes I can tell you
this is very interesting
because you know in our places the in
was the winter came earlier the cold
temperatures were not like now that you
have in
October you know we have in oober we
have a weather like California does like
we can grow late strains for for my
perception which was in when I start to
grow it you could not grow that kind of
late you have to finish until end of
September MH then the rain came yeah you
have mold and everything but also there
is another thing we started to realize
that there is some strains some genetics
that is also produced in Switzerland and
one of those companies or two I will
mention now one was the Alpine seed
company and the other one was Green
Hornet he was from both of them were
from Switzerland and they used genetics
that finished earlier they were breed in
the mountains
outside in Switzerland in the 90s uh
famous trains of Switzerland it's called
ER Bly it's called strawberry St
strawber you know that's where the St
strawberry comes actually from because
this is the airbe lead what was grown in
the '90s in Switzerland it was a very
fast finishing Indica strawberry plant
they had no mold no issues with mt
whatsoever it was Absol and it's a very
fast routing it was really good for
production and presumably they found it
on a on a field because they could grow
fields of of plants at that time mhm so
the selections was there people what who
was doing this are wasal already at that
time I mean just had opportunity
opportun you know Shanti Baba when he
moved from Amsterdam where where did he
go Putland of course because the
opportunity was there until 2001 he
could I think he's still in Switzerland
and I don't know but he made a legal
business he's a legal producer now yeah
yeah he made a legal business in
Switzerland yeah and that's because he
he was in that time also when it still
was legal before the illegalization with
the
criminalization of it happened I
remember Gabby and I used to go to these
like Harvest festivals Festival might be
a big word Harvest Gatherings where a
bunch of Growers would like they'd rent
they'd rent a huge house and everybody
would bring their weed and they would
all talk shop kind of thing and it was
still early enough that like overgrowing
cannabis World hadn't been shut down yet
right and I'll always remember there was
these guys one of them was this uh
gentleman named chip who later on made
this soil company called royal gold in
in California but he had gone to
Switzerland right when they first opened
up right and I always remember he had
these pictures because in America it was
like hard to get away with it he had
these pictures of himself standing in
these fields and in these huge green
houses like with his hands up like this
so you could see that he was just in
this you know football field sized
Greenhouse full of plants and I always
remember like at that time that was that
was the biggest I'd never seen weed
grown on that scale have you have you
heard about a strain from Switzerland it
was originated from Switzerland called
purpura
tiis never Dude tell me tell us about it
yeah purp before you do it's not very
often that people stump the genetic
experts so okay okay
there you go yeah purpura you can Google
it purpura
tenses kind of a little bit of outlier
from hemp Fields I think you know it was
very low low actually but okay it was F
in some Alps region in the in
Switzerland region of Alps lady that had
a really old
garden and you can Google that story
it's true it will tell you that story it
was found in a garden patch of a old
lady a characteristic of this train that
it has really red stems it has no
deficiency but it has really bloody poor
poor red
stems
um Switzerland breeders try to breed
with it and they did they did many many
crosses with it you know um to get these
red stems you know sure because you know
it you know have not red stems with
green stems you know so but the red stem
these poor poor red stems uh popular you
know in you know '90s early thousands we
when you Google this then you will find
that you know but it's not high thsc
strain it's a really low thsc strain
actually you know uh but for breathing
purposes that you want to take some
certain phenotypic uh character
characteristics and you know to want to
have it in your line you know to repeat
it with a combination of it was adapted
to the mountains it was adapted to the
mountain it would grow well her it was
adapted to the region and it finished in
I mean in the beginning of September
already you know it was so fast oh wow
yeah like the ER Bly you know like er
Bly was also absolutely when really fast
and then those guys from Alpine seats
you know which is a guy you know can
show you a book again because I'm a book
lover this is a book called their
Canabis which means Encyclopedia of
breeding guy that is called Mike m and
the guy who is Mike m is actually one of
the main guys from Alpine seeds from
that company that is was Switzerland
company and they did hybrids they also
had
some you know they had this Larry lemon
Larry OG Kush you
know yeah they had like some cams also
but they don't have the cam dog right
you know I mean they had some really
good genetics they were really on the
right path having having a production of
regular seeds you know and then Green
Hornet also and there were also some
others but I know these two for sure
they there is a Bushman sativa clone
that is still circulating in Austria
very early there's a Bushman sativa
clone yeah so that's that's one of the
things maybe I don't know this is out of
left field for me but if we're going to
talk genetics tell me it's okay we're
just sitting on the couch what are what
are what are your favorite genetics over
there like what are legendary clones for
you what are things that you really love
that you wish you could have again or
that still exist out there what were
famous clones that were passed around
and grown because in America we have our
own list yeah yeah you know okay but
with with Holland and Amsterdam and
different things getting passed around
and all that you guys have your own
stuff and they're not exactly the same
by any means yeah no no no so like what
are what are the things things like do
you name some famous strains that were
yeah name some famous stuff that people
really liked over there that had their
like time in the sun yeah I tell you for
example for the scene of Austria now you
know because in Austria is a legal
Market of Canabis clones you can have
them as ornamental plants you can sell
them as my company does as a B2B
supplier to other shops or you know to
private person you know okay there was
so many show already you know this plank
Santa Maria I got from another shop when
I was a customer there so but I I'm an
Enthusiast and I liked it you know as I
tell you the strains that you like you
keep in your library and that's how
until today it's still there like uh
clone called you know J jagen
Yen it was a big producer yen is a clone
of Jack
Flash strain from sensey seats you know
yeah
y jagen Yen was found jagen you know for
you maybe to read but we call it Jen and
jagan was a clone only that was produced
uh a guy named Dr kosp found it and Dr
Kos is the founder of a forum in Germany
called
hanb and that guy died very early
continued years after he's he passed but
he had uh you know he it was just
written that he slept uh woke up so they
found him you know maybe he had a stroke
brain stroke or something we don't know
about that I will not tell because there
are people out there maybe who listen
now and I'm somebody who never met him
who never but I know his
clone right sure and uh you know like my
story of the Shiva the the the lucky
clone is the same thing these people are
are they passed away but they're they're
maybe for your place Mand mandle bro you
know or somebody you know the same thing
people left something now deal with it
you know the guys who are you know who
are likeminded like us now you know you
like if you get that genetic of course I
will be the librarian again you know I
will keep it forever and I will until I
die and then hopefully somebody keeps it
so jagon is one plant and then from
Dragon was uh green hin the green hin
was uh was a really big producer so grun
hin is a offspring of jagen because
somebody had jagen plants and they were
pollinated by a warlock
male yeah and warlock was by Magus
genetics yeah genetics was a company
that then Simon from Sirus uh took under
his uh I mean he took the genetics
because I don't know know Magus in one
moment was not Magus again and all the
strains for Magus was with serious seats
you know in one moment right so this
grun hesin was even a bigger yielder
jagon but jagon is a beast when you see
it on seat finder you know it has a I
mean the prodction but I don't like my
personal opinion I don't like the Turpin
it has this it was a sativa yeah of
course it has a really sativa flavor and
everything but that's not my cup of tea
personally you know for example that is
also like m m my cup of tea but it was
called Ivory it was a clone only it's
just called Ivory you can also find it
with SE finder it was clone only I it
has a really like taste like I mean it
tastes like mushrooms and it was it was
purple you know we didn't have the Mando
perss you
know a strain for example called Shaman
from Dutch p
okay yeah my guys from mountain region
grew it a lot I mean it was a you know
this low TC sativa with really purple
purple Bots sell it today as regulars
also maybe that's one of the only
genetics that is still really original
with Dutch Bion I don't know I don't
want to insult nobody or something sure
no I understand yeah it's just like none
of none of the none of the seed
companies ever like to admix admit that
their mix has Chang and it's not it's
not it's not a problem for me to you
know I will not go in details now I I'm
not the guy you know who will like like
um others that the genetics are not the
same but I know that they are not the
same so you know 20 plus years ago
something like that I can't remember who
they are but Gabby had some good friends
of his and they gave us a warlock cut
and we grew the Warlock yeah we grew the
Warlock for a number of years mhm
sure I didn't know anything about it I
didn't know where it came from or
whatever they had they gave us a Black
Domina too and something else I can't
remember um they were some friends of
his from somoma but but yeah the Warlock
it was pretty tasty you know Sasha if um
if you could get one strain back that
you've lost over the years what would it
be o the two male plans from yog that I
got from LPA Farms little pack my
brother Ziggy that makes these papers I
told last time this is Ziggy papers
right
mhm he went to Colorado in
2015 or 14 uh before the legalization
and he's a he sold his papers there so
somehow he got the
seats uh it was little pack with this
ape you know ape Loompa Farms you know
and uh for me you have to understand I
never T tasted OG before
because everything on the market in
Europe what was called OG at that time
when you already had it it was not o it
was not when was
this
uh didn't you just say 10 yeah 2014 for
15 yeah because 14 uh everything is like
I was already because I was a Enthusiast
of other strains you know Switzerland
old races you know like I told you and
then the Amnesia we grow a lot you know
the the the corut that is circulating
still in Austria hypro genetics is from
hypro it's actually Super Silver Haze
right and I talked to Shanti also about
it and he said you know still Rose you
know for silver H right it's just a
right really nice phenotype yeah to the
conclusion that is uh yet OG you know is
from a pack of seeds that Ziggy from USA
from Colorado brought them and had them
in the fridge and he called me uh to his
place and you know I I got something
really interesting for you because
actually you will be the one maybe that
will do something with that and he gave
me a few packs not only that because he
was the guy that also made uh for S he
made packs like like that you know and
then inside hdden here hidden s and Zig
are friends they are Rasta culture so s
in business with Ziggy at that time
because the were sold and you had like
seven or five seeds in in the pack also
in the pack Itself by S seeds I have a
pack here wait I can show you s uh that
Ziggy sold at that time you know okay
yeah okay so these packs were um were
seeds also so zigg is the guy who gave
me the YG seeds and uh heard about this
before what Loompa Farms which seed
company and and then I'm a nerd and I
Google it of course I wanted to know
everything about them because when I I
got three seats and another friend of
Ziggy also got three seeds from the
other one he got three males and I got
two males and one
female so there was only one female in
six seats we had no selection nothing
there was just the only one plant this
was the Y that we knew
and it had golf ball hard
nuggets stinky as uh I mean not stinky
but it had a this certain certain Aroma
you
know certain Aroma I never smelled
something and even even saw a plant like
this before it was so aesthetic for me
it was like wow it's so beautiful look
at the the look at the corners look at
the dark leaves look at that you know it
is and then you know uh a while a clone
you know at my facility but it was very
lanky it was hard to deal with it was
really [ __ ] you know like what you know
but I threw away the two males because
when I grew this you know there was two
males I threw them away you know like
okay that's two males and that plant
actually uh you know I realized genetics
at that point so I started to study
mandle you know the first and the second
and the third rule of mandle you know
the Gen genetics and I kept the plant
and we crossed it to SK V gear to double
Crush mail so I keep and everything that
comes out is actually very dominant in
the yeti so we had a very big selection
and the yeti OG that I have now in my
facility I will tell the truth now is
not really Loompa Farm but it's a LPA
Farm y cross to double
Crush yeah because I I just looked it up
I think Yeti OG is a back Cross of uh
headband B yes
definitely yeah yeah you you know this
plant with uh with b and I know not so
from all your uh talks in the podcast
that is one of your favorites right I
mean there's a few one of the hard Parts
about the American weed group is that we
make nicknames for everything and we're
not very good at like lineage or any
like we so it's like one group can call
something one name and then it'll get
shifted to another group and they they
have a different nickname and so it can
get really difficult to figure things
out and then people sometimes rename
things to create confusion right like oh
I'm not supposed to have this so I can't
call it this but I'll call it that and
they won't figure it out type of thing
and so when you do like strain history
like I do it gets really difficult
because basically like every American
group of dudes that like to smoke weed
like nicknames yeah and so Loompa
headband in my opinion is a very OG um
very cush very OG Kush like what people
know is that and uh I have a one of the
guys that that was in Loompa hates me
and the other one is one of my better
friends so uh but yeah like Loompa OG is
um it's basically Loompa headband is
basically a really good OG you know it's
a really strong really potent really
flavorful anybody yes if anybody in
America was to get like a pure Loompa OG
uh they would immediately just classify
it as some kind of kush it's definitely
I mean I supposedly have the headband U
which I believe he renamed it to
Underdog OG cuz he originally thought it
was Da recer
Loompa headband part of the problem is
that Loompa like loali the old man who
who ran the company for a bit he would
make different names for different
Brokers and different different
customers but it was the same the it was
all the same it was all the same so to
some people it would be the underdog OG
to other people it would be Loompa
headband to other people it might be so
that's what makes it confusing is that
people like to name things what makes
their life easier for sale well the same
thing happens in Amsterdam or you know
when I used to go in Amsterdam you'd go
from one coffee shop to another and they
all had the
Haze but it was labeled something else
something else yeah you
know story yeah just Intero we got packs
of you know some friends not me you know
they got you know they imported wheat
also from Netherlands you know and on
the packs normally it was written this
was the early days man this is really
the first KS that we saw and it's a
certain place in Slovenia where they had
this import at the time they had the
connection somehow they imported a lot
of it so in the packs was written NL and
all of us everybody was thinking it's
Netherlands the Netherlands but not
after years we came to the idea that
that was Northern Lights actually you
know we don't know which one but it was
Northern Lights you know most potent
[ __ ] in that time you know it was
unbelievable you know stroke you know I
want you to talk about that Shiva is it
Shiva skunk or Shiva Shanti or just
Shiva we call it Shiva SK and also you
now after the podcast that we had you
know came to me and he brought the old
catalog uhuh we were looking through it
and it's the Shiva skunk picture looks
like this plant when it's
finished really yeah it's like like w
that's it that's the one actually you
know which like so similar that I was I
was bluffed you know I was like no way
man yeah
yeah Shiva skunk sincey renamed it when
Neville sold it under his brand and his
company it was called big skunk mhm and
it was Big Bud by Skunk
one and then sensey re sensey didn't
really want people to realize that they
just bought Neville's company and just
sold all his same seeds so they changed
not all but most of the names
right so like big skunk became Shiva
skunk nl5 nl5 by Skunk one became Shiva
Shanti nl2 became Hindu Kush okay very
good you know they just kept they kept
and what was weird about it though is
that the drunkers were lazy and they
kept this a lot of times they kept the
same pictures yeah from Neville's
earlier cataloges and they even kept
some of the same verbiage in the
descriptions they just made made it
shorter so you have a do you still have
it do you you have a you have a nice
Shiva yeah of course that is talk about
it tell us about it for a bit oh my God
you know uh it before in the other
podcast but I will tell you the story
again maybe now because it's the same
story actually but I called Lucky in
Slovenia he was a legend in sense of
Hardcore punks scene here you know he
was a guy that didn't care even one one
guy you know a friend of mine told me
now yeah that is the Gabby that is the
picture of the cut yesterday I how it
looks now in this
moment
sweet in 97 from
Amsterdam and lucky was one guy that
never stopped partying so he studied and
not he studied 10 years before me he
went to lubl that was end of the ' 80s
okay he was a roommate of a guy that uh
of wheat in Yugoslavia times and um that
we dealer quit dealing so he got access
to his customers he started to deal with
uh but he was also uh because he was so
crazy after the war you know in Slovenia
we were open for traveling so he could
go everywhere so he traveled and he went
to of course to Amsterdam you know in '
93 94 he was in Amsterdam and then you
know 95 or 97 he went again you know he
went many times but in 97 he brought
this cot back home and he was like he
tell us like guy that I know he told him
also that he had a cup in his jacket
with water prepared and it he caught
from that plant and he stole it actually
you know he stole it he nicked few that
time I don't know if you can realize
that not many people understand that if
you cut a branch of a plant and stick it
in a cup with water you can actually for
2 3 days you can drive around with it
and you can still root
it 100% yeah well that's what he did he
went with it from Amsterdam to lublana
and he had a indoor uh already there you
know because he was already growing
indoors after I don't know you know he
bought a judge pass to be on the high
times conam cops he went from coffee
shop to Coffee Shop you know to test
wheat but somehow maybe he got in some
we body together from the scene and he
was so crazy you know so interesting
also for those guys because there were
not so many people from Yugoslavia at
that time traveling you know or even
Slovenia because we were a new country
at that moment you know right
independent Slovenia we were in the news
the Balkan War continued in Croatia they
had really big war and Bosnia after and
Kosovo after and it was a bloody long
War so but but the Shiva the Shiva came
because luy was not only growing the
Shiva you know he bought seeds you know
in that times already in the '90s he had
a really selection of different strains
from from the '90s from Amsterdam and
they make make mother plants and they
cut they cut from those mod plants and
they repeated the the product you know
he wanted to standardize standard you
know station that you have all the time
the same product for the market lime
breeding lime breed you no he was not
really breeding they were just the the
seat making a mom from the elction
cloning it that's it so rather than
rather than growing a bunch of seed no
they didn't he would pick he would pick
a feno he would pick a feno and then
make a bunch of clones so he would have
a consistent crop that would all be the
same looking thing yes yes and the story
is that there was skunk number one which
was there with also with him 11 number
16 one was very piny the number 16 was
absolutely [ __ ] Piney you know like
the pinest plant ever that I smoked in
my life in the beginning and the number
11 was sweet and it was like wow it
looks like a sativa but it fled like a
Inda it had almost no leaves I mean it
has Lea very thin you know like a like a
sativa is but he has Inda flowers so
very interesting plant you know you know
for some other plants that we have in
the shops at that time in the two early
2000s you know I will asked me not so
before was siny star from Paradise
seats that one man is a legend in
Austria it's also a legend in Slovenia
because a lot of people grow for Rick
Simpson Oil here so when they start to
grow uh everybody knew that this plant
this material the biomass will give you
two times more oil than a normal normal
it was so it was so potent you know it
was so does it still exist
there maybe it does you know if I will
say no now there will be I hope no it
not exist now somebody should write in
the comments yes we still have it you
know yeah we still have it I think P has
it but the last time I got it you know
uh in condition that I would say that
was good we didn't know about H hop PL
and ra virus at that time or something
you know but I realized because I grew
it so long time you know and many others
did a lot long time years for the same
cut so you you know when you we talk
Master of the plant you know of growing
you know may be master of growing of a
particular phenotype a cut that you have
for many years that can be you can not
even be a master you can have you know a
really good recipe for it yeah yeah so
you get close you get close to the to
the ideal situation that you can to the
best end product is possible
I I talk about
thatal I talk about that all the time
actually I have like my own funny
analogy on it where I feel like each
strain I have is like a this might sound
weird but like is like a girlfriend
right and so it's like this living
female and I need to figure out a way to
make it happy right and like you can't
treat sometimes you have you have
something and you treat it you treat
this new thing the way you treated the
old thing that made the old thing really
happy and the new one isn't as happy and
so I really do feel like when you grow
different clones you have to build
relationships with them yes you have to
figure out like how they like to be fed
how they like to be grown how much light
they like to have and so you really have
to get to
know right and like to what you're
talking about like to get the kind of
phenotypic expression you want yes you
know like you have to know how to treat
her mhm and in order to get her to
express in the way that you're after and
so I almost feel like with most
strains it's like the first couple times
you grow it you're just winging it you
know and then if you pay attention you
start to learn things that make her
happy or make her unhappy and you can
sort of adjust what you do based on that
and it's very similar to like being in a
relationship with someone you know
because you have to you know if you want
want what you want you you have to
figure out a way to keep them happy keep
them you know cuz you can make them real
upset too you know and that's the only
way I I have a question for Francis huh
so that's P polyamory right polyamory I
mean yeah I you know I just look at it
as as plants but that's the thing is is
that I I mean obviously I'm not like
engaging in any kind of those activities
with them but it's uh you know like
canis love your plan
well it it well I just meant the love
factor and I you know I wanted to know
if the love Factor matters but it's also
like you can love something and still
really screw it up oh yeah you know and
cannabis you know cannabis like they
require very different things sometimes
like you know not you have to screw it
up because if you don't make mistakes
you never learn it yeah you don't learn
no you have to make the you have to make
the mistakes mistakes are so important
you know like without mistakes I mean
you don't do any there is a old saying
in my country where it say uh that are
without mix mistakes they are not
working yeah I mean a lot of times like
I wor I worked with Gabby at Gabby's
shop which we gave a ton of advice back
in the day and it was like you hear so
many of the same mistakes over and over
and over again that just like life
probably half of growing is just
avoiding any way you [ __ ] up or you've
seen other people [ __ ] up right like a
lot of life is just avoiding
screw-ups you know by what you've seen
and learned and you see some screw up
and you're like oh man I never want to
see that again that is not but but the
diagnostic must be there you know you
have to know what you did wrong in the
end if you did something wrong you have
to analyze it and they say oh that why
not that you [ __ ] up and then you don't
know why and you make the same mistake
again that's not how you how you do you
have to solve the problem you know what
you have to solve the problem you have
to figure out a way to do it but
normally it's like that if you are quite
focused on the thing that you do I mean
I mean you up you know it's like yeah if
you meet someone like let's say let's
say you and I were talking and you gave
me a strain like say the Shiva yes
because you've had a long relationship
ship with her you could tell me a lot
about what she likes and don't likes and
how to grow how big to get her does she
like to be to does she not all these
different little things that might take
me multiple years of growing her to
slowly figure out you could be like hey
I've I've grown this strain a long time
right here's what I've learned about
things she likes and dislikes and then
that person has like a huge Head Start
mhm because they don't have to
observationally make her happy make her
upset figure out why they can just learn
from your mistakes you know you know
what a clear example of that is is just
flowering height like what height should
you flower this plant at right yeah you
know like if someone if someone just
tells you that simple thing like hey if
you flowered at this height it's going
to get to this if you know that was like
a you know because we were trying to
figure it out and then we'd wait too
long and then the plant would be like 8
feet tall and not wanting to stop you
know so or we had this or we had this
strain a long time ago called the purple
Urkel right and it barely grew like the
slowest plant on Earth to grow plant
imaginable I know that so you kind of
had to grow it to get to be two or three
or four feet tall before you flipped it
because if you flipped it small it would
grow like that much and and like and
you'd be like oh my God have this like
Rinky Dink little thing where there's
other strains there's other strains that
you could flip them that big and they'd
get they'd grow another two or three
feet and Branch out and like and be so I
mean I'm I'm a really big proponent of
that of like you need to learn your
plants what makes them happy what makes
them
unhappy that's a that's a big part of it
well so yeah Nursery like are there are
there any practice that you found where
you're like I really have to do these
certain things to make sure that I
preserve some of these older genetics
health because it sounds like some of
the stuff that you have is at least like
20 years old and so yeah doing anything
special to keep their their health uh
for example two examples we talked about
the plank and the Shiva cut those are
the oldest Cuts in my facility right cut
is very very hard to keep uh perfect
shape to you know it has this you need
to to know about Trace
elements and you need to renew the mom
in every 3 months then you have a really
perfect cut with this particular strain
for me it's really hard to grow it for 6
months in a small container as a
mom which I do normally with other
plants yeah until 6 months we can keep
them in 11 lit container with for
production of clones
we have
a o we are feeding K
nutrients K nutrients is uh you know
I've been uh we do we did a lot of
different uh nutrients in the past a lot
kind of brand you could imagine you know
try it out we did it the thing is the
like me say organic products that are
certified that are not using animal
products uh like you know uh fermented
uhal matter and then know the best one
of your country is dragonfly Earth
medicine I think you know countries
there is all others but we don't have a
so specific for cannabis you know some
like nutrients from my guys from
Slovenia there's young guys you know
they still development in development
but they are successful and good Mater
it's good what they have but in my
facility I cannot use those products in
that sense because it's a you know
organic product ini container under
artificial light artificial
environment who is who is uh you know uh
with himself here you know I'm not uh
like what's the purpose of going the
purpose is to grow outside with those
things it's a really good for growing
outside and in green houses you know
when you put it in soil it's really good
but Caron nutrients for example have
been there since I've been a young for
Canabis is that Holland that is Holland
yeah yeah and this
class is Der Clen Clen yeah so traveling
around you know Europe all and I mean
it's a big company today right K it's a
really huge company that uh lines of
different uh you know for uh uh uh for
aquaone for Hydroponics right the
science behind it it's all there did
this totally and in Austria they are
really strong also they're supportive
also and we use now because also of the
trace elements because the thing is when
you grow for a long time in closed
containers plastic containers can feed
uh sometime with uh P you know with
nitrogen phosphor and
[ __ ] but uh uh
iron zinc sulfur Mangan mipan uh other
Trace elements start to here your moms
uh start to die so you have to feed
those Trace elements to be aware about
the water we have a luck here because we
have really good quality of water all
Slovenia and also of part of
Austria austri is also really good water
it's drinkable from the tap
so the plants like to drink it
too on where you live but the water is
really really good with my facility you
know it's it sounds a little bit
primitive but we grow it on soil on
light mix we use light mix and we are
the masters of the recipe which soil
it's it's like a Peete based formula
right based formula also containing
perlite yeah yeah yeah yeah but also you
know Kaa has its own uh you know if you
want to go pro you can go you know if
you want you can you know but others too
you know I have I will not name All
Brands now but you know cono for me is
one of those brands that is stable and
they know uh they sell those few
products that I have in line they don't
have like this 20 bottles of one line of
one you know how can I sell this to a
customer I try to sell it also to people
also to explain to them why some certain
stuff is good for them you know
why do you use the we call it in America
do you use the bio can like the organic
version I used to use bio but now I use
K Tera and K Aqua for the when the mom
when the mom gets older I Ka
Aqua okay m is Young and you build up
the mom kind of kind of line so me and a
NATO dog we used to sell the canaline
were one of the I think it was first
seven sores in the US so we're familiar
with them I believe the
canera is designed for use in a
fortified soil yes because they they
sold canera soil as well they still do
and I'm experimenting right now with
that you know I have kind of oil a
little bit I bought now to see if it you
know you have to try it I also I always
tell to people that you need to try
certain things out I also not I'm not a
God I cannot know if it's good or not
until I tried it and I I tested it and
then I see the results and you know what
I mean I tried it on my mom's here you
know so I'm not going to flower stage
and everything but that's the other
stuff you know I'm not I'm business in
Austria I sell clones in you know we
produce 10,000 clones a month now and in
in the season when the when uh May and
June we produce 20,000 clones a
month because we are retailers sale is
well how much like you you're producing
10,000 and not in dollars in clones so
you're prod producing 10,000 clones a
month and are you selling them one at a
time 10 at a time I have many shops you
know I Supply a lot of shops in
Austria a lot of there is a lot of shops
and most of these people for example I
live on a very uh rural area and the the
square meter that I pay for the facility
that a rent is very low cost for me you
know not it's not low cost but it's
reasonable price let me tell you that
but if you live in Vienna or if you live
in salsburg or Lind or Gratz on these
bigger cities the square meter is like
four times or five times more expensive
that for me to produce the
Clones mhm because you have if it's not
your uh if you don't own the place you
have to pay rent and the rent will kill
kill you with the with you know with
electricity you need helpers you know
people who you know you cannot have only
friends that come to your place and they
will help you out you not employees this
is a legal business so the the
government wants to have taxes from it
and that's what they are having and it's
fair people buy CBD plants there is a
lot of CBD production also you know do a
lot of CBD plans for Australian Market I
mean two years ago our our company
produced almost 880,000 880,000 CBD
plants yeah and CBG CBD CBG in a very
big
facility uh so but we have this smaller
facility now which is our library from
that Library we have this CBD strain
that we produced in 880,000 we have now
like three
months you know because theand is not
there there is a lot of other strains
coming but this particular train is very
good because it's a stabilized producing
product for for example we sell to
Croatia to a certain farmer that
produces CBD and
CBG High you know it's like 12% CBD 03
THC and he produces it in Dalmatia in
delmia Coast near
dnik the guy has also one of the bests
around dorik he like he's like wow yeah
you know and this guy also everything he
puts on the table is a quality product
so he wants clones for production of his
CBD and CBG oils which we also produce
for him and it's like places where we
can export to Croatia but not THC clones
that's not he has a permit for CBD and
CBG clones that we can produce for him
and that we produce and then we we sell
them to him and also it's like you know
as I said in the last podcast I have a
European passport for plant but I can
sell to companies that have the permit
yeah or to Germany to a hom grower now
from April
yeah which is really good you know the
it's like it's going Market here is like
opening up now it's it's like it's
starting you know this it's 10 years
already right it sounds like your orders
go from like anywhere from one to two
plants all way up to a thousand at yeah
yeah mhm for example PL to plant of
course yeah they come mhm grandmothers
and
grandfathers it's like that I cannot
talk about it flowering when people come
to me in the in the shop and normally
people understand it they just say which
one is best asking for a bong yeah no
they they asking for plans but I'm not
the one who will tell anything that
would be illegal for them to do
you understand one time you know I
assume that it was uh there were
police and they came into the shop the
first thing what they were asking me
have something for
smoke there was never a customer in the
last 6 years that would ask me that he
could get something to
smoke what you know and then this lady
went to this to this plant and she asked
you know when I flower this I want to
smoke you know it was so obvious it was
for me like pissing Against the Wind and
smelling a policeman you know like like
you know if you see the police call a
brother you know but you will not fool
me you know like I have a very good
relation to the police I have because we
don't we don't do anything illegal now
but that was time you know they come to
check you which is actually legi you
know they come to check if you're
selling drugs actually my mom uh is a
cancer patient Survivor and she cured
her uh three times having cancer on her
womb and on her left breast and then
after a few years on her right breast
and the last time when she had breast
cancer she said she will not take any
chemotherapy any any whatsoever and we
made Rick Simpson Oil for her and she's
still alive today it's like 15 years
uh she still takes a little bit oil yeah
you know she still takes the oil and
people know her about you know everybody
say she's rbo like she's like a rbo you
know she is John rbo you know my mom you
know like yeah that's what she is she's
ramble she's a bad talking about the
cops coming in is cops going into like
like I said that you could only buy
water pipes in head shops back in the
day when it was still you know cops
would come in undercover and they would
be like I want to buy a bong what's the
best one that's going to give me the
best hit like what a they would try to
trip people up and get them talking
about it so they could get them to admit
that it was for like a purpose that then
the cop could be like oh you're not
that's not
allowed you
know there two things I want to say
about that
so first a quick story in New York City
you could ask for a bong at the smoke
shop you
know nobody cared you could say whatever
you want I moved to California and I
went to this head shop it's called The
Mighty Quinn in Santa
Rosa and first thing I do when I arrive
I go to the head shop and I asked the
guy for a bong and he literally freaks
out oh he like freaks out you know and I
mean I just didn't know you know there
were signs saying these are water pipes
but I've called it a bong you know so
far all my life I didn't know so the guy
freaks
out and you know then I learn the
program and I just say waterpipe but
then I see him at every single Grateful
Dead show that I've ever been to in
California right always smoking weed M
and this is I mean man this is over 30
years ago I still go to the same smoke
shop and the same guy he doesn't own the
place he was like one of the main
workers he still worked there till till
just recently and I would tell all the
staff that works there yeah this guy he
used to freak out on me if I come in
here an Asom now they don't care now
it's like it it doesn't matter but back
then and they all you know they all
laugh the other thing is it was the same
thing at the grow stores because after
operation green Merchant yeah so when
you went to a grow store back in the day
you definitely didn't say you were
growing weed you know people would say
yeah I want to grow tomatoes I me you
know you
would they would a lot of the grow
stores would sell
seeds like
flowers but I mean like I'm talking like
like yeah like not not can seeds but I I
just mean like you would often buy seeds
they would recommend that you buy some
flower seeds or some you know brussels
sprouts or some this or some that or
whatever because you had to have a
purpose for why you were growing this
growing this you know buying this grow
equipment or whatever and then even then
like when I when I first started growing
we hired a friend
who was totally safe and was down to do
it and they would drive us to the store
in their car because the cops would
record your license plate to figure out
who you were sometimes so you had to
like you had to have someone else bring
you there because if they would write
your license plate down they could find
where the grow
was you know so it was sketch in that
regard you kind of had to you know the
first like uh Gabby knows what I'm
talking about but there was this store
called The Brew and Grow in the Midwest
and they they had a robust amount of you
know actual flour you know like lies and
this and that like tons of different
flower seeds and tons of different like
herbs and and and vegetables and stuff
and you would always buy packs of seeds
with your purchase because you
needed purchased so it's like oh what
are you going to grow this with what are
you going to choose and then so you
spend whatever five or 10 bucks extra on
some random packs of seeds so that you
had like a
reason you had a reason to buy the grow
light and the table you know for
your how many pounds of cherry tomatoes
do you think I can grow under this
thousand oo you know a lot of these
places you know a lot of grow stores
honestly they were
rare the information they had was rare
they could get hassled and there was
this cat and mouse game of of like the
owner would try to tell the buyer as
much as he could without getting in
trapped or in trouble you know because
people didn't know what they were doing
and so they would come in and they'd be
like I want to grow but I don't know
what to buy I don't know how it all goes
together I don't know the system you
know and like you said there wasn't
internet or anything like that or it was
very young still and so even just
figuring out the basics for a lot of
people was new fris when uh when you and
I were working at the Garden spout
that's exactly what was happening right
people were coming in and saying I want
to grow but like back then we were able
to actually give people I'll tell I'll
tell a funny story it's very brief but
because Gabby and I like when when you
worked at the grow store it was kind of
like in a way it was sort of like Gabby
owned a porn shop or something like that
where it was like I'm dead serious you
know like you would see people you would
see people in the grocery store that
absolutely would not want the public to
know that they shopped with you they
would give you fake names or nicknames
because they didn't want the grow store
to know their real name and so sometimes
you're in this little ass town in meno
and you're like rolling down the aisle
of the grocery store and you want to say
hey to somebody and they're with their
buddies or their family and they do not
want those people to know that they shop
with you or even where they know you
from right and you might just know their
nickname or whatever name they decided
to give you you know for the store and
it might not be at all their real name
or what other people call them so on
occasion there would be some awkward
unintentionally awkward stuff because
people did not want to get in trouble
they didn't want to get busted they
didn't want their family to know what
they were doing maybe or their friends
or maybe they had a regular job that it
wasn't cool to do what they were doing
and so we knew about their secret life
and they did not want everyone to know
about their secret life you
know brother there is there is still one
customer that comes to my place he's
from Hungaria Hungary and he comes over
the border from Hungaria and he never
buys clones but he always buys seeds you
know at my shop he has a mask all the
time you I know his eyes I never in his
face ever because he start to come to my
place when there was Corona virus
epidemia you know pandemic you know
everything was close so when he came
first time he already had the mask so he
kept this mask I don't you know he's buy
he's never bought plants but he buying
seeds but he's still keeping the mask
when he comes to our shop even today
when there is no more restance or
nothing because you know like you know
but this guy is like so for for him is
like when he comes he wants to finish it
in 5 minutes you know like what you have
uh I want actually I want something for
you but I want to get out of here as
soon as possible that is like you know
keep his mask on when he drives away
yeah yeah with a
mask in the car by
himself it's crazy you know it's still
here like this but it's you know Hungary
is a different place uh for cannabis law
it's really strict where restrict even
we are in the European Union but
Slovenia will legalize soon and Germany
has already legalized and other other
countries will follow definitely I mean
there is Luxembourg that only they all
can grow for a few years now and Malta
that can grow for a few years now Spain
has so
many I mean Spain is not legal but it's
it was always in Spain like this I
traveled with Bobble backs that was the
story from maybe before we want to tell
you bubble bags for the ice waterer hush
it was in the early 2000s I traveled
with this in Andalusia which is the
place where normally the Moroccan hash
comes in you know it's very near Morocco
so these guys not have a really old hash
culture they are not they at that time
they were not used to smoke flowers so
much because I know you know we had some
flower and they were like wow somebody
has flower you know like we will smoke
marijuana you know like and that it's
like okay but um the hash what they got
of course is all from Morocco but I have
these bags and I told them what I have
so one guy of those guys had a because
in in Spain even today I think and in
all this time also you have this law you
cannot go inside in somebody's house
because it's his
privacy so every they have this Henda
you know which is like a inner Garden
always from outside always walls but
when you enter in Spain a traditional
house for in the south of Spain in
Andalusia you will always see a you know
a garden inside and uh you know uh you
know normally it's a garden for for
shadow and people can have R there and
their own privacy but of course these
guys were growing cannabis as much you
can you know like even today um and they
have clones which they put out
and they start to flower first because
they were putting them out too early in
the season so the light was too you know
so they start to flower but then they
reved you know revegetation they made
these strange mutations la la la and
after 3 weeks they start to to put out
the vegetative state again and you know
they came and uh I said to them cut all
of these undeveloped you know uh fresh
BTS that are there cut it from the
plants because they will they will have
you know also the for the plant is good
to do that you know to you know to cut
the nails you know what I mean so she
can yeah so she can uh perform like she
should uh so there was a lot of this
biom material with a lot of crystals on
it it was in July you know so we made
ice water har for them there in
Malaga and they you know those people
were traditional in hash their father
and their grandfather already smoked
hash you know that's how integrated they
are has smoke has smokers and the the
the culture for harush is there so when
I make the Bobble hash and they saw it
and they tried it they said it's like
z00 yeah they call it z00 quality this
is like the the hash that you would
normally get you cannot get it because
Moroccans normally don't import z0 it is
for it is for the
family keep going down the farther away
from the farm it gets there's commercial
stuff that's made and there's the top
level yeah so so bubble has of course
didn't have this Aroma that were used to
normally from the from the dry sift poll
pollination of har traditionally you
know they beat it you know in Morocco
it's it's not gravity it falls so yeah
so it's like uh different flavor but it
was so strong for
them they say is like man that is and I
show them the bags and you know and of
course that was like bubble man you know
uh and and Mila of course before him
that you know with the with the the
extraction but bubbleman had so many
different grades of the of the silks you
know different screens so many you know
Moroccan hash typically
made well I mean where you were
traveling you know in Spain
andish they call it hashish dry sift
it's hash hashish dry sift they call it
po
Moroccan
poen because you can break it with your
it's like very Brownie and you can break
it apart very easily it's like caca you
know like yeah you have you know like
this it's like and it's very tasty and
it's not strong the poen you know poang
is really like the day smoke but then
the really black that I have of uh time
and in in in that time you know like
there was like I was a Street Music mus
with a friend of mine we were traveling
I was playing DJ redo and he was playing
drums uh on the streets with me and we
were earning money like this you know to
survive on the streets you know just to
travel you know not well not uh having
bad time we having we are a tourist but
we were tourist on that kind of that we
are connecting to the street people
there you know we having our own show
with music and we're connect with the
locals and there were guys from South
America some Colombian girls from you
know beautiful girls you know like wow
we had a really good time we spend
really good time in Spain you know this
was months man before I returned home to
my studies again you know uh it was it
was like that but the the the thing I
saw there you know because in the
beginning when I come there me and my
friend get some hash and we were like
trying to roll a joint on the you know
somewhere in the sea we eat something
then we old guy came you know old
fisherman and he's with his Moto bike
and he came and you were like hiding
first oh okay somebody came and that guy
was like more than 60 years old you know
like hiding our joint and so and then we
saw that he eat something and then after
that he start to make a joint in his
hand because Spanish people they always
make joints in the hand they make the
hashish and they rub it into the tobacco
or they rub it into the tobacco so they
how they they smoke Kish with tobacco so
that is Europeans do that you know but
they really Rob the hash into the day
like like massaging it into it you know
and this 60-year-old guy made a hash
joint there in front of us and we were
like watching each other like are we
[ __ ] idiots you know like if this guy
is smoking like that and then of course
we we saw that guys are smoking joints
in the street the police walks by nobody
cares nobody watch this that was in that
time today of course we have these
Social Clubs you have everywhere around
Spain and canari islands and everywhere
you have these social clubs a lot of
wheat has been bred there um like a lot
of uh seed companies that you think that
they are in-house production it's not
it's from Spain from closets from houses
from I don't know what kind of places
you know maybe I won't tell anything
because I assume that it's like that I
don't know but I assume because of uh
many years of experience you know uh
yeah and there is uh for example seed uh
banks that pop up you know every day
here that is like just having a few
strains now you know just like we popped
up we have like five strains and nobody
even heard about them ever there is some
random pics you know some you see that
it's white label actually when you ask
them is it light label seed banks come
to your shop and um he try to sell to
your shop that you would resell them
yeah so normally I ask those kind of
seed banks uh do you label you know
normally they say it's not white label
but we buy from friends from Spain no
it's white label you know that's white
label that's right you know what I mean
yeah I believe uh heres is um centered
in Spain is that correct have you heard
before and then same with uh attitude
right attitude attitude seat Bank yes
yes yes they move there because uh
genetics from um original Sensible Seeds
have you heard that original Sensible
Seeds yes I think it's all white label
though cuz they had a bunch of stuff
like I I got their Bruce Banner which
you know as we know Bruce Banner is
actually from Darkhorse and everything
and I actually still have the plant to
this day it was just a phenomenal plant
but it wasn't you know exactly um you
know it wasn't the Bruce braner strain
it was just their combination of the
genetics but um everything I've grown
from you know what I I've got from
Spanish companies were it were all
excellent genetics mhm do you guys know
G proof I'm familiar I don't know him
very well but I know who he is
yeah yeah for example I got uh clink you
know some people ask me already for some
of his trains here but in some time
Spanish resellers you could get his gear
but now it's almost impossible there is
the same thing for DJ Short seats we
could get them at a certain point of
time now it's impossible the old world
genetics that he has now or DJ Short
label that he has can get it you know
from American genetics what we can get
here you know from the from it is few
seat Banks but mostly it is like you
know we look to America and you look to
Europe you know what I mean you want our
strength we want your strs you know it
is a very funny situation actually right
because I I want your clones you want
mine clones actually it's like I would
like to try them because it's so
different from that what I know you know
I was talking with Gabby about Amnesia
core cut you know it is all around
Austria almost every second shop has
this cut so common here Amnesia the
super silver ha cut you know we feel the
same way like with Canada because
obviously there's a border and it's
different countries and so there's a lot
of communication now between Canada and
America with all the podcasting and all
the forums and IG and all that but
there's still a bunch of stuff up there
that people are interested in and stuff
that's down here that they're interested
in that borders just make it tough you
know cannabis isn't free you know it's
not it's not free moving it still has
issues and stuff like that and so
there's Pockets where yeah you look over
and you're like oh what do these people
have what's survived what's good over
there you know and um you know and then
all that stuff to me is like with all
the changes and legalization
like it's still hard to hold on to stuff
it just changes the reasons why because
right now it's like I would say in
California or America in general there's
this phrase purple candy gas which is
like you want purple weed that smells
kind of candish but has some gassy OG
notes and that sort of dominates
everything it's it's people are people
get it's tough to there isn't like a
repository yet where people can just
like store old strains and come back to
them you know like you every time
there's a huge like wave of popularity
in something you risk a lot of other
diversity just being lost you know
because people want to grow it's easy to
move yeah people want to grow what
Brokers want people want to grow what
the market wants and you
know huh you know what else happened
Francis when hop vroid came around a lot
of people got rid of their
genetics and didn't attempt to save it
you know using maram or they said oh
this plant's sick I got to get rid of it
and I wonder how many genetics we lost
that way of just like in the H in the
Cannabis Community hop Leon was like our
AIDS by the time that people realized it
was a problem it was all over the place
and people saw things plants getting
sick and issues happening but they
didn't know why they didn't know what
was causing it they didn't know what the
transmission was like so how to stop
it but uh can you can you tell me that
it was the damping effect you can just
see how a wildfire goes through a
facility with a damping it is like that
because I never saw that you know it's
like you know we test but uh for for us
we are lucky on this moment what we
trying to to prepare for what you know
like you know what mean like back when
Gabby and I first became friends you
would just take a razor blade or a pair
of scissors and you would just cut off
whatever plant you wanted until the
razor got dirty you never considered
anything like that and now I would say
once now that we've learned how hop
Laton works it's almost a little bit
like getting a tattoo where like each
plant needs a fresh blade or sterilized
blade or scissors and there's various
techniques you can do but that wasn't
the standard in cannabis so like when it
was starting to spread people were just
taking the same dirty scissors or the
same dirty razor and cutting dozens of
different plants and plugging them and
not realizing that they were spreading
it and then what really messed us up is
that people started buying clones from
nurseries so instead of just like
growing their own moms in their own
houses and so once it got into a nursery
that Nursery might sell it to thousands
of customers for years before they even
realized they had a problem and now
they're taking steps to make it not that
way but when it was spreading the first
four or five years it was percolating
around nobody was taking any steps black
heart Nursery out of Harbor dark heart
Nursery out a and then selling out of
harbor side that was like the the
epidemic and then they're like for sure
I'll be right back again gentlemen my
kids are calling hold
on noise yeah yeah so when the plants
got sick before they knew it was hop
latent they might have thrown it away
because the plant was just growing
shitty and then after when they knew it
was hop lant a lot of people destroyed
plants because they were just going to
go move on to something else that wasn't
sick that's how a lot of genetics were
lost I think you know
so
but we could have saved them we could
have saved them with them yeah today
it's actually you know that could you
can yeah I know that you do uh marem
extraction right I mean you you you do
it right yeah yeah so I mean um and it's
all because of hlvd you know earlier
this year um you know I was informed
about this clone company and you know
initially we thought it was okay and so
I I placed a big
order and um I got the order and you
know after talking with the community
and you know people recommending I test
it I said you know let's just take the
step further we'll get it tested and lo
and behold four out of the 12 you know
were U Were positive and so um I'm
sitting there freaking out like oh [ __ ]
dude like I just spent at least a grand
on on these plants and now I got to
throw them out and so you know I had it
quarantined the whole time um I threw
out those four I waited another two
weeks and I retested and another you
know four popped positive and so I was
like you know [ __ ] like this is crazy
like all my hard work um after these
years of feno hunting and selecting
these strains that I wanted to work with
you know they're all in Jeopardy because
I have these you know these sick plants
in you know inside my room of course
they're quarantining in their own
separate tent and everything like that
but I ended up throwing all those out
but it really didn't sit well with me
you know and um that kind of started me
on my path of learning about you know um
how can you save a plant that's infected
with you know a disease you know cuz as
we know it's not just hlvd but it could
be you know uh ferium or any of the
other you know fungal infections and
everything like that and
detrimental to the plant I mean we're
the the the the positive thing is one
day we're going to get to a point where
we're going to be able to trade a lot
more freely maybe among states and
countries and stuff like that with a lot
less risk the downside of that is that
we're going to definitely end up having
that continue and there's going to be
way more risk of pathogens fungal
diseases thyroids spreading around which
may be localized and then they're just
going to end up all over and just like
hop Lon there could be something right
now percolating around that people don't
know about and is unidentified it's not
like hop latent is the last it's
probably just the
first I def I treat like I have a bunch
of moms and stuff like that I treat my
moms like I'm a tattoo artist right
where every single plant gets its own
sterilized scissors or razor or gear I
try to take all these different steps to
like
prevent transmission and even though I
don't have it I think I assume I do yeah
that's how you have to treat your faity
I assume like I do you know so you know
I mean it just is uh it's it it's crappy
because yeah I um I can't see tried to
Glory because of how wet it is and um I
need to actually kind of attend to this
um I have several different samples in
there that I'm going to be kind of
taking out and you know uh putting into
their own containers and everything like
that but um this one I started uh
probably about the end of August and it
was all from Mary stems so um you know
can you show people what a fresh stem
looks like so they can see how much
that's grown it's tiny it's like a it's
like a sliver it's like a speck of yeah
right because you know most most people
look at that go that's just a little
plants growing in there but they don't
realize that came from virtually nothing
you know like he has to do these
cuttings under a
microscope so here's one from the
seventh sorry I have a little bit it's a
little dirty here let me see if
I so just right there it's from the sth
it's tiny yeah yeah so that's what
almost 20 days you know so it's tiny and
I have to use a microscope I work in
front of a laminar Flo hood you know to
make sure it's you know as sterile of an
environment that I could work because
you know um as far as the media that
you're using in here if there's any
specs of um yeah anything it'll take off
you know so you have to have a um
sterile area of working and um for
micropropagation you know uh as Gabby
he's talked about before you know um you
work with essentially a still air box
and it's not you know a perfect still a
box because you don't have like the the
gloves in it but um I don't think that
you could do the same with Mary stem I
think Mary Sim definitely would require
a
flood just the contact time alone you're
working with it for longer than a
smaller cutting mhm yeah I feel like
I've
got definitely quicker at it um and I
can extract a Mary Simmon I'd say
anywhere from five to 10 minutes you
know so but that's still a long time if
you're not sitting there in front of the
flo
Hood but actually it's great that we
it's it's coming this age where hom
Growers will also do uh marem extraction
or noal maybe at home you know what I
mean that that we have a possibility
that you know there is systems out there
that uh allow you to do that you know
this small you know one came in out from
this guy from American guy right uh
Graham yeah I mean crazy that's crazy
you know that's wow I have I have photos
and I'm going to share them in this
video of tissue culture that I did with
his kit and and it works and you know
the one thing about noal tissue culture
is um while it may not remove
virus you have clean clones of like
mildew and bugs and so like if you know
everyone that shared a plant with me
throughout the years had given me a
plant grown even with nodal tissue
culture that would have saved me a lot
of headaches from I mean got spidermites
countless times from people sharing
plants with people minus the whole thing
but I definitely think it has its
uses abely I would say another huge one
especially from all of us you know
enthusiasts who love every single strain
we come across or you know just without
but um the fact that I've had this in a
dish and then you know now in in this
container for uh what what are we
looking at like 3 months or so like the
ability to keep your genetics on a shelf
without having to worry about the SP
that the mom plant takes up or feeding
it even like I just let it sit there and
chill and once it gets big enough you
know I I'll move it to a different
container and I'm getting ready my my
next plan actually this week um
especially like with this bigger one
that's kind of yellowing a little bit on
the leaves I'm going to cut that one off
of the little um callus at the bottom
and Transplant it to another container
that I'm going to prepare with some uh
plant growth Regulators so everything
that far it has plant growth Regulators
at all this is all just agar sugar and
uh M&amp;S or you know I always [ __ ] up the
name it's like miraga and scoy or so
actually you you do your own agar you
mix your own agars for the purpose
whether you let it grow or you related
to root right right but I mean he
doesn't put
hormones he's not he's not putting so
one thing that I you know like CU not so
you know he has concerns about it right
yeah he told in one podcast I wanted to
ask him about this
conern yeah yeah I wonder if you have
concerns if you knew he's not using
hormones like those plants are basically
growing in water and
sugar you know so
like I I think that kind of addresses a
lot of your concerns so here I um I have
to deal with this today or but look at
all the roots coming out of this one
like there's no hormones in that at all
like this is going to be quite the for
me to
untangle but like like barely even any
green growth at the top you know like
it's kind of hard to see that on the
camera but just look at all the
we yeah that's insane and again no
hormones at all that's just the plant
doing you know what it does with the
hormones already in in that
like everything you you mentioned about
like storing genetics and having them
grow slowly and having them be healthy
and having them not take as much space
up I like a whole bunch I will say my
experience has been and I think
meristem is it's obviously expensive and
timec consuming for most people I do
think it cleans up like pesticides or
herbicides or you know different things
that might have been like sprayed on the
plant it doesn't seem to me sadly that
marem solves The Hop latent issue you
know or at least I've
heard plenty of failure you know like
when it comes to like thinking that that
was going to be the Cure and I have I do
think like with any I don't want to say
it's new technology but like new to
cannabis I worked in a a farm in Santa
Barbara where we got about 880,000
uh tissue culture clones and they had
been treated with some kind of hormone
okay and so when we grew them all out we
planted them in our beds and we grew out
Acres of them and they all threw male
balls like multiple times like I'm
talking I had the head guy I won't say
the company name because that would me
mean but I had the head grower visit the
farm and he was like I want to see how
bad this male problem is right and so he
walks up and there's like 40 or 40 like
the workforce down there is all Hispanic
or whatever so there's like a bunch
there's dozens of people picking
off male flowers and he walks up and I'm
like you want to see how many there are
look down and he looks down and we had
like two or three five gallon buckets
full of male flowers that they'd already
picked before he got
there like that many it really and then
as you guys know when a plant gets light
when seated it doesn't matter if it got
lightly seated or heavily seated it
stops growing flour the way that it
should and it focuses on finishing the
seed that is been like finishing what's
been pollinated so instead of like
getting these big robust plants about
two and a half or three weeks in it all
got pollinated then we got dink dink
dink dink dink dink dink of these nugs
and it was basically just they messed up
on on their hormones on their levels on
their agar or whatever they were doing
and so it was to the point where they
basically I think ended up going out of
business the genetics they Gene no it
wasn't it was their stuff but it was
crazy because it was a big enough Farm
we were running about 38 or 40 different
things all 12 things from them did the
same thing and nothing from anyone else
did it wow so it was just oh my God
that's crazy
selection that's but that's also
addressed by Cosmic but I just mean well
I just meant more like there's a
learning curve we don't know you know I
almost think in a way and maybe I'm
wrong but I also got like I have some
photos on my phone of like getting a 100
plants at a time from a different
company that was doing tissue culture
that didn't give us any issues at all
except for the Clones were literally
like this big in these tiny little
rooted like plugs and you had to plant
them and then we had to make in the
field we had to make like
little you rip open the top I can show
you pictures Gabby of like there were
these like 100 clones fit into a tray
like that big you know and yeah I've got
you know they grew fine but you needed
to Baby the heck out of them for the
first week to 10 days to get them
because it's such a small amount of
plant it could
die those clones took an extra month to
grow so I mean it literally took it it
took one month till they looked like a
clone that you would normally have
freshly rooted purchased from a nursery
they were tiny dud like for me at least
so far from what I've seen I think
cleaning up plants and trading plants
amongst friends using tissue culture or
going through Marist stem is cool but if
I was doing something production
oriented I would want to grow that plant
out in a normal fashion once it's been
cleaned up and get a big big vigorous
mom and start taking tons of clones off
it the way I normally do because then I
can start with a clone that's like this
big if I want you know what I mean or I
can leave extra leaves on it it's just
going to root and go and I'm not so I'm
not saying it's a negative I'm just
saying that like it requires its
own like application to be
successful so that's like the
application that companies like jungle
boys use it for where they're not doing
actual micropropagation it's more just
genetic preservation and then pulling
out clean mothers and actually vegging
them out producing
this is a the last 10% of your
production actually as a facility for
example I'm this Library yeah me because
I I met Mike uh from J boys Mike Hydro
yeah in Barcelona two years ago we were
speaking about this and he tell asked me
because I like how he approached me he
said to me you know if it's the last 10%
in your facility then it's something
that it's okay for you you know the flow
uh the linar flood the starter kit that
they have you know uh but if you're not
having your uh you know your your Sops
already you know if you're having
dealing with that and still not
developed your company until that moment
it's no use for you because you know he
he sells you a product but then he sells
you it you must be on 90% now if you
want to to buy this because otherwise it
will not have a use for you
yeah something that is true actually
because if you don't know how to grow
good moms with healthy healthiness you
know in a basic you know about growing
tables or any kind of forms that means
that you have to learn something before
that and then you can go to tissue
culture not not
before I under canopy lighting like you
don't want to use under canopy lighting
unless you already have everything else
dialed in and you can't get any more out
of that space without adding more light
it's just like it's maxing out your
production potentials but it's it's not
worth it if you're not already
there yes of course I mean tissue
culture it's very hard on the xplant you
know the the portion that you cut off so
if your mom plant's not healthy already
you know you're going to have a bad time
with it there's one other thing I to
kind bring up too that could potentially
I mean we don't know if it was the
hormones that they used for the tissue
culture that you know affected the
genetics to make you know um produce a
bunch of you know male pollen sacks um
but I do know one one thing that I've
read about is the potential for genetic
drift and um from what I understand and
of course people can correct me in the
comments see this is something I just
briefly read but every plant has two
sets of chromosomes and sometimes when
you do the tissue culture uh process
what will happen is the second set of
chromosomes will kind of take over and
that plant that you grow out will not um
it won't be the same plant that you you
tissue cultur from it will be almost
like this you know kind of um you know
like like I've seen you I've seen people
that that paid uh you know four five
$6,000 to have their heirloom plant
Marist stemmed and then they grew um you
know what they got back next to their
old you know what they had kept in their
mother plants or whatever and like the
new marem plant had more Vigor and more
Health but came out different flower
than they were used to and so there was
a change there I've always heard that
called like somaclonal variation where
you're where the chromosomes are
actually like uh dedifferentiated I
believe is what it's called and like
because genetic drift is something that
happens within a population over time uh
you wouldn't get genetic drift within a
single cultivar you get genetic drift
just with cloning as well a different
term he's saying
it's he's saying it's a different ter
genetic drift is the wrong term genetic
drift is something that happens like if
you had like a population of wild
cannabis where it would Reed itself and
reede itself season to season but it and
then it would adapt in in that area that
would be called genetic drift but the
what we're experiencing within like
having a clone be different than what
its mother plant uh presented when in
flower would be called something called
I have a hard stop that I have to do
because I have to do something with my
children so I hate to be uh I hate
well they are getting it's I have to
take one of them to a practice even
though they're off for uh for
Thanksgiving break or whatnot I still
have some dad responsibilities so I'm
getting frantically waved at that I'm
drifting into a bad time you don't have
to guys don't have to stop talking but I
need to
bail I love you too wonderful meeting
you wonderful meeting you know yeah me
too I think we will we will talk will
you guys all have a lovely
day you know we cannot stop that's the
basic thing you we are friends who sit
down on the couch guys you know like we
are I that's a great thing you know like
that's you know I mean we've been
drifting a little bit but it's always
like that it's very the best thing about
it is that you have this uh that is uh
Happening by you know by itself natural
it's not like oh we have a script now uh
I have some things that I didn't tell
you yet no it's not like that you know
well I I've been writing down questions
as we've been talking and of course we
didn't get to
like we'll have to continue again in the
future yeah yeah hopefully part three
hopefully part three real soon yeah one
thing I wanted to say before we left I
wanted to say this about the tissue
culture um
is when you do Maris them you're not
guaranteed to remove virus okay this is
this is what um NATO dog was saying but
when you do Marist stem and then you do
it again and then you test and then you
grow things at then it's possible to
remove the virus
so it it's just a process it you know
where some people say well I Mar stemmed
it now it's clean well no you've Marist
stemmed it now you have to grow it out
you have to and and the problem with the
hopen vroid is because it hides so well
mhm you have to grow it and test it for
some time before you know if if the work
actually was done but it's definitely
possible it's just not as easy as any of
us would like it to be from what I read
it's about a 50% chance to be able to
extract you know marriage stem that is
completely healthy free viroids if it
was coming from an infected mom but yeah
like you said it's it's almost like a
process of refinement of just doing it
over and over again until you know you
have that end product that you want you
know which is a clean and healthy plant
but can you tell me do you know do you
know about how it transmits over seed
production also I mean how how much
percent of the seeds when you cross
something that is infected MH you make
seeds and then you sell those seeds as a
breeder or something if I remember um
there's a great article from I think
it's like The nathal Institute of Health
or something it's like an actual
government article that they did a study
from I believe it was in the high 80
percen
80 you 80 yeah like originally they were
thinking oh it's which is actually
pretty
low well it's pretty low if you consider
that 20% of them of the crosses won't
have
hlvd you know like you could actually
like grow that out can identif or
whatever well I mean you got to grow
them out and then test them you know and
you might sick and you you know plants
next to healthy plants and stuff and
there's so hot and viral is you know
like how NATO dog said it's like AIDS
you don't have to worry about shaking
hands with somebody with
AIDS you have it's not that way with hot
lant yeah there could be like cross
contamination from water you know if
they not careful there could be well so
that's why I said there's there there's
things that you can do to make sure that
you're not sharing
water and so that uh you're not sharing
scissors like like a dirty needle
yeah well in in um I believe it was a
study out of gual in Canada that uh
found that it could transfer from
contact so like they they found that
like one plant didn't have it it was
next to a plant that did have it and
then it had it later and it they weren't
sharing any um like irrigation streams
or anything like they weren't connected
to the same Reservoir anything like that
before so like the potential is there uh
it's you know there is a there is a
study also that there is one plant you
they measured the the lent virus and
they found that in the upper part of the
plant there was no latency there was no
virus there present you know they
couldn't measure it but on the lower
branches there were virus you know
places of the plant it's mov the
vascular yeah yeah yeah but that's why
marem
works yeah because you are out
outgrowing the virus and then you take
before the virus came to this tissue you
you you cut it away and you try to to
culture it right so that is the idea
right I mean all the banana and all the
the Ora and all the everything in the
world you know food production is
relying on marem and culture as itself
for 100 years I mean a guy 100 years ago
uh developed this right it's like a very
old we are talking about something that
if somebody 100 years ago could do that
or the basics of it how could today more
than 100 years later we cannot do it at
home every you know not every grower
home grower but a lot of them the ones
that are dedicated with the
heart you know with a small system I'm
I'm doing it at home so it's it's
possible you know yeah yeah yeah you you
are a perfect example of it that's what
I want to say and I mean realistically
um it's only maybe
$2,000 I probably put in my lab you know
probably a little bit more because I got
a lot more supplies but you know the
microscope you know was about 700 my Flo
Hood was 500 and the pressure cooker um
was about 160 180 somewhere around there
and those are the biggest parts of a lab
that you would need everything else is
relatively inexpensive so if you can get
those three big Parts knocked out you
can definitely build yourself a home
lab well definitely hope we have Sasha
on for a part three again soon
yeah definitely there is few strains you
know there is few strains I had on the
list I didn't even mention to Noto
because he asked me and then I have like
and then we stopped because all of these
trains have so much history you know
they have a story behind that is not
like you know you cannot say like oh
that was that train and like in one a
minute and a half I will tell you the
story about it like that's not like it
easy you cannot because it it has so
much Story episode just on the Shiva
skunk and another one on the Santa Maria
Plank and so there is so many others you
know yeah and I hope people will come up
now in Austria you know because other
and shops and uh Librarians like me also
maybe maybe they could uh give us a
signal and they could join the
conversation that would be nice that
would be great or any part of the world
any part of the world not only this part
where we I am you know but anywhere you
know
all right before we go I just want to
make sure I tell you all you guys how
grateful I am for all of you and I look
forward to continuing this conversation
soon absolutely definitely forward to it
think it's so cool to be able to you
know not just talk Shop but you know to
get a glimpse in everyone else's you
know way of growing and especially all
the way across the world you know like
how cool is that like that's so awesome
about life and you not just you know how
many you know how many people are like
this in the world you know there is a we
are like a tribee you know this is a
tribe of people of Nomads of Nomads yeah
and what yes like it's a it's beautiful
yeah that it happened let's continue you
know let's do
it Gabby you will be keep me updated ask
I'm going to ask you publicly in front
of the world I want you to be our
European
correspondent and I want you to talk to
people that we don't know and that we
can't talk to and if it's in English we
obviously we want to be a part of it you
know
but yeah said we open we opened up the
box we can't shut it now now it's wide
open bro yeah we flip the rock you know
like it's open like P Pandora's Box open
so if there is uh you know yeah I I
think U will respond and I could be
actually your one of your respond
correspondents you know as you said I
could be one of them because I'm not the
only one you know there is so many
others that would be maybe more talented
to tell the the other stories and they
have their own stories and everything
but you know you have me here so you
have one the first one is like we want
we want to tell story yeah exactly
you're the first one we want to tell
stories with friends on the couch yeah
you know
so and you know hopefully you'll help us
make some more
friends oh yeah I think the people will
be also encouraged by this I think that
somebody stepped out you know and told a
little bit of the story what is going on
here because it's uh to your story but
also very different for your your story
you know from your your your place of
the world you have a different uh
different the same story with a
different uh different drama you know
all of us have uh all fed up with that
that the illegal to grow economies for a
little small purpose you know for
yourself or in a little small scale that
I think the world has enough of Lies you
know
[Music]
the this episode of gabbing with Gabby
is brought to you by the Breeders direct
Seed Company in my opinion the Breeders
direct Seed Company is your Premier
Source for clones and seeds and they are
the only place that you can get the
Gabby Staten Island collection so visit
breeders direct for all your seed and
clone needs