this episode of gabbing with Gabby is
brought to you by the Breeders direct
Seed Company in my opinion the Breeders
direct seed company is your Premier
Source for clones and seeds and they are
the only place that you can get the
Gabby Statin Island collection so visit
breeders direct for all your seed and
clone needs
[Music]
what's up everybody this is Gabby and
we're doing the gabbing with Gabby
podcast we've got our co-hosts wolf and
Cosmic here and I'm delighted to um
introduce to you Sasha Sasha is from um
Slovenia and he has a nursery in
Austria and
I met him on Instagram he had commented
on some of the videos that we' been
making and when I started to talk to him
I realized that he was somebody that we
absolutely had to have on this podcast
to tell his story I you know I don't
know anyone in Austria or Slovenia
that's um involved in cannabis so I was
really intrigued by him and anyway nice
to have you on the show Sasha thank you
for inviting me oh no it's our pleasure
hey guys oh and and I should have
introduced Sasha is my Hobbit brother
from
Slovenia exactly exact that's how he
likes to be
addressed exact Mundo it is uh a big
honor for me that I've been contacted
actually by you also like hey you know
like I just wanted to make a comment
like I do normally when I like something
you know um I think uh
it's quite a lot to explain but I will
be quite short about things but uh I've
been uh growing up I mean I was born in
the end of ' 70s in
Yugoslavia uh and particularly in a
place called Slovenia today because this
was one other country when I was born
you know so Yugoslavia was uh you I
don't know we will not do some
Geographic uh lecture now here but
Yugoslavia was one country that consists
of many other many countries that are
today separate uh but this is basically
Slovenia Croatia Bosnia Serbia
Montenegro Macedonia and Kosovo we are
we are the Balkans uh we belong to the
the European Peninsula that is called
the Balkans we are called South
Europe uh we are not the Western Europe
because the Western Europe starts uh
like 10 m from my house it is uh because
I am separated by a river uh between
Slovenia and
Austria uh historically this is a very
very um interesting place for war times
and blood shedding you know like it was
a lot of blood was spilled here in this
region a long time ago and you know it's
like there was a lot of War so uh
culture wise uh I've been growing up on
a property where I've been actually
exposed to a garden uh as a young child
by my grandmother I've been growing up
in a garden you know like there was no
babysitters you know so my grandmother
just said go outside you know so I went
outside so maybe in mesino where maybe
most of the people are that least I know
uh is uh the same thing it's a wild we
have Slovenia is uh half of the country
is Forest
we have 2 million people it's uh 20
times smaller than
California
um mostly people have Gardens here and
still today people have Garden at home
so everybody grows
food uh so basic uh thing is that also
everybody that not grow today or
something in the sense of not cannabis
food or cannabis too is uh you inh
herited that maybe a land even if you
are not growing up in a Countryside you
know because slovenians normally they
are owners of land so there is a lot of
culture of
gardening that's the first thing so
normally when you when you have a
culture like this that everybody has a
garden an eye that been exposed to a
garden as a child and been growing up
without internet without phone without
the things that we know today as common
common sense uh you you I've been
interested in um um ants and uh
butterflies and this stuff first because
you know as a kid you search for that
but after a while I realize today
because I'm dealing uh a lot with uh
plants today uh is that you uh you I was
exposed with plants all my life so I
came to to the realization
in life um I won't tell you my whole
story because this would be for another
podcast but how I come to it yeah is um
my parents were very uh open-minded uh
in that times and they were like the
Hipp generation you know and um we was
uh also cannabis is itself as a plant
was um my grand-grandfather was a hemp
farmer in Old Time Yugoslavia so we used
to grow hemp you know hemp we I as a
child I know a machine it's not a
machine it was a it was a bit cutting
knife for cutting hemp stems you know
because you what we grew my my my
ancestors grew hemp was because of fiber
they grew it for rope they grew it for
you know it was a material you know
nobody smoked him I uhy can I ask you a
question real fast yeah please so you
said that most people have land in
Slovenia yes
um to me that was already something
that's very interesting because in the
US it's not like that you wouldn't have
a corporate uh you know some corporation
that would come and buy uh 1,000 hectar
of land here you know you don't have
that so people own their own land they
they uh and even if they if I own it if
they never been to a farm because they
live in lublana and the grandmother and
grandfather died now so you inherit
inherit land you know it's yours now
many people from Liana that don't own
land in that sense they got um
possibility to to to not even Liana
everywhere you know what I mean in
Slovenia but I was living so long time
in lublana so that's why I tell the this
capital of Slovenia is you know we we
are a 2 million people country it's like
if you have a one big Capital the third
of population is there because of it's a
student place and it's the place where
centralization kicked in here really
fast so we are politically really like
centralized country you know so the the
peripheral I call the countryside is
quite um yeah
it's how I tell it it's harder to live
here but it's better to live here you
know I guess my question that I wanted
to know was is there poverty there cuz
like when you said that everyone owns
land it sounds like very it is a poverty
but it's not a poverty in sense of your
country you know we don't have people on
the street here in the countryside you
have some some people in the street in
lbl because there are heroin addicts or
uh I don't know Fenton kicked in also
now and you know that that's stuff but
in the countryside you don't have that
it's it's not there so there is no
poverty in that s they're alcoholics you
know because we are a nation that do a
lot of wine we have a wine culture like
California does we have a lot of where I
live there is only one there is wine
yards everywhere here yeah uh there is a
exposure of sun here is also at the
place I live is in East uh North East
Slovenia yeah which is south of Austria
so uh this is the place that the most
the sun is in the year you're like south
side of the mountain range yeah southide
of the mountain range and also we have
panonian region which is you know here
was panonian sea thousands years ago you
know uh Slovenia is a small country but
we have like different regions where I
live is flat then you have the little
mountain region and then have a high
mountain region to the Alps julan Alps
and then you have the seaside yeah uh
and a lot of wheat is also forest all
the time Slovenia is traditionally a
country that uh is growing wheat since I
was born you know like because it's a
you know sometimes people think that
wheed has been only
grown you know as a land race uh and
then it came to Western Europe and USA
and Canada yeah but it came to
Yugoslavia and to all the other
countries that it's all tradition here
you know um but the different kind of
cultural background uh with a different
sense of the con
we treat Canabis as medicine here uh
Canabis is not I mean it's a
recreational drug of course but cannabis
as a in a sense of cultural what I know
now that Slovenia will legalize soon I
think and it will be because of medical
uh I have a question really quick so um
since it sounds like they they may
legalize soon um what what do the
current um like what is the current
political stance on Canada AB like do
they do they ever arrest people for it
or like um yeah and and I guess like
that would be like one question for like
does like someone small who's just
growing at home for themselves as
medicine as you would say um like would
they ever be prosecuted or would it just
be people who are doing it yes yes I can
tell you many things is um there been
many cases now in the last years uh
people have been prosecuted for uh all
kind of growing because there is a lot
of people who grow here I mean there is
you don't even know now anymore if it's
left right wing people you know we don't
have like this political system of two-
party system here it's many parties it's
like the Christians and the others and
the one and the green ones and you know
let's like that so we treat uh Canabis
as a cultural plant and
um for example there there have been
cases that guys been growing 5 kilo of
uh flowers and turning them into oil
into Rick Simpson Oil you know everybody
this is also a story but they turning it
into oil and they've been prosecuted for
giving it to people and they they've
been freed because of 5 kilo they had
they've been growing and they've been
Pro processing the wheat for oil and
giving it out to people who are sick
with cancer and these people came with
medical certification
into the court with doctors that
certified that it helped
them so the case was dropped and yeah
and we are on the point we are on the
point now that uh two months ago or 3
months ago in August we have a
referendum you know uh how you call it
in English referendum referendum
referendum yeah like referendum yeah
yeah people being asked do you want
medical cannabies yes
60 or 70% yes do you want uh conies
grown in your own property uh uh as in a
small scale you know what I mean like
three personal use yeah three plant five
plant it was 51% yes nice barely so
government now is writing already the
the law they will present it before New
Year actually they said they will uh
there is you know do you guys know um um
international business conference
Canabis international business
conference IC yes I know about it it's
called yeah uh the it's a conference
that takes place all around the world
yeah uh mainly was I was in Zurich and
uh it is in Slovenia in Blade and it is
in Berlin and in Vancouver uh and the
the guy that has this the CEO of this is
called Alex Rogers he lives in lublana
he's married to Slovenian wife she has a
wife with kids there and he has this
this business thing you know and you
know Alex is somebody that I have to
tell you we've been I've been involved
into music scene a long time in Slovenia
and also in the region of wans I've been
working as a stage technician
for big bands and small bands and clubs
and you know I've been growing up with
music I cannot live without music music
is something that I need every day so
still but I choose Canabis for my
profession Alex Rogers is a guy we used
to call
jabon he was with dreadlocks he was a
guy that came from America and we have a
sound system we do Jamaican style do
music you know uh with with with records
you know with vinyls and you know heavy
sound and then were people coming
chanting you know Slovenia is a lot a
lot of Africans are are there you know
it is from the time also of Yugoslavia
because we were the independent between
USA and Russia we were not Russia you
know Yugoslavia and Russia were
separated so we were a communistic
country but we were uh with African
culture so a lot of Africans came to to
to Yugoslavia at that time so in lublana
there was like a lot of Africans you
know still today are they are you know
and um you know we have this sound
system culture so ja bong Alex Rogers
comes there and chanting you know and I
knew him as that you know and uh then he
disappeared and I was asking my friend
Ziggy who is uh making uh like papers
Ziggy papers we have here you know we
have rlaw you have OCB you have this we
have Ziggy papers like
zigzag yeah but zigzag is a very old
company too but Ziggy papers is from the
'90s they are based in lublana they are
my friends they are Rasta culture and
they are making really really quality
product I mean their their papers are
crazy good you know I I love them so
Ziggy is one guy you know and uh I ask
zig because we were all sound system
having sound systems in that time in
zigi you know Jamaicans used to come
into lubl and we making poers yeah
original artist so and you know uh I
will not be too long in this but it uh
it was a culture and then I called zigy
up and say where is Ja bong you know
Alex and he said hey it's a problem I
said what is uh he's been arrested in
Germany and I say why he's been he's
been selling we we in Germany and I said
I don't know about that Alex was uh head
security of High Times cannabis cops in
the 9s you know he was there so I think
he did some shady business then and he
was in prison I don't know 2 years or
something everybody knows today about
this because he's telling his story also
that's why I tell it open here so Alex
when he went out of prison um started
this
ICBC which is actually a a business
conference he's trying to get a place
where guys come together for cannabis
business and he actually made a really
good business with it I mean he's
everywhere every year you know and it's
successful and he's the one of those
guys who lobbies in Slovenia for the law
and he's actually very near not only him
but and he's the guy that the one that
is not Slovenian or because we
slovenians have From perspective of
ourselves like H we are small people
like the Hobbit that's why I'm with the
hobbits you know we are the hobbits who
are like you know Tolen story this is
the same was it we are so small we think
we can do we cannot change the world or
nothing we are just like leaving our
Gardens you know but hobit wouldn't that
mean that you have the ability to change
the world yeah you know what you don't
me ring carriers you know like um joke
uh Alex is the guy uh who actually tells
The Story About Slovenia like this I'm
admiring him because he opened uh some
window he says that Slovenia is the most
tolerant country for Canabis in Europe
or the world and I was like what you
know and actually he explains like this
you can sit anywhere in any Cafe in
lublana or outside
and smoke a
joint which is true you
can uh nobody will call the police
nobody they will they will tell you in
certain places definitely please put it
out but they will never call the
police you know what I mean you will not
have a problem because of that it is
like come on can you step like 10 ms
away or you know and then come back to
or I don't know you know it the smoke
might be bothering people so they'll ask
you to move away
but same is like a cigarette yeah and
also the wheat culture because so many
people you know left right wing uh
because Rick Simpson was in Slovenia so
long time already um Rick Simpson
everybody knows about Rick Simpson I
think yeah he went in Exile from Canada
into the world and he actually stayed in
the balans I think he's married to a
Croatian woman now or with her and he
had a stroke that's why he's not present
anymore on the internet so uh actually
Rick Simpson is somebody that is not a
grower you know but he's been spreading
the word about wheat and he's been
growing actually in can in Canada at
that time and he's been making a lot of
this oil which is essential for
Slovenian story because we are the
nation of Rick Simpson steers oil you
know like there is so many Gardens there
is old
grandmothers uh that grow cannabis
because of the oil nobody smoke joints
from this type of people you know but
they they they grow it for oil and of
course there is a longtime culture of
smok economies here also of course yeah
like everywhere you were telling me a
little bit about how in Slovenia you
know it's tolerant to smoke but you
aren't allowed to grow or you're not
allowed to harvest flour so I think that
would be a something before we talk
about your business tell us about that
in Slovenia wheat is absolutely illegal
that means the plant is already illegal
that's what I want to tell the plant in
Slovenia is illegal but it's been used
so much that it's you know even if it's
illegal it's
still it's weak you
know like few hundred k M from here is I
mean it's very near the border to
Hungary but in Hungary there is some
feral wheat
growing everywhere it's Canabis but it's
0.2 THC or something but it's FAL it's
feral you know so it grows everywhere
like wild wheat wild wild and nobody
touches it because it's really I mean
you know somebody would say yeah it's we
can work with it yeah you should but I
it's not my life you know you know I
don't have time for this but uh this is
feral wheed which is really wild wild so
the culture of Canabis here is quite old
very
old that's why people you know one thing
a difference between USA and the place
where I
live it is always been
illegal but it's never been so
prosecutive you know if you have a few
few plans they will give you a bill
nobody will put you in prison for that
ever it's been since I've been growing
up like this so it's still legal and
people don't really care so much about
it you know that's why legalization took
so long because it was not so uh you
know you you you would not go to jail
because of five to 10 plants you know
you would
not definitely I mean people went to
jail but they normally did other stuff
too yeah you know they have like I know
I mean one friend of mine I will not
tell his name he had 300 kilo of wheat
been harvested from a greenhouse Fresh
So 300 kilo would be how much 100 kilo
dry 600 700 lb oh okay you're talking
about dry he was in prison for one and a
half years and he's
out you know what I mean it's like you
will not spend your life in prison
because of wheat so that's why people
made the decision also to grow big here
they do so they did they you know I will
not talk about too much but uh it's
still illegal here so have in mind yeah
there still there's still a risk but
it's just less it's still a risk of
course yeah nobody is story go ahead
yeah the story you told me about like
you can grow um weed as long as you
don't Harvest it that what makes it
illegal was that in Austria Austria of
course oh okay that's why I got confused
so we'll talk about that in a moment
that's why because I live on the border
to Austria and Slovenia I've been
growing up here I've been born in
Austria because my mother worked here in
the town it's a town from the 13th
century it's a town that is like known
for uh thermal Spas you know tourism is
here
um and it's like for all people that
want to enjoy their life on the end of
life it's a very quality place it's
beautiful it's surrounded by castles and
and forests and we have good breweries
here and we have a good uh Nursery here
you know so I uh the law in Austria is
like this you can grow any kind of
Canabis any kind of Canabis plant
cannabis is not a drug THC Delta 9
substance is the drug so until the
Cannabis flowers there is no
drug you see they are
practical
um in the sense of the even you can go
that far that I would assume that if you
would grow at home the plant till the
end until it flowers and you would not
cut one flower from the plant and you
would have a police raid and they would
not find any dry flower in your house
not any clue that you would use it and
you say to them that you actually use it
for uh aroma therapy because you go with
your hands on the back to the plant and
you smell on
it and that is your aroma therapy every
judge in the country will free you
because there is no there is no
production of drugs when you don't cut a
flow from it you know what I mean it's
crazy it's kind of like opium like
poppies so like in the US as long as you
don't cut it that's that's right you
know until then you know cuz in in the
US it's legal to grow uh poppy flowers
it's illegal to cut them and you know
make them you know drop the sap that you
know becomes you know op yeah then you
produce the drug at that moment when you
make this action you know so in Austria
it's like this that there is many many
shops with uh living plants already you
know I used to buy clones in Austria 20
years ago as a grower yeah so I turned
my illegality into
legality and I made the business I went
over uh the the the border here and I
said okay I will make a company and I
will sell clones and they check you if
you are uh you know if you have any
record you know if you did something I
didn't so I was clean so I could do that
and I made a facility uh with different
cultivars that I gathered uh for 20
years because I have uh I know a lot of
people that grow that are growing I'm a
grower h still but I'm a legal grower
now you know what I mean yeah I just
turned it into a business you know you
know I have four employees now um we
have also another uh company which our
company is name is her betics her betics
is like herb ethics you know the herb
and the ethics so atics is a company in
Slovenia we have extraction company we
do extract with uh Buton gas with N1 gas
which is the most clean butane which is
allowed in food production uh in
Europe uh so we extract all kind of uh
materials
uh all kind of uh uh biomaterials you
can get yeah so we're not extracting
only cannabis uh which is in Slovenia we
extract CBD and CBG cannabies we are not
allowed to extract THC because we are
not pharmaceutical satified company with
GMP status we we're not having that yet
we try to in the future but you know we
are working on that for a long time um
GMP means good manufactur practice that
means this is the standard for uh for uh
drugs you know you can actually you know
uh sell it then for big money you know
what I mean but we're not uh we actually
do a lot of other extractions for you
know we do uh serum oils which is which
means you get grape seed oil and uh uh
um different kind of seeds that we can
extract the oils from this is the oil
which is called absolute oils and you
can use them in any shampoo any skin
cream normally the the the Cosmetic
industry comes to and buys this you know
so we actually did this but in Austria
we have this facility with Canabis
plants uh which is specializing in we
have now 35 different cultivar in our
library um I know Gabby
knows I've been saying a few days ago
the the list he knows about it is it's a
very interesting link I think because
I'm a I'm a nerd you know
I'm a cannabis nerd I'm listening you
know how I come to Gabby because I
listen to Nato dog for years and I
listen to SK every time I hear something
about SK VA I go I want to hear it you
know like this guy was so in cnit for me
and the whole genetic that uh I really
thank this guy for for some genetics
that I acquired uh in
spanis uh over the
years um
that I know the you know the American
genetics are very different from the
Europeans first of all something that
you grow now there it's so craft and
it's so made for also for looks
and some of them are interesting some of
them are very boring you know it's like
that it's the truth you know not yeah it
is actually some of them are really
interesting because we as we we people
we appreciate this but when it comes to
some genetics that you uh because the
the lack of uh you know when you go only
for THC levels when you breed only for
THC up you know then I think the it uh
the game changes and you lose some very
good effects on your body I think that's
my opinion because you can smoke uh or
consume cannabis that is um very much
less DC and you have a better
experience yeah I
mean the THC levels there's two things
about it number
one in most cases there's a good chance
that it's not accurate right because
here the testing Labs you know
everybody's going to take their weed to
the lab that says that they've got the
highest percentage of
THC the other thing is we don't really
know everything about cannabis or even
maybe the smallest bit about cannabis
about what gets you high and you know
all the other cannaboids that could be
in cannabis and the
tpin and what effect they have when you
consume it so I mean I was telling you a
story yesterday the chem dog it's one of
the most potent
weed you know I've ever smoked I I still
think to this day but it didn't test
very high yeah you know why as far as
the cannaboids go ahead I have a theory
uh it's because of turpins tpin are
consisting from mono and from CES so
they are like combination of Co it's a
code and it's so complicated that I
think we need like 50 years of research
for that that we will we will little bit
understand why you know is tping all the
time I mean we have the Shiva the old
Shiva um we call it Shiva this is one of
the strs on on his list that when I saw
it I was like oh my God I started dra I
mean we tasted Shiva for Content Paul
Hornby did this which is very
interesting guy I have to tell you about
him Paul Hornby is a Canadian he came
he's he died a few years ago he was the
researcher of Canabis a very very good
one you know he's been working cannabis
for 30 years um and he's been actually
paid by the government of Canada to do
it research and he he told me also that
the tpin are the the key to the thing
you know everything every substance that
you have like CBD or THC or THC V or any
kind CBG doesn't matter the Turpin have
to be there also because of the end to
rush effect you know there is this kind
of thing that we still can explain today
but for for example the wheat from the
the equator has a very specific turent
profile right right the wheat from
Afghanistan and Pakistan which is
actually OG and the indicas has also
very very similar uh uh picture of the
Turpin again you know and but we don't
still know the sequences between those
it will take us so many years I think
it's it's a very nice science actually
to do I I would assume because somebody
hopefully our children will figure that
out for us I think so too I mean I hope
so it's just uh the wheat the Shiva that
I was I mentioning before she will get
you couch locked with 17 or 18% THC only
what she has yep but I just I just threw
one that came out at 16% and it uh but
it was very very Stony put me right into
the couch and I um and I tried the other
one that we grew right in the same room
same fertilizers and everything and it
tested at I believe was like 28% and it
just didn't do anything for
me yeah and on the other hand some Yeti
OG that I have for years from lompa
farms test for
25% I can smoke it I mean not in the
morning but you can smoke it's uplifting
High it makes it's a headband actually y
so it's it's like it's a back Cross of
headband so it makes you it doesn't make
you like this Stone like the Shiva cut
which has less percent a lot like 6%
less or something on the test we we had
it from the same lab you know it's like
but I don't believe in this kind of test
anymore because it's just a PCR test I
think you know like like you would um
it's not so it's not so accurate as we
think actually I think so right now I
think in the future will be a much more
accurate picture of of the testing
because they will uh in they will also
include the turpins you know they they
do here in the
US in the US when you do testing you can
get the Turpin tested and you know they
test for other cannaboids and stuff like
that but we still don't know what that
means so for instance if it you know
something tests at 2% THC
well oh not TC Turpin yeah okay well the
the different Turf Pines could have a
different effect on people and maybe it
only takes 1% of those tpin to have a
dramatic effect where other um strains
might test that four or even 5% terpenes
but does that mean that it's going to be
more potent no I mean often it'll mean
that you can smell it more you know
which is nice Definitely yes and and
maybe taste it but as far as the
effect we just don't know like you said
hopefully our children will figure this
out for us yes and also you know uh here
in Slovenia there is a lot of farmers
that grow in the seaside region they
grow uh lavender a lot I have a very
good friend that is a weed grower and
also a lavender grower you know and uh
he's testing his material so he says for
the Le lavanda that is tasting normally
for
6% of turpins but he has two strains of
the
lavender not the uh cannabis the normal
lavanda you
know but the one with 4% that he has
smells much much more
powerful explain it to me where the 6%
does not smell that much than the the
four you know because of only testing
for tpin TP tpin yeah mm so but you know
the problem is they make the steam
distillation very old old this is 3,000
year old technique technique to to to
get out the turpins you know I told them
already that they should tast it in my
facility with the butane because we will
make it on a lower temperature and we
will get the full spectrum you know from
the smell only you know because the
Turpin you can with butane is beautiful
to extract the turpins you know it's
really yeah it's better than any other
so well I I also wonder just because of
the um like even within cannabis we only
test for Turpin but there's other
volatile organic compounds that are
giving off a lot of the smells that that
we're picking up um you know like uh
like a lot of people hunt for like
roadkill skunk smell and stuff like that
that can't be explained through a
specific turine profile but can be
explained through things like um methyl
groups and um different uh different
other um like carboxy groups it it uh it
doesn't necessarily just fall into uh
tpin so it's I ALS I also just wonder
how much of that is playing a role in
the different effects felt by different
uh absolutely and the thing is that you
mention it already now you know
the thing is that it has to go on the
the research I think until we didn't
research it we don't know I have here I
want to show you this is one
book it's from
19 uh 2 it's 120 years old now and there
is cannabis inside I will show you this
is the book of my grand
grandfather this is this is Poppy and
then you have here you have hum and then
you have a picture of a male of a male
they they somebody grow they they they
go and they they they picture a mail
they didn't you know they put
they from Vienna or some somewhere some
guy have to draw Coles now so he picked
a mail to draw you know a male this is a
male plant you know yeah but it's from
120 year old uh yeah the book and take
some photos of the book for me to
include in the video I will I will and
also with the text is is written with
old Gothic so people who will know
German they can read it you can read it
I know German so I read it um it's very
interesting because you know what it
mention in the this book for fertilizing
the kabes
guano oh really B guano really I will
make a picture and you will see that's
years the origin of using guos for
cannabis yes my brother you
know when we were beginners all of us
the
Growers what we were using for
fertilizing huh what were you reading in
your first you were high you had high
times we had grow magazine from Germany
you know we were all reading about guano
soup you know like tea make make guano
tea or by guano the B you know the bird
guano and the bad guano and always was
guano we knew about I was reading about
guano Wars man the wars of guano you
know they they were having Wars for that
for bad [__] you in South America you
know what I mean yeah in the old times
you know in the you can Google it it's
true they were having pirating like they
were fighting for sugar and you know all
kind of stuff they were fighting for the
bad [__] you
know yeah you know yeah such a good
fertilizer yeah it's still actually a
problem there's still actually a lot of
um uh slavery and child slavery used to
collect different bird guanas and bad
guanas out of South America and it's
it's one of the least uh sustainable
products on the market laed as organic
mhm yeah absolutely I to people about it
problematic absolutely problematic one
of my friends from libl went to Jamaica
and he was in some caves and they were
harvesting some guano because he was
like this guy of wheat you know like
let's go Harvest some guano you know
they went into some caves they harvest
some guano but then he almost lost his
lung because he's breathing this [__]
you know the dust yeah it's I you know
it's funny
I don't want to get too far off topic
but um you know when we talk about the
difference between growing with minerals
like hydron nutrient Organics people for
some reason think Organics are clean but
like it's literally [__] and yes you
know and like wolf said there are you
know children dying and getting you know
lung diseases because they're harvesting
this stuff without proper protection
and without pay it's it's slavery it's
it's terrible yes yes so people should
be aware I think this need to be aware
yeah we don't sell guano in my shop I
mean I I used to grow with it but I
don't do it anymore you know I don't cuz
it's I know it's also exploiting n
nature you know when you buy one you buy
it because some they destroy these
islands which is actually inhabited by
birds only or Penguins only you know
what I
mean like a whole ecosystem within the
caves that the that the bats live in and
so once you're the guano you destroy the
the ecosystem and some of those
ecosystems are you know they're older
than a lot of human civilizations
they're they're thousands and thousands
of years old yeah we have this issue
maybe I can talk about this now because
uh people have problem s now here in
Slovenia there is a lot of outdoor
growing let me tell you like maybe in
Austria also there is a lot of people
that grow
outside uh the problem is that from year
to year uh I see uh a lot of um more and
more increase of different Predator uh
you know uh
um we have this from the corn fields
there is this worms you know eating our
butts then is this worm goes inside of
your steam it's crazy how much of it
changed because there is no more winter
here winter used to be minus
20 now they are like if there is - one
2 you know you here used to be a lot of
snow half a meter now there is no snow
since the last 5 years wow yeah that's
how it's going on you know people think
global warming doesn't exist
you know and the Earth is the proof is
right there in
Slovenia and so you're saying you're
getting a lot more of these uh different
um tests like these different Wars
because uh we never had them before and
now we fighting you know how we fight
against them we plant late in the season
because uh sometimes you can escape
uh the time when this the the the
butterfly goes and uh puts the eggs into
your plants is maybe later you plant the
later he he can do it so this year we
planted already some Growers that they
went they came and they said uh on the
end of July they get bigger plants you
know so they put them outside and there
is not so much problems if you put them
out too early they are full of warm they
are full of it's
catastrophic from here use any like
sorry do you use any sprays no most of
those people they don't want to because
we are used to grow organically here you
know normally people never sprays their
plants even you know maybe in veget
vegetation when they are vegetative
plants but not in flower You Don't Spray
nothing on when it's flowering that's
that is like ridiculous you know for us
we
don't you consume it you know like you
will put it in your body no way you know
so there I don't even want to spray
organic stuff on flour you can you can I
don't want to like you know like not
even I you know spraying anything on
your flow is just is you know like for
instance people will spray products that
are considered acceptable for organic
cultivation that contain an oil but if
you spray an oil on your
flour you know you're going to be
consuming that oil yes and so um I'm
sure Nick was going to say something
about products that we use here for
caterpillars oh yeah I was just thinking
like Bia basana or something that's just
like a um like a m insecticide where
it's uh it's basically just like a a
predatory mushroom that just attacks the
um yeah people use that here in
agriculture yeah they I know about this
because they use it you know we are Farm
you know the plants that we grow here in
the area is all there is a lot of tomato
Growers and uh uh all kind of salads
here everybody has a garden you know so
there is all time alltime grow yeah um
what I think also is uh point would be
that you um use nettle nettle you know
when you put nettle into water and you
sit it for 12 hours you can spray with
it when you sit it for 24 hours you will
kill your plants with it really yeah
yeah it's so strong because it's so
strong yeah it's so strong here um
people just need dilute it more yeah you
need to dilute it more and but actually
everything what we need to know is in
the
nature everything all the plants are
there they have uh different uh uh
elements so actually if you would
ferment them
you would get everything you know you
would you don't need animal products to
do that you know I'm not vegetarian you
know I don't tell you because of that
but I know that it's possible just the
trace element you need for example
cannabis as itself is uh a plant that
consumes the most iron in the world
there is no plant in the world that
would consume more iron than
Canabis h
very interesting also they use cannabis
here in my region and in this area of
the world as a cleaning of the soil
remediation of soil sure when you put
when you put hemp plants which is for me
when somebody says hemp is not wheat or
hemp is not Canabis it's Canabis it can
it can fertilize your your your plants
you know we have a lot of hemp growing
in Slovenia
a lot of hemp you know growing yeah so
people who who who grow uh traditional
uh plants you know let me say
traditional have a problem sometimes
because they are pollinated by hemp
fields in the in the
area which is problematic you know how
can you protect that you know because
these things if if you have a rainy
season and in this time you have luck
but sometime it's very dry High season
and then the Poland gets blown 10 kilm
not three as they tell you I had really
good clones outside years ago and there
was this haa which I still have in my
facility we call it the Isabella the
good one the the one that smells so good
you know it's it smells like Isabella uh
grapes I don't know if you know Isabella
grapes with we have we have a wine
region and these are blue grapes very
big one they have really this um very
sweet and they have this certain Aroma
is is it for wine production it is for
wine production yeah is there is that I
might know it if there is a French
equivalent it is because French people
came here 300 years ago and they made
wine here so we still use their
tradition to do it you know we have
sparkling champagne wine which is not
champagne because it's not from
Champagne region you know but it's the
same grapes you know grown in our region
with uh the same process of how you do
champagne wine with sparkling you know
the same thing you know it's not Crystal
but but so these are called is Isabella
grapes they are called Isabella but we
call it yka WEA in my language we say
Ura everybody knows what kind of and
when people come and they buy my clone
the wapa clone from Paradise seats that
I have so long I got it from the
mountains
2015 I got it from mountain region in
Slovenia I will not expose anybody but
uh my friends I will tell from the
mountains these are very old Growers
they're older than me they teach me how
to grow moms they teach me how to do
clones and then I went to Austria and do
my business you know very much later uh
the culture is there but these people
grow in they are living in the mountains
maybe in mesino is the same you far away
away from a from a city and you like to
stay at home so these people don't go to
shops to buy clones you know they keep
their own moms their own selections
their own in the beginning they were not
depending on
nobody so the same thing a little little
mesino a little California in our
country is there too but I will not tell
which place because it's so
small but it's in the mountains so these
are people who are who are depending on
nature they cannot survive uh just like
that you know there is no shop you know
it's very similar you know the stories
that I hear from our countries I mean
from California especially and from USA
as it is we are I mean we still the same
you know I don't know I mean we we speak
different languages and everything but
we are all the same people black white
Chinese you don't Name It We Are the
human race actually you should go
together out in space without Wars and
without anything you know this my idea
of the future but you know I'm a I'm a
optimist so I like it cares yeah I like
it yeah um so you're saying this uh this
Isabella it smells like
grapes it's very grapy yes mhm nice I I
love gra they actually they had two at
that time those guys are like that you
know they have like numbering they pop
few packs and they have the numbers you
know the vaa number you know 25 or the
vaa number three or the vaa number five
you know it's and then the winner from
those my vaa is the vaa number
four and they never could grow it in
their region because they are in the
mountains but I live in the Flatlands in
my region outside she always performed
always no no mold
nothing in their region she she didn't
perform and they have another wapa which
is called number
two and the two I think they don't have
anymore but it performed for them and
after a few years they came back to me
and said can you give us the four again
so we'll try it again maybe maybe this
time it will work so I give give it
back and uh they they they have the same
results they said no it's not working
you
know uh those are the people who
organized the Shiva cut back for me I
can I can talk maybe a little bit about
the Shiva yeah yeah I have few Cuts you
know this is very old in my facility in
Austria uh but the Shiva cut is very
interesting one uh it it it is one cut
that a friend of mine um acquired he
came back from Amsterdam with this C in
1997 and uh he was one guy that was
partying all the time you know he was
one guy that is in the hardcore punk
culture of my country he was one of
those guys you know really like crazy
crazy guy he went to study from the
region where I live also to luo like six
seven years before I went to study so he
we went to apartment where one guy was
already a dealer a weed dealer that was
end of the'
80s uh so that we dealer he quit to deal
with but he got the customers that were
used to come to this apartment so the
guy you know my guy I call him lucky let
let Call Him Lucky CU that was his name
we call him lucky lucky took all his
customers so he started to grow wheat
indoors also because he went to
Amsterdam in the beginning of the 8 '90s
and he saw the indoor wheight you know
like he's a guy from you know after
Yugoslavia split up there was no control
Slovenia in one moment had no visa for
Iran or USA can you imagine I could get
I could travel to USA without a Visa and
in the next day I would travel to Iran
without the Visa it's crazy crazy you
know it's crazy we had one year that you
could travel like this so he went but he
went after also but he was this guy you
know and he actually acquired this cut
let me say on a high times can of cop
when he was a judge like he you could
buy a judge P because I was always
thinking long time uh that he was like
chosen to be a judge you know which is
for me ridiculous because who knows this
guy you know from from Slovenia you know
nobody knew him of course he paid for
for to be a judge because you have to
pay to go from coffee shop to coffee
shop in the 19s to get the wheat that
they were like judging on right yeah so
how he get the cut will never be known
because he got it and he he came with it
but he always said it's the
Shiva and we don't know is the Shiva one
Shanti Shiva Shanti 1 Shiva Shanti 2 is
the Shiva skunk or is it the super skunk
because he said it is labeled s s you
know and he always call it the Shiva he
said it's a
Shiva so actually you know but is one
plant that is very very uh fast fast
rooting it is absolutely the fastest
rooting plant in my facility definitely
it roots in the first plant start to
root in 6 days they start you know start
and then on the 10th day you have to
open the lead and put it out and crazy
crazy you know and all the pry what what
we cross because KV smes that we you
know we search for weed that is not
related to this wheat to make F1
generation to make one good hybrid and
we choose Kung V's gear in the beginning
because he was the one with the cand do
you know we couldn't get the cam do from
you guys at that time but still now we
don't have it but uh we wanted something
that is very very far away genetically
from this plant yeah so we crossed it
and we got one hybrid from that which is
one of the best selling plants in my
facility now you know nice yeah what do
you call
it rodigo
express say the first word again rodig
[__]
expresso I can show
you Bank logo that I develop no maybe
it's uh turned uh but this is a hand
with a
sprout
uh this is something I will put out in
the future sometime you know and make a
little send me some photos and I'll I'll
add the photos but one thing I wanted to
tell you is don't feel bad about not
having the chem dog because most people
in the US don't have it either
it's it's like one of the most tightly
kept strains that that exist that's
really never been circulated actually
because you told me why because it's
hard to
grow well that and because the people
that have it hold it closely you know
because of that it's a very people want
to buy it but it's very difficult to to
buy it
mhm actually the only way we could get
to the flavor of this C dog which I
believed that is the truth you know uh
is through V's gear you know and uh the
friend of mine which I will shout out
now uh is old school genetics from
Barcelona his old man green and his crew
of people that grow those are true
Growers I love them they are the ones
that still put out regular seats in
European market which is a [__]
Rarity besides Shanti and Karma genetics
Nobody Does it it's it's very rare to do
that it me Europe the femin seeds are
dominating now and I'm with Gabby we
talked already about femin seeds we have
both uh our different opinions about
femin seeds uh but both of us are the
same uh I think uh opinion that regulars
should not die
out y ever if we get rid of males then
we are [__] you know really [__] and
also we agree on one point that uh
finding the real male is [__] [__]
difficult it's the most difficult maybe
you will find it or you will never find
it you will never find it yeah I agree
it's like maybe the guy somebody who
will find it will not know that it's so
valuable and he'll throw it away
I think that is really I think that
happens with females too yeah yes yes
definitely uh the male cannabis plant is
like the male cannabis plant is the most
underappreciated plant on the
planet you know like considering what
its real value is to to how little
appreciation it gets it's it's pretty
ridiculous yeah it's like all trial and
error with males and you got to I feel
like the best ones that I've found are
always structure and stem rubs like as
long as they got a a good branching
structure I'm happy with them
usually I mean I few years ago I listen
you know you have to understand I live
on the other side of this planet but I
still I'm very updated what you guys are
talking yeah so I listen to minin from
and thein a few years ago mhm and he
tells uh Theory like he has one
technique
of finding males a little bit better
than you would
normally you have to grow them out for
sure yeah but how do you grow them out
you grow them and then you find out it's
the males you separate them put them
into a place where they are for
themselves and you label them and then
you wait that they are like growing and
putting out the the flowers and then
before they opening
you're cutting them you cut the most of
this plant cut away and you leave the
lower
branches so they have to grow again and
put a little bit of sex again and pollen
right they're getting older you have
more of the aroma for from
steamr uh and maybe they have some
crystals you
know so before I like that yeah me mean
Jean from Andino told this few years ago
you he your guy so oh yeah but if you
ask him he will definitely say yeah I
told it because that's a way how to skip
a little bit if you are trying to find
from one generation you know uh of males
from the same you know Brothers you know
from the same cross try to find the best
one you know maybe the one that smells
better not looks better is the one you
know because I choose a mail that is
looks good you know but it's make
actually pretty decent weat so I know
you know you never know you have to work
work work work yeah and something that I
recently heard on another podcast um and
we talked about it Sasha but I want to
see if Nick knows anything about this I
was hearding hearing about reversing
males and that when you reverse a male
and try to make it into a female you
know it's not going to produce buds like
a female but you can get it to do
something so that maybe you can get more
of a smell off of
it e you can provide a mail with uh like
ethylene gas supplements and have it
produce more female sex Parts yeah it's
it's something you can do but it's a
it's a whole different process cuz you
have to have an enclosed chamber to
provide the ethylene gas exchange
properly H it's very and I were talking
about yesterday was how when people talk
about selecting the
male you know you're doing the best you
can
but you know the only way to really
select a male is to pollinate plants
with it and then grow those plants out
and then pollinate the same plants with
another male and then grow those plants
out that's the only way you can tell
which male is doing better work we can
make guests guesses
but I I think it's a lot of arrogance
when people think that you know they
pheno hunted a male you know and also
you know these are the same people that
they say they F feno hunted a male from
a 10 pack of
seeds you know it's like proper feno
hunt you need many many seats and you
know picking one male out of five you
know males that you got out of a seed
pack that's not a a feno hunt it's luck
you know if you get something good it's
it's a hell of a lot of luck yes I mean
females are obviously easy you see them
you can smoke them you can smell them
right so choosing a female you know is
easier choosing a
male you know like
people in sh pollen get a lot of uh I
don't want to say grief but you know
they look they get looked down upon by
you know people that are real
breeders but you know the real breeders
are doing the same thing they're
chucking pollen the real breeders they
don't know until they're using
accidental Cuts their bases like with
anything that was like like
in the lineage or anything that has Sour
Diesel in the
lineage that's they're they're using
accidental
genetics I mean who does line breeding
today you know line real line breeding
to multiple generation line breeding so
there is a guy that
um that I met on Reddit and he goes by
lemon
hoko and that's what he's doing
and you know when I listen to him I'm
like this is one of the real breeders of
today you know that's you know where
everyone else is doing a lot of pollen
chucking he's actually trying to
make um you know stabilized lines like
that I think like skunk Tech with his
like lario gf9 or whatever that he's uh
he's already taken to like the I think
he's at like the F10 or f11 St
where Burg STS come from and um he like
the guy that found GMO and
stuff lemon lemon Larry OG
Kush uh lemon hoko I think is his name
is that you're talking about lemon hoko
and then I'm talking about skunk Tech
skunk that did uh like uh
Larry you know I only know about these
people because of Instagram you know for
example how I came you know I will tell
you now how I came to you guys actually
first guy that I really
followed was a guy is a guy named named
Duke Diamond you know uh he has this
Dominion SE company and I actually know
about him because I I I'm a really big
fan of the old Cindy
99 uh uh strain which came from Brothers
Grim seeds at a certain time in the '90s
and I like the story how he cubed it and
he made back crosses several generation
back crosses until he found the C the99
yeah and then uh I heard about how it
was
resurrected by an american guy and I was
like who is this guy and it was Duke
diamond and and uh over Duke Diamond I
came to skan
VA because they were like you you can
still find it on YouTube there is some I
don't know Affair where they sit
together and they having a talk on the
stage both of
them and I think after that Duke went to
prison again and he disappeared and then
he came back and I think he's one of the
most underrated breeders in
USA the the [__] that he does I mean I
don't know but I from the far that what
I can read and I can see this is the
most humble guy next to Shanti in Europe
that I
know the most humble guy
ever uh I met him I never met Duke I
hope I will um I hope he's he's good
he's well he's living a good life with
his family family now and I know that
he's done time and it's been horrible
what he has gone through definitely I
mean what this guy has but the genetics
that he put out have you seen the logo
of him he has a Virginia
logo with instead of the guy that lying
you know a skunk with a with a butt is
over it standing on it you know and
that's Dominion SE company and all the
gear that he's put
out uh I mean and then I came to SK VA
and all the kok story and everything
around it yeah so that's why we sit
together here without Duke Diamond I
think and all the the stuff I heard
about him I would not be so motivated to
listen to the story because he's a very
uh professional humble guy the guy that
grew up in a Countryside like me he
knows about plants he has a torture
chamber before he puts out
gear can you imagine he's putting to the
stress test he's putting out uh the gear
to the stress that he can explain to you
if there will be nanners in the e n
week no no don't worry you know it's
just you know so he explains the
genetics uh with uh very
truthful I mean nobody writes about
seeds like him
does and you know that's fantastic I
mean he's a Marvel and I I don't have no
seats from
him I would like to have one day you
know but um you know I got to skan VA
seats and I consider them actually I
have seats from him because I bought the
first generation of Brothers GM seeds
when they came out again
I think Tommy his name is Tommy Duke
Tommy was working on those so I got the
Rosetta Stone I got the the C the 99 we
had we we had a clone for years and we
don't have it anymore but we have still
some genetics from him still so uh Hey I
want to interrupt you real fast Sasha I
want to say that my hope and dream is
that someday this podcast that we're
having together with you does the same
inspiration for someone else you know
and particularly you know
like you know you're in Slovenia and I'm
in California and next uh Oregon and you
know Instagram or the podcast or
whatever it it brought us together you
know we always talk about how we're
6,000 Mi away but we're talking to each
other live and seeing each other live so
so hopefully more people from Slovenia
and and you know throughout the world
will be inspired by conversations like
that like this but I want to get back to
talking about your nursery and what um
what growing cannabis in Austria and and
Slovenia is like I started my Nursery in
2019 yeah I mean started it started for
me as a business because I was was
working for other people before yeah in
Austria this business is
already more than 35 years so 25 years
and I started my bus business 5 years
ago so when I went into this business it
was already a 20 year business in the
country so I was asking myself do you
have to offer something that you can
compete because you know you have to
compete you can't not be some idiot [__]
and start a business with that you know
if you don't know [__] so I did you know
and uh I was successful in that sense
that I my all the library that I have uh
before I acquired clones from other
countries uh I put in
myself because of my connections
um I got clones from the mountains I got
my own clones I got clones from the
Flatlands I got clones from you know let
me tell you this you know like so many
people contributed to this library that
is not only mine this is not my library
this is also people who died already
they are gone but I still keep their
plans all like and the Legacy goes on
you know it's a beautiful thing in that
sense that I can still sell the the the
Shiva cut which is uh lucky you know
Luck's cot he even asked me before he
died you know because you know lucky
died like this you know um I knew about
that it that he has cancer one friend
called me like lucky has cancer and like
four five months after they called me
that he died so he was like it was
really
fast and uh he I met him on a concert
before before I even know that he has
cancer or something and he told me can
you name that cut after
me I said I will his name was s and that
means Lucky in our language
to means
luck so his name wasko the lucky one you
know and he was the lucky one in that
sense
and um the library consists of many Cuts
Like This one of those cuts is his Shiva
the another cut which is very old came
from grats
uh it's Santa Maria it's a plank cut we
call it it is a production plant from
the '90s from
Holland um it's a very much sativa
dominant plant but a very FL fast
flowering you know it has 7 and 1/2
weeks of flower indoors it's a silver
Pearl
F7 crossed with Mexican something I
don't know you know it's
like the there very interesting story
about this plant because I was attacked
by um one year ago I have to change the
name of my list because it's only plank
clone only now before that it was Santa
Maria PL
no mercy Supply was the company that put
this clone out and no mercy Supply is a
company from Holland from NE
Netherlands which uh was owned by a guy
named C and he was a
legend I don't I don't know much about
him but I got last year a threatening
male that I should put this plant out of
my list and that is his intellectual
intellectual property and you know I
just said okay I will remove the company
the No Mercy Supply you know I talk
about it no but it's like people should
know it's funny you were giving him
credit I'm giving him credit he he
doesn't want the credit he you no and I
said to him hey I'm admiring you you are
the breeder can I send you the cut of
course for free it's yours right and he
was like even more threatening me that
he will come to the balans and you know
they said come to the balans man you are
there you know my
brother yeah go try to find a hobbit in
the forest good
luck yeah so but I don't you know I'm
not dealing with this kind
of uh energy in my life I'm a positive
guy you know I want I'm a I'm a li
librarian you know I like keeping
genetic material alive for the future
generation
and I I know that this plank cut is
definitely older than any cut in my
facility
because in N uh 2005 when I uh first see
it in GRS in Austria I saw it in GRS in
a shop called Pyon NOA and still exist
and the guy that runs the shop is called
Marian and Maran is one of the nicest
people on Earth and and he's the guy
that has uh a little bit of my facility
you know as a room and he's keeping 50
50 strains you know he's like you know
of each cultiv he's like one or two
plants only and he's cutting you know
and caring for it and everything and he
has a small shop and he helps people he
helps people out like you did Gabby I
think with your shop like so many people
that benefited from your energy and from
your experience you know uh this the
same it's the same story everybody in
grats you know this is south of Vienna
you know Vienna is the capital of
Austria grat is South it's the capital
of sta the the land where we live so
this shop still sells plants they don't
make any advertisement they're like the
one you know have to search them you
have to search them they not going on
like my site Gabby I have I'm not really
advertising but you know what I mean
it's like I I have a site you know this
guy does not he has a Google info site
or something you know with the list of
clones and he's still work doing his
thing he's the oldest one and and Maran
told me uh when I acquired the clone
from him 2005 he told me hey sash this
is the oldest clone I have and I said
how old is it it's like it's 15 years
definitely from the Netherlands you know
and that was in 2005 so ' 90s so '90s
you know like end of the 80s nobody can
know for
sure yeah nobody can really know for
sure I don't I will not uh argue because
we all know this uh we stories yeah I
think Noto was talking about it a lot
how we have our own perception of each
card that we acquired or you know people
live through life and nobody really
thought at a certain point of time that
it believe it will be so important you
know I I didn't you know the the the
cuts that I have maybe for you the most
interesting in my facility is the least
interesting cuts for the people that are
around me you know they all want the
American Cuts now they all want Cali
with you know yeah but we already have
that the and the plank and and the other
thing that's becomes super rare here is
sativa you know seven we flowering
sativa I was like yeah that would sell
really well he said a seven week
flowering sativa that grows short short
short it cannot handle its own weight
that's also it produces too much dense
flowers to to keep it you know you have
to net you have to put netting because
can't handle my own weight
either when you say sativa do you mean
in in effect or like is the flower
structure uh no the flow structure is
absolutely
Indica it has three leaf tips it has
three leaf uh when you Google it on seed
finder you will find the real uh cut the
Santa Maria plank cut that's it it is CL
I'm going to make a note but there is
like you know uh because the seed
company still sells it a seed they went
into F
f8 because this should be F6 or F7
because I acquired it so long time ago
it is production plant you know and it's
a silver Pearl cross to Mexican I think
you know and what do the leaves look
like you said the bud but does it have
fat leaves like in Inda or is it more
skinny leaves like a
sativa oh it has a mix between and it
has three fingers
only always not only sometimes five but
mostly
three and it's uh smelling like mango
fruit and it has only 14 to 15%
THC it's a very uplifting plant it
sounds amazing that sounds really
good I'm I haven't had breakfast and I'm
drooling I'm like I mean people tell
about it you know there is a old story
about this particular cut that is from
the Brazilian Amazon used for ritual
purposes blah blah blah blah but this is
all fake I think this is not true this
they breed it in Holland maybe they got
the genetics from South America maybe
but they it was stabilized and breed in
Holland in the in the green houses yeah
so it also a it was a purposely bread
plant for production
definitely it looks like this I mean if
you so something that go ahead Nick if C
if you know CI weed is what people want
out there now um what do you keep uh as
selections of that style of weed in your
uh in your mother program okay
um there was a time a few years ago when
I acquired a first four clones from USA
gentic
and those are in Zan in the membrane
from atos wedding cake Portland we only
know that is the wedding cake Portland
Fino over we don't know SE no breeder no
name no
nothing then the Mac we we first thought
is the Mac one from
cap but it's not it's Mac V2 because we
searched we asked then the guy again who
gave us this card and he show us the
package and it was Mac
V2 it is still in seat form uh it's not
the Clone only version it's good one
it's really nice selection it's good uh
and another one which is wait the
wedding cake and Z which one wait I will
have to see and the Skittles cookies
that what I want to there the skittle
cookies is uh a plant uh that we also
don't know the breeder but is Skittles
versus
cookies you know it's a good it's very
similar to Mac those are the first four
and we got it from a source that will
not name now then the second round of
American clones we got from finest
condoms in
California and uh we got them by Co
coincidence coincidence means I was in
my shop one
day two years ago
almost and a guy that is my actually a
guy that I know he's also working for
UPS by the way you know for the
delivery and he came with a package and
he said Sasha you owe me
560 this is like $700 or
$650 and I I was like
Yuri why you know I don't know why
I didn't order nothing for $600 hm you
know
so um he said to me the look at the
package and I said package is from USA I
look at the you know what the paper is
USA okay and uh I open it because I said
to him I cannot pay you $600 if you if I
don't know what is inside because I
order
nothing and open it and they were hidden
inside into into small zip bags clones
and all of the Clones have
names it is U apple banana Joker
31 uh grapes and cream cush Crasher
hippie
Crasher uh you know the [__] Detroit
runs runs you nothing I ordered nothing
where did it come
from it was a gift from the Cannabis
Gods dude and to have those show up on
your door step that's crazy jaw you know
yeah he opened the the heaven for me jaw
and give it to me you know like you know
thank you but who who yeah I will not
tell from which country now yeah but in
2021 I had an export which is official
from Austria to a country that is
outside of
Europe it is outside of Europe it's not
European Union
yeah and uh it's a company and they I
exported officially to this
place with uh food and rug
Administration it took me 4 months for
the paperwork it was very
complicated
uh these same people went to
USA and buy clones and send it to me
first because they knew that they can
import it again because otherwise they
could not be
imported because of the paperwork I will
not tell who it
is I will not tell which country it is
but it's not
Europe so understand these people say me
these clones were uh uh also sent to me
without being
rooted they send
it in one day and the next day they were
in Austria from
California unrooted in in tissue which
is wet in zip bags that are
closed and I got a lot of I mean and so
do you still have all those genetics
then at your facility or did you uh just
kind of were you a pit stop for them
no I I keep the moms cool I keep the
moms those are some good ones I I have a
few of those at my facility that I that
I work
at what was weird about that story is
that they didn't ask you first they
didn't say hey Sasha we want to send
these genetics we can't get them we want
to send them to you and then you know I
mean they just like you open up a box
plausible deniability baby
yeah nobody asked I think I was not the
only address for them also you know what
I mean oh for sure you were one of the
many that they probably sent the
genetics to so that they would
eventually get them I have a feeling I
know which country was the destination
but we won't talk about that here
no yes so I acquired also this American
American genetics from which I'm very
you know I I'm excited of course I mean
you know I'm totally excited about it
but on the other
hand uh some of them are really
boring yeah you're going to find a lot
of them are and that a lot of them are
similar you
know if you breed only for THC that what
I wanted to tell before if you only
breed for THC and looks it's not uh
going to the end product will result in
lower quality for the experience I think
because on the end what do you care
about how the weed looks when you when
you consume it right I mean well who
cares I I hold on let me just say this
that's like
saying and I'm going to try to say this
delicately um what do you care about how
beautiful your woman is if you're having
sex with her right
you know so I mean like I I
think I think physical appearance isn't
as important as we make it and you know
but I think it does mean something and I
do think that you can tell
something about the quality of cannabis
by looking at it right so when something
looks better when something looks better
you know but I mean with qu
right right chem dog was some shitty
looking weed it really didn't look great
you know um but the way it smelled the
way it smelled you know so you have to
kind of look at all the parameters you
know first the way it looks then the way
it smells you know then of course you
smoke it you know or consume it how
however you would do that
um but you know it's the same with any
um any plant right with all plants we
breed for
looks okay even in you know the organic
section you know of the supermarket
where I shop when you look at the
tomatoes they like to get the tomatoes
that have lots of different
colors right you know the the heirloom
varieties but you know people want their
food to look pretty you know you don't
want to put something on a plate that's
ugly and it's it's kind of the same
thing with cannabis also in the US
particularly or I I think it's probably
everywhere but definitely in California
you don't even get to smell the weed
before you buy it at a dispensary no you
get to see it in a
jar right so the only right so the only
way you could wait and it gets worse so
the way you judge weed when you don't
know right when the average consumer who
is not a cultivator he goes into a club
they can look at two things they look at
what does the bud look like you know in
a jar and then what is the THC
content right those are the two metrics
that they have to make their decision so
a a lot of the breeding for high
THC is based on the
bureaucracy of that's one of the two
metrics that people have to choose their
weed right when it was only it was one
of the only metrics that was able to be
Quantified early on as well and so it
that like when you went into a
dispensary like in the 25 prop 215 days
you would maybe get th I think you were
able to get THC percentage uh in most of
the places smell the weed they would let
you smell the weed back absolutely some
places will let you touch it if it was
just like their uh their grab jar or
whatever they called it at the time umh
but uh yeah they they still like THC was
still the only actual quantifiable
metric that they could give you I give
you I give you a one example you know I
got a lot of uh inquiries from Germany
now right now you know from April this
year because Germany
legalized and in one day to another you
can actually send plans to Germany which
was absolutely impossible before that
absolutely
and I was not uh even I'm the last shop
in Austria that start to do it because
I'm the I'm the guy that will you know
look for I will not be you know in any
risk of anything because I can lose my
whole business just because one one male
you know I will not do that so we tried
to know how many plants we can sell to
Germany to one person in the beginning
nobody knew
uh and now we know that it's like they
can grow three plants we can send five
plants we can send seven
seats per
person wow it's still it's still going
to be um like it is uh a personal use
you know so so any German citizen can
order from you yes oh that's really cool
yes it started now that's why you know
and uh my my genetic libraries also is
very vast for that and people who like
wheat you know of course Germany is a
big Market you know they they already
called me years ago if I could send
plants I I always said no because it's
illegal yeah they even Germany even had
a law EXT extra law for not selling
cannabis seeds in the country even seeds
were forbidden which in all the other
countries are not they are souvenirs
they are sold as souvenirs which you as
an 18 or older year old person can
sprout in your country or not depending
on your
law you know so Germany is a big market
now I want to tell you this that I get
inquiries every day uh almost and uh I
don't sell to everybody because uh I
don't want to risk you know some some
people ask for too lot too much and um
but I you know the things that we have
in our facility as genetic
material grow people that does not uh
you know in your place they cannot buy
this because it's too
expensive but they are
Hobbits so they can grow
it and they grow it nice and uh you
change perception
you change perceptions you help people
with cancer you help people with
different kind of diseases they are you
know I'm not actually for that that
everybody should cook their own oil at
home because people are stupid also so
they would use uh bad solvents and uh
you know yeah also I'm for that that
that the government takes over and has
the the standard you know the quality
control for that you know that would be
appropriate in a civilized society that
doesn't work
this that doesn't work here you put it
in the hands of the government they're
going to [__] it up how many countries
are you allowed to export to legally all
Europe if they have a
permit I have a European I have a
European passport for the plants is um
is Germany the only country where the um
there's uh Recreation grow or um
personal grow ah uh I think yeah
personal grow yes well how you're
allowed to grow you're allowed to grow
for personal I don't know about I
thought you were allowed to grow like
five plants or something there that
could be you know Luxembourg yeah of
course Luxembourg you they can grow okay
and Malta and Malta they can grow okay
they have legalized Canabis and
Spain but Spain we cannot send to Spain
we try it uh the plot won't survive I
mean even if I sendic
express it's like also Spain got so much
weed yeah you it's it's crazy we go to
spawn Abes every year because there
that's where I meet my people you know I
can also meet American people you that
can you know that's the only point where
we can meet actually and we do and it's
nice you know uh
yeah that would be
awesome yeah it's a big party also
Barcelona is a fantastic place to have
party and it's great food there's great
people people it's great people it's
positive vibe absolutely totally and the
spab as itself is a it's like a free
it's free you can smoke everywhere you
know even Barcelona the social clubs are
really I mean you have to follow rules
of course you know you you're not
standing in front of of a social club in
front of in Barcelona Screaming in the
Night drunk you know and high you don't
do that cuz they have problems and they
always tell you walk as soon as you're
out walk you know and don't have
anything with you because you are not
allowed actually you allowed to consume
cannabis in these certain places but
it's not allowed to buy like I don't
know how much and then go home I mean of
course logically everyone does
but they are very quiet about it and
they respect the rules that's why you
know they want shut down yeah and you
you want your Club shut being shut down
where the best wheat is for you no you
don't so actually you care you care
Economist people always care we are we
are not alcoholics we are not um you
know we are not uh people who are on
cocaine we are not the heroin addicts we
are not we are the
normal people we're pretty Cal everyday
normal people pretty calm you know we
have our habits of course munches maybe
is the
worst you
know terrible food yeah yeah but
otherwise we are creative people we are
musicians we are
artists we are uh
activists We Care other people don't so
you know I think all of these people is
great great people not all of course not
all but you know a great
majority yes a great majority of course
everywhere you go in the world you know
I mean if I would stumble on you
man we would be a party I mean we have
we would have to talk a lot like to
Gabby we just met a few days ago over
the
internet you know we talk every day now
we talk every day know yeah for hours
yeah I you know it will be normalized in
the time but but actually we will meet
all day uh one day in person too and I
I'm really happy about this you know
so me too yeah you know like uh I I I
felt lucky to be able to talk to you for
the last you know week that we've been
talking we've been talking like every
day like really late your time like
putting you to bed no it's not so late
you know my kids are going to bed in 20
minutes I but weal we talked later in
the day you know other times as well and
uh yeah I'm just glad that we get to
tell people a little bit about your
story and the Cannabis culture in
Slovenia and Australia uh not Australia
Austria Austria yeah um yeah I hope
people find it as interesting as as I I
am and I I know Nick is as well I mean
this is just so fascinating to just hear
that from someone a similar mindset in a
different area of the world like it's
you know we talk when I see the photos
of your grow it's it's so beautiful you
know it's so clean it's like a retail
environment you know and um it's not
something that you see every day over
here and you know like they're being
like a place that's that's legal to just
buy plant like that it doesn't even
exist here so here what happens is like
you can have a nursery no no you can
have a
nursery a licensed cannabis Nursery that
maybe they sell to a
dispensary right and that dispensary has
a couple of plants there that they don't
know how to care for you know because
they don't have cultivators there you
know so the plants are basically just
there dying yeah you know like you know
what you have to do is if you buy plants
from a nurs a dispensary you have to buy
them like the day they show up you have
to like talk to The Dispensary you want
to say when do the plants show up 9:00
on Monday so 9:00 on Monday you got to
be there waiting online so that you can
choose the best plants before you know
they get hurt or or picked by other
people you know so when I saw the photos
of your place so it's you know yeah it's
either that or you can order clones
online but even that is still somewhat
of a um a risky business just
because yeah it's it's it's falling
still under the the US hemp bill um or
the the farm bill that includes the hemp
bill but it it's something that could be
repealed at any time and and that's the
only legal way that seeds and clones are
being shipped across state lines and
even within States now um so it's it's
not nearly as open as that I'm I I feel
like Gabby was also just as blown away
as me just to hear that you can ship
clones to Germany to a home grower yeah
that's MH that's insane that's so cool
but you have he has
is you have the like yeah you have the
phyto uh what is it called the phyto
sanitary certificate so that's basically
like if somebody wants to ship any
plants you know not cannabis of course
but any plants throughout the
you're supposed to have that certificate
just to ship it from one state to
another and in Europe that's the way it
is for you know the whole uh you know
you know all the continent of Europe is
that you know because they have the
European Union you could ship and the
plants are considered legal and you know
one thing I was Sasha was telling me
about is how like once a month or you
know very often they come to inspect you
to make make sure that your plants have
no virus and right you want to tell a
little something about that it's once
it's once a year Gabby once a year once
a year but very they're very uh you know
if you if you they see everything first
of all uh let me not say that now that
new virus came the the the Hop latent
you know that is now the they of course
don't know about that from when they see
the plants but they make the the tests
the Deep scans they make you know it
cost
500 every time they come every year yes
oh so it's like uh you pay also for
other they check for everything there's
like they check for Mosaic and for tabac
virus also not only hop plent you know
there is other viruses still The Hop
plent is more prevalent now in cannabis
for the last years but uh I think in the
future there will be others and Endo
fights will come you know V was talking
about this uh one week or two weeks ago
in a podcast on the on
the he talks about the truth actually we
have to fight this [__] you know
especially with older plants with older
CS that been old through the closets and
all kind of environments that they been
through you have to be careful you mean
you know whole plent is so like a like a
white fire you can you cannot stop it if
if it comes so yeah it's like the tissue
culture thing is real so we have to do
it actually all of us I think do you
have a tissue culture lab set up not yet
but we are working on it very very uh
much now it's going to be very fast now
yeah I feel like that'll be such a such
an uh amazing way to also have genetics
imported um with with as little risk as
possible found this so fascinating to to
hear from somebody else that has you
know a a gen Library as large as you do
that and and you're keeping it in such
great health with with such strict
regulations that's very impressive the
regulations for the health of plants in
the Cannabis industry out here are
basically zero until it reaches final
product um like there there would be no
testing for any pathogens even in the
final flower of of plants um
only thing they would test for would be
like molds and and that's not even
necessarily the case or wasn't
necessarily the case in all the
different states that have
legalized um you know from the Inception
of their legalization they they just
didn't have that in place to uh to test
for molds or pathogens and now only some
of them test for molds and um some of
them it's only for the like a Mot toxin
that could have formed from a mold uh so
they don't actually test for like the
molds themselves
um but it's just it's just really
fascinating to hear that like you're
you're
uh required by the local or by the
regulatory body to have inspectors come
in that you pay for the testing and have
the proper testing done to their
specific standards like that's I'm I'm
sure that if the US goes legal that's
how it's going to go as well where it's
going to have these more stricter
standards and it's just interesting to
see that it there's models already out
there where this is happening there is
there is actually it's very smart to do
that because otherwise we will infect
each other with different kind of stuff
that you you know it's not it's it's
grown here but I send it to you in to
America and the whole economy will drop
because of some virus you know it's like
that's not uh it it's irresponsible to
do that actually it's very responsible
to have a
certification to pay for that you know
that normally people don't ask do you
test regularly on a regular basis yeah
test but one time in a year on the on
the government basis not on
uncertificated Labs that will tell me
PCR tests that I that I don't buy you
know that's is like he tells me it's 2
a test it's so cheap yeah but it doesn't
mean anything to me I rather pay
500 to have it really done the
professional way that ISO certification
that is also required for shipment into
other countries if you have that I will
pay if not you I will not you know
that's very leg so important yes it does
it is and it's also for other crops not
for Canabis only I mean this system this
was built for other stuff you not
cannabis just came in now you know what
I mean u i mean the three plants that
I'm in my life is associated is with
Canabis first of all uh I grow bamboo a
lot Gabby I will send you some videos of
my Bamboo Gardens because I have a lot
of bamboo here nice and to and
tomatoes I have a vast library of halom
tomato seeds which is from all around
the world mostly here from my region in
Serbia Macedonia
Kosovo uh Slovenian old varieties also
Indonesia because I live there for some
time um you know a lot of different
seeds so I my Trinity is cannabis bamboo
and tomato and in when I'm old guy I'm
going to be
beekeeper because slovenians are
beekeepers we we have a tradition of
beekeeping beekeeper hits ni yes
beekeeper you know that's why we are so
Hobbit and we are going to have to
continue because we have so much more to
talk about but uh I just want you to say
anything that you want to say in the
last two and a half minutes before we uh
we have to say goodbye yeah I want just
to say tell the people that uh I will
spread the love all the time I'm a small
guy from nowhere and
uh um we are all overseen by the mighty
unse unseen force that makes everything
possible so let's keep that in mind you
know don't complicate you know it's life
is Too
Short that's that's
it well this uh podcast we're calling it
grown with love from
Slovenia and
uh I I hope our relationship gets to
grow like the plants that you
do yes so my
brother thank thank you very much cheers
thanks for joining us as well wolf yep
absolutely
[Music]
this episode of gabbing with Gabby is
brought to you by the Breeders direct
Seed Company in my opinion the Breeders
direct seed company is your Premier
Source for clones and seeds and they are
the only place that you can get the
Gabby Staten Island collection so visit
breeders direct for all your seed and
clone needs